<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881219-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-19-88 2336EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-MexicoReform     12-19 0230</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Mexico Reform,0236</SECOND>
<HEAD>Government Plans Talks on Possible Electoral Reforms</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MEXICO CITY (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Salinas </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Gortari </PERSON> on Monday announced plans for talks on possible reforms to <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>'s electoral laws, a key demand of opposition politicians from both right and left. A statement from the president's office said the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Election </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> will begin `` a great public consultation'' next month and the Chamber of Deputies will discuss electoral reform at a special June session. The opposition says election laws are designed and administered to ensure continued rule by the <ORGANIZATION> Institutional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Revolutionary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, which has held power since 1929. <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Clouthier </PERSON>, who ran for president as nominee of the right-of-center <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Action </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, has been on a public fast since Thursday to dramatize his party's demand for electoral reform. Party president <PERSON> Luis </PERSON> <PERSON> Alvarez </PERSON> said <PERSON> Salinas </PERSON>' proposals do not go far enough for <PERSON> Clouthier </PERSON> to stop his hunger strike. He complained that `` they still have n't set up a special commission in the <ORGANIZATION> Chamber </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Deputies </ORGANIZATION> to begin changing election laws right now.'' <PERSON> Salinas </PERSON>' announcement came after he met with representatives of the leftist <ORGANIZATION> Authentic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> the </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mexican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Revolution </ORGANIZATION>, which backed runner-up <PERSON> Cuauhtemoc </PERSON> <PERSON> Cardenas </PERSON> in disputed July 6 elections. <PERSON> Clouthier </PERSON> came third. It was <PERSON> Salinas </PERSON>' second meeting with an opposition party since he took office Dec. 1. The day after his inauguration, he met <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Action </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> officials.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881219-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-19-88 2342EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-SriLanka 7thLd-Writethru a0734 12-19 0677</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Sri Lanka, 7th Ld-Writethru, a0734,0699</SECOND>
<HEAD>Governing Party Candidate Leading In Presidential Voting</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: LEADS with 7 grafs to UPDATE with new results; Restores
dropped first reference of election official. PICKS UP graf 7 pvs,
`In the north ...'
^LaserPhoto COL3</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By PATRICK CRUEZ</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>COLOMBO, Sri Lanka (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Prime Minister <PERSON> Ranasinghe </PERSON> <PERSON> Premadasa </PERSON> maintained his lead Tuesday in presidential elections marred by attacks from Sinhalese extremists who killed at least 15 people, officials said. Although the violence did not stop Monday's balloting in this ethnically divided island nation, it kept droves of eligible voters away. Turnout in reporting districts was below 50 percent of eligible voters. With 104 of 182 polling districts counted, <PERSON> Premadasa </PERSON> of the ruling <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> had 1,155,594 votes, or 51 percent, according to state television. His main rival, former Prime Minister <PERSON> Sirimavo </PERSON> <PERSON> Bandaranaike </PERSON> of the opposition <ORGANIZATION> Sri </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lanka </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Freedom </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> had 1,001,572, or 44 percent. <PERSON> Ossie </PERSON> <PERSON> Abeygoonesekera </PERSON>, head of a coalition of four small leftist parties, polled 99,129, or 4 percent. About 9.3 million people were eligible to vote. Turnout in the reporting districts was about 47 percent of eligible voters. Deputy Elections Commissioner <PERSON> Lakshman </PERSON> <PERSON> Perera </PERSON> compared it with 80 percent nationwide in the last presidential election six years ago. Sir <LOCATION> Lanka </LOCATION> has 9.3 million registered voters. In the north, where militants of the Tamil minority are fighting for an independent state, many districts reported less than 10 percent turnout. And in the south, where Sinhalese extremists of the <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION> oppose government concessions to the Tamils, turnout ranged from 20-70 percent All three candidates pledged to end ethnic strife that has brought this former tourist paradise off the southern tip of <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> to the brink of ruin. At least 8,500 people have been killed since separatists from the Tamil minority began a civil war in 1983. `` This is a battle between the ballot and the bullet. The bullet must not win,'' <PERSON> Premadasa </PERSON> said after voting in the capital, <LOCATION> Colombo </LOCATION>. Attacks by Sinhalese militants began after an agreement 18 months ago that promised Tamils regional autonomy in the north and east and introduced Indian troops to help disarm the rebels. <PERSON> Perera </PERSON> blamed violence and the <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION> threats to kill voters for the low turnout. The front is made up of Sinhalese extremists who oppose terms outgoing President <PERSON> Junius </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Jayewardene </PERSON> offered for settlement of the Tamil war. They have vowed to kill anyone who supported the government. All the presidential candidates are Sinhalese, a predominantly <ORGANIZATION> Buddhist </ORGANIZATION> group that makes up 75 percent of the <LOCATION> Sri </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lanka </LOCATION>'s 16 million people and runs the government, judiciary and military. Tamils, who are overwhelmingly Hindu and total 18 percent of the population, claim discrimination by the Sinhalese. Hundreds of people have been killed in the violence blamed on Sinhalese extremists. On Monday, police and military officials reported bomb and gun attacks on five voting stations in the Sinhalese heartland near the capital in southern <LOCATION> Sri </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lanka </LOCATION>. Nine voters, a soldier and a policeman were killed and 25 people were wounded, the officials said, speaking on condition of anonymity. A police sergeant, an election official and a driver were killed in ambushes of two jeeps carrying ballot boxes after polls closed in the southern <LOCATION> Moneragala </LOCATION> district, the military said. Police in <LOCATION> Ambalanagoda </LOCATION>, 50 miles south of <LOCATION> Colombo </LOCATION>, reported an officer killed. Military forces and police guarded polling places, particularly in the south where the Sinhalese gunmen operate. <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> personnel with automatic rifles joined police on guard duty at <LOCATION> Kaluthra </LOCATION>, 20 miles south of the capital. Soldiers were deployed at such crowded public places as the town's main bus station. <PERSON> Premadasa </PERSON> campaigned as a champion of the poor and promised monthly allowances equivalent to $ 75 for the poorest families but did not explain how he would pay for it. He and Mrs. <PERSON> Bandaranaike </PERSON>, who was prime minister in 1960-66 and 1970-77, oppose the agreement with <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> under which 47,000 Indian troops are in <LOCATION> Sri </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lanka </LOCATION>, former known as <ORGANIZATION> Ceylon </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Abeygoonasekera </PERSON> blamed both major parties for <LOCATION> Sri </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lanka </LOCATION>'s economic and ethnic problems
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881219-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-19-88 2350EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Japan-Assets     12-19 0193</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Japan-Assets,0197</SECOND>
<HEAD>Value of Japan's Land and Structures Tops GNP For First Time</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Spiraling real estate prices last year have boosted <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s actual assets past its gross national product for the first time, the government said today. The value of <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s actual assets _ its land and structures _ rose 20.2 percent to $ 3.04 trillion last year, while its GNP was $ 2.87 trillion, said <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Planning </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> chief <PERSON> Eiichi </PERSON> <PERSON> Nakao </PERSON>. Last year's soaring prices made land assets in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, a country roughly the size of <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, worth 4.1 times as much as all the land in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Kyodo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> said. In 1986, Japanese land value was calculated at 2.5 times that of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. Financial assets such as equity and deposits also rose, to $ 23.2 billion _ a 15.6 percent increase over 1986, the agency said. `` Rapid rise in land prices and booming stock trading'' fueled the explosion of assets, agency officials said. Urban land prices have stabilized somewhat in recent months following a series of measures by the central and local governments to control the spiral, but prices continue to rise in fast-growing suburbs.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881219-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-19-88 2350EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--QuakeConcert     12-19 0131</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Quake Concert,0133</SECOND>
<HEAD>Concert Raised $660,000 For Armenia</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A quickly arranged concert by world-famous musicians last week raised more than $ 660,000 to help victims of the devastating earthquake in <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Armenia </LOCATION>, organizers say. Cellist <PERSON> Mstislav </PERSON> <PERSON> Rostropovich </PERSON>, flutist <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Galway </PERSON>, and conductor <PERSON> Andre </PERSON> <PERSON> Previn </PERSON> joined the English Chamber Orchestra and several other musicians for Saturday's concert at <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>'s Barbican. The funds, to benefit the <ORGANIZATION> British </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION> Armenian earthquake appeal, came from video and record rights as well as ticket sales at the soldout performance in the 2,026-seat hall, according to the <ORGANIZATION> Armenia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appeal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>. The concert was broadcast live by the <ORGANIZATION> British </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Broadcasting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, and the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> and five other nations televised it. The Dec. 7 earthquake killed an estimated 55,000 people and left 500,000 homeless.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881219-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-19-88 0021EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Italy-Storm     12-19 0249</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Italy-Storm,0254</SECOND>
<HEAD>Winter Storm Leaves At Least Six Dead</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ROME (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A winter storm that locked much of <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION> in an icy grip of snow and frigid temperatures has left at least six people dead and five others missing and presumed drowned, news reports said. About 30 small mountain villages in central and southern <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION> and 10 on the island of <LOCATION> Sicily </LOCATION> were still isolated Sunday by snow, up to two six-feet deep in some places. The snow blocked blocked roads and passes. Four of the missing were aboard the oceanography research vessel Posillipo-Loran, missing and presumed sunk in the storm-tossed sea off <LOCATION> Naples </LOCATION>. Waves as high as 21 feet hampered the search for the crew. The body of a fisherman whose boat apparently was swamped during the storm washed up on a beach near <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION> early Sunday. Authorities were still looking for the other man aboard the boat, who was presumed drowned. Italian news reports said five other deaths from traffic accidents and heart failure had been attributed to the snow and cold. The thermometer dipped as low as six degrees below zero in the Dolomites in far northern <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION> and to freezing as far south as <LOCATION> Sicily </LOCATION>. None of the snow fell on <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION>, but the city was gripped by freezing temperatures. In <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, Pope <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> II </PERSON> on Sunday blessed nativity dolls during a traditional ceremony at <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Peter </LOCATION><LOCATION> 's </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Square </LOCATION>, where two fountains that normally shoot streams of water were locked in ice.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881219-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-19-88 0014EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-AIDSStudy     12-19 0354</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-AIDS Study,0360</SECOND>
<HEAD>Few New Yorkers Participate In AIDS Study</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A federal study to determine whether a drug can fight the onset of AIDS in people who carry the AIDS virus may be delayed because of a failure to attract enough volunteers in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, according to a published report. Six <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> medical centers participating in the study have attracted only 257 volunteers, <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> reported Sunday. Recruitment may be suffering because carriers of the AIDS virus do not want to risk being among the volunteers given a placebo and not the drug, it said. The study was designed to see whether AZT, or azidothymidine, can prevent or delay the onset of AIDS in people who carry the virus but have not developed symptoms of the disease. The antiviral agent has already been shown to prolong the lives of seriously ill AIDS patients. Some volunteers in the study are given AZT while others are given a placebo. Clinics in other cities participating in the study have not experienced serious recruitment difficulties. The <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Minnesota </ORGANIZATION> had 166 patients enrolled in the study, while <ORGANIZATION> Cornell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> had just nine volunteers after five months of recruitment through newspaper advertisements, doctors who have large AIDS practices and gay organizations. The recruitment problems in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, which has more AIDS patients than any other city, could slow down the entire study, the Times said. Some <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> study participants also may be cheating by taking steps to find out if they are getting AZT or the placebo, and then dropping out of the study or getting AZT from other doctors, the newspaper reported. Some volunteers in the study also are said to be taking anti-AIDS drugs that have not been approved for use, it said. Act Up, an AIDS organization, has charged that other tests for experimental drugs at three city medical schools have excluded the poor, minorities and women by drawing their volunteers from private hospitals, where most AIDS patients are white, middle-class men, rather than from municipal hospitals, the Times said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881219-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-19-88 0021EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--China-Fires     12-19 0150</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--China-Fires,0156</SECOND>
<HEAD>Fires Kill and Injure 60,000 Chinese in Past Decade</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Chinese have died in fires at a rate of seven per day over the past decade, an official newspaper reported today. The <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> Daily said 410,000 fires killed or injured 60,000 people and caused $ 784 million in damage over the past 10 years. The report did not give a figure for deaths, but at seven fatalities a day the total would be about 25,000. The daily, quoting the <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION>'s fire control department, said the majority of fires are caused by human error, negligence and failure to carry out fire safety measures. One-third of fires are a result of faulty electrical wiring in buildings, it said, and senior officials of enterprises hit by fires are rarely punished. The daily also quoted <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> fire officials as saying their communications and fire-fighting equipment are outdated.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881219-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-19-88 0022EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-PolygamistTrial     12-19 0701</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Polygamist Trial,0719</SECOND>
<HEAD>Late Patriarch's Memory Lingers Over Murder Trial Of Trio</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By PEG McENTEE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>COALVILLE, Utah (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The spirit of polygamist <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Singer </PERSON>, gunned down by lawmen nearly a decade ago, is a constant presence at the murder trial of three young men who took up arms for his cause. It lives in his son, <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Timothy </PERSON> <PERSON> Singer </PERSON>, who has spoken with anguish of his father's death, and in the testimony of <LOCATION> Addam </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Swapp </LOCATION>, husband of two of Singer's daughters and his father-in-law's spiritual heir And it is felt in the German immigrant's handmade buckskin coat, worn by <PERSON> Addam </PERSON>'s brother <PERSON> Jonathan </PERSON>, and in the volumes of Mormon scripture the three defendants have brought each day to a courtroom where closing arguments were scheduled today and the jury, after nine days of testimony, was expected to begin deliberating. Singer and the Swapp brothers are charged with murdering a state officer during a gunfight that ended the clan's 13-day standoff with police at their Marion homestead last winter. The confrontation began after Singer and the Swapp brothers bombed a nearby Mormon chapel on Jan. 16, the ninth anniversary of the elder Singer's death, and retreated to the family compound. Clan leader <PERSON> Addam </PERSON> <PERSON> Swapp </PERSON>, 27, said the bombing was prompted by a divine revelation. `` It has to do with the injustices perpetrated against our family,'' he testified. `` <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Singer </PERSON> was shot in the back, and nobody cared. `` The truth has been trampled on more than once, and we took a stand,'' <PERSON> Swapp </PERSON> said. `` We knew we had to do it. We knew we had to take one day at a time and trust in our God.'' Corrections Lt. <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> House </PERSON>, who had joined an <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> team in an attempt to arrest the Swapps on Jan. 28, was ordering a reluctant police dog to subdue the pair when he was shot in a volley of rifle fire from the wheelchair-bound Singer. Singer, 22, admitted firing the fatal shot but contended he was aiming at the dogs. <PERSON> Swapp </PERSON>, an excommunicated <PERSON> Mormon </PERSON>, married <PERSON> Heidi </PERSON> <PERSON> Singer </PERSON> in 1980 and her sister <LOCATION> Charlotte </LOCATION> a few years later. The father of seven, he has said he believed the bombing would trigger <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Singer </PERSON>'s resurrection and the collapse of a `` wicked and corrupt'' church and state Singer's widow, <PERSON> Vickie </PERSON>, says her husband's death was the result of a conspiracy between state authorities and church officials angry at his open practice of polygamy and refusal to send his children to public schools. The Mormon church officially abandoned polygamy in 1890. The Singers, also excommunicated Mormons, taught their children at home to shield them from a system they believed was tainted by sexual promiscuity, drug abuse and racial mixing. Finally, fearing the state would place his children in foster homes, Singer, 48, holed up in the compound for 18 days before being shot by officers in 1979. Police said he pointed a gun at officers trying to arrest him. In an interview taped by federal agents and played for the jury, <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Timothy </PERSON> <PERSON> Singer </PERSON> said that his father was shot as he walked to a mailbox. `` All these men zoomed in on him on snowmobiles, 10 men, what I've heard,'' he said. `` And he pulled out his gun and he, you know, -LRB- said -RRB- ` Back off, I do n't want any trouble now.' And he turned around to run home, my sister saw this through binoculars, and as he turned around to run home they shot him two to three times in the back.'' The younger Singer, a thin, quiet man left a paraplegic by a logging accident four years ago, told of his mother's wrongful death lawsuit, which was dismissed by a federal judge for insufficient evidence. `` I mean, we could n't get justice,'' he said. `` I mean, my dad's been killed and shot, and it would n't even be tried. If convicted, Singer and the Swapp brothers face five years to life in prison. <PERSON> Addam </PERSON> <PERSON> Swapp </PERSON> already has been sentenced to 15 years in prison on federal charges related to the bombing and standoff. Singer and <PERSON> Jonathan </PERSON> <PERSON> Swapp </PERSON> were given 10-year sentences in the case, while <PERSON> Vickie </PERSON> <PERSON> Singer </PERSON> was sentenced to five years.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881219-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-19-88 0025EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Argentina-Military     12-19 0784</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Argentina-Military,0806</SECOND>
<HEAD>Military Crisis Over; Military Problem Remains</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</NOTE>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ED McCULLOUGH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BUENOS AIRES, Argentina (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The columns of tanks are gone from city streets, and hundreds of soldiers who staged an abortive rebellion earlier this month have returned to the barracks. But <LOCATION> Argentina </LOCATION>'s military remains restive, and no one is predicting that the third insurrection in 20 months against the civilian government of President <PERSON> Raul </PERSON> <PERSON> Alfonsin </PERSON> will be the last. `` The military crisis was resolved, not the military question,'' says <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Berhongaray </PERSON>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>. `` There could be another insurrection.'' Government officials have worked since the four-day revolt ended Dec. 4 to assess the loyalty of army units _ some of which openly sided with the rebels, and others which refused to confront them _ and to meet some of the rebel demands. A general who publicly sympathized with rebel commander Col. <PERSON> Mohamed </PERSON> <PERSON> Ali </PERSON> <PERSON> Seineldin </PERSON> was retired, and the government hastily put together funds to give soldiers a 20 percent pay increase and a Christmas bonus. That may reduce tensions in the ranks, but it does n't address the root of the problem, say some prominent Argentines. Many in the military want an end to human rights trials of officers for their roles in a campaign of repression during the 1976-83 military dictatorship. They want a better role in society for the military, which lost the 1982 Falklands War and led <LOCATION> Argentina </LOCATION> into economic chaos during its rule. But <LOCATION> Argentina </LOCATION>'s military has toppled six civilian leaders since 1930, and some say it has never learned its place in society. `` The point is, the central point is, the military does not respond to civilian political power,'' says <PERSON> Adolfo </PERSON> <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> <PERSON> Esquivel </PERSON>, director of the human rights group <ORGANIZATION> Peace </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> and winner of the 1980 Nobel Peace Prize. In an interview at his sparsely furnished office, <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> <PERSON> Esquivel </PERSON> referred to one of the last incidents of the rebellion and said, `` Right in front of ` loyal' troops, ` rebels' fired tear gas and shot at civilians.'' `` There are n't ` loyal' troops. They're all accomplices of the rebels,'' he said, his voice devoid of stridency or anger. `` They share the same ideology. They only differ in method. Some were against the insurrection, some wanted to work through the political system.'' On Dec. 12, the commander of the 5th army corps, Gen. <PERSON> Humberto </PERSON> <PERSON> Ferrucci </PERSON>, confirmed the suspicions of many when he said the insurrection ended with an agreement between army chief Lt. Gen. <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Dante </PERSON> <PERSON> Caridi </PERSON> and <PERSON> Seineldin </PERSON>. There is widespread doubt that loyal troops `` suffocated'' the rebellion, as <PERSON> Alfonsin </PERSON> ordered them to do, but instead reached an agreement with the rebels, the terms of which have yet to be disclosed. That prospect unsettles, among others, <PERSON> Elias </PERSON> <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Salazar </PERSON>, president of the 8,000-member <ORGANIZATION> Buenos </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aires </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lawyers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>. Asked if the end of the rebellion meant democracy in <LOCATION> Argentina </LOCATION> was strengthened, or the institution of the presidency was fortified, <PERSON> Salazar </PERSON> shook his head from side to side and said: `` I think the situation of civilian political power is worse because the armed forces demonstrated that they are loyal to themselves and not to the president and commander-in-chief -LRB- <PERSON> Alfonsin </PERSON> -RRB-. `` The conclusion I draw is that the military does n't want power right now because the situation is not favorable. They would be repudiated by the people and economically, they would be taking over a situation that would not allow them to govern. ... They do n't want power, but they want to give the orders.'' Their demand for a recuperation of military honor and dignity, which had widespread resonance through the ranks, was a reaffirmation of the military view that the battle to curtail the kidnappings, bombings and assassinations of the 1970s was a civil war. A speech Saturday by Defense Minister <PERSON> Horacio </PERSON> <PERSON> Jaunarena </PERSON> supported that view. <PERSON> Jaunarena </PERSON> said the campaign, through brutal, was necessary. The view of human rights groups and others is that the arrest, `` disappearance'' and presumed execution of 9,000 Argentines was a brutal repression of society. <PERSON> Alfonsin </PERSON> has portrayed the end of the rebellion as a clear-cut victory in which organized labor, big business, foreign governments and tens of thousands of Argentines who gathered in plazas to protest the insurrection forced the rebels to give in. But the opposition <ORGANIZATION> Peronist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, with an eye to May 1989 national elections, is criticizing <PERSON> Alfonsin </PERSON> for his handling of the revolt, and demanding he develop a policy toward the military that reduces the risk of another revolt. Asked what effect the insurrection might have in the election, pollster <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Mora </PERSON> <PERSON> y </PERSON> <PERSON> Araujo </PERSON> said, `` We're asking ourselves that, but so far we do n't know ... It has n't ended.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881219-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-19-88 0026EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-DonaPaz     12-19 0714</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Dona Paz,0735</SECOND>
<HEAD>Nightmares, Abandonment Haunt Survivor Of Major Ship Disaster</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By EILEEN GUERRERO</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MANILA, Philippines (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Seventeen-year-old <PERSON> Arnel </PERSON> <PERSON> Galang </PERSON> still wakes up screaming, haunted by the faces of the 23 relatives he lost a year ago when the ferry Dona Paz sank with more than 3,000 people aboard. <PERSON> Arnel </PERSON>, then a high school senior, was one of only 26 passengers and crew who survived after the 2,215-ton <PERSON> Dona </PERSON> <PERSON> Paz </PERSON> collided with the 629-ton oil tanker Vector and exploded off <LOCATION> Mindoro </LOCATION> island the night of Dec. 20, 1987. A presidential commission said at least 3,563 people were aboard the two ships, but the precise figure may never be known. Only 108 bodies were recovered after the disaster, which the coast guard blamed on the Vector. For <PERSON> Arnel </PERSON>, the year has been one of bitterness and pain. He feels abandoned by a government that he says has done little to help him. Family members blame <PERSON> Arnel </PERSON> for not saving his relatives, including cousins, aunts and an infant niece, who perished on the Dona Paz. `` Everything that happened is still clear to me,'' he said, his hands trembling. `` Sometimes, I ca n't sleep. Sometimes, I get nightmares. I shout and cry, then I stay awake all night. In my dreams, they tell me they have not died, only wandered off to an unknown place. But I have to face reality. I just pray for them.'' <PERSON> Arnel </PERSON> and his relatives boarded the <PERSON> Dona </PERSON> <PERSON> Paz </PERSON> to go to <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION> to visit his sister, <PERSON> Rose </PERSON>, whom he had n't seen since childhood. It was his first time on a ship. Suddenly, about 10 p.m., he felt a strong thud. He ran for a wall and squeezed himself through a porthole. `` I struggled free and fell into the water,'' he recalled. `` I could n't hear anything anymore. There was just silence. The sea was on fire. My face was scalded. The water was very hot as if it were boiling water. I swam so fast. I do n't know how I did it.'' <PERSON> Arnel </PERSON> and the other survivors were rescued by a passing ship and brought to <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION>. There, he saw Rose. Burned and bandaged, he raced to embrace her. But the joy of reunion soon gave way to resentment. Relatives blamed him for not saving other family members. `` They ask me ` <PERSON> Arnel </PERSON>, Why did you not save your cousins?''' he said, fighting back tears. `` I tell them, ` There was nothing I could do.' It was difficult enough saving myself. Maybe if I tried to save them, we would all have died.'' Since the disaster, <PERSON> Arnel </PERSON> said he has shunned other relatives, including his parents, who live in <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Arnel </PERSON> is also bitter at the government, which he says abandoned him. He received 5,000 pesos, or $ 250, which President <PERSON> Corazon </PERSON> <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON> allocated for each survivor. But he said there has been no psychological counseling or rehabilitation for the survivors. Mrs. <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON> recommended <PERSON> Arnel </PERSON> for a job in a pharmacy but the company refused to hire him. His family is too poor to afford fees to complete his final year of high school. He works as an unpaid volunteer for an association of relatives of <PERSON> Dona </PERSON> <PERSON> Paz </PERSON> victims and survives on charity. <PERSON> Arnel </PERSON> said he and some relatives of victims have refused to accept a $ 1,500 lump sum payment from the shipowners, <ORGANIZATION> Sulpicio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Shipping </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lines </ORGANIZATION>, because the company insists they sign a waiver promising no further claims. In April, a group of survivors and relatives filed a class action suit seeking more compensation. The case was dismissed and an appeal is pending before the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>. In the meantime, <PERSON> Arnel </PERSON> is considering becoming a priest. `` When I think about the things I've gone through and am going through, I think that maybe God wants me to be a priest and serve him,'' he said. `` At this point, I have nothing else to lose and I am ready to offer my life.'' The sense of loneliness and abandonment is all the more painful at Christmas. Last Christmas, five days after the tragedy, <PERSON> Arnel </PERSON> spent the day crying in a corner of his parents' home, gazing out the window. This year, he plans to spend the holiday alone. `` I ca n't bear to face them again,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881219-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-19-88 0034EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-ShiiteBaalbek 1stLd-Writethru   12-19 0836</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Shiite Baalbek, 1st Ld-Writethru,a0408,0862</SECOND>
<HEAD>Shiites Bring Islamic Fundamentalism To Lebanon's Ancient Baalbek</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: To CORRECT to 15 number of foreign hostages, SUB 10th graf,
``Most Shiites ... in Khomeini.' Picks up 11th graf, ```We follow
...'
^By DONNA ABU-NASR</NOTE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BAALBEK, Lebanon (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The scantily dressed dancers are long gone. The last liquor store was blown up six years ago. This ancient Roman city now is the capital in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> of Shiite Moslem fundamentalism. Public drinking and dancing are forbidden now, but brief male-female unions called pleasure marriages are condoned. On the surface at least, life in <LOCATION> Baalbek </LOCATION> is governed by the dictates of <PERSON> Ayatollah </PERSON> <PERSON> Ruhollah </PERSON> <PERSON> Khomeini </PERSON>'s stern brand of Islamic fundamentalism in <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>, which to Western eyes appears joyless and forbidding. Wearing make-up or jewelery in public is taboo. So is singing and dancing at mixed gatherings, because as one woman noted, `` it causes psychological imbalance and tempts men.'' But when the sun goes down and the doors are locked, the black robe-like chadors Shiite women have to wear in public are discarded in favor of shorts and strapless tops, along with make-up and perfume. `` People think we're made of stone just because we cover ourselves with chadors. But we're not. We're ready to do anything to please our husbands,'' said <LOCATION> Selma </LOCATION>, a housewife. Before <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>'s civil war erupted in 1975, <LOCATION> Baalbek </LOCATION> was a cultural center where dance and theatrical festivals were held in the breathtaking Roman amphitheaters. Now the ruins echo to Islamic slogans as the fundamentalists stage political rallies there, chanting ritual denunciations of `` Death to <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>! Death to <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>!'' The amphitheaters have also been used as mortar positions in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>'s sectarian fighting. The Shiites' strict lifestyle has drawn bitter criticism from many Lebanese, Moslems and Christians alike, who say that the fundamentalists' `` double standards'' has brought Islam into disrepute. Most Shiites in <LOCATION> Baalbek </LOCATION> belong to <ORGANIZATION> Hezbollah </ORGANIZATION> -LRB- Party of God -RRB-, which is believed to be an umbrella for <ORGANIZATION> Shiite </ORGANIZATION> kidnappers holding most of the 15 foreigners missing in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>. It's made up of zealots blindly loyal to <PERSON> Khomeini </PERSON>. `` We follow whatever <PERSON> Khomeini </PERSON> decrees. Whatever he rejects, we reject,'' said <PERSON> Zeinab </PERSON> <PERSON> Nasser </PERSON>, an administrator at the women's `` haouzeh,'' or religious center, in <LOCATION> Baalbek </LOCATION> The practice of pleasure marriage is one of the many customs frowned on by other Lebanese, especially moderate Shiites and Sunnis. In a pleasure marriage, a young woman who would not dare expose a curl of her hair from under her chador can take on an unlimited number of lovers in the name of religion. But most of the women who take part in pleasure marriages are considered respectable and far from promiscuous. The practice is widespread in <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>, where overwhelming majority of the 54 million population is Shiite. <PERSON> Nasser </PERSON> said the Prophet <PERSON> Mohammed </PERSON> sanctioned pleasure marriage, making it acceptable for a couple to marry for a specified period which could last `` for an hour, two days, a month, or as long as they desire.'' `` It's all perfectly legal and provisions are made for any child born after the marriage contract expires,'' she explained. She said pleasure marriage is especially practical amid <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>'s economic crisis because `` men can not afford a regular marriage, and let's face it, they have physical needs `` If these can not be met within a permanent marriage, pleasure marriage provides the outlet,'' she added. `` It's much better than doing it illicitly.'' No cleric is required to perform the cermony. The woman, who should preferably be either divorced or widowed, tells the man, `` I give myself to you in pleasure.'' He responds: `` I accept.'' And that's it. Virgins need the consent of their parents, but they often do not seek it. As for forms of entertainment, the fundamentalists permit classical music `` because it does not have any negative psychological effects,'' <PERSON> Nasser </PERSON> said. She observed that a scientific report proved that loud music is bad for `` the nerves and the blood circulation.'' Like other factions in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>, where the government has collapsed, the Shiites have established their own medical and welfare systems, amply funded by <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Abbas </PERSON> <PERSON> Mousavi </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Hezbollah </ORGANIZATION> leader, told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>: `` Social work has become one of our main responsibilities because of the catastrophes that have befallen <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>. `` We've founded the <ORGANIZATION> Imam </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Khomeini </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION> here which provides free medical treatment. There are similar centers in other Shiite areas.'' He noted: `` We've also founded pharmacies that make a very small profit, as well as schools, which we hope will accommodate 6,000 students in the near future. `` We've given money to needy families and bought deep-bore drills to provide wells in remote villages, especially those we consider have military or political importance.'' Asked about complaints on restrictions against alcohol and night clubs, <PERSON> Mousavi </PERSON> noted: `` We're not imposing Islamic values on people. No one can say we've raided houses where people gamble or drink.'' Asked about the bombing of liquor stores and clubs, he conceded: `` There were incidents where young men acted out of Islamic zeal after witnessing aberrant behavior. But <ORGANIZATION> Hezbollah </ORGANIZATION> is against that.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881219-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-19-88 0035EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p AM-ChicagoMayoral     12-19 0468</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Chicago Mayoral,0480</SECOND>
<HEAD>Reports Conflict on Whether Jane Byrne May Run to Regain Mayor's
Office</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CHICAGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A 39-year-old alderman on Sunday became the only Hispanic candidate to enter the mayor's race, while reports conflicted on whether former Mayor <PERSON> Jane </PERSON> <PERSON> Byrne </PERSON> would announce her intention to regain her old office. <ORGANIZATION> WBBM-TV </ORGANIZATION> reported late Sunday that Mrs. <PERSON> Byrne </PERSON> said she would file her nominating petitions Monday and would announce her candidacy as a Republican. <ORGANIZATION> Cook </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Dvorak </PERSON> confirmed Mrs. <PERSON> Byrne </PERSON>'s plans and also said he would meet Monday with another rumored <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> candidate, former <PERSON> Alderman </PERSON> <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Vrdolyak </PERSON>, the television station said. Mrs. <PERSON> Byrne </PERSON>'s home telephone went unanswered Sunday evening. A local radio station, WMAQ-AM, said it had talked with Mrs. <PERSON> Byrne </PERSON> on Sunday and she had indicated she did not intend to file petitions Monday, the deadline. Meanwhile, <PERSON> Alderman </PERSON> <PERSON> Juan </PERSON> <PERSON> Soliz </PERSON>, president pro tem of the <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>, announced his candidacy, saying he could bridge the city's racial divisions better than either the announced white or black candidates <PERSON> Soliz </PERSON> joined five other Democrats _ three black and two white _ in seeking the highest office in the heavily Democratic city. The only announced <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> candidate is <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Howlett </PERSON>, the son of a former <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Illinois </ORGANIZATION> secretary of State. Republican slatemakers recently declined to endorse <PERSON> Howlett </PERSON>, saying instead that <PERSON> Vrdolyak </PERSON> and four lesser-known unannounced candidates have their go-ahead to run. Mrs. <PERSON> Byrne </PERSON> served her term as mayor, 1979-83, as a Democrat. In the Democratic mayoral primary of 1983, she split the white vote with <ORGANIZATION> Cook </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION>'s Attorney <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Daley </PERSON>, which allowed the late <PERSON> Harold </PERSON> <PERSON> Washington </PERSON> to win the nomination, and ultimately to become the city's first black mayor. <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> died of a heart attack in November 1987 a few months after winning a second term. The <ORGANIZATION> Illinois </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> has set April 4 as the date for a special election to fill the remaining two years of <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>'s second term The Democratic primary is scheduled for Feb. 28. <PERSON> Daley </PERSON>, son of the late Mayor <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Daley </PERSON>, again is a candidate for the Democratic nomination, as are <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>'s successor, Mayor <PERSON> Eugene </PERSON> <PERSON> Sawyer </PERSON>, <PERSON> Aldermen </PERSON> <PERSON> Timothy </PERSON> <PERSON> Evans </PERSON> and <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> <PERSON> Bloom </PERSON>, former state Sen. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON> and <PERSON> Soliz </PERSON> <PERSON> Daley </PERSON> and Bloom are white, while <PERSON> Sawyer </PERSON>, <PERSON> Evans </PERSON> and <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON> are black. Another black alderman, <PERSON> Danny </PERSON> <PERSON> Davis </PERSON>, dropped out of the race Thursday, saying <PERSON> Daley </PERSON> would win the election unless blacks unite behind a single candidate. <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> pledged his support to <PERSON> Evans </PERSON>. <PERSON> Soliz </PERSON> said he hopes for the support of other local Hispanic leaders, although he acknowledged that two other Hispanics in the City Council have already thrown their support to <PERSON> Evans </PERSON>. The city's population is a little more than 40 percent white, 40 percent black, 15 percent Hispanic and less than 5 percent of other races.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881219-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-19-88 0039EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lights     12-19 0367</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lights,0383</SECOND>
<HEAD>On The Light Side</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SAN FRANCISCO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The government is looking for a dozen men who would n't mind feasting on a diet of King salmon for 100 days. They'd even get paid a $ 2,300 salary. But there's a catch for those who participate in the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> study. `` We're talking about salmon with dill weed, broiled salmon, baked salmon _ just like the fine restaurant food,'' said <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON>, project coordinator for the department's <ORGANIZATION> Western </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Human </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nutrition </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> at the Presidio. He said the study should begin in January, and cautioned that it might not be quite as tantalizing as it sounds because it entails confinement, lots of physical tests and no conjugal visits. Participants will sleep, eat and drink at the center's hotellike facility that has a pool table, compact disc player and television. There will be daily walks and some organized activities, but no monkey business allowed. `` We do n't want anyone to sneak a candy bar or a beer,'' said <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON>. The <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> originally wanted women for its study, but could n't find any takers. The study is intended to gauge the effect that a steady diet of fish has on keeping arteries free of blood clots.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>FRANKLIN, Neb. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 City officials decided to brighten the holidays for the 1,170 residents of this rural <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION> community by paying their December electric bills. <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> agreed to forgive December bills totaling $ 41,069 when an audit showed a surplus in the city's electricity fund. City Clerk <PERSON> Dean </PERSON> <PERSON> Gartin </PERSON> said business and residential customers were pleased to find out they did n't have an electric bill when they came to City Hall to settle their monthly accounts. <PERSON> Helen </PERSON> <PERSON> Schmidt </PERSON>, director of the <ORGANIZATION> Franklin </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Senior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Citizens </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>, said the electricity bonus was well-received. `` Senior citizens thought it was great because it saved individuals approximately $ 50,'' Ms. <PERSON> Schmidt </PERSON> said. `` It was a wonderful Christmas present to everyone and we are glad the city passed it on to us.'' <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilsman </PERSON>, owner of Rightway Grocery, said the council's goodwill saved him $ 1,200 It was `` like finding money on the street,'' he said. The city purchases electricity for residences and businesses from three utilities.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881219-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-19-88 0039EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Quake-CandyMoney     12-19 0223</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Quake-Candy Money,0228</SECOND>
<HEAD>Fourth-Grade Students Donate $31.77 To Armenian Victims</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CALDWELL, Idaho (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Fourth-grade students at <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Elementary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> gave up their usual Friday afternoon treats to donate $ 31.77 in pennies, nickels, dimes and quarters to victims of the earthquake in <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Armenia </LOCATION>. `` We were reading about the <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION> effort in the paper and the kids just starting digging into their pockets,'' said teacher <PERSON> Ruth </PERSON> <PERSON> Cook </PERSON>. `` It was really spontaneous.'' Mrs. <PERSON> Cook </PERSON>'s class was studying geology when the earthquake hit Dec. 7, and discussions soon turned to the hardships being endured by the Armenian people. Her students decided to donate their weekly candy money to the victims, and classes taught by <PERSON> Jan </PERSON> <PERSON> Bolton </PERSON> and <PERSON> Kathy </PERSON> <PERSON> Drew </PERSON> soon joined in. `` I think when they heard about it, at first they thought, ` Russians, they're the enemy.' But that changed to ` How can we help,''' Mrs. <PERSON> Cook </PERSON> said. All the students wrote letters to an official at the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Embassy </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION>, explaining the donation. Nine-year-old <PERSON> Jared </PERSON> <PERSON> Howell </PERSON>'s letter was chosen to represent the group. `` We are very sorry to hear about the tragedy. We have thought a lot about the people who were left without families and homes, and would like to do what we can to try to help,'' he wrote. `` Please accept our Christmas gift from <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Russia </LOCATION>.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881219-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-19-88 0051EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-DeathMarch Bjt   12-19 0673</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Death March, Bjt,0695</SECOND>
<HEAD>Marine's Death In Desert Provokes Corps Investigation</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY9</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DENNIS ANDERSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SAN BERNARDINO, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Not far from where Marine <PERSON> Lance </PERSON> <PERSON> Cpl </PERSON>. <PERSON> Jason </PERSON> <PERSON> Rother </PERSON> ended his heroic march through the scorching <LOCATION> Mojave </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Desert </LOCATION> lies the shimmering ribbon of old Route 66. He nearly made it. Assigned to traffic duties during night desert maneuvers on Aug. 31, <PERSON> Rother </PERSON> was to have been picked up by 1 p.m.. A communications foul-up left him stranded with three canteens of water, some dry rations and a poncho to protect him from the <LOCATION> Mojave </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Desert </LOCATION>, where temperatures soar beyond 110 degrees Nearly two days passed before a search for the 19-year-old Marine began. The <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corps </ORGANIZATION> is investigating the delay and why <PERSON> Rother </PERSON> was stranded by his unit of the 2nd Marine Division based at <LOCATION> Camp </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lejeune </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.C. </LOCATION> Those matters, as well as why <PERSON> Rother </PERSON> was posted alone, will be raised during court-martial proceedings against <PERSON> Rother </PERSON>'s superiors `` The real issue is why it was 40 hours before we started looking,'' says <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corps </ORGANIZATION> Lt. Col. <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> Peck </PERSON> from <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. The mistake of <PERSON> Rother </PERSON>'s superiors cost him his life. Two officers have been relieved of their commands as a result. Another officer and two sergeants face special courts-martial for charges of dereliction of duty. Meanwhile, the commandant of the <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corps </ORGANIZATION> ordered his own inquiry to prevent a future tragedy. At some point during his ordeal, <PERSON> Rother </PERSON> set out, marking an arrow with stones to point his direction as he marched south out of a canyon. Leaving two additional arrows, he turned north and began walking toward the highway that was once <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Route 66, the cross-country road of hope and despair described in <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Steinbeck </PERSON>'s novel, `` The Grapes of Wrath.'' `` Who knows how long he waited?'' said <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bernardino </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> Sheriff's Deputy Chief <PERSON> Jerome </PERSON> <PERSON> Ringhofer </PERSON>. <PERSON> Ringhofer </PERSON> led the 160-member team that ultimately discovered <PERSON> Rother </PERSON>'s skeletal remains Dec. 4. Two earlier Marine-led searches yielded some of <PERSON> Rother </PERSON>'s equipment: a helmet, pack and flak jacket he abandoned on his way. `` We always advise that anyone in the desert or mountains stay put. But once he decided to move, he moved with direction and purpose,'' said <PERSON> Ringhofer </PERSON>. <PERSON> Rother </PERSON>'s bones, a wallet, his poncho, his clothing and an M203 rifle-grenade launcher were found near the community of <LOCATION> Bagdad </LOCATION>, less than a mile from old Highway 66 and just north of the boundary of the sprawling <ORGANIZATION> Twentynine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Palms </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> training base, about 125 miles east of <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>. `` He covered approximately 17 miles,'' <PERSON> Ringhofer </PERSON> said. `` He made a heroic effort, and he almost succeeded. `` He had to see the highway. You ca n't miss it.'' At the last, suffering from heat exhaustion and dehydration, <PERSON> Rother </PERSON> took off his clothes and neatly folded them. He neatly folded his poncho. He was probably delirious. `` He removed all his clothing, all his gear. He walked away and wandered,'' <PERSON> Ringhofer </PERSON> said. `` At that point, it was over.'' The case is an unwanted first in an arm of the services that prides itself on taking care of its own. Of the tens of thousands of Marines who train every year at the <ORGANIZATION> Twentynine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Palms </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corps </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ground </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Combat </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Rother </PERSON> was the first lost to the blistering wasteland. `` It is beautiful and unforgiving country,'' <PERSON> Ringhofer </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Peck </PERSON> defended the <ORGANIZATION> Marines </ORGANIZATION>' initial failed search for <PERSON> Rother </PERSON>, citing the use of about 1,700 people, aided by aircraft, thermal heat imaging devices and the expertise of desert survival experts. The real issue in the case, he said, was how <PERSON> Rother </PERSON> was left unaccounted for, for nearly two days. `` The -LRB- commandant's -RRB- investigation is to try and determine how did all this happen,'' <PERSON> Peck </PERSON> said. `` It has never happened before and we do n't want it to happen again.'' Last week, <PERSON> Rother </PERSON> was buried with full military honors at <ORGANIZATION> Fort </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Snelling </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cemetery </ORGANIZATION> near his hometown, <LOCATION> Minneapolis </LOCATION>. `` He was proud of being a Marine,'' said his mother, <PERSON> Cecelia </PERSON> <PERSON> King </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Minneapolis </LOCATION>. `` Every time he came home, he presented himself to his friends in uniform.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881219-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-19-88 0054EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Carter'sNightmare Bjt   12-19 0666</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Carter's Nightmare, Bjt,670</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHINGTON TODAY: A Peaceful Interlude But For How Long?</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GEORGE GEDDA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President-elect <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> will take over next month during a period of unusual international harmony, with both the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Palestine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> sounding increasingly moderate. Foreign forces are likely to begin withdrawing from southern <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> and Soviet troops should be about to conclude their scheduled departure from <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>. These are good portents for <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> but history shows how ephemeral peaceful interludes can be. Just ask <PERSON> Jimmy </PERSON> <PERSON> Carter </PERSON>. It was just 10 years ago _ in December 1978 _ that <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> could look out at the world with an air of confidence, able to boast three foreign policy breakthroughs that won him widespread, albeit temporary, admiration. Over a period of a few months, <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> successfully guided the <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Canal </LOCATION> treaties past a skeptical <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>, reached agreement with <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> on the establishment of diplomatic relations and _ his most shining achievement _ spurred the Camp David breakthrough between <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>. At the end of 1978, <PERSON> Carter </PERSON>'s standing in the polls had risen to 50 per cent, high by standards of the time, and he seemed destined for a second term in the White House. Then came 1979, a year which ranks among the most disastrous endured by any president. The year began with the ouster of the pro-Western monarchy in <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> and its replacement by an avowedly anti-American Islamic fundamentalist regime. It ended with the seizure of American hostages in <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION> and their detention for 444 days. Indeed, the takeover of the American embassy there was part of a pattern of anti-American turmoil in Islamic countries in the fall of 1979. In the space of one month, the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> embassies in <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Libya </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> were attacked by mobs. Before the year was out, the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> had invaded <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>, starting a downward spiral in superpower relations that was n't reversed for years. The invasion induced <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> to slap a grain embargo on the Soviets, to withdraw from the 1980 summer Olympics in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> and to shelve the SALT II treaty, which had been the centerpiece of a June summit meeting between <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> and Soviet President <PERSON> Leonid </PERSON> <PERSON> Brezhnev </PERSON>. It seemed a new development buffeted the <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> administration every month. Vietnamese troops occupied neighboring <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION>. Leftists took control in <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>, paving the way for perhaps the most divisive foreign policy issue of the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> presidency: <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> backing for the Nicaraguan Contras. Almost unnoticed at the time of the Soviet invasion of <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> was the collapse of a coalition government in <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>, which in turn laid the groundwork for a civil war that claimed the lives of an average of 800 civilians a month in 1980. On the domestic front, the news for <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> was no better. By year's end, inflation reached 12 per cent, the result in large measure of a hefty midyear price increase decreed by the oil export cartel. There also was the widespread perception that <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> looked foolish when his subordinates claimed to have `` discovered'' in the late summer of 1979 the presence of a Soviet brigade in <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION>, only to concede later that the brigade had been there for years. <PERSON> Carter </PERSON>'s showing in the polls dipped to 32 per cent in October after the brigade fiasco, reviving somewhat by year's end because of initial public support for his handling of the hostage crisis. But restiveness within the Democratic party over <PERSON> Carter </PERSON>'s performance was such that Sen. <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, D-Mass., decided in November 1979 to challenge him for the party's 1980 presidential <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> survived that challenge but lost 44 states in his re-election bid. He never recovered from the 1979 debacle. In contrast to that dismal era, the world nowadays seems downright tame. Being president seems easier than it did in 1979. Or was <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> just more fortunate than his hard-luck predecessor?
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Gedda </PERSON> has covered foreign affairs for <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> since 1968.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881219-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-19-88 0055EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Bush-Defense     12-19 0895</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bush-Defense,850</SECOND>
<HEAD>Pentagon Fraud Cases Challenge Bush</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DONNA CASSATA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 President-elect <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has an opportunity to pull the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> from the quagmire of purchasing scandals by appointing strong managers to monitor the weapons buying process more closely, analysts say. `` It's the best opportunity we've ever had,'' said <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> <PERSON> Korb </PERSON>, a former <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> official now with the <ORGANIZATION> Brookings </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institution </ORGANIZATION>, a liberal think tank. `` If someone goes in there with the right team and the right attitude, you can do more good for this country, in my view, than any secretary of defense.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has indicated a desire to reverse the trend that has made household names of such scandal-ridden contractors as <ORGANIZATION> Wedtech </ORGANIZATION> and has made the practice of defrauding the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> almost commonplace. The president-elect on Friday announced the appointment of former <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Armed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> chairman <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Tower </PERSON> as <ORGANIZATION> defense </ORGANIZATION> secretary. Although Tower earned a reputation as a friend of military contractors during his years in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> and has worked for some of them in recent years, he bowed to <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s oft-stated commitment to reform. `` The bottom line is that we must provide at least as much, if not more, defense for less money. And to meet that challenge, we must do several things. We must rationalize our force structure, we must refine and reform our management and procurement procedures, we must have biennial budgeting,'' Tower said. During the campaign, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> embraced the recommendations of the <ORGANIZATION> Packard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION>, a panel appointed by President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> to study ways to reform the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>. In its 1986 report, the commission proposed creation of an undersecretary of defense for acquisition, strengthening the role of the <ORGANIZATION> Joint </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chiefs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Staff </ORGANIZATION> and having the president submit a two-year military budget for congressional approval. The panel was headed by former Deputy Defense Secretary <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Packard </PERSON>. `` I favor the <ORGANIZATION> Packard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> reforms,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> told employees of a <ORGANIZATION> Martin </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Marietta </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, plant in <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Colo. </LOCATION>, last October. `` The head of that commission, <PERSON> Dave </PERSON> <PERSON> Packard </PERSON>, supports me for a good reason. He knows that I'm going to put his reforms into effect because I understand that those reforms ca n't be carried out piecemeal,'' the vice president said. During the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration, the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> relinquished control of the acquisition process to the various armed services, according to <PERSON> Korb </PERSON>, who served as assistant secretary for manpower installation logistics from 1981 to 1985. <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> already has acted on the commission recommendation to create the undersecretary position for acquisition. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Costello </PERSON> currently holds the post, although <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> likely will name his own person to the job -- a critical selection, analysts said. `` For the administration to run a more effective bidding process, they must have top quality personnel,'' said <PERSON> Jay </PERSON> <PERSON> Koswinsky </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Heritage </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION>, a conservative think tank. <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> also approved reorganization legislation sponsored by former Sen. <PERSON> Barry </PERSON> <PERSON> Goldwater </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Ariz </LOCATION>., and the late <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Nichols </PERSON>, a Democratic congressman from <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION> The law overhauled the upper echelons of the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION>, strengthening the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> and designating the chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Joint </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chiefs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Staff </ORGANIZATION> as the principal adviser to the president and the secretary of defense. `` Up until 1985-1986 ... <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> traditionally had prevented secretaries of defense from running that department because it was an alliance between services and these uniformed guys and these old barons on the Hill,'' <PERSON> Korb </PERSON> said. `` With the passage of <ORGANIZATION> Goldwater-Nichols </ORGANIZATION>, they gave the secretary of defense and the chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Joint </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chiefs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Staff </ORGANIZATION> ... the power to run it.'' The department Tower will run has been rocked by one scandal after another, culminating with a federal investigation this year into allegations of purchasing fraud and bribery involving government officials, military contractors and consultants. Targets of the two-year probe include <PERSON> Melvyn </PERSON> <PERSON> Paisley </PERSON>, a former assistant <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> secretary who became a consultant to several aerospace contractors immediately upon leaving the Pentagon. Some of the largest defense contractors, including <ORGANIZATION> McDonnell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Douglas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Technologies </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, and <ORGANIZATION> Unisys </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, had their offices searched, as did <PERSON> Victor </PERSON> <PERSON> Cohen </PERSON>, a top <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> acquisitions official. Among the other scandals: _ In December 1983, the <ORGANIZATION> Sperry </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> pleaded guilty to falsifying payment requests for defense contracts and paid a $ 1 million fine _ Reports circulated in 1984 that the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> paid $ 7,622 for a 10-cup coffeemaker used on the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION>'s C-5A cargo plane and $ 600 for a toilet seat cover _ In 1985, <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dynamics </ORGANIZATION> withdrew its request for $ 491,840 from the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> for the 76 trips <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON>, the company's chairman, made from <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Louis </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Albany </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ga. </LOCATION>, where he owned a The company later withdrew $ 23 million in bills. _ In 1987, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> prosecutors revealed that four former <ORGANIZATION> Wedtech </ORGANIZATION> officials pleaded guilty to conspiring to bribe federal, state and city officials The four also pleaded guilty to grand larceny and bribery charges, conspiring to submit $ 5 million in phony government invoices and fraudulently passing off the <LOCATION> Bronx </LOCATION>, N.Y.-based <ORGANIZATION> Wedtech </ORGANIZATION> as a minority-owned business. _ In 1988, <ORGANIZATION> Sundstrand </ORGANIZATION>, a <LOCATION> Rockford </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ill. </LOCATION>, manufacturer of electronic, mechanical and hydraulic systems for aircraft, pleaded guilty to four counts of defrauding the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> by overbilling on aircraft parts The company also pleaded guilty in <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION> to mischarging on government contracts. The company was fined $ 115 million for the <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> crimes and $ 12.3 million for its <ORGANIZATION> Sundstrand </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Data </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Control </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Operation </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION> _ the largest fines paid for government contract fraud.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881219-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-19-88 0056EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-WeaponsPlants     12-19 0447</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Weapons Plants,440</SECOND>
<HEAD>Reagan Officials At Odds On Weapons Plants Money</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration says its new budget will contain enough money to run the nation's nuclear weapons plants safely, despite <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Herrington </PERSON>'s warning of a $ 360 million shortfall that could lead to shutdowns. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s chief of staff, <PERSON> Kenneth </PERSON> <PERSON> N. </PERSON> <PERSON> Duberstein </PERSON>, said Sunday that `` unobligated balances'' found within the department will make it possible to bring the facilities into compliance with safety and environmental laws. `` Mr. <PERSON> Herrington </PERSON> suggested that he wanted some additional spending rather than going into the <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> resources and looking for some money, which we have done,'' <PERSON> Duberstein </PERSON> said in an appearance on <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Meet The Press.'' `` The president has said consistently we wo n't operate any of these plants unless we can operate them in a safe manner,'' he said. <PERSON> Herrington </PERSON> suggested in a Dec. 9 letter to <PERSON> Duberstein </PERSON> that the department might have to shut some of its plants unless the administration proposes more than the $ 12.9 billion planned for fiscal 1989. `` I must in good conscience advise you that ... the system will, in all likelihood, be operating beyond the bounds of acceptable risk,'' he wrote. Details of the letter were published in Sunday editions of The Washington Post. If the department gives priority to production rather than upgrading safety at the plants, <PERSON> Herrington </PERSON> said in the letter, `` then unresolved environmental and safety issues are likely to lead to further shutdowns in the weapons complex.'' He said `` a significant increase in resources'' is needed over the next five years or the government will risk compromising the country's ability to produce and maintain its nuclear weapons stockpile. <PERSON> Herrington </PERSON> told <PERSON> Duberstein </PERSON> in his letter that the department would use the last of an emergency contingency fund to pay for $ 200 million in improvements at its <LOCATION> Savannah </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> plant in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>, which has been plagued with safety and environmental problems. He also cited unforeseen expenses at Rocky Flats, a <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION> area plutonium processing facility with hazardous waste problems that are jeopardizing its operation, in explaining the expected $ 360 million shortfall. <PERSON> Duberstein </PERSON> said he had sent a response to <PERSON> Herrington </PERSON>. He did not indicate on the television program whether the unobligated money to which he referred was in the contingency fund or elsewhere, and did not say how much money had been found within the department. <PERSON> Duberstein </PERSON> said the department is in line for a $ 900 million budget increase next year, up from its current budget of $ 12 billion. The <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> operates 17 weapons plants. It has proposed spending $ 50 billion in the next 20 years to build new facilities and correct the most pressing environmental problems.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881219-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-19-88 0116EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-CarlucciFarewell     12-19 0529</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Carlucci Farewell,540</SECOND>
<HEAD>Outgoing Pentagon Chief Advises Tower to Stick to His Guns</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By NORMAN BLACK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Military Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Outgoing <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Carlucci </PERSON> served in the job little more than a year, but he has some advice for his successor _ work with <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> but do n't stop fighting for an increase in military spending. <PERSON> Carlucci </PERSON> also says former Sen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Tower </PERSON> should n't turn the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> on its head in the name of reforming the weapons-buying process, despite a string of scandals under the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration. <PERSON> Carlucci </PERSON> says the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> defense industry needs stability and without it, the industrial base could collapse. He has called for a 2 percent increase in the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION>'s budget while President-elect <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, faced with a huge federal deficit, has talked of zero-growth. `` It's not a question of we ca n't afford it,'' <PERSON> Carlucci </PERSON> said. `` If you look at the domestic programs, they continue to go up at a rate of about 8 percent. Therefore, using that yardstick, I see nothing wrong with 2 percent in defense,'' he said. Asked if he thought a <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> would go along with an increase, <PERSON> Carlucci </PERSON> replied, `` If you do n't try it's not politically doable.'' The defense secretary said he thought Tower, a veteran <ORGANIZATION> Armed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> chairman in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>, could make the case `` the world is coming our way'' in part because of a stronger military. <PERSON> Carlucci </PERSON> was interviewed last week in his Pentagon office as he awaited <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s announcement of the man who would replace him. There is no question Tower will have problems managing <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> contracting, <PERSON> Carlucci </PERSON> said. Indictments could be returned any day in the long-running <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> investigation into <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> fraud. `` But the last thing the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> needs is somebody to come in and yank the procurement system out by the roots again and say we're going to reform it or change it,'' <PERSON> Carlucci </PERSON> said. `` The best reform for the procurement system is stability, predictability. The blueprint is laid out ... we've made a large number of changes in the procurement system. Real changes are taking place in the procurement system and I am proud of them.'' He said he had instituted a `` total quality management program'' to impress on contractors the need for quality products as well as ethical conduct. The 58-year-old defense chief said he was looking forward to finding a job in the private sector but had yet to do so. He listed among his accomplishments `` establishing a good rapport'' with his Soviet counterparts, protecting U.S.-flagged Kuwaiti tankers in the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION>, and convincing <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> it was time to close unneeded bases. He said in addition to the Pentagon purchasing problems, Tower will have to help develop arms-control strategy and strengthen the <ORGANIZATION> North </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Atlantic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Treaty </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> while convincing <LOCATION> European </LOCATION> allies to resist `` the seductive appeal'' of Soviet arms-control proposals. <PERSON> Carlucci </PERSON>, who replaced <PERSON> Caspar </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Weinberger </PERSON> as <ORGANIZATION> defense </ORGANIZATION> secretary for the last 14 months of the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration, said he had enjoyed the position but found it truly was `` a full-time job.'' `` On a per-hour basis, I make about as much as my babysitter,'' he joked, adding the secretary's salary of $ 99,500 is `` lousy.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881219-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-19-88 0124EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-PeaceforPalestine Bjt   12-19 0859</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Peace for Palestine, Bjt,0892</SECOND>
<HEAD>For Arabs and Israelis, Any Road To Peace Will Be Long And Arduous</HEAD>
<HEAD>AP News Analysis</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN RICE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>TUNIS, Tunisia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>' decision to open talks with the <ORGANIZATION> Palestine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> is merely a first step into a baffling maze toward <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> peace. Myriad thorny obstacles lie ahead and centuries of enmity must be surmounted. The competing claims of Arabs and Jews to the same lands are rooted in thousands of years of history. Many Israelis and Palestinians harbor the often justified fear that their foes would like them to forcibly disappear. It is a fear that makes every compromise a national trauma, seemingly a step toward national doom. Every Israeli recalls the vow of former <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Ahmad </PERSON> <PERSON> Shukairy </PERSON> to `` drive <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> into the sea.'' Every Palestinian recalls the contention of <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s late Prime Minister <PERSON> Golda </PERSON> <PERSON> Meir </PERSON> that the Palestinian people `` do not exist.'' Both sides cherish the memories of thousands of heroes who died in the name of nationalism. <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> chairman <PERSON> Yasser </PERSON> <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON> has now met <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> criteria for negotiation and <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> has begun talking with <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> representatives. But <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s leaders, despite nearly universal acknowledgement that the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> represents the Palestinians, still refuse to deal with what they call a `` terrorist'' organization. Before any kind of peace talks can start, <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s objections must be overcome _ or a way found to sugarcoat the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION>'s bitter presence. The <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> adminstration has favored submerging the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> in a <LOCATION> Jordanian </LOCATION> delegation to talks. It has also toyed with the idea of having the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> represented in talks by outside negotiators. The <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> rejects both plans. Israeli leaders have suggested staging limited elections to choose Palestinian negotiators from in the occupied <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strip </LOCATION>. But the last elections there produced a clutch of <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> supporters, most of whom were deposed or deported by <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>. Due in part to their year-long uprising in the occupied lands, the <LOCATION> Palestinians </LOCATION> have won wide international acceptance of their call for a U.N.-sponsored peace conference. But the ground rules remain a major point of contention, even beyond the invitation list. <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> reject the Arab idea that a conference could force a solution if the parties themselves reach a deadlock. The Palestinians also say a conference should be based on <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> withdrawal from the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strip </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Golan </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Heights </LOCATION>, which it seized in the 1967 Arab-Israeli war, as well as creation of a Palestinian state. But even Foreign Minister <PERSON> Shimon </PERSON> <PERSON> Peres </PERSON>, a moderate <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> leader who favors some form of international conference, refuses to consider a total withdrawal from the occupied lands. And no <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> leader would even consider the key Arab demand that <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION> be capital of the Palestinian state. The Israelis annexed the city's eastern Arab sector after seizing it in 1967. And what of a <LOCATION> Palestinian </LOCATION> state? The Palestinians accept at least a period in which it would be demilitarized _ a nod to <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s security fears. And they call for confederation with moderate <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION> _ an attempt to assuage <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> worries about a radical, independent actor on their flanks. Israelis and Americans, however, have tended to speak of such an entity as a province of <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION>, or a sub-state whose police are overseen by <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> itself. Such an entity would be located in the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strip </LOCATION>. But roughly 70,000 Jewish settlers now live there _ and half the land has been confiscated or bought by <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>. Much of the area's water, a commodity as precious as gold in the region, is already used by <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>, which would be hard-pressed to forfeit it. The Palestinians would find it difficult to thrive without it. More than 3 million Palestinians live in diaspora, and most claim legal rights to homes and lands in what is now <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> or Israeli-controlled lands. The right of return they claim would cause shattering trauma in <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>. While many might remain in the countries that have sheltered them for 40 years, compensation would cost billions of dollars. And many would not accept. While the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> itself has agreed to live in peace with <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>, a handful of splinter groups regard acceptance of <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> as tantamount to treason. Some Israelis who believe all of <LOCATION> Palestine </LOCATION> was promised to them by God would also object. Any peace settlement would almost certainly unleash terrorism by people desperate to sabotage it. Some leftist Israelis and some Palestinians see the answer in a confederation between the two feuding peoples themselves. And many Palestinians still cling to the hope that <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>, one day, will peacefully decide to merge with a <LOCATION> Palestinian </LOCATION> state. `` I ca n't even visit the family tombs in the yard of my house'' in <LOCATION> Haifa </LOCATION>, said <PERSON> Khalid </PERSON> <PERSON> al-Hassan </PERSON>, a senior <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> official, who said he still hopes for such a peaceful road to a `` democratic, secular state.'' `` We ca n't have a democracy via violence,'' he said. For many Israelis, however, even a peaceful end to their state would be unthinkable.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>___</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 EDITOR'S NOTE: <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Rice </PERSON>, correspondent for <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Amman </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION>, has covered the <LOCATION> Arab-Israeli </LOCATION> conflict since 1984.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881219-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-19-88 0124EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i BC-Japan-Stocks     12-19 0027</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Japan-Stocks,0026</SECOND>
<HEAD>Stocks Down In Tokyo</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Nikkei Stock Average closed at 29,470.08 points, down 66.63 points, on the <ORGANIZATION> Tokyo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Stock </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Exchange </ORGANIZATION> Monday.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881219-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-19-88 0125EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Herrington-OPEC     12-19 0709</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Herrington-OPEC,680</SECOND>
<HEAD>Energy Secretary Says OPEC Doomed</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GUY DARST</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Energy Secretary <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Herrington </PERSON> is leaving office firm in his conviction that the Organization of Petroleum Exporting Countries is doomed. `` In the long run, the <ORGANIZATION> OPEC </ORGANIZATION> cartel can not survive,'' <PERSON> Herrington </PERSON> said in a recent interview marking the end of his nearly four-year tenure. `` Cartels do not work. They have never worked in history.'' Several of <ORGANIZATION> OPEC </ORGANIZATION>'s larger members have new incentives to produce oil, rather than comply with last month's decision by the cartel to limit production to 18.5 million barrels a day. <PERSON> Herrington </PERSON> cited the following examples: _ <LOCATION> Venezuela </LOCATION> has a major stake in the <ORGANIZATION> Citgo </ORGANIZATION> chain of service stations and despite previous support of <ORGANIZATION> OPEC </ORGANIZATION>, the <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> nation's `` future is here, not with <ORGANIZATION> OPEC </ORGANIZATION>. _ <LOCATION> Saudi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arabia </LOCATION> is buying service stations and a refinery from <ORGANIZATION> Texaco </ORGANIZATION> `` and that's a major change. _ `` We've got two countries who have been at war for eight years -LRB- <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> -RRB- with 40 to 50 billion dollars in war debt, and a reconstruction budget that is going to be horrendous, with one thing to sell _ oil.'' <PERSON> Herrington </PERSON> contends that ownership of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> distribution facilities by overseas producers should be welcomed because of the incentives it gives producers to bring oil to market. `` It's good for the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and it's good for <LOCATION> Saudi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arabia </LOCATION>. No. 1, it's a guaranteed market for <LOCATION> Saudi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arabia </LOCATION> and No. 2, it's a guaranteed supply for us,'' <PERSON> Herrington </PERSON> said. Those who fear a resumption of the oil shocks of the 1970s do n't realize `` we live in a fundamentally different world,'' he said In the first half of 1986, the oil industry was devastated by the collapse of crude oil from above $ 27 a barrel to less than $ 12 -LRB- measured by average refiner cost -RRB-. Half the 1,980 exploration rigs active in 1985 were idled and 120,000 out of 585,000 exploration and production jobs vanished. Crude oil now sells for about $ 15 a barrel. Imports have risen from less than 30 percent of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> consumption in 1985 to more than 40 percent now. At the same time, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> production has fallen by a million barrels of crude a day to a little more than 8 million barrels. While <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> producers of crude oil have pleaded for trade protection, <PERSON> Herrington </PERSON> and President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> maintained that quotas or tariffs would harm the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> economy more than they would help the oil industry. A tariff might be politically impossible anyway because of the demands for exemptions by <ORGANIZATION> Northeast </ORGANIZATION> consumers, <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> and the petrochemical industry plus the mandatory exemption for <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> under the free-trade agreement, <PERSON> Herrington </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Herrington </PERSON> said `` cooperation with <ORGANIZATION> OPEC </ORGANIZATION> is not the solution,'' although he said he understood why <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION> sent observers to the <ORGANIZATION> OPEC </ORGANIZATION> meeting. `` This is not an industry we can allow to go by the boards,'' <PERSON> Herrington </PERSON> said. He said he did not know just how big an industry the nation should try to preserve, but, `` I think it should be a lean, mean, efficient industrial part of our economy, which I think it is today.'' On other issues, <PERSON> Herrington </PERSON> said the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> economy has to become more energy-efficient. The nation has made big gains in efficiency. The economy in 1987 was 40 percent larger than it was in 1973, but it used only 2 percent more energy. However, the gains are slowing down. <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> use energy with twice the efficiency of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. `` That's got to change. Now, is that the federal government's job? <PERSON> Herrington </PERSON> said. `` My position is, a lot of these problems are tax policy questions'' that will yield to `` tried and true'' tax incentives. Advocacy groups have blasted <PERSON> Herrington </PERSON> and his predecessors under <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> for sharply curtailing spending on conservation, efficiency and renewable sources of energy. <PERSON> Herrington </PERSON> dismisses the criticisms. `` Are we spending enough money? I think we are. It's true we're not building the giant wind machines for $ 10 million any more, like Mod 2 and <ORGANIZATION> Mod </ORGANIZATION> 3, that we're reselling years later for $ 13,000. As for an environmentalist favorite, higher taxes on gasoline to discourage consumption, <PERSON> Herrington </PERSON> admitted that a big increase would do the job but said `` I stand foursquare with the president'' against more taxes.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881219-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-19-88 0131EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FarmScene     12-19 0657</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Farm Scene,640</SECOND>
<HEAD>Salmon Soar as Commercial Crop</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DON KENDALL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Farm Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Salmon production is soaring at fish farms worldwide, spurred in part by greater demand and buying power in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, an <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> report says. `` Worldwide salmon production is estimated up 75 percent from last year to over 300 million pounds,'' the report said. `` <LOCATION> Norway </LOCATION>, the top producer, likely raised about 160 million pounds in 1988, almost double 1987's output.'' In the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> salmon farming, or aquaculture, is concentrated in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> and, most recently, <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION>. Last year's production was around 85 million pounds, but the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> salmon figures for 1988 are not available yet. Large Japanese demand and the strong value of the yen has boosted competition in world salmon markets, the report said. The heavy buying by <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> has reduced the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> supply of top-quality salmon available to consumers, forcing some restaurants to remove salmon from their menus. `` A buying frenzy resulted from early reports of a small Alaskan catch coupled with losses in the Norwegian salmon crop because of a ` red tide' infestation of a microorganism that reduces the oxygen level of the water so the fish suffocate,'' the report said. Salmon farming makes up only a fraction of total <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> aquaculture production, but some authorities believe the industry is poised for a major expansion, perhaps doubling or tripling domestic output in a few years. The report was prepared by economists <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Dicks </PERSON> and <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Harvey </PERSON> of the department's <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>, who are the agency's chief aquaculture specialists <PERSON> Harvey </PERSON> said in a telephone interview that the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> salmon production figures are being studied and revised to get a more accurate picture of how much of the output goes into the commercial food supply. Also, he said, whether the current salmon boom continues will depend on many economic, legal and consumer factors. Overall, including food and non-food fish, shellfish and other aquatic products, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> aquacultural output rose by 20 percent in 1987 to almost 750 million pounds worth $ 650 million. The 1987 expansion was led by catfish, crawfish and salmon, with a combined production of more than 550 million pounds, or about 73 percent of the total. Catfish output was estimated at 370 million pounds; crawfish, 95 million pounds; and salmon, about 85 million pounds. But the report said that expansion probably will slow to less than 10 percent a year in the next 10 years unless new technology and more resources become available. `` A shortage of water supplies likely will impede expansion, particularly in areas where production is already highly concentrated,'' the report said. `` Where aquaculture is just beginning to develop, limited management resources, capital and industry infrastructure will constrain expansion.'' With a slower growth and little increase expected in the commercial catch of wild fish, Americans probably will depend increasingly on imports, which totaled $ 8.8 billion in 1987. However, the report added, this could be modified by new technology, growth of the commercial fishing fleet and shifts in consumer demand. The report noted some of the new research and technology in the industry: _ In <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION>, research continues on lobster production, and in <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> scientists are working with the black cod, a favorite in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> _ Striped bass, or rockfish, were in short supply following a ban on their catch three years ago in the <LOCATION> Chesapeake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION>, the main production area The fish are now being produced in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>, with production likely starting up next year in <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION>. _ Oysters, littleneck clams, red fish and sturgeon are other species traditionally supplied from the wild catch that are now being farmed _ The development of genetically superior catfish and trout offers potential for expansion For example, <ORGANIZATION> Auburn </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> has crossed a commercial blue catfish with the channel catfish to produce a hybrid with a 40 percent greater growth rate and a high tolerance for low-oxygen water.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881219-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-19-88 0132EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-RedArmy     12-19 0764</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Red Army,780</SECOND>
<HEAD>Soviet Press Gave Hints of Coming Troop Cuts</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BRYAN BRUMLEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
