<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881031-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-31-88 2323EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-NewarkCorruption     10-31 0209</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Newark Corruption,0217</SECOND>
<HEAD>School Board Member Indicted In Newark Corruption Investigation</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEWARK, N.J. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A school board member took $ 8,000 in bribes from two teachers seeking promotions to vice principal, a federal grand jury charged Monday. <PERSON> Malcolm </PERSON> <PERSON> George </PERSON>, 32, of <LOCATION> Newark </LOCATION>, was indicted by the panel on two counts of bribe-taking and two counts of extortion by a public official. He faces 60 years in prison if convicted on all counts. <PERSON> George </PERSON>, the board's second vice president, allegedly took $ 5,000 from one teacher as early as spring 1987 and $ 3,000 from another teacher last August in exchange for improving their chances for promotion, the indictment said. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Attorney <PERSON> Samuel </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Alito </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> declined to identify the teachers or their schools or say if they were ever promoted. `` This is part of a continuing investigation into activities of this type,'' <PERSON> Alito </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Sheldon </PERSON> <PERSON> Bross </PERSON>, a board attorney, said he believes the teachers were not promoted. <PERSON> George </PERSON> could not be reached Monday. His phone number is unlisted, and his attorney, <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Sarcone </PERSON>, did not return a message. No date has been set for <PERSON> George </PERSON> to appear in court. He was not arrested. Authorities said <PERSON> George </PERSON> was a former <LOCATION> Essex </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> employee but did not know his current occupation.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881031-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-31-88 2330EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p AM-Bush-Lobbying     10-31 0488</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Bush-Lobbying,480</SECOND>
<HEAD>Firm Owned By Two GOP Staffers Solicits Haiti For Lobbying, Report
Says</HEAD>
<HEAD>With AM-Political Rdp Bjt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ORLANDO, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A political consulting firm led by two top officials in <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s presidential campaign has offered to represent the government of <LOCATION> Haiti </LOCATION>, citing the firm's ability to work in `` the transitional environment in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>,'' The <ORGANIZATION> Orlando </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sentinel </ORGANIZATION> reported Tuesday. `` Given the fragile environment in <LOCATION> Haiti </LOCATION> and the ensuing presidential election in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> there exists a window of opportunity for us to combine our resources and energies for the mutual benefit of our two countries,'' stated the letter from <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> & amp; Co. The letter, dated Oct. 12, also expressed hope that <PERSON> Avril </PERSON> would `` retain our services.'' The <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> firm is run by <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> campaign officials <PERSON> Frederick </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, who is unrelated to the vice president, and <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON>. The letter to <LOCATION> Haitian </LOCATION> president <PERSON> Prosper </PERSON> <PERSON> Avril </PERSON> appeared to be signed by <PERSON> Frederick </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, but he told the newspaper Monday that his name had been signed by an associate without his permission or his knowledge. `` This upsets me very much,'' he said. `` This was totaly unauthorized. I want nothing to do with the government of <LOCATION> Haiti </LOCATION>.'' The switchboard operator at <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s headquarters in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> said no one was available late Monday for comment. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, 39, is deputy finance chairman of the vice president's election campaign He was a White House staffer and the vice president's deputy chief of staff during President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s first term. <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON> is both <ORGANIZATION> Bush </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ; </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>'s vice president and finance director for this year's <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> presidential bid. She was on the finance committee for the Reagan-Bush 1984 re-election campaign. The letter sent by <ORGANIZATION> Bush </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ; </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> offered <PERSON> Avril </PERSON> a variety of lobbying services and said, `` We are confident that we can effectively work in the transitional environment in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> to assist <LOCATION> Haiti </LOCATION>.'' <PERSON> Frederick </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> acknowledged he was aware the Haitian government `` had requested information about the company several weeks ago,'' but he said he wanted no part of any subsequent discussions. `` I specifically said that I would not be involved,'' he said. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said that he has not been active in the company for the past two years because of his fund-raising duties for the vice president. An attachment to the two-page letter, however, promoted <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s position with the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> presidential campaign and <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s background as a White House staffer Six weeks ago <PERSON> Avril </PERSON>'s regime ousted the government that had been having trouble conducting a peaceful election. After a November 1987 election was canceled because of violence, the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government cut off $ 89 million in aid. Only food and development aid has continued through international humanitarian organizations. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials, while pleased with recent steps taken by <PERSON> Avril </PERSON> to improve the political climate and reign in <LOCATION> Haiti </LOCATION>'s military, have said there is little prospect of renewing the full foreign-aid package until the new administration and the new <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> take office in January.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881031-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-31-88 2338EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-WPPSSTrial     10-31 0555</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-WPPSS Trial,0568</SECOND>
<HEAD>Utilities Vote To Settle In Giant Securities Fraud Suit</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JIM KLAHN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SEATTLE (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Fourteen public utilities across <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> state voted Monday to approve a $ 226 million settlement letting them out of the giant <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Power </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supply </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> System </ORGANIZATION> securities fraud trial in <LOCATION> Tucson </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ariz. </LOCATION> `` It's a -LRB- settlement -RRB- we can certainly live with and handle, and it wo n't have great diverse ... impact on our state,'' said <LOCATION> Tacoma </LOCATION> attorney <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Malanca </PERSON>, who engineered the complex agreement involving utilities, the state of <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> and the federal <ORGANIZATION> Bonneville </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Power </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>. While several utilities agreeing to the settlement on Monday said rate increases may be necessary, they added that those increases would be small and the economic damage to the Northwest region minimal. Under terms of the agreement, the 14 utilities would pay $ 181 million, <ORGANIZATION> BPA </ORGANIZATION> and the federal government would pay $ 35 million and the state would pay $ 10 million to plaintiffs who sued after <ORGANIZATION> WPPSS </ORGANIZATION> defaulted in 1983 on $ 2.25 billion in bonds used to build two nuclear power plants. The plaintiffs include more than 24,000 past and present bondholders. The plants were begun but never finished after regional energy planners determined power from the plants would n't be needed. The region's economy suffered when <ORGANIZATION> WPPSS </ORGANIZATION> attempted to build five multibillion dollar nuclear power plants and finished only one. In <LOCATION> Olympia </LOCATION>, Gov. <PERSON> Booth </PERSON> <PERSON> Gardner </PERSON> announced the state would pay $ 10 million toward the settlement, if the <ORGANIZATION> Legislature </ORGANIZATION> concurs. <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> state faces a separate lawsuit involving the same plaintiffs. <ORGANIZATION> BPA </ORGANIZATION> participation still requires the approval of the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION>, which is expected this week, and final approval will have to come from <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Browning </PERSON>, who is overseeing the trial in <LOCATION> Tucson </LOCATION>. The pact leaves <ORGANIZATION> Snohomish </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Utility </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> the only utility remaining as a defendant in the trial, although it has an option to settle until Nov. 10. Snohomish contracted for the biggest single share, 13 percent, on the two terminated <ORGANIZATION> WPPSS </ORGANIZATION> plants. The trial, over the largest municipal bond default in history, was recessed last week in <LOCATION> Tucson </LOCATION> when attorneys reported a settlement was possible. It was scheduled to resume Wednesday. Besides Snohomish, other defendants remaining include two engineering firms and a financial adviser firm. The price for Snohomish if it takes up the Nov. 10 option would be $ 48.7 million. That would be in line with the $ 3.7 million per-percentage-point of interest in the two abandoned nuclear plants other defendant utilities agreed to pay. <LOCATION> Tacoma </LOCATION> director of utilities <PERSON> Ted </PERSON> <PERSON> Coates </PERSON> said the settlement would bring to $ 591 million the amount paid to the class of plaintiffs in the giant federal lawsuit. Settlements during the past year have removed most defendants and totaled $ 365 million in cash. In addition to the $ 591 million would be $ 96 million in contested insurance claims. <PERSON> Coates </PERSON> estimated the settlement would add 3 -LCB- to 4 percent to <LOCATION> Tacoma </LOCATION> City Light's expenses. He said the city planned to pay the bill through floating long-term bonds. Under terms of the agreements, most utilities would have to make initial payments Dec. 15, with final payments Dec. 15, 1989. Interest would be paid, according to the agreement. The settlement memorandum noted some utilities could recover substantial amounts through insurance carriers that have so far `` refused to pay the insurance coverage contracted for.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881031-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-31-88 2347EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Brawley-Suit     10-31 0266</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Brawley-Suit,0276</SECOND>
<HEAD>Prosecutor Files $800 Million Against Brawley and Advisers</HEAD>
<DATELINE>POUGHKEEPSIE, N.Y. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A prosecutor filed an $ 800 million defamation lawsuit Monday against <PERSON> Tawana </PERSON> <PERSON> Brawley </PERSON>, the black teen-ager who a grand jury said concocted a story of abduction and rape by six white men. <LOCATION> Dutchess </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> prosecutor <PERSON> Steven </PERSON> <PERSON> Pagones </PERSON>' lawsuit also named as defendants the Rev. <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> Sharpton </PERSON> and lawyers <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Vernon </PERSON> <PERSON> Mason </PERSON> and <PERSON> Alton </PERSON> <PERSON> Maddox </PERSON>, advisers to <PERSON> Miss </PERSON> <PERSON> Brawley </PERSON> who had claimed that <PERSON> Pagones </PERSON> was involved in the purported attack last November. A grand jury cleared <PERSON> Pagones </PERSON> of any involvement in the case that began when <PERSON> Miss </PERSON> <PERSON> Brawley </PERSON>, then 16, was found in <LOCATION> Wappingers </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Falls </LOCATION> smeared with dog feces and with racial slurs written on her body. Miss <PERSON> Brawley </PERSON> never cooperated with the grand jury, and her advisers dismissed the resulting report as the product of a racist system. `` I hope he goes through with it,'' <PERSON> Sharpton </PERSON> said in response to the lawsuit Monday. `` Well, I think that Mr. <PERSON> Pagones </PERSON> has the potential of making history in being the first man to sue himself into jail,'' he said. <PERSON> Sharpton </PERSON> said Miss <PERSON> Brawley </PERSON> would tell her story in court and, along with other witnesses, would prove <PERSON> Pagones </PERSON>' involvement. `` He will be proven guilty of rape and sodomy and will go to jail,'' <PERSON> Sharpton </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Mason </PERSON> had no comment on the lawsuit, according to a receptionist at his law office. <PERSON> Maddox </PERSON> did not immediately return telephone calls for comment. <PERSON> Pagones </PERSON>' lawyer, <PERSON> Gerald </PERSON> <PERSON> Hayes </PERSON>, also did not return telephone calls. <PERSON> Pagones </PERSON> had said at a news conference on Oct. 10 that he intended to file suit.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881031-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-31-88 2351EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--Iraq-Locusts     10-31 0144</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Iraq-Locusts,0147</SECOND>
<HEAD>Locusts Invade Basra</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BAGHDAD, Iraq (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The southern city of <LOCATION> Basra </LOCATION>, devastated by the 8-year-old Iran-Iraq war, now has been invaded by swarms of desert locusts, the <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Irrigation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> says. A report on state-run television Monday said six separate clouds of the crop-devouring insects were in the city, but that the ministry was using helicopters to bring the situation under control. No further details were immediately available. Locusts can eat twice their body weight every day, so the swarms are sprayed with insecticides to keep them from reaching agricultural areas. Locusts from <LOCATION> Sudan </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Ethiopia </LOCATION> have swept across the Arabian peninsula in the past two weeks. The <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Food </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> said in a recent report that the spread of locusts represents `` a lateral extension of the plague, which will make control efforts much more difficult.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881031-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-31-88 2351EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Algeria     10-31 0146</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Algeria,0150</SECOND>
<HEAD>Riot Prisoners Ordered Released</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ALGIERS, Algeria (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 At the direction of President <PERSON> Chadli </PERSON> <PERSON> Bendjedid </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> has decided to release provisionally everyone who was arrested during the October riots, the official news agency reported. <ORGANIZATION> Algerie </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Presse </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> said Monday that the decision was taken `` in application of the orientations received from the president and on the occasion of the 34th anniversary of Nov. 1, 1954.'' The Algerian revolution began on that date, resulting in independence from <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> eight years later. The number of people set free was not revealed. Earlier, an unstated number of minors were let go. Officially, 159 people died in the riots and 154 were injured. Unofficial reports put the death toll at 400 or more in disturbances that started over rising prices and food shortages. The move comes three days before a nationwide referendum on political reforms.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881031-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-31-88 2356EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Poland-Analysis Bjt   10-31 0797</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Poland-Analysis, Bjt,0825</SECOND>
<HEAD>Shipyard Closure Seen as Attempt to Cripple Solidarity</HEAD>
<HEAD>AP News Analysis</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN DANISZEWSKI</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WARSAW, Poland (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Whatever sense it may make on solely economic grounds, the decision to shut the <PERSON> Lenin </PERSON> shipyard is a slap at the Solidarity trade union movement at a time the government ostensibly is seeking dialogue. The closing poses a difficult challenge for union leader <PERSON> Lech </PERSON> <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON>, who has been preaching economic reform but undoubtedly did not want it to begin by eliminating his workplace and political base. Monday's announcement follows closely a government demand that <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> remove two longtime Solidarity advisers from his delegation to promised `` round-table'' talks with authorities, which were to start in mid-October. <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> refused and the talks now appear in jeopardy. The developments underscore an end to the accommodative mood on both sides that briefly seemed to dominate Polish politics after <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> ended a series of strikes in early September in exchange for the promise of the talks on Solidarity's future. The government has taken a more energetic, decisive tone since the ascension to prime minister last month of <PERSON> Mieczyslaw </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Rakowski </PERSON>, the party propaganda chief and a longtime Solidarity foe. <PERSON> Rakowski </PERSON> has said the situation is too urgent to wait for talks with the opposition before trying to revitalize the economy. But the opposition, which has long distrusted <PERSON> Rakowski </PERSON>, questions whether he is interested in talks at all. <PERSON> Rakowski </PERSON> said in a broadcast interview Monday that the decision to close the <LOCATION> Gdansk </LOCATION> shipyard Dec. 1 and liquidate it over the next year was purely economic and had `` nothing to do with Solidarity.'' The official media gave heavy coverage to the decision, but made no mention of the shipyard's symbolic importance as the birthplace and stronghold of the only independent labor movement allowed in the Soviet bloc. The official news agency <ORGANIZATION> PAP </ORGANIZATION> said the state-owned shipyard, <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>'s largest, has been losing money and increasingly draining the public treasury. But <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> said it was no coincidence that the shipyard was the first industrial enterprise in the country to fall victim to the budget ax. `` Premier <PERSON> Rakowski </PERSON>'s decision was not dictated by economic reasons,'' he said, calling the move <PERSON> Rakowski </PERSON>'s `` personal provocation'' against the yard where Solidarity sprang to life in August 1980 after a nationwide strike wave. While vowing to fight the closing, <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> said he agreed the `` economy needs restructuring and basic changes. Solidarity is and has been for those changes.'' But he said the yard could be saved by dismissing incompetent managers and allowing workers to run it more efficiently themselves. Historian <PERSON> Bronislaw </PERSON> <PERSON> Geremek </PERSON>, a close <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> adviser, said Solidarity always was prepared to accept painful economic choices in the course of reform. But those steps were supposed to be a subject for agreement in the now-delayed talks with authorities, he said. By deciding unilaterally to close the shipyard, <PERSON> Rakowski </PERSON> `` either buried the chances for the round table or considered the round table already buried,'' <PERSON> Geremek </PERSON> said. `` If such decisions are taken without first achieving a social contract, then what one wants to prove is that there is no need for such a way, no need for dialogue.'' One Western diplomat, speaking on condition of anonymity, called the government's move a political `` masterstroke''. If Solidarity strikes, it will lend credence to <PERSON> Rakowski </PERSON>'s argument that the union is unreasonable and poses an obstacle to efforts to reform <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>'s inefficient, debt-ridden economy And by shutting down the shipyard, the strikers would only be hastening what the government wants to do next month anyway. But if Solidarity does not mount a protest to defend its home base, <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> and the Solidarity leadership run the risk of seeming toothless to militant followers at home and would-be supporters abroad. <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>'s first major plant closing is likely to send shock waves through factories nationwide. But because the closing was announced during a four-day holiday weekend, it was difficult to immediately judge the degree of public sympathy for the workers. The government, meanwhile, was trying to take the sting out of the closure for the approximately 10,000 workers facing layoffs. It said state enterprises have far more than enough jobs going begging in <LOCATION> Gdansk </LOCATION> province at equal or higher pay. And it promised free job retraining for those who need it. Ironically and perhaps not accidentally, <PERSON> Rakowski </PERSON> made the move only days before Prime Minister <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> is due to arrive for a visit that is to include a trip to <LOCATION> Gdansk </LOCATION> to see <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> on Friday. Official commentators have been drawing parallels between <PERSON> Rakowski </PERSON>'s plans to overhaul <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>'s economy and the toughness shown by Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> in facing down the unions and cutting back money-losing state industry in <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>___</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Daniszewski </PERSON> is the <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> correspondent in <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881031-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-31-88 2358EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Afghanistan-Mines     10-31 0466</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Afghanistan-Mines,0482</SECOND>
<HEAD>Anti-Personnel Mines Delay Refugees' Return To Afghanistan</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By KATHY GANNON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ISLAMABAD, Pakistan (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Anti-personnel mines designed to maim an enemy remain scattered about <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> and must be cleared before more than 5 million refugees in <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> can return home, <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> officials say. The mines are estimated to range in number from hundreds of thousands to 5 million. Some look like toys and are small enough to fit in the palm of a person's hand. If picked up, they can blow away a hand; if stepped on, a victim can lose a foot. <PERSON> Zia </PERSON> <PERSON> Rizvi </PERSON>, spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> and Humanitarian Program for Afghan refugees, said the landmines have to be found and defused before a billion-dollar rebuilding program can begin. The devices are believed to have been laid by Soviet and Afghan government forces during their nine-year war against Moslem insurgents. The insurgents also have laid a number of anti-tank devices. Teams of mine-clearing experts from the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Turkey </LOCATION> have been in <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> to plan a training program designed to show Afghans how to locate, identify and defuse the mines. A $ 9-million training program is scheduled to begin shortly, <PERSON> Rizvi </PERSON> said. Clearing the mines `` is a pre-requisite to any -LRB- rebuilding -RRB- activity,'' said <PERSON> Rizvi </PERSON>. The Soviets are not a contributor to the mine-clearing effort, but they `` have assured us of their total cooperation,'' said <PERSON> Rizvi </PERSON>. Since the April signing of an accord providing for the withdrawal of more than 100,000 Soviet troops from <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> has begun mobilizing for one of the largest refugee movements in its history. <PERSON> Rizvi </PERSON> said the widespread use of the landmines `` is a comment on the people who make, sell, buy and use them.'' The U.S.-backed Moslem guerrillas, known as the <ORGANIZATION> Mujahedeen </ORGANIZATION>, have been fighting the <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>'s Marxist government since it seized power in 1978. The <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> entered the conflict in December 1979. Fifteen different types of anti-personnel mines have been identified along with five models of anti-tank mines, <PERSON> Rizvi </PERSON> said. In addition to the anti-personnel devices that resemble toys are are scattered around villages, another common type is a bright green plastic device that looks like a butterfly and fits into the palm of a hand. <PERSON> Rizvi </PERSON> said unexploded ordnance of other kinds, such as dud bombs, also are scattered around the Afghan countryside. The first task of foreign mine-detecting experts will be to make Afghans aware of what to look for. <PERSON> Rizvi </PERSON> said children will be educated to the dangers as well. Foreign experts will train Afghans who in turn will pass on their knowledge to others, he said. Eventually, said <PERSON> Rizvi </PERSON>, an Afghan mine-clearing team would be established in most villages or cluster of villages.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881031-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-31-88 0007EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Hirohito     10-31 0217</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Hirohito,0225</SECOND>
<HEAD>Emperor's Condition Called Stable After Weekend Hemorrhaging</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Emperor <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON> discharged small amounts of blood early today and his blood pressure fell, but palace officials described the 87-year-old monarch's condition as stable after a serious weekend setback. Palace spokesman <PERSON> Kenji </PERSON> <PERSON> Maeda </PERSON> said <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON> discharged blood early today but added that doctors did not administer another transfusion. He told reporters that palace physicians described the discharge as remnants of blood lost Saturday night and Sunday morning. The world's longest reigning monarch has been bedridden since falling ill with internal hemorrhaging on Sept. 19. Despite a drop in the emperor's blood pressure today, <PERSON> Maeda </PERSON> said doctors were not `` particularly concerned.'' He said the emperor was fully conscious this morning, chatting with his physicians. On Sunday, <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON>'s blood pressure had dropped dangerously low and he received a total of 3.8 pints of blood in the largest transfusion since becoming bedridden. Since Sept. 19, the emperor has received 31.5 pints of blood, about three times the normal amount in his body. <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON> has not taken any solid food since falling ill, with the exception of a few spoons of porridge. He is being fed intravenously, receiving some 600-700 calories daily. Palace officials have refused to confirm or deny media reports that the emperor has pancreatic cancer.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881031-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-31-88 0007EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-AbortionProtests CORRECTIVE   10-31 0050</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Abortion Protests, CORRECTIVE,0048</SECOND>
<NOTE>Eds: Members who used a0540, PM-Abortion Protests, UNDATED, sent
Oct. 29 are asked to use the following:</NOTE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> erroneously reported Friday that 40 protesters were arrested at two abortion clinics in <LOCATION> Nashville </LOCATION>. There were no arrests reported in <LOCATION> Nashville </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881031-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-31-88 0015EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-AlaskaHighways     10-31 0932</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Alaska Highways,0958</SECOND>
<HEAD>Tourists Fuel Debate Over Pushing Roads Through Alaska Wilds</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</NOTE>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID FOSTER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>TOK, Alaska (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Taylor Highway, a rib-jarring gravel washboard that snakes through mining hills northeast of this interior <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> village, does n't rate much mention in the tourist brochures. But the <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON> is <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Champagne </PERSON>'s specialty. He drives a tow truck and, as they say in the trade, business is picking up. He sat the other day in his <ORGANIZATION> Chevron </ORGANIZATION> station and pointed out the highway's latest victim: a van with a crushed roof and shattered windows `` He was passing a motor home on a curve, got over too far, and t-h-p-p-t, into the river,'' he said. Champagne was happy to haul the van and its uninjured driver back to Tok, for $ 700. A 1984 legislative study found that 60 percent of <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> highways were in fair to poor condition. But the potholes and frost heaves do n't slow the flow of vacationers. Growing herds of tourists not only keep Champagne smiling but also help fuel debate over this frontier state's transportation future. More roads! say business leaders who see a young and developing state with little access to remote villages and mineral deposits. Stop the bulldozers! cry environmentalists who see a pristine land needing protection from the forces that paved over the lower 48 states. The arguments likely will continue as long as there are places people can not drive to, and much of <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> fits that category. The state's 11,600 miles of roads are concentrated in the southeastern quarter, leaving vast areas untracked. One-fourth of <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>'s half-million residents live unconnected by road to the outside world. Of 151 incorporated communities, 133 are unconnected, including the state capital of <LOCATION> Juneau </LOCATION>. Given the mountains and permanently frozen ground that cover much of <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>, it's a wonder roads were ever built. Turn-of-the-century gold rushes spurred the first major construction. In World War II, concerns about a Japanese invasion prompted another building frenzy; the 1,520-mile <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Highway </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>'s first overland link to the lower 48, was finished in just nine months. Since statehood in 1959, expansion has continued steadily. The latest road, completed this summer in northwestern <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>, is a 54-mile link from the coast to a mineral deposit known as Red Dog. `` I try not to think about that,'' said <PERSON> Susan </PERSON> <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON>, state representative for the <ORGANIZATION> Wilderness </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION>, which unsuccessfully fought the road's route through <LOCATION> Cape </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Krusenstern </LOCATION> National Monument. She said wilderness is easily destroyed by roads and resulting development and pollution. She cited the 416-mile <LOCATION> Dalton </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Highway </LOCATION>, built in 1974 to link Fairbanks and the <LOCATION> Prudhoe </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION> oil fields. Although only the highway's southern half is open to the public, lax enforcement lets many drivers slip through to the north, and <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON> worries about the effect on wildlife. `` Increased access means increased poaching, and there definitely has been poaching along the road. The road lets in people, hunters, who would n't have been there otherwise,'' she said. Letting more people into <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> is what economic boosters have had in mind for years. Wherever roads have gone, tourism has followed. <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Customs </ORGANIZATION> officials say 38,150 vehicles _ about 70 percent of them motor homes and campers _ entered the state on the <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> Highway last year. Roads can cut shipping costs to villages and make remote mining more competitive, say the boosters, who over the years have proposed dozens of roads to fill blank spaces on the map. In 1977, travel guides called the 152-mile <LOCATION> Elliott </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Highway </LOCATION> near <LOCATION> Fairbanks </LOCATION> the `` Road to <LOCATION> Nome </LOCATION>,'' even though it dead-ended, and still does, 500 miles short of the <LOCATION> Bering </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sea </LOCATION> town. In 1986, the <ORGANIZATION> Greater </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fairbanks </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chamber </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> suggested a road that would head 200 miles southwest from <LOCATION> Denali </LOCATION> <LOCATION> National </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Park </LOCATION> to <PERSON> McGrath </PERSON>, then swing north another 200 miles to the <LOCATION> Yukon </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION>. In southeastern <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>, plans surface occasionally to connect <LOCATION> Juneau </LOCATION> to highways that now stop in <LOCATION> Haines </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Skagway </LOCATION>. But such projects, each estimated to cost hundreds of millions of dollars, are distant dreams for state officials who can barely raise the $ 52 million needed each year to maintain existing roads. <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>'s oil-dependent government has grown cautious since the oil boom busted, and the state <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> plans no major highway expansion. It would cost $ 600 million just to bring <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>'s rural highways up to standards, said <PERSON> Ron </PERSON> <PERSON> Lind </PERSON>, the agency's planning and budget director. Patterns of land use and ownership also discourage road-building. National parks, preserves and monuments now cover 50 million of <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>'s 375 million acres. Natives, protective of open space needed for subsistence hunting and fishing, own 44 million acres. But things could change quickly in <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>'s boom-bust economy. As publisher <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Henning </PERSON> wrote in an <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> Geographic book called `` Adventure Roads North'': `` Strong anti-roads sentiments of environmentalist groups have slowed Alaskan road construction, but in the history of the North, there has ever been the cry for ` more roads, more trails,' and it is inevitable that the road building will continue. ... Like it or not, it seems to be the American way.'' Wherever and whenever roads are built, the likes of <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Champagne </PERSON> will be there to pick up the pieces. Back at the <ORGANIZATION> Chevron </ORGANIZATION> station, Champagne was smiling again; a Winnebago driver was in for the second time that day with a flat tire. Champagne quickly fixed the tire and proceeded to the cash register. `` That'll be $ 10,'' he said. `` You have a nice day.''
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Foster </PERSON> is the <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Northwest </ORGANIZATION> regional reporter, based in <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881031-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-31-88 0018EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-SubterraneanParis     10-31 1120</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Subterranean Paris,1153</SECOND>
<HEAD>`Cataphiles' Haunt The Bowels Of Paris</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</NOTE>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 The City of Light sits on a subterranean city of darkness, a vast network of stone quarries that has given refuge to scoundrels, saints and the bones of 6 million souls. It is where the Phantom of the Opera set up house. Here is a report by an AP correspondent who visited the catacombs.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>By ELAINE GANLEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PARIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Phantom was laid to rest long ago in the cellars of the Opera, but figures nearly as macabre still haunt the catacombs that wind through the belly of <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> like entrails and conceal millions of human bones. Each weekend, dozens of people slip out of their city skins and into the maze on which the city rests. They descend as far as 90 feet into a world where night is eternal, the unexpected waits at each turn and the game is to the fearless. Some are history buffs seeking the dank breath of ancient <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION>, others are adventurers and still others inhabit a marginal world whether above ground or below. They are called `` cataphiles'' and are drawn, as if by enchantment, to the darkness beneath the City of Light. They tread in the footsteps of sorcerers, bandits, smugglers, the quick and the sly who haunted the tunnels centuries ago. Many who spend time below use nicknames _ `` Destroy,'' `` Calamity'' or `` Professor <PERSON> Sato </PERSON>'' _ and dress in exaggerated punk or skinhead style. The eternal, eerie silence and stillness enclose a voyager who weaves through the sand-colored maze of galleries, rooms, nooks and niches as if pulled along by the flashlight beam. Fossils of ancient creatures are imbedded in walls nicked by the pickaxes of workers long dead. Minuscule stalactites have formed on the dripping ceilings of what once were quarries for the limestone that built <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION>, most of them worked in the Middle Ages. During World War II, the catacombs were bunkers for the German occupiers and hideouts for the French Resistance. They have been a blessing to mushroom growers who harvested tons of `` champignons de <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION>'' each day from the murky gardens. `` It's a milieu that is such an anachronism compared with the rest of the capital,'' said Inspector <PERSON> Jean-Claude </PERSON> <PERSON> Saratte </PERSON>, director of police operations in the catacombs. It has been against the law to go underground since 1955 because of risks both to travelers and the city's foundations, but <PERSON> Saratte </PERSON> said: `` It's an adventure ... so everyone goes down, from sons of Cabinet ministers to little punks.'' Quarries of <LOCATION> Lutecian </LOCATION> limestone running under southern <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION>, just a corner of the 188 miles of accessible catacombs, are assigned to the dead. The galleries are lined with the skulls and other bones of 6 million people, some guillotined in the French Revolution but most merely overflow from the crowded cemeteries of <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Anne-Marie </PERSON> <PERSON> Leparmentier </PERSON>, a geologist with the General Inspection of the Quarries, the city agency in charge since the 18th century, said a `` reserve'' of bones is kept in other sections of the quarries, but `` sometimes a skull disappears'' now that the cataphiles have come. People have had regular access since the last century to the bone caverns at the <LOCATION> Place </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Denfert-Rochereau </LOCATION> in southern <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> and regular tours are conducted. The rest of the catacombs are reached by manhole, under cover of darkness, down a steel ladder to another world. Going underground became a fad more than a decade ago when students of the <ORGANIZATION> Ecole </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nationale </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> des </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mines </ORGANIZATION> nearly made it a ritual. `` We ended up spending days finding people lost inside,'' <PERSON> Saratte </PERSON> said, so all but eight of about 300 accesses to the catacombs have been soldered shut. The quarries are the lowest level of subterranean <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION>, which also is honeycombed with subway lines and 1,313 miles of navigable sewers. The vast underworld inspired <PERSON> Victor </PERSON> <PERSON> Hugo </PERSON>, and later <PERSON> Gaston </PERSON> <PERSON> Leroux </PERSON>, whose `` Phantom of the Opera'' hid out in `` that infernal underground maze.'' Around one corner is a bath carved into the rock by quarry workers centuries ago, around the next an open well that may descend to the center of <LOCATION> Earth </LOCATION>. Around still another, `` Lost in the catas. Help!'' is scrawled on the wall. Some writings reek of threat or foreboding: `` This is the domain of the Klan,'' `` Avenue of the Black Mass,'' `` I'm Dead.'' A shuffling sound comes from a corridor nearby. The path forks and the swamp route beckons. Travelers slosh through the ancient mud of <LOCATION> Lutecia </LOCATION>, as <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> was called in Roman times. Eras collide in the catacombs. Punks, skinheads and weekend revelers hold all-night seances. In Room Z, a large, confusing, amorphous cavity reached by slithering on the stomach through a narrow tunnel, the walls are scrolls of obscenities, swastikas and death wails. Subterranean <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> is `` a very particular little world, a little planet all its own'' where groups of regulars establish zones of influence, said <PERSON> Saratte </PERSON>, the police inspector. <PERSON> Philip </PERSON>, who uses only his first name, said: `` This world is divided into two races, the tourists and the cataphiles. The tourists are a hated race. ... You have to do everything to chase them out.'' `` Actually, it is a rather hostile milieu'' where `` criminals do n't think of hiding out, said <PERSON> Michel </PERSON> <PERSON> Laroche </PERSON>, another geologist for the city quarries agency. Since the beginning, the quarries of <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> have attracted those either in hiding or in search of the celestial or the damned. <PERSON> St. </PERSON> <PERSON> Denis </PERSON>, patron saint of <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>, said Mass in the quarries during the Christian persecution, according to <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> <PERSON> Lacordaire </PERSON>'s book `` The Secret History of Subterranean <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION>. Some 13th century bandits hid under the Chateau de Vauvert, replaced long ago by the <LOCATION> Luxembourg </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gardens </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Lacordaire </PERSON> said. Sorcerers used the quarries for black masses, especially during the 1348 plague that filled the <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> cemeteries and caused the living to search for solace in the occult. In the last century, merchants used the catacombs to smuggle untaxed black-market goods to clients. Official concern now centers on preserving the natural beauty of the quarries and fears that unauthorized travelers will harm the city foundations. `` There have always been cataphiles, but perhaps in the past they were more respectful,'' <PERSON> Laroche </PERSON> said. `` It is not a sacred place, but it is our patrimony.'' Over-ambitious excavations weakened the subterranean infrastructure. There were reports a century ago of the earth swallowing homes on the Boulevard St. <PERSON> Michel </PERSON> and neighboring streets. <PERSON> Laroche </PERSON> said the last fatal accident was a 1961 cave-in at <LOCATION> Clamart </LOCATION>, a southern suburb, that killed 20 people. Authorities began mapping and reinforcing the quarries in the mid-18th century and do so today when the need arises. Quarrying has been prohibited since 1788.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881031-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-31-88 0022EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Czechoslovakia-Future     10-31 0754</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Czechoslovakia-Future,0779</SECOND>
<HEAD>Czechoslovak Leaders Chart Conservative Course</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</NOTE>
<HEAD>AP News Analysis</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ALISON SMALE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PRAGUE, Czechoslovakia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Unimpressed with sweeping Soviet reform and demands for change at home, <LOCATION> Czechoslovakia </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> leaders are holding firm to policies pursued since 1968, when `` Prague Spring'' reforms were crushed. Tough police reaction to a mass protest in <LOCATION> Prague </LOCATION> on Friday and to a demonstration in August signaled that authorities will not tolerate public expressions of a desire for more freedom. For the thousands of peaceful protesters, the mass rallies could strengthen their resolve in demanding a more democratic society. The next public show of support for such demands is likely to come on International Human Rights Day on Dec. 10. A demonstration called that day last year by the Charter 77 human rights movement attracted a few thousand people. <LOCATION> Czechoslovakia </LOCATION> was an independent democracy for 20 years before World War II and has a long tradition of civil movements predating independence in 1918. The 70th anniversary of that independence was the occasion for Friday's rally in <LOCATION> Wenceslas </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Square </LOCATION>, 24 hours after the authorities organized their own mass celebration of the anniversary for the first time in four decades of Communist rule. The two events were sharply contrasting, with the official rally seeming ritualized and the banned independent gathering appearing a more genuine expression of national sentiment, dissident filmmaker <PERSON> Stanislav </PERSON> <PERSON> Milota </PERSON> noted in an interview. `` The government, at their rally, did n't sing the national anthem, which was played by an <ORGANIZATION> Interior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> band and sung by an <ORGANIZATION> Interior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> choir'' and not taken up by the organized, massed crowd, <PERSON> Milota </PERSON> noted. By contrast, on Friday, thousands sang the national anthem with great feeling before riot police with truncheons marched down the square toward a core of hundreds of protesters who stood their ground. The authorities have made clear they will seek no contact with such people or unofficial groups, as Communist officials tentatively have in neighboring <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>. `` There can be no dialogue here,'' <ORGANIZATION> Prague </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> party chief <PERSON> Miroslav </PERSON> <PERSON> Stepan </PERSON> told Thursday's official rally. At 43, <PERSON> Stepan </PERSON>, a member of the ruling Politburo, is one of a new generation of Communist leaders slowly rising into the ruling elite in a reshuffle by <PERSON> Milos </PERSON> <PERSON> Jakes </PERSON>, who took over as party chief from <PERSON> Gustav </PERSON> <PERSON> Husak </PERSON> in December. Czechoslovaks had few expectations of reform from <PERSON> Jakes </PERSON>, who oversaw the purge of an estimated half million Communists from the party after August 1968, when Soviet and <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION> Pact tanks put an end to the `` Prague Spring'' reform of <PERSON> Husak </PERSON>'s predecessor, <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON> <PERSON> Dubcek </PERSON>. A reshuffle this month confirmed <PERSON> Jakes </PERSON> and his allies do not intend to follow Soviet President <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> into sweeping economic or political reforms. The leading proponent of change in the top elite, <PERSON> Lubomir </PERSON> <PERSON> Strougal </PERSON>, lost his Politburo seat and his post as premier. According to a Czechoslovak source, his replacement, <PERSON> Ladislav </PERSON> <PERSON> Adamec </PERSON>, was one of a group of party members who backed Soviet criticism of <PERSON> Dubcek </PERSON> before the 1968 invasion. The reshuffle also saw the first professional policeman named Interior Minister. <PERSON> Frantisek </PERSON> <PERSON> Kincl </PERSON>, who had overall responsibility for Friday's tough police action and the strict security in force for days beforehand, is a former police chief in northern and central <LOCATION> Moravia </LOCATION>, two areas known as the toughest on dissidents. The police action and detention of at least 85 dissidents in one of the biggest pre-emptive crackdowns nationwide in years stood in stark contrast to Soviet policy as presented a few days earlier by West German Chancellor <PERSON> Helmut </PERSON> <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON>. He announced that all Soviet political prisoners would be freed by the end of the year. Other Western nations greeted that announcement with skepticism. But recent Soviet policy does contrast with the trend in <LOCATION> Czechoslovakia </LOCATION> toward what one <LOCATION> Prague </LOCATION> resident summed up as `` retrenchment.'' The dissident community, meanwhile, is inching forward to more overt political activity. Charter 77 has been primarily a human rights movement, a loose association of an estimated 1,300 signatories who issue documents on Czechoslovak society and history and include former <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> members who still believe in Socialism and many intellectuals who do not. Earlier this month, several leading Chartists, including banned playwright <PERSON> Vaclav </PERSON> <PERSON> Havel </PERSON>, joined a new <ORGANIZATION> Movement </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Civil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Freedom </ORGANIZATION>, which has formulated 11 demands for a multiparty democracy and a largely denationalized economy.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Alison </PERSON> <PERSON> Smale </PERSON> has been reporting on <LOCATION> Czechoslovakia </LOCATION> and other East European countries as the <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>' <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION> bureau chief and East European correspondent for the past two years.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881031-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-31-88 0029EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BattleForCities     10-31 0696</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Battle For Cities,0720</SECOND>
<HEAD>An Afghan Turning Point: Who Will Control The Cities?</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By EARLEEN FISHER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>HERAT, Afghanistan (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 As the pink-tinged sunset fades over ruins of bombed-out houses, and kerosene lanterns start twinkling through the darkness, the gunfire begins. It lasts until sunrise, to be followed intermittently through the day by the more distant boom of rockets aimed at the city. <LOCATION> Herat </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>'s third-largest city with a population of 106,000, is one of the cities the Moscow-backed government considers `` safe'' because Soviet troops are still present. The government professes to be able to defend the city against U.S.-supported Moslem guerrillas known as mujahedeen, or Islamic holy warriors, even after the Soviet pullout scheduled this winter. The designation `` safe'' appears to be a delusion, if not an outright fraud. The guerrillas are about 12 to 13 miles from the city, according to <PERSON> Juma </PERSON> <PERSON> Mohammad </PERSON>, provincial commander of the <LOCATION> Sarandoy </LOCATION>, a paramilitary armored force considered more loyal and better-trained than the Afghan army's rank and file. But the outgoing fire at night in <LOCATION> Herat </LOCATION> seems aimed at an enemy much closer. Most of what can be heard from the balcony of a government building on the northern edge of the city sounds no bigger than .50 - caliber _ whose range is about 1 -LCB- The mortars used by Sarandoy troops in <LOCATION> Herat </LOCATION>'s 14th century citadel show signs of recent firing and are of the type that has a maximum range of about five miles. In the Afghan capital of <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION>, non-Soviet bloc diplomats predict <LOCATION> Herat </LOCATION> will fall quickly to the mujahedeen after Soviet troops pull out in accordance with a U.N.-mediated accord. The withdrawal must be completed by Feb. 15. But Soviet troops left <LOCATION> Kandahar </LOCATION> this past summer and the mujahedeen still have not dislodged the Afghan garrison and taken that city, the largest in the country after <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION>, the capital. Rockets also land in <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION> several times a week, sometimes by the scores. Most of the time the damage is insignificant. But the cities are vulnerable, more to siege tactics than to any direct military attack the mujahedeen can mount with their poorly targeted rockets. The capture of <LOCATION> Kandahar </LOCATION> or <LOCATION> Herat </LOCATION> would deal a major psychological blow to <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>'s Soviet-style government. <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>'s mountains afford sanctuary to the mujahedeen but it is the cities they must capture. Whether they can achieve victory through direct military attacks, the mujahedeen are in a good position to isolate the cities from their supplies of food, fuel and military reinforcements. <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION> gets a periodic taste of this when the mujahedeen cut the roads leading to the capital, causing sugar to disappear from the markets and doubling the prices of dwindling stocks of flour. <LOCATION> Herat </LOCATION> is even more vulnerable. Fuel comes from the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, a two-hour drive up the 95-mile highway to the Afghan border town of <LOCATION> Torghundi </LOCATION> when the road is not blocked by winter snows or year-round guerrillas. The fuel is needed not only for automobiles, which are outnumbered in <LOCATION> Herat </LOCATION> by horse-drawn vehicles and bicycles, but for heating, cooking and running the city's power plant. The plan provides electricity only from sundown to sunrise and only for the few relatively prosperous neighborhoods, government institutions and hospitals. <LOCATION> Herat </LOCATION> has never had around-the-clock electricity, not even before the war That began a decade ago when a coup-installed communist government took power and quickly required Soviet assistance to survive. The guerrillas surrounding <LOCATION> Herat </LOCATION> are led by one of the mujahedeen's ablest commanders, <PERSON> Ismail </PERSON> <PERSON> Khan </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> Jamiat-e-Islami </ORGANIZATION>, the largest of the seven Pakistani-based guerrilla groups. Main roads and bridges around the city are now guarded by Soviet troops. Sarandoy commander <PERSON> Mohammad </PERSON> said he has 4,000 men in <LOCATION> Herat </LOCATION> province, 600 of them in <LOCATION> Herat </LOCATION> city. In addition, he said, there are 2,000 government-paid village militiamen and 4,000 `` Defenders of the Revolution,'' gun-toting civilians the government pays $ 4.75 to $ 7.15 a month. <PERSON> Mohammad </PERSON> said he had no idea how many mujahedeen were outside the city. `` Their activity is too secret. It is difficult to say,'' he said in an interview in his office where the second-story windows were bricked up and sandbagged.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881031-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-31-88 0037EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-DeadlyTravel     10-31 0763</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Deadly Travel,0784</SECOND>
<HEAD>Sea Travel Major Threat To Filipinos, Studies Say Little Being
Done</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</NOTE>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MIGUEL C. SUAREZ</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MANILA, Philippines (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Last year, after more than 1,500 people died in the collision of a packed ferry and an oil tanker, investigations concluded that government agencies and shipowners habitually ignored maritime safety measures. Last week's sinking of the ferry <PERSON> Dona </PERSON> <PERSON> Marilyn </PERSON> during a typhoon showed little has changed, despite sea disasters that have killed thousands of people and left hundreds missing in the past year. `` Largely a seafaring people living in an archipelago, Filipinos rightfully expect a government attentive to the needs of sea travel,'' a <ORGANIZATION> Philippine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> study said in April. `` Instead, they find a government disorganized in its treatment of sea travel and the shipping industry.'' It speculated that neglect of the public safety in shipping was probably due to the fact that most who travel by sea are poor and can not afford plane fares. The House of Representatives noted in another study that most of the 588 ports throughout the island nation were designed primarily to handle cargo and none has a passenger terminal. The reports followed separate investigations by the two chambers into the December crash of the <PERSON> Dona </PERSON> <PERSON> Paz </PERSON> and an oil tanker. Official reports put the death toll at about 1,700, but most estimates placed the actual figure at more than 3,000. Only 28 survived. The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> report said that despite frequent fatal accidents, the government had done so little that when the <PERSON> Dona </PERSON> <PERSON> Paz </PERSON> sank, `` the bureaucracy had little to offer except knee-jerk reactions and confusion.'' Despite pledges by shipowners and authorities to enforce rules on manifesting passengers, neither knew the precise number of people aboard when Typhoon Ruby sank the <PERSON> Dona </PERSON> <PERSON> Marilyn </PERSON>, the sister ship of the Dona Paz. The <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> recorded 379 passengers and 60 crew members. <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> Go, president and general manager <ORGANIZATION> Sulpicio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lines </ORGANIZATION>, which owned the ferry, said 451 passengers and 66 crewmen were on the <PERSON> Dona </PERSON> <PERSON> Marilyn </PERSON> when it left <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION> Oct. 23 for the central Philippine port of <LOCATION> Tacloban </LOCATION>. By Sulpicio's count, at most 20 people were not listed on the manifest. But <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION> newspapers said at least 52 survivors were not on the list. President <PERSON> Corazon </PERSON> <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON> ordered an investigation, saying that among other things she wanted to know `` why they sailed despite very bad weather.'' <PERSON> Commodore </PERSON> <PERSON> Pio </PERSON> <PERSON> Garrido </PERSON>, commandant of the <ORGANIZATION> Philippine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION>, which clears commercial ships for sailing to ensure safety regulations are followed, said <PERSON> Dona </PERSON> <PERSON> Marilyn </PERSON> was allowed to sail because `` the weather was clear in <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION>.'' Previous warnings by the government's weather service showed the ship's destination was in <PERSON> Ruby </PERSON>'s path. <PERSON> Garrido </PERSON> said nothing in maritime regulations prevents a vessel from sailing if there is bad weather at its destination. The investigations of the Dona Paz disaster showed virtually everything was wrong with the shipping industry. Both laid most of the blame on government neglect and apathy. Both reports said that not only was there a shortage of ships, but communications equipment and navigational aids were obsolete and personnel poorly trained. In addition, maritime safety regulations could not be enforced because of corruption and overlapping regulatory agencies, the reports said. The reports noted that up to seven agencies were overseeing the shipping industry so that responsibility could easily be passed from one to the other. It said corruption was such that operators could obtain lincenses for even the most unseaworthy vessels by bribing licensing officials. The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> expressed surprise that despite the country's heavy dependence on water transport, only a total of $ 150 million had been invested in all aspects of the shipping industry. It cited figures from the <ORGANIZATION> Maritime </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Industry </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Authority </ORGANIZATION> showing that in 1986 the country had 3,000 vessels `` of different sizes, configurations and uses,'' which moved a total of 16 million passengers and 39.6 million tons of cargo. It said the average annual maritime death toll of 152 between 1980-87 was already bad enough before the <ORGANIZATION> Dona </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Paz </ORGANIZATION> disaster raised it to 508 per annum. The figure does not include hundreds of accidents involving unregistered outriggers in rural areas. Despite Mrs. <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON>'s promise of an investigation, the Philippine press has been skeptical that improvements will be made. `` After every sea disaster, there is usually a lot of talk about reforms in the shipping and maritime industry,'' wrote The Philippine Star columnist <PERSON> Art </PERSON> <PERSON> Borjal </PERSON>. `` But after all is said and done, nothing much really happens. And when another sea tragedy takes place, the vicious cycle is repeated.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881031-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-31-88 0039EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Prince-Architecture     10-31 0619</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Prince-Architecture,0639</SECOND>
<HEAD>Prince Charles Gains Support In His Battle With The Builders</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By AUDREY WOODS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Prince <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> took on the architectural establishment in his own television documentary and gained a powerful vote of confidence from ordinary citizens, newspapers, and even some architects. A newspaper survey showed that more than 75 percent of Britons agreed with the prince's views that many architects and developers ignore people's wishes and build ugly, characterless buildings that are unpleasant to live in. However, <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Rodgers </PERSON>, director general of <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Royal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> British </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Architects </ORGANIZATION>, responded Sunday that `` there is too much hypocrisy ... and we are not going to allow architects to be made scapegoats.'' <PERSON> Charles </PERSON>' maiden venture into television writing and performing was an outspoken and often humorous return to the subject of modern architecture, which he has discussed publicly for several years. He has angered leading architects and raised complaints that a member of the royal family has no business publicizing such views. With 75 minutes of uninterrupted television time on the <ORGANIZATION> British </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Broadcasting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> on Friday night, <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> took a more positive approach, showing viewers new buildings and developments he admired. But his criticism of others was severe. Glancing at a low, stark-white structure among Victorian buildings at the edge of the <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Thames </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> commented: `` That's redolent of a word processor to me, and I do n't see that people particularly want to live looking at a word processor.'' The Sunday Telegraph newspaper called the show a tour de force that established the 39-year-old heir to the throne as a `` great communicator.'' The Observer said it was admirable, and <ORGANIZATION> Sunday </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> columnist <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> <PERSON> Jenkins </PERSON> wished <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> luck in a `` genuinely popular crusade.'' Other Britons seemed to agree. `` He follows what the ordinary man in the street believes, I think, about <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>: it is being drowned out by skyscrapers,'' said an unidentified woman in a TV interview Saturday. In its poll by <ORGANIZATION> Telephone </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Surveys </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ltd. </ORGANIZATION>, the Sunday Express said 75.5 percent of 1,000 people in a nationally representative sample agreed with <PERSON> Charles </PERSON>. Almost 88 percent thought it right for members of the royal family to speak out on such issues. No margin of error was given. <PERSON> Denys </PERSON> <PERSON> Lasdun </PERSON>, architect of the concrete National Theater, was asked by a <ORGANIZATION> BBC </ORGANIZATION> interviewer whether the prince should voice his opinions in public. `` Of course he should ... so should anybody, it's a public art,'' <PERSON> Lasdun </PERSON> said. `` But because everyone shoots their mouth off, it does n't mean ... they talk sense.'' <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> called <PERSON> Lasdun </PERSON>'s creation `` a clever way of building a nuclear power station in the middle of <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> without anyone objecting.'' He called a projected <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> development by <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Palumbo </PERSON> `` rather like a 1930s wireless -LRB- radio -RRB-.'' `` I can only say, ` God bless the Prince of <LOCATION> Wales </LOCATION>, and <PERSON> God </PERSON> save us from his architectural judgment,''' responded <PERSON> Palumbo </PERSON>, new chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Arts </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>, which allocates state funds to <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s arts. <PERSON> Max </PERSON> <PERSON> Hutchinson </PERSON>, president-elect of the <ORGANIZATION> Royal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> British </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Architects </ORGANIZATION>, defended the latest generation of architects. He said they have `` no greater love than the prince for much of what happened 20 or more years ago.'' <ORGANIZATION> Conservative </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> lawmaker <PERSON> Sydney </PERSON> <PERSON> Chapman </PERSON>, the only architect in the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commons </ORGANIZATION>, backed <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> in his attack on `` ugly, multi-story slabs of concrete.'' But the legislator said they were principally the fault of politicians who rushed to rebuild cities damaged in World War II. In its page-one editorial, The Sunday Telegraph said <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> could become a major television personality. `` It will only take a few more charismatic performances like last week's for him to hold the nation in the palm of his hand,'' the newspaper said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881031-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-31-88 0055EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     10-31 0873</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0912</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in the News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>JAKARTA, Indonesia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 British rock star <PERSON> Mick </PERSON> <PERSON> Jagger </PERSON> thrilled an audience of more than 60,000 with a two-hour concert of songs from his days with the <ORGANIZATION> Rolling </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Stones </ORGANIZATION> and his solo career. <PERSON> Jagger </PERSON>, appearing Sunday at the nation's biggest soccer stadium, sang at least 22 songs, including the Stones' `` Honky Tonk Woman,'' and `` I Ca n't Get No -LRB- Satisfaction -RRB-'' and his own `` Just Another Night.'' After bidding his fans farewell in <LOCATION> Indonesian </LOCATION> and English, <PERSON> Jagger </PERSON> flew back to his hotel in a helicopter, passing over the stadium.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>TEOTIHUACAN, Mexico (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 With the great pyramids of <LOCATION> Teotihuacan </LOCATION> as a backdrop, Spanish tenor <PERSON> Placido </PERSON> <PERSON> Domingo </PERSON> led the premier of `` Aztec Songs,'' a choral symphony written in a 500-year-old Indian language. `` Aztec Songs'' is based on the poetry of <LOCATION> Nezahualcoyotl </LOCATION>, a ruler of the Nahuatl tribe who died in 1472. The songs were performed Saturday in Nahuatl, an ancient Mexican tongue that gave the world the word for chocolate. Thousands of people in <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> still speak Nahuatl and there are <ORGANIZATION> Nahuatl </ORGANIZATION> poets still writing today. Argentine composer <PERSON> Lalo </PERSON> <PERSON> Schifrin </PERSON> conducted the symphony with a baton of obsidian, the gleaming black volcanic rock fashioned into works of art by <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>'s pre-Colombian peoples, in an icy wind before an estimated 10,000 people at the foot of the Pyramid of the Moon. The audience greeted <PERSON> Domingo </PERSON>, who performed with a cold, with an especially warm round of applause. The tenor has relatives in <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> and his efforts to help it recover from the devasting 1985 earthquake has endeared him to Mexicans. The performance was part of a campaign to raise $ 300,000 to preserve <LOCATION> Teotihuacan </LOCATION>, 25 miles north of <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>TACOMA, Wash. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The flu forced pop star <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> to cancel three concerts here this week, his publicist says. The decision to cancel the shows scheduled for today, Tuesday and Wednesday at the Tacoma Dome was made on the advice of <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s physician and after consultation with the singer's manager, <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> DiLeo </PERSON>, publicist <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON> said Sunday
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Leonard </PERSON> <PERSON> Nimoy </PERSON>, who went from playing Mr. <PERSON> Spock </PERSON> on `` Star Trek'' to directing hit movies, says it's good to be just an actor again _ and Mr. <PERSON> Spock </PERSON> at that. `` I was fantasizing about this when I was making ` The Good Mother,''' <PERSON> Nimoy </PERSON> told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> during filming of `` Star Trek V.'' `` The actor comes to work and says, ` Where's the coffee? What time is lunch? Why are you keeping me waiting?''' Co-star <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Shatner </PERSON>, <PERSON> Nimoy </PERSON>'s `` Star Trek'' shipmate as Captain <PERSON> Kirk </PERSON>, is the director of `` Star Trek V.'' <PERSON> Nimoy </PERSON> directed `` Star Trek III'' and the popular `` Star Trek IV'' before returning to <LOCATION> Earth </LOCATION> to make the hit `` Three Men and a Baby.'' His latest film, `` The Good Mother'' starring <PERSON> Diane </PERSON> <PERSON> Keaton </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jason </PERSON> <PERSON> Robards </PERSON>, opens this week. `` I feel like I've been struck by lightning,'' <PERSON> Nimoy </PERSON> said in the interview published Sunday. `` But I feel like I've been standing out in a rainstorm for quite a while and I finally got hit.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Rettig </PERSON>, who was <PERSON> Lassie </PERSON>'s best friend as farm boy <PERSON> Jeff </PERSON> <PERSON> Miller </PERSON> on TV's most famous dog show, says he discovered that life outside of show business has its hazards. <PERSON> Rettig </PERSON>, who played <PERSON> Jeff </PERSON> from 1954 to 1957, dropped out of show biz at age 15. `` I wanted to be a real kid and see what the real world was like,'' he said in an interview in this week's People magazine. After high school, <PERSON> Rettig </PERSON> tried odd jobs and tried to go back into acting, but did n't have much success. `` I went into the most painful period of my life,'' he said. `` I considered suicide every day.'' In 1971, he was arrested for growing marijuana. Three years later, he was jailed on another drug charge, and his wife left him with their two boys. The latter conviction was overturned in 1979. <PERSON> Rettig </PERSON>'s story had a happy ending. Today, he lives in <LOCATION> Marina </LOCATION> <LOCATION> del </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rey </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, and owns computer software company. `` I'm at the happiest place I've ever been,'' he told People. `` I'm happy with myself, my career and my life.''
</TEXT>
<NOTE>Eds: A version moving sports wire.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>CHICAGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Professional basketball superstar <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Jordan </PERSON> says he plans to take more time out to smell the flowers. `` Next year, I plan to cut down on my endorsements and personal appearances,'' the <ORGANIZATION> Chicago </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bulls </ORGANIZATION> guard said recently. `` I want to have more time for myself. `` At the same time, I do n't want to isolate myself from people. I do n't have fences around my house or guards standing in front of it. No bodyguards with me when I go out.'' Although basketball has made him a millionaire, <PERSON> Jordan </PERSON> said he enjoyed it more when he was a child in <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>. `` Then, there was no business surrounding it,'' he said. `` No crowds following your every step. The game was cut down to its bare basic. It was pure fun, something everybody in the neighborhood just loved to do. `` Now, there is too much pressure on me. Not just in terms of how you play the game, but how you are perceived away from the game.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881031-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-31-88 0058EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Pentagon-Indictments Bjt   10-31 0772</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Pentagon-Indictments, Bjt,760</SECOND>
<HEAD>No Pre-Election Indictments in Pentagon Fraud Case</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOAN MOWER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The prosecutor in a massive defense contracting probe says the complexity of the case _ not politics _ will delay indictments until after the Nov. 8 election. <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Hudson </PERSON>, the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> attorney in <LOCATION> Alexandria </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, who is coordinating the multistate investigation, also said indictments could continue for a year as a result of a probe into the $ 150-billion-a-year <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> purchasing system. A federal grand jury resumes meeting Nov. 15, so indictments could come then, which would be about five months after the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> revealed the investigation by searching more than 40 premises across the country. `` I am very optimistic on November indictments,'' <PERSON> Hudson </PERSON> said. Information about the case has been scarce because prosecutors have sealed most search warrants and affidavits. The investigation centers on whether private consultants, many of them former <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> employees, paid bribes to <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> officials for inside information about contracts, chiefly within the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Hudson </PERSON>, a Republican, denied any suggestion that indictments were slowed so that Democratic presidential candidate <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> could not make them an issue in his campaign against Vice President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. `` Nothing would have given me greater pleasure than to hand down indictments in the first part of October,'' <PERSON> Hudson </PERSON> said in an interview. But the prosecutor said the case has been `` administratively complex'' with attorneys forced to examine about 700,000 documents and listen to `` thousands and thousands of tapes of two years of telephone interceptions.'' Federal and defense sources also indicate <PERSON> Hudson </PERSON>'s staff has been kept waiting for answers from some potential defendants who have been offered plea bargains. Adding to the task was the time-consuming process of gathering financial evidence from foreign bank accounts, which <PERSON> Hudson </PERSON> described as an `` always delicate issue.'' <PERSON> Hudson </PERSON> said there were good reasons for thoroughness, including the `` high national visibility'' of the case, and the propensity for judges in <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> to schedule trials shortly after indictments are returned. `` I will not present this indictment until we are ready for trial, and we feel we will be ready ... within the next month,'' he said. As the case evolves, indictments and trials could be held in other cities, sources said. <PERSON> Hudson </PERSON> did not discuss charges that could be filed. But the use of <ORGANIZATION> Internal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Revenue </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> agents on the case suggests that tax charges may be contemplated in addition to the more obvious counts of theft of government property, bribery, fraud and conspiracy to defraud the government. Fifteen attorneys, some of them working 12-hour days and weekends, plus 75 federal agents from the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Naval </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Investigative </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> IRS </ORGANIZATION> have been assigned to the case, which <PERSON> Hudson </PERSON> called, `` the largest case ever handled in the eastern district of <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>.'' <PERSON> Hudson </PERSON> refused to say how many indictments he expected to be returned initially, but noted that courtroom space generally confines the number to less than 12. Though <PERSON> Hudson </PERSON> declined to name the targets of the investigation, he did not rule out members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. `` All individuals that may have been engaged in wrongdoing or committed a criminal act in connection with the defense procurement process will be scrutinized and prosecuted if appropriate,'' he said. <PERSON> Hudson </PERSON> disputed reports that he had told members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> during the summer that none was a target. `` I never made such a statement,'' he said. `` I told the members of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Representatives </ORGANIZATION> that no member of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> had been the subject of electronic surveillance, had received a subpoena to testify in front of the grand jury at that time or had been the subject of a search warrant,'' he said. Court papers filed in <LOCATION> Brooklyn </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION>, indicate prosecutors are looking at allegations that campaign contributions were extorted. Raids in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> came at the business of <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Kane </PERSON>, who set up the <ORGANIZATION> Long </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Island </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aerospace </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Political </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Action </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> to make contributions that might help area defense contractors, and at the home of <PERSON> Dennis </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Unisys </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> official identified as turning over contributions to Rep. <PERSON> Roy </PERSON> <PERSON> Dyson </PERSON>, D-Md., who sits on the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Armed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> <PERSON> Dyson </PERSON> has denied any wrongdoing. The name of another committee member, Rep. <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Chappell </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, has also surfaced in connection with the probe. <PERSON> Chappell </PERSON> says he has done nothing wrong. Among those whose names have been linked to the investigation are five <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> officials, including <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Gaines </PERSON>, deputy assistant <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> secretary for acquisition and management; <PERSON> Melvyn </PERSON> <PERSON> Paisley </PERSON>, a consultant who was assistant secretary of the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> for research, engineering and systems before leaving government in 1987, and <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Galvin </PERSON>, another defense consultant.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881031-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-31-88 0059EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FarmScene     10-31 0807</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Farm Scene,780</SECOND>
<HEAD>USDA Economist Predicts Bumper Crops Next Year</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DON KENDALL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Farm Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 This year's drought is not likely to be repeated in 1989, and <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> farmers probably will harvest bumper crops of wheat, corn and soybeans, according to an <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> economist. Corn production, for example, could nearly double from this year's drought-riddled yield. But <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Cole </PERSON> of the department's <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> warned that a backlog of demand will siphon off most of the 1989 crop increases without allowing the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> to rebuild its stockpiles significantly. `` Production of all commodities almost certainly will be much greater next year, but consumption of wheat, corn and soybeans also will remain high, resulting in only limited increases in stocks during 1989-90,'' <PERSON> Cole </PERSON> said. The odds are good for such a harvest improvement in 1989, he said. Since 1970, drought has shriveled <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> crops five times _ 1970, 1974, 1980, 1983 and 1988 _ and in each case harvest yields were up significantly the following year. According to <PERSON> Cole </PERSON>'s analysis, which was prepared for the November issue of Agricultural Outlook magazine, 1989 wheat production may rebound to about 2.5 billion bushels from 1.8 billion bushels this year; corn to 7.5 billion to 8 billion bushels from 4.4 billion in 1988; and soybeans to almost 2 billion bushels from this year's harvest of 1.5 billion. <PERSON> Cole </PERSON> said the larger crops of 1989 `` will be used to sustain growing consumption'' by domestic and foreign users. Therefore, he added, inventories `` may rise only slightly'' by the end of the 1989-90 crop year. `` The real impact of the drought _ markedly reduced stocks _ will remain for some time to come,'' <PERSON> Cole </PERSON> said. `` Some rebuilding of inventories that had been severely depleted in 1988-89 is expected, but gains will be small. Larger increases, if desired, will take more time.'' Despite the odds that the 1988 drought will not be repeated next year, the possibility still exists, no matter how unsavory the subject is for <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> officials. <PERSON> Lester </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>, president of <ORGANIZATION> Worldwatch </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION>, a non-profit research organization based in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, recently said that another <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> drought in 1989 would trigger a `` desperate scramble'' by needy countries for dwindling grain supplies. <PERSON> Cole </PERSON> explained further about drought's track record in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and how it backs up his contention that 1989 may be a bumper crop year. `` Unlike other countries, the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has not had back-to-back droughts in at least 75 years,'' he said. `` The <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> recently endured as many as four successive years of drought. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> weather history and prospects give little reason to believe that crop yields will not rebound next year.'' Moreover, he said, rainfall in September and October has helped replenish badly depleted soil moisture in parts of the corn and soybean belts, and across the Southeast. Long-term forecasts call for average or slightly above-average chances for normal precipitation this fall. `` Even so, most of the upper <LOCATION> Midwest </LOCATION> and Southeast still require as much as 6 to 10 inches of rainfall this fall and winter to restore soil moisture to more normal levels,'' <PERSON> Cole </PERSON> said. `` Temperatures are likely to be somewhat higher than normal.'' Some other reasons cited by Cole for expecting 1989 crop production to rise sharply: _ The <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> has used provisions of the 1985 farm law to reduce the amount of land farmers must idle in order to qualify for price supports and other program benefits, including `` deficiency'' payments, or direct subsidies For 1989, as an example, only 10 percent of a farmer's feed grain base acreage will have to be set aside, compared with 20 percent this year. Wheat farmers also will have to idle only 10 percent instead of 27.5 percent for 1988. _ The Disaster Assistance Act of 1988, which provides drought aid to stricken farmers, also permits <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> to let farmers plant soybeans or sunflowers on corn acres without losing acreage credit for future program calculations Although 1989 soybean plantings are likely to expand less than either wheat or corn, production is expected to rise substantially. Soybean acreage in the South has been declining for several years as farmers returned land to fallow or other uses. Recovery could begin in 1989, but it will take sustained higher prices to boost the South's soybean acreage to levels of the late 1970s, when prices were high and exports boomed. `` Consumption of wheat, corn and soybeans is expected to increase in 1989-90,'' <PERSON> Cole </PERSON> said. `` Domestic food, seed and industrial uses likely will be near present levels. However, global grain and oilseed use probably will increase slightly.'' Cole added: `` Export growth will be spurred further by increased demand from developing countries, as the value of the dollar remains relatively low. Price declines accompanying next year's harvest will make it easier for importing nations to maintain or expand purchases in 1989-90.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881031-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-31-88 0101EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-EndangeredForests Bjt   10-31 0770</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Endangered Forests, Bjt,750</SECOND>
<HEAD>Could the Marbled Murrelet Be a Red Herring?</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto WX14</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LES BLUMENTHAL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 If the marbled murrelet turns out to be an endangered bird, it may endanger loggers' plans to take timber from some of the oldest forests in <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>. The Fish and <ORGANIZATION> Wildlife </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>, in a little-noticed decision published in the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Register </ORGANIZATION>, agreed to consider listing the marbled murrelet as an endangered species. The agency found that a <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Audubon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION> petition for listing the bird `` presented substantial information indicating that the requested action may be warranted.'' Not much is known about the marbled murrelet, a robin-sized seabird that seems to swim better than it walks or flies. But scientists are convinced the bird nests almost exclusively in the old-growth timber that towers over the coastal regions of the <LOCATION> Northwest </LOCATION> _ some of the oldest forests in <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>. Listing the bird as endangered or threatened could result in a ban on cutting trees that are prized by the timber industry for their top-quality logs and premium market price. Timber industry officials accuse environmentalists of using the marbled murrelet to attempt a `` backdoor'' prohibition against old-growth timber harvesting on public lands. `` It sounds like a red herring,'' said <PERSON> Jay </PERSON> <PERSON> Goldstein </PERSON>, a spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> which includes among its members some of the largest forest-products companies in the Northwest. `` We need to decide what to do and get on with it,'' said <PERSON> Goldstein </PERSON>. `` But let's not play games and use soft little birds to defraud the process. These never-ending tactics aimed at foiling the process are irresponsible.'' Environmentalists do n't deny that they are waging a battle to halt the cutting of old-growth timber, but add that the marbled murrelet is worthy of protection in its own right. `` We are going to make the survival of the ancient forest a national issue,'' said <PERSON> Brock </PERSON> <PERSON> Evans </PERSON>, an <ORGANIZATION> Audubon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION> vice president. `` This is not just a problem for the <LOCATION> Northwest </LOCATION>. Everyone owns these forests. It's like saying the Grand Canyon only belongs to the people of <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION>.'' Caught in the middle is the Fish and <ORGANIZATION> Wildlife </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>, which recently declared that another bird that nests in old-growth timber, the spotted owl, was n't worthy of listing as endangered or threatened. That decision is now being reviewed in a lawsuit brought in federal court in <LOCATION> Portland </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ore. </LOCATION> `` What we have to answer is how important is old growth to the marbled murrelet,'' said <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Bottroff </PERSON>, a Fish and Wildlife biologist based in <LOCATION> Portland </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> Audubon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION> believes that the bird could eventually become extinct if logging of the old-growth forest continues. According to biologists' estimates, only 3,400 breeding pairs of marbled murrelets remain in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> state, maybe 2,400 breeding pairs in <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION> and less than 1,000 in <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>. Estimates for <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> range up to 50,000 breeding pairs and the bird is also found in <LOCATION> Western </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Pissot </PERSON>, an <ORGANIZATION> Audubon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION> specialist, said that since the turn of the century people have been trying to discover where the marbled murrelet nests. `` Now we know or think we know: 150 feet up on the thick branches of old-growth trees,'' said <PERSON> Pissot </PERSON>. `` They are very dependent on old growth.'' Environmentalists believe that more than 160 species may be dependent for survival on old-growth forests. `` The spotted owl and the marbled murrelet are just the tip of the iceberg,'' said <PERSON> Evans </PERSON>. `` They dramatize what is at stake.'' The <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> has estimated that about 7.5 million acres of old growth remains in the <LOCATION> Northwest </LOCATION> with more than 80 percent of it on national forest lands. Plans call for cutting about half of that total over the next 50 years and <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> officials have warned that unless it is cut the region's timber industry could collapse. Environmentalists say the <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> estimates are grossly inflated and even include trees that were destroyed by the 1980 eruption of <LOCATION> Mount </LOCATION> <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Helens </LOCATION>. They also say that the old growth is being cut at the rate of more than 170 acres a day _ the equivalent of roughly 129 football fields. <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> asked the <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> to survey the remaining old growth and to come up with a common definition for an ancient tree. A <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> task force earlier defined old-growth trees as being at least 200 years old and almost three feet in diameter. Environmentalists say that definition is too narrow and that officials also should take into account how many of the trees are in a given area and whether it has the characteristics of a mature forest.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881031-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-31-88 0105EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-PestControls     10-31 0631</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Pest Controls,620</SECOND>
<HEAD>Savings Seen in Fighting Farm Pests with Other Insects</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CARL HARTMAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
