<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881214-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-14-88 2338EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Israel-PLO 2ndLd-Writethru a0847 12-14 0763</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Israel-PLO, 2nd Ld-Writethru, a0847,0785</SECOND>
<HEAD>Israeli Leaders Cool on U.S. Move to Talk to PLO</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: SUBS 8th graf, `One official...' to ADD that Shultz said he
consulted Israeli representatives in advance. Pick up 9th pvs,
`Israel has...'</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By NICOLAS B. TATRO</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>JERUSALEM (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Israelis from both major parties reacted coldly and sometimes angrily Thursday to the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> decision to open talks with the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION>, and one official said <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> was given no advance notice of the move. <PERSON> Avi </PERSON> <PERSON> Pazner </PERSON>, spokesman for Prime Minister <PERSON> Yitzhak </PERSON> <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON> of the rightist <ORGANIZATION> Likud </ORGANIZATION> bloc, was quoted by <ORGANIZATION> Israel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> radio </ORGANIZATION> as lamenting the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> move. He said <ORGANIZATION> Palestine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> chief <PERSON> Yasser </PERSON> <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON> has not changed his position despite his more moderate language of recent weeks, the radio reported. `` They are cheap words and nothing more,'' <PERSON> Pazner </PERSON> was quoted as saying. Police Minister <PERSON> Chaim </PERSON> <PERSON> Bar-Lev </PERSON>, a senior member of the left-of-center <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, said <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON> had made a `` small step forward'' in his recent statements but fell short of renouncing terror and recognizing <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>, as <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> had demanded. He said he doubted a planned U.S.-PLO meeting in <LOCATION> Tunisia </LOCATION> would lead to substantive agreement because of the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION>'s declaration of a Palestinian state. `` If there is a meeting, not much will happen because the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> is familiar enough with the problem to know that a Palestinian state is not a solution,'' he said. <PERSON> Alon </PERSON> <PERSON> Liel </PERSON>, spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> headed by <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> leader <PERSON> Shimon </PERSON> <PERSON> Peres </PERSON>, said the Ministry was studying the situation. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Secretary of State <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON>, who announced the decision Wednesday in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, said he had discussed it beforehand with representatives of <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>. But one Israeli official said on condition of anonymity that neither <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> nor other <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials had consulted <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> in advance. <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> has shunned any contacts with the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> regardless of its statements on recognizing <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>, abandoning terrorism, and accepting <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> Security Council Resolutions 242 and 338. The resolutions call for <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> withdrawal from occupied lands and guarantee the rights of all states in the region to have secure borders. Israeli officials have contended <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON> did not fully renounce terrorism because he praised the yearlong Palestinian uprising, in which Arabs have engaged in violent riots and attacked Israelis with firebombs and other makeshift weapons. Politicians from both <ORGANIZATION> Likud </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> said Thursday they believed the PO had not fulfilled all the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> conditions for a dialogue. <ORGANIZATION> Likud </ORGANIZATION> supporters were clearly angered by the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> move. <PERSON> Benny </PERSON> <PERSON> Begin </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Likud </ORGANIZATION> parliament member and son of former prime minister <PERSON> Menachem </PERSON> <PERSON> Begin </PERSON>, said the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> was known to Israelis as `` a bunch of killers,'' and their aim of destroying <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> has not changed. `` From our point of view, a snake wearing a jacket and tie is nothing but a well-dressed snake,'' he said. `` We shall not negotiate with these people because no one is expected to choose the method of his own execution.'' <PERSON> Binyamin </PERSON> <PERSON> Netanyahu </PERSON>, a former <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> ambassador and close associate of <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON>, said the decision was a `` terrible mistake.'' `` The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has breached its policy -LRB- of not talking to the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> -RRB- and the credibility of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has been compromised,'' said <PERSON> Netanyahu </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Likud </ORGANIZATION> bloc parliament member. `` The <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> government has been either duped or they are deceiving themselves. The American government will regret what they have done once they realize who they are dealing with,'' he said in a telephone interview. The <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> decision was welcomed, however, by a leading member of the liberal <ORGANIZATION> Citizens </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rights </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Movement </ORGANIZATION>, which was allied with the <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> in the Nov. 1 parliament elections. `` It's a great victory for American policy,'' said <PERSON> Ran </PERSON> <PERSON> Cohen </PERSON>, a parliament member of the small party. `` With this new success, we are at the beginning of the peace process.'' Wednesday's announcement in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> could upset sensitive negotiations under way between Labor and <ORGANIZATION> Likud </ORGANIZATION> over the formation of a new coalition government. <PERSON> Peres </PERSON> and <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON> have been bitterly divided on the peace issue, and their reactions to <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> speech in <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> on Tuesday showed they were also divided on the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON> earlier issued an uncompromising rejection of the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> and of <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON>'s peace bid, labeling the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> speech as double-talk. <PERSON> Peres </PERSON>, however, complimented <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON> for the peace bid by saying: `` He has learned to say peace, and I welcome this. He is learning.'' <PERSON> Peres </PERSON> also called for a peace dialogue with Palestinians `` immediately and without the Jordanians, if they so decide, as long as they do n't shoot.'' The Labor leader said, however, that <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON> should do more to end terrorism.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881214-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-14-88 2357EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-ScholarhipPrograms     12-14 0390</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Scholarhip Programs,0401</SECOND>
<HEAD>Students In Pioneering Scholarship Program Beat National Graduation
Rate</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By THOMAS J. SHEERAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CLEVELAND (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A pioneering private effort to help underprivileged students get college scholarships has achieved a graduation rate sharply above the national average, a study concluded. The 21-year-old, privately financed <ORGANIZATION> Cleveland </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Scholarship </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Programs </ORGANIZATION> released a study of its first two decades Wednesday showing 80 percent of those who got grants from the program and enrolled in four-year colleges graduated. Nationally, about 50 percent of students who start college receive their degrees, the program said. <ORGANIZATION> CSP </ORGANIZATION> has assisted more than 57,000 students, most from <LOCATION> Cleveland </LOCATION> public high schools, since its founding. Last year 3,700 students received specialized help applying for college admission and scholarships, and 540 underprivileged students received grants averaging $ 375. Under the program, counseling is available to all students but only students from underprivileged economic backgrounds can qualify for its direct grants. `` They really helped me a lot,'' said <PERSON> Dwight </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Newsom </PERSON>, 34, who graduated from <ORGANIZATION> Bowling </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Green </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> in 1976 and is now a sales executive with a concrete supply company. <PERSON> Newsom </PERSON>, the first member of his family to attend college, said <ORGANIZATION> CSP </ORGANIZATION> provided him with crucial help meeting an array of unfamiliar college admission and scholarship requirements and deadlines. `` As far as filling out paperwork, it was totally new for me,'' <PERSON> Newsom </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Christina </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Milano </PERSON>, the program's executive director, said the result of the survey showed that `` a private partnership can have a major impact on assisting economically disadvantaged students. ... They can go on to college and be very successful.'' <ORGANIZATION> CSP </ORGANIZATION> has 21 part-time counselers who visit high schools and meet with students to help them apply to college and seek financial assistance from various sources. Follow-up counseling continues through the campus years. The alumni study was conducted by <PERSON> Eugene </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Uyeki </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> Case </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Western </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reserve </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> among a random sample of 633 students out of the 8,205 who received direct <ORGANIZATION> CSP </ORGANIZATION> grants from 1967 to 1983. Eighty-five percent of those surveyed had average family incomes of less than $ 25,000 and more than half were the first family member to attend college. <ORGANIZATION> CSP </ORGANIZATION> calls itself the nation's oldest non-profit, privately supported college financial aid counseling service. It has been used as a model for similar programs in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> and other cities.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881214-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-14-88 0026EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-MascotDead     12-14 0201</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Mascot Dead,0206</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bill XXII is Dead; Long Live Bill XXVI</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ANNAPOLIS, Md. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> XXII </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> Naval </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION>'s mascot goat, has died. But the duty of goading the Midshipmen to victory on the football field wo n't go to <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> XXIII </PERSON>, Bill XXIV or Bill XXV. They're too ornery. <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> XXVI </PERSON>, who like his predecessors is a long-haired Angora goat, was named the mascot after <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> XXII </PERSON> was found dead Tuesday in his pen at the academy's dairy farm, said spokesman <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Kiser </PERSON>. Bill XXII had just about reached the end of his normal life expectancy and apparently died peacefully in his sleep, said <PERSON> Kiser </PERSON>, who did not know how old the goat was. `` I hope he rests in peace after faithful service since 1979,'' the academy spokesman aid. <PERSON> Kiser </PERSON> said Bills XXII-XXV were retired prematurely `` because of unfavorable dispositions.'' That means they were normal, ornery goats and did n't have the gentle disposition of Bill XXII or the new mascot, a youngster that is 12 to 18 months old. A goat became <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>'s mascot in 1893 when when <PERSON> El </PERSON> <PERSON> Cid </PERSON> was brought from the cruiser USS <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> for the fourth Army-Navy game. The Midshipmen won that one 6-4.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881214-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-14-88 0016EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Japan-Scandal 2ndLd-Writethru   12-14 0523</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Japan-Scandal, 2nd Ld-Writethru,a0412,0534</SECOND>
<HEAD>Chairman Of World's Largest Company Resigns In Stock Scandal</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDS: LEADS with five grafs to UPDATE with resignation. Pick up 6th
pvs, `The so-called...'</NOTE>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The chairman of <ORGANIZATION> Nippon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Telegraph </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Telephone </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, the world's biggest company, resigned Wednesday under fire for alleged involvement in a major business and political scandal. The minister of posts and telecommunications, <PERSON> Masaaki </PERSON> <PERSON> Nakayama </PERSON>, told a news conference he accepted the resignation of the company's chairman, <PERSON> Hisashi </PERSON> <PERSON> Shinto </PERSON> <PERSON> Nakayama </PERSON> said Shinto denied any personal involvement in unethical stock trading but accepted responsibility for actions by his personal secretary. Japanese press reports said prosecutors traced about $ 81,000 to Shinto's bank account from proceeds of the sale of shares in <ORGANIZATION> Recruit-Cosmos </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, a real-estate subsidiary of the Recruit conglomerate. Shinto on Tuesday issued a statement denying involvement in the share transaction and said it was carried out by his personal secretary, <PERSON> Kozo </PERSON> <PERSON> Murata </PERSON>, in 1986. <PERSON> Murata </PERSON> has since resigned as Shinto's aide. The so-called Recruit scandal last week brought the resignation of <PERSON> Kiichi </PERSON> <PERSON> Miyazawa </PERSON> as finance minister and deputy prime minister. It has rocked <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s business and political worlds with allegations that government figures bought Recruit stock at low prices and made huge profits when the company went public. The Recruit company allegedly sought favors by distributing shares in Recruit-Cosmos with a guarantee of easy, tax-free profits. <ORGANIZATION> Nippon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Telegraph </ORGANIZATION> and Telephone, ranked as the largest corporation in the world in terms of stock market capitalization, had business links with Recruit, which bought two U.S.-made supercomputers from the company and leased data communications circuits from it. As a former telecommunications monopoly, the company has been partially privatized, but Shinto and all other officials of the utility remain under regulations that it illegal for them to receive cash or shares from private firms that it does business with. Shinto has been the chief executive of the telecommunications giant since 1981 when it was still a government-owned monopoly. He oversaw the privatization, which started in 1985, and then took the title of president. He held that post until June this year, when he became chairman and chief executive, and the title of president went to <PERSON> Haruo </PERSON> <PERSON> Yamaguchi </PERSON>. Shinto's resignation would make him the most prominent victim in the business world of the Recruit scandal. It has also brought the resignation of news media executives and has broken several political careers in addition to that of <PERSON> Miyazawa </PERSON>, who a year ago was a major contender to be prime minister. Prime Minister <PERSON> Noboru </PERSON> <PERSON> Takeshita </PERSON> is on a list of prominent politicians whose aides profited from owning <ORGANIZATION> Recruit-Cosmos </ORGANIZATION> shares, but he and the others denied any knowledge or involvement in the transactions. Among the others are former Prime Minister <PERSON> Yasuhiro </PERSON> <PERSON> Nakasone </PERSON> and <PERSON> Shintaro </PERSON> <PERSON> Abe </PERSON>, secretary-general of the governing <ORGANIZATION> Liberal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>. The roots of the scandal go back to 1986, when unlisted <ORGANIZATION> Recruit-Cosmos </ORGANIZATION> shares were offered to the prominent figures or their aides, often to be paid for with loans from a Recruit-linked finance company. The shares were listed for sale over the counter in October 1986 and immediately skyrocketed in value, yielding tax-free profits when they were sold.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881214-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-14-88 0050EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-NewArms     12-14 0437</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-New Arms,0450</SECOND>
<HEAD>Learning to Use Mechanical Arms a Breeze for Boy</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhotos AQ1-2</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ALBUQUERQUE, N.M. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Before he was fitted with his new automated arms, 12-year-old <PERSON> Armando </PERSON> <PERSON> Gutierrez </PERSON> pulled on his shoes and socks with his teeth and wrote with his foot. Now, his new battery-powered arms are helping him learn to do everyday tasks in a more conventional way. `` It's easy. Nothing to it,'' said <PERSON> Armando </PERSON>, who lives in <LOCATION> Las </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Cruces </LOCATION>, about 180 miles south of <LOCATION> Albuquerque </LOCATION> and was born with arm stubs. <PERSON> Armando </PERSON>'s occupational therapist, <PERSON> Teresa </PERSON> <PERSON> Pollpeter </PERSON>, said the boy started using the mechanical arms correctly minutes after they were fitted on him Nov. 30 at <LOCATION> Carrie </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Tingley </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Albuquerque </LOCATION>. `` We put them on him one day, and he immediately started using them accurately,'' Ms. <PERSON> Pollpeter </PERSON> said Tuesday. `` He already had the muscle control mastered.'' Now all he has to do is work on improving his accuracy, she said. The arms flex up and down, and hooks open and close when <PERSON> Armando </PERSON> moves his shoulders a certain way. Thin cables attached to a switch on each arm make them move. Each arm weighs about 3 pounds and is strapped over <PERSON> Armando </PERSON>'s stubs and onto his shoulders with a small harness on his back Batteries power the arms during the day and are recharged at night, said <PERSON> Eloy </PERSON> <PERSON> Padilla </PERSON>, <PERSON> Armando </PERSON>'s prosthetist. <PERSON> Armando </PERSON> is the second child to be fitted with the $ 12,000 arms at the hospital. This particular line of prostheses has been available for four years. His last pair was not automated, and he had to push the forearms against an object to get them to lock in a bent position. Many things were easier by foot than by hand as a result. He wrote with his left foot, holding the pencil between his big toe and second toe, and he used to pull on his shoes and socks with his teeth. `` When I was 5, I saw my mom drop a fork and pick it up with her toes,'' he said. `` That's how I got the idea for -LRB- holding -RRB- the pencil. I only have four toes, so I put the pencil where the space is. It's easy.'' Ms. <PERSON> Pollpeter </PERSON> said eating with the new arms has been the priority for <PERSON> Armando </PERSON>. `` It's not totally acceptable to have your feet at the table, so this is really going to help him,'' she said. `` His parents like for him to use the prostheses. That's why we were eager for him to master that skill.'' He will work at home on the other tasks, such as getting dressed and writing, Ms. <PERSON> Pollpeter </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881214-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-14-88 0059EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Teen-AgeSex     12-14 0362</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Teen-Age Sex,0374</SECOND>
<HEAD>U.N. Report: American Teen-Agers Have Most Abortions In Developed
World</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PETER JAMES SPIELMANN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>UNITED NATIONS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 American teen-agers have the highest rate of abortion in the developed world, more than double that of teen-agers in most European countries, according to a new <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> report. The report released Tuesday by the world body's Population Division also found the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> to have the highest teen-age pregnancy rate, contrasting with declining rates in almost every other developed country. About 9.8 percent of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> females ranging in age from 15 to 19 are becoming pregnant on an annual basis, the highest rate among the nations studied. <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> ranked second at 8.5 percent. <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> was lowest overall at 1 percent. The <LOCATION> Netherlands </LOCATION> was lowest in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> at 1.2 percent, and most other European nations averaged about 3.5 percent. In the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, 4.4 percent of women in the age group studied had abortions on a yearly basis, compared with 2.7 percent in <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>, 0.5 percent in the <LOCATION> Netherlands </LOCATION> and 0.6 percent in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>. The report, entitled `` Adolescent Reproductive Behavior,'' deals only with developed nations. The pregnancy and abortion rates it cites represent the latest figures available for each country. `` Liberalization of abortion laws does not always bring about an increase in abortion rates,'' the report says. `` In <LOCATION> Sweden </LOCATION>, a liberalization of the laws in 1975 brought about only a small increase in rates.'' `` The one outstanding characteristic of teen-agers requesting abortion is that the majority of them are unmarried,'' the report found. `` The option to carry a pregnancy to term is becoming less and less popular among pregnant teen-agers,'' the report says. `` The proportion of pregnancies that end in abortion has increased since the early 1970s.'' Examining other sexual trends, the report found that cohabitation has gained popularity among European men and women of all ages. `` In the past, couples frequently lived together for short periods before marriage, but such unions have become more and more common and may or may not result in marriage,'' it says. The survey covered <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION> and <LOCATION> Western </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Zealand </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881214-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-14-88 0102EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-US-Arafat Bjt   12-14 0684</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-US-Arafat, Bjt,680</SECOND>
<HEAD>Secret Diplomacy Ends In Surprising Disappointment</HEAD>
<BYLINE>An AP New Analysis</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>By BARRY SCHWEID</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Diplomatic Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Even while denying <PERSON> Yasser </PERSON> <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON> a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> visa, the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> tried through public and private diplomacy to induce the <ORGANIZATION> Palestine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> to renounce terrorism in all forms and explicitly recognize <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s right to exist. The prize held out to <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON> was a `` substantive dialogue'' with the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, a major step toward <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> acceptance of the <LOCATION> Palestinian </LOCATION> leader who only two weeks ago had been condemned by Secretary of State <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> as an `` accessory'' to acts of terrorism. With <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON> already accepted by a number of West European governments, an end to <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> diplomatic isolation would have strengthened his hand in the Palestinian conflict with <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> and assured him a voice in any <LOCATION> Mideast </LOCATION> negotiations. But <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials declared that the speech <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON> delivered to the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> on Tuesday failed to meet the three <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> conditions for <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> acceptance. Diplomatic sources said the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> was so sure that <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON> would satisfy the demands, <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> had notified <PERSON> Moshe </PERSON> <PERSON> Arad </PERSON>, the <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> ambassador, on Monday night that if the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> leader followed through, the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> was prepared to hold the dialogue <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON> had long sought. <LOCATION> Sweden </LOCATION> had acted as an intermediary over the past few weeks, relaying the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> conditions and receiving in return what was taken as advance word on what <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON> would say. In the end, though, <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Redman </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> spokesman, credited <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON> only with `` some interesting and positive developments'' and said the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> leader had failed to meet the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> requirements. These include explicit acceptance of <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s right to exist and renunciation of terrorism in all forms. The third requirement is approval of <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> resolutions affirming that all Middle Eastern states are entitled to live within secure borders. On the third point, the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> found some significant movement by <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON>. Last month, the <ORGANIZATION> Palestine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>, the would-be parliament of the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION>, merely said a peace conference could be held under the 1967 and 1973 resolutions. Still, <PERSON> Redman </PERSON> said, `` These issues must be addressed clearly, squarely and without ambiguity. That did not happen.'' President-elect <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said, meanwhile, that his administration will not meet with the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> based on what <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON> said in <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION>. `` We've got to get a much clearer statement of everything,'' he said. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> policy prohibits negotiations with the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION>, which is committed by covenant to dismantling <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> as a Jewish state. As a result, diplomatic sources said, `` pieces of paper'' were exchanged through <LOCATION> Sweden </LOCATION>, a neutralist country which has taken a sympathetic stance toward the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> and hosted a meeting of a handful of American Jews with <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON> after <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> barred him from speaking to the <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>. Asked if the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> had suggested language for <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON> to use in his speech, <PERSON> Redman </PERSON> replied: `` What we have done is to respond to requests from third parties, people who said, ` Would you provide us, tell us in specific terms, exactly what your position is, what your conditions are?' And that, of course, we are happy to do.'' Referring to the way <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON> dealt with the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> conditions in the speech, <PERSON> Redman </PERSON> said there were `` problems with all three.'' The spokesman called the `` overall tone'' of the speech positive and said the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> saw `` some movement'' by <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON> on the two <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> resolutions, but he did not elaborate. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Zogby </PERSON>, executive director of the <ORGANIZATION> Arab </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION>, said <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON> had met the three <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> conditions. He called <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> rejection of <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON>'s speech `` gratuitous,'' and said it was based more on <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON>'s `` stubborn pro-Israel reflex than on sound diplomacy.'' <PERSON> Geoffrey </PERSON> <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON>, a senior associate at the <ORGANIZATION> Carnegie </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Endowment </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Peace </ORGANIZATION>, said <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON> is `` inching along.'' But <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON>, who served on the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> in the first <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration, said, `` The problem is he is not declaring <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> has a right to exist.''
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Barry </PERSON> <PERSON> Schweid </PERSON> is the chief diplomatic writer for <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881214-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-14-88 0116EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-CabinetLag Bjt   12-14 0773</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Cabinet Lag, Bjt,770</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHINGTON TODAY: Slowdown In Bush Appointments Concerns Even Some
Supporters</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TOM RAUM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 After a quick start, President-elect <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> is falling behind the pace set by his predecessors in filling the Cabinet, causing consternation among even some of his loyalists. He once boasted about how swiftly he was naming his team in comparison with other recent presidents, but <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> now has fallen behind Presidents <PERSON> Eisenhower </PERSON> and <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON>, who had their Cabinet selections completed by this point in their transitions. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> transition sources said the president-elect will announce as early as today that he wants Trade Representative <PERSON> Clayton </PERSON> <PERSON> Yeutter </PERSON> to be his agriculture secretary and that he has chosen <PERSON> Samuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Skinner </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> to head the <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>. Even so, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> will still fall behind President <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> if he has n't filled his Cabinet by Saturday; behind President <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> if he is n't done by next Friday. Among the snags: _ A long delay in completion of the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION>'s investigation into the background of former Sen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Tower </PERSON> may have seriously weakened Tower's prospects for <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> confirmation even if he is, as expected, ultimately appointed defense secretary _ The inability of <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s transition team to come up with a suitable job for former <ORGANIZATION> Transporation </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> has left the wife of <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Republican Leader <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> awkwardly hanging _ The contention of <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s vice presidential chief-of-staff <PERSON> Craig </PERSON> <PERSON> Fuller </PERSON> that no current member of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> will be appointed to the Cabinet, so as not to thin <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> ranks in the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, has infuriated more than a few <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> lawmakers, according to sources Transition and congressional <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> sources said that the edict appeared aimed at softening the blow of a no-job-offer to Rep. <PERSON> Lynn </PERSON> <PERSON> Martin </PERSON>, R-Ill., a vigorous political supporter of the vice president from the early days of his campaign If so, it may have been a case of overkill, taking along a dozen or so other <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> lawmakers who had figured prominently in recent Cabinet speculation. With a lopsided Democratic majority of 259 to 175 in the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, one or two fewer Republicans would n't have made all that much difference. The move had echoes of an announcement on July 30, 1964, by President <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> that ended widespread speculation that he would name then-Attorney General <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> to be his vice presidential running mate in the coming presidential election. At a hastily arranged television appearance, <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> said that members of his <ORGANIZATION> Cabinet </ORGANIZATION> were too valuable to him and that it would be `` inadvisable to select any member of my Cabinet'' as his running mate. <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, who resigned later that summer after winning the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> nominination, accepted <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>'s rationale philosophically but responded that he was sorry he had to take so many good men overboard with him. In a recent interview, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Sununu </PERSON>, whom <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has picked to be his presidential chief of staff, defended the delays and blamed them on the necessity of conducting thorough and meticulous background checks on each candidate for a Cabinet job. However, <PERSON> Sununu </PERSON> conceded, `` You always wish things could go faster.'' He said delays were inevitable `` as we get more and more people to be reviewed and more and more -LRB- of a -RRB- stretching resources thin.'' Little more than a week after the election, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> boasted to reporters that he was off to a quick start compared to predecessors dating back to <PERSON> Eisenhower </PERSON>. At that time, he had already designated four members of his Cabinet _ secretaries of <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION>, Education and an attorney general and had picked a chief of staff. At a similar point in mid-November after their elections to the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, former Presidents <PERSON> Eisenhower </PERSON>, <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON>, and <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> and President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> had not even begun to name Cabinet choices, according to a breakdown provided by the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> transition office and cited by <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> in his conversation with reporters. Since then, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> also has designated a national security adviser, a press secretary, a trade representative, a <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> chief, a <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> ambassador, a chief economist and a secretary of <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION>. Still, he has already dropped behind <PERSON> Dwight </PERSON> <PERSON> Eisenhower </PERSON>, who finished his Cabinet by Dec. 1, 1952, and <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON>, who completed his choices by Dec. 11, 1968. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> had his entire Cabinet announced by Dec. 17; <PERSON> Jimmy </PERSON> <PERSON> Carter </PERSON>, by Dec. 23, 1976. <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, by contrast, did n't have his Cabinet selection completed until Jan. 1, 1980 Congressional sources, who spoke on the condition of anonymity, said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s delay in naming a defense secretary, and his treatment of Mrs. <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> and Mrs. <PERSON> Martin </PERSON>, had dispirited some of <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s most faithful loyalists on <LOCATION> Capitol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881214-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-14-88 0122EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-ColliderAnts Bjt   12-14 0467</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Collider Ants, Bjt,460</SECOND>
<HEAD>$4.4 Billion Research Center Threatened by Ants</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JENNIFER DIXON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Researchers who hope to study the secrets of nature at the government's planned $ 4.4 billion super collider may first need protection from a venomous ant with a penchant for munching its way through underground cables. A 10,000-page environmental impact statement on the project says the <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> site chosen by the <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> for the research center is in an area infested with the fire ant. The ill-tempered ant inflicts painful bites, is blamed by local residents for disabling home and farm equipment, and has caused power failures by chewing through underground cables, the department reports. Plans call for the super collider to be built in a 53-mile tunnel under what is now farmland in <LOCATION> Ellis </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>. Subatomic particles will be accelerated to astronomical speeds inside the tunnel and studied by scientists hoping to learn more about the fundamental nature of matter and energy. Scientists, however, have yet to find a way to eradicate the fire ant. The Energy Department says special attention will have to be paid at the super collider site to the design of electrical facilities and other underground components; construction practices to protect workers from the ant's painful sting; and development of an environmentally sound pesticide policy. Texans who commented on the super collider project to the <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> said fire ants `` routinely tunnel to water table depths in search of water, chewing their way through underground cables and insulation around wiring en route,'' the impact statement said. `` Fire ants appear to be attracted to electrical equipment and can cause shorts by chewing through insulation and by crowding into spaces around electrical contacts,'' the study said. The study said local utility companies and highway departments have reported problems with damage caused by the ants. Thirty years of study by federal and state agriculture officials still has not yielded an effective method of eradicating the ant, only control procedures, the study said. A <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> representative told the <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> that the control programs were only 80 percent effective. Fire ants also pose a health risk since their bite is painful and can sometimes lead to serious reactions in humans, the study said. For most people, a sting results in swelling, pain and itching that lasts a week, the study said. For others, immediate medical attention may be needed, especially for a few victims so sensitive to the ants' venom they go into shock. The final environmental impact statement examined all seven sites that had been in contention for the super collider, incorporating 6,000 pages of comments and letters received after the draft statement was released in August. The Energy Department announced in November it would locate the project in <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881214-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-14-88 0123EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Nicaraguans-Asylum     12-14 0493</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nicaraguans-Asylum,520</SECOND>
<HEAD>INS Plan Called Attack on Asylum for Central Americans</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PETE YOST</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An attorney for a legal rights group says the government's proposals on Nicaraguan asylum-seekers constitute a broad attack on asylum for Central Americans. The <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Immigration </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Naturalization </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> proposals could sharply reduce Nicaraguans' chances of obtaining work permits while they await decisions on asylum applications. If implemented fully, the draft <ORGANIZATION> INS </ORGANIZATION> proposals also could result in detention for Central Americans whose asylum applications are rejected and who are awaiting final decisions on deportation. `` I regard this as a broad attack on asylum,'' <PERSON> Arthur </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Helton </PERSON>, director of the political asylum project of the <ORGANIZATION> Lawyers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Human </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rights </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, said Tuesday. `` The first victims are the Nicaraguans in south <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> who are to be deprived of the opportunity to subsist. But tens of thousands of other asylum applicants will face unnecessary hardship on account of these measures.'' He said that while `` the immediate inspiration'' for the proposals is a huge increase in Nicaraguans seeking asylum who have come across the border in <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, `` this is not a measure solely attributable to the arrival of Nicaraguans.'' Asylum applications from Salvadorans rose from 2,700 in fiscal 1987 to more than 27,000 for fiscal 1988, which ended Sept. 30. Immigration officials acknowledged that the proposals would apply to other Central American asylum seekers as well as to Nicaraguans. But they denied they are trying to discourage the filing of legitimate asylum claims by Central Americans who have a well-founded fear of persecution in their homeland. `` We have to have an orderly immigration system,'' said immigration commissioner <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON> said. `` We want those with legitimate claims to immigrate and get them approved, but we must avoid abuses, and we're seeing evidence of that in south <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>.'' <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON> said that in <LOCATION> Harlingen </LOCATION>, salesmen are offering phony packets of asylum documents to Nicaraguans and other Central Americans. Nicaraguans are particularly upset over the proposals because work permits would be withheld until after immigration officers make a determination of whether the asylum claim is legitimate. Under a July 1987 directive from then-Attorney General <PERSON> Edwin </PERSON> <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>, Nicaraguans in most instances were automatically granted permits allowing them to work here legally while their asylum requests were pending. The backlog of cases has risen steadily since then and <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON> said the agency is increasing efforts to review some 22,000 pending asylum claims from Nicaraguans, starting with the most recent applicants. Canceling work permits issued to Nicaraguans or not issuing work permits to new asylum applicants wo n't stop the influx of Nicaraguans into the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, said <PERSON> Roberto </PERSON> <PERSON> Arguello </PERSON>, chairman of the public relations committee of the <ORGANIZATION> Nicaraguan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bankers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> INS </ORGANIZATION> steps are `` not going to stop people from coming,'' agreed <PERSON> Maritza </PERSON> <PERSON> Herrera </PERSON>, executive director of the <ORGANIZATION> Nicaraguan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION>. `` They come here and they're going to stay in the underground economy, underpaid.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881214-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-14-88 0127EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Nielsens     12-14 0354</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nielsens,0366</SECOND>
<HEAD>The Bottom Is Falling</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KATHRYN BAKER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Television Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The bottom is falling out of the weekly <ORGANIZATION> A.C. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nielsen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> prime-time listings now that <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> has dropped five of last week's 10 lowest-rated shows. Gone from the schedule are `` <PERSON> Annie </PERSON> <PERSON> McGuire </PERSON>,'' `` The <PERSON> Van </PERSON> <PERSON> Dyke </PERSON> Show,'' `` Raising Miranda,'' `` Dirty Dancing'' and `` <ORGANIZATION> Simon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> Simon </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> announced Tuesday. At the other end, a repeat of <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Night Court'' returned to Thursday night for a week and was the No. 1 show last week. Its regular time period this season is Wednesday. The new show, `` Dear <PERSON> John </PERSON>,'' was taking a night off. The rest of the top 10 were: <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` The Cosby Show,'' `` Cheers,'' `` A Different World'' and `` Golden Girls,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Roseanne,'' CBS' `` 60 Minutes,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Who's the Boss? and <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` L.A. Law'' and `` Empty Nest.'' Some of the shine appeared to be off <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Moonlighting.'' Its season premiere ranked 13th, compared with last season's premiere at fifth. Another <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> season premiere, `` thirtysomething,'' ranked only 29th. On Sunday, <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> ran the network premiere of the film `` Spies Like Us'' against <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Roots: The Gift'' and came out at 17th to `` Roots''' 25th. <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> won the week for the 25th straight time. Its average, prime-time rating was 15.1; <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> had 13.2; CBS 10.7. The news race was a virtual tie with less than half a rating point separating the three broadcasts. The `` CBS Evening News'' edged the others with an 11.2 rating. `` ABC World News Tonight'' had a 10.9. `` NBC Nightly News'' had a 10.8. Each rating point represents 904,000 households with television. The lowest-rated prime-time shows last week were: <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s analysis of President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s news conference, `` <ORGANIZATION> Simon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> Simon </PERSON>,'' `` <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON>'s Law,'' `` West 57th,'' `` Dirty Dancing,'' `` TV 101,'' `` Knightwatch,'' `` Raising Miranda,'' `` The <PERSON> Van </PERSON> <PERSON> Dyke </PERSON> Show'' and `` <PERSON> Annie </PERSON> <PERSON> McGuire </PERSON>. <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> canceled `` Van Dyke'' and `` Raising Miranda.'' `` Dirty Dancing'' was put `` on hiatus.'' <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Tyler </PERSON> <PERSON> Moore </PERSON>'s `` <PERSON> Annie </PERSON> <PERSON> McGuire </PERSON>'' and `` <ORGANIZATION> Simon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; Simon'' were removed from the schedule but might return. <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> said it would move `` TV 101'' from Tuesday to Wednesday night. <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> already has canceled another of the bottom 10, `` Knightwatch.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881214-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-14-88 0128EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-NielsensList     12-14 0576</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nielsens List,0656</SECOND>
<HEAD>List of Week's Top-Rated TV Shows</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Year-to-date rankings not available.</NOTE>
<HEAD>With PM-Nielsens</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the prime-time television ratings as compiled by the <ORGANIZATION> A.C. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nielsen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> for the week of Dec. 5-11. Top 20 listings include the week's ranking, rating for the week, and total homes. A rating measures the percentage of the nation's 90.4 million TV homes. 1. `` Night Court Special,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 23.9 rating, 21.6 million homes. 2. `` The Cosby Show,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 23.8, 21.5 million homes. 3. `` Cheers,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 23.7, 21.4 million homes. 4. `` A Different World,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 23.2, 21.0 million homes. 5. `` Golden Girls,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 22.2, 20.1 million homes. 6. `` Roseanne,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 22.0, 19.9 million homes. 7. `` 60 Minutes,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 20.9, 18.9 million homes. 8. `` Who's the Boss?'', <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 20.3, 18.4 million homes. 9. `` <LOCATION> L.A. </LOCATION> Law,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 19.4, 17.5 million homes. 10. `` Empty Nest,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 19.2, 17.4 million homes. 11. `` NFL Monday Night Football: <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> vs. <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 18.5, 16.7 million homes. 12. `` Growing Pains,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 18.0, 16.3 million homes. 13. `` Moonlighting,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 17.9, 16.2 million homes. 14. `` <PERSON> Hunter </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 17.5, 15.8 million homes. 14. `` Head of the Class,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 17.5, 15.8 million homes. 16. `` Maybe Baby'' _ `` <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> Monday Night Movies,'' 17.2, 15.5 million homes. 17. `` Spies Like Us'' _ `` NBC Sunday Night Movie,'' 17.1, 15.4 million homes. 17. `` Rudolph the Red-Nosed Reindeer,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 17.1, 15.4 million homes. 19. `` Heat of the Night,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 16.8, 15.2 million homes. 20. `` Matlock,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 16.6, 15.0 million homes.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 21. `` Amen,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 16.3. 22. `` Family Ties,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 16.2. 23. `` Wonder Years'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 15.7. 24. `` ALF,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 15.5. 25. `` 227,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 15.4. 25. `` Roots: The Gift'' _ `` <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> Sunday Night Movie,'' 15.4. 27. `` Full House,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 15.2. 27. `` <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION>,'' CBS, 15.2. 29. `` thirtysomething,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 14.7. 30. `` Kate & amp; <PERSON> Allie </PERSON> <PERSON> Special </PERSON>,'' CBS, 14.5. 31. `` The <PERSON> Hogan </PERSON> Family,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 14.3. 32. `` Knots Landing,'' CBS, 14.0. 32. `` Murphy Brown Special,'' CBS, 14.0. 34. `` Perfect Strangers,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.7. 34. `` Midnight Caller,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.7. 34. `` Day By Day,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.7. 37. `` <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>,'' CBS, 13.6. 38. `` 20-20,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.4. 39. `` Hooperman,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.0. 40. `` Designing Women,'' CBS, 12.8. 41. `` Falcon Crest,'' CBS, 12.7. 41. `` Mission: Impossible,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.7. 43. `` <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION>,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.3. 44. `` Mr. <PERSON> Belvedere </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.8. 44. `` Highway to Heaven Special,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.8. 46. `` Miami Vice,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.7. 46. `` MacGyver,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.7. 48. `` Wiseguy,'' CBS, 11.6. 48. `` Tricks of the Trade'' _ `` CBS Tuesday Movie,'' 11.6. 50. `` Just the Ten of Us,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.4. 51. `` Glory Days'' _ `` CBS Sunday Movie,'' 11.1. 52. `` Dynasty,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 9.7. 53. `` Magical World of Disney,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 9.6. 54. `` Incredible Sunday,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 9.5. 55. `` Beauty and the Beast,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 9.1. 56. `` Almost Grown,'' CBS, 8.7. 57. `` Battle of the <ORGANIZATION> Network </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Stars </ORGANIZATION>,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 8.5. 57. `` <PERSON> Sonny </PERSON> <PERSON> Spoon </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 8.5. 57. `` Paradise,'' CBS, 8.5. 60. `` <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s Most Wanted,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 8.4. 61. `` 48 Hours: <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>,'' CBS, 8.2. 61. `` Married ... With Children,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 8.2. 63. `` Something Is Out There,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 8.1. 64. `` The Equalizer,'' CBS, 7.7. 65. `` Tattinger's,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 7.5. 66. `` <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> Press Conference Analysis,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 7.0. 67. `` <ORGANIZATION> Simon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> Simon </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 6.8. 67. `` <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON>'s Law,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 6.8. 67. `` 21 Jump Street,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 6.8. 70. `` West 57th,'' CBS, 6.7. 71. `` Dirty Dancing,'' CBS, 6.0. 71. `` Knightwatch,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 6.0. 71. `` TV 101,'' CBS, 6.0. 74. `` Rock & amp; Roll Christmas Special,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 5.8. 75. `` Raising Miranda,'' CBS, 5.5. 76. `` Duet,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 4.8. 77. `` <PERSON> Van </PERSON> <PERSON> Dyke </PERSON> Show,'' CBS, 4.7. 78. `` <PERSON> Annie </PERSON> <PERSON> McGuire </PERSON>,'' CBS, 4.4. 79. `` The Reporters,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 4.3. 80. `` Beyond Tomorrow,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 2.9.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881214-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-14-88 0037EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-HighwayKillings 1stLd-Writethru a0421 12-14 0282</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Highway Killings, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0421,0283</SECOND>
<HEAD>Man Arrested In Highway Kidnapping In Area Where Six Bodies Found</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: SUBS last graf pvs with 3 grafs to add further detail. Should
stand for AMs</NOTE>
<DATELINE>NEW BEDFORD, Mass. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 State police arrested a 35-year-old New Bedford man Tuesday and accused of kidnapping and raping a woman along Interstate 195 in the same area where six bodies have been found since July. <PERSON> Raymond </PERSON> <PERSON> Veary </PERSON>, an assistant district attorney in <LOCATION> Bristol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, declined to comment on a report by <ORGANIZATION> WBZ-TV </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> that the man was a suspect in the killings as well. <PERSON> Veary </PERSON> said the man, <PERSON> Neil </PERSON> <PERSON> Andersen </PERSON>, was scheduled for arraignment Wednesday morning in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bedford </LOCATION> <LOCATION> District </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Court </LOCATION> on charges of kidnapping and aggravated assault stemming from an incident in August 1987 along Interstate 195 in the town of <LOCATION> Dartmouth </LOCATION>. The television station reported that the victim was a former prostitute, but <PERSON> Veary </PERSON> declined to confirm or deny the report. State police officers attached to the <LOCATION> Bristol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> district attorney's office made the arrest at 4:30 p.m., <PERSON> Veary </PERSON> said. The partially clad skeletons of the six women were found within a few miles of each other along I-95 and Route 140 in <LOCATION> Dartmouth </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Freetown </LOCATION>. Just three of the bodies have been identified. The most recent discovery of a body occurred Saturday. Police say the woman apparently had been dead since spring, longer than the other five victims. District Attorney <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Pina </PERSON> has said he believed the six killings were likely the victims of the same killer or killers. He said it is believed the victims had ties to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bedford </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Weld </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Square </LOCATION> neighborhood, known for prostitution and drugs.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881214-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-14-88 0129EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w WildlifeServiceUncoversViolationsAmongTexasOperations 
   12-14 0498</FIRST>
<SECOND>Wildlife Service Uncovers Violations Among Texas Operations</SECOND>
<BYLINE>By JENNIFER DIXON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Undercover wildlife agents have found `` flagrant'' poaching violations and `` unsporting practices'' by waterfowl hunting businesses along the <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> coast that led to charges against 210 people in seven states. The poaching violations come at a time when duck populations are already hurt by an eight-year drought in their breeding grounds. `` Duck numbers already are near record lows because of the drought and continued destruction of their natural habitat,'' said <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Dunkle </PERSON>, director of the <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. Fish and <ORGANIZATION> Wildlife </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>. `` They can not long withstand additional losses from illegal harvest.'' More than 100 wildlife service agents spent three years in an undercover investigation of 41 commercial waterfowl hunting businesses on the <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> coast, documenting more than 1,300 violations in one of the agency's biggest operations, officials said. `` During this investigation, service agents reported flagrant violations of laws intended to protect waterfowl,'' <PERSON> Dunkle </PERSON> said Tuesday. `` Law-abiding waterfowlers are outraged by these unethical and unsporting practices that betray total lack of concern for the status of waterfowl populations.'' Agents from around the country went undercover to book hunts with guides and owners of hunting businesses charging $ 65 to 500 a day who were suspected of killing waterfowl illegally and encouraging and helping customers to do likewise. Alleged violations occurred on 92 percent of the hunts, the service said. The agency said 23 hunting guides and owners were being arrested, 22 of them in <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> and one in <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>. Indictments or charges contained in a federal document named 50 others, and 137 people were to receive misdemeanor notices of violation in <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION>. Charges include shooting more than the legal limit; `` rallying,'' or stirring up waterfowl to drive them toward hunters; use of lead shot in steel shot zones; failure to retrieve shot fowl _ wanton waste; use of electronic calls; taking birds after the season has closed or outside legal hunting hours; and tagging and record-keeping violations, such as claiming birds belonged to someone who had not hunted that day, or falsifying when birds were shot. In several cases, the service said raptors, herons, ibises and other non-game migratory birds were allegedly killed and sold to undercover agents. Agents documented one case in which a dozen hunters in blinds around a pond shot as many geese as they could, killing more than 200 birds _ 139 over their limit. Wildlife service spokeswoman <PERSON> Megan </PERSON> <PERSON> Durham </PERSON> said the agents went undercover because the violations were occurring `` behind locked gates and in remote areas and it's difficult to get information any other way.'' Maximum penalties for the misdemeanors could be six months to one year in prison, and fines of $ 5,000 to $ 100,000 for individuals and $ 10,000 to $ 200,000 for organizations, depending on the charge. Maximum penalties for felony violations could be two to five years in prison and fines of $ 250,000 for individuals and $ 500,000 for organizations, depending on the charge.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881214-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-14-88 0129EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-US-SovietVentures     12-14 0530</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-US-Soviet Ventures,530</SECOND>
<HEAD>Director of U.S.-Soviet Effort Sees More Liberal Joint Venture
Arrangements</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID BRISCOE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A director of a new U.S.-Soviet effort to help <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> businesses sell everything from cosmetics to caviar in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> says he expects <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> to relax its limits on foreign ownership of companies early next year. Current Soviet law requires that joint business ventures be no more than 49 percent foreign owned, but <PERSON> Randy </PERSON> <PERSON> Bregman </PERSON> of Washington-based <ORGANIZATION> APCO </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associates </ORGANIZATION> said he expects this to be liberalized, possibly within the first three months of 1989. <ORGANIZATION> APCO </ORGANIZATION> is an affiliate of the law firm of <ORGANIZATION> Arnold </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <LOCATION> Porter </LOCATION>, which held a news conference Tuesday to announce that <ORGANIZATION> APCO </ORGANIZATION> had set up a joint venture with <LOCATION> INFEKS </LOCATION>, a six-month-old Soviet consulting cooperative affiliated with the <ORGANIZATION> U.S.S.R. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Relations </ORGANIZATION>. New Soviet efforts to open and restructure the country's economy offer `` access to a market of 280 million highly educated Soviet consumers with an enormous need for goods and technology,'' said <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>, the firm's managing partner. He said Soviet President <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s policies are `` setting an exciting new course for East-West business relationships.'' <PERSON> Bregman </PERSON>, director of Soviet and East European services for <ORGANIZATION> APCO </ORGANIZATION>, said the new venture will help <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> businesses set up joint operations with Soviet cooperatives and other enterprises. Speaking before a Soviet and <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> flag and with a direct telephone hookup to <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>, officials said the partners in the venture would draw up final details and meet with prospective clients later this week. <PERSON> Bregman </PERSON> said <ORGANIZATION> APCO </ORGANIZATION> hopes to double the number of U.S.-Soviet ventures by the end of next year. Ten joint U.S.-Soviet business agreements have been concluded to date, along with about 100 Soviet ventures with businesses from other countries, he said. <PERSON> Bregman </PERSON> said he looks to the day when a Soviet citizen can buy borscht made by <ORGANIZATION> Campbell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Soup </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co </ORGANIZATION>. He said <PERSON> Campbell </PERSON> is not one of the companies now involved, but this is an example of the kind of enterprise that might result from the new agreement. <PERSON> Bregman </PERSON> declined to name companies that might deal with the Soviets through <ORGANIZATION> APCO </ORGANIZATION>, but he said they include about a dozen companies involved in food processing, pollution control, medical equipment, cosmetics, tourism and telecommunications. One <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> company even wants to get into caviar production, he said. <PERSON> Vladimir </PERSON> <PERSON> Gusinsky </PERSON>, INFEKS president, said from <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> that the Soviet enterprise is part of the economic `` perestroika,'' or restructuring, under way in his country. `` We are looking forward to developing economic relations with <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> companies,'' <PERSON> Gusinsky </PERSON> said through a translator who also translated the <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> news conference in Russian over the telephone hookup. <PERSON> Gusinsky </PERSON> and other INFEKS officials were to arrive in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> later this week. <ORGANIZATION> APCO </ORGANIZATION> President <PERSON> Margery </PERSON> <PERSON> Kraus </PERSON> said the company, which also has set up joint ventures with Japanese and <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> businesses, would open an office in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> early next year. She said the company would provide `` one-stop shopping'' for companies wanting to do business in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, charging fees for its services. She said there were no plans for <ORGANIZATION> APCO </ORGANIZATION> to share in profits of the joint ventures it helps set up.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881214-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-14-88 0130EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-GroundWater-Pesticides     12-14 0451</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Ground Water-Pesticides,450</SECOND>
<HEAD>EPA Says Farming Responsible For Much Ground Water Pollution</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GUY DARST</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> says ground water has been contaminated by pesticides in parts of 38 states, but it cautions that more study is needed before the full extent of such pollution can be determined. The agency said Tuesday a review of 150 ground water studies over the past 10 years found 74 different chemicals in 38 states. Similar findings had been announced by advocacy groups using <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> documents obtained under the Freedom of Information Act. The EPA has added new information: Farming has put 46 chemicals in the ground water of 26 states and 32 chemicals got into ground water in 12 states because of `` point source'' pollution, such as an accidental spill. Unknown sources account for 28 chemicals in 12 states, not necessarily the same 12 involved in point-source contamination. `` There are dangers'' in trying to draw national conclusions from the data, which are `` not appropriate for assessing human exposure,'' said <PERSON> Victor </PERSON> <PERSON> Kimm </PERSON>, acting assistant administrator in charge of pesticides. `` Many agricultural areas have not been sampled and are not statistically represented,'' he said. The studies sampled shallow sampling wells and aquifers used for irrigation in addition to drinking water. The agency said concentrations generally were below its `` health advisory'' levels for drinking water, but some were not. EPA is in the process of sampling 1,300 drinking water wells nationwide to check for 125 different chemicals according to a statistically based scheme that should yield national conclusions in late 1989 or early 1990. The studies responsible for Tuesday's findings were conducted by government agencies, universities and holders of pesticide licenses, and <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> said it was still interviewing the authors to check the validity of their work. <PERSON> Diane </PERSON> <PERSON> Baxter </PERSON>, staff scientist of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coalition </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Against </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> the </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Misuse </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pesticides </ORGANIZATION>, said she was not surprised by <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION>'s findings `` This is the tip of the iceberg. As more samples are taken, we are going to find more instances of contamination.'' <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> McCarthy </PERSON>, vice president for science and regulatory affairs at the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agricultural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chemicals </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, a pesticide manufacturers' trade group, agreed that the results were not appropriate for assessing human exposure, and said `` <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION>'s current sampling is the kind of information we will look to as to whether there's a health issue.'' Until 1979, pesticides had been thought not to get into ground water, but to remain bound to soil. Since then, concern has risen as more and more contamination has been found. When <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> announced a proposed pesticides-in-ground water strategy in February, it said it knew of 19 pesticides from farming in the ground water of 24 states.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881214-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-14-88 0132EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-S&amp;Ls     12-14 0692</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-S&amp;Ls,690</SECOND>
<HEAD>Economists Say Thrifts Threatened By Rising Money Costs</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVE SKIDMORE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Rising interest rates threaten to end a recent letup in losses by savings institutions, some economists say. According to the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Home </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Loan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION>, losses for the nation's 3,024 <ORGANIZATION> S </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; Ls had dropped to $ 1.6 billion in the July-September period, down from $ 3.9 billion in both the first and second quarters. Most of the improvement came in non-operating losses _ meaning institutions wrote off fewer bad loans. They dropped from $ 3.6 billion in the second quarter to $ 1.4 billion in the third. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Barth </PERSON>, chief economist of the bank board, declined to predict non-operating losses in the current October-December quarter, but he said operating profits, which rose in the third quarter, will be hurt because of rising interest rates this quarter. Rising interest rates narrow the spread between what an institution has to pay for its money and what it can earn on loans and other investments. `` Interest rates do not bode well for the future,'' said <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Regalia </PERSON>, chief economist of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Savings </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institutions </ORGANIZATION>, a trade group. The bank board released the loss figures for the third quarter two weeks ago. On Tuesday, in a more detailed report, it said the number of insolvent savings institutions continued to fall. But, it said, even as government rescues soared, other institutions were slipping. The bank board said 434 S & amp; Ls were insolvent at the end of September, down from 498 three months earlier and substantially lower from the peak of 520 at the end of last year. However, regulators had to `` resolve'' the cases of 129 insolvent institutions _ either through rescues or closures _ to whittle down the insolvent list by 86 over the first nine months of the year. That means 43 other institutions slipped into the red. In the third quarter, an additional 150 institutions were on the edge of insolvency, with capital levels between zero and 1.5 percent. Losses for the first nine months _ $ 9.4 billion _ already surpass last year's post-Depression record of $ 7.8 billion. As in the past, the losses were heavily concentrated in <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> and in just a few institutions in the third quarter. The 244 <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> thrifts _ 114 of them insolvent _ reported losses of $ 1.7 billion. All thrifts outside of <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> managed a modest gain of $ 45 million. The worst 20 institutions _ 14 of them in <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> _ lost $ 1.3 billion. `` It may be misconstruing it to say, ` Hey, we're coming out of the woods.' These numbers say, ` Hey, you're still losing a lot of money.' ... It's nothing to get euphoric over,'' Regalia said. `` The hole is still bigger, it's just not getting bigger as fast. You can take some solace in that. I just would n't take too much solace,'' he said. <PERSON> Barth </PERSON> said the quarterly loss would have been $ 2 billion without the government actions, still a substantial improvement. But, <PERSON> Bert </PERSON> <PERSON> Ely </PERSON>, an analyst in <LOCATION> Alexandria </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, said a large portion of the industry's operating income is coming from a flow of assistance income to restructured institutions. <PERSON> Ely </PERSON> said the bank board made assistance payments of $ 528 million in the third quarter, up from $ 466 million in the second quarter. Payments on government promissory notes were $ 948 million, up from $ 101 million, he said. `` There's a substantial amount of income support coming in. ... It is adding to income level, it is adding to the bottom line,'' he said. All three economists expressed concern about the effect of rising interest rates on thrift earnings in the current quarter, which will be released by the bank board in March. Also, <PERSON> Ely </PERSON> and Regalia noted that non-operating losses frequently rise sharply in the final quarter of the year because institutions often account for loan losses as they prepare their books for the end of the year. The condition of S & amp; Ls stands in stark contrast to the relative health of commercial banking. Despite more than 200 bank failures so far this year, banking as a whole posted record profits totaling $ 16.4 billion in the first nine months of the year.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881214-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-14-88 0144EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-PoachingInvestigation     12-14 0505</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Poaching Investigation,500</SECOND>
<HEAD>RETRANSMITTING a0435 to restore slugline</HEAD>
<HEAD>Wildlife Service Uncovers Violations Among Texas Operations</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JENNIFER DIXON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Undercover wildlife agents have found `` flagrant'' poaching violations and `` unsporting practices'' by waterfowl hunting businesses along the <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> coast that led to charges against 210 people in seven states. The poaching violations come at a time when duck populations are already hurt by an eight-year drought in their breeding grounds. `` Duck numbers already are near record lows because of the drought and continued destruction of their natural habitat,'' said <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Dunkle </PERSON>, director of the <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. Fish and <ORGANIZATION> Wildlife </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>. `` They can not long withstand additional losses from illegal harvest.'' More than 100 wildlife service agents spent three years in an undercover investigation of 41 commercial waterfowl hunting businesses on the <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> coast, documenting more than 1,300 violations in one of the agency's biggest operations, officials said. `` During this investigation, service agents reported flagrant violations of laws intended to protect waterfowl,'' <PERSON> Dunkle </PERSON> said Tuesday. `` Law-abiding waterfowlers are outraged by these unethical and unsporting practices that betray total lack of concern for the status of waterfowl populations.'' Agents from around the country went undercover to book hunts with guides and owners of hunting businesses charging $ 65 to $ 500 a day who were suspected of killing waterfowl illegally and encouraging and helping customers to do likewise. Alleged violations occurred on 92 percent of the hunts, the service said. The agency said 23 hunting guides and owners were being arrested, 22 of them in <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> and one in <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>. Indictments or charges contained in a federal document named 50 others, and 137 people were to receive misdemeanor notices of violation in <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION>. Charges include shooting more than the legal limit; `` rallying,'' or stirring up waterfowl to drive them toward hunters; use of lead shot in steel shot zones; failure to retrieve shot fowl _ wanton waste; use of electronic calls; taking birds after the season has closed or outside legal hunting hours; and tagging and record-keeping violations, such as claiming birds belonged to someone who had not hunted that day, or falsifying when birds were shot. In several cases, the service said raptors, herons, ibises and other non-game migratory birds were allegedly killed and sold to undercover agents. Agents documented one case in which a dozen hunters in blinds around a pond shot as many geese as they could, killing more than 200 birds _ 139 over their limit. Wildlife service spokeswoman <PERSON> Megan </PERSON> <PERSON> Durham </PERSON> said the agents went undercover because the violations were occurring `` behind locked gates and in remote areas and it's difficult to get information any other way.'' Maximum penalties for the misdemeanors could be six months to one year in prison, and fines of $ 5,000 to $ 100,000 for individuals and $ 10,000 to $ 200,000 for organizations, depending on the charge. Maximum penalties for felony violations could be two to five years in prison and fines of $ 250,000 for individuals and $ 500,000 for organizations, depending on the charge.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881214-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-14-88 0146EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-LaRouche     12-14 0601</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-LaRouche,580</SECOND>
<HEAD>LaRouche's Underwear, Haircuts Subject of Tax Trial Dispute</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDS: trial resumes 10 a.m. EST; early afternoon lead expected</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT M. ANDREWS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ALEXANDRIA, Va. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Jurors in <PERSON> Lyndon </PERSON> <PERSON> LaRouche </PERSON>'s tax fraud trial are being asked to decide whether items ranging from free meals to free underwear should be considered taxable income. For four hours in an overheated federal courtroom Tuesday, as jurors stifled yawns and a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> marshal dozed off, defense lawyers and government prosecutors bickered over the arcane language of the federal tax code. The issue was whether <PERSON> LaRouche </PERSON>, a perennial minor-party presidential candidate, broke the law by failing to file federal income tax returns for any year since 1978. <PERSON> LaRouche </PERSON> argues that he had no taxable income because all his personal expenses were paid by various corporations he controls. `` Mr. <PERSON> LaRouche </PERSON> does not have to file income tax returns for 1979 through 1987 nor pay income taxes for that period,'' declared <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> accountant <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Seay </PERSON>, who was hired by defense lawyers to conduct a yearlong review of <PERSON> LaRouche </PERSON>'s financial records. <PERSON> Seay </PERSON> argued that <PERSON> LaRouche </PERSON> was an employee of all the groups he headed and that under the tax code, what he received from his `` employers'' as their business expense _ including meals, lodging, plane flights, bodyguards, horseback rides and even the new set of underwear during his campaign travels _ was `` non-taxable compensation.'' What if he accepted a free trim of `` such hair as he has,'' asked defense attorney <PERSON> Odin </PERSON> <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON>, prompting a grin from the balding <PERSON> LaRouche </PERSON>. The courtroom erupted in laughter when <PERSON> Seay </PERSON> responded that it might be considered a `` fringe benefit'' from LaRouche's employers. Under questioning by government prosecutors, <PERSON> Seay </PERSON> conceded he had been denied access to financial records prior to July 1985 which were seized when federal agents raided <PERSON> LaRouche </PERSON>'s <LOCATION> Leesburg </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, headquarters in October 1986. The accountant acknowledged he was relying on court testimony in concluding that <PERSON> LaRouche </PERSON> had never received enough taxable income _ currently a minimum of $ 1,080 _ to require filing a tax return. <PERSON> Seay </PERSON> testified as defense lawyers pushed to wrap up their case before the end of the fourth week of the trial in <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>. Besides a charge of conspiring to defraud the <ORGANIZATION> Internal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Revenue </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> LaRouche </PERSON> and six associates are accused of mail fraud and conspiracy for allegedly raising more than $ 30 million in loans from supporters without any intention of repaying them. If convicted of all 13 counts against him, <PERSON> LaRouche </PERSON> would face a maximum penalty of 65 years in prison and fines totaling $ 3.25 million. Another key defense witness Tuesday was <PERSON> Mayer </PERSON> <PERSON> Morganroth </PERSON>, a tax lawyer from <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Southfield </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mich. </LOCATION>, who said he advised <PERSON> LaRouche </PERSON> in 1979 that he did not have to file any income tax returns. <PERSON> Morganroth </PERSON> said his opinion, endorsed at a second conference on <PERSON> LaRouche </PERSON>'s tax status in late 1984, was that the goods and services provided to <PERSON> LaRouche </PERSON> were not payments but instead were intended to yield benefits to his publishers and other <PERSON> LaRouche </PERSON> entities that promoted his causes. <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> lawyer <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Morris </PERSON> told the trial jury that he had numerous contacts with <PERSON> LaRouche </PERSON> operatives while he was an aide to former White House national security adviser <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Clark </PERSON> in 1982-83. <PERSON> Morris </PERSON> said he considered their positions on such issues as Soviet intelligence, terrorism and Third World debt, but never divulged any information in return. He said he curbed those contacts when <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> and defense intelligence officials warned him that <PERSON> LaRouche </PERSON> was `` a socialist, a fascist, a communist, a member of the <ORGANIZATION> KGB </ORGANIZATION> and even a Democrat.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881214-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-14-88 0149EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-CongressionalPay     12-14 0660</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Congressional Pay,650</SECOND>
<HEAD>Pay Raise Plan Comes with String Attached</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JIM DRINKARD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A presidential advisory commission is proposing a hefty pay raise for <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, but it also is pushing lawmakers toward a dilemma: whether to abandon income from speaking fees in return for higher salaries. `` Members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> are caught in a vise between editorial writers and reporters, who are opposed to honoraria, and voters, who are opposed to pay raises,'' said Sen. <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Maine </LOCATION>, who will be the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> majority leader in the next <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. `` It is apparent, however, that there is a serious perception problem regarding honoraria, which <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> will have to consider along with the salary issue early next year,'' <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON> said in a statement. The Commission on Executive, <ORGANIZATION> Legislative </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Judicial </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Salaries </ORGANIZATION> met on Tuesday and approved recommendations for pay increases averaging 50 percent next year for the government's top 2,500 officials. That would send members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> from their current pay of $ 89,500 to $ 135,000. But in an unusual move, the panel also included strong language linking the pay boost to a ban on congressional speaking fees, which reached a record $ 9.8 million in 1987. Such a ban would require separate action by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. House leaders have spoken out in favor of such a ban. In the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>, where members are allowed to take home more in speaking fees and are generally in greater demand as speakers, the issue is more difficult. It is now up to President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> to decide whether to accept or modify the commission's recommendations. He will include his decision in the budget he sends <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> on Jan. 9, and any pay raise would automatically take effect 30 days later unless both the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> vote to head it off. <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON> was noncommittal on the pay raise, saying only that he looked forward to reviewing the president's suggestions. Senate Minority Leader <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>, R-Kan., said he would meet with <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON> on the subject next week In the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, leaders said they planned to support both the increase that the president recommends and the ban on outside speaking fees. `` Any honoraria known to mankind or yet to be conceived should be covered'' by the ban, said Rep. <PERSON> Tony </PERSON> <PERSON> Coelho </PERSON>, D-Calif., the No 3 official in the Democratic leadership. But <PERSON> Coelho </PERSON> said leaders are braced for an onslaught of criticism from the public and from lawmakers who fear the political backlash of accepting such a large raise when their salaries already are far higher than the average American's. It appeared likely that, as in 1986, the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> would vote to turn down the raise and the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> would take the heat for allowing the 30-day clock to run out without voting on the increase. Chief Justice <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Rehnquist </PERSON> welcomed the pay-raise proposal, saying it `` is bound to be encouraging to the nation's federal judges. `` The commission's salary recommendations would restore to those judges the cuts in real income which have been caused by inflation over the last 20 years,'' <PERSON> Rehnquist </PERSON> said. <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> chairman <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Cutler </PERSON> said federal courts have been particularly hard hit by the erosion in salaries caused by inflation. `` Judges are leaving in droves,'' he said, because they can make far more money in private legal practice. <PERSON> Ralph </PERSON> <PERSON> Nader </PERSON>, the self-styled consumer advocate, contested the commission's argument that it was only seeking to restore purchasing power lost by members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and other federal officials over the past two decades. He noted that in 1964, lawmakers were paid $ 22,500. Two years ago they received a $ 12,100 increase to the current level of $ 89,500. `` It sounds like members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and their peers in the other branches of government have kept up with inflation quite well,'' he said. `` While members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> have been overly generous to themselves, they have failed to act to increase wages for the 6.7 million workers who are at or below the minimum wage,'' <PERSON> Nader </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881214-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-14-88 0201EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FarmScene     12-14 0876</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Farm Scene,870</SECOND>
<HEAD>Chinese Lab Could Boost Crop Production In United States</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DON KENDALL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Farm Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Not only is <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> a big grain customer of the American farmer, there's a new laboratory in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> that may help develop trade with the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> in tiny organisms that protect crops from destructive insects and weeds. The new research operation was announced Tuesday by the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> as a way to help find natural enemies of insects and weeds that threaten crops in the two countries. Ultimately, the exchange of `` biocontrol'' organisms and scientific information could help boost crop production in both <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Orville </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentley </PERSON>, assistant secretary for science and education, said the new <ORGANIZATION> Sino-American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Biological </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Control </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Collaborative </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Laboratory </ORGANIZATION> is located at the <ORGANIZATION> Chinese </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agricultural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sciences </ORGANIZATION>. Under a five-year agreement with the academy, three <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> scientists will go to the laboratory next May and conduct research there for six months each year. They will work in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> the remaining six months of the year. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Soper </PERSON>, biocontrol research leader in the department's <ORGANIZATION> Agricultural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>, said the <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> laboratory will be a quarantine and research facility for exchanging potential biocontrol organisms between the two countries The targeted <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> pests include: leafy spurge, a noxious rangeland weed; two water weeds, hydrilla and watermilfoil; and the Russian wheat aphid. <PERSON> Soper </PERSON> said the aphid is `` the most worrisome pest.'' It was first spotted in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> in 1986 and has spread rapidly to wheat-growing areas. Pests of concern to <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> are: croftonweed, a weed so toxic to horses that they ca n't be kept on certain land; scale insects; and apple leaf mites. Next year the Chinese academy is expected to send scientists to <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> laboratories in <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lauderdale </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>; and <LOCATION> Buenos </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Aires </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Argentina </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Soper </PERSON> said scientists at four agency laboratories in <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Argentina </LOCATION> are searching overseas to find biocontrols for <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> pests. But until now, he said, scientists have not been able to easily explore most of the vast Eurasian land area. `` The new lab takes care of much of <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION> that we've missed, and we're hoping we can develop similar arrangements with the Soviets,'' he said. Meanwhile, the <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> also announced that private exporters have sold <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> an additional 400,000 metric tons of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> wheat at subsidized prices for shipment in January and February. The sales, equal to about 14.7 million bushels, were handled by four companies: <ORGANIZATION> Cargill </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, 190,000 tons; <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> States </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Enterprises </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, 40,000; <ORGANIZATION> Richco </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Grain </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ltd. </ORGANIZATION>, 40,000; and <ORGANIZATION> Ferruzzi </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, 130,000. <PERSON> Melvin </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Sims </PERSON>, general sales manager for the department's <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agricultural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>, said the sales were part of an authorized 1 million tons of wheat announced on Dec. 7 under the Export Enhancement Program, or EEP About 10,000 tons also remained of an earlier <ORGANIZATION> EEP </ORGANIZATION> authorization.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> has granted 13 states a total of $ 2.9 million to help finance mediation efforts between financially strapped farmers and their creditors. La <PERSON> Verne </PERSON> <PERSON> Ausman </PERSON>, acting administrator of the <ORGANIZATION> Farmers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Home </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>, said Tuesday the funds _ to be matched by the states _ will be used to `` resolve differences between other lenders and farmers'' who have loans from the <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> agency. The money, he said, `` will help make it possible for a neutral, third party mediator to cast a fresh eye on the problem. Many disputes are resolved in this manner.'' For example, the <ORGANIZATION> FmHA </ORGANIZATION> and other lenders might agree to write down, or reduce, a borrower's debt or in some other way work together to help the farmer meet his obligations. The matching grants were authorized in the Agricultural Credit Act passed by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> last year. States qualifying for the FmHA grants in the fiscal year that began Oct. 1 are: <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION>, $ 110,208; <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>, $ 305,000; <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION>, $ 431,150; <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION>, $ 500,000; <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION>, $ 75,040; <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION>, $ 75,000; <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION>, $ 168,140; <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION>, $ 250,000; <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION>, $ 269,870; <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION>, $ 97,000; <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, $ 500,000; <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION>, $ 87,440; and <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION>, $ 25,000.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
