<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880822-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-22-88 2338EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Mexico-Politics 1stLd-Writethru a0729 08-22 0610</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Mexico-Politics, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0729,0625</SECOND>
<HEAD>Soldiers Block Opposition Deputies From Examining Disputed Ballots</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: ADD 4 grafs at end UPDATING with Cardenas files criminal
charges against election officials</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By CONCEPCION BADILLO</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MEXICO CITY (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Hours after soldiers blocked opposition deputies from examining ballots in the disputed July 6 elections, the government party assured the nation Monday that a new congress will be certified by a Sept. 1 deadline. Soldiers wearing helmets and carrying automatic rifles stopped about 150 opposition representatives late Sunday night from entering a room at the Legislative Palace where millions of ballots are being held. The deputies-elect said the ballots would prove opposition charges that the governing <ORGANIZATION> Institutional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Revolutionary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, or <ORGANIZATION> PRI </ORGANIZATION>, rigged the election. The army is required to guard the ballots until the election is certified. The air of antagonism at the <ORGANIZATION> Chamber </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Deputies </ORGANIZATION>, now sitting as an electoral college, raised the question of whether the review will be finished in time for the president to swear in a new chamber by the constitutional deadline. The <ORGANIZATION> PRI </ORGANIZATION> holds a slim plurality in the chamber. Once the chamber finishes ratifying 26 disputed congressional races, it is supposed to move on to the presidential election. By custom, the outgoing chief executive formally introduces his successor to the nation on Sept. 1 during his final state-of-the-union address. Failure to do so would be an embarrassing breach of tradition, even though the new president is not sworn in until Dec. 1. Missing the deadline could `` interrupt the constitutional order and put the nation on the threshold of a coup d'etat'' <PERSON> Francisco </PERSON> <PERSON> Cardenas </PERSON>, one of <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>'s best-known political commentators, said Monday in the independent daily El Universal. The confrontation between soldiers and deputies was the latest in a series of incidents that marked the review of an election which produced unprecedented opposition gains. It was front-page news throughout <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>. Before dawn on Monday, a few hours after the incident, the leader of the <ORGANIZATION> PRI </ORGANIZATION> delegation, <PERSON> Guillermo </PERSON> <PERSON> Jimenez </PERSON>, told reporters `` there will be a chamber on time'' despite the conflict. The showdown prompted two prominent Roman Catholic clergymen to issue statements. The archbishops of <LOCATION> Zacatecas </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Javier </PERSON> <PERSON> Lozano </PERSON> <PERSON> Barragan </PERSON>, and of <LOCATION> Chihuahua </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Disan </PERSON> <PERSON> Vazquez </PERSON>, said they hoped common sense would prevail and the electoral college would finish by Sept. 1. The PRI-dominated <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Election </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> has said the <ORGANIZATION> PRI </ORGANIZATION> candidate, <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Salinas </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Gortari </PERSON>, won with 50.36 percent of the vote. Mexican presidents serve single, six-year terms beginning on Dec. 1. The <ORGANIZATION> PRI </ORGANIZATION> has won every presidential election since it was created in 1929. <PERSON> Lucia </PERSON> <PERSON> Santes </PERSON>, a leader of the opposition <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> coalition </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> party </ORGANIZATION> in southeastern <LOCATION> Tabasco </LOCATION> state, meanwhile said she had switched to the <ORGANIZATION> PRI </ORGANIZATION>. She said she had been the object of `` low blows, envy and rancor'' and that the <ORGANIZATION> PRI </ORGANIZATION> `` represents the real option for change.'' The Santes defection was a blow to supporters of <PERSON> Cuauhtemoc </PERSON> <PERSON> Cardenas </PERSON>, presidential candidate for the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION>, the largest opposition party, who ran strongly in <LOCATION> Tabasco </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Cardenas </PERSON> came in second place in presidential voting but maintains that a fair count would make him the winner. Late Monday, <PERSON> Cardenas </PERSON> filed criminal charges against <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Bartlett </PERSON> <PERSON> Diaz </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Election </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION>, and <PERSON> Fernando </PERSON> <PERSON> Elias </PERSON> <PERSON> Calles </PERSON>, the technical secretary, accusing them of violating the electoral code by not releasing individual results from nearly half of the 55,000 voting stations nationwide. <PERSON> Bartlett </PERSON> also is interior minister. `` We asked that the -LRB- vote -RRB- information be made known and that the authorities fulfill their responsibility,'' <PERSON> Cardenas </PERSON> said. He brought charges against the two earlier this month but was told he needed to file personally with the federal attorney general's office.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880822-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-22-88 2331EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-ForestFiresRdp 1stLd-Writethru a0674 08-22 0886</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Forest Fires Rdp, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0674,0899</SECOND>
<HEAD>Improved Weather Helps Battle Against Wyoming Fires</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: INSERTS 2 grafs after 13th graf, `In addition...' to UPDATE
with report on helicopter crash; picks up 14th graf, `Officials
in...' INSERTS 1 graf after 15th graf, `They'll be...' to UPDATE
with containment of Warm Springs fire expected Tuesday; picks up
16th graf, `Elsewhere in...' SUBS last 2 grafs, `The Hellroaring
... 12,000 acres' to UPDATE with downward revision in Hellroaring
Creek acreage, containment of Kirby fire expected Tuesday.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Temperatures fell, the wind died down and the <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> arrived Monday, improving conditions for weary firefighters battling forest fires that have charred thousands of acres of <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION>, especially in Yellowstone National Park. A first wave of 612 infantrymen from <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lewis </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wash. </LOCATION>, landed at <LOCATION> Bozeman </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mont. </LOCATION>, and headed for the 157,000-acre Clover Mist fire in <ORGANIZATION> Yellowstone </ORGANIZATION>'s northeastern corner. Soldiers were to help prevent the fire, one of 10 burning in the park involving about 350,000 acres, from crossing into <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Custer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> or commercial areas of <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION>'s Shoshone National Forest Park spokeswoman <PERSON> Joan </PERSON> <PERSON> Anzelmo </PERSON> said it was possible some of the soldiers might remain in the southern <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION> towns of <LOCATION> Cooke </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> and Silvergate to help protect them from the Clover Mist fire burning about 3 miles to the south. Approximately 3,000 firefighters were at work in <LOCATION> Yellowstone </LOCATION>, the nation's first national park. Elsewhere, reinforcements were called out in <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION> to back up firefighters working to keep the 700-acre Eagle Bar fire away from a timber sale tract in the <ORGANIZATION> Payette </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION>. Spokeswoman <PERSON> Carla </PERSON> <PERSON> Tipton </PERSON> said two 20-member crews were on the scene and three more were expected; an order was put in for 280 more people. Wind blew at only 5 to 15 mph Monday in <LOCATION> Yellowstone </LOCATION>, down from Saturday's 60 mph gusts. However, the park's south entrance remained closed, forcing visitors coming from the south to detour about 150 miles to the park's west entrance at <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Yellowstone </LOCATION>, Mont. The northern gate and two eastern entries remained open. Other roads closed included the road from the south entrance to <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Thumb </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Junction </LOCATION>, on the shore of <LOCATION> Yellowstone </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION>; the road from <ORGANIZATION> Madison </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Junction </ORGANIZATION> to <PERSON> Norris </PERSON> <PERSON> Juction </PERSON> and on to Indian <LOCATION> Creek </LOCATION>; and from <PERSON> Norris </PERSON> to Canyon Junction, an east-west shortcut between the western and eastern sides of the main road that circles the park in a rough hourglass pattern. The closings basically cut off the shortest route between the west and north entrances. And closing the Norris-Canyon road meant the trip from <LOCATION> Madison </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Junction </LOCATION> on the western side of the park to the famous Fishing Bridge in the east went from 39 miles up to 54, by way of the Old Faithful geyser. The majority of the park remained accessible. In addition, the <LOCATION> Grant </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Village </LOCATION> area, which contains a hotel, campground, visitor center and park staff dormitories, was closed, as were the Norris, <LOCATION> Pebble </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Creek </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Madison </PERSON> and <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON> <PERSON> Lake </PERSON> campgrounds. The park contains 12 campgrounds. South of <ORGANIZATION> Yellowstone </ORGANIZATION>, in Grand Teton National Park and the <ORGANIZATION> Bridger-Teton </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION>, the Hunter fire that had grown to more than 2,900 acres in one day had calmed Monday, said <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Bright </PERSON>, fire information officer. In addition, firefighters completed bulldozer lines around the southwest and northwest flanks of the Hunter blaze, and officials allowed residents evacuated Saturday to return to their homes, as well as guests of the <ORGANIZATION> Teton </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Science </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> and <LOCATION> Lost </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Creek </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ranch </LOCATION>, Bright said. Meanwhile, a preliminary investigation concluded that a helicopter involved in firefighting efforts in the <ORGANIZATION> Bighorn </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> crashed after it lost power to its rear rotor, which stabilizes the craft. Investigators are unsure why the rotor lost power, fire information officer <PERSON> Harvalou </PERSON> <PERSON> Buchanan </PERSON> said. Last Friday's crash killed <PERSON> Merrin </PERSON> <PERSON> Rodgers </PERSON>, 51, a <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Land </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Management </ORGANIZATION> communications technician, and injured the pilot and two other passengers. Officials in <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION> took advantage of the calmer, cooler weather to have crews dig a fire line by hand in rugged terrain along the southern edge of the 13-day-old Warm Springs Creek fire, southeast of <PERSON> Helena </PERSON>. `` They'll be right at the burning edge,'' fire information officer <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Krepps </PERSON> said Monday. He said the 37,200-acre fire was only smoldering there Monday, allowing crews to go in with less risk. Officials predicted the fire would be contained Tuesday night. Elsewhere in <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION>, 20 smokejumpers parachuted into the <LOCATION> Storm </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Creek </LOCATION> fire that has burned 22,000 acres of the Absaroka-Beartooth Wilderness, and 80 more were to be taken in by four-wheel drive vehicles, said Beartooth District Ranger <PERSON> Phil </PERSON> <PERSON> Jaquith </PERSON>. The fire raced eight miles in a matter of hours Saturday, kicked up by high wind, he said. The Hellroaring Creek fire, in a different section of the same giant wilderness area northeast of Yellowstone National Park, had covered an estimated 24,400 acres by Monday. Spokeswoman <PERSON> Maggie </PERSON> <PERSON> Pittman </PERSON> said about 360 firefighters were working on the blaze, which officials hope will burn into natural barriers. In southeastern <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION>, officials called for reinforcements to help battle a blaze out of control south of the Northern Cheyenne Indian Reservation. <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Kendall </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lands </ORGANIZATION> said the <PERSON> Kirby </PERSON> fire _ fanned by wind blowing at 35 to 40 mph _ had grown to 10,000 to 12,000 acres, but firefighters expected to contain the blaze Tuesday.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880822-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-22-88 2339EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Afghan-Soviets     08-22 0378</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Afghan-Soviets,0390</SECOND>
<HEAD>Reports Up To 710 Soviets Killed In Afghan Rocket Attack</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A British newspaper said Tuesday up to 710 Soviet soldiers and civilians were killed in a rocket attack by Afghan rebels on a military base north of <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION>, the capital of <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Telegraph </ORGANIZATION> said its account of the rocket assault, that occurred either Aug. 10 or 11, was based on reports received in <LOCATION> Peshawar </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>, from Afghan guerrillas. Earlier reports had surfaced from diplomatic and guerrilla sources of the attack on the <LOCATION> Kalagay </LOCATION> military base 100 miles north of <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION>, but they had few details and a lower death toll. <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Telegraph </ORGANIZATION> correspondent <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Bone </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Peshawar </LOCATION> reported a spokesman for a guerrilla group said the rockets devastated the Kalagay ammunition depot and turned the Soviet compound into an inferno. Bone quoted the spokesman, who was not identified, as saying, `` Maybe it was lucky but it was a good hit and our greatest day.'' Western diplomatic sources in <LOCATION> Islamabad </LOCATION> had said at least 109 Soviet soldiers died at <LOCATION> Kalagay </LOCATION>. Bone said the casualties were much higher according to a report written on cloth by <PERSON> Muhibullah </PERSON> <PERSON> Khan </PERSON>, a guerrilla commander in the <LOCATION> Kalagay </LOCATION> district, and received in <LOCATION> Peshawar </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Bone </PERSON> said <PERSON> Muhibullah </PERSON> <PERSON> Khan </PERSON>'s report quoted a leader of the government militia as saying 598 Soviet soldiers and 112 Soviet civilians were killed and 284 Soviets were wounded. He wrote that the report said the guerrillas fired eight 107mm rockets into the supply base. Western reporters generally are barred from <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> and there was no independent confirmation of conflicting claims by the government and guerrillas. If the report attributed to <PERSON> Muhibullah </PERSON> <PERSON> Khan </PERSON> was accurate, it would be possibly the worst single loss by <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> forces since they entered <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> in December 1979 to help the Marxist government battle the rebels. Under an accord signed by <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> with Soviet participation last April, all Soviet military personnesl are to be withdrawn from <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> by Feb. 15. The <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> had up to 115,000 troopers in the country but announced that half of the force had been removed as of Aug. 15 according to the withdrawal schedule. The anti-communist guerrillas did not participate in the peace negotiations and have vowed to continue their fight.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880822-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-22-88 2333EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-TropicalWeather 2ndLd-Writethru a0688 08-22 0379</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Tropical Weather, 2nd Ld - Writethru, a0688,0384</SECOND>
<HEAD>Third Depression Forms In Tropical Atlantic</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: SUBS grafs 2, 4, 11 graf with 10:30 p.m. advisories, new
positions</NOTE>
<DATELINE>MIAMI (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Hurricane forecasters Monday were tracking three tropical depressions, the closest one expected to gradually strengthen as it moves into the western <LOCATION> Caribbean </LOCATION>. The newest tropical depression formed Monday in the middle <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ocean </LOCATION>, east of the <LOCATION> Lesser </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Antilles </LOCATION>. The westward-moving system's highest sustained winds were near 35 mph around a center roughly 325 miles east of the island of <LOCATION> Guadeloupe </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hurricane </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in suburban <LOCATION> Coral </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gables </LOCATION> reported at 10:30 p.m. Monday. The depression was moving about 20 to 25 mph. An <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> reconnaissance aircraft was scheduled to investigate the depression Tuesday morning. Forecasters were most concerned with the <LOCATION> Caribbean </LOCATION> depression, which was moving west-northwest at about at about 15 to 20 mph and had highest sustained winds of near 35 mph, the hurricane center said. The poorly organized depression was about 175 miles southeast of <LOCATION> Kingston </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Jamaica </LOCATION>. `` The one in the <LOCATION> Caribbean </LOCATION> probably has the best potential,'' said forecaster <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Case </PERSON>. `` Once it moves into the western <LOCATION> Caribbean </LOCATION>, it seems more favorable for development.'' Some strengthening was expected over the next 24 hours, <ORGANIZATION> Case </ORGANIZATION> said Monday. `` Any time there's a tropical depression southeast of us at this time of year, you need to pay attention,'' Case added. Of the tropical activity, <PERSON> Case </PERSON> said it was `` quite normal'' at this point in the hurricane season, which began June 1 and ends Nov. 30. `` We're really approaching the peak of the season,'' he said. Little strengthening was expected in the newly formed depression unless it slowed its forward speed, Case said. Meanwhile, the most distant system, located about 200 miles northwest of <LOCATION> Santo </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Antao </LOCATION> in the <LOCATION> Cape </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Verde </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Islands </LOCATION> off <LOCATION> west </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>, was moving northwest at 15 to 20 mph into colder water, and little change in strength was expected until a gradual decrease late Tuesday. Its highest sustained winds were estimated near 35 mph. Depressions are upgraded to named tropical storms when their sustained winds reach 39 mph and to hurricanes when winds hit 74 mph. There have been two tropical storms so far in the 1988 <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ocean </LOCATION> hurricane season, but neither reached hurricane strength.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880822-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-22-88 2341EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p AM-Quayle 6thLd-Writethru a0749 08-22 1022</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Quayle, 6th Ld-Writethru, a0749,1000</SECOND>
<HEAD>Ex-Reagan Aides Coach Quayle For Solo Trip, Bush Defends Him To
Vets</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: INSERTS two grafs after 6th pvs, Presidential nominee...to
end, to update with reports on national guard situation in 1969;
SUBS 10th graf, Thompson is ... to appear, to CORRECT to Quayle
sted Bush being invited; edits to tighten.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By WILLIAM C. HIDLAY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CHICAGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Sen. <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> told a veterans group Monday `` absolutely no influence was used'' to get him into the <ORGANIZATION> Indiana </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> during the height of the Vietnam War. In brief remarks to a convention of the Veterans of Foreign Wars in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>, the Republican vice presidential nominee: `` Influence was not even necessary if I had chosen to use it, which I never would have. `` The reason is because my <ORGANIZATION> Indiana </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> unit had openings before I applied, they had openings when I applied, and they had openings after I applied. So there was absolutedly no influence used.'' The crowd of about 2,500 veterans cheered and whistled turing the hastily called appearance, in which the <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION> senator joked: `` My national guard unit was never called up to active duty, but let me say that after these last 72 hours no one can say I've never faced combat.'' Presidential nominee <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and his aides have sought to play down suggestions that <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>'s candidacy needed shoring up after a rocky week dominated by the controversy over whether <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>, a pro-military conservative on <LOCATION> Capitol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION>, pulled strings to enter the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> in 1969 as his college draft deferment was about to end. In a report in Tuesday's editions of <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION>, the guard official who swore in <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> said he received no special treatment. Retired major general <PERSON> Alfred </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Ahner </PERSON> said in a telephone interview that `` there had to have been a vacancy before he enlisted.'' The -LRB- <LOCATION> Cleveland </LOCATION> -RRB- Plain Dealer reported, however, that records show the guard under a virtual freeze on recruitment imposed 49 days before <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>'s enlistment on May 19, 1969. The documents also appear to contradict assertions from some former <ORGANIZATION> Indiana </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> officers that the Guard had more than 200 vacancies and therefore was open to <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> without special treatment or favoritism, the story said. At the VFW conference, where <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> had appeared earlier Monday, <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> also said he hoped to put the issue of his military record behind him so attention could be focused on `` the real issues'' of the campaign. `` The question before all of us is: Not what <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> did 20 years in the past _ but what either President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> or President <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> will do in the future to secure world peace,'' <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> said. The circumstances surrounding <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>'s unplanned, last-minute appearance before the veterans group were in dispute. <PERSON> Wade </PERSON> <PERSON> LaDue </PERSON>, the spokesman for the organization, said <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> was invited Monday after Illinois Gov. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON> intervened with Commander in Chief Earl Stock. <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON> is a key <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> supporter in <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> press secretary <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Prosperi </PERSON> said <PERSON> Stock </PERSON> made the invitation. <PERSON> Kevin </PERSON> <PERSON> Morris </PERSON>, communications director for the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> campaign in <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION>, said members of the VFW encouraged <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON> to persuade <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> to appear. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> flew back to the nation's capital Sunday, accompanied by <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s campaign chairman and top strategist, to meet with the new campaign staff assembled for him by <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> aides. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> departed from his prepared remarks to a Veterans of Foreign Wars convention in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> on Monday to defend his running mate: `` <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> served in the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION>, signing up in a unit that had vacancies at the time and now he is under shrill partisan attack,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said, his voice rising. `` So let his attackers cast the first stone. He served honorably. True, he did n't go to <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>, but his unit was n't sent. `` But there's another truth _ he did not go to <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>, he did not burn his draft card and he damned sure did n't burn the American flag,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said, drawing cheers and a standing ovation from the veterans. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> is scheduled to return to the campaign trail Wednesday, certain to face more questions about the Guard issue and how he got into law school when he did not meet admission requirements. He is to attend legislative conferences in <LOCATION> Cincinnati </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Lexington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ky. </LOCATION>, before traveling to <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Louis </LOCATION>, where aides say he will deliver a major address to the Enlisted Association of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION>, composed of current and former enlisted personnel. Meanwhile, <ORGANIZATION> Newsweek </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> magazine </ORGANIZATION> reported that during his 1980 <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> campaign, <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> referred to himself in political pamphlets as a `` Vietnam-era veteran.'' <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> dropped the reference after objections by some <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> combat veterans. Although the reference was technically correct, <ORGANIZATION> Newsweek </ORGANIZATION> said that his <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> duty was not the type of service implied in the leaflet. In the interview, <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> also said his influential family did n't pull strings to get him admitted to <ORGANIZATION> Indiana </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Law </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> The staff that the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> campaign has assembled for <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> is a group with substantial experience in the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and presidential politics. <PERSON> Stuart </PERSON> <PERSON> Spencer </PERSON>, a longtime <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> adviser and member of the president's `` kitchen cabinet,'' is chairing <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>'s campaign. His deputy is <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Canzeri </PERSON>, known as an expert detail man during his years in the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> White House. <PERSON> Spencer </PERSON>, long a <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> intimate, is a savvy strategist who has been at <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s side in most of his political decisions. <PERSON> Canzeri </PERSON> served <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON> <PERSON> Rockefeller </PERSON>, titan of the <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>'s moderate wing, for nearly 20 years. A presidential assistant and deputy to <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> aide <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Deaver </PERSON>, <PERSON> Canzeri </PERSON> was known as a Mr. <PERSON> Fixit </PERSON> in the White House for his quick humor and ability to get things done. <PERSON> Canzeri </PERSON> resigned in 1982 under a cloud after accepting mortgages from friends at favorable interest rates and double-billing the White House and the <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> for `` $ 700 and change'' for two dinners he gave while out of the country preparing for presidential trips. The <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> later concluded that <PERSON> Canzeri </PERSON> did not violate federal law. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>'s press secretary, <PERSON> Prosperi </PERSON>, was <ORGANIZATION> Interior </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Hodel </PERSON>'s spokesman and also worked at the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> White House.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880822-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-22-88 2342EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-Valerie'sLawsuit     08-22 0534</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Valerie's Lawsuit,0554</SECOND>
<HEAD>Valerie Harper Denies She Tried to Control `Valerie' Show</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LINDA DEUTSCH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actress <PERSON> Valerie </PERSON> <PERSON> Harper </PERSON> denied from the witness stand Monday that she demanded absolute control over the TV series she was fired from, declaring, `` I was n't trying to be <PERSON> Genghis </PERSON> <PERSON> Khan </PERSON>.'' `` I wanted to have participation, early knowledge of stories so I would be in a partnership on the show,'' she said of her situation comedy series `` Valerie.'' Ms. <PERSON> Harper </PERSON> was called to the stand by attorneys for <ORGANIZATION> Lorimar </ORGANIZATION>, the production company suing her for alleged breach of contract. She is countersuing the company, contending it wrongfully fired her from the show. Attorney <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Engel </PERSON> sought to show that Ms. <PERSON> Harper </PERSON> was aware of all aspects of her 1985 contract with <PERSON> Lorimar </PERSON> and tried to renegotiate it because she craved more money and total control over all aspects of the show. Ms. <PERSON> Harper </PERSON> denied this, saying that she left business matters in the hands of her husband, <PERSON> Tony </PERSON> <PERSON> Cacciotti </PERSON>, and left the contract to her agent and lawyer whose advice she later came to doubt. `` I'm not good with contracts,'' she said, holding the <ORGANIZATION> Lorimar </ORGANIZATION> document. `` I read these and start to get cross-eyed.'' Ms. <PERSON> Harper </PERSON> acknowledged that even before the pilot for `` Valerie'' was sold, her relations with other members of the production staff began to erode. The first problem, she said, arose when <PERSON> Cacciotti </PERSON>'s name was left off the list of credits on the pilot for `` Valerie'' even though he had acted as supervising producer. `` I was disappointed and hurt,'' she said. `` It felt like a betrayal.'' She told jurors that she and <PERSON> Cacciotti </PERSON> have been business partners since 1979 and have been married just over a year. <PERSON> Engel </PERSON> enumerated the financial terms of the contract that brought Ms. <PERSON> Harper </PERSON> $ 1.5 million for the first one-and-a-half seasons on the air and provided profit shares and escalating salaries for her and her husband in subsequent years. In the sixth season, she would have received $ 90,000 per episode. `` Did n't you realize that you had a very favorable deal?'' asked <PERSON> Engel </PERSON>. `` I felt financially it was a start,'' Ms. <PERSON> Harper </PERSON> replied. She faulted herself for letting too many unwritten agreements stay out of the contract. `` There was a rush to sign the contract and -LRB- they said -RRB- we'll work out the details later,'' she said Ms. <PERSON> Harper </PERSON> said, she sought to renegotiate her contract later to increase her salary and put in writing her creative participation in story ideas for each episode. By then, she conceded, she felt she was losing the right to affect story lines. `` The consultation I had enjoyed had eroded and the relationship with -LRB- the producers -RRB- had started to turn,'' she said. `` What you thought you had was total control,'' said <PERSON> Engel </PERSON>. `` I would disagree,'' said Ms. <PERSON> Harper </PERSON>. `` I wanted participation, not control ... I was n't trying to be <PERSON> Genghis </PERSON> <PERSON> Khan </PERSON>. I wanted participation with people I loved and respected.'' <PERSON> Lorimar </PERSON> fired Ms. <PERSON> Harper </PERSON> from the show a year ago and replaced her with <PERSON> Sandy </PERSON> <PERSON> Duncan </PERSON>. The show is now known as `` The <PERSON> Hogan </PERSON> Family.'' Ms. <PERSON> Harper </PERSON>'s testimony came on her 48th birthday, but the event was not mentioned in the courtroom.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880822-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-22-88 2353EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-SocialClubs     08-22 0714</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Social Clubs,0735</SECOND>
<HEAD>Social Club: Fire Succeeds Where Police Heat Could Not</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By RICK HAMPSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The basement warren called The Hole where fire claimed seven lives is one of hundreds of illegal `` social clubs'' dotting the city's poorer neighborhoods that continue to operate despite repeated police raids. More than 30 people were injured in the fire at the <LOCATION> Bronx </LOCATION> club Sunday afternoon as 60 to 100 panicked patrons tried to escape through the lone exit. Despite periodic campaigns to close them down, social clubs _ a local term everyone admits is misleading _ have been centers of urban problems ranging from noise and double-parking to gambling, prostitution and drug dealing. Police had raided The Hole five times since March to try to shut it down. Rife with building, health and fire code violations, the clubs repeatedly have been the scene of serious fires, including one in <LOCATION> Brooklyn </LOCATION> three years ago that killed five people. Such clubs are common in large cities. In 1967 a police raid on an illegal club in <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION> _ `` blind pig'' was the local term _ sparked days of rioting. In <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, alcohol is sold without a license at more than 200 locations, according to estimates by police precinct commanders. Clubs have operated in the past at another 400 locations and could reopen any time. Some were closed under the city's `` padlock law,'' which allows police to shutter a location for a year if two crimes are committed on the site within a 12-month period. But police have been unable to close many other clubs. The Hole, first raided in May 1984, is a prime example. Police hit the club five times between March 22 and July 26, seizing cash and liquor and arresting a total of nine people, most of them employees charged with selling liquor without a state license. But the club never stayed closed because the police could n't get even the two criminal convictions needed under the padlock law. When the fire broke out Sunday most of the cases were still plodding through the city's overloaded court system. In the three that were resolved, defendants were allowed to plead guilty to disorderly conduct and pay fines of between $ 50 and $ 100. `` That is useless to us,'' said Deputy Inspector <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Biehler </PERSON>, because disorderly conduct does not qualify as a criminal conviction under the padlock law. The fines were particularly puny compared to those prescribed for violations of the liquor law _ about $ 10,000 each. Despite the label, places like The Hole are neither social nor clubs. `` The consumption of alcohol is often of secondary importance,'' a state task force report said. `` The primary function of these operations has developed into prostitution, gambling, drugs and trafficking in stolen property.'' City police have made 1,128 arrests at clubs in the past 12 months. <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> State </LOCATION> liquor licenses cost up to $ 5,100 and are good for three years. But many people do not apply for one, often because they have a criminal record or plan to employ others who do. Also, if a bar is not licensed it does n't have to worry about state inspectors `` coming in and seeing things they do n't want seen,'' said <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Chernela </PERSON>, spokesman for the state <ORGANIZATION> Liquor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Authority </ORGANIZATION>. Just about anyone can go to a social club, despite the term's implication of exclusivity An employee usually keeps an eye on the door, but a club member is generally anyone who walks in on a given night. Or morning. While the city's licensed bars are required to close by 4 a.m., social clubs often are open until dawn or later, usually to the distress of neighborhood residents. When the police do stage a raid, securing evidence is problematic. `` When we come in, a lot of things hit the floor and go down the toilet,'' <PERSON> Biehler </PERSON> said. Owners are rarely convicted. `` When you arrest a bartender, you have n't arrested the guy who's really calling the shots, and so the place is back in business with a new bartender the next day,'' <PERSON> Chernela </PERSON> said. `` After a tragedy like this everyone looks at the government, but it's a very difficult problem,'' said <PERSON> Chernela </PERSON>. `` You close them and they just spring back up.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880822-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-22-88 0000EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-WickesBuyout     08-21 0452</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Wickes Buyout,0464</SECOND>
<HEAD>Wickes `White Knight' Sigoloff Makes Leveraged Buyout Offer</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SANTA MONICA, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Sanford </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Sigoloff </PERSON>, the corporate `` White Knight'' who rescued <ORGANIZATION> Wickes </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cos. </ORGANIZATION>. Inc. from bankruptcy five years ago, on Sunday announced a management-led leveraged buyout offer of $ 12 a share The retail giant, including the Builder's Emporium and <ORGANIZATION> Wickes </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Furniture </ORGANIZATION> stores, also announced a net loss of $ 12.4 million for the second quarter ended July 30, said company spokesman <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Sitrick </PERSON>. <PERSON> Sigoloff </PERSON> disclosed that <ORGANIZATION> WII </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Holdings </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, a firm he established with members of his <ORGANIZATION> Wickes </ORGANIZATION> management team, will offer to purchase nearly 40 million shares of outstanding common stock, <PERSON> Sitrick </PERSON> said. He said WII stands for W-2 or <ORGANIZATION> Wickes </ORGANIZATION> 2. The offer is nearly $ 3 higher than <ORGANIZATION> Wickes </ORGANIZATION>' closing stock price of 9 -RRB- on the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Stock </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Exchange </ORGANIZATION> last Friday. `` While I have strong confidence in the long-term viability and prospects of our continuing businesses,'' <PERSON> Sigoloff </PERSON> said in a prepared statement, `` it has become increasingly clear to me, as well as the other directors of the company, that our stockholders want to maximize the value of their investment in the company in the immediate near-term.'' The 39,846,600 shares sought in the merger deal represent about 83 percent of <ORGANIZATION> Wickes </ORGANIZATION>' outstanding shares, <PERSON> Sitrick </PERSON> said. The offer is scheduled to be in effect from Aug. 26 to Oct. 20, he said. It is expected that the principal investors in <ORGANIZATION> WII </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Holdings </ORGANIZATION> will be institutional investors, including <ORGANIZATION> Drexel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Burnham </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lambert </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, which promised no problems in arranging financing for the buyout, <PERSON> Sitrick </PERSON> said. The offer is void if fewer than 50 percent of outstanding shares are sold, he said. The company's net loss for the second quarter amounted to 28 cents a share, with reported earnings of $ 10.4 million, or 19 cents a share, on sales of $ 937.9 million and losses from discontinued operation of $ 22.8 million, or 47 cents a share. In April 1982, <ORGANIZATION> Wickes </ORGANIZATION>, with assets estimated at about $ 3 billion, became the largest <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> company to file for bankruptcy protection. But less than two years later, creditors approved a plan allowing <ORGANIZATION> Wickes </ORGANIZATION> to emerge from Chapter 11 proceedings. Analysts had predicted it would take <ORGANIZATION> Wickes </ORGANIZATION> at least five years to erase the accumulated red ink. The force behind the comeback was <PERSON> Sigoloff </PERSON>, who earned the nickname `` Ming the Merciless'' for the tough-minded business moves and hard-nosed cost cutting he employed to resuscitate two other <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> companies in the 1970s: <ORGANIZATION> Republic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Daylin </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Sigoloff </PERSON> reorganized <ORGANIZATION> Wickes </ORGANIZATION> by selling off seasonal divisions such as <ORGANIZATION> MacGregor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Golf </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Wickes </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> At the same time he revamped store displays and appeared in television commercials and offered his personal guarantee of renewed product quality and service.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880822-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-22-88 0000EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Cambodia     08-22 0174</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Cambodia,0177</SECOND>
<HEAD>Major Changes Announced in Cambodian Government</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BANGKOK, Thailand (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Heng </PERSON> <PERSON> Samrin </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION> has retired or shifted 11 members of his Cabinet and abolished the office of cooperation with Soviet bloc allies, state-run radio said. The radio report, seen Sunday in <LOCATION> Bangkok </LOCATION>, said the reshuffle included the key portfolios of defense and interior. No reason was given for the changes. The moves were made Saturday at `` an ordinary meeting of the <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> in the presence of Comrade <PERSON> Heng </PERSON> <PERSON> Samrin </PERSON>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION>,'' the broadcast said. <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> installed the <PERSON> Heng </PERSON> <PERSON> Samrin </PERSON> government when it invaded <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION> in late 1978. The <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> recognizes as <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION>'s legitimate government a coalition of three guerrilla groups fighting the Vietnamese occupation `` It is decided to dissolve the office of the minister of economic and cultural cooperation with <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Laos </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, and other fraternal socialist countries,'' the radio said. The Soviet-backed Vietnamese have pledged to withdraw by early 1990 the up to 100,000 troops they maintain in <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880822-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-22-88 0005EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-HongKong-Gold     08-22 0029</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Hong Kong-Gold,0027</SECOND>
<HEAD>Gold Drops</HEAD>
<DATELINE>HONG KONG (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Gold dropped the equivalent of 90 cents an ounce on Monday, opening at $ 432.72. It closed Saturday at $ 433.62.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880822-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-22-88 0008EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Britain-ArmsDealer Bjt   08-22 0808</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Britain-Arms Dealer, Bjt,0829</SECOND>
<HEAD>British Arms Sales Boom: From Bullets To Jet Fighters
^An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MAUREEN JOHNSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> is booming as an arms dealer, supplanting the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> as wealthy <LOCATION> Saudi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arabia </LOCATION>'s biggest supplier and edging out long-time rival <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> globally as purveyor of everything from bullets to jet fighters. Less particular than the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> about who buys its increasingly sophisticated wares, <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> has doubled its sales in the past three years through a mixture of politics, hard-sell and technical advances. The most glittering prize is a $ 17 billion deal clinched last month with <LOCATION> Saudi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arabia </LOCATION> that includes 50 Tornado fighter-bombers. It underlines <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s major advantage over the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>: there are no political constraints on British arms sales to <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s Arab enemies. `` The number of restrictions the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has on sales is preposterous,'' says <PERSON> Francis </PERSON> <PERSON> Tusa </PERSON>, analyst at the London-based <ORGANIZATION> Royal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Studies </ORGANIZATION>. `` The Saudis have made it clear that they are not going to be told any longer by the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, ` You can have what you want _ but only a third of it and not for another five years and providing you do n't base it where you want to','' he said in an interview. With the ink just dry on the <LOCATION> Saudi </LOCATION> deal, <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Younger </PERSON> was back in the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION>, this time in <LOCATION> Kuwait </LOCATION>, talking arms. About the same time, the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> blocked the sale of Maverick air-to-surface missiles that were to accompany 40 American F-18 fighters <LOCATION> Kuwait </LOCATION> had agreed to buy, throwing doubt on the near $ 2 billion deal. `` Our friends and friendly rivals have their problems,'' acknowledged an official of the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Exports </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION>, requesting anonymity. With a staff of 250, the organization's main job is to oil the wheels of sales drives by privately owned British armament manufacturers, such as the airplane giant British Aerospace, and also check that they do n't sell to banned countries. These include <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Libya </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>, which is officially under a <LOCATION> British </LOCATION> arms embargo since the 1982 invasion of <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>. According to <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> figures, between 1985 and 1987 <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> doubled to 12 percent its share of the world arms market outside the <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> bloc. <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> says, is now the world's third largest arms supplier, ranking well behind the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> _ `` <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> probably gives away more than we sell worldwide,'' said one official _ and the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, but pushing <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> down to fourth place. <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> signed defense contracts worth $ 4 billion in 1985. In 1986, the figure was nearly $ 9 billion with a first major Saudi contract to buy Tornado planes, and last year contracts totaled an estimated $ 5.6 billion. <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Export </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> chief Sir <PERSON> Colin </PERSON> <PERSON> Chandler </PERSON>, who received a knighthood this year on Prime Minister <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON>'s recommendation, says <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s 1987 figure keeps it ahead of <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>. In 1986, with the <LOCATION> Saudi </LOCATION> deal, <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> moved temporarily into second place, ahead of the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> has assiduously cultivated the oil-rich Saudis on official visits and rolled out the red carpet for King Fahd in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>. She slips in plugs for British armaments during foreign trips, including recently in <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>, where <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> are competing for a multimillion-dollar order for nuclear-powered submarines. British officials, arms manufacturers and some analysts say prime factors in the increased sales are improved weapons and warplanes, including the multinational Tornado developed with <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>, and the free-enterprise atmosphere generated by nearly a decade of <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> government. `` It is a fact that we're producing more things with fewer people,'' said a British official, adding the 130,000-strong workforce in the defense industry has declined slightly in the past few years. He requested anonymity. Others familiar with the secretive world of arms sales say <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> has also been hurt by a tradition of gearing arms exports to Third World countries on generous credit terms. <PERSON> Philip </PERSON> <PERSON> Parker </PERSON>, marketing director for <ORGANIZATION> Plessey </ORGANIZATION>, one of five British defense electronics manufacturers, said that with <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> cutting defense spending, companies are forced to expand foreign sales. `` We have to go and slug it out in the market place in the major countries,'' said <PERSON> Parker </PERSON> in an interview. <ORGANIZATION> Plessey </ORGANIZATION> says its annual turnover from defense sales has more than trebled to $ 850 million since 1980, with sonar systems going to the Swedish, <LOCATION> Thai </LOCATION> and South Korean navies, an $ 850 million communications network for the Australian army, and smaller deals with <LOCATION> Oman </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Zealand </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Greece </LOCATION> and an unidentified Far Eastern country. But British manufacturers have suffered some big failures too. The most expensive was the scrapping of the Nimrod spy plane in 1986, after nine years' work by <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Electric </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Company </ORGANIZATION> costing nearly $ 1.7 billion. <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> ordered the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airborne </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Warning </ORGANIZATION> and Command System instead.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880822-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-22-88 0024EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Deaths 1stLd-Writethru a0724 08-22 0365</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Deaths, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0724,0374</SECOND>
<NOTE>Eds: Adds Christian. An AMs separate on Aron moved as a0656.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Jean-Paul Aron</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PARIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Jean-Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Aron </PERSON>, a philosopher and self-proclaimed `` dandy'' who announced last year he was suffering from AIDS, died Saturday. He was 61. <PERSON> Aron </PERSON>, a nephew of the late French philosopher <PERSON> Raymond </PERSON> <PERSON> Aron </PERSON>, taught philosphy at the universities of <LOCATION> Tourcoing </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Lille </LOCATION>, wrote books on the sociology of the 19th century, published novels, produced plays and wrote for the newspapers <PERSON> Le </PERSON> <PERSON> Matin </PERSON> and <PERSON> Le </PERSON> <PERSON> Monde </PERSON>. In a recent interview on French television, <PERSON> Aron </PERSON> said he felt an obligation to break the `` taboo'' surrounding acquired immune deficiency syndrome. `` The silence about this illness must be broken,'' he said. `` Nothing in the world would have made me talk publicly about my homosexuality,'' if he had not contracted AIDS, <PERSON> Aron </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>Rene Bine</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SAN FRANCISCO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Dr. <PERSON> Rene </PERSON> <PERSON> Bine </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, a heart disease specialist who was one of the first physicians to enter <LOCATION> Dachau </LOCATION> concentration camp after its liberation by Allied troops in World War II, died Saturday. He was 73. <PERSON> Bine </PERSON> died at <LOCATION> Mount </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Zion </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION>, where he practiced and taught for nearly four decades. He suffered from a rare neurological disorder and had been ill for several years. The <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> native served as a captain in the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corps </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> during the war. He was an expert in nutrition and its relation to heart disease and wrote numerous articles and pamphlets on cardiovascular topics.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>Charles Donald Christian</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>TUCSON, Ariz. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Dr. <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Christian </PERSON>, who created the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Arizona </ORGANIZATION> medical school's <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Obstetrics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Gynecology </ORGANIZATION> in 1969 and later discovered the hazards of intrauterine devices, died of cancer Sunday at his <LOCATION> Tucson </LOCATION> home. He was 57. <PERSON> Christian </PERSON> was credited in 1974 with informing the manufacturers of the Dalkon Shield that the birth-control device was causing severe complications and death in women who used it. Data provided by <PERSON> Christian </PERSON> led the manufacturer, <ORGANIZATION> A.H. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Robins </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, to issue a safety warning for the product. A year later, <ORGANIZATION> Robins </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> suspended distribution of the device at the request of the <ORGANIZATION> Food </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Drug </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880822-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-22-88 0038EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Burma 1stLd-Writethru a0660 08-22 0724</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Burma, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0660,0739</SECOND>
<HEAD>General Strike Appears To Take Hold, Soldiers On Streets</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: LEADS with 6 grafs to UPDATE with soldiers guarding Rangoon,
shops closed, but diplomat saying Rangoon quiet. Picks up 6th graf
pvs, `For the ...'</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By JAMES W. HATTON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BANGKOK, Thailand (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Soldiers manned barricades in <LOCATION> Burma </LOCATION>'s capital Monday and most shops were closed as merchants heeded student calls for a nationwide strike to demand a return to democracy, <ORGANIZATION> Kyodo </ORGANIZATION> news service said The general strike was expected to be a test for President <PERSON> Maung </PERSON> <PERSON> Maung </PERSON>, who came to power Friday and is <LOCATION> Burma </LOCATION>'s first civilian leader in the 26 years since a military coup replaced democracy with one-party rule. A messenger representing student groups, defying an 8 p.m. to 4 a.m. curfew, ran through residential areas of <LOCATION> Rangoon </LOCATION> to rally support for the strike, the Japanese news agency reported from the <LOCATION> Burmese </LOCATION> capital. Soldiers stood at major points in the center of <LOCATION> Rangoon </LOCATION>, where barbed wire barricades had been erected to guard against demonstrators, <ORGANIZATION> Kyodo </ORGANIZATION> said, adding that people were seen cutting palm trees on the roads to set up barricades against the military. The report quoted unidentified sources as saying a large number of demonstrators rode trucks into the capital on Sunday night. An <LOCATION> Asian </LOCATION> diplomat in <LOCATION> Rangoon </LOCATION> said the city was `` relatively quiet'' Monday morning. For the sixth straight day Sunday, authorities released people arrested in <LOCATION> Rangoon </LOCATION> during Aug. 8-12 riots that prompted the resignation of <PERSON> Maung </PERSON> <PERSON> Maung </PERSON>'s predecessor, <PERSON> Sein </PERSON> <PERSON> Lwin </PERSON>, after only 17 days in power. Troops fired into crowds of demonstrators in the riots, and the government said 112 people were killed. Official Radio <LOCATION> Rangoon </LOCATION> said 100 people were freed Sunday, bringing the total reported released in <LOCATION> Rangoon </LOCATION> to 408. Thousands of people are still believed detained. On Saturday, people demonstrated peacefully in <LOCATION> Mandalay </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Burma </LOCATION>'s second-largest city, and in five other towns, according to Radio <LOCATION> Rangoon </LOCATION> The state-run newspaper <ORGANIZATION> Working </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> reported Saturday that during the Aug. 8-12 protests, hysterical mobs decapitated at least five people, including three police officers, in the <LOCATION> Rangoon </LOCATION> suburb of <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Okkalapa </LOCATION>. `` Two of the -LRB- policemen's -RRB- heads were stuck on bamboo poles and one was put on a stool for all to see,'' according to the newspaper, obtained Sunday from a Western embassy in <LOCATION> Bangkok </LOCATION>. The report said the protesters then burned the bodies. One of the victims was a civilian mistaken for an intelligence agent and beheaded after a mob stoned him to death, it said. `` The leader of the demonstration in <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Okkalapa </LOCATION> township wore a hood to hide his face as he screamed at the top of his voice for the emergence of the ` <PERSON> Aung </PERSON> <PERSON> Gyi </PERSON> government,''' the newspaper said. <PERSON> Aung </PERSON> <PERSON> Gyi </PERSON>, the country's leading dissident, was arrested with several other prominent figures July 29-30. Among those seized was Sein Win, the <LOCATION> Burma </LOCATION> correspondent of <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>. The wave of turmoil in <LOCATION> Burma </LOCATION> began July 27, when leader <PERSON> Ne </PERSON> <PERSON> Win </PERSON> resigned and <PERSON> Sein </PERSON> <PERSON> Lwin </PERSON> came to power. A retired army general, <PERSON> Sein </PERSON> <PERSON> Lwin </PERSON> was widely hated for ruthlessly suppressing dissent, and disturbances began almost immediately. At first peaceful, the demonstrations became violent on Aug. 8 and security personnel fired shots to disperse the crowds. Some protesters fought back and the government said 112 people were killed and 267 wounded in <LOCATION> Rangoon </LOCATION>. Diplomats there believe hundreds may have been killed. The violence continued until Aug. 12, when <PERSON> Sein </PERSON> <PERSON> Lwin </PERSON> resigned. But smaller, student-led protests continued almost daily to press for an end to one-party rule and for economic reforms. The <LOCATION> Asian </LOCATION> diplomat said the government was unlikely to agree to multi-party democracy after a quarter-century of iron-fisted control by the <ORGANIZATION> Burma </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Socialist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Program </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, founded by Gen. Ne Win. The general led the March 2, 1962, coup that toppled the elected government of Prime Minister U Nu. <LOCATION> Burmese </LOCATION> media also have rejected the idea of returning to a multi-party system, noting in recent days that the government during <LOCATION> Burma </LOCATION>'s 14 years of democracy was corrupt and inefficient. But officials have said in recent days that the current government also is corrupt. A <LOCATION> Western </LOCATION> diplomat, who asked for anonymity, said Saturday that <PERSON> Maung </PERSON> <PERSON> Maung </PERSON> has remained silent on the issue. The president did not flatly reject democracy in his speech Friday before the emergency party session that elected him.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880822-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-22-88 0045EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     08-22 0964</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,1005</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names In The News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CHICAGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 It's been two decades but fans still go ape for the <ORGANIZATION> Monkees </ORGANIZATION> _ the musicians, not the primates A new generation of fans gathered by the thousands this weekend to pay homage to the group at the 1988 Official Monkees Convention. `` I have practically memorized every show,'' said <PERSON> Lisa </PERSON> <PERSON> Mason </PERSON>, 15, of <LOCATION> Portsmouth </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, about the television series that showcased the madcap Monkees. `` I have a crush on <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> -LRB- <PERSON> Nesmith </PERSON> -RRB- because he's the strong, silent type.'' The band, which had six Top 10 hits during the series that ran from 1966 to 1968, is enjoying a revival of its show on cable television. `` I'm closer in spirit to their ages now,'' guitarist <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Tork </PERSON>, 46, said Saturday before performing at convention. `` I thought I was older then.'' <PERSON> Tork </PERSON> was joined by fellow <PERSON> Monkees </PERSON> <PERSON> Micky </PERSON> <PERSON> Dolenz </PERSON> and <PERSON> Davy </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> at the convention, but <PERSON> Nesmith </PERSON> declined to attend.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Spanish crooner <PERSON> Julio </PERSON> <PERSON> Iglesias </PERSON> says his new album, Nonstop, was a source of non-stop worry for him. `` The more I listened, the more insecure I got,'' <PERSON> Iglesias </PERSON> said in an interview in this week's People magazine. `` I had a big depression and all kinds of psychosomatic problems,'' he said. `` My new album is like a beautiful candle without a fire. Now I have to find a way to put the fire in the candle.'' `` Nonstop,'' his second English-language album, was released in May and stalled at No. 52 on <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> pop charts. `` If I go to <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> or <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>, I am established for a whole generation,'' said <PERSON> Iglesias </PERSON>, 44. `` But in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, they know me for selling too many records and making love to too many women.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Dale </PERSON> <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> and <PERSON> Doug </PERSON> <PERSON> McClure </PERSON> now can saunter down the Western Walk and find their names gracing the lineup of Western luminaries. <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON>, the 65-year-old rugged star of Western films and television series, and <PERSON> McClure </PERSON>, 53, a leading man in television Westerns, were inducted Saturday in the Western Walk of Fame. The two were honored along with the late <PERSON> Hoot </PERSON> <PERSON> Gibson </PERSON> at a ceremony that drew 600 Western buffs and some past inductees, who celebrated with a barbecue and square dance. The Western Walk was started in 1981 and is modeled after the famous <ORGANIZATION> Hollywood </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Walk </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fame </ORGANIZATION>, in which star's names are imbedded in the sidewalk. `` Frankly, <PERSON> Scarlett </PERSON>, I do n't give a damn!'' <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> bellowed during the ceremony, explaining later that <PERSON> Clark </PERSON> <PERSON> Gable </PERSON>'s line from `` Gone With The Wind'' was n't meant to insult the Western Walk. `` I'm just glad to be honored for anything.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>PETERBOROUGH, N.H. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Author <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Styron </PERSON> expressed ambivalence about adding the prestigious <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> MacDowell </PERSON> <PERSON> Medal </PERSON> to a room already bulging with trophies, honorary cups and plaques. `` I am a Gemini with a bifurcated ego,'' <PERSON> Styron </PERSON>, author of `` Sophie's Choice'' and `` The Confessions of <PERSON> Nat </PERSON> <PERSON> Turner </PERSON>,'' said Sunday at the <ORGANIZATION> MacDowell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Colony </ORGANIZATION> for artists. `` One branch ... delights in being stroked, while the other emits howls.'' Joining the ranks of 28 previous medalists including <PERSON> Leonard </PERSON> <PERSON> Bernstein </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Georgia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> O'Keeffe </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON> <PERSON> Calder </PERSON> and <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Updike </PERSON>, <PERSON> Styron </PERSON> questioned whether awards and medals might actually hinder an artist's progress. `` It's hard to believe that medals and honors might have improved the quality of the work of our literary ancestors,'' <PERSON> Styron </PERSON> said, noting that <PERSON> Edgar </PERSON> <PERSON> Allan </PERSON> <PERSON> Poe </PERSON>, <PERSON> Nathaniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Hawthorne </PERSON>, <PERSON> Emily </PERSON> <PERSON> Dickinson </PERSON> and <PERSON> Walt </PERSON> <PERSON> Whitman </PERSON> never received awards. `` The immense and fomented loneliness of the writers of that time ... makes it plausible to think they might have been violated, perhaps irreparably, had that loneliness been intruded upon by anxiety over winning a prize,'' he said.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>Eds: Longer versions of the following two items moved on sports</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 wire.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Yankees </ORGANIZATION> star <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Mattingly </PERSON> says he's disillusioned with this season and indirectly blamed owner <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Steinbrenner </PERSON> for the team's recent fade in the American League East `` The players get no respect around here. They give you money, that's it. Not respect. Money is not respect,'' <PERSON> Mattingly </PERSON> said Sunday after a 4-2 loss to <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> Yankees </ORGANIZATION>, who held first place from May 3 to June 19, have lost three in a row and nine of 13. They fell six games behind division-leading <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION>, their biggest deficit this season. When <PERSON> Mattingly </PERSON> signed a three-year contract last spring, he `` guaranteed'' this would be the <ORGANIZATION> Yankees </ORGANIZATION>' year. The <ORGANIZATION> Yankees </ORGANIZATION> have not won the division since 1981. At midseason, <PERSON> Steinbrenner </PERSON> criticized <PERSON> Mattingly </PERSON> for not producing enough. <PERSON> Steinbrenner </PERSON> also blasted <ORGANIZATION> Yankee </ORGANIZATION> stars <PERSON> Rickey </PERSON> <PERSON> Henderson </PERSON> and <PERSON> Dave </PERSON> <PERSON> Winfield </PERSON>. `` You ca n't get beaten over the head every day and want to play. It's hard to come to the ballpark every day when you're unhappy,'' <PERSON> Mattingly </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>INDIANAPOLIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Kimball </PERSON>'s determined bid for a return trip to the Olympics ended with tears, hugs and happiness for a group that protested the possibility of him representing the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> next month. <PERSON> Kimball </PERSON>, an Olympic silver medalist in 1984, finished fourth Sunday in his best event _ the 10-meter platform _ after earlier finishing sixth in springboard at the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Olympic diving trials. At an emotional news conference, <PERSON> Kimball </PERSON> announced last week he would compete despite facing charges in connection with an Aug. 1 auto accident in which two people were killed and six were injured. <PERSON> Kimball </PERSON> is free on $ 10,000 bond and charged with five felony counts of driving under the influence pending his Aug. 29 arraignment. `` I just gave him a hug and told him I loved him and told him I was proud of him,'' said his father, <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Kimball </PERSON>, a veteran Olympic coach. The elder <PERSON> Kimball </PERSON>, however, will make the trip to <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION> to coach <PERSON> Wendy </PERSON> <PERSON> Lucero </PERSON>, one of his divers who qualified in the women's springboard event
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880822-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-22-88 0050EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lites     08-22 0521</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lites,0544</SECOND>
<HEAD>On The Lite Side</HEAD>
<DATELINE>STAMFORD, Conn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON> <PERSON> Hoylman </PERSON> spent much of the weekend puzzling down and across before coming up as winner of the 11th Annual American Crossword Puzzle Tournament. Hoylman, of <LOCATION> Chevy </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Chase </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Md. </LOCATION>, took 10 minutes and 44 seconds to perfectly fill in a crossword puzzle Sunday at the competition that drew puzzle aces from around the country, according to tournament director <PERSON> Will </PERSON> <PERSON> Shortz </PERSON>. The three finalists from a field of 136 reached the playoff round after scoring points on accuracy and speed in earlier rounds. <PERSON> Hoylman </PERSON>'s first-place efforts won him $ 500. Second place finisher was <PERSON> Jon </PERSON> <PERSON> Delfin </PERSON>, a pianist from <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, who clocked 13 minutes and 4 seconds to finish the puzzle without an error. <PERSON> Ellen </PERSON> <PERSON> Ripstein </PERSON> of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> scored the best time of 7 minutes 19 seconds, but she had one error. <PERSON> Shortz </PERSON> said the final puzzle was very difficult and offered some examples: `` One clue was ` court pronouncement' which make you think about the legal area but the answer actually was ` game, set and match' in the tennis court.'' Another clue was the state in which you might see stars. `` It's supposed to make you thnk about <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, but the anwer was ` senseless,''' he said. The competition was sponsored by the publishers of the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Herald </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tribune </ORGANIZATION> Crosswords magazines.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Supermarket checker <PERSON> Vicki </PERSON> <PERSON> McClure </PERSON> says she's glad her moment in the spotlight as solo singer at the opening of the 1984 Olympic Summer Games did n't catapult her to instant success `` I'm not disappointed for what has happened because being thrust in at that level with my inexperience would have been a mistake,'' <PERSON> McClure </PERSON> said. `` I really would n't have had an inkling of how to handle it.'' Still, she has fond memories of the grand event four years ago. `` It was the most spectacular moment. It was bigger than life,'' she said recently. `` It was a really magical experience.'' Ms. <PERSON> McClure </PERSON> sang the hit, `` Reach Out and Touch -LRB- Somebody's Hand -RRB-'' at the opening ceremonies of the 1984 Olympics at <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> Memorial Coliseum The $ 7 million opening ceremony had a cast of thousands and was staged before a capacity crowd of 90,000 and an international television audience. The show included a 1,000-voice choir, a 750-piece marching band, a 100-piece symphony orchestra, 7,500 athletes and 2,500 pigeons. Ms. <PERSON> McClure </PERSON>, who was 30 at the time, appeared as the lead singer in the <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jazz </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Choir </LOCATION>, a position originally intended for a star of the caliber of <PERSON> Diana </PERSON> <PERSON> Ross </PERSON>. But after Olympics officials heard her sing, they chose her to perform because they liked the idea of having an unknown singer. `` It was kind of in keeping with the amateur spirit of the Olympics,'' she said. Ms. <PERSON> McClure </PERSON> said she is happy working as a professional singer, performing at banquets and ceremonies and with the group Daddy's Money, which performs nostalgic and rhythm and blues songs `` I have n't really done a <PERSON> Vicki </PERSON> <PERSON> McClure </PERSON> act as of yet,'' she said. `` I'm still looking for a repertoire. It's hard to find material you're comfortable with by yourself.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880822-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-22-88 0057EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Panama-Harassment 2ndLd-Writethru a0736 08-22 0782</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Panama-Harassment, 2nd Ld - Writethru, a0736,0798</SECOND>
<HEAD>U.S. Officials Say Harassment Of U.S. Military in Panama Increases</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: INSERTS graf after 3rd graf `Noriega is...' with summary of
PDF statement. Pickup 4th graf pvs `Ms. Farrell...'; INSERTS 2
grafs after 14th pvs, `The story...' with more from statement.
Picks up 15th graf pvs, `Washington imposed ...'</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By RAFAEL CANDANEDO</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PANAMA CITY, Panama (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military personnel are reporting increased harassment by local officials, but there is no indication the actions are part of a new campaign by the government of Gen. <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> authorities said Sunday. <PERSON> Cynthia </PERSON> <PERSON> Farrell </PERSON>, a spokeswoman for the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION>, said the incidents involved harassment, `` not attacks.'' <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> is commander of <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forces </ORGANIZATION> and controls the civilian government. He was indicted in February by two grand juries in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> on drug trafficking charges and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has imposed economic sanctions in an effort to force him to resign and leave <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>. A statement by the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forces </ORGANIZATION> late Sunday called the accusations of harassment part of a campaign of disinformation in an effort to destabilize <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> and listed numerous allegations of misconduct by <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> forces in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>. Ms. <PERSON> Farrell </PERSON> said the reports of harassment are coming only from <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military personnel. `` Civilians, business people and embassy personnel have reported no increase in harassment,'' she said. She added she did not know if <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military personnel are being bothered more or are `` simply reporting more cases.'' An official at the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Command </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>, who spoke on condition of anonymity, said 240 cases of harassment had been reported between February and August of this year. He said incidents of harassment have increased in number and gravity but denied reports the incidents were being considered attacks. `` What's going on these days has been going on for months _ going way back to last year,'' the official said. `` If there was an increase, it probably came in January, February, March and April, not in the last month or two.'' `` One of the things that's happening is that a lot of people are being asked for bribes when they're stopped for traffic violations, and that's probably because the police are n't getting paid regularly'' the official said. <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s economy has been damaged by the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> sanctions. The Southern Command official said a more serious incident occurred last week when <ORGANIZATION> Panamanian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forces </ORGANIZATION> officers refused to let <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military vehicles pick up mail for three days at <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>'s international airport. The dispute was resolved after three days, the official said, but he did not elaborate. The <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> on Sunday quoted <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Southern Command, State and <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> officials as saying there have been an increasing number of beatings, abductions, rape and extortion of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military personnel and their dependents in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>. The story, under a <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> dateline, said the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials view the incidents as a campaign by <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> to pressure the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> to lift economic sanctions against <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>. The Defense Forces statement said: `` The supposed <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government officials -LRB- cited by the Times -RRB- must have the IQ of a 3-year-old Cro-Magnon when they assert that actions taken by the <ORGANIZATION> Panama </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forces </ORGANIZATION> against <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military personnel are attempts to force the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration to lift or soften economic sanctions imposed on <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>.'' The statement said <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> troops cause daily problems for Panamanian authorities, including fights, mistreatment of women, venereal disease, shooting in public places and refusing to pay bar and restaurant tabs. <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> imposed economic sanctions on <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> in March after the <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> ousted President <PERSON> Eric </PERSON> <PERSON> Arturo </PERSON> <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON>. <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON> has since been in hiding, but the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> continues to recognize him as <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s legitimate president. About 12,000 <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> servicemen are stationed in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> by treaty to protect the <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Canal </LOCATION>, a vital waterway linking the <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> oceans. They are attached to the <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Command </ORGANIZATION>, which is in charge of all <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military operations south of the U.S.-Mexico border. The first Southern Command official reached by The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> acknowledged several specific incidents reported by the Times, including a case in June in which an enlisted man and his wife were assaulted at gunpoint by a man described as a Panamanian military officer. The assailant forced the enlisted man into the trunk of his car, then beat and raped his wife. `` The individual was dressed in a camouflaged uniform, but he could have been military, paramilitary, a civilian guard or just some guy who knows somebody in the PDF -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> Panamanian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forces </ORGANIZATION> -RRB- and somehow managed to get himself a uniform,'' said the Southern Command official. `` As far as I know, we do n't have a definite description or identification.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880822-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-22-88 0115EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-VeteransBenefits Bjt   08-22 0718</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Veterans Benefits, Bjt,730</SECOND>
<HEAD>VA Bungled Files but Favored Few Got Special Treatment</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LARRY MARGASAK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> panel says the Veterans Administration made numerous errors as it hurriedly processed disability claims but had time to give special treatment to applicants who `` had the ear'' of influential lawmakers. A <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Government </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Operations </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> report, released Sunday, described two separate systems for handling claims. Applicants without `` pull'' had their cases rushed to judgment by error-prone managers trying to win pay bonuses for meeting production quotas, the report said. But the panel said the <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Veterans </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appeals </ORGANIZATION> _ the court of last resort for claimants whose benefits were denied _ `` maintained a list of congressmen who should be brought to the <ORGANIZATION> BVA </ORGANIZATION> chairman's attention if they inquire about an appeal. At a hearing last February by the panel's subcommittee on human resources, a former appeals board member, <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> J.B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bierman </PERSON>, was asked whether there was preferential treatment when a lawmaker on the list intervened. <PERSON> Bierman </PERSON> replied, `` It is difficult for me to say, but I suspect that to be the case, sir. Otherwise, there would be no reason for it -LRB- the list -RRB-.'' `` The BVA ... showed favoritism to claimants who had the ear of certain influential members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>,'' the committee concluded. The <ORGANIZATION> VA </ORGANIZATION> said in a statement it `` has not been provided with a copy of the committee's report and is obviously disadvantaged by the fact that it was released to the media before it came to us. We intend to review it thoroughly when it is received.'' VA officials refused to reply to the panel's specific allegations. Addressing the appeals board's quota system, the report said, `` The <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Veterans </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appeals </ORGANIZATION> ... was so caught up in an unreasonable production quota standard, that some members were deciding cases at the rate of one every eight minutes.'' The committee noted that earlier this year, the <ORGANIZATION> VA </ORGANIZATION> ended production-based bonuses and preferential treatment after both practices were publicized in subcommittee hearings and challenged in a lawsuit filed by <ORGANIZATION> Vietnam </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Veterans </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION>. The report suggested that <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> end a 55-year-old prohibition and allow veterans who are denied benefits to appeal their cases in federal court. In 1987, veterans won less than 13 percent of the time under the now-abolished quota system at the <ORGANIZATION> VA </ORGANIZATION> appeals board. The committee said the <ORGANIZATION> VA </ORGANIZATION> tried to cover up its frequent mistakes in disability claims by deliberately under-reporting the error rate to staffers for the human resources subcommittee, headed by Rep. <PERSON> Ted </PERSON> <PERSON> Weiss </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> VA </ORGANIZATION> approves about $ 11 billion in disability benefits annually to 2.5 million veterans, widows and children. While some veterans were improperly denied benefits under the <ORGANIZATION> VA </ORGANIZATION>'s error-plagued system, others may have received money to which they were not entitled, according to committee staffers Nine of the 15 Republicans on the 38-member committee filed dissenting views disagreeing with the recommendation for court appeals. `` While we share the committee's concerns about ... practices such as production quotas ... we can not support the committee's inference that the -LRB- appeals board -RRB- does not have the best interests of the veterans in mind,'' they said The report did not give exact numbers of errors, but cited a 1984 internal study of 1,700 cases by <ORGANIZATION> VA </ORGANIZATION> lawyer <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Abrams </PERSON>. He found: _ A `` substantive'' error rate of 8.4 percent that led to denial of claims that should have been approved This category refers to mathematical and other factual errors. _ An 18.2 percent `` judgmental'' error rate, in which the wrong decision was made even though the data used to render the opinion were accurate _ A `` procedural'' error rate of 21.5 percent, in cases where the mistake did not affect the final benefit determination The VA, however, gave the subcommittee lower error rates for the 1983-87 period: substantive errors, 1.02 percent to 1.73 percent; judgmental errors, 1.11 percent to 1.81 percent, and procedural discrepancies, 3.91 percent to 5.09 percent. The <ORGANIZATION> VA </ORGANIZATION>'s quota system was described to the subcommittee earlier this year by <PERSON> Ernest </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>, a member of the <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Veterans </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appeals </ORGANIZATION>, and <PERSON> Bierman </PERSON>. `` They testified that <ORGANIZATION> BVA </ORGANIZATION> members ... had production quotas of 40 cases per week, which if fulfilled, could result in merit pay increases as high as 5 percent of a member's pay,'' the report said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880822-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-22-88 0122EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-TeenLine     08-22 0722</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Teen Line,0745</SECOND>
<HEAD>Teen-agers Help Peers Via Telephone Hotline</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto LA6</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Note publishable editor's note at end.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By LISA WOLFSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 It's 8 o'clock at night and <PERSON> Tiffany </PERSON> <PERSON> Gardner </PERSON> is lying on a couch, a pillow over her head to block the light and a telephone pressed to her ear. It's a common scene for a 17-year-old whiling away a summer before senior year in high school. But <PERSON> Tiffany </PERSON> is at work and she is speaking to a stranger _ an unmarried 19-year-old girl who recently had a baby. `` Her parents ignored her pregnancy and her boyfriend is away in the military,'' said the volunteer listener at <ORGANIZATION> Teen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Line </ORGANIZATION>, a teen-to-teen hotline. `` She was just really depressed,'' <PERSON> Tiffany </PERSON> said. `` She was n't looking for advice, just someone to listen. In the seven years since Teen Line began, more than 50,000 calls have come in to people like <PERSON> Tiffany </PERSON>, who was on duty during a recent night with three other teen listeners and an adult health care professional. The listeners work out of <ORGANIZATION> Cedars-Sinai </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in an office where nearly every inch of wall space is covered with referral numbers to hundreds of service organizations such as Planned Parenthood, Suicide Prevention, the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Child </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> and AIDS information centers. `` When teens are in need, no matter what their socio-economic status, they contact their peers,'' said psychiatrist Dr. <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Lipton </PERSON>, president of <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> the </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Study </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Young </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> in </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Groups </ORGANIZATION> and co-founder of Teen Line. `` They wo n't talk to school counselors, psychiatrists or priests, but what they will do is pick up the phone and call a friend.'' Teen Line is staffed nightly from 6 p.m. to 10 p.m. Off-hour callers can leave a message and their call will be returned by a teen listener. <PERSON> Lipton </PERSON> and <PERSON> Elaine </PERSON> <PERSON> Leader </PERSON>, a senior staff member at <ORGANIZATION> Cedar-Sinai </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Psychiatry </ORGANIZATION> and program coordinator of <ORGANIZATION> Teen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Line </ORGANIZATION>, say it is one of the most cost-efficient ways to provide mental health services to adolescents Most callers are between ages 13-19, although parents sometimes phone to get a teen-ager's perspective on problems their children are experiencing, Ms. <PERSON> Leader </PERSON> said. Most calls deal with boyfriend-girlfriend problems, but the listeners often hear from pregnant teens, those seeking sexual advice, and child-abuse victims. From 3 percent to 4 percent of the Teen Line calls are suicidal, Ms. <PERSON> Leader </PERSON> said. The volunteer listeners are carefully screened before being accepted, then must train 12 weeks before answering a hotline phone. The training focuses on developing rapport, crisis intervention, addictive behaviors, all aspects of sexuality, family problems and more. The volunteers must attend either a recovery program meeting such as Alcoholics Anonymous or Overeaters Anonymous, participate in a Teen Line outreach program in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> high schools, attend monthly staff meetings and commit one night per week to the hotline. <PERSON> Lipton </PERSON>, Ms. <PERSON> Leader </PERSON> and other adult specialists unaffiliated with the program have few reservations about allowing teen-agers to take on the responsibility of suicide calls. `` These young people are in that position anyway,'' <PERSON> Lipton </PERSON> said. `` On a daily basis they are in school with kids and peers who constantly give clues about their own despair.'' The listeners establish if the caller is suicidal through a series of questions. `` We'll ask them, ` Have you ever tried it before? How did you do it? What kinds of pills were they? Do you have them with you now?''' said <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> <PERSON> Yorra </PERSON>, 17, a high school senior who has been a listener for the past year. The callers are encouraged to telephone as often as they want but not to establish a relationship with their listener. `` In that case, they often need ongoing professional therapy,'' Ms. <PERSON> Leader </PERSON> said. Calls are confidential and records are kept only of the caller's age, sex and type of problem Listeners try, however, to get abuse victims to report their cases to the county <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Child </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> for immediate action. The hospital provides the office and phones, and the hotline's estimated $ 150,000 in annual costs are covered by individual donations and corporate grants Last November, an 800 number was established for the entire state. Ms. Leader is hoping to expand the service nationwide.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Teen Line can be reached at -LRB- 213 -RRB- 855-HOPE, or toll-free in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> 1-800-TLC-TEEN.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880822-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-22-88 0122EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-LuccheseTrial Bjt   08-22 0639</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lucchese Trial, Bjt,0661</SECOND>
<HEAD>Mob Trial Concluding After Nearly Two Years</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NR1</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DANIEL J. WAKIN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEWARK, N.J. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
