<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880702-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-02-88 0037EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-RoarkRelease     07-02 0278</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Roark Release,0285</SECOND>
<HEAD>Former Charleston Mayor Earns Early Release For Good Behavior</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KELLY P. KISSEL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CHARLESTON, W.Va. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Former <LOCATION> Charleston </LOCATION> Mayor <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Roark </PERSON> will be released from federal prison 18 days early because he has been a model prisoner while serving time for cocaine possession, authorities said Friday. <PERSON> Roark </PERSON>, who was sentenced to 179 days in prison in November after pleading guilty to cocaine possession, will be released July 20, said <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Sizer </PERSON>, director of the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Correctional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institution </ORGANIZATION> at <LOCATION> Petersburg </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va </LOCATION>. The former <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> mayor and <LOCATION> Kanawha </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> prosecutor will be credited with 16 days of time for good behavior and two days for time served after his arrest, <PERSON> Sizer </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Roark </PERSON>, who earned the nickname `` Mad Dog'' for his zealous prosecution of drug offenders during his days as <LOCATION> Kanawha </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> prosecutor, had just started his second four-year term when he was indicted. <PERSON> Roark </PERSON> was indicted in July 1987 on 27 cocaine-related counts and three charges of conspiracy to obstruct justice. All but six misdemeanor possession counts were dropped in a plea bargain in which he agreed to resign his office. A spokesman for the State Bar this week said <PERSON> Roark </PERSON> will be called in for a hearing soon after his release. The bar is deciding whether to revoke or suspend his license as a result of his guilty plea. <PERSON> Roark </PERSON> served as an assistant <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> attorney in western <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> in the mid-1970s before returning to <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>'s largest city to begin his political career in 1978 He never lost an election and had been talked up as a future <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> candidate for governor or <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> before his legal problems started.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880702-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-02-88 0038EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-PitBullCollars     07-02 0209</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Pit Bull Collars,0213</SECOND>
<HEAD>Pit Bulls, Other Animals Must Wear Fluorescent Collars</HEAD>
<DATELINE>GALVESTON, Texas (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Postal workers cheered as the city council approved a law requiring vicious animals to wear fluorescent yellow collars and some owners to take out liability insurance on their pets. The law, passed Thursday in response to pit bull attacks, requires vicious animals to wear the collars, which signify the wearer has attacked humans or other animals or has been legally declared likely to do so without provocation. The ordinance also requires that an animal declared vicious be tattooed with the number that appears on the permit allowing the owner to keep it inside the city limits. In addition, owners of vicious animals can be forced to carry at least $ 100,000 in liability insurance to keep the pets in the city and can be fined up to $ 2,000 for violations of the new ordinance. Local letter carriers who gathered in council chambers cheered Thursday when the ordinance was passed. A <LOCATION> Galveston </LOCATION> postal worker was severely bitten by a pit bull in January, and an 83-year-old man died from wounds inflicted in a November attack by two pit bulls. `` I hope this action today will save lives in the future,'' Mayor <PERSON> Jan </PERSON> <PERSON> Coggeshall </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880702-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-02-88 0038EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Cat-NappingBurglar     07-02 0195</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Cat-Napping Burglar,0201</SECOND>
<HEAD>Police Catch Man After He Falls Asleep During Burglary Search</HEAD>
<DATELINE>RIVERSIDE, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Police searching a department store for a burglar arrested a man after the sound of his snoring led them to a store air duct where he was sleeping. `` We woke the young man up and took him to jail,'' police Lt. <PERSON> Ellis </PERSON> <PERSON> Asper </PERSON> said Thursday. The search began Wednesday night when the <ORGANIZATION> Montgomery </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ward </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>'s silent alarm was tripped. Officers looked through the store windows and saw a man wearing black, <PERSON> Asper </PERSON> said. Eight officers searched the roof and the store, a police helicopter circled overhead and two police dogs sniffed about, but the burglar could not be found, <PERSON> Asper </PERSON> said. By 5 a.m. Thursday, all but two officers were called off the search. Then, a noise that sounded like snoring drew Officer <PERSON> Warren </PERSON> <PERSON> Holm </PERSON> to the air duct above the ceiling panels over the store's optometrist Near <PERSON> Vincent </PERSON> <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Torres </PERSON>' sleeping body, police found ropes, a knapsack, and about $ 3,800 worth of videotape recording equipment, <PERSON> Asper </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Torres </PERSON>, 18, was being held in <LOCATION> Riverside </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jail </LOCATION> in lieu of $ 5,000 bail for investigation of burglary.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880702-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-02-88 0123EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-TanglewoodAnniversary     07-02 0228</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Tanglewood Anniversary,0232</SECOND>
<HEAD>Boston Symphony Orchestra Celebrates 50th Anniversary of First
Shed Concert</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LENOX, Mass. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Tanglewood </LOCATION>, the summer home of the <ORGANIZATION> Boston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Symphony </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Orchestra </ORGANIZATION>, observed the 50th birthday of its Music Shed with a 50-candle cake and a reunion of musicians and ushers from the shed's first concert. Also in honor of the half-century-old concert hall, symphony trustees voted Friday to rename the Music Shed after the late conductor <PERSON> Serge </PERSON> <PERSON> Koussevitzky </PERSON>, founder of the prestigious summer music festival who inaugurated the hall with a performance of <PERSON> Beethoven </PERSON>'s Ninth Symphony and <PERSON> Bach </PERSON>'s Cantata No. 80 in 1938. <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kidder </PERSON>, symphony president, played tapes of <PERSON> Koussevitzky </PERSON>, giving his reasons for choosing <PERSON> Beethoven </PERSON>'s Ninth Symphony for the inaugural performance, which the symphony orchestra played again Friday night. `` On this significant day in the musical life, I have selected to give the Ninth Symphony not only because it is the greatest masterpiece in the musical literature, but also to hear the voices of <LOCATION> Tanglewood </LOCATION> repeating -LRB- German poet <PERSON> Johann </PERSON> -RRB- <PERSON> Shiller </PERSON>'s great words calling all nations to brotherhood,'' <PERSON> Koussevitsky </PERSON> said on one of the tapes. During a break in the program, <PERSON> Kidder </PERSON> also introduced several people who had been at the 1938 performance, including three ushers. Orchestra members and concert-goers who were present at the Aug. 4, 1938, inaugural performance were honored at a luncheon Friday at <PERSON> Koussevitzky </PERSON>'s home, <PERSON> Seranak </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880702-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-02-88 0123EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lottery     07-02 0025</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lottery,0024</SECOND>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the winning weekly state lottery numbers picked Friday:
</TEXT>
<HEAD>CONNECTICUT</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Lotto: 07; 20; 27; 30; 33; 34.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880702-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-02-88 0125EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-LotteryRdp     07-02 0083</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lottery Rdp,0088</SECOND>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the winning weekly state lottery numbers picked so far this week:
</TEXT>
<HEAD>CONNECTICUT</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Lotto: 07; 20; 27; 30; 33; 34.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>DELAWARE</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Play 4: 4-1-8-9.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>MASSACHUSETTS</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Wednesday Megabucks: 01; 08; 11; 18; 27; 29.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>NEW JERSEY</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Pick 6 Lotto: 18; 19; 21; 33; 40; 42. Bonus: 38270.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>NEW YORK</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Wednesday Lotto 54 Game: 13; 27; 31; 32; 37; 53. Supplementary 20.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>PENNSYLVANIA</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Big 4 Lottery: 6-7-5-1.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>RHODE ISLAND</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Grand Lot Game: 1-2-8; 2-3-1-9; 7-3-1-6-6; 7-7-5-9-3-3.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880702-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-02-88 0012EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-Reagan-Medicare 2ndLd-Writethru a0803 07-02 0771</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Reagan-Medicare, 2nd Ld-Writethru, a0803,760</SECOND>
<NOTE>Eds: SUBS 10th graf pvs, bgng: ``The flat ...'' to CORRECT figure
to $10.20 sted $10.10 for increase in 1993.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By W. DALE NELSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> on Friday signed a major expansion of Medicare to provide insurance against lingering major illnesses but warned future presidents and Congresses to keep the cost down lest it grow into `` a program we ca n't afford.'' `` Every administration since the <ORGANIZATION> Medicare </ORGANIZATION> program was passed has worried about the seemingly uncontrollable cost increases in our government health care programs,'' <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said at a ceremony in the White House Rose Garden. `` Whoever the president in office, program costs have exceeded the best congressional budget estimates,'' he said. `` Unless we are careful, it is possible that aspects of this legislation will do the same.'' The bill is the first substantial expansion of Medicare since it was established in 1965. Major portions of the new program will take effect in 1989, with some provisions phased in over subsequent years. <ORGANIZATION> Medicare </ORGANIZATION> officials plan to mail a pamphlet to all beneficiaries explaining details of the changes. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> noted that the legislation provides new benefits for the nation's 32 million Medicare recipients, including prescription drugs and care provided to patients in their homes. `` We have no real way of knowinghow much these services will cost,'' he said. `` So if future administrations and Congresses are n't diligent, these new benefits could contribute to a program we ca n't afford. `` This could be more than a budget problem. It could be a tragedy. The program, after all, is to be paid for by the elderly themselves. So we must control the costs of these new benefits or we'll harm the very people we are trying to help.'' <ORGANIZATION> Medicare </ORGANIZATION> enrollees will pay for the additional benefits through a flat increase in the premium deducted from monthly Social Security checks and an additional sliding scale premium on the approximately 40 percent of the elderly who pay federal income tax. The flat increase will be $ 4 a month in 1989, climbing to $ 10.20 in 1993. The sliding scale premium is projected to rise from a maximum of 15 percent of regular income tax liability in 1989 to about 28 percent in 1993. `` If administered with prudence, this program can povide countless Americans with peace of mind,'' the president said. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> has long been a foe of expanded federal welfare and other programs. However, he said the catastrophic-illness insurance is needed to `` help remove a terrible threat from the lives of elderly and disabled Americans, the threat of an illness requiring acute care, one so devastating that it could wipe out the savings of an entire lifetime.'' The new program provides full hospital coverage after a once-a-year deductible. The deductible is estimated at $ 564 in 1989 and is designed to rise with hospital inflation. <ORGANIZATION> Medicare </ORGANIZATION> now pays full charges for no more than 59 days a year. The recipient is subject to a deductible for each hospitalization. <ORGANIZATION> Medicare </ORGANIZATION> now pays 80 percent of approved doctor bills after a $ 75 deductible. This will continue to be the case for the first $ 1,370 a year, but above that the legislation provides that <ORGANIZATION> Medicare </ORGANIZATION> will pay the approved bills in full. The recipient will still have to pay any amount over the fee approved by <ORGANIZATION> Medicare </ORGANIZATION>. The measure also provides a new benefit in which <ORGANIZATION> Medicare </ORGANIZATION> will pay half of outpatient prescription drug costs in 1991 after a $ 600 deductible is met. The government share rises to 60 percent in 1992 and 80 percent in 1993. The deductible is also expected to increase each year to keep pace with rising drug costs. Medicare does not cover outpatient drugs now, except for a few very expensive ones such anti-rejection medication for organ transplant recipients. Another new benefit is so-called respite care, covering up to 80 hours a year for a nurse or home health aide to relieve a family caring for a patient at home. It will be available to those who exceed the limit on out-of-pocket expenses for doctors' care or the prescription drug deductible. Also for the first time, <ORGANIZATION> Medicare </ORGANIZATION> will pay for breast cancer-detecting mammograms at specified frequencies, starting in 1990. The limit on such payments will be $ 50 per mammogram at first, but may be increased later if fees rise. The legislation is the product of a <ORGANIZATION> Senate-House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> conference </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> committee </ORGANIZATION> that met from February until May to hammer out a compromise version of separate bills approved by the two chambers. The final measure passed the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, 238-72, on June 2 and sailed through the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>, 86-11, on June 9.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880702-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-02-88 0018EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Soviet-Secrets Bjt   07-02 0500</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Soviet-Secrets, Bjt,0516</SECOND>
<HEAD>Ligachev Reveals Secrets Behind Rise Of Gorbachev</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ALISON SMALE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MOSCOW (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Yegor </PERSON> <PERSON> K. </PERSON> <PERSON> Ligachev </PERSON>, the No. 2 man in the <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION>, provided an unprecedented look into the inner workings of the Soviet leadership with his description of the events that brought <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> to power. <PERSON> Ligachev </PERSON> said Friday at the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> conference that <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> had crucial support from himself, <PERSON> Andrei </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gromyko </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> KGB </ORGANIZATION> chief <PERSON> Viktor </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Chebrikov </PERSON> when he became party general secretary in March 1985. <PERSON> Gromyko </PERSON>, now president, was foreign minister at the time. <PERSON> Ligachev </PERSON>, recounting emotions and experiences in a manner rare for a member of the traditionally stoic party Politburo, disputed claims from ousted <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> Communist Party boss <PERSON> Boris </PERSON> <PERSON> N. </PERSON> <PERSON> Yeltsin </PERSON> that he had slowed reform. He said he had been deeply worried about the fate of the country during the final days of <PERSON> Leonid </PERSON> <PERSON> I. </PERSON> <PERSON> Brezhnev </PERSON>, who ruled from 1964 to 1982 in a `` time of stagnation.'' More `` very disquieting days and hours'' came when the party elite assembled to choose a successor to <PERSON> Konstantin </PERSON> <PERSON> U. </PERSON> <PERSON> Chernenko </PERSON> in March 1985, <PERSON> Ligachev </PERSON> said. `` Fate put me in the center'' of action, he said. `` We could have made quite different decisions. And, sometimes I think: What would have happened to the country after that?'' he told the conference delegates. With the support of <PERSON> Chebrikov </PERSON>, <PERSON> Gromyko </PERSON>, Politburo member <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Solomentsev </PERSON> and some regional party leaders, `` the only correct decision was taken,'' he added. <PERSON> Gromyko </PERSON> made the nominating speech proposing <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> as general secretary after <PERSON> Chernenko </PERSON>'s death, but <PERSON> Ligachev </PERSON>'s account was the first to suggest Solomentsev had supported <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>. His comments appeared to confirm rumors that circulated at the time that former <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> party boss <PERSON> Viktor </PERSON> <PERSON> V. </PERSON> <PERSON> Grishin </PERSON>, an ally of <PERSON> Chernenko </PERSON> and <PERSON> Brezhnev </PERSON>, had made a last-minute attempt to secure the leadership. <PERSON> Ligachev </PERSON>'s statements, which were televised, also could boost <PERSON> Gromyko </PERSON> and <PERSON> Solomentsev </PERSON> a day after they were criticized by name at the four-day conference, which ended Friday. <PERSON> Gromyko </PERSON>, 78, was foreign minister for 28 years before accepting the largely ceremonial presidency in July 1985. He and <PERSON> Solomentsev </PERSON> have sat on the policy-setting <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> since the early 1960s. `` The country came to a crisis'' before <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> became leader, <PERSON> Ligachev </PERSON> said. He spoke of corruption, lack of discipline and alcoholism. Because of a lack of frankness, even `` the party was in danger,'' he said. `` All revolutionary parties that died did so because they were afraid to talk about their weaknesses,'' he said. <PERSON> Ligachev </PERSON> spoke of his career during the <PERSON> Brezhnev </PERSON> years. `` In the years of stagnation I worked and lived in <LOCATION> Siberia </LOCATION>,'' said <PERSON> Ligachev </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> leader in the Siberian city of <LOCATION> Tomsk </LOCATION> from 1965-83. `` I say with pride that I built socialism. And there were millions of such people.'' Referring with a touch of humor to the Russian practice of sending misfits and disidents to <LOCATION> Siberia </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Ligachev </PERSON> said, `` Perhaps we worked like that because we knew that they would n't send us farther than <LOCATION> Siberia </LOCATION>.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880702-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-02-88 0018EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Soviet-Afghanistan Bjt   07-02 0643</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Soviet-Afghanistan, Bjt,0661</SECOND>
<HEAD>Commander Says Soviets Not Defeated in Afghanistan</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Soviet-Party, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARK J. PORUBCANSKY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MOSCOW (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The commander of Soviet troops in <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> said they served with honor and were not defeated, but two influential officials criticized the decision to intervene in the fight against U.S.-backed rebels. `` We came to <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> not to win battles, but to defend women and children, villages and cities. And we have performed our duty with honor,'' Lt. Gen. <PERSON> Boris </PERSON> <PERSON> Gromov </PERSON> told the national <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> conference on Friday. The <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> entered in <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> in December 1979, and more than 100,000 troops were helping the Marxist government fight the Moslem guerrillas until a withdrawal agreement was signed in April. <PERSON> Gromov </PERSON>, who told reporters this week that the <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> is no longer taking active part in the fighting, rejected claims that the Soviet force was beaten. <PERSON> Grigory </PERSON> <PERSON> Baklanov </PERSON>, editor of the literary journal <LOCATION> Znamya </LOCATION>, said the decision to intervene was made `` in defiance of the machinery of democracy.'' He said some non-voting members of the ruling Politburo learned about the decision only by reading the newspapers. `` I receive many letters from mothers,'' he said in remarks broadcast by Soviet television. `` They ask, ` How did this happen? Who supported it?''' <PERSON> Yevgeny </PERSON> <PERSON> Primakov </PERSON> said the decision under late President <PERSON> Leonid </PERSON> <PERSON> I. </PERSON> <PERSON> Brezhnev </PERSON> was made `` without a proper examination of the possible alternatives of a political resolution.'' The remarks by <PERSON> Primakov </PERSON>, head of the <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Economics </ORGANIZATION> and International Relations of the <ORGANIZATION> Soviet </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sciences </ORGANIZATION>, were provided by the <ORGANIZATION> Tass </ORGANIZATION> news agency. The discussion of <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> on the fourth and final day of the conference lacked the sharp character of debates on the bolder news media, the economy and other issues. But coupled with Soviet leader <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s own critique and some personal criticism during the conference of President <PERSON> Andrei </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gromyko </PERSON> _ the foreign minister for 28 years _ it indicated serious dissatisfaction with the conduct of foreign policy earlier this decade. Soviet military officials have refused to criticize the orders to fight in <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>, which cost them more than 13,000 dead and 35,000 wounded. According to the terms of an April 14 agreement signed in <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION>, a fifth of the 100,000 Soviet soldiers have left <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> and the remainder must be gone by Feb. 15, 1989. In his opening address to the party conference Tuesday, <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> praised the soldiers who served in <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>, but the criticism of <PERSON> Baklanov </PERSON> and <PERSON> Primakov </PERSON> echoed other remarks of <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>. `` It sometimes happened that even decisions of vital importance were taken by a narrow circle of people without collective, comprehensive examination of analysis, on occasion without properly consulting friends either. This led to an inadequate reaction to international events and to the policies of other states, if not to mistaken decisions,'' he said. The <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> agreement and withdrawal from <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> `` have become an international milestone in the political settlement of regional conflicts, which are fraught with a danger to the world as a whole and which hinder the progress of the nations,'' <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> said. He said the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> too often in the past has emphasized military strength rather than political skill. He has been extremely critical of the rule of <PERSON> Brezhnev </PERSON> as a period of stagnation and corruption. In an address Thursday, a local party official called for a pair of officials long influential in foreign affairs to step down because they had been part of <PERSON> Brezhnev </PERSON>'s administration. Prompted by <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> to name names, <PERSON> Vladimir </PERSON> <PERSON> I. </PERSON> <PERSON> Melnikov </PERSON> of the <LOCATION> Siberian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Komi </LOCATION> region called for <PERSON> Gromyko </PERSON> and <PERSON> Georgy </PERSON> <PERSON> Arbatov </PERSON>, head of the <ORGANIZATION> U.S.A.-Canada </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> for the past 21 years, to step down. Other Soviet officials in recent months have suggested that the decision to send soldiers into <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> was a mistake, but their comments were in less - influential and less-public forums
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880702-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-02-88 0133EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Soviet-EastBloc     07-02 0389</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Soviet-East Bloc,0401</SECOND>
<HEAD>Soviet Bloc Allies Generally Praise Party Conference</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Soviet-Party, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By VIOREL URMA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>VIENNA, Austria (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> conference in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> generally brought praise from <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, where the <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION>'s new policies are pressuring leaders to reform their own countries `` In <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>, in our party, we are deeply satisfied with the course of the <ORGANIZATION> CPSU </ORGANIZATION> -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> Soviet </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> -RRB- conference,'' said a commentary of the official Polish news agency <ORGANIZATION> PAP </ORGANIZATION>. `` With satisfaction we receive the changes brought by perestroika and new thinking.'' <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> have gone the farthest in matching or even exceeding Soviet leader <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s reforms in the economy and politics. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>, who closed the four-day conference Friday, will be paying a six-day visit to <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION> beginning July 11. The `` new thinking'' at the conference `` creates fresh possibilities of a gradual demilitarization and humanization of international relations,'' Polish <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Stefan </PERSON> <PERSON> Staniszewski </PERSON> told a news conference Thursday. In <LOCATION> Czechoslovakia </LOCATION>, where officials privately say they are waiting to see whether <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> will strengthen his position at the conference, the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> daily Rude Pravo said the event `` will be an inspiration and a source of practical enlightment for us.'' If the <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION> leader gets a mandate for more radical reforms, it would increase pressure on <LOCATION> Czechoslovakia </LOCATION>'s leaders _ installed after <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> crushed Gorbachev-like reforms with tanks 20 years ago _ to adopt political change and to reform economic structure more quickly. `` The ideas ... are worth thinking about,'' Rude Pravo said. In <LOCATION> Yugoslavia </LOCATION>, which broke with <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> over ideological issues 40 years ago, the state press carried lengthy reports from the conference describing it as `` historic, dramatic and exceptionally open.'' Yugoslav media pointed to <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s words that there will be no prosperity for socialism without fundamental and deep democratization of the Soviet society. All the Communist leaderships in <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, many of them now more secretive and orthodox than the modern <ORGANIZATION> Kremlin </ORGANIZATION>, have followed the conference debate over the Stalinist past and the need to open up <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> life. One exception was <LOCATION> Romania </LOCATION>, whose leader <PERSON> Nicolae </PERSON> <PERSON> Ceausescu </PERSON> has so far rejected any need to reform his rigid economic and political system. The <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> daily <ORGANIZATION> Scinteia </ORGANIZATION> carried a four-paragraph report about the conference opening without any comment and did not publish any excerpts from <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s speech.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880702-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-02-88 0028EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Shultz Bjt   07-02 0653</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Shultz, Bjt,0669</SECOND>
<HEAD>Arias Tells Shultz That Negotiations Only Path To Peace</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By REID G. MILLER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SAN JOSE, Costa Rica (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Negotiations are the only road to peace in <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>, President <PERSON> Oscar </PERSON> <PERSON> Arias </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Costa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rica </LOCATION> told Secretary of State <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON>, who reportedly is considering a new aid program for the rebels. <PERSON> Arias </PERSON> said he told <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> on Friday that negotiating between <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>'s leftist Sandinista government and the rebels, known as Contras, was still possible despite a breakdown in talks last month. `` I am sure that the offer of the Sandinista government is not their final offer,'' <PERSON> Arias </PERSON> told reporters at his home moments after <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON>'s departure for <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> spent six hours in <LOCATION> Costa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rica </LOCATION>, the last stop on a three-day, four-nation Central American trip. In <LOCATION> Guatemala </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> met with Contra leaders. He was said to have discussed a $ 30 million aid package for the rebels that could also hold out the promise of economic aid to the Sandinistas. <PERSON> Alfredo </PERSON> <PERSON> Cesar </PERSON>, a member of the Contra directorate, said he and his colleagues talked with <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> about a package that might include the promise of financial help to <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> if the Sandinistas bring about promised democratic reforms. Even a qualified offer of aid to <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> would represent a sharp turnaround in <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> policy. The <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration cut off all direct aid to <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> seven years ago and has applied an economic embargo for the past four years. <PERSON> Adolfo </PERSON> <PERSON> Calero </PERSON>, another Contra leader, said $ 7 million of the aid to the rebels might be earmarked for military hardware, but would be held in escrow and released only if the <ORGANIZATION> Sandinistas </ORGANIZATION> failed to negotiate in good faith during peace talks. <PERSON> Calero </PERSON>, however, described the talks with <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> as only informal consultations, and the secretary himself declined to discuss them. The <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration has said only that <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> will be asked to approve an unspecified amount of new assistance to the rebels. At a news conference between two formal meetings with <PERSON> Arias </PERSON>, <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> said the administration is `` seeking obviously to support those who stand up and are ready to struggle'' against the <ORGANIZATION> Sandinistas </ORGANIZATION>. But, as he did throughout his trip, <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> devoted most of his comments to comparing <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> unfavorably with the rest of <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>. Only <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>, he said, has suffered economic and social decline in the past decade. The Contras have received no military aid since Feb. 29. <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> approved a $ 17 million humanitarian aid package in late March after the rebels and the Sandinista government agreed on a 60-day cease-fire. <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>'s president, <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON>, unilaterally extended the cease-fire earlier this week until July 31, and <PERSON> Arias </PERSON> said that gave new hope to the negotiating process, which he has been championing for more than a year. The on-again, off-again talks have been held under the aegis of an Arias-sponsored peace plan signed by all five <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> presidents last Aug. 7. The plan won <PERSON> Arias </PERSON> the 1987 Nobel Peace Prize. The five presidents plan to meet again in August to assess progress of the peace plan. <PERSON> Arias </PERSON> said <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> suggested meeting personally with the foreign ministers of <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Guatemala </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Costa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rica </LOCATION> shortly before that summit. `` Now that the truce has been extended 30 days more, I'm sure that we should take advantage of that extension and keep on with the dialoque,'' <PERSON> Arias </PERSON> said. `` I'm sure we can reach a cease-fire soon, and also to advance to real democracy in <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> really soon. `` There is no better way to resolve the crisis than through negotiations, dialoque,'' <PERSON> Arias </PERSON> said, adding that he had conveyed the same message to <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON>. <PERSON> Arias </PERSON> also said he agreed with <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON>' proposal that the secretary of state meet with the four foreign ministers before the summit, tentatively set for Aug. 7 in either <LOCATION> Guatemala </LOCATION> or <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> would be excluded from the preliminary meeting, but not from the summit itself.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880702-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-02-88 0145EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Soviet-PartyTV     07-02 0525</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Soviet-Party TV,0539</SECOND>
<HEAD>Soviet Television Gets into Glasnost Act with Live Interviews</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Soviet-Party, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ANDREW KATELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MOSCOW (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 State-run television interrupted its usual bland fare for spicy, live interviews after a disgraced leader pleaded for forgiveness in a dramatic speech at a national <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> conference. One delegate told a television correspondent that the conference discussion about ousted <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> party chief <PERSON> Boris </PERSON> <PERSON> N. </PERSON> <PERSON> Yeltsin </PERSON> was a healthy sign that democracy and `` glasnost,'' leader <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s policy of openness, was taking hold. `` We can speak our minds openly and directly, without being afraid of anything,'' said <PERSON> Ivan </PERSON> <PERSON> I. </PERSON> <PERSON> Maximov </PERSON>, a balding metalworker from the Siberian town of <LOCATION> Biisk </LOCATION>. During a Friday afternoon break in the final session of the first party conference in 47 years, Soviet television broadcast the live interviews in the lobby of the <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION>'s Palace of Congresses with some of the 5,000 delegates. Most of the discussion during the broadcast focused on what one delegate called the highlight of Friday's session of the four-day conference, the speech by <PERSON> Yeltsin </PERSON>, a former <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> protege. `` It's the most heated discussion we have heard in a long time,'' a gray-haired delegate told the television correspondent. A studio anchorman began the 30-minute broadcast and then switched live to the correspondent on the scene. Delegates had just ended floor debate about <PERSON> Yeltsin </PERSON>'s speech, in which he asked to be cleared of blame for criticizing other Soviet leaders and saying reform was proceeding too slowly. The discussion spilled over into the television interviews. Some delegates told viewers they supported <PERSON> Yeltsin </PERSON>, while others condemned his remarks as `` politically incorrect.'' <PERSON> Yeltsin </PERSON> was fired as <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> party boss and removed from his post as a non-voting member of the ruling Politburo after a bitter speech to the party's <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> last October, in which he complained that economic reforms had stalled and asked to be relieved of his duties. His speech at that meeting has never been published. <PERSON> Maximov </PERSON>, the delegate from <LOCATION> Biisk </LOCATION>, said it is difficult for people to make up their minds about whether <PERSON> Yeltsin </PERSON>'s criticism was justified because his <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> speech remains secret. `` Glasnost must be deep; then such questions would n't arise,'' he told the television interviewer. During the conference, Soviet television and radio provided periodic newsbriefs with highlights of speeches and live interviews with delegates. The popular evening news program `` Vremya,'' which reportedly has a nightly audience of tens of millions of Soviets, departed from its usual fare of dull reports about the latest beet harvest or other economic achievement to carry extensive coverage on the party conference. The nightly program normally runs 45 minutes but Friday it continued for three hours with extensive clips of <PERSON> Yeltsin </PERSON>'s address and remarks by his critics. Videotape showed <PERSON> Yeltsin </PERSON> appealing for political rehabilitation, and when there was a roar from the delegates <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> waved his hands and asked that <PERSON> Yeltsin </PERSON> be allowed to continue. `` Vremya'' directors apparently felt the <PERSON> Yeltsin </PERSON> issue was so important that they continued showing the taped reports even after <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> began his speech closing the conference. Soviet radio carried <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s speech live and Vremya later broadcast a recording.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880702-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-02-88 0158EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     07-02 0959</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0997</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names In The News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>COSTA MESA, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Teen pop star <PERSON> Tiffany </PERSON>, about to embark on her first world tour, says that unlike many sudden success stories, her career has not gone to her head. `` I'm real cautious about staying a regular teen-ager,'' said <PERSON> Tiffany </PERSON>, 16, who is scheduled to perform here Saturday night at the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Amphitheatre </LOCATION>. With 5 million copies of her first album sold and a second album on the way, it's easy to see how a young singer could get heady. `` I've had other friends who hit it big with a record or something, and they changed completely. I do n't want that to happen to me,'' she said recently. <PERSON> Tiffany </PERSON>, who recently petitioned a court to have herself legally recognized as an adult, withdrew the petition in an out-of-court settlement with her mother. However, a legal battle between her mother and manager is still being waged over who will control the teen's growing fortune.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>SOUTH BURLINGTON, Vt. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Zaccaro </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> has begun his four-month house arrest for selling a quarter-gram of cocaine to an undercover officer. <PERSON> Zaccaro </PERSON>, the 24-year-old son of former vice presidential candidate <PERSON> Geraldine </PERSON> <PERSON> Ferraro </PERSON>, was booked Friday at <ORGANIZATION> Chittenden </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Community </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Correctional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> and then left to begin <LOCATION> Vermont </LOCATION>'s special house arrest program for non-violent criminals <PERSON> Zaccaro </PERSON> will live in a state-approved apartment during the sentence. He will not be allowed to consume alcohol and must request permission to have visitors. In addition to the four-month sentence, <PERSON> Zaccaro </PERSON> was ordered to serve 300 hours of community service and pay a $ 1,500 fine. <PERSON> Zaccaro </PERSON> was arrested two years ago after selling $ 25 worth of cocaine to an undercover officer at <ORGANIZATION> Middlebury </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION>, where he was a student at the time. <PERSON> Zaccaro </PERSON>'s lawyers plan to appeal his conviction to the <ORGANIZATION> Vermont </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>OLYMPIA, Wash. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Gov. <PERSON> Booth </PERSON> <PERSON> Gardner </PERSON> has his own version of independence to celebrate this July 4th weekend. The governor and his wife, <PERSON> Jean </PERSON>, are giving away their daughter, <PERSON> Gail </PERSON>, in marriage. Ms. <PERSON> Gardner </PERSON>, 24, was to become the bride of <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Nettleton </PERSON>, 24, of <LOCATION> Albany </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION>, in a wedding today at the <LOCATION> Raynor </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Chapel </LOCATION> at <ORGANIZATION> Annie </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wright </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Tacoma </LOCATION>. Ms. <PERSON> Gardner </PERSON> attended <PERSON> Annie </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> for eight years. A reception was planned follow at the governor's mansion in <LOCATION> Olympia </LOCATION> Ms. <PERSON> Gardner </PERSON> and <PERSON> Nettleton </PERSON> met while they were undergraduates at <ORGANIZATION> Dartmouth </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Nettleton </PERSON>, who is working on the <PERSON> Gardner </PERSON> re-election campaign, plans to enter law school this fall. Ms. <PERSON> Gardner </PERSON> is completing work on a graduate degree in education at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A Canadian who claims <PERSON> Eddie </PERSON> <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON>'s new `` Coming to <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'' movie was based on his idea has filed a $ 10 million copyright lawsuit against the actor, two writers and <ORGANIZATION> Paramount </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Studios </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Shelby </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gregory </PERSON>, 38, now living in <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION>, said he filed the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> suit because <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON> and the two writers allegedly used his ideas without compensation. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Wachs </PERSON>, <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON>'s manager, said Friday he had not seen the suit, but denied any wrongdoing. `` It's <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON>'s story,'' <PERSON> Wachs </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON> was reported to be unavailable for comment and <ORGANIZATION> Paramount </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pictures </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman <PERSON> Deborah </PERSON> <PERSON> Rosen </PERSON> said the studio does not comment on lawsuits. The suit states that <PERSON> Lassine </PERSON> <PERSON> Ousseni </PERSON>, a Nigerian who claimed to be an actor-producer, offered <PERSON> Gregory </PERSON> $ 5,000 in 1983 to write a treatment, or detailed outline, and a story. <PERSON> Gregory </PERSON> said he registered a federal copyright for the completed `` Toto, The African Prince.'' <PERSON> Gregory </PERSON> was never paid, according to the suit filed Wednesday. <PERSON> Ousseni </PERSON> then submitted a redrafted copy of the work to <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON> in 1986, which <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON> rejected, the suit says. <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON> and the two writers eventually turned out a screenplay that became `` Coming to <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>,'' the suit alleges.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>PHOENIX, Ariz. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Garrett </PERSON>, lead singer for the Australian rock group <ORGANIZATION> Midnight </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Oil </ORGANIZATION>, says his 11-year-old band is finally making it big in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> after passing up a chance at national exposure six years ago. In 1982, <ORGANIZATION> Midnight </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Oil </ORGANIZATION> turned down an offer to be the opening act on The Who's farewell tour, partly because <PERSON> Garrett </PERSON> and his five fellow band members did n't approve of the tour's sponsorship by a beer company, <PERSON> Schlitz </PERSON>. `` We had never been sponsored by anyone and we never will,'' <PERSON> Garrett </PERSON> said. `` We ca n't understand why someone who's already famous and wealthy would turn their faces and names over to a drinks company or whatever.'' Midnight Oil, which played here Friday night, is on the American charts now with its million-selling album `` Diesel And Dust'' and the hit single `` Beds Are Burning,'' which champions the rights of <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION>'s aborigines. `` We believe in the human potential to organize and resolve problems. We believe in hope,'' said <PERSON> Garrett </PERSON>, a 35-year-old former lawyer whose 6-foot-5 frame and clean-shaven head make him an atypical rock star.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>BOSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Although probable presidential candidate Gov. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> is still shopping for a Democratic running mate, his wife, <PERSON> Kitty </PERSON>, has already made her choice for the convention. She's selected a three-piece silk suit by <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> designer <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Josef </PERSON>. Mrs. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> also will wear several other outfits by <PERSON> Josef </PERSON>, 31, during the Democratic National Convention in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> July 18-21. `` Kitty is an issue-oriented woman and her approach to fashion is more casual,'' said <PERSON> Josef </PERSON>, whose original name is <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Prignano </PERSON>. `` Fashion is not the be-all and end-all to her and I respect her for that. Mrs. -LRB- Nancy -RRB- <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> is very fashion-first.'' <PERSON> Josef </PERSON> would not disclose the price for Mrs. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' outfits. His designs normally sell for $ 300 to $ 770 in stores such as <PERSON> Neiman </PERSON> <PERSON> Marcus </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> Saks </ORGANIZATION> Fifth Avenue. Mrs. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> left <ORGANIZATION> Massachusetts </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION> last month wearing one of <PERSON> Josef </PERSON>'s jackets after undergoing spinal surgery.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880702-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-02-88 0159EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-PornoArrests Bjt   07-02 0624</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Porno Arrests, Bjt,610</SECOND>
<HEAD>Pornography Outlets Nationwide Charged In Obscene Mailings</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Note contents, grafs 13-14 bgng: Ward said ...</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By EILEEN PUTMAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 People who received unsolicited pornography sparked an investigation that authorities said resulted in federal charges against companies responsible for much of the country's sexually oriented mailings Indictments unsealed Friday in eight states charged 20 people and 14 companies under a section of federal law that makes it a crime to use the mails for advertising or distributing obscene material. `` Project Postporn,'' the official moniker for the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department-Postal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> probe, specifically targeted hard-core pornography, which depicts actual sexual acts. Mailings usually arrived at homes addressed to adults, children or simply `` resident,'' said <PERSON> Brent </PERSON> <PERSON> Ward </PERSON>, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> attorney for <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION> and chairman of the attorney general's subcommittee on obscenity. `` They arrive unsolicited in innocuous-looking envelopes in the homes of unsuspecting people who have never subscribed to pornography, do not want it in their homes and are never going to order any obscene material,'' <PERSON> Ward </PERSON> said at a <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> news conference Friday. <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Swagerty </PERSON>, assistant chief postal inspector, said such mailings had increased in recent years, prompting more than 350,000 people to file postal service forms requesting that they not receive sexually oriented material though the mail. About 100,000 of them were filed in the last year, he said. The investigation began a year ago in response to complaints, officials said. <PERSON> Ward </PERSON> said it had targeted only `` hard-core obscenity which the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> has held is not protected by the First Amendment.'' The <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>'s test of obscenity is that the material, taken as a whole, has to appeal to prurient interest; portray sexual conduct in a patently offensive way in light of contemporary community standards; and lack serious artistic, political or scientific value. A 1986 report by Attorney General <PERSON> Edwin </PERSON> <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>'s pornography commission linked hard-core pornography to sex crimes. <PERSON> Ward </PERSON> restated that view Friday when asked by reporters whether the material had actually caused any harm. `` I think it's an accepted fact that the depiction of explicit sex acts ... has the effect of conditioning individuals to committing those acts and conditioning society so that that is accepted as the norm,'' he said. But <PERSON> Barry </PERSON> <PERSON> Lynn </PERSON>, legislative counsel for the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Civil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberties </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION>, denounced that view as `` hysteria'' and said it conflicted with the First Amendment guaranteeing the right of free speech. `` There is n't any evidence that links adults looking at pornography to any real crime,'' he said in an interview later. `` It may be grotesque, but much of the stuff is just obviously consenting adults having sex.'' <PERSON> Ward </PERSON> said the targeted material depicts sexual acts, `` often in a context of violence toward women and children, and often stressing themes such as rape, incest, torture, bondage, child sexual abuse and bestiality.'' The officials displayed at the news conference samples of the advertisements, which included one promoting nine `` full-length movies'' for $ 79 featuring `` 12 hours of the rawest sex ever filmed.'' Another advertised `` new bondage videos,'' including `` Captive Co-Eds'' and `` Harem Girls in Bondage.'' Undercover agents responding to complaints about the material purchased samples and compiled evidence to search 11 companies, and then developed evidence on others, officials said. <PERSON> Ward </PERSON> said the companies represent `` as much as three-fourths of mailings of sexually oriented material in this country.'' The companies charged operated under a variety of names and had a number of other associated companies. Indictments or criminal complaints were returned in <LOCATION> Sioux </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Buffalo </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Harrisburg </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Tallahassee </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Nashville </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Memphis </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Tenn. </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Worth </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Salt </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION>; and <LOCATION> Spokane </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wash </LOCATION>. The criminal charges were filed in the city where the obscene material was received, not necessarily where the distributors operated.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880702-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-02-88 0204EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Veteran'sReturn 1stLd-Writethru a0707 07-02 0358</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Veteran's Return, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0707,0359</SECOND>
<HEAD>Handicapped Vet Begins Solo Flight To Germany</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: SUBS 3rd graf to CORRECT that Harrison was wounded four days
after he arrived in Germany, sted four days after Normandy
invasion.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>ATLANTA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A World War II veteran paralyzed from the chest down left Friday on a solo, 4,669-mile trans-Atlantic flight to the <LOCATION> German </LOCATION> battlefield where he was wounded in World War II. <PERSON> Clark </PERSON> <PERSON> Harrison </PERSON>, a 63-year-old real estate company owner and bank chairman in suburban <LOCATION> Decatur </LOCATION>, took off from <LOCATION> DeKalb-Peachtree </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION> about 9:30 a.m. Friday in a single-engine <ORGANIZATION> Cherokee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Piper </ORGANIZATION> equipped with hand controls. He is scheduled to arrive at <LOCATION> Aachen </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, on July 11 and attend a reception in nearby Stolberg, where he was wounded by a sniper during a battle four days after he landed following the <LOCATION> Normandy </LOCATION> invasion. `` What scares me the most is rolling around in this wheelchair and getting in and out of it,'' he said. `` The easy part is the flying. Once I get on the ground, that's the hard part.'' <PERSON> Harrison </PERSON> plans to fly his `` Spirit of Shepherd'' airplane up the <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Seaboard </LOCATION> and across <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> to the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Base </ORGANIZATION> at <LOCATION> Sondrestrom </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Greenland </LOCATION>, where he plans to spend the Fourth of July. Flying by visual flight rules about 2,000 feet above the ground, <PERSON> Harrison </PERSON> then will cross the <LOCATION> Greenland </LOCATION> ice cap and go on to <LOCATION> Reykjavik </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Iceland </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Bagar </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> in the <LOCATION> Faeroe </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Islands </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Stornoway </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Scotland </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Biggin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>; and <LOCATION> Aachen </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Harrison </PERSON> flies in a cramped two-seat cockpit filled with his wheelchair, his luggage, a life raft, survival kit and an auxiliary fuel tank. He gets in and out of the plane by crawling onto the wing, which sits about three feet off the ground, and then pulling the wheelchair up or letting it down with a strap. He hopes the trip will raise money for a Center for Independent Living at the <ORGANIZATION> Shepherd </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Spinal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>. He is a founding director of the 13-year-old <ORGANIZATION> Shepherd </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Spinal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>; supporters are pledging to donate to the hospital up to $ 1 for each mile <PERSON> Harrison </PERSON> plans to travel.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880702-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-02-88 0204EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Politics-Quotes     07-02 0097</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Politics-Quotes,100</SECOND>
<HEAD>Quotes From The Presidential Campaign Trail</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are some comments from the presidential campaign trail: <PERSON> MICHAEL </PERSON> <PERSON> DUKAKIS </PERSON>, after auditioning <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> Sen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON> for vice president, asked by reporters if he agreed with assessments that the senator was dull and boring: `` Dull and boring _ I kind of like that.'' <PERSON> BOB </PERSON> <PERSON> DOLE </PERSON>, one whether bhe is seeking or would accept the vice presidential nomination if it is offered by <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>: `` I'd be happy to discuss it. If someone makes that call ... you talk about it very seriously.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880702-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-02-88 0105EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-US-SovietInspections 1stLd-Writethru a06lding 07-02
0557</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-US-Soviet Inspections, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0668,560</SECOND>
<HEAD>US, Soviet Teams Begin Inspections to Verify INF Treaty</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Top 3 grafs new to UPDATE with Soviets arriving in
California; Picks up 2nd graf pvs, bgng: ``The Soviet ...''</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By BRYAN BRUMLEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Soviet missile specialists arrived in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> on Friday to verify compliance with a treaty to eliminate superpower medium-range missiles as a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> inspection team made its way to <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>. In <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Vyacheslav </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Lebedev </PERSON>, the Soviet team chief, said through an interpreter that his inspectors will `` follow the letter and spirit'' of a treaty they hope will further world peace. The 70 Soviet inspectors arrived at <ORGANIZATION> Travis </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Base </ORGANIZATION>, located about 50 miles west of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION>, on an IL-62 Aeroflot flown by a 10-member Soviet crew. The Soviet government notified the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> early Friday that five teams were landing in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION>, said <PERSON> Kendall </PERSON> <PERSON> Pease </PERSON>, spokesman for the <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. On-Site Inspection Agency, created last January to monitor compliance with the Intermediate-range Nuclear Forces treaty. Under the treaty, signed last Dec. 9 at the <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> summit, the Soviets need not list the sites they want to visit until they have been in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> 48 hours, <PERSON> Pease </PERSON> said. Other Soviet teams will inspect sites in the eastern <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, but their arrival time has not been relayed to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Pease </PERSON> said. The teams have 60 days to carry out the `` baseline inspections,'' designed to verify the exact number of missiles and related components to be destroyed under treaty. In <LOCATION> Frankfurt </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, two <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> inspection teams, consisting of 10 experts each, met with reporters before boarding an <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> jet for the flight to <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>. `` We all feel this is a historic mission,'' the head of the inspection agency, <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Brig </ORGANIZATION>. Gen. <PERSON> Roland </PERSON> <PERSON> Lajoie </PERSON>, told reporters One <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> team was headed from <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> to the Soviet city of <LOCATION> Votkinsk </LOCATION>, the site of a plant that formerly built the SS-20 missiles, the most important Soviet weapon to be eliminated under the treaty. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has the right to keep a team at <LOCATION> Votkinsk </LOCATION> for up to 13 years, and the Soviets may station inspectors for the same period at <ORGANIZATION> Magna </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION>, site of Hercules Plant No. 1, where <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> missiles were produced. Inspection teams will verify destruction of 1,800 missiles and check on about 3,200 related components, including storage and transport missile containers and special hauling vehicles, <PERSON> Lajoie </PERSON> told reporters. `` We're going in with the attitude, ` Trust everybody, but always cut the cards,''' <PERSON> Lajoie </PERSON> said. Over the next 60 days, the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> team will inspect 126 sites in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, including 33 in eastern <LOCATION> Siberia </LOCATION>, he said. Soviet teams will inspect 26 sites in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Western </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, including 11 in the continental <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials said. The treaty allows the two sides to visit the other's country on 16 hours' notice, then permits them to wait 48 hours before giving notification of the exact sites to be visited. Reporters were not to be allowed to accompany the teams. The pact, the first to allow such on-site inspection, is viewed as a trial for the proposed <ORGANIZATION> Strategic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Arms </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reduction </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Treaty </ORGANIZATION>, which would slash arsenals of long-range superpower nuclear weapons by 30 percent to 50 percent, and involve much more complicated verification procedures.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880702-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-02-88 0217EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Reagan-Drought     07-02 0357</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Reagan-Drought,350</SECOND>
<HEAD>Lyng Says Government Wants to Help Distressed Farmers</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto WX7</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MERRILL HARTSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Agriculture Secretary <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Lyng </PERSON> says the government will likely extend `` a helping hand'' to drought-stricken farmers as soon as there's a solid assessment of crop damage. But <PERSON> Lyng </PERSON> said despite stark evidence of the havoc wreaked by the dry spell, `` I think it would be premature to start putting dollars up there.'' After briefing President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> on the findings of an interagency task force on the drought, the secretary told reporters Friday that long-range weather forecasts are discouraging. `` We did have some showers in the last few days that helped in some places and the weather's cooler, so those are good signs,'' he said, `` but the weather forecasts indicate that it -LRB- the drought -RRB- has not broken and is continuing and is still very, very serious.'' Meanwhile, it was disclosed by a senior administration official that <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> will fly to <LOCATION> Davenport </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>, July 14 to view drought damage. <PERSON> Lyng </PERSON>, who heads a drought-relief task force <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> set up last month, said that `` sooner or later I suspect that the <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and the administration will see that we need to help with money if the thing continues as bad as it's been. Just how you do that is very complex.'' <PERSON> Lyng </PERSON> would not speculate on whether aid money might be available from the roughly $ 17 billion in the commodity price support payments the administration requested for the new budget year starting Oct. 1. There had been indications that because of the drought, not all of the $ 17 billion would be needed for subsidies and that the excess money might be used for aid purposes. `` To get into writing checks to farmers for relief to help tide them over almost needs to await the normal harvest period so that they can compare what they are harvesting, what happened to them,'' he said. `` At that time, we should be standing there with a helping hand.'' It was the fourth briefing that <PERSON> Lyng </PERSON> has given <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, who established the task force in mid-June to recommend steps the government can take.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880702-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-02-88 0218EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-GlennFinances     07-02 0155</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Glenn Finances,160</SECOND>
<HEAD>Financial Report Shows Glenn a Multi-Millionaire</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Sen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON> has reported personal holdings worth between $ 8 million and $ 15 million or more, making the <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> Democrat among the wealthiest members of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>. According to <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON>'s financial disclosure report released Friday, the senator earned between $ 1,280,906 and $ 2,704,480 in income in 1987. His assets were valued at between $ 7,753,163 and $ 15,320,012 or more. For 1986, <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON> reported assets of between $ 7.9 million and $ 15.8 million or more. Members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> are required to file reports each year detailing income, gifts, assets and liabilities. Senators were required to file by May 15, but <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON> had requested an extension. The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> disclosure forms are only guideposts to actual wealth because the information is listed only in category of value. <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON>'s largest holdings include interest in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> hotels. <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON> is being considered as a vice presidential running mate for <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880702-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-02-88 0220EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-CNWStrike     07-02 0401</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-CNW Strike,400</SECOND>
<HEAD>Emergency Board Proposes Compromise To Avert Strike</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID FOX</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A presidential panel trying to resolve a dispute between the <ORGANIZATION> Chicago </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <ORGANIZATION> Northwestern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> and one of its unions is offering a compromise that would preserve some jobs and prevent a threatened strike. The White House released a 29-page report late Friday in which an emergency board said both sides should make sacrifices. The report also recommended arbitration if the nation's eighth-largest railroad and the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION> can not agree on specific personnel cuts At issue is a <ORGANIZATION> CNW </ORGANIZATION> proposal to eliminate the jobs of 1,050 <ORGANIZATION> UTU </ORGANIZATION> brakemen by cutting the size of its train crews from four to two workers _ an engineer and conductor _ in most cases. Spokeswoman <PERSON> Leslie </PERSON> <PERSON> Cleveland </PERSON> said <ORGANIZATION> Chicago </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; Northwestern could save about $ 51 million a year by reducing manpower, calling it a necessary step to remain competitive. However, the union characterized the cuts affecting half its <ORGANIZATION> CNW </ORGANIZATION> members as a contract violation and demanded no change from the status quo. It threatened to strike on April 22, prompting President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> to appoint the emergency board under the Railway Labor Act. `` The carrier, unlike many of the other railroads in the industry, has an economic need for relief from its present crew-consist rules. ...,'' the board said. `` This is not to say that the employees, alone, should be expected to bear the burden.'' Although the board said <ORGANIZATION> CNW </ORGANIZATION> should be allowed to eliminate one brakemen per train, it recommended that further reductions be decided by an arbitration board case-by-case. The panel also said <ORGANIZATION> CNW </ORGANIZATION> should be able to terminate some workers if not enough accept voluntary separation allowances. But it also recommended raising the railroad's proposed $ 25,000 allowance to $ 50,000 for employees leaving voluntarily and $ 45,000 for those forced into separation. Company officials said they had not seen the report and had no immediate comment Friday. <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Markgraf </PERSON>, the union's general chairman, said: `` These things work out in strange ways sometimes. We're still hoping for a settlement.'' A strike can not begin before 12:01 a.m. Aug. 4, said <PERSON> Roland </PERSON> <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON>, an administrative assistant to the emergency board. <ORGANIZATION> Chicago </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; Northwestern ranks eighth among <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> railroads in revenue and handled nearly 1.5 million carloads of traffic in 1986. It also provides the principal daily rail service for about 40,000 commuters in the <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> area.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880702-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-02-88 0223EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-PoliticalRdp Bjt   07-02 0606</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Political Rdp, Bjt,610</SECOND>
<HEAD>Vice Presidential Search Dominates Pre-Holiday Activities</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JAMES H. RUBIN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Speculation over vice presidential candidates continues to be the hottest topic for both parties, with little political fireworks in store for the start of the holiday weekend. Democrat <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> and Republican <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, their parties' presidential nominations sewn up, are n't tipping their hands over running mates. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, campaigning Friday with Sen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, said he would `` make a decision when I'm ready to make a decision.'' <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON>, considered a leading choice for a spot on the Democratic ticket, received an enthusiastic welcome from a home-state crowd at an Auto Workers union hall in <LOCATION> Dayton </LOCATION>. `` I've been taking a poll all over <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> about running mates,'' said <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>. `` What do you think about <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON>?'' The crowded cheered and whistled. `` Sounds unanimous to me,'' said the <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> governor. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, meanwhile, was spending a quiet few days at a vacation home in <LOCATION> Kennebunkport </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION>, before heading back to the campaign trail for a Fourth of July swing through <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION>. What little activity there was on the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> side was provided by Sen. <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>, who fenced with reporters in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> over his vice presidential chances. `` I'd be happy to discuss it'' with the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> campaign, <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> said. `` If someone makes that call ... you talk about it very seriously.'' The <ORGANIZATION> Kansas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> met with reporters following a private breakfast in <LOCATION> Sacramento </LOCATION> with Gov. <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Deukmejian </PERSON> of <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, another possible <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> running mate. <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>, asked if they discussed the vice presidential nomination, said: `` We indicated there probably would be one. We did n't go into details. I indicated he'd be a good one, and he indicated the same, that I'd be a good one.'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> is back in <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> today, with plans to cap the holiday weekend by hosting <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> at a Fourth of July dinner. With two weeks until the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Convention </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> is playing it close to the vest on a running mate. He said he expects to notify those he does n't choose before making any public announcement. `` I generally have the practice of notifying people I do n't pick,'' he said but declined to say whether <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> might get the word at dinner on Monday `` We're going to have dinner and listen to some good music,'' he said. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> invited <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> and his wife, <PERSON> Jacqueline </PERSON>, to join him and his wife, <PERSON> Kitty </PERSON>, for a holiday dinner at their home in <LOCATION> Brookline </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mass. </LOCATION>, and then attend a <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> Pops concert. In another development with possible political ramifications, sources said appraisals of land in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Braintree </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mass. </LOCATION>, where state officials want to build a 500-bed prison list the property's value at between $ 5 million and $ 6 million That is well below the $ 9.5 million developers sought when the state became interested in the land two years ago. The appraisals are being reviewed by a third company, which is scheduled to submit its estimate of the property's worth next week. All three will be used by the state to determine how much to offer for the 782 acres bought by two developers in December 1985 for $ 3 million. The selection of the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Braintree </LOCATION> site in 1986 by <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> for a 500-bed medium security prison has been controversial from the outset, with local residents claiming a prison would ruin the tiny central <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> community. The <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> is conducting a preliminary inquiry into allegations that the <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> administration leaked word of its interest in the land to the developers, who bought it from a church. The <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> has said <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> is not under investigation.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880702-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-02-88 0227EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-DefenseProbe-Chappell     07-02 0542</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Defense Probe-Chappell,500</SECOND>
<HEAD>Martin-Marietta Says It Bought Club</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Defense contractor <ORGANIZATION> Martin </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Marietta </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> says it bought a <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> health club once owned in part by a congressman who chairs a military appropriations subcommittee because the purchase `` appears to have been a good investment.'' <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Marietta </PERSON> disclosed Friday it bought the club in <LOCATION> Ocala </LOCATION> little more than a year after a company executive and other partners reportedly rescued Rep. <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Chappell </PERSON> from foreclosure on the property. <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Marietta </PERSON> issued a statement saying that a company subsidiary bought Fun and <ORGANIZATION> Fitness </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ocala </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, on May 30, 1986, for $ 200,000 `` from a group of five private investors who had purchased the property for $ 175,000'' in a bank foreclosure process. The company said the corporation was aware at the time that <PERSON> Chappell </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Fla </LOCATION>., `` had held a prior interest in the racquet club. One of the five private investors had been <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Dalferes </PERSON>, vice president of government affairs at <ORGANIZATION> Martin </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Marietta </ORGANIZATION> headquarters in <LOCATION> Bethesda </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Md. </LOCATION>, just outside <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Marietta </PERSON> said its purchase `` appears to have been a good investment because the property has a market value in excess of the purchase price.'' <PERSON> Chappell </PERSON> said Friday he had kept an `` arm's length'' away from the transaction in which the investors, all representatives of defense contractors, reportedly intervened for him. <PERSON> Chappell </PERSON>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Appropriations defense subcommittee, refused to discuss details of the complex transaction, reported Friday by <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION>. But in a statement issued by his office, he said: `` If you are going to do something wrong, you do n't do it on the public record. This entire transaction is a matter of public record. It has been since its inception several years ago.'' <PERSON> Chappell </PERSON> has said he is not a target in the ongoing criminal investigation of <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> weapons-buying. That investigation involves allegations that defense contractors and consultants, many of them former military men, bribed <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> officials for contracting details that could be vital in winning contracts worth billions of dollars. The <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> reported that the <ORGANIZATION> Racquet </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Club </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ocala </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> intervened in late 1984 to cancel <PERSON> Chappell </PERSON>'s and his partner's personal liability for a large part of their indebtedness and also removed the two men as defendants in a suit related to the health club's foreclosure The principal officers of <ORGANIZATION> Racquet </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Club </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Ocala </LOCATION> were <PERSON> Leonard </PERSON> <PERSON> Killgore </PERSON> and <PERSON> Dalferes </PERSON>. <PERSON> Killgore </PERSON>, a former <PERSON> Chappell </PERSON> aide, was then an official with the <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> office of <ORGANIZATION> Avco </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, a rocket builder, the newspaper said. A <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> court had ruled in November 1984 that <PERSON> Chappell </PERSON> and his partner, <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Austin </PERSON>, personally had guaranteed some $ 172,000 of the overall obligation in the failed club, the <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> said. The December 1984 settlement resulted in <PERSON> Killgore </PERSON> and his investment partners obtaining the health club and its properties for $ 175,000, <PERSON> Chappell </PERSON>'s statement noted. <PERSON> Chappell </PERSON>'s statement said: `` This property was appraised by the bank at $ 425,000. According to public record, the purchaser sold the property for at least a $ 20,000 profit 13 months later.'' `` There was absolutely no benefit to me either way,'' he said. `` The transaction changed no legal responsibilities with reference to <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Chappell </PERSON>, no consideration of any sort passed to <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Chappell </PERSON>. It was an arm's length transaction, as supported by public record.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880702-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-02-88 0139EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p PM-Candidates-Schedules     07-02 0191</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Candidates-Schedules,200</SECOND>
<HEAD>Presidential Candidates' Schedules</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are tentative schedules for the presidential candidates for the week beginning July 3. The information was provided by the candidates. Sunday, July 3: Democrats: <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> -LRB- down -RRB- <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> -LRB- down -RRB- Republican: <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> Kennebunkport </LOCATION> -LRB- down -RRB- Monday, July 4: Democrats: <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> Charleston </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Brookline </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mass </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> Republican: <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION> Tuesday, July 5: Democrats: <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jackson </LOCATION> _ <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> Republican: <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION> Wednesday, July 6: Democrats: <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> _ <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jackson </LOCATION> _ open Republican: <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION> Thursday, July 7: Democrats: <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> _ Western swing <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> _ open Republican: <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> Friday, July 8: Democrats: <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> _ Western swing <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> _ open Republican: <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION> Saturday, July 9: Democrats: <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> _ Western swing <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> _ open Republican: <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION> Sunday, July 10: Democrats: <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> _ Western swing <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> _ open Republican: <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> _ open
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880702-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-02-88 0247EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-SriLanka 1stLd-Writethru   07-02 0578</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Sri Lanka, 1st Ld-Writethru,a0438,0593</SECOND>
<HEAD>Tamil Sources Say Negotiations Stalled</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDS: INSERTS two grafs after 13th, `Neither the...' to UPDATE with
deaths. Pick up 14th pvs, `The Tamil...'</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By PATRICK CRUEZ</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>COLOMBO, Sri Lanka (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Tamil militants in <LOCATION> Sri </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lanka </LOCATION> are ready to surrender, but negotiations have stalled because the rebels are demanding $ 38.4 million from the Indian government, Tamil sources said. Sources close to the rebels in <LOCATION> Colombo </LOCATION>, speaking on condition of anonymity, said Friday the militants were not willing to allow monitoring of how the money was spent. In the southern Indian city of <LOCATION> Madras </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Sadasivam </PERSON> <PERSON> Krishnakumar </PERSON>, a senior member of the <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tigers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tamil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Eelam </ORGANIZATION>, was quoted as saying the group was willing to surrender but awaited final orders from its commander. The <ORGANIZATION> Tigers </ORGANIZATION>, the largest rebel group in <LOCATION> Sri </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lanka </LOCATION>, have been at the forefront of the five-year guerrilla war with the ethnic Sinhalese-dominated government for an independent Tamil homeland. <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>, which has 50,000 peacekeeping troops in <LOCATION> Sri </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lanka </LOCATION>, has been trying to negotiate an end to the separatist war in the neighboring island nation. The Sri Lankan government on Thursday offered amnesty to the rebels and promised to conduct provincial elections by the end of July in northern and eastern <LOCATION> Sri </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lanka </LOCATION>, where the rebels want a separate homeland. The <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> India </ORGANIZATION> quoted <PERSON> Krishnakumar </PERSON> as telling reporters in <LOCATION> Madras </LOCATION> that the <ORGANIZATION> Tigers </ORGANIZATION> would participate in the provincial elections. But he said no decision had been made on whether the <ORGANIZATION> Tigers </ORGANIZATION>' organization would participate in the elections itself or would form a new political party, the news agency It quoted <PERSON> Krishnakumar </PERSON> as saying the <ORGANIZATION> Tigers </ORGANIZATION> would hand over their weapons as soon as an agreement was reached on the timing of a surrender and the number of arms to be given up. He also said a final decision would be taken only after consultations with the <ORGANIZATION> Tigers </ORGANIZATION>' commander, <PERSON> Velupillai </PERSON> <PERSON> Prabhakaran </PERSON>. <PERSON> Prabhakaran </PERSON> is based in <LOCATION> Sri </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lanka </LOCATION> and has successfully eluded a series of manhunts by Indian troops. Last July 29, <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Sri </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lanka </LOCATION> signed a peace accord aimed at ending the ethnic warfare in the island nation off <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>'s southern coast. The <ORGANIZATION> Tigers </ORGANIZATION> accepted the accord but reneged in October. The accord was accompanied by a payment of $ 384,600 by the Indian government to the rebels for rehabilitation of people affected by the fighting. Since October, more than 400 Indian soldiers have been killed in ambushes and battles with the Tamil rebels, according to the Indian government. Neither the Indians nor the Tamils have estimated the number of rebel deaths. In the latest reported violence, seven Indian soldiers were killed in two ambushes Thursday, said Sri Lankan military officials who spoke on condition of anonymity. They said four were killed near <LOCATION> Trincomalee </LOCATION>, 150 miles north of <LOCATION> Colombo </LOCATION>; and three were killed near <LOCATION> Vavuniya </LOCATION>, 110 miles north of <LOCATION> Colombo </LOCATION>. Two Tamils were killed in <LOCATION> Vavuniya </LOCATION> during search operations launched Friday by the Indians, the officials said. The Tamil insurgency grew out of the belief the community was being discriminated against by the Sinhalese ethnic majority, which controls the country's government and armed forces. Tamils comprise 18 percent of <LOCATION> Sri </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lanka </LOCATION>'s 16 million people and the Sinhalese form 75 percent. Most Tamils are Hindus, like the majority of Indians, while most Sinhalese are Buddhists. <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> became involved in the Sri Lankan ethnic strife because of the sympathies of its own 60 million Tamils to the rebel cause.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880702-0025 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-02-88 0248EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Brazil-Constitution     07-02 0689</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Brazil-Constitution,0715</SECOND>
<BYLINE>Brazil Steeps its New Constitution in Controversy
^By JORGE MEDEROS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>RIO DE JANEIRO, Brazil (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 National lawmakers are preparing for final voting on the draft of a new constitution that would reject sweeping land reform but liberalize work rules and end foreign control of mining. The new charter for <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s largest country would also give President <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Sarney </PERSON> and his successors a five-year term, a victory for the national leader. The proposed document was born in five months of heated debate in the <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, doubling as a Constitutional Convention. It has come up 235 articles that will be the basis for the eighth constitution in the 166 years of <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION>'s independence from <LOCATION> Portugal </LOCATION>. The final round of voting is expected to start near the end of July. But the document appears largely to have assumed its final form because a hefty 280 votes in the 559-member convention would be needed to change it. The convention, made up of representatives and senators picked in free elections in 1986, began rewriting the current constitution, dictated during a 1964-1985 military regime, in February 1987. The project started with a computer-generated document touching nearly every aspect of life imaginable in this country of about 140 million people. It then progressed to a first draft of more than 3,000 articles, which critics derided as an `` encyclopedia.'' The real paring began last February with article-by-article voting, in which a majority of 280 was needed for approval. Lawmakers debated vociferously, sometimes violently, especially about issues like land reform, workers' rights and the role of foreign capital. Other hotly contested matters involved how long <PERSON> Sarney </PERSON>, the civilian who assumed office in 1985, should stay there; and whether <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION> should have a U.S.-type presidential form of government or a European-style prime minister system. As it stands, the proposed constitution contains these provisions: _ <PERSON> Sarney </PERSON> and future presidents will serve for five years, compared to the six years of former military presidents. The presidential system remains in place. _ Wide-ranging land reform, in a country where 4 percent of the people own 50 percent of the farmable land, was rejected. _ Workers appear headed for a shorter work week and more liberal vacation benefits. But a liberal maternity leave program might not survive the final vote because businesses view it as too expensive. _ Foreign companies involved in mining will have to leave <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION> in four years or transfer financial control to residents of the country. _ Risk contracts allowing foreign companies to drill for oil probably wo n't be continued. _ The return of legalized casino gambling was rejected. The biggest fight broke out between <PERSON> Sarney </PERSON> and convention members over the length of the presidential term. <PERSON> Tancredo </PERSON> <PERSON> Neves </PERSON>, a moderate who said he wanted only four years as president before holding elections, died before taking office in 1985. <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION>'s last presidential election was in 1960. <PERSON> Sarney </PERSON>, vice president-elect and former chief of the military regime's official party, moved into the presidency. He made it clear he believed he had inherited the six-year term of his military predecessor, Gen. <PERSON> Joao </PERSON> <PERSON> Figueiredo </PERSON>, but said he would consider stepping down after five years. However, many congressmen wanted <PERSON> Sarney </PERSON> out after four years, with presidential elections in November 1988. <PERSON> Sarney </PERSON> won his five years in the constitutional debating, but at the cost of splitting his <ORGANIZATION> Brazilian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Movement </ORGANIZATION> party. Various groups are still seeking changes in the final form of the document. A conservative block, known as the `` Big Center,'' is trying to gain support to strike the anti-foreign articles involving mining and oil prospecting and a proposition allowing civil servants strike under certain circumstances. Leftists, including members of <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION>'s two small Communist parties, want to try to knock out conservative provisions on land reform and one that lets civilian powers call in the armed forces to deal with internal problems. There is no time limit for the last round of debate. But Rep. <PERSON> Ulysses </PERSON> <PERSON> Guimaraes </PERSON>, speaker of <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and president of the constitutional convention, says he would like officially to proclaim the new constitution on Sept. 7, the national holiday that commemmorates independence.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880702-0026 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-02-88 0238EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a PM-FireDeaths Bjt   07-02 0492</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Fire Deaths, Bjt,0508</SECOND>
<HEAD>Five Firefighters Die In Blaze At Auto Dealership</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhotos NY6, NY7</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MICHAEL MORAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>HACKENSACK, N.J. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Five firemen killed when a burning roof collapsed onto them were like `` family'' in this city, which had never had a firefighter die in the line of duty. `` There are only 100 of us in this department and this is just a small place,'' Fire Chief <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON> <PERSON> Aiellos </PERSON> said Friday. `` In a town like this these are your friends.'' `` It's a sad day in <LOCATION> Hackensack </LOCATION>,'' added Mayor <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> Cerbo </PERSON>. `` We've never had anything like this in our city before. To have five firemen die is just incredible.'' The fire, which destroyed the building and contents of a car dealership, started shortly after 3 p.m. Friday in the rear service section of the building, <PERSON> Aiellos </PERSON> said. The ceiling collapsed as the firefighters, who were inside the building, were cutting a hole in it to get a hose on flames in a space between the ceiling and the roof, <PERSON> Aiellos </PERSON> said. The five were killed almost instantly. `` All of a sudden the entire 60 foot square inside ceiling fell on them,'' he said, adding that four other firefighters inside at the time escaped injury. The fire apparently started in the space between the ceiling and roof above the dealership's service area, <PERSON> Aiellos </PERSON> said. The men were spraying the space to try to create a `` fog'' to decrease the fire's heat, he said. `` They did what they were supposed to do,'' <PERSON> Aiellos </PERSON> said. All of <LOCATION> Hackensack </LOCATION>'s 100 firefighters as well as units from surrounding towns responded to the blaze, which was under control by 6:30 p.m. Later, fire investigators picked through the debris. But the roof collapse may make it impossible to find the exact cause, <PERSON> Aiellos </PERSON> said. A damage estimate was not immediately available. Hundreds of bystanders watched along the busy intersection in this <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> suburb of 40,000 people while the firefighters' bodies were placed in ambulances Many clutched friends when stretchers bearing the bodies came briefly into view. The victims were Capt. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>, 54, Lt. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Reinhogen </PERSON>, 48, and firefighters <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Krejsa </PERSON>, 52, <PERSON> Leonard </PERSON> <PERSON> Radumski </PERSON> 38, and <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> Ennis </PERSON>, 30. All five were from <LOCATION> Hackensack </LOCATION>. All the employees of <ORGANIZATION> Hackensack </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> were evacuated without injuries, police said. There were no other firefighters injured. <PERSON> Cerbo </PERSON> said a memorial service would be held next week. Aiellos planned to meet with the families today after autopsies are performed. `` These were good men,'' he said. `` And there are a lot of kids.'' The fatalities were the first deaths in action in <LOCATION> Hackensack </LOCATION> Fire Department history, <PERSON> Aiellos </PERSON> said. <LOCATION> Hackensack </LOCATION>, only four square miles in size, has many longtime residents who will be hit hard by the deaths, he said. At the department's headquarters, a wreath and an <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> flag at half - staff paid tribute to the victims `` It was like losing a member of your family,'' firefighter <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Canzanella </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880702-0027 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-02-88 0244EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w PM-DefenseProbe-Glance     07-02 0415</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Defense Probe-Glance,400</SECOND>
<HEAD>Highlights of Developments in The Defense Probe</HEAD>
<HEAD>With AM-Defense Probe</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are some of the major developments Friday in the investigation of <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> procurement practices.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>PAYMENTS SUSPENDED</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Defense Secretary <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Carlucci </PERSON>, declaring `` we do not need to wait -LRB- for -RRB- convictions, or even trials,'' in the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> procurement affair, suspended payment on $ 1 billion worth of potentially tainted military contracts. <PERSON> Carlucci </PERSON> acted on the basis of information included in search-warrant affidavits that were unsealed by a federal magistrate in <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION> on Thursday. In the documents, the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> said it eavesdropped as one consultant obtained and passed along inside information on nine contracts worth more than $ 522 million. They heard a <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> procurement official read off 10 sealed bids in a $ 120 million contract. <PERSON> Carlucci </PERSON> also announced that the Pentagon was beginning suspension procedures against three individuals and a company named in the documents.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>CONGRESSMAN COMMENTS</HEAD>
<TEXT>
