<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880430-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-30-88 0203EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-FloridaLottery     04-30 0276</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Florida Lottery,0283</SECOND>
<HEAD>859 People, One Newspaper Have Winning Florida Lottery Numbers</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ED BIRK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>TALLAHASSEE, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Petersburg </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> had a winning ticket but no winners in the fledgling <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> lottery's first computerized numbers game. A photo at the top of the front page of Friday morning's newspaper showed the numbers 8-0-6, which turned out to be the winning combination in the first Cash 3 contest that night The photo, used to illustrate a story about the lottery, was of a sample ticket sent to the paper a month ago. `` This was entirely coincidental,'' City Editor <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Reed </PERSON> said. `` It does n't seem like that should need to be said, but we've gotten so many calls. The first daily contest produced 859 winners but none in the Times newsroom. `` In fact, I do n't know anyone that played daily game in the newsroom,'' <PERSON> Reed </PERSON> said. A spokesman for the lottery said the first Cash 3 game drawing went off without a hitch. Pingpong balls with the winning numbers were selected in only 60 seconds. The payout totaled $ 94,090. Ticket sales are expected to top $ 10 million in the first week. By 7:30 p.m. Friday, $ 616,543 had been wagered on Cash 3 and $ 345,377 on the jackpot Lotto game. Thirty-five percent of all lottery revenues are earmarked for public education. The first Lotto drawing will be held May 7. The prize will be at least $ 2 million but could reach $ 4 million. <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> joins 27 other states and the <LOCATION> District </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION> that have legalized lotteries. Law enforcement officials hope the legalized <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> numbers games will help undermine illegal numbers rackets.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880430-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-30-88 0212EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-China-YouthCrime     04-30 0218</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-China-Youth Crime,0224</SECOND>
<HEAD>Juveniles Cause Two-Thirds of Crimes in China</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Juveniles cause more than 60 percent of the crime in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> the crimes they commit are becoming more violent, the official <ORGANIZATION> China </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> reported today. The newspaper quoted <PERSON> Xu </PERSON> <PERSON> Jian </PERSON>, vice president of <ORGANIZATION> China </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Juvenile </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Delinquency </ORGANIZATION>, as saying the rate of juvenile crime is 12 per 10,000 of the same age group. He said that was more than double the overall crime rate of 5 per 10,000 people, but still much lower than in developed countries. <PERSON> Xu </PERSON> gave no figures for juvenile crimes or what age group is classified as juveniles. He said youths who in the past mainly committed minor offenses such as petty thefts and fighting are now engaged in robberies, violent assaults and rapes. <PERSON> Xu </PERSON> attributed the rise in juvenile crime to the lack of proper laws, the spread of pornography, the increasing numbers of working parents and divorce. Girls, mainly involved in hooliganism _ a general term for unsocial behavior _ or sex crimes, made up 18.6 percent of juvenile criminals in 1985, up from 10 percent in 1983, he said. <PERSON> Xu </PERSON> said juvenile delinquency would continue to rise in the near future and called for a national network to educate and prevent youths from committing crimes.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880430-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-30-88 0215EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-OPEC     04-30 0653</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-OPEC,0672</SECOND>
<BYLINE>Proposed Oil Deal Hinges On Saudi Assent</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT BURNS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>VIENNA, Austria (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> OPEC </ORGANIZATION> moved one major step closer today to an agreement that could slightly increase oil prices and set the stage for closer coordination with oil producers outside its ranks. But clinching the deal required the approval of oil ministers from <LOCATION> Saudi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arabia </LOCATION> and its three <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arab </LOCATION> allies, who said they needed to consult their governments first. A meeting of all <ORGANIZATION> OPEC </ORGANIZATION> oil ministers was set for tonight at cartel headquarters, but it was not certain a final decision would be made then. Eight of the 13 members of the <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Petroleum </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Exporting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Countries </ORGANIZATION> agreed in a meeting that ended early today to a proposed 2 percent cut in <ORGANIZATION> OPEC </ORGANIZATION>'s total oil production, according to oil ministers from <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Venezuela </LOCATION>. The cuts would be for May and June only, said Venezuelan Oil Minister <PERSON> Arturo </PERSON> <PERSON> Hernandez </PERSON> <PERSON> Grisanti </PERSON>. The Saudis earlier indicated they opposed production cuts, believing prices would rebound soon anyway since oil demand is likely to rise this summer. Saudi King <PERSON> Fahd </PERSON> said in a newspaper interview Thursday that <ORGANIZATION> OPEC </ORGANIZATION> should simply stick to its current set of production quotas, which often are exceeded. He did not explicitly rule out cuts as small as those proposed in <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION>. Besides <LOCATION> Saudi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arabia </LOCATION>, the others saying they wanted to think it over were <LOCATION> Kuwait </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Qatar </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arab </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Emirates </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>, which is not party to <ORGANIZATION> OPEC </ORGANIZATION>'s existing agreement on production limits, was not expected to take part in the proposed cuts, <PERSON> Hernandez </PERSON> said. The eight that tentatively accepted the deal this morning were <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Algeria </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Libya </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Nigeria </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Gabon </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Venezuela </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ecuador </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Indonesia </LOCATION>. The proposal was put on the table by <LOCATION> Algeria </LOCATION>. The proposed cuts in output, in conjunction with similarly small cuts by a group of six independent oil-producing nations, would remove a total of 500,000 barrels a day from the world oil market. The goal is to lift oil prices to <ORGANIZATION> OPEC </ORGANIZATION>'s target of $ 18 a 42-gallon barrel from the range now of between $ 14 and $ 16. Oil prices on the open market moved erratically in nervous trading Friday. Prices fell more than 60 cents a barrel in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> but recovered in later <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> trading. On the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mercantile </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Exchange </ORGANIZATION>, June contracts for West Texas Intermediate, the main <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> grade of oil, closed at $ 17.99 a barrel, up one cent from Thursday. At one point, the price was off 43 cents but then recovered. The proposed <ORGANIZATION> OPEC </ORGANIZATION> cuts are so small that analysts said the main effect on the market would be psychological. For <ORGANIZATION> OPEC </ORGANIZATION>, the principal benefit would be establishing closer ties to rival oil producers, who in recent years have weakened <ORGANIZATION> OPEC </ORGANIZATION> by taking away its market share. <ORGANIZATION> OPEC </ORGANIZATION> and non-OPEC producers have never before formally agreed to mutual cuts in production, although <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> has informally sought to align its policies with <ORGANIZATION> OPEC </ORGANIZATION>. The non-OPEC countries involved in the current proposal are <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Oman </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Malaysia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION>. Representatives of these independent producers were in <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION> earlier this week for talks with a committee of six <ORGANIZATION> OPEC </ORGANIZATION> oil ministers. They left before <ORGANIZATION> OPEC </ORGANIZATION>'s meeting began Thursday, so it was not immediately clear if they would be satisfied with the proposed cut of 2 percent, or 300,000 barrels a day, in <ORGANIZATION> OPEC </ORGANIZATION> production. The non-OPEC group stipulated it would cut its oil exports by 5 percent, or 200,000 barrels a day, only if <ORGANIZATION> OPEC </ORGANIZATION> made `` similar, proportional'' reductions. It was not more precise about the reciprocity. Regardless of the outcome of the talks on production cuts, <ORGANIZATION> OPEC </ORGANIZATION> intended to step up contacts with the non-OPEC group in hopes of establishing a regular dialogue that could lead to more coordination of production and pricing policy in the future, several oil ministers said. `` We must send a positive signal to them,'' said <PERSON> Gholamreza </PERSON> <PERSON> Aghazadeh </PERSON>, the oil minister of <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880430-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-30-88 0215EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-US-Panama Bjt   04-30 0519</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-US-Panama, Bjt,510</SECOND>
<HEAD>Panamanian Opposition Angered by Reported Deal on Noriega</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GEORGE GEDDA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Panamanian opposition leaders are reacting angrily to a proposed deal under which military strongman <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> would resign his post but remain in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> at least temporarily instead of going into exile. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials confirmed Friday that <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> agreed during negotiations with the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration to step down as commander of the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forces </ORGANIZATION> but that he had rejected <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> efforts to persuade him to leave the country immediately after resigning. The <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> said <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> is expected to step down in a matter of weeks and would prefer to live in the <LOCATION> Dominican </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Republic </LOCATION> if he is forced into exile. Panamanian Ambassador <PERSON> Juan </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Sosa </PERSON>, a leader of the anti-Noriega forces in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, reacted sharply to word of the proposed agreement. He accused the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> of going beyond its authority in trying to negotiate <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s political future. That issue, he said in an interview, `` has to be negotiated by Panamanians.'' He said <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>, by remaining in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>, would be able to `` wield his considerable influence'' because of the many Panamanians in the Defense Forces and in other key positions who are loyal to him. A <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> official, insisting on anonymity, acknowledged that the arrangement was `` less than ideal'' because it does not contemplate <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>'s short-term departure from <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Sosa </PERSON> has remained on as <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s ambassador to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, refusing to relinquish the embassy to a replacement envoy named by Panamanian President <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Solis </PERSON> <PERSON> Palma </PERSON>. <PERSON> Sosa </PERSON> and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> share the view that President <PERSON> Eric </PERSON> <PERSON> Arturo </PERSON> <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON>, deposed on Feb. 26 by <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>'s supporters, continues to be the legitimate authority in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>. In <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Roberto </PERSON> <PERSON> Eisenmann </PERSON>, exiled publisher of the closed independent newspaper <ORGANIZATION> La </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Prensa </ORGANIZATION>, said: `` This sounds like a surrender with cosmetics. This is the same mistake all over again _ the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> intervening in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>, ignoring totally the political forces of the country.'' <PERSON> Gilberto </PERSON> <PERSON> Mallol </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> representative of the Panamanian opposition umbrella group, the Civic Crusade, agreed. `` This cosmetic solution will only take the country down the road to disaster,'' said <PERSON> Mallol </PERSON>. `` The <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration has no right to decide <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> can remain in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>.'' Mallol disputed <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> contentions that <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> will be out of power as soon as he is out of uniform. `` Obviously, this deal shows <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> is making conditions. He will continue to interfere and continue the militarization of <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>.'' <PERSON> Mallol </PERSON> warned that the deal could backfire on the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, causing a wave of anti-American sentiment among <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> opponents. The administration has been seeking <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>'s ouster since he was indicted in early February on drug smuggling charges by two <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> grand juries. <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION> has offered to give <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> political asylum and, as an inducement to him, the administration has said it would make no effort to extradite him if he accepted the Spanish bid. The administration has refused to recognize <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s 2-month-old government and has frozen Panamanian government assets in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, among other measures. These steps have contributed to the collapse of the Panamanian economy.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880430-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-30-88 0216EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-GulfPolicy Bjt   04-30 0584</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Gulf Policy, Bjt,570</SECOND>
<HEAD>New Persian Gulf Policy Will Put Pressure On Iran, Official Says</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TERENCE HUNT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP White House Correspondent</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration is expanding the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military role in the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION>, saying it will not `` stand by and watch innocent people be killed or maimed'' in attacks on neutral ships. Under a policy announced Friday by <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Carlucci </PERSON>, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> forces will go to the aid of non-communist, neutral ships that are fired on and ask for help. Previously, the umbrella of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> protection had covered only American-flagged vessels and 11 Kuwaiti oil tankers that were allowed to register last summer as U.S.-flag vessels. The new policy, approved by President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> at a White House meeting Friday, is aimed chiefly at <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>, which <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials blame for nearly all of the attacks on ships outside declared war-exclusion zones. However, <PERSON> Carlucci </PERSON> said the policy should not be viewed as `` a tilt in either direction'' in the nearly eight-year war between <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s order came 11 days after American warships and aircraft clashed with Iranian forces in the gulf, sinking or disabling six Iranian vessels. The battles erupted following a <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> attack on Iranian oil platforms in retaliation for the mining of a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> frigate. Describing the new policy, <PERSON> Carlucci </PERSON> said: `` We are not the policeman of the gulf, nor do we wish to be. `` For over 200 years, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> policy has been to help protect freedom of navigation in international waters. This -LRB- new -RRB- assistance is a logical and humanitarian outgrowth of recent events in the gulf which further strengthens our adherence to this principle. `` We can not stand by and watch innocent people be killed or maimed by malicious, lawless actions when we have the means to assist, and perhaps prevent them. We do not intend to describe our specific rules of engagement or the methods we plan to use in rendering this assistance.'' <PERSON> Carlucci </PERSON> said the new policy will be provided to `` friendly, innocent neutral vessels flying a non-belligerent flag, outside declared war-exclusion zones, that are not carrying contraband or resisting legitimate visit and search by a <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> belligerent.'' An administration official said the policy will put `` a little more pressure'' on <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> to accept a cease-fire and withdrawal to pre-war borders. Most of <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'s attacks on ships have been in open, territorial waters that will be covered by the new policy, said the official, declining to be identified. By contrast, <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>'s attacks have been confined largely to so-called exclusionary zones that are not covered. The official noted that the protective coverage does not apply to ships from communist countries, and emphasized that skippers must request aid before an American ship renders assistance. Currently, the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> has 17 ships in the gulf, including six mine-sweepers, and 10 others in nearby waters. The current protective effort costs $ 1 million a day. <PERSON> Carlucci </PERSON> said that he does not anticipate the new policy will require an increase in <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> forces. The <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corps </ORGANIZATION>, meanwhile, declared that two officers who were listed as missing after the fighting 11 days earlier were `` killed in action'' and disclosed that they had reported a hostile radar had locked on their helicopter gunship before it disappeared. In a statement, the corps refused to say the AH-1T Cobra gunship flown by Capt. <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Leslie </PERSON>, 30, of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bern </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.C. </LOCATION>, and Capt. <PERSON> Kenneth </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Hill </PERSON>, 33, of <LOCATION> Thomasville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.C. </LOCATION>, had definitely been shot down by Iranian forces, as <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> has claimed.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880430-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-30-88 0219EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-DefenseSpending 610   04-30 0612</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Defense Spending, 610</SECOND>
<HEAD>House Rejects Threat Of Pullout To Increase Allied Spending</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TIM AHERN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The House says the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration ought to talk with <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> countries and <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> about spending more for defense, but has rejected calls to bring <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> troops home if that is n't done. The decisions were part of the Democratic-controlled <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>'s effort to write a <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> budget bill for the fiscal year starting Oct. 1 The <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> voted 359-0 late Friday afternoon to approve a proposal calling for the administration to initiate talks with <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> and <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> member nations about sharing the burden for defense. The <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> vote came as the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> released its 1988 report on `` Allied Contributions to the Common Defense,'' an annual assessment mandated by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. The report was accompanied by a personal pledge from <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Carlucci </PERSON> to `` press at every opportunity for progress'' in sharing the burdens of the alliance. <PERSON> Carlucci </PERSON> said the report's `` principal conclusion'' is that the allies are making more of a contribution than they receive credit for, but he said `` there are substantial variations in performance among individual allies.'' The <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> vote echoed a similar proposal approved last summer by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, but the administration has n't yet pushed hard for the talks. Both <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> members have criticized <LOCATION> Western </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> for failing to spend more on defense. They note that the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> spends about 6.9 percent of its gross national product on defense, a far larger share than other western nations. Despite the criticism, <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> has refused for three years to order sanctions against <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> and the alliance, a refusal that was continued Friday by the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has about 326,000 troops stationed in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> and 63,000 in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>. By a 240-120 vote, the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> rejected a proposal by Rep. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Bryant </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Texas </LOCATION>, to bring 30,000 troops a year back from <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> and 7,000 troops a year from <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> starting in 1991. Minutes later it voted 332-21 to reject a plan by Rep. <PERSON> Tommy </PERSON> <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Ark </LOCATION>., to withdraw 70,000 troops a year from <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> `` Let's get smart and begin to tell our allies that we expect them to pay their fair share,'' <PERSON> Bryant </PERSON> said. `` We are subsidizing their defense.'' <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> made a similar appeal, telling his colleagues: `` The real purpose of this amendment is to demonstrate to our allies that we've had it. These people are stealing our jobs because we have been suckered into paying for their defense.'' But Rep. <PERSON> Curt </PERSON> <PERSON> Weldon </PERSON>, R-Pa., said the issue should be `` considered in a clear process and not on an emotional basis. `` It is simply not possible to maintain the viability of a voluntary alliance of free countries if one of those countries tries to impose standards on the others,'' said Rep. <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> Solarz </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N </LOCATION>. But Rep. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Obey </PERSON>, D-Wis., said, `` It's time Uncle <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> quit being taken for Uncle Sucker. The spending bill would authorize the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> to spend $ 299.5 billion in the fiscal year starting Oct. 1, which is the same amount proposed by the separate bill that will be considered next month by the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>. Differences between the bills eventually will be reconciled by a <ORGANIZATION> House-Senate </ORGANIZATION> conference committee. The <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> report said that the 6.1 percent of gross national product spent by <LOCATION> Greece </LOCATION> for defense in 1986 was the closest to the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> share. <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> was third with 5.1 percent, followed by <LOCATION> Turkey </LOCATION> at 4.8 percent and <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> at 3.9 percent. `` All of the remaining nations have shares of 3.2 percent or less,'' the study found. The report used 1986 data because that is the most recent year for which figures were available.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880430-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-30-88 0226EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Durenberger-Espionage     04-30 0534</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Durenberger-Espionage,520</SECOND>
<HEAD>Ethics Committee Chastises Durenberger On Espionage Disclosure</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LEE GOULD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> ethics panel says comments by Sen. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Durenberger </PERSON> on an espionage case hurt relations between <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and intelligence agencies, but <PERSON> Durenberger </PERSON> says the harm already had been done by the late <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> chief <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Casey </PERSON>. <PERSON> Durenberger </PERSON> was chastised Friday by the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ethics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> as it closed an investigation that began last year after the <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION> Republican publicly discussed an espionage case involving the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>. The committee told <PERSON> Durenberger </PERSON> in a letter: `` The <ORGANIZATION> Ethics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> has determined that your statements gave the appearance that you were disclosing sensitive national security information and such appearance jeopardized the mutual confidence which must exist between the <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and the intelligence community. ... `` Because the committee has concluded that your actions were not intentional, deliberate, nor attended with gross negligence, and because of the particular facts of this case, we will not recommend that the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> take institutional action against you. However, the committee wants to make it clear that it does not condone your actions.'' The ethics investigation centered on comments <PERSON> Durenberger </PERSON> made at an event sponsored by the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Israel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Affairs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Palm </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>, on March 15, 1987. <PERSON> Durenberger </PERSON> reportedly disclosed to the group that <PERSON> Casey </PERSON> in 1982 had `` changed the rules'' under which allies did not spy on each other by recruiting an <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> military officer to spy on <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> for the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Durenberger </PERSON>'s comments were said to be aimed at giving context to the case of <PERSON> Jonathan </PERSON> <PERSON> Jay </PERSON> <PERSON> Pollard </PERSON>, an American convicted of spying on the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> for <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Durenberger </PERSON> said he based his remarks on newspaper accounts and maintained that he exercised `` due care'' in preparation for the speech. The former chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Select </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> on </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Intelligence </ORGANIZATION> issued a statement saying he was pleased that the committee had concluded its investigation and determined that no action was necessary. But he added: `` The late <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> Director <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Casey </PERSON>'s fundamental disagreement over the philosophy of congressional oversight led to frequent clashes with the <ORGANIZATION> Intelligence </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>. `` Director <PERSON> Casey </PERSON> was a strong leader, loyal to his own view of the public interest, but his belief that <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> should play little or no role in intelligence oversight led to a lack of mutual confidence long before March 1987.'' He added, `` I respectfully disagree with the ethic committee's conclusion that my statements gave the appearance that I was disclosing sensitive information. Sources present at the <LOCATION> Palm </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION> meeting and who said they took careful notes reported that <PERSON> Durenberger </PERSON> said the <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> recruited its Israeli spy after <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s 1982 invasion of <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>. The spy passed along sensitive information about the invasion, <PERSON> Durenberger </PERSON> reportedly told the group. In a separate statement Friday, <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Minority Leader <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>, R-Kan., said <PERSON> Durenberger </PERSON> `` was an excellent chairman during one of the most demanding and crucial periods for intelligence oversight I had just as much confidence in <PERSON> Dave </PERSON> before the <ORGANIZATION> Ethics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> examination as I do right now.'' The Ethics <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> letter was signed by <PERSON> Sens </PERSON>. <PERSON> Howell </PERSON> <PERSON> Heflin </PERSON>, D-Ala., <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Pryor </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Ark </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> <PERSON> Sanford </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.C. </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Warren </PERSON> <PERSON> Rudman </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-N.H. </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Helms </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-N.C. </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> <PERSON> Kassebaum </PERSON>, R-Kan
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880430-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-30-88 0227EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-OSHA-WarningTags     04-30 0507</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-OSHA-Warning Tags,490</SECOND>
<HEAD>Agency Issues Long-Awaited Regulations On Idled Machinery</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MATT YANCEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Labor Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Occupational </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> wants employers to put warning tags on machinery that has been shut off to prevent injuries and deaths caused when the machines are turned on while being cleaned or serviced. Nine years and 1,000 deaths after unions first pleaded for action on one of the single biggest causes of industrial accidents, the agency issued proposed regulations Friday on so-called `` tagouts'' and `` lockouts.'' The proposals appeared in the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Register </ORGANIZATION> a week after <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, D-Mass., said the delay showed the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration's `` decision to let workers die while waiting on a standard. <ORGANIZATION> OSHA </ORGANIZATION> officials testified last week at a <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> hearing chaired by <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> that the proposed regulations had been completed by the agency in early 1987 but had languished at the White House for nearly a year. About 7 percent of all occupational fatalities and 2 per cent of accident-caused injuries in the workplace occur now because such equipment is inadvertently restarted while someone is working on it. The agency estimated Friday that the so-called `` performance-oriented'' regulations will save 122 lives and prevent 60,000 job injuries a year. But they would require employers only to follow certain steps in turning off equipment and `` minimize'' the potential for inadvertently reactivating it. `` Very simple lockout, tagout measures, which taken only a few minutes, can prevent up to 10 percent of all the serious injuries in some major manufacturing industries,'' said Assistant Labor Secretary <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Pendergrass </PERSON>. Agency officials estimated it will be a minimum of another year before the regulations are actually enacted. Unions had begun petitioning the agency for the regulations in 1979. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Molovich </PERSON>, a safety specialist for the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Steelworkers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION>, predicted employers will ignore the guidelines and `` take the cheapest way out'' by using cardboard warning tags instead of locks to prevent a machine from being turned on. `` There will be no positive means of assuring that the equipment wo n't start,'' he said. The regulations, if adopted in current form, will apply to only 1.6 million employers and cover only 39 million workers, most of them in manufacturing. <ORGANIZATION> OSHA </ORGANIZATION> estimated the annual cost of compliance to businesses at $ 135 million. Exempted are millions of companies and workers in agriculture, oil and gas drilling, electric utilities, the maritime industry and construction. <ORGANIZATION> OSHA </ORGANIZATION> said protections for them will be included in other regulations to be proposed later. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Scully </PERSON>, an <ORGANIZATION> OSHA </ORGANIZATION> official who worked on the regulations for more than a decade, testified at the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> hearings last week that the agency had first seen a need for them back in 1977. But <ORGANIZATION> OSHA </ORGANIZATION> took no serious action until 1979, when the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Auto </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Workers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION>, reacting to the deaths of 22 of its members in related accidents the previous five years, formally asked the government for emergency action. <ORGANIZATION> OSHA </ORGANIZATION> denied that request and similar pleas in 1982 and 1986 from other unions.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880430-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-30-88 0226EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-BRF--NewMadonna     04-30 0174</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--New Madonna,0178</SECOND>
<HEAD>New York Artist Wins Contest to Create New Image of the Madonna</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CHICAGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> artist was named as the winner of a nationwide contest to create a new image of the <PERSON> Madonna </PERSON> for <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>'s oldest <ORGANIZATION> Roman </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Bryan </PERSON> <PERSON> Hunt </PERSON>'s entry, a pair of oil, pastel and graphite panels titled `` <PERSON> Madonna </PERSON> and Child I and II,'' was selected as the best of more than 400 entries sent by the nation's artists to <LOCATION> Old </LOCATION> <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Patrick </LOCATION>'s Church. The Rev. <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Wall </PERSON>, pastor of Old St. <PERSON> Patrick </PERSON>'s, announced Friday that <PERSON> Hunt </PERSON>'s work was chosen from a field of 17 finalists by a jury of art critics and curators, including a representative of the church. `` We are very pleased with the jurors' selection,'' <PERSON> Wall </PERSON> said. `` We were seeking a dramatic way to relook at <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> in the Catholic church, and we have found it in this winning piece.'' As winner, <PERSON> Hunt </PERSON> will receive a purchase price of $ 10,000 for the two panels, which each measure 22 by 33 inches.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880430-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-30-88 0228EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-ChristiansRally     04-30 0512</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Christians Rally,510</SECOND>
<HEAD>Rally Calls For Healing Of Nation, Evangelical Movement</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PHYLLIS MESSINGER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Tens of thousands of <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> activists braved cold, damp weather to hear a message of support from President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> as they prayed for `` the sins of the nation'' and the scandal-plagued evangelical movement. `` It has been prayer which has strengthened this nation to weather storms both here and abroad,'' <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> told the group Friday in a videotaped message. `` I am convinced that prayer has made it possible for me to continue in this office.'' <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Park </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION> estimated that the dawn-to-dusk `` <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> for <PERSON> Jesus </PERSON> in'88'' rally attracted 150,000 people. Organizers emphasized the racial, ethnic and religious diversity of the crowd. They said they hoped the gathering would show all Americans that Christians remain as ardent and unified as ever, despite the well-publicized downfall of television evangelists <PERSON> Jimmy </PERSON> <PERSON> Swaggart </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> and <PERSON> Tammy </PERSON> <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON>. `` The world thought the scandals of the last year brought the church to its knees,'' <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Coral </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ridge </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Presbyterian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Church </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> said. `` The church will arise from its knees, cleaner and purer and stronger.'' The gathering was meant to be non-political, which was why organizers said Republican presidential candidate <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> was not invited. <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> was one of the main speakers at a similar rally in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> eight years ago. In fact, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> was the only national political figure to speak to the crowd. `` Today, American society must face serious problems, from within and without, which threaten to steal our liberties and destroy our freedoms,'' <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said. `` Abortion, child abuse, pornography and drug addiction eat away at our most precious national resource _ our children. `` Yet we do not falter in the face of such evil for there is a wind of prayer blowing throughout our land.'' Earlier, evangelist <PERSON> Oral </PERSON> <PERSON> Roberts </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Tulsa </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Okla. </LOCATION>, made a brief speech recalling how `` a man of God'' laid hands on him and cured him of tuberculosis when he was 17. `` I stand here today, 53 years later with my lungs sound and whole, my body healed by the power of God,'' he said as members of the audience applauded. One of the first speakers of the day was the Rev. <PERSON> Gerald </PERSON> <PERSON> Derstine </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Bradenton </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>, who urged `` Christians to offer prayers of `` repentance for the sins of the naion.'' `` I am talking about drug addiction, alcoholism and suicides. We feel prayer in the schools is still an important issue and we believe abortion still is an issue,'' <PERSON> Derstine </PERSON> said. Such sentiments were echoed in the banners and signs carried by rally participants. One banner said, `` Take drugs out of our schools and put God back in.'' Another sign said, `` <PERSON> Jesus </PERSON> forgives sinning, let him.'' One of the rally-goers, <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Goldbloom </PERSON>, assistant pastor of Full Gospel Tabernacle in <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION>, said he thought it significant that the rally was being held in the nation's capital. `` I believe a public display of prayer and repentence will let <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> know and the country know that people still love God,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880430-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-30-88 0229EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-OrganizedCrime     04-30 0620</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Organized Crime,610</SECOND>
<HEAD>Mobster Says ``We Don't Kill Innocent People''</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LARRY MARGASAK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An indicted <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> mobster says <LOCATION> La </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Cosa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Nostra </LOCATION> families use murder to enforce their internal rules, but insists, `` We do n't kill innocent people.'' <PERSON> Vincent </PERSON> `` The Fish'' <PERSON> Cafaro </PERSON>, who was a `` soldier'' in the Genovese organized crime family, told senators Friday the organization was `` very disciplined'' and members paid a high price for breaking the rules. `` Killings were mandatory'' for fooling around with another member's wife and dealing in drugs, he said. `` When it comes to an amico nostra's wife or ` junk' there was no talk,'' <PERSON> Cafaro </PERSON> said. An amico nostra is a member of a mob family, and `` junk'' means narcotics. <PERSON> Cafaro </PERSON> said mob members also could get murdered for `` ratting, refusing to go on a ` hit' if asked or knowingly killing a cop or other law enforcement agent.'' To win approval to carry out a murder, <PERSON> Cafaro </PERSON> said, mob members had to go through the chain of command, right up to the boss of the family. But he insisted, `` We do n't kill innocent people.'' Unlike witnesses who spoke from behind a screen, <PERSON> Cafaro </PERSON> _ a thin, balding man with glasses _ testified in full public view before the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Permanent </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Subcommittee </ORGANIZATION> on Investigations. He currently is in custody while awaiting trial in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> on racketeering, extortion and conspiracy charges. After his arrest in 1986, he cooperated with federal authorities and even carried a concealed microphone while talking to other mobsters. But <PERSON> Cafaro </PERSON> said personal safety concerns have persuaded him to end the effort, and he was heavily guarded in the hearing room. `` I'm fair game, no question about it,'' he said. <PERSON> Cafaro </PERSON> said he had worked for the mob since 1958, as an associate of `` Fat Tony'' <PERSON> Salerno </PERSON>, a major figure in the Genovese family. <PERSON> Salerno </PERSON>, who <PERSON> Cafaro </PERSON> said was `` like a father to me,'' is now on trial in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> on charges related to mob activities. <PERSON> Cafaro </PERSON> also told the committee, headed by Sen. <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> <PERSON> Nunn </PERSON>, D-Ga., that four organized crime families run the high-rise construction industry in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> through control over the concrete industry and construction unions He said bids were rigged, and that contractors and unions winning construction jobs had to kick back 2 percent of the contract price to the mob. <PERSON> Cafaro </PERSON> said the system was arranged through the `` ` 2 <ORGANIZATION> Percent </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Club </ORGANIZATION>,'' an organization run by the Genovese, <PERSON> Gambino </PERSON>, Lucchese and <LOCATION> Colombo </LOCATION> families. He estimated that at least 50 percent of the high-rise construction in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> had a mob connection and added, `` Legitimate guys ai n't got a chance'' to win contracts for those buildings. <PERSON> Cafaro </PERSON> said each of the four mob families had an expert on the construction business in the organization. Members read the Dodge Reports, a construction trade publication that lists upcoming jobs, he said. `` The club members split up all of the jobs over $ 2 million,'' he said. But if the contract went over $ 5 million, it went to a mob-run company, <ORGANIZATION> S </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; A Concrete, he said. When the smaller contractors complained of the arrangement, he said, they won the right to split all jobs over $ 3 million. As a mob soldier who turned down promotions because he did n't want the added responsibility, <PERSON> Cafaro </PERSON> said he preferred to run the numbers business in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Harlem </LOCATION> `` I had some bad years, but in a good year I could make as much as $ 2 million or more,'' he said. When <PERSON> Nunn </PERSON> asked if he kept the money, <PERSON> Cafaro </PERSON> said: `` I spent it. I gave it away. I loaned a lot of money to people and never got it back.'' The mobster said he only carried cash.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880430-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-30-88 0240EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FarmScene     04-30 0750</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Farm Scene,790</SECOND>
<HEAD>Farm Prices Unchanged From March To April</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DON KENDALL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Farm Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A preliminary report for April shows that prices farmers got for raw products were unchanged, on average, for the second month in a row but were still 4 percent above a year ago. But the report Friday by the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> also said that farm production expenses have crept higher in recent months. `` Prices were higher for soybeans, cattle, hay and oranges, and lower for lettuce, eggs, milk and strawberries,'' the department's <ORGANIZATION> Agricultural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Statistics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> said New quarterly figures showed prices paid by farmers to meet expenses were up 1.8 percent from January and averaged 3.7 percent more than in April 1987. `` Higher prices for feeder pigs, fertilizer, agricultural chemicals, tractors and other machinery contributed most to the increase from January,'' the report said. Department economists say net cash income of farmers set a record in 1987 of about $ 57 billion. This year's net _ the difference between cash receipts and cash expenses _ may be in the range of $ 50 billion to $ 55 billion. Consumer food prices are expected to rise 2 percent to 4 percent this year, compared with a 4.1 percent average increase in 1987. According to the preliminary April figures, based mostly on mid-month averages, the index for livestock and livestock products was unchanged from March but was up 0.7 percent from a year ago. `` Higher prices for cattle, calves and broilers were offset by lower prices for eggs, milk and hogs,'' the report said. Crop prices overall were up 0.9 percent from March and averaged 9.9 percent more than a year ago. The price index for oil-bearing crops, which consist mainly of soybeans, was up 3.3 percent from March and averaged 22 percent more than in April 1987. Soybeans prices, at $ 6.36 per bushel, were up 30 cents during the month. Prices paid to commercial vegetable growers, overall, dropped 4.4 percent from March and also were down 4.4 percent from a year ago. The prices of most individual vegetables rose from March to April, but those increases were more than offset by a sharp drop for lettuce and a seasonal decline in asparagus prices. April farm commodity prices averaged 130 percent of a 1977 base used for comparison, according to the preliminary figures, the same as in March and February. A year ago the April index was 125 percent. The quarterly parity ratio was reported at 51 percent in April, down two percentage points from the revised January reading of 53 percent. The revised parity ratio for April 1987 also was 51 percent. Although many economists say the old parity standard is outmoded because it does n't take into full account changes in farm productivity, others contend the ratio is useful in comparing year-to-year changes. Under the parity formula, prices farmers get for commodities are compared with prices they pay to meet expenses. It then uses a 1910-14 measurement to express what happened. At 100 percent, the indicator would theoretically mean farmers had the same buying power as they had in 1910-14. For example, the average price of wheat in April was $ 2.81 per bushel, according to the preliminary figures. That was 40 percent of the parity price of $ 7.07 per bushel. The report also said: _ Cattle averaged $ 68.90 per 100 pounds of live weight nationally, up from $ 68.30 in March and above the $ 62.60 reported for April 1987 Those are averages for all types of cattle sold as beef. _ Hogs averaged $ 41.80 per 100 pounds, compared with $ 42.20 in March and $ 50.80 a year earlier _ Corn, at $ 1.85 a bushel, was down from $ 1.86 in March, but was up from the average of $ 1.52 a year earlier _ Wheat prices at the farm, according to preliminary figures, averaged $ 2.81 per bushel, compared with $ 2.74 in March and $ 2.63 a year earlier _ Rice averaged $ 8.41 per 100 pounds, compared with $ 8.79 in March and $ 3.63 a year earlier _ Soybeans were $ 6.36 per bushel, compared with $ 6.06 in March and $ 4.90 a year earlier _ Upland cotton was reported at 57.3 cents per pound, compared with 57.7 in March and 50.4 cents in April 1987 _ Eggs were 45.5 cents per dozen, compared with 50.8 cents in March and 54.8 cents a year earlier _ Milk was $ 11.70 per 100 pounds, compared with $ 11.90 in March and $ 12.20 a year earlier _ Broilers were 28 cents per pound, live weight, compared with 27.5 cents in March and 29.2 cents a year ago
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880430-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-30-88 0009EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-PromRevival 1stLd-Writethru a0726 04-30 0686</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Prom Revival, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0726,0704</SECOND>
<HEAD>Senior Prom Returns after 25-Year Hiatus</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: LEADS with two grafs to UPDATE with prom under way. PICKS UP
2nd graf pvs, `The last ...'; INSERTS three grafs after 10th graf
pvs, `The town ...' to UPDATE with prom underway.</NOTE>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto LR1</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TOM PARSONS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>FORREST CITY, Ark. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The senior prom returned to <ORGANIZATION> Forrest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> High </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> on Friday, more than 25 years after it was banned by school officials. `` I'm gon na do Da Bump,'' <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>, an 18-year-old senior, said as he made his appearance at the <ORGANIZATION> Forrest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Civic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> dressed all in white but for a black snap-brim hat and black cane. The last prom was in 1962, said <PERSON> Principal </PERSON> <PERSON> Oscar </PERSON> <PERSON> Collins </PERSON>, who helped plan the last one as a senior class sponsor early in his career. He said he did n't know what had prompted the ban _ `` I was just a teacher at the time'' _ noting that it would n't have been a racial issue because the first black student did n't enter the school until 1965. `` That was before integration. After that, the board voted not to have them any more,'' <PERSON> Collins </PERSON> said. However, the student council officers decided not to have a king and queen for the new prom partly because the couple might be racially mixed, the <ORGANIZATION> Arkansas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Gazette </ORGANIZATION> reported Friday. The newspaper's assertion was disputed by <PERSON> Kaki </PERSON> <PERSON> Dunn </PERSON>, 17, recording secretary for the council. `` We decided not to have a prom king and queen because we feel that we're all kings and queens,'' she said. `` We talked about it and said, ` No, we do n't want to do that.' More than half the 355 seniors were expected to attend the dance in the <ORGANIZATION> Forrest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Civic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>, Student Council President <PERSON> Tangella </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> said. Assistant Principal <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Bridges </PERSON> said he expected the crowd to be about evenly divided between black and white students, like the composition of the 1,450-student school. `` I do n't think that's even been thought about,'' Bridges said. The town of about 14,000, 45 miles west of <LOCATION> Memphis </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Tenn. </LOCATION>, is about evenly divided between black and white. The boys wore black, white or gray but the colors of the girls' gowns ranged across the spectrum and skirt lengths were anywhere between the ankles and the knees Three couples stepped out of a stretch limouisine from a funeral home, the driver holding the door. Then, at the request of a TV crew, they got back in and did it again. <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> McNair </PERSON>, 18, sharply dressed in an Army Junior ROTC uniform, came all the way from <LOCATION> Benton </LOCATION>, 125 miles to the west, to escort his cousin, <PERSON> Lori </PERSON> <PERSON> Martin </PERSON>, 18. Precautions were taken to avoid any problems at the prom, Bridges said. `` There'll be strictly no drinking,'' he said. `` We do n't allow smoking anyway, at the school, so there'll be no smoking at the prom, no drinking, no drugs.'' Students who leave the prom will not be able to return, he said. `` And there wo n't be any press or anything like that,'' Bridges said. `` It's going to be strictly for the kids.'' The <ORGANIZATION> Forrest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> voted last fall to allow the <ORGANIZATION> Student </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> to sponsor a prom for 1988's graduating seniors. `` We just thought it was time for us to do like other folks,'' school board member <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Baxter </PERSON> said after that meeting. `` It's a milestone,'' said Mayor <PERSON> Danny </PERSON> <PERSON> Ferguson </PERSON>, a 1967 graduate of the school. `` People in <LOCATION> Forrest </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> are pulling together to project a positive image.'' No dances have been sponsored by the school since 1962, not even informal hops in the gym, Ms. <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> said this week. `` They've had them, but they were provided by different fraternities or different sororities,'' said Ms. <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>, 17, who is black. `` But as for those provided by the school, this will be the first.'' The private dances, <PERSON> Collins </PERSON> said, have been strictly black or white affairs, none of them integrated. The theme chosen for the prom was `` A Night on the Town,'' said Bridges. `` They've got skyscrapers and all that,'' he said. `` It'll look pretty good.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880430-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-30-88 0308EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Bowen-Drugs     04-30 0596</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bowen-Drugs,590</SECOND>
<HEAD>Reagan Administration Soft-Pedals Bowen Pessimism On Drug War</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JERRY ESTILL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Health Secretary <PERSON> Otis </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bowen </PERSON>, in a move acknowledged by the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> to be `` a little unusual,'' is taking public issue with the assertion that the administration is winning the war on drugs. `` Generally speaking, Mr. President, I prefer optimism to pessimism, as you do,'' <PERSON> Bowen </PERSON> told <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and three <ORGANIZATION> Cabinet </ORGANIZATION> colleagues at a meeting of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Drug </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Policy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION>. `` But today, I do n't know how I can honestly be very optimistic about the war on drugs.'' <PERSON> Bowen </PERSON> said <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s leadership has resulted in `` major gains.'' `` We're winning some battles,'' he said, `` but it's difficult for me to say we're winning the war, especially when we consider drug dealing and use in our streets and our homes.'' A text of <PERSON> Bowen </PERSON>'s remarks at the private <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> meeting on Thursday was made public Friday by the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Human </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION>. White House spokesman <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> acknowledged afterward that it was `` a little unusual'' for a Cabinet officer to go public with remarks delivered to the president in a private meeting. But he sought to soft-pedal any differences between <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and <PERSON> Bowen </PERSON>. `` That's the same thing the president said _ we've made progress but obviously we need to do more,'' said <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON>. `` I do n't know what he's up to,'' <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said of <PERSON> Bowen </PERSON>'s action `` On the other hand, there's nothing wrong with it.'' <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> often has been upbeat about the war on drugs. `` With all the headlines about how we're losing the drug war, let's keep in mind the progress we've made,'' he told a White House Conference for a <LOCATION> Drug-Free </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> on Feb. 29, adding, `` We've strengthened the laws'' and `` drug seizures are at an all-time high.'' <PERSON> Bowen </PERSON> backed the administration's call for tougher law enforcement in his Thursday presentation, but he also called for more attention to effective treatment and strong federal leadership to establish additional treatment clinics. And he made clear there was a pragmatic political component to his appeal. `` Mr. <PERSON> President </PERSON>, there are political dangers as well,'' said the <ORGANIZATION> HHS </ORGANIZATION> chief. In a clear refererence to <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, <PERSON> Bowen </PERSON> said, `` One of the two remaining Democrat candidates for president is getting some of his highest marks for his passionate and creative oratory on the drug epidemic and is poised to steal from our party what has been a traditional Republican issue _ law enforcement.'' <PERSON> Bowen </PERSON> supported aggressive law enforcement and other approaches such as first lady <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s `` Just Say No'' campaign, but he said `` some'' are using the first lady's campaign `` as a political football, saying it's an empty slogan, however unfair that characterization might be.'' He went on: `` I believe as we approach the end of this second term, we need to take a fresh look at what we're doing to secure a lasting end to the demand for illicit drugs.'' He called for more research to improve the efficiency of treatment strategies and expanded treatment facilities. `` On the topic of treatment,'' <PERSON> Bowen </PERSON> said, `` we also need to talk turkey with big-city mayors, councils, and suburban jurisdictions as well, who often knuckle under to pressure from those who are, quote-unquote, ` all for treatment, as long as it's not in my backyard. `` Communities and neighborhoods need to be willing to accept treatment facilities,'' he said. `` In some instances, -LRB- federal -RRB- funding is available, it's just not being used.'' Among those at the Thursday meeting were Attorney General <PERSON> Edwin </PERSON> <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>, Education Secretary <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Burnley </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880430-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-30-88 0223EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-HijackDeal Bjt   04-30 0632</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Hijack Deal, Bjt,620</SECOND>
<HEAD>Hijackers Still In Algeria, US Officials Say</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BARRY SCHWEID</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Diplomatic Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The gunmen who hijacked a <ORGANIZATION> Kuwaiti </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airways </ORGANIZATION> jumbo jet for 15 days remain in <LOCATION> Algeria </LOCATION>, where the ordeal ended last week after a <LOCATION> Kuwaiti </LOCATION> promise to give `` early release'' to a handful of Shiite Moslem prisoners, according to a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> account. On Thursday, Algerian Ambassador <PERSON> Mohammed </PERSON> <PERSON> Sahnoun </PERSON> said the hijackers had left <LOCATION> Algeria </LOCATION> without getting what they wanted and without obtaining any concessions for freeing the 31 remaining passengers. But two <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> on Friday the hijackers had been promised that five or six of the 17 prisoners held in <LOCATION> Kuwait </LOCATION> for bomb attacks on the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and French embassies in 1983 would be released early. However, the prisoners have not been released and the gunmen, who had been promised safe passage, remain in <LOCATION> Algeria </LOCATION>, the officials said on condition of anonymity. According to this account of the negotiations, Algerian intermediaries faithfully conveyed <LOCATION> Kuwait </LOCATION>'s promise to the hijackers. But the officials said <LOCATION> Kuwait </LOCATION>, which has a firm policy of not yielding to terrorism, may not have had any intention of letting the prisoners go in the first place. `` They have stood so fast for so long, they probably had no intention of letting them go early,'' one of the officials said. The five-year prison terms of three of the 17 Shiite Moslems are due to expire at the end of the year. During the long ordeal, the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> repeatedly urged <LOCATION> Kuwait </LOCATION> publicly and privately not to yield to the hijackers. The <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration was not aware of the terms to end the siege because they were worked out through Algerian intermediaries, the officials said. The account was provided by <LOCATION> Algeria </LOCATION>, which has played a role in resolving several hijackings, in diplomatic contacts with the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> in the aftermath of the hijacking. <PERSON> Sahnoun </PERSON> also said that while his government would have liked to apprehend the hijackers, such a move would have damaged its credibility as a mediator in international crises such as attempts to obtain the release of the eight American hostages in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Sahnoun </PERSON>, addressing reporters at the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Club </ORGANIZATION> here, said the hijackers `` went back without achieving anything.'' The Kuwaiti press agency also said on April 20 that the hijackers _ there were believed to be eight or nine _ had probably been flown to <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> or <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>. But the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> the gunmen had remained in <LOCATION> Algeria </LOCATION>. Another <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> official, interviewed separately, said <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION> had assured the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> that despite reports to the contrary, the hijackers had not been flown from <LOCATION> Algeria </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Damascus </LOCATION>. Reports from <LOCATION> Algiers </LOCATION> had said the terrorists were flown to <LOCATION> Damascus </LOCATION>, from where they made their way by land to <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> has identified one of the hijackers as <PERSON> Hassan </PERSON> <PERSON> Izz-al-Din </PERSON> and said he might have been involved in the killing of <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> diver <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Stethem </PERSON> in the hijacking of a <ORGANIZATION> TWA </ORGANIZATION> jetliner in 1985. He was charged by a federal grand jury in seizing the plane. This raises a possibility of a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> request for extradition. Also, Secretary of State <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> has said one of the passengers may have had dual <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> citizenship. He condemned the hijackers last week as murderers. The plane, a <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> 747 with 112 passengers and crew members, was hijacked April 5 on a flight from <LOCATION> Thailand </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Kuwait </LOCATION> and spent several days in Meshed, <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>, and <LOCATION> Larnaca </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Cyprus </LOCATION>, before flying to <LOCATION> Algiers </LOCATION>. Two Kuwaiti passengers were killed and their bodies dumped from the plane while it was in <LOCATION> Cyprus </LOCATION>. The hijackers' principal demand was the release of the 17 prisoners in <LOCATION> Kuwait </LOCATION>. The freed hostages included three members of the <LOCATION> Kuwaiti </LOCATION> royal family.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880430-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-30-88 0308EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Gonzalez-Spain     04-30 0314</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Gonzalez-Spain,0322</SECOND>
<HEAD>Spain's Prime Minister Urges More Respect for His `Awakening'
Country</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DANA KENNEDY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CAMBRIDGE, Mass. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <LOCATION> Spanish </LOCATION> prime minister has a message for Americans who think <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION> is a sleepy, dusty country crippled by years of dictatorship. <PERSON> Felipe </PERSON> <PERSON> Gonzalez </PERSON>, who was elected in 1982, is in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> making what amounts to an announcement that his country should no longer be considered the <PERSON> Rodney </PERSON> <PERSON> Dangerfield </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION> wants some respect. `` We'd like to change the nature of relations between the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Gonzalez </PERSON> said Friday, speaking through an interpreter in his hotel room. `` Above all, we want <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION> to be accepted by the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> as we are now. <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION> is going to be economically sound by the end of the century.'' The year 1992, <PERSON> Gonzalez </PERSON> said, marks <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION>'s `` awakening'' from <PERSON> Francisco </PERSON> <PERSON> Franco </PERSON>'s 36-year rule that ended with <PERSON> Franco </PERSON>'s death in 1975. In four years, the Summer Olympics will be held in <LOCATION> Barcelona </LOCATION>, a World's Fair will take place in <LOCATION> Seville </LOCATION> and the 500th anniversary of <PERSON> Christopher </PERSON> <PERSON> Columbus </PERSON>' voyage will be celebrated in <LOCATION> Madrid </LOCATION>. The year 1992 also marks the completion of <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION>'s integration into the European Economic Community. `` Over the last 10 years that have gone by, the economy has begun producing rapidly,'' said <PERSON> Gonzalez </PERSON>. `` <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION> for over half a century had a hyper-protectionist economy but now that it's opened up we've seen rapid development and economic growth. This is what we want to communicate to the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION>'' On Thursday, speaking at <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Gonzalez </PERSON> said <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION> was part of a growing political and economic union in <LOCATION> Western </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> that could lead to a stronger <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> alliance. However, the 46-year-old prime minister said it will take time for <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION> to recover from <PERSON> Franco </PERSON>'s regime. At present, the per capita income in <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION> is less than half of <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>'s, he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880430-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-30-88 0320EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-TuskegeeProtest     04-30 0285</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Tuskegee Protest,0296</SECOND>
<HEAD>Judge Throws Out Temporary Restraining Order Against University</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TUSKEGEE, Ala. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A judge Friday allowed <ORGANIZATION> Tuskegee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> to bar students who owe more than $ 300 in overdue fees from taking final exams, a school spokesman said. Judge <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bryan </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Macon </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> dissolved the restraining order he had issued Wednesday against enforcement of the policy, said <PERSON> J.J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>. Students who owe more than $ 300 on Monday _ when final exams begin _ will not be allowed to take their tests, <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> said. University officials testified Friday that 600 students owed more than $ 300 in fees, said <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Pintard </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> Student </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Government </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>. The judge ordered Tuskegee to open its business office all day Saturday and part of Sunday so students could make payments on overdue fees, <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> said. The university announced earlier that abuse of an installment plan had prompted it to enforce its policy barring students with overdue fees from attending class or taking exams. Officials estimated 2,000 students owe almost $ 1.5 million. The crackdown had sparked a week of protests, including a sit-in at the administration building last weekend. Student leaders said the university should have warned students earlier about the crackdown and should have allowed students in financial difficulty to work out a timetable for repayment. <PERSON> Pintard </PERSON> calling the judge's ruling Friday a `` serious miscarriage of justice.'' University President <PERSON> Benjamin </PERSON> <PERSON> Payton </PERSON> said the ruling `` underscores the fact that when students make loans they have to pay them.'' `` What everybody needs to be clear about, however, is this is not a case of <ORGANIZATION> Tuskegee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> fighting its students,'' <PERSON> Payton </PERSON> said. `` It's a case of <ORGANIZATION> Tuskegee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> insisting that students learn very important lessons for life.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880430-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-30-88 0321EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-KingMarch     04-30 0299</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-King March,0305</SECOND>
<HEAD>Monthlong King Pilgrimage to Wind Up in Atlanta Today</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Rally scheduled for 2 p.m.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>ATLANTA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A month-long, multi-state journey that began on the 20th anniversary of the assassination of the Rev. <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Luther </PERSON> <PERSON> King </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> was headed for the city of his birth today to close with a `` Jobs with Justice'' rally. Thousands of civil rights activists, church congregants and labor union members were expected to join the group of about 30 marchers at the afternoon rally at the <ORGANIZATION> Atlanta </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Civic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>, organizers said. The pilgrimage, organized by the <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Leadership </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conference </ORGANIZATION> founded by <PERSON> King </PERSON>, started in <LOCATION> Memphis </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Tenn. </LOCATION>, on April 5 _ one day after a memorial service there in memory of the slain civil rights leader. The Rev. <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Lowery </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> SCLC </ORGANIZATION>, said at the outset that he wanted to draw attention to the plight of the poor, which was a major concern of King's at the time of his death. `` We're trying to stir up the countryside,'' <PERSON> Lowery </PERSON> said. `` We're trying to bring people out to express their outrage about poverty.'' <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> Mayor <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> <PERSON> Young </PERSON>, who was a close aide to King, was scheduled to welcome the rally today. Among the scheduled speakers were <PERSON> Lowery </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> Commissioner of Agriculture <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Hightower </PERSON> and a representative of the <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Luther </PERSON> <PERSON> King </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>. Center for Nonviolent Social Change Folk singers <PERSON> Peter </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Paul </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> were expected to perform. King was fatally shot on a balcony of the <ORGANIZATION> Lorraine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Motel </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Memphis </LOCATION> on April 4, 1968. The pilgrimage, which started with about 30 marchers, has included marches and rallies in towns along the route through <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION> on the way to <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>, King's birthplace. Most of the trail has been covered in vans, with short marches at each destination.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880430-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-30-88 0330EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-AirportRankings     04-30 0198</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Airport Rankings,0203</SECOND>
<HEAD>Washington Ranks Top in Airport Study</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> National landed on top in a study of passenger convenience and amenities at the nation's 20 busiest airports, Money magazine said in its May issue. <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> got high marks for being easy to reach _ only four miles from downtown _ and for the nation's third best on-time record. Next are <ORGANIZATION> Phoenix </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sky </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Harbor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> and <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Logan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION>, both close to downtown and ranked high on amenities <ORGANIZATION> John </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> F. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Kennedy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Newark </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION>, both serving <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, rated last. Both are low on amenities and costly to reach from the city _ $ 22 or $ 28 by taxi, Money said. `` Airports have as much, if not more, to do with the quality of air travel as the airlines they serve,'' said Money, which studied federal flight-delay data and sent a team of reporters to airports. In separate listings, Money also picked the best and worst airports overall. They included: _ <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> National, best airport to fly to; <ORGANIZATION> Dallas-Fort </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Worth </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION>, the worst _ <LOCATION> Phoenix </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Sky </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Harbor </LOCATION>, best airport `` to get stuck at'' because of its amenities and `` distinct Southwest flavor''; <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>, the worst
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880430-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-30-88 0336EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lites     04-30 0644</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lites,0666</SECOND>
<HEAD>On The Light Side</HEAD>
<DATELINE>FREDONIA, N.Y. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 If you're crazy like a duck and do n't mind cigar smoke, harp music and horns there's only one place to be today _ <LOCATION> Fredonia </LOCATION>. That's <LOCATION> Fredonia </LOCATION> with one `` e'' as in this western <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> college town and not <LOCATION> Freedonia </LOCATION> with two `` E's'' as in the mythical kingdom of <LOCATION> Freedonia </LOCATION> that served as the setting for the <ORGANIZATION> Marx </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Brothers </ORGANIZATION>' 1933 movie `` Duck Soup.'' If that seems confusing, think how confused Mayor <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Hickey </PERSON> must have been in 1933 when he sent a letter to <ORGANIZATION> Paramount </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pictures </ORGANIZATION> complaining about the studio's `` intentions in using the name of our city in your picture'' and got back the following reply from the <ORGANIZATION> Marx </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Brothers </ORGANIZATION> themselves: `` Your excellency. Our advice is that you change the name of your town. It is hurting our picture. What makes you think you are mayor of <LOCATION> Fredonia </LOCATION>? Do you wear a black moustache, play the harp, speak with an Italian accent or chase girls like <PERSON> Harpo </PERSON>? We are certain you do not. Therefore, we must be the mayor of <LOCATION> Fredonia </LOCATION>, not you.'' <LOCATION> Fredonia </LOCATION> today celebrates the second annual `` <LOCATION> Freedonia </LOCATION> Marxonia Film Festival and Symposium.'' Several hundred people wearing <PERSON> Groucho </PERSON> glasses and noses are expected at <ORGANIZATION> Fredonia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> for a group picture in the afternoon. But that's not all. There will be a speech by <ORGANIZATION> Marx </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Brothers </ORGANIZATION> expert <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Wesolowski </PERSON> and a duck soup recipe competition. The local Post Office will cancel stamps with a mark that shows <PERSON> Groucho </PERSON>, <PERSON> Harpo </PERSON> and <PERSON> Chico </PERSON> and has the extra `` e'' in <LOCATION> Fredonia </LOCATION>. Postmaster <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Kaus </PERSON> says he's gotten about 150 requests for the cancellation, some from as far away as <LOCATION> Belgium </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>, and the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>DOTHAN, Ala. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Twelve-year-old <PERSON> Steven </PERSON> <PERSON> Young </PERSON> was just doodling with a pencil at his desk, but his teacher thought the drawings could be put to use. <PERSON> Steven </PERSON> wound up having lunch with a group of auto executives who said his classroom doodles showed promise for a dual-spring suspension system for heavy-duty vehicles. His seventh-grade teacher, <PERSON> Sandra </PERSON> <PERSON> Hefner </PERSON>, and <ORGANIZATION> Honeysuckle </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Middle </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> principal <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> <PERSON> Nichols </PERSON> turned to local engineers at <ORGANIZATION> Michelin </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tire </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> for guidance on the drawings. The company invited all three to lunch Thursday where they discussed the possible uses of the youngster's design. <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Conn </PERSON>, an engineer for <ORGANIZATION> Michelin </ORGANIZATION>, said the design probably is over-engineered for an ordinary passenger car, but it might enhance the performance of a heavy-duty vehicle or racing car needing extra strength. <PERSON> Steven </PERSON>'s father, <PERSON> Jeffery </PERSON> <PERSON> Young </PERSON>, is an engineer at <ORGANIZATION> Great </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Paper </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> and his mother, <PERSON> Kathy </PERSON> <PERSON> Young </PERSON>, is a kindergarten teacher. They said he's always wanted to know how things work.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>TULSA, Okla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Old planning boards do n't die _ or apparently fade away either. That's what members of the <ORGANIZATION> Regional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Solid </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Waste </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Planning </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> are discovering. Some members believe the board has served its purpose and should be disbanded. But officials say they ca n't get enough people together for a quorum to officially close up shop. `` I'm just tired of meeting here every few months to find out we ca n't do anything,'' said <PERSON> Roy </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>, board vice chairman. `` The board is well on its way to melting away. It should be terminated with the same dignity as it was formed.'' The board, with representatives from communities in the <LOCATION> Tulsa </LOCATION> area, was one member short of a quorum at its meeting Thursday. Only 16 of 60 board members attended the previous meeting in February. The board was formed in 1986 to investigate the area's solid waste situation and propose sites for landfills. `` This conceivably could go on forever, if enough member communities play the game of not attending meetings, but not resigning,'' said <PERSON> Marilyn </PERSON> <PERSON> Hinkle </PERSON>, board chairman. The board will try to meet again, probably in September, with disbanding on the agenda, she said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880430-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-30-88 0118EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Japan-Markets 1stLd-Writethru a0878 04-30 0195</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Japan-Markets, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0878,0197</SECOND>
<HEAD>Stock Prices Close At Record High</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: UPDATES thruout with closing figures. No pickup</NOTE>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Tokyo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Stock </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Exchange </ORGANIZATION>'s key index closed at a record high Saturday for the second consecutive trading day. The Nikkei Stock Average of 225 selected issues, which gained 242.15 points Thursday, added another 75.42 points, or 0.16 percent, to finish Saturday's half-day session at 27,509.54. `` The <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION> market has been in good, stable condition without any bad news to prompt selling,'' said a stock analyst for a major brokerage, who spoke on condition of anonymity. The Japanese yen's stability on foreign exchange markets also has helped boost stock prices, he said. Trading was a relatively quiet 450 million shares on the market's first section Saturday because of the holiday-studded `` Golden Week'' which started Friday, traders said. During Thursday's full-day session, 800 million shares were traded. Popular issues included electricals, machineries and chemicals. Foodstuffs, textiles and real estates also gained ground, while some drugs and banks declined. Most major Japanese financial institutions will be closed Wednesday through Friday because of holidays. The <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION> foreign exchange market normally is closed on Saturdays.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880430-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-30-88 0123EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-CondorEgg 3rdLd-Writethru a0892 04-30 0525</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Condor Egg, 3rd Ld - Writethru, a0892,0534</SECOND>
<HEAD>Condor Chick Hatches With Help From Its Keepers</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: INSERTS 5 grafs to UPDATE with comments from news conference.
Picks up 5th graf pvs, `A recording...' Edits to conform.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By DENNIS GEORGATOS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SAN DIEGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The first <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> condor conceived in captivity hatched Friday, its keepers using tweezers and their fingertips to help the newest member of the nearly extinct species break free from its shell, officials said. `` It's alive and it looks healthy,'' said <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Hanscom </PERSON>, a spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> San </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Diego </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wild </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Animal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Park </ORGANIZATION>. `` It's resting now. We do n't have any other details.'' The hatching represents a tremendous boost to efforts to save the species. It brings the known population of <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s largest land bird to 28, all in captivity _ 15 at the park here and 13 at the <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> Zoo The squawking infant, named <PERSON> Molloko </PERSON>, an Indian word for `` condor,'' was swaddled in a towel and placed in the same type of incubator used for premature infants. `` Early this morning there were 27 <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> condors left in the world,'' said <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Toone </PERSON>, curator of birds at the park. `` This afternoon there's 28 of them, and we could n't be more excited about that. `` When the numbers are so low, one bird is seen as a very big step away from extinction,'' <PERSON> Toone </PERSON> added. Although the tiny bird was not brought forth to `` meet the press,'' its history-making birth was recorded on videotape and shown at a press conference Friday night. Earlier, the chick had become stuck in dried membrane and albumen and could no longer rotate in the shell to peck its way out. Its keepers removed it cautiously because of the danger of rupturing blood vessels linked to egg membranes. A recording of vultures making hissing and grunting sounds was played at intervals to duplicate the sounds the chick would hear in a natural setting. Park officials had said they intended to intervene by Saturday if the chick, which began hatching Wednesday, had n't emerged from the shell. Allowing the hatching struggle to continue would overexhaust the bird. The chick, conceived by the only known activing breeding pair of the <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> condor, was expected to weigh about 9 ounces, <ORGANIZATION> Hanscom </ORGANIZATION> said. The species has a wingspan of up to 10 feet at maturity. The 10-ounce blue-green egg, about 5 inches long, had been under a 24-hour watch since Wednesday, when keepers noticed `` pip'' cracks in one end signaling the start of hatching, which can take three days. After the egg was laid March 3, it was taken away from the parent birds and incubated artificially in hopes that the female bird would produce a second egg. So far, this has not happened. It will be a while before the sex of the bird can be determined through a blood test, officials said. <ORGANIZATION> Hanscom </ORGANIZATION> said that representatives of the Chumash Indian tribe had been enlisted to select the name for the chick upon hatching. The tribe inhabited the <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Barbara </LOCATION> area that most recently served as <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> condor habitat, and the bird figures prominently in the tribe's religion.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880430-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-30-88 0405EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-People-Stark     04-30 0395</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-People-Stark,0406</SECOND>
<HEAD>Producer Ray Stark Gives Siskel and Ebert Two Thumbs Down</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Producer <PERSON> Ray </PERSON> <PERSON> Stark </PERSON>, stung by negative reviews of `` Biloxi Blues'' from televison movie critics <PERSON> Gene </PERSON> <PERSON> Siskel </PERSON> and <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> Ebert </PERSON>, has sent the two a letter calling them a `` critical version of Laurel and <PERSON> Hardy </PERSON>.'' `` Your thumb system is a clever bit of show business; I suggest you sit on them,'' <PERSON> Stark </PERSON> said, referring to the pair's trademark `` thumbs up'' or `` thumbs down'' method of evaluation. <PERSON> Siskel </PERSON> responded that someone perhaps had purloined Stark's stationery to write a rude note Stark, calling the two a `` critical version of Laurel and <PERSON> Hardy </PERSON>,'' said he will suggest to fellow producers that they refrain from offering early screenings to the pair. `` <LOCATION> Biloxi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Blues </LOCATION>,'' about an <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> recruit from <LOCATION> Brooklyn </LOCATION> who gets his basic training in the Deep South, is based on a play by <PERSON> Neil </PERSON> <PERSON> Simon </PERSON>, stars <PERSON> Matthew </PERSON> <PERSON> Broderick </PERSON> and was directed by <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Nichols </PERSON>. Stark is the head of <ORGANIZATION> Rastar </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Productions </ORGANIZATION>, which produced the film. In an April 20 letter to <PERSON> Siskel </PERSON> at the <ORGANIZATION> Chicago </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tribune </ORGANIZATION>, Stark recounts several positive reviews of `` Biloxi Blues'' that appeared in the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Time </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> magazine </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION>, and the <ORGANIZATION> Chicago </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tribune </ORGANIZATION>. But `` there on television was <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> Ebert </PERSON> saying ` I realized to my shock that his -LRB- <PERSON> Nichols </PERSON> -RRB- career has gone nowhere in recent years. ... What has happened to him as a director? ... He's just another one of the hacks brought in to direct another <PERSON> Neil </PERSON> <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> screenplay.' `` And there were you agreeing, ` I think the word hack is right. ... I was very shocked at how dull the film was,''' Stark wrote to <PERSON> Siskel </PERSON>. `` For such men of the world, the two of you shock very easily,'' said Stark in the three-page letter, listing a number of problems such as <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> tensions, AIDS, and homelessness. The letter was sent to the heads of several major studios. In a letter obtained by the <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Siskel </PERSON> replied to Stark and referred to an earlier, apparently friendlier, letter. `` I think you should know that someone using your name and good stationery has just violated the reasonable opinions of the earlier letter you sent me,'' <PERSON> Siskel </PERSON> wrote. `` I suggest that you have someone stand guard at your desk to make sure that no crackpot gets ahold of your letterhead.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880430-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-30-88 0403EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Strike-Scene     04-30 0387</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Strike-Scene,0402</SECOND>
<HEAD>Workers Determined To Win Higher Pay From Government They Don't
Trust</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Poland, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN DANISZEWSKI</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>KRAKOW, Poland (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Workers glared with icy determination at platoons of plainclothes police as they streamed out through the gates of the huge strike-bound <PERSON> Lenin </PERSON> steelworks during a shift change. Striding toward a bus stop, a few flashed the V-for-victory sign once out of sight of police. Their strike at the plant in the <LOCATION> Krakow </LOCATION> suburb of <LOCATION> Nowa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Huta </LOCATION> has shaken the government at the highest level. At the bus stop 100 yards from the gates, a knot of workers began to talk freely with foreign reporters. `` They have to give people what they deserve,'' A beefy man in a shiny tan jacket said of communist authorities. He punched the air angrily with his finger as he spoke: `` We are working. Prices are going up. We have no money.'' Others murmured agreement and nodded. It was Friday night and workers had occuped the plant for four days, demanding pay raises, the restoration of union rights and reinstatement of dismissed Solidarity activists. A worker on the edge of the group said he made $ 107 a month, half of which he must spend on the maintenance and mortgage on his home: `` We are working all the time, on Sundays too. And we can hardly live.'' Prices have gone up 42 percent so far this year as the result of government reforms aimed at making the economy more market-oriented. `` We do n't believe them anymore,'' a middle-aged man with a quiet manner said of authorities. `` They keep promising -LRB- that things will get better -RRB- and yet we ca n't earn in one day even enough for two kilos -LRB- 4 pounds -RRB- of herring. `` They share millions and we are near starvation.'' The workers have been inside the plant for 16 hours at a stretch during the strike, the nation's worst since martial law stifled the Solidarity independent labor federation 6 -LCB- yearss ago. Strikers spend their day at the plant sitting, talking, tinkering, but not working. They said some workers have not joined the stoppage and toil while their colleagues in a neighboring department sit idle. The strike committee says it represents half the plant's 32,000 workers, and from 12,000 to 14,000 workers are in the plant at any one time.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880430-0025 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-30-88 0403EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-ForestFireSpring Bjt   04-30 0647</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Forest Fire Spring, Bjt,0661</SECOND>
<HEAD>Spring Brings Blooms To Charred Ruins Of Forest</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JEFF BARNARD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>GRANTS PASS, Ore. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
