<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880712-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-12-88 2325EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Shultz 2ndLd-Writethru a0860 07-12 0506</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Shultz, 2nd Ld-Writethru, a0860,0518</SECOND>
<HEAD>Secretary of State Sees Breakthrough in Bases Impasse</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Two grafs SUB for grafs 6-7 pvs, He left ... UPDATING with
Shultz arriving in Hong Kong. PICKS up 8th graf pvs, House speaker
...</NOTE>
<BYLINE>BY DENIS D. GRAY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MANILA, Philippines (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Secretary of State <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> indicated Tuesday that he and Philippine leaders have scored a breakthrough in stalled talks on the future of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military bases in the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION>. President <PERSON> Corazon </PERSON> <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON> said after Tuesday's discussions, `` We both hope that the talks would be over by the end of this month.'' <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> told a news conference, `` I'm more than ever convinced that there is a very strong mutuality of interest in the security field and all the reason in the world that somehow we'll be able to work out a continuing partnership.'' A review of the 41-year-old bases agreement, which expires in 1991, has been marked by calls from some people for more compensation from the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and by demonstrations against the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military presence. The review began in April and stalled over the issue of how much <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> should pay each year for the <ORGANIZATION> Subic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bay </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Naval </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Base </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Clark </PERSON> <PERSON> Air </PERSON> <PERSON> Base </PERSON> and four smaller military installations. <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON>, on a 36-hour visit to <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION>, met with Mrs. <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON>, Foreign Secretary <PERSON> Raul </PERSON> <PERSON> Manglapus </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Fidel </PERSON> <PERSON> V. </PERSON> <PERSON> Ramos </PERSON> and prominent legislators. He later left for <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION>, arriving there Wednesday for a one-day stay. <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> was the fifth stop on the secretary's nine-nation Asian and Pacific tour He earlier visited <LOCATION> Thailand </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Malaysia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Indonesia </LOCATION> and will proceed after <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Marshall </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Islands </LOCATION>. Both the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and Filipino sides refused to discuss details of the compensation proposals. House speaker <PERSON> Ramon </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitra </PERSON> told reporters, `` If the Philippine -LRB- side -RRB- gets favorable conditions, I presume this is going to register very well among members of the house.'' <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> sources, speaking on condition of anonymity, said a reasonable compromise on the bases could mean increased support by <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> of <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION>'s war against the 19-year-old communist insurgency. Under the present accord, the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> gives <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION> $ 180 million a year in economic and military aid. The bases are the largest <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military facilities outside the continental <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Manglapus </PERSON> said last April that $ 1.2 billion a year was a more `` realistic figure.'' <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> said the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military had worked out options in case the bases were ousted, but the best choice was to stay in the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION>. He said the two sides had `` perhaps identified some methods that might work'' in reaching a compromise. <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> also said the <LOCATION> Philippine </LOCATION> military had improved in the past two years. `` There is a far greater degree of professionalism, they are better equipped ... there is a clear mission and a record increasingly of success,'' he said. <PERSON> Ramos </PERSON> said <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> promised to expedite the delivery of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military equipment to the <LOCATION> Philippine </LOCATION> military. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> this year provided more than $ 85 million in military help.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880712-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-12-88 2329EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Taiwan-China     07-12 0399</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Taiwan-China,0413</SECOND>
<HEAD>Taiwan Eases Ban on Travel From China</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ANNIE HUANG</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>TAIPEI, Taiwan (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The governing <ORGANIZATION> Nationalist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> on Tuesday eased a 39-year-old ban on visits to <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION> by mainland <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> residents and approved expanding indirect trade with <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> to include raw materials. The new policy toward rival Communist <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> approved by the 13th <ORGANIZATION> Nationalist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> congress </ORGANIZATION> after several days of debate also suggested <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION> journalists and athletes may be allowed to go the mainland. Under the new policy, the <ORGANIZATION> Nationalist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, or Kuomintang, will review requests from mainland Chinese to travel to <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION> if close relatives are gravely ill or die. Intellectuals from mainland <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> `` who are opposed to Marxism-Leninism or have fought to maintain academic freedom'' will be allowed to come to <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION> if invited. Further relaxation will depend on `` whether and how the mainland responds to our new policy,'' <PERSON> Hsiao </PERSON> <PERSON> Chang-le </PERSON>, head of the <ORGANIZATION> Nationalists </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ' </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mainland </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Operations </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, told a news conference. Last October, the Nationalists ended a longstanding ban on travel to <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> so <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION> residents could visit relatives for family reunions. More than 100,000 have made the trip since. The ban on travel across the <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Straits </LOCATION> was imposed when the Nationalists fled to this island in 1949 after losing a civil war to the Communists on the Chinese mainland. The Nationalists government still claims to be the rightful ruler of all <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> and refuses all official contact with <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Hsiao </PERSON> said that also under the new policy, mainland Chinese students studying in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> or <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> can apply to visit <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION> through an unidentified private organization beginning in August or September. He said <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION> athletes may be allowed to compete on mainland <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> in events sponsored by private organizations and said the island's Olympic committee would study the possibility of sending a team to <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> for the 1990 Asian Games. The party statement also indicated reporters may soon be allowed to travel to the mainland for news-gathering, but did not propose relax other travel restrictions opposed by many Taiwanese. Although no direct trade links exist between <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, the Nationalists tolerate a flourishing trade through third countries that could reach a record $ 2 billion this year. <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION> government officials last year announced 29 items could be imported from <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> indirectly but the list did not include raw materials and agricultural products now to be tolerated.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880712-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-12-88 2332EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p AM-Price'sSeat 1stLd-Writethru a0878 07-12 0337</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Price's Seat, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0878,0340</SECOND>
<HEAD>Costello Wins Special Primary</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Leads with 4 grafs to UPDATE with Costello winning. Picks up
4th graf pvs `The five-county...'</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By PAUL DE LA GARZA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BELLEVILLE, Ill. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Democratic candidate in a southern <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> congressional race in November won a special primary Tuesday allowing him to also run to serve out the current term of the late <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Rep. <PERSON> Melvin </PERSON> <PERSON> Price </PERSON>. <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Costello </PERSON>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Clair </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION>, easily defeated <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Louis </LOCATION> <PERSON> Alderman </PERSON> <PERSON> Clarence </PERSON> <PERSON> Ellis </PERSON> <PERSON> Sr. </PERSON> in the the 21st Congressional District's Democratic primary. With 429 of the 469 precincts, or 91.5 percent, reporting, unofficial returns showed Costello with 17,040 votes to <PERSON> Ellis </PERSON>' 1,930 Republican <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> `` </PERSON> <PERSON> Bob </PERSON><PERSON> '' </PERSON> <PERSON> Gaffner </PERSON>, of <LOCATION> Greenville </LOCATION>, who had no opposition in the special primary, had 3,671 votes. The five-county district has 270,060 registered voters, but morning thundershowers, summer distractions and a lack of interest in the election held down turnout, officials said. The primary winners will face off Aug. 9 in a special general election. The winner of that contest will finish the term of Price, a Democrat from <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Louis </LOCATION>, who died April 22 of pancreatic cancer. Price, who was 83, had already announced he would not seek re-election after serving 44 years in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. In March, Costello and <PERSON> Gaffner </PERSON> won their respective primaries for the right to run in the November election. After Price's death, <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> law mandated a special election to fill the office for the remainder of the term that ends in January. The special election offers its winner a possible advantage in November and, if elected then, seniority over 30 to 40 incoming freshmen House members in January. During the current campaign, <PERSON> Ellis </PERSON> stressed his political experience and education. He has served 13 years on the <ORGANIZATION> Aldermanic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> and has masters' degrees in public administration and education administration. The Costello camp promised to work for economic development, for protection of the Social Security system and against drugs.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880712-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-12-88 2350EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Korea     07-12 0375</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Korea,0386</SECOND>
<HEAD>South Korea Proposes Resumption Of Family-Reunion Program</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PAUL SHIN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SEOUL, South Korea (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> called on communist <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> Wednesday to resume humanitarian programs to promote reunions between some 10 million people separated from their families on this divided peninsula. <PERSON> Kim </PERSON> <PERSON> Sang-hyup </PERSON>, president of <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION>, made the proposal in a telephone message to his North Korean counterpart <PERSON> Son </PERSON> <PERSON> Sung </PERSON> <PERSON> Pil </PERSON>. `` In view of the ardent aspirations of separated family members, it is our imperative task to find out the whereabouts of their dispersed family members and relatives and help them to meet freely,'' <PERSON> Kim </PERSON> said in the message. <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> was divided into the Soviet-backed north and U.S.-supported south at the end of World War II. It is estimated that at least 10 million people were separated from their relatives by the division and during the Korean War in 1950-53. In his message, <PERSON> Kim </PERSON> proposed the two Koreas resume by the end of the year a family-reunion program suspended since 1986. His appeal followed a statement Thursday by President <PERSON> Roh </PERSON> <PERSON> Tae-woo </PERSON> who called for improved relations with <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>, including broad exchanges of visits between people of the two countries. <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> dismissed <PERSON> Roh </PERSON>'s gestures as `` nothing new'' and renewed its own demand for holding a `` national conference'' to discuss, among other things, co-hosting of this summer's Olympic Games in <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION> and the withdrawal of 42,000 <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military personnel from <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>. Under the North Korean plan, the conference would be attended by about 50 government officials as well as social, political and cultural leaders from each side. <PERSON> Kim </PERSON> specifically proposed that the <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION> societies of the two Koreas serve as an intermediary to help elderly people contact each other. His office said the program could be extended to include some one million overseas Koreans who want to locate relatives in the two Koreas through the Geneva-based <ORGANIZATION> Interantional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION>. In 1985, for the first time in 40 years, the two governments agreed to an exchange involving 151 people. The agreement also included visits by cultural groups and 51 journalists. <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> withdrew from the <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION> contacts and economic and parliamentary talks in 1986 to protest joint <LOCATION> U.S.-South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> military exercises.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880712-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-12-88 2353EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-MostlyMozart     07-12 0461</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Mostly Mozart,0469</SECOND>
<HEAD>22nd Season Opens With Gala Concert</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MIKE SILVERMAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Mostly <PERSON> Mozart </PERSON> was Mostly Marvelous. The 22nd season of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>'s alliterative summer musical festival opened Tuesday night with a gala concert featuring not one, but two, superstar soloists _ American mezzo-soprano <PERSON> Frederica </PERSON> <PERSON> von </PERSON> <PERSON> Stade </PERSON> and Soviet emigre pianist <PERSON> Vladimir </PERSON> <PERSON> Feltsman </PERSON>. Both made strong impressions. Miss <PERSON> von </PERSON> <PERSON> Stade </PERSON> sang `` Parto, parto,'' an aria from <PERSON> Mozart </PERSON>'s last opera, `` La Clemenza di Tito'' and both of <PERSON> Cherubino </PERSON>'s arias from `` Le Nozze di <PERSON> Figaro </PERSON>.'' She sounded at ease in all three, her tone aristocratic, yet free and unaffected. Her technique was flawless in the difficult runs of the first selection, with only a hint of strain in the highest part of her register. <PERSON> Cherubino </PERSON> is perhaps <PERSON> Miss </PERSON> <PERSON> von </PERSON> <PERSON> Stade </PERSON>'s most famous role on stage and she demonstrated why, communicating the restless energy of a lovesick young boy with simple directness. <PERSON> Feltsman </PERSON>, who arrived in this country just last year, provided an elegant performance of <PERSON> Mozart </PERSON>'s last piano concerto, No. 27 in B-flat major. This work, written less than a year before the composer died, strikes a mood of serenity and triumph with little of the turmoil and tragedy that mark the concertos preceding it. <PERSON> Feltsman </PERSON> played with grace and clarity. Ironically, the least satisfying selection of the night was a collaboration between the two _ the concert aria for soprano, piano and orchestra `` Ch ` io mi scordi di te which <PERSON> Mozart </PERSON> wrote for an 18-year-old English singer with whom he had fallen in love. What sets this difficult aria apart is the intricate interplay between the female voice and the piano, each seeming to address the other in long, loving phrases. Miss <PERSON> von </PERSON> <PERSON> Stade </PERSON> and <PERSON> Feltsman </PERSON> missed the emotional spark and too often seemed to be going through their paces rather than communicating. The opening program _ which is being repeated tonight and televised live on the <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Broadcasting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> _ was true to the title: mostly <PERSON> Mozart </PERSON>, but with a little something else thrown in. Conductor <PERSON> Gerard </PERSON> <PERSON> Schwartz </PERSON> led a spirited performance of <PERSON> Haydn </PERSON>'s grand and humorous Symphony No 100, known as the `` Military'' symphony. The concert opened with the overture to <PERSON> Mozart </PERSON>'s opera `` Die Entfuhrung aus dem Serail.'' It all went to show once again that <PERSON> Mozart </PERSON>, who died in poverty in <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION> at the age of 35, left behind a unique and inexhaustible supply of musical riches. What other composer could serve as the mainstay of a music festival that puts on concerts for seven weeks year after year? Highlights of the current season, performed in <ORGANIZATION> Lincoln </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>'s <PERSON> Avery </PERSON> <PERSON> Fisher </PERSON> <PERSON> Hall </PERSON>, include <PERSON> Mozart </PERSON>'s rarely heard early opera `` <PERSON> Lucia </PERSON> <PERSON> Silla </PERSON>,'' <PERSON> Haydn </PERSON>'s `` Lord Nelson'' Mass, and a chamber concert devoted entirely to <PERSON> Schubert </PERSON>
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880712-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-12-88 0004EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p AM-Dukakis 6thLd-Writethru a0781 07-12 0739</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Dukakis, 6th Ld-Writethru, a0781,650</SECOND>
<HEAD>Veep Decision Nears; Jackson Says He Wants The Job</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: INSERTS new grafs 6-8 to UPDATE with Brountas comments after
meeting with Dukakis</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By JOHN KING</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BOSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Democratic presidential nominee-to-be <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> pondered possible running mates on Monday, with <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> pressing more strongly than ever for a spot on the ticket. Signs pointed to an announcement within a few days. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> and his top adviser, <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Brountas </PERSON>, met at <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' house Monday morning <PERSON> Brountas </PERSON> then traveled to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> to meet with <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, who said for the first time Monday that he would take <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> up on an offer to join the ticket. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> told reporters after his meeting with <PERSON> Brountas </PERSON> that `` it is self-evident'' that he wants the job, and said he assured <PERSON> Brountas </PERSON> he would be a loyal vice president. `` If it was offered to me, I would accept it,'' <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> said. He has said repeatedly he deserves an offer of the No. 2 spot, but up until Monday, he had declined to say publicly what his answer would be if that offer were extended. <PERSON> Brountas </PERSON> said the two had an `` excellent meeting ... very productive'' but declined to provide any details of the discussion. Afterward, he flew back to <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> for a late-night meeting with <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>. After a 45-minute session at <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' home, with campaign manager <PERSON> Susan </PERSON> <PERSON> Estrich </PERSON> in attendance, <PERSON> Brountas </PERSON> was asked if a decision had been made. `` No comment,'' he said. Asked if the selection process was over, <PERSON> Brountas </PERSON> responded: `` He -LRB- <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> -RRB- can always ask more questions if he wants.'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> is expected to announce his choice this week before heading to the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Convention </ORGANIZATION>, which opens next Monday. Some aides said an announcement could come as soon at Tuesday, but others said there was still no timetable. Although the <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> governor faces a budget crisis at home that threatens to hurt his national candidacy, he arrived at the Statehouse late because of the <LOCATION> Brountas </LOCATION> meeting. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> had planned to leave within three hours but ended up staying for nearly seven _ still a few hours shorter than his usual workday. `` Have a good evening,'' was all <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> would say to reporters as he left for home after a meeting with three top campaign aides, including campaign manager <PERSON> Susan </PERSON> <PERSON> Estrich </PERSON>. Several campaign aides said privately that the time at home was to be spent working to pick a running mate. `` He has n't made up his mind yet,'' said one <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> aide. `` Or if he has, he has n't told anybody.'' <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> had been scheduled to meet with <PERSON> Brountas </PERSON> last Friday, but the meeting was postponed with <PERSON> Brountas </PERSON> saying he needed more time to `` receive and review'' information from the <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> campaign. The <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> campaign had requested detailed personal, financial and medical information from <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> and other prospects. The civil rights leader has said he is the most qualified to share the ticket with <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> and has called the others known to be under consideration `` unknown quantities.'' They include Sens. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Graham </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> and Reps. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Hamilton </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> aides have been aggravated by <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s aggressive effort to portray himself as the logical running mate and by an apparent effort by <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> campaign manager <PERSON> Gerald </PERSON> <PERSON> Austin </PERSON> to discourage the selection of <PERSON> Gore </PERSON>. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> said <PERSON> Austin </PERSON>'s comments were unathorized. During a weekend campaign swing through several Western states, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> responded tersely when asked if <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> would have veto power over his decision. He said the decision was his alone to make. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> is to travel Tuesday night to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, where he is scheduled to hold a series of Capitol Hill meetings on Wednesday and also address the annual convention of the <ORGANIZATION> NAACP </ORGANIZATION>. When he arrives back in <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> on Wednesday night, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> will have two work days left to make good on his promise to resolve the state's budget problems by the end of the week. On his desk is an $ 11.75 billion spending plan for fiscal 1989, which began July 1. Legislative leaders have urged <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> to use his line-item veto power to reduce that spending plan. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> also is awaiting legislative passage of a politically sensitive plan to eliminate the $ 370 million deficit remaining from fiscal 1988. The governor is scheduled to take Saturday off and fly to <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> for the convention on Sunday.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880712-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-12-88 2345EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-Newspage-All-Stars     07-12 0167</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Newspage-All-Stars,0172</SECOND>
<HEAD>AL 2, NL 1</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CINCINNATI (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> League </ORGANIZATION> beat the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> League </ORGANIZATION> 2-1 in another pitcher-dominated All-Star Game Tuesday night, winning the matchup for only the fourth time in 26 games. American League pitchers held the <ORGANIZATION> NL </ORGANIZATION> stars to six hits. The NL still leads the series 37-21, with three of those losses coming under Manager <PERSON> Whitey </PERSON> <PERSON> Herzog </PERSON>. He became the only <ORGANIZATION> NL </ORGANIZATION> manager to lose three times. <ORGANIZATION> Oakland </ORGANIZATION>'s <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> <PERSON> Steinbach </PERSON>, who has only a .217 batting average, homered in the third inning off <PERSON> Dwight </PERSON> <PERSON> Gooden </PERSON> and hit a bases-loaded sacrifice fly to the warning track in the fourth against <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Knepper </PERSON>. <PERSON> Steinbach </PERSON>, one of 30 first-time All-Stars, was named the game's most valuable player. AL pitcher <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Viola </PERSON> set down the only six hitters he faced for the victory and <PERSON> Dennis </PERSON> <PERSON> Eckersley </PERSON>, leading the majors with 26 saves, got the final three batters. A crowd of 55,837 watched the game, including Vice President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, who threw out the first ball.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880712-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-12-88 2357EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--China-Euthanasia     07-12 0145</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--China-Euthanasia,0150</SECOND>
<HEAD>Report Says Mercy Killing Is Common In Hospitals</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Mercy killing is common in many Chinese hospitals, an official report said today. The <ORGANIZATION> China </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> said that one <LOCATION> Shanghai </LOCATION> hospital reported 28 percent of the 563 deaths in its medical, surgical and gynecology departments in the past three years were the result of euthanasia. Incurably ill patients were allowed to die at the request of relatives who wanted to end the patients' suffering, it said. The report said most cases of euthanasia in Chinese hospitals were `` passive,'' meaning the withholding of life-preserving treatment to terminally ill patients. Mercy killing is not a sanctioned medical practice in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, but recent polls have shown substantial popular acceptance. The People's Daily reported last April that a survey of 283 retired people in <LOCATION> Shanghai </LOCATION> found more than half favored euthanasia for incurably ill patients.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880712-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-12-88 2357EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--PamplonaBulls     07-12 0165</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Pamplona Bulls,0170</SECOND>
<HEAD>25 Injured In Running Of The Bulls</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PAMPLONA, Spain (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Six youths were gored seriously and at least 19 others suffered minor injuries in the seventh and most dangerous running of the bulls at the San Fermin Festival. The six bulls and a group of lead steers ran the half-mile stretch from the corrals to the bull ring in less than eight minutes Tuesday, with more than 1,000 youths running ahead. The running took a dangerous turn when one bull stopped and began attacking several youths who had taken refuge in doorways and against the wooden planks lining the route. Every afternoon, the bulls are killed in professional bullfights. The festival began last Wednesday and is to continue through Thursday. Held continously since 1591, the festival gained fame when <PERSON> Ernest </PERSON> <PERSON> Hemingway </PERSON> used it as a setting for his 1926 novel, `` The Sun Also Rises.'' Since 1591, bulls have gored 52 people to death, 12 since 1924, according to official records.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880712-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-12-88 2352EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-NelsonMandela Bjt   07-12 0799</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nelson Mandela, Bjt,0820</SECOND>
<HEAD>Black Leader Turns 70, Gaining Stature During Years in Jail</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID CRARY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>JOHANNESBURG, South Africa (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Rock' n' roll stars perform in his honor. Archbishop <PERSON> Desmond </PERSON> <PERSON> Tutu </PERSON> calls him `` my leader.'' Publishing his picture is illegal in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>, but even toddlers chant his name. <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON> <PERSON> Mandela </PERSON>, who turns 70 on Monday, is arguably the world's most influential prisoner Although jailed since 1962, he is the most admired leader among South African blacks, the embodiment of their quest for political freedom. His birthday, celebrated by protest marches and rock concerts overseas, has reminded the government of the legions of people worldwide who want him released. Blacks spanning <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>'s ideological spectrum, as well as many whites, say no political breakthrough can occur while <PERSON> Mandela </PERSON> is behind bars `` Nothing the South African government can do will gain credibility while it treats Dr. <PERSON> Mandela </PERSON> as a dangerous enemy,'' Zulu leader <PERSON> Mangosuthu </PERSON> <PERSON> Buthelezi </PERSON> said in a recent speech. `` Black <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> will not rest until he is free.'' <PERSON> Buthelezi </PERSON> is a bitter foe of the <ORGANIZATION> African </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, the outlawed guerrilla movement <PERSON> Mandela </PERSON> led from underground prior to his imprisonment. But <PERSON> Buthelezi </PERSON>, like other blacks who oppose the <ORGANIZATION> ANC </ORGANIZATION>'s strategy of violence, sets <PERSON> Mandela </PERSON> apart and discusses him with deep respect. President P.W. <PERSON> Botha </PERSON>'s government has considered the idea of freeing <PERSON> Mandela </PERSON>, and several times in recent years there were flurries of speculation that his freedom was imminent. One such period came last November when authorities freed <PERSON> Govan </PERSON> <PERSON> Mbeki </PERSON>, one of seven <ORGANIZATION> ANC </ORGANIZATION> leaders sentenced along with <PERSON> Mandela </PERSON> to life prison terms in 1964 for plotting a sabotage campaign aimed at overthrowing white-minority rule. The speculation was swiftly dampened when police imposed severe restrictions on <PERSON> Mbeki </PERSON>. Since then, government officials have indicated <PERSON> Mandela </PERSON>'s release is unlikely unless he publicly renounces violence _ a condition he rejects unless the <ORGANIZATION> ANC </ORGANIZATION> is made legal and apartheid dismantled. When convicted for sabotage, <PERSON> Mandela </PERSON> already had served two years in prison, having received a five-year sentence in 1962 for incitement and leaving the country illegally. He spent the first 18 years of his life sentence on <LOCATION> Robben </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Cape </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Town </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Table </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION>. He was transferred in 1982 to <LOCATION> Pollsmoor </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Prison </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Cape </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Town </LOCATION>, where he is reported in good physical and mental health. <PERSON> Mandela </PERSON> reads uncensored newspapers and is expected to earn an advanced law degree later this year through correspondence courses. He was a practicing lawyer before he went underground and has been awarded honorary doctorates from various universities during his imprisonment. He reportedly has a spacious cell with access to a rooftop garden. The government has given permission to <PERSON> Mandela </PERSON>'s family to have a six-hour reunion with him Monday at <LOCATION> Pollsmoor </LOCATION>, by far the longest such meeting since he was jailed. <PERSON> Mandela </PERSON>'s wife, <PERSON> Winnie </PERSON>, has asked that the birthday be observed `` as a day of peace, in line with the peaceful struggle we have always tried to maintain.'' She has not commented publicly about the recent series of bombings of civilian targets in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> _ attacks South African police officials blame on the <ORGANIZATION> ANC </ORGANIZATION>. Dr. <PERSON> Nthato </PERSON> <PERSON> Motlana </PERSON>, an anti-apartheid activist from <LOCATION> Soweto </LOCATION> and an <ORGANIZATION> ANC </ORGANIZATION> member before it was outlawed in 1960, said <PERSON> Mandela </PERSON> seeks to avoid civilian casualties. He resorted to a strategy of sabotage in 1961 `` because all other avenues were exhausted,'' <PERSON> Motlana </PERSON> said. `` He is the one man who, assuming he is willing, could lead us out of this mess.'' <PERSON> Buthelezi </PERSON> also views <PERSON> Mandela </PERSON> as a potential peacemaker, as perhaps the only person capable of ending a bloody power struggle in <LOCATION> Natal </LOCATION> province between militant <ORGANIZATION> ANC </ORGANIZATION> supporters and more conservative blacks who follow <PERSON> Buthelezi </PERSON>. `` I believe he -LRB- <PERSON> Mandela </PERSON> -RRB- would come out of jail to thump anybody ... who set black brother against black brother on the eve of a final victory over apartheid,'' <PERSON> Buthelezi </PERSON> said. Some South Africans believe <PERSON> Mandela </PERSON> causes more trouble for the government in jail than he would if freed. Some warn of a violent black backlash if he dies in prison. The largest daily newspaper, The Star, recently urged <PERSON> Mandela </PERSON>'s release on pragmatic grounds It said in an editorial: `` Should <PERSON> Mandela </PERSON> die in prison, he will be accorded universal political canonization and <LOCATION> Pretoria </LOCATION> will attract even more censure. Once he is free, the Mandela myth would be cut down to size'' The world hears from <PERSON> Mandela </PERSON> himself primarily through past statements which relatives and colleagues continue to quote. In one such statement in 1985, he rejected <PERSON> Botha </PERSON>'s offer of conditional release. `` I can not and will not give any undertaking at a time when I and you the people are not free,'' he said in a statement read by his youngest daughter, <PERSON> Zinzi </PERSON>. `` Your freedom and mine can not be separated. I shall return.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880712-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-12-88 0020EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p AM-PoliticalRdp 4thLd-Writethru a0728 07-12 1044</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Political Rdp, 4th Ld-Writethru, a0728,990</SECOND>
<HEAD>Jackson Says He Wants Veep Slot</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDs: Combines a0728-729; SUBS graf 14 pvs, bgng: The governor, to
UPDATE with Brountas holding late-night meeting with Dukakis</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By DAVID ESPO</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Political Writer</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> huddled at home with his closest adviser Monday as time grew short to pick a <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> vice presidential running mate. <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> openly sought the nomination widely expected to go elsewhere, saying `` If it was offered to me I would accept it.'' Vice President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said he might consider <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> or another former Republican rival as his partner when he picks a running mate next month. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> met with <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Brountas </PERSON> and then sent his longtime confidant to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> to meet with <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, runner-up in the primaries and widely regarded as unlikely to receive an offer to join the ticket. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, one of seven known candidates for the vice presidential nomination, termed the session `` an oral interview and @ or exam'' on the topic. He said he gave <PERSON> Brountas </PERSON> his `` candid view as to the office of vice president ... and what I thought my qualifications might be.'' He said it was `` self-evident'' he would like to be vice president. But more likely candidates were Sens. <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Graham </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>; <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>; <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> and Reps. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Hamilton </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION>. The increasingly delicate maneuvering came as a <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News-New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> poll found the <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> governor holding a 47 percent to 39 percent lead over <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> in a nationwide survey conducted last week. Democratic chairman <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Kirk </PERSON> preached the gospel of party unity at a news conference in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> one week before the party nominating convention opens. He said any disagreements over the party's bare-bones platform `` are gradually being worked out'' between the <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> forces. `` I do n't expect there will be any so-called floor fights over the platform,'' he said. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> adviser <PERSON> Ron </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> was n't ready to go that far, although he said the two sides are continuing to negotiate in an attempt to work out remaining differences. `` There might be some very serious issues of principle that go to the floor of the convention,'' he said in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> supports calls for higher taxes on the wealthy and a five-year freeze in military spending; <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> opposes both. The convention hall itself was a hardhat zone. The television network skyboxes were in place, but painters, carpenters and electricians all worked to ready the <LOCATION> Omni </LOCATION> for the invasion of Democrats, reporters and political junkies that will fill every available inch of space. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> stayed mum on the subject on every Democrat's mind _ his choice of a political partner for the fall campaign. `` Have a good evening,'' was all he said to reporters as he left his statehouse office at the end of the day. But the signs pointed to a decision soon, and the calendar dictated one. An announcement was expected this week, at least in part to allow <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> supporters time to absorb the decision before their arrival in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>. The governor spent part of the day at his statehouse office working on a <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> budget crunch, and the balance of the day at home. His aides said <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> was mulling his choices. He met during the morning with <PERSON> Brountas </PERSON>, and the two had a second, late-night session after <PERSON> Brountas </PERSON> returned from <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. Afterward, <PERSON> Brountas </PERSON> refused to say whether a running mate had been picked. `` He has n't made up his mind yet,'' said one <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> aide, speaking on condition he not be identified by name. `` Or if he has, he has n't told anybody.'' <PERSON> Brountas </PERSON> flew to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> to meet with <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, regarded as too liberal and too controversial to get <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' nod. He joked about the subject at one point, saying, `` So far, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> has not accepted my offer and I have not refused his.'' But later, <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> turned serious. `` If I am not on the team, then the governor must determine who the team members are and what role they will play,'' <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> said before the session began. He added, `` Certainly I am convinced that we have the challenge and the obligation to work together to win for the fall. But beyond that we must establish a partnership of equity and shared responsibility.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> took a jab at <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> in a speech to farm editors and broadcasters that he billed as non-partisan. `` I am not the one who feels that the problems of agricultural <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> can be solved by planting more Belgian endive,'' he said, poking fun at an off-hand comment <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> made in <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> last year. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, who is waiting for <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> to pick a running mate before he does, offered praise of one-time primary foe <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> and said he does n't rule out any of the men who ran against him for the Republican nomination. `` The fact that you ran against somebody certainly in my view would not preclude consideration of that person,'' the vice president told a meeting of agricultural editors, writers and broadcasters in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. `` I will say this about <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> _ he and I went head on head. So did <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> and <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> Haig </PERSON> and <PERSON> Pete </PERSON> <PERSON> du </PERSON> <PERSON> Pont </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON>. ... My party has never been more unified going into a Republican convention than we are right now, thanks to the way <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> and the others have been conducting themselves and their sense of advocacy.'' The vice president said he would solicit advice from a variety of <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> lawmakers and <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> members, and then `` make a very personal decision.'' But, he said, `` I just do n't want to start going through long lists or short lists because believe me, at this juncture, we do n't have them. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' eight-point lead in the <ORGANIZATION> CBS-New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> poll represented a small drop from a 10-point edge in a similar survey in May. In addition, 28 percent of those polled expressed a favorable view of <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, down from 38 percent in May. Twenty-one percent expressed an unfavorable view, up from 14 percent. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s favorable rating was 26 percent, down from 33 percent, and his unfavorable rating was 31 percent, about the same as its 35 percent in May.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880712-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-12-88 0047EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-InsiderTrading     07-12 0567</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Insider Trading,570</SECOND>
<HEAD>Giuliani Urges More Liability For Brokerage Firms</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVE SKIDMORE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 One of the best ways to get brokerage firms to combat insider trading is to make them pay when one of their employees gets caught, says the top federal prosecutor of securities law violations. `` It's the only way we're going to get institutions to start taking responsibility for individual behavior,'' <PERSON> Rudolph </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Giuliani </PERSON>, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> attorney in <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION>, told a <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> panel on Monday. However, <PERSON> Giuliani </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> Securities </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Exchange </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Ruder </PERSON> both cautioned that the law should exempt firms and supervisors that make a good-faith effort to stop their employees from using non-public information to profit from trading in securities. `` All of us are certainly sensitive to the fact that whenever anyone runs any institution, large or small, they can be victimized by the criminal activities of others,'' said <PERSON> Giuliani </PERSON>, whose office has prosecuted a string of prominent Wall Street insider trading cases during the last two years. Meanwhile, <PERSON> Ruder </PERSON> said his agency is investigating the role of the firm that employed <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> Wang </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, accused two weeks ago in the second-biggest insider trading case ever handled by the <ORGANIZATION> SEC </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Wang </PERSON>, a 24-year-old <ORGANIZATION> Morgan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Stanley </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ; </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> analyst, is accused of passing non-public information to <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Lee </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> businessman. The $ 19 million in illegal profits they allegedly reaped is second only to the <PERSON> Ivan </PERSON> <PERSON> Boesky </PERSON> case. `` We will be looking ... at whether <ORGANIZATION> Morgan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Stanley </ORGANIZATION>'s supervisory procedures were adequate and whether <PERSON> Morgan </PERSON> <PERSON> Stanley </PERSON> bears any fault,'' <PERSON> Ruder </PERSON> told reporters outside the hearing room. `` If they were directly responsible for the activity ... we might consider including them as one of the parties to the action, but I do n't mean for a minute to suggest that we have any indication of that at all,'' he said. <PERSON> Ruder </PERSON> and <PERSON> Giuliani </PERSON> said a draft bill offered by Rep. <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Markey </PERSON>, D-Mass., chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> finance subcommittee, should more carefully spell out when brokerage firms would be subject to fines for the violations of their employees <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bachmann </PERSON>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Securities </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Industry </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, the trade group representing brokerages, said firms and supervisors should be required to have policies designed to prevent insider trading. But he said they should be held liable only when they actively aided a violation. <PERSON> Bachmann </PERSON> also sought to limit a provision that would allow the <ORGANIZATION> SEC </ORGANIZATION> to pay bounties of up to 10 percent of any insider-trading penalty to informers who tip the agency off to a violation. He said participants in an insider trading scheme should not be allowed to receive bounties. <PERSON> Ruder </PERSON> also expressed reservations, saying juries may not believe witnesses who are paid to testify. However, <PERSON> Giuliani </PERSON> said the <ORGANIZATION> Internal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Revenue </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> has used bounties effectively to prosecute tax cheats. Although tipsters are sometimes peripherally involved in illegalities, it is worth paying a reward when it results in a windfall for federal coffers, he said. `` It's the only way in which you are going to bring this information forward,'' he said. <PERSON> Markey </PERSON> said he intends to pass the bill out of his subcommittee in time for congressional action this year. Other provisions increase the fines for insider trading, create a basis for private investors to sue inside traders and enhance the <ORGANIZATION> SEC </ORGANIZATION>'s power to cooperate in investigations with foreign securities agencies.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880712-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-12-88 0057EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Convention-Windfall Bjt   07-12 0697</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Convention-Windfall, Bjt,700</SECOND>
<HEAD>Price Hikes Commonplace As Democrats Converge On Atlanta</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOSEPH B. FRAZIER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ATLANTA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 With hot water going for nearly $ 27 a gallon and potted plants renting for $ 79.50, there is money to be made at next week's Democratic National Convention. The days when delegates pulled into town with a $ 10 bill and a clean shirt and left without changing either are history. The 35,000 visitors for the July 18-21 event are expected to leave about $ 30 million in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>. But some local plans to partake of the windfall have gone awry. An employee of an <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> office furniture and equipment rental firm told one caller his company and many others like it had raised prices 30 to 40 percent in anticipation of the convention rush. So many news organizations and some <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> groups flocked to a Detroit-area firm willing to deliver, install, maintain and remove typewriters, computers, copiers, telefax machines and office furniture at roughly half the going <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> cost. For example, water coolers were quoted locally at $ 30 a day. The Detroit firm provides them at $ 30 a month. Some <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> companies are renting typing tables at $ 50 each, waste baskets for up to $ 27 and chairs for as much as $ 40. Convention Florist Service Int' l. <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> lists the rental price on 7-foot green plant at $ 79.50. Local florists checked by telephone offered to sell similar plants outright for from $ 45 to $ 65. Hotels are also looking at a boom, with rooms for delegates, reporters, VIPs, fund-raisers, lobbyists, protesters and the curious at a premium. A prospectus for a major textile convention coming to <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> in September lists a single room at the <ORGANIZATION> Atlanta </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hilton </ORGANIZATION> at $ 102. A reservations clerk quoted a rate of $ 135 for the Democratic convention. A spot check found some hotels charging higher rates although some quoted rates at or below the rate being charged at the September textile convention. Many of the receptions, news conferences and hospitality rooms scheduled for the convention will be held at the <ORGANIZATION> Georgia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>, home base for most of the 12,000 news media representatives plus the party faithful who can not fit into the convention hall. <ORGANIZATION> MGR </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, the food service contractor for all events there, will cater about 950 convention functions over four days, from small hospitality suites to a windup `` victory party'' for 30,000. MGR president <PERSON> Phillip </PERSON> <PERSON> Noyes </PERSON> said the company is hiring about 500 extra employees to handle the rush. However, the prices have been in effect for a year. `` We are n't the cheapest in the country,'' he acknowledged. `` We provide a highly specialized service and people pay for that. Our business is n't any different. People want a product that's iced down, chilled and ready, and all that goes with it.'' Last year a poll of 500 trade shows and conventions picked MGR as the best convention catering firm in the country. MGR will provide soft drinks at about $ 43 a case. Most meals will be served buffet-style with lunch at $ 14.50 and dinner at $ 18.50. Coffee, or hot water to make tea or instant coffee, is about $ 27 a gallon after tax and a 17 percent service charge are added. Fruit juice will be about $ 29 a gallon. Convention tenants are barred from having their own coffee makers. `` They're charging $ 165 for 100 little pieces of chicken. Everybody is complaining,'' said <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> aide <PERSON> Yolanda </PERSON> <PERSON> Carroway </PERSON>. `` Prices have not been raised at all,'' said <PERSON> Tim </PERSON> <PERSON> Sterns </PERSON>, who oversees convention catering for the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>. He said <ORGANIZATION> DNC </ORGANIZATION> surveys showed the prices to be lower than those at many downtown hotels. `` They have been very accommodating,'' he said when asked about the price of MGR's coffee service. `` They put in a program where the initial service is $ 50 and they provide a coffee maker. Each day they will deliver supplies at a lower rate for people who want to make their own coffee. They have made some concessions in that way.'' Delegates may get a break, however, if they come down with toothaches. An <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> dentist, <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> J </PERSON>. <PERSON> Mills </PERSON>, is offering free emergency dental service to delegates during the convention.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880712-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-12-88 0109EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Duarte     07-12 0387</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Duarte,0398</SECOND>
<HEAD>Duarte, Defying Cancer, Gets Back to Work</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DOUGLAS GRANT MINE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SAN SALVADOR, El Salvador (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Defying terminal cancer, President <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Napoleon </PERSON> <PERSON> Duarte </PERSON> returned from <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> to begin catching up on official business after six weeks' absence. `` I am here now to reassume the presidency, in order to continue working for what I most love: democracy,'' the 62-year-old <PERSON> Duarte </PERSON> said upon arriving Monday from the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> capital, where he underwent diagnosis and treatment beginning May 31. `` I certainly am not cured. But I am strong. I have the capacity and the strength to carry out both the medical requisites my disease demands and my work for the people,'' said <PERSON> Duarte </PERSON>, the <LOCATION> Western </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hemisphere </LOCATION>' staunchest <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> ally. <PERSON> Duarte </PERSON>, whose five-year term ends June 1, 1989, was leaner than when he left and his face was somewhat drawn. But his step was firm and his embrace appeared strong as he greeted <PERSON> Rodolfo </PERSON> <PERSON> Castillo </PERSON> <PERSON> Claramount </PERSON>, the vice president and acting chief executive, and other officials on the tarmac of <LOCATION> Ilopango </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION> outside the capital. After a brief airport ceremony, he was driven to the presidential residence to rest. The chemotherapy <PERSON> Duarte </PERSON> is undergoing for liver cancer has debilitated him somewhat, but he vowed the illness would not keep him down. Doctors have given him between six and 18 months to live. <PERSON> Duarte </PERSON> promised to continue working with the military against leftist guerrillas `` in order to bring peace to my people ... in that way I will make it to the first of June and hand power over to the one who is elected by the people.'' <PERSON> Duarte </PERSON>'s governing <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> is in the deepest crisis of its 28-year history. Each of two bitterly feuding factions has nominated a presidential candidate. The right-wing opposition won municipal and legislative elections in March. That victory, along with the <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democrats </ORGANIZATION>' internal problems, have created the impression that the right-wing <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nationalist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Alliance </ORGANIZATION> could win the March 1989 presidential election. <PERSON> Castillo </PERSON> told a news conference last week that <PERSON> Duarte </PERSON>'s work routine will be established `` according to the evolution of his disease.'' The president is to return to <ORGANIZATION> Walter </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> next month for at least one more massive chemotherapy application. Salvadoran officials have said subsequent treatment could be carried out in <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880712-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-12-88 0105EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     07-12 0899</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0937</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names In The News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: First name `Bobs' in 4th graf of 4th item is cq.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Pop star <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> was greeted by 800 screaming fans as he arrived at <LOCATION> Heathrow </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION> to begin his first British tour. As <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, 29, was whisked through customs Monday, fans waving banners saying `` We Love You Michael'' and `` Welcome To <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>'' strained for a glimpse of the man they had awaited for since early morning. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> appeared briefly on a viewing platform, wearing dark glasses and a `` Sgt. Pepper'' suit in the style of the Beatles. He waved back at his fans and said, `` This welcome is truly wonderful, I love the English people,'' before six security guards escorted him away. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> opens his tour Thursday with a concert at <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Wembley </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Stadium </LOCATION> He will perform Saturday at a charity concert to be attended by <PERSON> Prince </PERSON> <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> and his wife, <PERSON> Diana </PERSON>. Later this month, <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s `` Bad Tour'' _ named for his album `` Bad'' _ will continue in <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Wales </LOCATION> before returning to <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> in August.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>BEVERLY HILLS, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Sinatra </PERSON>, <PERSON> Sid </PERSON> <PERSON> Caesar </PERSON> and <PERSON> Gregory </PERSON> <PERSON> Peck </PERSON> are among the 200 friends expected to help comedian <PERSON> Milton </PERSON> <PERSON> Berle </PERSON> celebrate his 80th birthday tonight. <PERSON> Said </PERSON> <PERSON> Berle </PERSON>, `` I'm going to miss the All-Star -LRB- baseball -RRB- game, but I'm going to have an all-star game of my own.'' The guest list for the bash at the nightclub <ORGANIZATION> La </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cage </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aux </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Folles </ORGANIZATION> includes <PERSON> Lucille </PERSON> <PERSON> Ball </PERSON>, <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Lemmon </PERSON>, Red Buttons, <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Allen </PERSON>, <PERSON> Danny </PERSON> <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> and <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Rickles </PERSON>. `` He's really excited about the party,'' <PERSON> Berle </PERSON>'s wife, <PERSON> Ruth </PERSON>, who set it up, said Monday. <PERSON> Berle </PERSON> was host of TV's first hit show, `` Texaco Star Theater.'' His vaudevillian antics endeared him to a generation of <LOCATION> Americans </LOCATION> and earned him the title `` Mr. Television.'' <PERSON> Berle </PERSON> opens at <PERSON> Caesar </PERSON>'s Palace in <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.J. </LOCATION>, on Aug. 9 with <PERSON> Danny </PERSON> <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> and <PERSON> Sid </PERSON> <PERSON> Caesar </PERSON>. He then has performances scheduled in <LOCATION> Las </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vegas </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Nev. </LOCATION>, beginning Aug. 24. `` He's really 80 years young and his contribution to the world of comedy will live forever,'' Miss <PERSON> Ball </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Television producer <PERSON> Norman </PERSON> <PERSON> Lear </PERSON> and his wife are the proud new parents of a baby boy, a spokeswoman says. <PERSON> Benjamin </PERSON> <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> <PERSON> Lear </PERSON> was born late Sunday, weighing 7 pounds, 2 -LCB- ounces, <PERSON> Lear </PERSON> publicist <PERSON> Pam </PERSON> <PERSON> Ruben </PERSON> said Monday. The child is <PERSON> Lear </PERSON>'s fourth but the first for his wife, psychologist <PERSON> Lyn </PERSON> <PERSON> Davis </PERSON>, 40. The two were married in September. <PERSON> Lear </PERSON>, 65, is best known for creating the hit television series `` All in the Family.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>OMAHA, Neb. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Mickey </PERSON> <PERSON> Rooney </PERSON>, appearing at a ceremony marking the 50th anniversary of the making of the film `` Boys Town,'' said he wants to make a weekly TV series based on the famous home for boys. <PERSON> Rooney </PERSON>, who played the tough teen-ager <PERSON> Whitey </PERSON> <PERSON> James </PERSON> in the 1938 film, said he would approach <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pictures </ORGANIZATION> next year about the possibility of creating the TV series. `` Yours truly is going to be Father <PERSON> Whitey </PERSON> <PERSON> Marsh </PERSON>, the head of <ORGANIZATION> Boys </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Town </ORGANIZATION>,'' he said Monday. <PERSON> Rooney </PERSON> appeared Monday with <PERSON> Bobs </PERSON> <PERSON> Watson </PERSON>, who was 7 years old when he played little Pee Wee in the movie starring <PERSON> Spencer </PERSON> <PERSON> Tracy </PERSON> as Father <PERSON> Flanagan </PERSON>, founder of <LOCATION> Boys </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Town </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Rooney </PERSON> was 18 when the movie was made. <PERSON> Watson </PERSON>, who became a <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Methodist </ORGANIZATION> minister 25 years ago and lives in <LOCATION> Southern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, said making the movie had a big impact on his life. `` Father <PERSON> Flanagan </PERSON> was one of those men who touched my life deeply and was one of the reasons why I went into the ministry,'' he said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Liza </PERSON> <PERSON> Minnelli </PERSON>, once dependent on alcohol and drugs, now dances and does 200 sit-ups a day to stay in shape. `` I've never felt so wonderful in my whole life,'' the 42-year-old singer, dancer and actress says in the August issue of Ladies' Home Journal. `` I feel younger than I've ever felt. Carefree.'' She kicked her chemical dependencies during a stay at the <ORGANIZATION> Betty </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>. `` Chemical dependency is a sad, lonely story that millions of women share,'' she said. `` The only solution is education. If I can spare somebody from going through what I went through, I'll gladly do that.'' The entertainer said she is cultivating a quiet, reflective side of her personality. `` I'm learning to be a friend to myself,'' she said. `` Once a day, you say to yourself, ` How are you, honey? How are you doing?' `` We ca n't all look like <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON> but we can look like that inside,'' she said. `` If you get your mind right, you can do anything.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>BEVERLY HILLS, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Society band leader <PERSON> Lester </PERSON> <PERSON> Lanin </PERSON> will try his hand at movies after a music career that has spanned nearly 75 years. <PERSON> Lanin </PERSON>, who is closing in on 80 but refuses to reveal just how close, is here this week to film `` Life After Life,'' a Tri-Star picture starring <PERSON> Cybill </PERSON> <PERSON> Shepherd </PERSON> and <PERSON> Ryan </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Neal </PERSON>. <PERSON> Lanin </PERSON> will portray himself in the film, leading his orchestra in three fox trots and a rock number. It's the first time <PERSON> Lanin </PERSON> has agreed to do a movie, although he's received other offers. `` I feel at this stage of the game I can go forward. I'm going in for some better things.'' <PERSON> Lanin </PERSON> has been hired to perform by eight presidents and four kings and queens.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880712-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-12-88 0110EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Reagan-Seabrook     07-12 0488</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Reagan-Seabrook,490</SECOND>
<HEAD>Reagan Promises To Consider Lawmakers' Opposition To Seabrook
Order</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CHRISTOPHER CALLAHAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> has promised to weigh opposition to a proposed executive order that could help license the <LOCATION> Seabrook </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.H. </LOCATION>, nuclear power plant by circumventing the objections of <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>. Lawmakers from the all-Republican <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION> congressional delegation, upset over the proposed federal intervention, said they received the pledge Monday after a White House briefing with <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>. `` We found the president very positive, very sympathetic, very understanding,'' said Sen. <PERSON> Warren </PERSON> <PERSON> Rudman </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-N.H. </LOCATION> `` It was clear to all of us that the president was going to very actively consider our request that this order never be published.'' <PERSON> Rudman </PERSON> and Sen. <PERSON> Gordon </PERSON> <PERSON> Humphrey </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-N.H. </LOCATION>, expressed optimism that the president may reject the proposal. `` I am very hopeful that this visit has an effect on the president in convincing him that the process was working -LRB- and -RRB- the federal government need not become involved at this time,'' <PERSON> Rudman </PERSON> told reporters outside the White House. <PERSON> Humphrey </PERSON> added, `` The president did n't say yes or no, but I came away more encouraged about our prospects of blocking this order than frankly I had expected to.'' But Rep. <PERSON> Judd </PERSON> <PERSON> Gregg </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-N.H. </LOCATION>, who said before the briefing that he thought it would be extremely difficult to derail the proposal, said afterwards that he felt no more optimistic about the lawmakers' chances. `` He gave us no reading at all as to what his decision would be,'' said <PERSON> Gregg </PERSON>, noting that <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> reiterated his strong support for atomic power and expressed concern over state governments' ability to block reactor licenses `` The president has not made a decision,'' said Rep. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-N.H. </LOCATION> `` He will weigh our evidence and our advice. That's the best we can hope for at this time. The four lawmakers, loyal and long-time allies of the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration, have expressed support for plant licensing as long as federal regulators determine that the plant and evacuation plan are safe. Licensing for the <LOCATION> Seabrook </LOCATION> reactor has been stalled largely by the refusal of <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> to submit evacuation plans for the six <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> communities that fall within the plant's 10-mile emergency zone. The proposed executive order would give the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Emergency </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Management </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION>, which has served a strictly advisory role in atomic safety issues, the power to design and implement evacuation plans when local governments refuse to do so. The four were infuriated last month when they learned of the proposal through plant opponents, who discovered a draft and leaked it to reporters. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> told the delegation that he had not seen any draft of the proposal, which sources said was initiated by the <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, pushed by four senators and approved unanimously by the president's <ORGANIZATION> Domestic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Policy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> and other plant opponents have said it is impossible to evacuate the area quickly and safely because of narrow rural roads and a large summertime population.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880712-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-12-88 0101EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-BlueFlu 2ndLd-Writethru a0689 07-12 0351</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Blue Flu, 2nd Ld - Writethru, a0689,0357</SECOND>
<HEAD>State Police Move In As City Cops Call In Sick; `Flu' Cured After
24 Hours</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: LEADS with 3 grafs to UPDATE with late-evening shift back to
normal, picking up 3rd graf pvs, `Woodfork said...'.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>NEW ORLEANS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 State troopers patrolled city streets Monday to make up for an apparent sick-out by more than 300 officers upset over low wages and the lack of a labor contract. The job action ended at late evening. Police Chief <PERSON> Warren </PERSON> <PERSON> Woodfork </PERSON> said city streets were probably safer than usual because of the 60 troopers in the city. There were 143 officers and troopers on patrol, compared with a usual 83, police said. Officers began straggling back to work for the start of their late-evening shift, said police department spokesman <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Bryson </PERSON>. `` They have returned to work. We're back up to normal strength,'' he said. <PERSON> Woodfork </PERSON> said his department could continue to maintain security in the city of 500,000 even if police union members carry out a threat to stop work during next month's Republican National Convention. About 130 troopers already are scheduled to be in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION> next month during the GOP convention. The sick-out began Sunday night and <PERSON> Woodfork </PERSON> said he did n't know how long it would last, although he heard it was to end Monday night. Leaders of the <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Orleans </ORGANIZATION> have long been pressuring Mayor <PERSON> Sidney </PERSON> <PERSON> Barthelemy </PERSON> to enter the city's first collective bargaining agreement with the union. The union claims a membership of about 900 of the 1,100-member police force. <PERSON> Barthelemy </PERSON>, who was out of town Monday and unavailable for comment, has refused to recognize <ORGANIZATION> PANO </ORGANIZATION> as a collective bargaining group. Union President <PERSON> Ron </PERSON> <PERSON> Cannatella </PERSON> did not return telephone calls and there was no word from the union on whether it had called for the sick-out. <PERSON> Woodfork </PERSON> said he had no immediate plans to discipline officers who called in sick Sunday or Monday. `` I would just ask the officers who are out sick to search their consciences. Do n't hold the city of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION> hostage,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880712-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-12-88 0114EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Convention-Networks Bjt   07-12 0773</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Convention-Networks, Bjt,750</SECOND>
<HEAD>1988: Last of the Prime-Time Convention Coverage?</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KATHRYN BAKER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Television Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 In 1984, there was great hand-wringing over the networks' decision to drop gavel-to-gavel coverage of the national conventions in favor of roughly two hours of live prime-time coverage a night. In 1988, the question that's starting to be asked is whether two hours of prime-time coverage a night is too much. Former NBC News President <PERSON> Reuven </PERSON> <PERSON> Frank </PERSON>, who has attended seven conventions as a network producer, saw the end of gavel-to-gavel coverage and expects this year to watch the last prime-time coverage. `` Conventions are now being held by the two major parties only because there's television,'' <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> said. `` That's the only justification for the convention at all. There is no journalistic reason for our being there. I think we ought to be there; I do n't think we ought to carry it live `` There's nothing going to happen that you do n't know now sitting here. But we do n't know how to stop. It's like ` The Old Man and the Sea.''' Next week, when the Democrats meet in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>, they are certain to nominate <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>. The only major questions remaining are who his running mate will be and what <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, the runner-up, will do or say. Media-wise political parties know that prime-time bickering turns off voters, so conventions have become little more than prime-time commercials. A one-time major network event, the conventions are becoming a made-for-cable show. Complete coverage will be available on <ORGANIZATION> C-SPAN </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Cable </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Network </ORGANIZATION>, a trend that will no doubt allow the three major networks to say by 1992 that cable TV provides sufficient coverage to meet the public need and the networks no longer need devote live prime time to the proceedings. Indeed, they are already beginning to say that. `` Our responsibility as a news organization has changed somewhat,'' said <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> producer <PERSON> Anne </PERSON> <PERSON> Binford </PERSON>. `` In the past, we felt we had to provide coverage of the entire convention, but now, with cable and C-SPAN and <ORGANIZATION> CNN </ORGANIZATION>, the viewers can watch the coverage from many different sources. We're now trying to bring the audience a condensed version of the important events of the night.'' All three networks say their coverage plans are flexible, depending on events. But the intention is to go on the air from 9-11 p.m. EDT each of the four nights. <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> plans to start at 8 p.m. on Thursday. C-SPAN will carry each session of the convention live, in its entirety, without commentary or interviews. <ORGANIZATION> CNN </ORGANIZATION> plans to carry convention updates throughout the day, the convention session in its entirety, followed by a half-hour wrapup, then `` Crossfire'' and `` Inside Politics'88.'' The most devout political junkies can even catch convention highlights from 4-6 a.m. <PERSON> Jeff </PERSON> <PERSON> Gralnick </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s executive producer of special broadcasts, wishes the networks could justify such extensive coverage. `` I think there's a hell of a vibrant political story at the conventions,'' he said. `` I'm a political junkie, and I just find what the Democrats are doing and later the Republicans a fascinating political dynamic.'' But he concedes the conventions `` are not a mass-audience program.'' `` For the sake of the union, I wish they were, but if you look at the number of people who choose to vote out of the universe of people who can vote, you begin to get an answer of why people do n't watch political conventions If they do n't care to vote, they certainly are n't going to watch the end product of the voting.'' <ORGANIZATION> CNN </ORGANIZATION> stands to become the star of the Democrats' convention. It has anchor power in <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Alice </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> and <PERSON> Bernard </PERSON> <PERSON> Shaw </PERSON>, and with the networks paring down their staffs for budgetary considerations, the cable network is in their league. <ORGANIZATION> CNN </ORGANIZATION> will have 275 staffers compared to the 300-350 each for the bigger networks. In addition, <ORGANIZATION> CNN </ORGANIZATION> is based in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> and has a home-field advantage. The three networks are taking 25-50 percent fewer staffers to this year's conventions than they did in 1984. `` I'd be lying if I said it was n't a matter of budget, but more it's a matter of each time you do one of these things, you learn how to do them a little more efficiently,'' said <PERSON> Gralnick </PERSON>. `` It's new times,'' said <PERSON> Binford </PERSON>. `` I think with the new technology, we're able to cover it just as efficiently.'' <PERSON> Frank </PERSON>, himself an innovator of much of the present-day convention coverage, such as anchor booths overlooking the convention floor, agrees that the networks have learned a lot. But, he adds, `` now that we know how to cover it, there's nothing to cover.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880712-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-12-88 0115EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-EnergyEfficiency     07-12 0527</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Energy Efficiency,520</SECOND>
<NOTE>For Release 10:30 a.m. EDT;
^Research Group Calls For Fuel, Gas-Guzzler Taxes</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By GUY DARST</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> should raise gasoline taxes by 50 cents a gallon, require cars to get 45 miles per gallon and boost the gas-guzzler tax to raise money for rebates to buyers of fuel-efficient cars, an organization of environmentalists, scientists and business executives said today. Those were central measures in a program outlined by the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> for an Energy-Efficient Economy that would set a national goal of maintaining momentum in improving energy efficiency for the rest of the century. `` Energy efficiency does not require sacrifice,'' the group argued in its report. `` We do not advocate saving energy as an end in itself. It makes sense only when saving energy costs less than providing energy, including environmental damage and security risks in the comparison.'' Environmental risks of inefficiency are severe, the group said. Man-made gases, notably carbon dioxide produced by fossil fuels, threaten to warm the earth by as much as eight degrees Fahrenheit in the next century, raising sea levels and drastically changing patterns of rainfall and drought _ a process some scientists say is under way. Increasing the 9-cent-per-gallon federal gasoline tax by 10 cents annually for five years _ three years if crude oil prices double _ would yield $ 40 billion to $ 60 billion a year. Such a tax would help make sure `` consumers are given a price signal that better reflects the real cost of the resource and encourages conservation.'' Some money could be rebated to the poor through income tax provisions. Cars, now required to get 26 mpg, should get 45 mpg by 2000. `` It need not be so'' that the standards would mean less safety from lighter weight if cars are carefully designed, the group said. Cars twice as efficient as current models would cost $ 200 to $ 800 more, the group estimated. The increase would be recouped over the life of the car through lower cost of operation. A stiffer `` gas-guzzler'' tax, which can reach more than $ 2,000 now but generally applies to only a few luxury cars like <ORGANIZATION> Jaguar </ORGANIZATION>, would discourage production of highly inefficient cars and provide funds _ more than $ 1.1 billion a year in 1994 _ to encourage purchase of `` gas sippers.'' The rebate could be `` on the order of $ 1,000'' for models with mileage 50 percent better than today's best _ implying rebates for cars getting about 75 mpg. Energy used per dollar of economic activity declined at a rate of about 2.7 percent per year from 1976 through 1986, and was still declining at a 2.5 percent per year during the economic recovery of 1983 through 1986. The 1986 oil price collapse discouraged further gains, and the decline was only 0.5 percent in 1987. The <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> says it expects gains of about 0.9 percent a year for the rest of the century. A reasonable international goal would be annual reductions of 2 percent, and `` We suggest that the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> set an example by pursuing a goal of at least 2.5 percent per year'' until 2000, the group said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880712-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-12-88 0117EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-China-HeatWave     07-12 0182</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-China-Heat Wave,0185</SECOND>
<HEAD>Heat Wave Kills 83 In Nanking</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Eighty-three people have died and another 1,500 have been hospitalized in a heat wave that has smothered the eastern Chinese city of <LOCATION> Nanking </LOCATION> for 10 days, the official <ORGANIZATION> Xinhua </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> reported. The report quoted <PERSON> Zhu </PERSON> <PERSON> Qingxue </PERSON>, director of the city public health bureau, as saying four-fifths of those who died were over age 60. It said temperatures in the city have hovered around 102 degrees in the third-hottest heat spell since 1905. On Monday, the high reached 100 degrees in the city of 3 million. Roads have been melting, factories have been told to cut back on electricity consumption and hospitals have been asked to set up rescue centers, <ORGANIZATION> Xinhua </ORGANIZATION> said. It said people have been helping policemen to keep cool by giving them cold water and cold towels and have been crowding into department stores and cinemas, among the few places in the city with air conditioning. <LOCATION> Nanking </LOCATION>, located on the <LOCATION> Yangtze </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION>, is known as one of the `` furnaces'' of <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> because of its hot summers.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880712-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-12-88 0121EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-NAACPAward     07-12 0520</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-NAACP Award,520</SECOND>
<HEAD>NAACP Honors Medgar Evers 25 Years After His Murder</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CRISPIN Y. CAMPBELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Promoting the memory and ideals of civil rights leaders such as <PERSON> Medgar </PERSON> <PERSON> Evers </PERSON> may help black youth steer clear of crime and drugs, says <PERSON> Evers </PERSON>' widow, <PERSON> Myrlie </PERSON>. `` It is so important that we remember our leaders who have passed and those who are with us now, and that our young people know who they are and the contributions that they have made,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Evers </PERSON> said upon acceptance of the <ORGANIZATION> NAACP </ORGANIZATION>'s first Chairman Civil Rights Leadership Award in behalf of her husband. `` In so knowing they will have something to aspire to,'' she said, `` they will not as readily go into black on black crime, or into drugs. But there will be a sense of well-being, a sense of going forward. That is what <PERSON> Medgar </PERSON> stood for.'' `` I am so grateful that <PERSON> Medger </PERSON> is being remembered by the organization that he loved so much and the organization that no one could take him away from,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Evers </PERSON> told the 79th annual convention of the National Association For the Advancement of Colored People. <PERSON> Evers </PERSON>, who led the fight against segregation as the <ORGANIZATION> NAACP </ORGANIZATION>'s <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> state field secretary from 1954 to 1963, received national attention as the man who counseled <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Meredith </PERSON> through his successful bid to enter the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mississippi </ORGANIZATION> in 1962 Mrs. <PERSON> Evers </PERSON>, currently the <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> city commissioner of public works, told the <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> about the day her husband was gunned-down in front of their home in <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>. `` I was in the kitchen with the children, as he entered the driveway, the children said ` there's <PERSON> Daddy </PERSON>'s,' as he opened the car door the shot rang out. The children fell to the floor _ as he had taught them _ and I bolted for the door ... thinking ` Oh God, do n't let him be hit.'' <PERSON> Evers </PERSON> had been fatally wounded with a shot from a high powered rifle, `` the kind they used to kill large animals like deer,'' she said. A member of the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Citizens </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> was charged and tried twice by an all-white jury which was unable to reach a verdict. Mrs. <PERSON> Evers </PERSON> admitted she `` always felt he never got the recognition for the work he had done and I wanted so badly for people to know about him and his work. ... and his organization, the <ORGANIZATION> NAACP </ORGANIZATION> is doing that.'' `` Keeping his memory alive was something he and I had discussed before his death,'' she said. `` We both knew that something was coming and tried to prepare ourselves and each other for the inevitable. And the last two weeks of his life we stopped denying -LRB- that -RRB- something would not happen, -LRB- something -RRB- that we knew was going to happen. `` He told me ` <PERSON> Myrlie </PERSON>, do n't worry about people remembering me _ at some point in history my deeds will speak for themselves.' `` Once I told him he was n't getting enough publicity, and he said ` I do n't want publicity. I'm in it for the people _ it does n't make any difference to me.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880712-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-12-88 0121EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-BerlinOpera     07-12 0231</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Berlin Opera,230</SECOND>
<HEAD>Berlin Opera to Perform Wagner at Kennedy Center</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Berlin Opera will present two performances of <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Wagner </PERSON>'s sprawling opera masterpiece `` Der Ring des <PERSON> Nibelungen </PERSON>'' in an exclusive American engagement at the <ORGANIZATION> Kennedy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> next June, center officials announced today. The four-opera `` Ring'' cycle, which consists of nearly 15 hours of music, will be performed twice in the <ORGANIZATION> Kennedy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Opera </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, June 2-18, to mark the 40th anniversary of the founding of the West German republic. <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION>'s leading opera company will present the innovative 1985 staging of the `` Ring'' cycles by general director <PERSON> Gotz </PERSON> <PERSON> Friedrich </PERSON>, which features a `` time tunnel'' extending the full depth of the stage. Each cycle includes the operas `` Das Rheingold,'' `` Die Walkure,'' `` Siegfried'' and `` Gotterdammerung'' and will be performed over four days and last almost 18 hours, including intermissions and a dinner break. The <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Opera </LOCATION>'s first <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> appearance since 1976 is being underwritten by the <LOCATION> Bonn </LOCATION> government. <PERSON> Marta </PERSON> <PERSON> Istomin </PERSON>, artistic director of the <ORGANIZATION> Kennedy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>, said audiences `` will be able to see and hear one of the central masterpieces of German art performed by a great German opera company on a historic occasion.'' <PERSON> Friedrich </PERSON> said his company will be paying tribute to `` the strong ties that exist between <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> and the U.S.A.'' and expressing `` the gratitude of the citizens of <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> to the American people.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880712-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-12-88 0123EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Convention-TV     07-12 0310</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Convention-TV,280</SECOND>
<HEAD>With PM-Convention-Networks Bjt</HEAD>
<HEAD>Networks Plan Prime-Time Convention Coverage</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The three major networks plan to carry live coverage of the Democratic National Convention for approximately two hours of prime time each night, Monday through Thursday. All three networks plan coverage from 9-11 p.m. EDT each night. <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> will start at 8 p.m. on Thursday. <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s coverage will be anchored by <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Jennings </PERSON> with commentary by <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Brinkley </PERSON>. `` World News Tonight'' and `` Good Morning America'' will originate from <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> during the convention. `` Nightline'' will stay home in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, but will include reports on the convention as news merits. <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> Cronkite </PERSON>, who is under contract negotiations with <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, nevertheless returns for his 19th convention serving as network commentator. <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Rather </PERSON> will anchor the convention coverage. `` CBS Evening News'' will originate from <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>, as will `` CBS This Morning.'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Brokaw </PERSON> will anchor his network's coverage with <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Chancellor </PERSON> providing commentary. `` NBC Nightly News'' and the `` Today'' show will originate from <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>. C-SPAN will carry each session of the convention live without commentary each night. Cable News Network will have updates throughout the day, then carry complete live coverage of the convention session each night, followed by a half-hour wrapup, then `` Crossfire'' and `` Inside Politics'88.'' Convention highlights will be shown 4-6 a.m. EDT. PBS' `` MacNeil-Lehrer NewsHour'' will also report from the convention. In the battle of the political columnist-commentators, <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> landed columnists <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Will </PERSON> and <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Wicker </PERSON>. <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> snagged <PERSON> Kevin </PERSON> <PERSON> Phillips </PERSON> and <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> Rosenblatt </PERSON>. <ORGANIZATION> CNN </ORGANIZATION>'s lineup of experts include columnists <PERSON> Patrick </PERSON> <PERSON> Buchanan </PERSON>, <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Braden </PERSON>, <PERSON> Rowland </PERSON> <PERSON> Evans </PERSON>, <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Green </PERSON> and <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Novak </PERSON>. <ORGANIZATION> PBS </ORGANIZATION> has <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; World Report Editor <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Gergen </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> columnist <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Shields </PERSON>. <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> says it is depending on its own Chancellor, <PERSON> Brokaw </PERSON> and political reporter <PERSON> Ken </PERSON> <PERSON> Bode </PERSON>, though political consultants <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Squier </PERSON> and <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Sears </PERSON> will offer commentary on `` Today.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880712-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-12-88 0126EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Israel     07-12 0716</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Israel,0740</SECOND>
<HEAD>Two Arabs Killed, At Least 13 Wounded, In Clashes With Soldiers</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAN IZENBERG</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>JERUSALEM (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
