<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880613-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-13-88 0000EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Deaths 1stLd-Writethru a0771 06-12 0610</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Deaths, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0771,0634</SECOND>
<NOTE>Eds: ADDS Branigin, Clark obits; an AMs separate moved on L'Amour
as a0714.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>Louis L'Amour</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Louis </PERSON> <PERSON> L'Amour </PERSON>, whose Old West novels about gunfighters, lawmen and drifters drew on his colorful past as a gold prospector, roustabout and jack-of-all-trades, died Friday of lung cancer. He was 80. He wrote 101 books, nearly all of them Westerns, including `` Hondo,'' `` How the West Was Won,'' `` The Iron Marshal,'' `` The Quick and the Dead,'' `` <PERSON> Sackett </PERSON>'s Land,'' and `` Ride the Dark Trail.'' Nearly 200 million copies of L'Amour's books were printed; his works were translated into 20 languages, according to his publisher, <ORGANIZATION> Bantam </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Books </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> L'Amour </PERSON> left home in <LOCATION> Jamestown </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.D. </LOCATION>, when he was 15, working as prize fighter, deckhand, longshoreman, lumberjack, gold prospector, coal miner, circus roustabout, fruit picker, elephant handler and amateur archaeologist. He became a prolific contributor in the 1940s and 1950s to pulp magazines and his first novel, `` Hondo,'' was published in 1953. It was followed by 85 more, along with 14 short story collections and one non-fiction book. In 1984, President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> presented L'Amour with the Presidential Medal of Freedom. <PERSON> L'Amour </PERSON> is survived by his wife <PERSON> Kathy </PERSON>, and a son and daughter.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>Robert Stewart</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WEST LAFAYETTE, Ind. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Stewart </PERSON>, retired <ORGANIZATION> Purdue </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> treasurer and executive who administered billions of dollars in GI <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> veterans benefits, died Friday in <LOCATION> Vero </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla </LOCATION>. He was 92. <PERSON> Stewart </PERSON>'s 36 years with <ORGANIZATION> Purdue </ORGANIZATION> began in 1925 as its controller. In 1945 he was named vice president and treasurer, a post he held until his retirement in 1961. After World War II, as administrator of <ORGANIZATION> Veteran </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Affairs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Advisory </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> on </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Vocational </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rehabilitation </ORGANIZATION>, Education and Training, <PERSON> Stewart </PERSON> coordinated $ 14.5 billion in G.I. Bill benefits for 8 million veterans. He successfully fought President <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Truman </PERSON>'s request that the Veterans Administration examine all textbooks used by veterans to make sure they did not support communist doctrine. Born in <LOCATION> Duluth </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Minn. </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Stewart </PERSON> graduated from the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wisconsin </ORGANIZATION>, earned his doctorate from <ORGANIZATION> Butler </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> and taught in <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION>. He was business manager of <ORGANIZATION> Albion </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> before coming to <ORGANIZATION> Purdue </ORGANIZATION>. Survivors include his wife, <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> <PERSON> Stewart </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>Josephine Branigin</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WEST LAFAYETTE , Ind. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Josephine </PERSON> <PERSON> Mardis </PERSON> <PERSON> Branigin </PERSON>, widow of former Gov. <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Branigin </PERSON>, died Saturday at age 80. She was born Feb. 4, 1908, in <LOCATION> Shelbyville </LOCATION> and graduated cum laude from <LOCATION> Franklin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> College </LOCATION>, where she majored in mathematics and biology, in 1929. In 1929 she married <PERSON> Branigin </PERSON>, who served as <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION>'s 42nd governor from 1965 to 1968. A retired <LOCATION> Lafayette </LOCATION> attorney, he died Nov. 19, 1975. She is survived by her son, <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Branigin </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, seven grandchildren; and two great-grandchildren.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>Bill Clark</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WATERVILLE, Maine (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Clark </PERSON>, a former schoolteacher who became one of <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION>'s most widely read newspaper columnists, died Sunday after a brief illness. He was 74. <PERSON> Clark </PERSON>'s columns for the editorial pages of <ORGANIZATION> Guy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Gannett </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Publishing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> newspapers embraced traditional values, often featuring the fictional town of <LOCATION> Cedar </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> and country characters dispensing folksy wisdom. A native of <LOCATION> Schenectady </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Clark </PERSON> graduated from <ORGANIZATION> Colby </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> and obtained an education degree from <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Teachers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION>. He taught in <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> state </LOCATION>, where he became a school principal in <LOCATION> Greenbush </LOCATION>. After serving with the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> during World War II, he built log cabins around <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> George </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION>, area and operated a sawmill before moving to <LOCATION> Kennebunkport </LOCATION>. He taught speech and composition at <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> High </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> and writing at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Maine </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Portland </LOCATION>. His column, `` Logrolling,'' first appeared in the fall of 1956. He is survived by his wife, the former <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON>, and two sons.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880613-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-13-88 0002EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-HongKong-RedTide     06-13 0810</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Hong Kong-Red Tide,0833</SECOND>
<HEAD>China's Presence In Hong Kong Is Everywhere _ And Expanding</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By DAN BIERS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>HONG KONG (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 High above <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION>'s imposing skyline, the final girders are swinging into place atop the <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> China </ORGANIZATION>'s striking prism-shaped building The 70-story glass-and-steel building, to be the local headquarters of mainland <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s official bank, is a none-too-subtle symbol of <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s unrivaled influence and growing activity in this British colony which reverts to Chinese sovereignty in 1997. Communist <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s soaring presence is a result of market-oriented economic reforms championed by <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> leader <PERSON> Deng </PERSON> <PERSON> Xiaoping </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> and the part of the agreement with <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> that says <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> can keep its capitalist system for 50 years after 1997. Chinese officials of various ranks are invading <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> for a crash course in capitalism and to secure money-making deals. The big Chinese companies are wheeling and dealing in <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION>'s high-flying property market, investing in major construction projects and even buying large blocks of local stock Chinese diplomats are busy too. <PERSON> Xu </PERSON> <PERSON> Jiatun </PERSON>, <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s top diplomat in <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION>, shows up at pop concerts and cocktail parties. He heads the local branch of <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s official <ORGANIZATION> Xinhua </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> but is viewed by many as the colony's shadow <PERSON> Xu </PERSON>'s main task is to promote stability and prosperity in <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION>, and he is full of kind words for its capitalist society. `` We have some comrades who always fear capitalism, but in fact they do n't understand that the modern capitalist system is a great creation of human civilization,'' he has told reporters. No official figures are available to show how many China-backed companies are in <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION>, but estimates run into the thousands. <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> is widely regarded as the largest foreign investor in <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION>, with estimates ranging from $ 6 billion to $ 8 billion. The investments include department stores, factories, supermarkets and real estate. Much of the activity is financed by the 14-member <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> China </ORGANIZATION> group, which saw profits rise by 30 percent to 60 percent in 1987, according to the <ORGANIZATION> Capital </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Information </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> financial research firm. <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s property purchases in <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> totaled about $ 1 billion last year, exceeded only by Japanese and local investors, according to <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Kwan </PERSON> of <PERSON> Chesterton </PERSON> <PERSON> Petty </PERSON>, an international property consulting company. <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> snatched up hotels, office buildings and residential high-rises. `` They have to support the political confidence of people'' in the years before 1997, <PERSON> Kwan </PERSON> said, noting that the injection of Chinese capital creates demand and raises real estate prices. Some deals reflect the need for more space by expanding Chinese companies while other deals are strictly to make money. <ORGANIZATION> China </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Trust </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Investment </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, for example, bought an office building near the central business district for about $ 45 million in May 1987 and then sold it to Japanese interests five months later for a 35 percent profit, according to <PERSON> Chesterton </PERSON> <PERSON> Petty </PERSON>. Other Chinese moves that have turned heads in <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> include: _ Bailouts of financially troubled <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> banks and a pledge by the <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> China </ORGANIZATION> of the equivalent in <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> dollars of $ 128 million to save the colony's teetering futures exchange after the global stock market crash in October _ The purchase by <ORGANIZATION> CITIC </ORGANIZATION>, which is <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s premier international investment company, of 12.5 percent of <ORGANIZATION> Cathay </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pacific </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airways </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ltd. </ORGANIZATION>, the territory's profitable flag carrier _ Participation of three Chinese companies in three competing consortia bidding for a multimillion-dollar tunnel project through the suburban New Territories Matching <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s flurry of economic activity in <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> has been its expanded political work. From the <ORGANIZATION> Xinhua </ORGANIZATION> headquarters across the street from the <LOCATION> Happy </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION> race track, a staff of several hundred stay in touch with nearly every sector of society. <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION>'s Chinese-language Wide Angle magazine reported that the news agency has separate departments responsible for keeping in touch with the <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> government, students, grass-root organizations and the colony's elite. <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Y.S </PERSON>. <PERSON> Cheng </PERSON>, a political science lecturer at <ORGANIZATION> Chinese </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hong </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Kong </ORGANIZATION>, says <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s plan to win over local residents is `` a longtime process of befriending us, of co-opting us, so when the Chinese come -LRB- in 1997 -RRB- there's a very good chance of us being immobilized or at least neutralized.'' One group that <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> has successfully cultivated is the power elite, who believe toeing the <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> line is the best way to keep their businesses healthy after 1997. <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> also can count on several local organizations to support its policies here. For example, the <ORGANIZATION> Hong </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Kong </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Trade </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Unions </ORGANIZATION>, which represents about 170,000 workers, mobilized its members last year to support <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s opposition to general legislative elections in <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> this year. This, along with the colonial government's decision to delay elections until 1991, has led some local activists to believe <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> already is calling the shots in <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880613-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-13-88 0011EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a PM-Names     06-13 0937</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0971</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in the News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Tiffany </PERSON>, the 16-year-old pop star who sued for freedom from her mother, believes she and her mother will overcome their differences. In an interview conducted before she agreed to withdraw her petition to be legally recognized as an adult, <PERSON> Tiffany </PERSON> vowed she would n't go home again, but not because she does n't like her mother. `` I love my mom and my mom loves me,'' she said. `` We'll overcome this Hopefully I'll be emancipated. I still want to be emancipated and have not at all changed my mind. But I do n't think my mom at all is saying, ` If you get emancipated I'll never talk to you again.' That's just not my mom.'' Terms of Tuesday's settlement between <PERSON> Tiffany </PERSON> and her mother, <PERSON> Janie </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>, were not disclosed. `` This whole court thing in some people's eyes has been made out to be such a bad thing, but it's really reality,'' said <PERSON> Tiffany </PERSON>, who filed emancipation papers for legal status as an adult in March after her mother refused to approve a management contract between the singer and <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Tobin </PERSON>, her manager. <PERSON> Tiffany </PERSON> has scored on the pop charts with remakes of'60s hits such as `` I Saw Her Standing There'' and `` I Think We're Alone Now.''
</TEXT>
<NOTE>Eds: A version of the following item moved on sports wire.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Heavyweight boxing champ <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Tyson </PERSON>, whose wife, actress <PERSON> Robin </PERSON> <PERSON> Givens </PERSON>, is pregnant, says he hopes his children never have to take the punches he's had to. `` I ca n't wait to have a little baby so I can strap her into one of those pouches and walk her around,'' the 22-year-old <PERSON> Tyson </PERSON> said in July's Life magazine. `` It will be good to see my kids have some things I never had and see how they respond to it,'' he said. `` That's why I take the punches, so they'll never have to.'' `` He's the only man I know who can articulate what he truly needs,'' said <PERSON> Givens </PERSON>, 23, star of <ORGANIZATION> ABC-TV </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Head of the Class.'' It's the closeness of this couple, who have been married five months, that <ORGANIZATION> Life </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> magazine </ORGANIZATION> says has people in the boxing world worried that <PERSON> Tyson </PERSON> may be distracted and never achieve his full potential in the ring. But <PERSON> Tyson </PERSON>, who has won 34 straight and will defend his crown on June 27 against <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Spinks </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, is n't worried. `` I do n't own the title, I just borrowed it for a while,'' <PERSON> Tyson </PERSON> said. `` There's life beyond that.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>FORT PAYNE, Ala. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The country-music band <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION> drew 35,000 people to its seventh annual charity concert, and lead singer <PERSON> Randy </PERSON> <PERSON> Owen </PERSON> says past problems wo n't stand in the way of future June Jams. Saturday's crowd was far below the 61,000 who attended in 1986, when <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION> was at the peak of its popularity. But last year's June Jam was hit with heavy rain and paid attendance fell to 20,000, leaving no money for charity The first five June Jams raised $ 1.5 million. Because of last year's problems, <PERSON> Owen </PERSON> and other band members fought rumors that this year's concert would not occur. Once plans became final, band members had to dispel rumors that this would be the last. Entertainers joining <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION> for the daylong concert included the <PERSON> Charlie </PERSON> <PERSON> Daniels </PERSON> <PERSON> Band </PERSON>, Exile, K.T. <PERSON> Oslin </PERSON>, <PERSON> Carl </PERSON> <PERSON> Perkins </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> Bellamy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Brothers </ORGANIZATION>, Sweethearts of the Rodeo, <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Seals </PERSON>, <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Morris </PERSON> and <PERSON> Ricky </PERSON> <PERSON> Van </PERSON> <PERSON> Shelton </PERSON>. <PERSON> Owen </PERSON> says he's making plans to mark the state's homecoming celebration, <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Reunion </LOCATION>, at June Jam VIII. Festivities will include having the <ORGANIZATION> Alabama </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Symphony </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Orchestra </ORGANIZATION> join the band on stage to perform its hit `` My Home's in <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION>.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Lily </PERSON> <PERSON> Tomlin </PERSON>, whose humor is as sly as <PERSON> Bette </PERSON> <PERSON> Midler </PERSON>'s is raucous, says she and <PERSON> Midler </PERSON>, her co-star in the newly released comedy `` Big Business,'' have a `` similar heart'' despite their differences. The two comedians pointed out their contrasting acting styles in this week's People magazine. `` I immerse myself totally in the character and prepare everything before hand,'' said <PERSON> Tomlin </PERSON>, 47. `` I do n't like to think too much,'' said the 42-year-old <PERSON> Midler </PERSON>. In `` Big Business,'' the actresses play two sets of identical twins who were mixed up at birth by a shortsighted nurse. <PERSON> Tomlin </PERSON> says of her opposite number, `` Obviously she's a fantastic performer. But there's a lot more to <PERSON> Bette </PERSON> than the Divine Miss M. There's this tenderness and frailty and a wonderful kind of dearness that's truly touching.'' She adds, `` There is something about us that has a similar center, a similar heart. We're both kind of outrageous but with a down-to-earth core. I like <PERSON> Bette </PERSON> tremendously because she's out there, bawdy, then sweet and real.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>FRUITLAND, Utah (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Nearly 2,000 people brought their motorcycles, motor homes and pickups to a three-day rock revival featuring the New Riders of the Purple Sage, <ORGANIZATION> Big </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Brother </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; The <ORGANIZATION> Holding </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Company </ORGANIZATION>, Canned Heat, <ORGANIZATION> Spirit </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Black </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Oak </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Arkansas </ORGANIZATION>. The festival, dubbed The Boondock Bikers Bash, started Friday in a remote cow pasture near this tiny eastern <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION> town. Law enforcement officials had braced for potential problems, but most of those in attendance seemed content to listen to the music and make an occasional sojourn into neighboring towns. `` We're not here to prove anything to anybody,'' insisted <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> of the sponsoring group, <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bikers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aiming </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Toward </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Education </ORGANIZATION>, which opposes mandatory motorcycle helmet laws. `` But I think the public would be surprised by what they'd see here,'' he said. `` I think they'd see that we're no different than any other diverse group of people _ cowboys, Mormons or whoever.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880613-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-13-88 0016EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--Japan-Circus     06-13 0169</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Japan-Circus,0173</SECOND>
<HEAD>Ringling Elephants Arrive For Circus</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Ending a trans-Pacific boat ride, 16 bleary-eyed performing pachyderms were greeted at a <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION> pier by confetti-tossing Shinto priests. Cranes at <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION> unloaded the <LOCATION> Ringling </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bros. </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Barnum </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> Bailey </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Circus </ORGANIZATION> performers on Sunday from a cargo ship that left <LOCATION> Oakland </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>. June 1 The elephants, whose weight ranges up to 14,000 pounds, dutifully lined up for photographers. One youngster executed a polite bow. A pair of Shinto priests in ceremonial caps and robes waved twigs at the pachyderms and threw confetti across their trunks, a slight departure from traditional purification rites. The ritual also bestowed hopes for success and safety for the circus' 15-week tour of <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>. Ringling's lions, horses, camels, llamas and chimpanzees arrived earlier to meet quarantine requirements. A circus official said humans and elephants were the only animals Japanese authorities exempted. The elephants continue on to the northern city of <LOCATION> Sapporo </LOCATION>, where the American circus opens its first overseas tour on July 1.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880613-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-13-88 0024EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-MadamMao     06-13 0220</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Madam Mao,0225</SECOND>
<HEAD>China Says Jiang Qing Still in Prison, Not In Villa</HEAD>
<DATELINE>HONG KONG (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Jiang </PERSON> <PERSON> Qing </PERSON>, the ailing widow of the late Communist Chinese leader <PERSON> Mao </PERSON> <PERSON> Tse-tung </PERSON> and a key figure in the tumultuous Cultural Revolution, is still in prison and not living in a villa, an official Chinese report said. The <ORGANIZATION> China </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>, in a dispatch published in <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> newspapers on Sunday, said a spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> had denied unconfirmed press reports that the 74-year-old <PERSON> Jiang </PERSON> was released from jail, where she is serving a life sentence, and lives with her daughter in a villa in a <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> suburb. The <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> spokesman said <PERSON> Jiang </PERSON> is receiving special medical care in jail, the <ORGANIZATION> China </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> reported. Chinese officials said earlier this year that <PERSON> Jiang </PERSON> was suffering from an unidentified `` geriatric disease.'' Recent unconfirmed reports have said she is suffering from throat cancer but had refused treatment because it would leave her voiceless. <PERSON> Jiang </PERSON> was a member of the notorious `` Gang of Four,'' who were accused of ordering illegal arrests during the 1966-76 Cultural Revolution and trying to seize power in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> after <PERSON> Mao </PERSON> died in 1976. Members of the gang were convicted in 1981 and <PERSON> Jiang </PERSON> was sentenced to death, but the sentence was commuted to life imprisonment in 1983.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880613-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-13-88 0024EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-DogGone     06-13 0281</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Dog Gone,0290</SECOND>
<HEAD>`Here, Puli. Here, Boy. Puli? PULI?'</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto SE1 of June 12</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MEDINA, Wash. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Puli </LOCATION> is a well-behaved Hungarian sheepdog that spends most of his time lying in front of a fireplace, never jumps on the furniture and never makes any noise. <LOCATION> Puli </LOCATION> has been dead four years. But his owners, <PERSON> Suzanne </PERSON> and <PERSON> Rob </PERSON> <PERSON> Fleming </PERSON>, continue to enjoy their preserved dog. `` It's sort of like <LOCATION> Puli </LOCATION> is still alive because of all the laughs he gets,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Fleming </PERSON> said. The Flemings once left the fluffy white dog in the back seat of their car while they went sailing. Upon returning, they asked a friend to let the dog out. `` <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> kept whistling, ` Come here, boy,' took a closer look and said, ` Uh, <PERSON> Rob </PERSON>, I think you might have left your dog in the car too long. He's not moving.' We were in tears we were laughing so hard,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Fleming </PERSON> said. The <ORGANIZATION> Flemings </ORGANIZATION>' teen-age daughter had a different reaction when she learned her parents had decided to have the family pet freeze-dried instead of buried. The dog was diagnosed with spinal cancer and the <ORGANIZATION> Flemings </ORGANIZATION> had him put to sleep in 1984. Mrs. <PERSON> Fleming </PERSON> understood her daughter's fury. `` I mean, how do you tell your friends that your parents are having -LRB- the family -RRB- dog freeze-dried?'' she asked. For $ 650 a taxidermist in <LOCATION> Portland </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ore. </LOCATION>, posed the dog lying on its side with head up and looking alert. The dog weighs about 10 pounds and needs only occasional cleaning with acetone. The Flemings say they made the right decision, and enjoy having their dog around the house. `` He was like a child to us,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Fleming </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880613-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-13-88 0026EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-MysteriousKabul Bjt   06-13 0792</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Mysterious Kabul, Bjt,0817</SECOND>
<HEAD>A City With A Bustling Free Market, Run By Besieged Communists</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By EARLEEN FISHER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>KABUL, Afghanistan (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 When the dust storms come, <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION> vanishes from sight behind a white cloud that grittily obscures all sense of what is and is not real. Then the winds die down, and the dust suspended in the air drifts to the ground. The sun breaks through and the city of mud brick houses and 2 million people shimmers back into view. It's a bit like stepping into a magic spell and visiting `` Brigadoon,'' the Scottish Highlands town in the Broadway musical that appears for a day once every hundred years before fading away into the mist again. <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION> has that same sense. The distinction between reality and fantasy blurs. The Afghan capital is at once communist and capitalist. The government of the <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Afghanistan </ORGANIZATION> is one of the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>'s most successful attempts to impose communist rule on a Moslem nation. But here, the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has entered the fray by supporting and helping arm the anti-communist guerrillas who are fighting Afghan and Soviet soldiers. And in spite of the Soviet-style government, <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION> is a capitalist city. Dollars are avidly sought by merchants who sell everything from century-old handwoven Afghan carpets to gaudy lace stockings from <LOCATION> Far </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> sweatshops. <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION> is a city full of life and, increasingly, of death. Teen-age girls strive for the latest styles as their tailors stitch government-issue blue cotton into school uniforms patterned on the skirts and jackets shown in European fashion magazines. The markets bustle with more traditionally clad women wearing the `` chadri,'' an all-enveloping veil that descends in pleats from a skullcap with only a coarse mesh panel over the eyes to let the wearer see out. Small boys in pajama-like tunics and pants turn cartwheels in grassy traffic circles, dodging sprays of water from tanker trucks that keep the geraniums blossoming. At night, streets are virtually deserted. The rare motorist is suddenly stopped by an Afghan soldier who emerges from the gloom to wave his rifle and check the traveler's identity. Soviet soldiers have started withdrawing from other cities as part of a pullout the <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION> says will by Feb. 15 end its eight-year military intervention. But they still surround <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION> with a ring of tanks, armored personnel carriers and fortified bunkers. Guerrilla rockets hit <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION> several times a week, usually at night. Often they land near <LOCATION> Afghan </LOCATION> and Soviet military posts, but rockets are notoriously inaccurate and many of the casualties are civilians asleep in their homes. One of these victims was carried into a hospital X-ray room a few days ago. The white-haired man lay unconscious on a narrow bed of ropes woven across a wooden frame. His right eye was closed, his left concealed by a bloody bandage. Blood stains covered the shoulders of his brown tunic, and one leg lay at an improbable angle under a red plaid blanket. He had been brought to the hospital, bed and all, by three men wearing turbans, baggy trousers and layers of robes. The old man lived, according to a hospital staff member who said such victims arrive almost every morning. But the staffer refused to give specific numbers, reflecting a reluctance to make statements not authorized by the government. Death is tangible at <LOCATION> Tapa-e-Shuhadan </LOCATION>, `` the Hill of the Martyrs,'' <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION>'s cemetery for government troops who have died in the decade of fighting the mujahedeen, or Moslem holy warriors. <PERSON> Tapa-e-Shuhadan </PERSON> is off-limits much of the time, even to mourners, for it is in a military zone. A visit to the hill quickly reveals the reason: <PERSON> Tapa-e-Shuhadan </PERSON> sits atop a huge ammunition dump, evident from the concrete doorways and little ventilation chimneys built into the slopes below the graves. The members of the Peace, <ORGANIZATION> Solidarity </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Friendship </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> who escort foreign visitors to the cemtery were at a loss to say how many men are buried there. But a rough reckoning, achieved by counting graves in one quadrant and extrapolating, made 10,000 seem a conservative estimate. These escorted visits add to the blurring of reality and unreality in <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION>. But there are other encounters that seem genuine, like the one with a man in a crocheted white skullcap who declared himself a `` mujahed,'' one of those seeking to oust the government. He spat on the ground to express his contempt for the Afghan government, communism and the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. Speaking in Arabic he said he had learned from the Koran, Islam's holy book, and from three pilgrimmages to <LOCATION> Mecca </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Saudi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arabia </LOCATION> _ one of the countries arming the mujahedeen, he said: `` God willing, the brotherhood of Moslems will see victory in <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880613-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-13-88 0034EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-AIDS-Children     06-13 0597</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AIDS-Children,0617</SECOND>
<HEAD>Drug Raises IQ Of AIDS-afflicted Children, Report Says</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-AIDS Conference, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DANIEL Q. HANEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Science Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>STOCKHOLM (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A drug widely used to treat adults with AIDS appears to dramatically reverse the devastating effects of the disease on the brains of children, new research shows. The AIDS virus frequently robs young victims of their ability to talk and walk and lowers their intelligence. The latest research shows that the drug AZT seems to bring back children's speech as well as other functions controlled by the brain. `` Functional ability returned to normal in many kids,'' said Dr. <PERSON> Philip </PERSON> <PERSON> Pizzo </PERSON>, who directed the study at the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cancer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION>. His research was presented Sunday at the opening of the Fourth International Conference on AIDS. AZT, also known as zidovudine or Retrovir, is the only medicine routinely used to suppress the AIDS virus, called HIV. In adults, it can slow the progression of Acquired Immune Deficiency Syndrome but does not cure it. <PERSON> Pizzo </PERSON>'s findings were made unexpectedly during the testing of a portable pump to administer the drug to children. He found that among other changes, the youngsters' IQ scores rose about 15 points after they got the medicine. `` Everybody who looks at this data has to get excited,'' said Dr. <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Hoth </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Allergy </ORGANIZATION> and Infectious Diseases. `` We are all nervous by small numbers -LRB- of patients studied -RRB-, but the data itself is very exciting.'' Dr. <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Hirsch </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> Massachusetts </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> also cautioned that the preliminary study did not include a comparison group. `` It's intriguing,'' he said of the results. `` I would have liked to have seen a control group who were not treated.'' <PERSON> Pizzo </PERSON> tested AZT on 21 AIDS-infected children who ranged in age from 14 months to 12 years. About two-thirds got the virus from blood products, while the rest were infected by their mothers before birth. <PERSON> Pizzo </PERSON> said that 62 percent of the patients had suffered clear neurological damage from the virus, and `` in every case they were improved'' after taking AZT. The IQs of those who had obvious brain impairment rose from about 70 to 85. Among those who were judged to be mentally normal when the study began, the IQs improved from about 95 to 105, suggesting that they had probably already suffered subtle mental injury from the infection. <PERSON> Pizzo </PERSON> said the youngsters' continued to improve steadily nine months after the treatment started. Brain scans also showed that missing tissue seemed to be restored in the infected youngsters' brains. <PERSON> Pizzo </PERSON> speculated that cells that had been shrunken by the virus were restored to their normal size. He cautioned that further study will be necessary to learn how long the improvement lasts and whether the children eventually worsen again. In a separate study, Dr. <PERSON> Catherine </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilfert </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> Duke </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Durham </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.C. </LOCATION>, described a preliminary three-month study of the drug's safety in children. She said the work shows that youngsters tolerate the treatment well, and while it's too soon to draw firm conclusions, `` our feeling is that the number of opportunistic infections is substantially reduced.'' Research by Dr. <PERSON> Maxime </PERSON> <PERSON> Seligmann </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> Hopital </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Saint-Louis </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> suggests that combining AZT with the herpes drug acyclovir significantly improves its effectiveness in people with AIDS. In four months of testing on 130 patients, there were 25 deaths among patients who got AZT alone, compared with 11 among people who got both drugs. `` These preliminary data suggest that acyclovir may have additional benefit without additional toxicity in patients with full-blown AIDS,'' <PERSON> Seligmann </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880613-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-13-88 0049EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-BlairHouse Bjt   06-13 0763</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Blair House, Bjt,750</SECOND>
<HEAD>After A $13 Million Facelift, Blair House Now Fit For A King</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By EILEEN PUTMAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The president's guest house is meant to be fit for a king, but when explosive gas leaked in and a chandelier crashed onto the bed where visiting heads of state sleep, some work was clearly in order. Six years and $ 13 million later, <ORGANIZATION> Blair </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> is now a `` guest house worthy of this great nation,'' says Ambassador <PERSON> Selwa </PERSON> <PERSON> Roosevelt </PERSON>, the chief of protocol, who oversaw the restoration. <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> could n't stay there last December for his summit with President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> because the house was closed for repairs. But should he return this year he would find a new wing, renovated kitchen, plumbing, fire and safety systems, new electrical heating and air conditioning. Not a palace, perhaps, but not the dilapidated antique it was in June 1982. Then the house was judged uninhabitable after gas leaked into the boiler room and a chandelier fell on the bed, fortunately then unoccupied. `` We all realized that the house was in very bad shape. All you had to do was look at it,'' says Mrs. <PERSON> Roosevelt </PERSON>. `` It had a veneer of looking all right because it had a certain warmth and all of that. But the minute you started looking, the rugs were threadbare, the steps were sagging. The plumbing was unbelievable. The kitchens were like kitchens at the turn of the century.'' <ORGANIZATION> Blair </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> actually predates the turn of the century, and it is an architectural gem rich in history. It consists of four connecting buildings across from the White House on <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Avenue </LOCATION> and around the corner on Jackson Place. The original house dates from 1824 and was long owned by <PERSON> Francis </PERSON> <PERSON> Preston </PERSON> <PERSON> Blair </PERSON>, a member of the powerful, intimate group around President <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> that was called the `` kitchen cabinet.'' Later, the house was a meeting place for leaders on both sides of the conflict that became the Civil War. In a small room to the right of the front door, Col. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> was offered the command of the Union Armies and declined in favor of his native Commonwealth of <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>. President <PERSON> Roosevelt </PERSON> approved the acquisition of the house in 1942, saying the government needed it `` for the entertainment of distinguished visitors.'' On Nov. 1, 1950, an assassination attempt was made on President <PERSON> Truman </PERSON> at <ORGANIZATION> Blair </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> by two Puerto Rican nationalists who attempted to force their way in. The attempt failed, and one of the nationalists was killed. <PERSON> Leslie </PERSON> <PERSON> Coffelt </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> guard, died in preventing the assailants from gaining entrance, and a plaque outside the house commemorates his heroism. In more recent times, columnist <PERSON> Diana </PERSON> <PERSON> McLellan </PERSON> got into hot water in 1981 when, writing her column for <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION>, she carried an item that then-President <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> had `` bugged'' Blair House where President-elect <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> was staying before the inaugural. The Post retracted the item after <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> threatened to sue for libel. When the <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> decided in 1982 that <ORGANIZATION> Blair </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> was so dilapidated it was dangerous, the agency said millions of dollars were needed to repair the structure. `` The alternative was to tear it down. There was nothing in between,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Roosevelt </PERSON> said. <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> appropriated $ 8.6 million, and another $ 4.8 million was raised from private sources to pay for the project. Mrs. <PERSON> Roosevelt </PERSON> hopes to have more than $ 1 million left for a fund to maintain the house. There has been little skimping in the refurbishing. The collection of antiques has been expanded, many of them donated along with china, silver and fabrics. The room where visiting heads of state receive the press is an uncommonly elegant pressroom with its two fireplaces, blue damask upholstery, red serabend rugs and view of the White House across <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Avenue </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> sees the house as one of its diplomatic assets. Secretary of State <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> has said the `` feelings of being truly welcome, which staying at the presidential guest house foster, can tip the balance in our favor with many nations where personal relationships are vitally important.'' `` When people feel well-treated and warmly treated, this makes it much easier,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Roosevelt </PERSON> says. She believes the <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> people can be proud of the house, which she says is neither ostentatious nor `` plebian.'' `` They do n't want pretensions because the <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> people are n't that way This house sort of straddles a very nice line. It's not too grand, but it has elegance,'' she says. `` It's really just the right degree of grandness.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880613-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-13-88 0049EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Stalker Bjt   06-13 0779</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Stalker, Bjt,770</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHINGTON WIRE: British Cop Describes Frame Over Northern Ireland
Probe</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RUTH SINAI</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 British police have a new expression in their vocabulary. `` He's been Stalkered,'' they say, meaning, `` He's been framed.'' The term also has become synonymous with abuse of power by British authorities in <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION>. For instance, when policemen shot and killed three unarmed guerrillas of the <ORGANIZATION> Irish </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> in the British colony of <LOCATION> Gibraltar </LOCATION> in March, the media raised the specter of another `` Stalker Affair.'' The man whose gave rise to such expressions is <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Stalker </PERSON>, a former detective with <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s national police agency who has written a book about his official inquiry into suspicions that the police in <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION> had a `` shoot to kill'' policy toward suspected guerrillas of the outlawed <ORGANIZATION> IRA </ORGANIZATION>. `` The Stalker Affair,'' which chronicles Stalker's investigation of the Royal Ulster Constabulary -LRB- RUC -RRB- and his subsequent downfall, has swiftly risen to the top of <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>'s best-seller charts and was published in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> in May. It will be published in paperback in <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> this fall. Stalker, tall and lean, was in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> recently to promote his book. `` The book has become a handle to attach to the issue of the accountability of police and security services in <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION>,'' he said in an interview. With unassuming calm, Stalker discussed the furor his book has stirred in <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION> and the embarrassment it caused the government of <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> by describing clumsy handling of the tensions between majority Protestants and minority <PERSON> Roman </PERSON> <PERSON> Catholics </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION>. Aptly named, <PERSON> Stalker </PERSON> made his career hunting moors murderers, thieves and prostitutes. In 1984 he was asked to investigate the <ORGANIZATION> RUC </ORGANIZATION> after one of its members reported that fellow officers had lied in court about the 1982 shooting deaths of six suspected <ORGANIZATION> IRA </ORGANIZATION> guerrillas. The six were unarmed. `` The circumstances of those shootings pointed to a police inclination, if not a policy, to shoot suspects dead without warning rather than to arrest them,'' Stalker wrote. His investigation took a bizarre twist when, on the verge of obtaining a secret tape to prove his suspicions, Stalker was pulled off the case and suspended from the force. Over the next three months, in the summer of 1986, he endured a humiliating and much publicized investigation into what now appear to have been trumped-up charges. Stalker was accused of consorting with a suspected criminal and of impropriety in the use of police cars. A police board subsequently exonerated him and he was reinstated as the deputy chief of the <LOCATION> Manchester </LOCATION> police _ <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s second-largest urban police force. He resigned seven months later, saying his commander did not want him on the force. In an interim report, Stalker had recommended that 11 police officers be prosected for perjury and conspiracy to pervert the course of justice by lying under oath about the <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION> shooting incidents. The government has since said that although `` serious criminal breaches'' were found in the affair, prosecution of the 11 would damage security and would not be in the public interest. In the course of his probe, Stalker discovered the existence of a tape which recorded events in the hayshed where one of the six victims, <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Justin </PERSON> <PERSON> Tighe </PERSON>, 17, was shot dead. Stalker was told by informants that the tape would prove <PERSON> Tighe </PERSON> had been killed without warning. Stalker battled for months to get the tape of the electronic surveillance of the hayshed, which was believed to be an arms depot for the <ORGANIZATION> IRA </ORGANIZATION>. About to get the tape, Stalker was called off the investigation. `` The decision that resulted in my removal was, I think, a political one,'' he wrote. `` My interim report was read with anger and fear at senior levels within the <ORGANIZATION> RUC </ORGANIZATION>,'' he said. The investigation also disturbed the delicate balance between Catholics and Protestants in the volatile province. `` The <ORGANIZATION> RUC </ORGANIZATION> has tried very hard to shed its sectarian image'' as a predominantly <ORGANIZATION> Protestant </ORGANIZATION> force, but the investigation was `` a setback,'' Stalker wrote. Stalker said he decided to write the book `` as a purge for me and my family'' after the harrowing experience they underwent. Stalker said he felt partly vindicated by a government announcement that changes had been made in the <ORGANIZATION> RUC </ORGANIZATION> regarding the accountability of its anti-terrorism squads, based on his report. Now, he added with resignation, he wants to get on with his new career in journalism. `` There is no one I can sue, no one I can name,'' he said. `` I am just another casualty of the political situation in <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION>.''
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Ruth </PERSON> <PERSON> Sinai </PERSON> covers international affairs for <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880613-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-13-88 0053EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-SloppySurvey     06-13 0536</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Sloppy Survey,0555</SECOND>
<HEAD>Newington Tries To Solve Problem Of Poorly Surveyed Subdivision</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DEAN GOLEMBESKI</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEWINGTON, Conn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Residents of a subdivision have mowed each other's lawns for years but they never knew it until a surveyor's error was recently discovered and showed that all 104 lots were improperly plotted. Due to the surveyor's miscalculation more than a decade ago when the <LOCATION> Little </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Brook </LOCATION> subdivision was laid out, none of the lots in the subdivision of the <LOCATION> Hartford </LOCATION> suburb was correctly mapped out, officials said. For example, while one homeowner may have built a fence on what appears to be his lot, it technically sits on his neighbor's property Early indications are that some the boundaries are off as much as 3 feet, said Town Manager <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Connolly </PERSON>. The error was discovered during the construction of an adjacent condominium project. `` The acreage is right, it's just not where you think it is,'' <PERSON> Connolly </PERSON> said last week. All the houses, which range in value from $ 200,000 to $ 300,000, and built-in swimming pools appear to be on their proper lots. But shrubs, fences and sidewalks are n't. Town officials have intervened because of the number of homeowners involved and because the town's right-of-way, which includes the sidewalks, may have to be moved. As a first step, the town appropriated $ 17,500 to resurvey the subdivision, and the results are expected in August. `` We're preparing a map showing all the trees and all the fences,'' <PERSON> Connolly </PERSON> said. Once they have the map in hand, officials will try to sort out the problem. Officials say they might just leave everything as it is and file new deeds, or they might make everything conform to existing deeds. <PERSON> Connolly </PERSON> said that because of legal obligations, such as mortgage agreements, things ca n't be left alone. Both solutions undoubtedly will prove difficult and involve banks, title insurance companies, attorneys and lots of paperwork. `` We do n't know which is more practical, which is more economical. It can get ticklish if you move boundaries,'' <PERSON> Connolly </PERSON> said. `` You're talking about a community effort.'' So far, <LOCATION> Little </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Brook </LOCATION> residents have cooperated and have reacted calmly to the situtation. `` Obviously, people are nervous about it. I call it a sleeping-dog issue,'' said <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Harpie </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Little </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Brook </LOCATION> resident and town councilman. `` No one wants to be the first to draw their gun. I'm hopeful that once the town determines its right-of-way, the neighbors will work something out.'' One resident, who spoke on condition of anonymity, said some neighbors are willing to rewrite deeds, if necessary, to conform to what exists. But, two are fighting over the location of a fence that may have to come down. <PERSON> Vinny </PERSON> <PERSON> Hayes </PERSON>, another subdivision resident, laughed about the situation. `` It's unfortunate,'' he said, `` the city is going to spend a lot of money resurveying.'' <PERSON> Hayes </PERSON> became serious only when talking about the possible expense of refiling his deed. The surveyor, <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Peters </PERSON> of W.E. Peters Land Surveyors, is dead. A developer of the subdivision said his company has no stake in the matter. `` The ironic part is that if there was n't additional development going on -LRB- in <LOCATION> Newington </LOCATION> -RRB- it would never have been picked up,'' <PERSON> Connolly </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880613-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-13-88 0057EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-SoftballNameGame Bjt   06-13 0517</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Softball Name Game, Bjt,510</SECOND>
<HEAD>It's the `Gramm Slammers' vs the `Hot D'Amatos' in Congressional
Softball</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JEFF BARKER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Each summer, members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and their staffs get to sum up their identities in two or three words. They do this by naming their softball teams. Some of the titles are revealing. Sen. <PERSON> Strom </PERSON> <PERSON> Thurmond </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-S.C. </LOCATION>, calls his team `` <PERSON> Strom </PERSON>'s Right Swingers.'' The squad fielded by Sen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Heinz </PERSON>, R-Pa., is the `` Buy Americans. In all, there are about 320 teams in three congressional leagues. Many of the team titles are derived from lawmakers' names. There is the `` Boren To Run'' of Sen. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Boren </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Okla </LOCATION>.; the `` Hot D'Amatos'' of Sen. <PERSON> Alfonse </PERSON> <PERSON> D'Amato </PERSON>, R-N. Y; the `` Dollar Bills'' of Sen. <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.J. </LOCATION>; the `` Bumpers Stickers'' of Sen. <PERSON> Dale </PERSON> <PERSON> Bumpers </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Ark </LOCATION>; the `` Graham Crackers'' of Sen. <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Graham </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Fla </LOCATION>.; the `` Gramm Slammers'' of Sen. <PERSON> Phil </PERSON> <PERSON> Gramm </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Texas </LOCATION>; and `` Arlen's <PERSON> Darlin </PERSON>'s'' of Sen. <PERSON> Arlen </PERSON> <PERSON> Specter </PERSON>, R-Pa. On the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> side, Rep. <PERSON> Phil </PERSON> <PERSON> Crane </PERSON>, R-Ill., heads the `` Whooping Cranes;'' Rep. <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Wheat </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Mo </LOCATION>., captains the `` Wheat Germs;'' Rep. <PERSON> Claude </PERSON> <PERSON> Pepper </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Fla </LOCATION>., is the inspiration for the `` Hot Peppers;'' and Rep. <PERSON> Barney </PERSON> <PERSON> Frank </PERSON>, D-Mass., is The `` Penny Pinchers'' are named after Rep. <PERSON> Timothy </PERSON> <PERSON> Penny </PERSON>, D-Minn.; and `` <PERSON> Dingell </PERSON>'s Dingbats'' are derived from Rep. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Dingell </PERSON>, D-Mich The team of Rep. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Oberstar </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Minn </LOCATION>., is the `` Minnesota Knee-Jerk Liberals. While many of the teams are manned by congressional staffers, the leagues are notoriously loose on who can play. `` We let lobbyists and trade associations in,'' said <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Caruso </PERSON>, commissioner of the 200-team <ORGANIZATION> Congressional </ORGANIZATION> `` B'' League, which neither uses umpires nor calls balls and strikes. `` Sometimes we have to stretch it to, ` If you pay taxes, you're in,''' <PERSON> Caruso </PERSON> said `` We're the ` B' League _ beer-drinking league.'' A congressional `` A'' league has about 40 teams, while a third league fields about 80 more and consists mainly of <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> staffers. Former members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, and even the staffs of former presidents, are welcome. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON>, a former <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> congressman from <LOCATION> Staten </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION>, still has a team called the `` <LOCATION> Staten </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> Ferries,'' according to <PERSON> Caruso </PERSON>. A team of former staff members of the presidential administration of <PERSON> Gerald </PERSON> <PERSON> Ford </PERSON> is the `` Outhouse Gang.'' Committees and agencies also field teams. The House Select Committee on Aging is the `` Silver Streaks.'' The <LOCATION> Export-Import </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> is the `` Debt Busters.'' Some names have stories attached. Sen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Ohio </LOCATION>, fields a team called `` The Right Stuff,'' which was the title of a best-selling book and movie about <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON> and other early astronauts. The `` Greatest Hits'' of Rep. <PERSON> Chet </PERSON> <PERSON> Atkins </PERSON>, D-Mass., is derived from the congressman's country guitarist namesake The team of Rep. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Andrews </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Texas </LOCATION>, is the `` No Ways, No Means,'' reflecting his membership on the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ways </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Means </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>. Some team members want to change the name to `` Ways, But No Means.'' But some names are incomprehensible, at least to outsiders. `` There's one team called ` Shoot The Wounded,''' said <PERSON> Vince </PERSON> <PERSON> Morelli </PERSON>, a commissioner of the `` A'' league. `` I have no reason to understand that one.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880613-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-13-88 0102EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-TaxIncrease Bjt   06-13 0810</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Tax Increase, Bjt,750</SECOND>
<HEAD>Medicare Benefits Bill Contains Tax-Increase Surprise</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JIM LUTHER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Tax Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The politicians taking credit for passage of a new program to protect the elderly from the financial ravages of catastrophic illness have been less eager to acknowledge that it also means a major tax increase for millions of older Americans. Those who benefit from the legislation now awaiting President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s signature would pay the entire cost _ at least for the near future. <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> itself estimates the average tax increase will be $ 285 per person in 1989 and $ 506 in 1993. Sponsors of the bill, however, are reluctant to use the term `` tax increase'' in public discussions of the bill. Rep. <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Rostenkowski </PERSON>, D-Ill., chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ways </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Means </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, repeatedly referred to it as `` a new income-related premium. For many Medicare recipients, the increase would more than wipe out what they gained when the tax system was overhauled in 1986. The tax increase would start at 15 percent next year, jump to 25 percent in 1990 and then rise by as much as one percentage point a year thereafter, conceivably reaching 35 percent by the end of the century. This tax increase would pay for about two-thirds of the cost of protecting <ORGANIZATION> Medicare </ORGANIZATION> recipients against catastrophic hospital, physician and drug expenses; the program would cost an estimated $ 33 billion over the next five years alone. The remainder of the cost would be covered by raising the monthly Part B premium paid by recipients for doctors' services. `` We have not asked our children to pay the medical bills that we incur,'' said Rep. <PERSON> J.J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Pickle </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Texas </LOCATION>. `` These benefits will be paid for by the men and women who will use the coverage.'' But even some members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> who voted for the bill worried aloud that as the tax burden on the elderly grows, pressure will mount to have other taxpayers share the cost. The compromise bill cleared by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> last week is considerably more generous than the version recommended by <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>. Nevertheless, there is no indication that the president will veto it, even with the tax increase. Backers of the bill acknowledge that no more than 7 percent of the elderly and disabled who are eligible for Medicare would benefit from the bill, even though all will have to pay the Part B increase and many will face the new tax. Sen. <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Texas </LOCATION>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Finance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, compared the bill to fire insurance. `` Not everybody is going to have a catastrophic illness and not everybody wants to have a fire either,'' <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> said, `` but what you are paying is an insurance premium that takes the law of averages and applies it to the individual, with the fervent hope that the vast majority never have the need to use this benefit.'' Negotiators who wrote the final version of the bill decided that paying for the expansion solely by raising the Part B premium would have made it prohibitively expensive for lower-income people. The final compromise, said Sen. <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>, R-Kan., `` takes into consideration an individual's ability to pay for this protection and in doing so allows this coverage to be more affordable for low-income beneficiaries. The bill includes several restrictions on how the tax would be applied: _ It would hit only those people eligible for Medicare -LRB- generally age 65 or older or disabled -RRB- whose incomes are high enough that they already pay at least $ 150 income tax Typically, a couple over 65 with adjusted gross income of $ 11,000 or less would not be subject to the increase. Congressional staffers estimate that in 1989, about 40 percent of Americans over the age of 65 would have to pay the tax increase. A private organization, the <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> on </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> the </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Economics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Taxation </ORGANIZATION>, estimates 46 percent next year and 56 percent by 1993. _ The maximum tax would be $ 800 per person in 1989 -LRB- $ 1,600 for a couple if both spouses are eligible for <ORGANIZATION> Medicare </ORGANIZATION> -RRB-, rising to $ 1,050 -LRB- $ 2,100 per couple -RRB- in 1993 _ The tax will be at a rate of $ 22.50 for each $ 150 of regular income-tax liability in 1989; by 1993, $ 42 per $ 150 of liability According to the <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION>, a couple with $ 21,000 adjusted gross income and taking the standard deduction would face a tax increase of $ 236 in 1989 and $ 441 in 1993. At $ 31,500 income, the increase would be $ 473 next year and $ 882 in 1993. On the average, taxpayers with incomes between $ 20,000 and $ 30,000 were given a $ 220 tax cut in the 1986 tax overhaul; those between $ 30,000 and $ 40,000 averaged $ 273. The increase in the monthly Part B premium required by the bill would be the same regardless of income. In 1989, the $ 27.10 premium would rise to $ 31.10, and by 1993 would be $ 42.60 a month.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880613-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-13-88 0104EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Democrats-Platform Bjt   06-13 0667</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Democrats-Platform, Bjt,640</SECOND>
<HEAD>Splits Over Taxes, Defense, But Jackson Prevails On South Africa</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CHRISTOPHER CONNELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MACKINAC ISLAND, Mich. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The forces of <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> are still miles apart on taxes, defense and many foreign policy issues. But a preliminary platform-drafting session ended with <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> getting one wish: that the Democrats brand <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> a terrorist state. The platform writers boarded this island's horse-drawn taxis and headed home Sunday after three days of deliberations that produced working papers on health, education, civil rights and other issues. The papers were generated by committee staff working with surrogates of <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>. The papers on defense and foreign policy have yet to be written, and on taxes `` we agreed to disagree,'' said <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Barnes </PERSON>, a former <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION> congressman leading <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>'s platform team. The 16-member drafting committee left without casting any votes, but will meet again sometime before the full 186-member <ORGANIZATION> Platform </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> convenes in <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION> June 25-26. The Jackson forces encountered little opposition on the <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> issue, although earlier in the campaign, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> balked when <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> tried to extract such a pledge from him. `` We have no problem declaring <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> a terrorist state, but let's go beyond that,'' said Rep. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Matsui </PERSON>, a <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> backer from <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>. The <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> governor, the certain nominee, favors passage of the tough sanctions in a bill that could put the apartheid regime in <LOCATION> Johannesburg </LOCATION> on the same <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> list of terrorist states as <LOCATION> Libya </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>. But the delegates parted company Sunday on another bedrock issue for the <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> campaign: whether to freeze <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> spending. Two labor leaders rose to the defense of the defense budget and nuclear deterrence. <PERSON> Rachelle </PERSON> <PERSON> Horowitz </PERSON>, political director of the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Teachers </ORGANIZATION>, said the Democrats must root out <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> waste, but also `` honor our treaty obligations and defend democratic institutions and our freedoms.'' `` I hope this platform will call for a stable defense budget,'' she said. `` The defense budget is not a sacred cow,'' retorted <PERSON> Leslie </PERSON> <PERSON> McLemore </PERSON>, a <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> backer from <ORGANIZATION> Jackson </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION>. Later, when <PERSON> McLemore </PERSON> urged the party to forswear first use of nuclear weapons, <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Booe </PERSON>, secretary-treasurer of the <ORGANIZATION> Communications </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Workers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION>, said 40 years of bargaining has taught him never to tell `` any adversary for sure I'm not going to do anything. ... I want to keep them off balance.'' The Democrats' working papers call for appointment of a federal drug czar, an Equal Rights Amendment, ending homelessness, expanding AIDS research, and providing advance notice of plant closings. Without using the word abortion, the civil rights paper calls for `` freedom of reproductive choice ... regardless of ability to pay.'' `` I found more areas of agreement than disagreement,'' said Rep. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Gray </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION>, the drafting panel chair. Those who hoped for divisive bloodletting `` will find the floor is clean,'' said <PERSON> Eleanor </PERSON> <PERSON> Holmes </PERSON> <PERSON> Norton </PERSON>, <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s platform chief. She predicted it will be easier to reach an accord on defense than on taxes. `` If by ` stable' they mean something close to what we mean by ` freeze,' then perhaps there's room for compromise,'' <PERSON> Norton </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Madeleine </PERSON> <PERSON> Albright </PERSON>, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> foreign policy adviser, said: `` I think you will not see ... ` freeze' in the platform. <PERSON> Janice </PERSON> <PERSON> Thurmond </PERSON>, an <LOCATION> Athens </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ga. </LOCATION>, lawyer, urged that the platform embrace <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s views on self-determination for the Palestinians. <PERSON> Albright </PERSON> told reporters flatly the platform will not contain such language. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Borosage </PERSON>, a senior <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> adviser, said the <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> camp will be insistent on its demand to further tax the rich and freeze defense spending. `` We've got agreements with <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> on commitments for a whole range of domestic programs, but where's the money going to come from?'' he said. <PERSON> Barnes </PERSON>, the <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> platform team leader, was asked if the <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> campaign would relish an opportunity in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> to reject a minority plank favoring a tax hike. `` We're not seeking floor fights,'' he said, adding that <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> has enough delegates `` to take anything he wishes to the convention.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880613-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-13-88 0056EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-CaliforniaQuakes 3rdLd-Writethru a0424 06-13 0798</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-California Quakes, 3rd Ld - Writethru, a0424,0814</SECOND>
<HEAD>Sharp Temblor Hits; Preliminary Estimate 5.3</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: SUBS 3rd graf, `The U.S. ...'' to UPDATE with 5.3 Richter
reading, epicenter near 19884 quake; SUBS 8th graf, ``It was ...'
to include that meteorologist is life-long resident of the area.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>ALUM ROCK, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A strong earthquake startled residents over a 350-mile expanse of Northern and <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> on Sunday night, but authorities said there were no immediate reports of serious damage or injuries. The quake hit at 6:45 p.m. and had a magnitude of 5.1 on the <PERSON> Richter </PERSON> scale, said a spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Seismographic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Stations </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Berkeley </LOCATION>. Its epicenter was on the <LOCATION> Calaveras </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Fault </LOCATION> about 10 miles northeast of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jose </LOCATION> near <LOCATION> Alum </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rock </LOCATION>, said spokesman <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON> <PERSON> Lomax </PERSON>. The <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Geological Survey in <LOCATION> Menlo </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Park </LOCATION> estimated the temblor at 5.3. Geophysicist <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Ellsworth </PERSON> said the earthquake's 5-mile-long center was just north of the epicenter of a 6.2 quake in <LOCATION> Morgan </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION> in 1984, the region's largest temblor in years An earthquake of 5 on the <PERSON> Richter </PERSON> scale is considered capable of causing substantial damage, but authorities said they had no damage reports worse than a few cracked ceilings and a broken water heater and water pipe in nearby <LOCATION> Milpitas </LOCATION>. `` The whole mountain shook,'' said <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> Wong </PERSON>, a maintenance supervisor for the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aviation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> atop 2,571-foot <LOCATION> Mount </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Tamalpais </LOCATION> 10 miles north of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Marin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>. Residents as far south as <LOCATION> Bakersfield </LOCATION> and as far north as <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rosa </LOCATION> flooded authorities and media with calls about the quake. Police and sheriff's spokesmen throughout the <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION> area, the <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Napa </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Sonoma </LOCATION> counties to the north all said they had felt it but were unaware of any damage. `` It lasted longer than they usually do,'' said <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Clara </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> sheriff's Deputy <PERSON> Ray </PERSON> <PERSON> Dominguez </PERSON>. `` It came all of a sudden and then leveled and rolled off.'' `` It was the strongest quake I've felt here in years,'' said meteorologist <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Pechner </PERSON> of radio station <ORGANIZATION> KNBR </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> and a life-long resident of the area. A resident of <LOCATION> Foster </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> on the <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Peninsula </LOCATION> said people ran out into the street after the quake hit. A <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> resident said bottles fell off the shelf in his house and plants were tipped over. <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Trevan </PERSON>, a motorist who was driving over the Golden Gate Bridge, said his car `` jumped a little bit'' during the quake. <ORGANIZATION> Bay </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Area </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rapid </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transit </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pacific </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Railroad </ORGANIZATION> crews slowed trains to check for damage to the tracks, but found none, officials said. <ORGANIZATION> Pacific </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Gas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <ORGANIZATION> Electric </ORGANIZATION> said it had no reports of power outages in the <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jose </LOCATION> area adjacent to the epicenter. The quake was the third reported Sunday in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>. Mild earthquakes jolted <LOCATION> Napa </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Solano </LOCATION> counties in <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> and the inland area of <LOCATION> Southern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> around <LOCATION> Ontario </LOCATION>, but there were no reports of damage or injury. The <LOCATION> Ontario </LOCATION> quake also was felt in the cities of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bernardino </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Fontana </PERSON> and <LOCATION> Riverside </LOCATION>, about 50 miles east of <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>. It struck about 2:20 p.m. PDT, was centered about five miles east-southeast of <LOCATION> Ontario </LOCATION>, and measured 3.4 on the <PERSON> Richter </PERSON> scale, said Hall Daily, a spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Technology </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Pasadena </LOCATION>. The temblor was the second widely felt quake to hit <LOCATION> Southern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> since Friday, when a shaker measuring 5.2 on the <PERSON> Richter </PERSON> scale hit 40 miles northwest of <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> and was felt in much of central and southern <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>. Daily said initial data indicated it was unlikely the Sunday quake was related to the one which struck Friday. The Napa-Solano quake which measured 3.3 on the Richter scale, occurred at 2:44 p.m., the Seismographic Stations at <LOCATION> Berkeley </LOCATION> reported. The epicenter was near <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berryessa </LOCATION>, about 40 miles north of <LOCATION> Berkeley </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Vacaville </LOCATION> police received dozens of calls from residents who were n't sure what the jolt was, said dispatcher <PERSON> Jamie </PERSON> <PERSON> Weishaar </PERSON>. `` Many of the people were confused because it did n't feel like an earthquake. Some people thought it might have been a sonic boom,'' she said. The <PERSON> Richter </PERSON> scale is a measure of ground motion as recorded on seismographs. Every increase of one number means a tenfold increase in the strenth of the shaking. Thus, a reading of 7.5 reflects an earthquake 10 times stronger than one of 6.5. An earthquake of 3.5 on the <PERSON> Richter </PERSON> scale can cause slight damage in the local area, 4 moderate damage, 5 considerable damage, 6 severe damage. A 7 reading is a `` major'' earthquake, capable of widespread heavy damage, and 8 is a `` great'' quake, capable of tremendous damage. The <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> earthquake of 1906, which occurred before the <PERSON> Richter </PERSON> scale was devised, has been estimated at 8.3 on the <PERSON> Richter </PERSON> scale.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880613-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-13-88 0102EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p PM-Poll-PresidentialChoices Bjt   06-13 0720</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Poll-Presidential Choices, Bjt,0737</SECOND>
<HEAD>Poll: Three-Quarters Say Veep's Race, Sex Irrelevant</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GARY LANGER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Most Americans say a vice presidential nominee's race and sex are irrelevant, but some independents and Republicans would hestiate to support a black for the job, a <ORGANIZATION> Media </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> General-Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> poll has found Some Republicans also expressed reluctance about supporting a woman for vice president, the national survey said. Independents did not shy from a woman candidate, and Democrats did not lean away from a black or a woman. The survey also indicated a substantial majority of <LOCATION> Americans </LOCATION> would oppose President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> for a third term if he could run again. Most Republicans favored another <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> term; independents and Democrats did not. The poll also found that 89 percent of <LOCATION> Americans </LOCATION> would not want to be president and a plurality would not want their child to be. Fifty-nine percent thought it possible their child could be president. On the question of vice presidential candidates, 75 percent of the 1,204 respondents said it would not matter to them if a ticket's second slot were filled by a black or a woman. Still, 17 percent of independents said they would be less likely to vote for a ticket with a black for vice president, compared with 4 percent who would be more likely to back it. The division was wider among Republicans, while there was no measurable split among Democrats. The survey did not specify any candidate. Black civil rights activist <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, second-place finisher for the Democratic presidential nomination, has said he should be offered the vice presidential slot. With a woman for vice president, 20 percent of Republicans said they would be less likely to support the ticket, while 6 percent said they would be more likely. There was no such reluctance among Democrats or independents. No potential woman candidate was specified. There have been suggestions that Vice President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, who has locked up the <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> nomination for president, may select a woman to shore up his support among women. Overall, 10 percent of respondents said they would be more likely to support a woman for vice president, 14 percent less likely. That split was within the poll's margin of sampling error of 3 points. Given a black vice presidential candidate, 6 percent overall said they would be more likely to lend their support, 18 percent less likely. The split was wider for the presidency: Five percent said they would be more likely to support a black, 27 percent less likely. Ten percent said they would be more likely to back a woman for president, 25 percent less likely. However, more than six in 10 said it would not matter if a candidate for president were black or female. The poll's finding on <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> indicates a sharp drop with Democrats and independents, whose support was critical to his 1980 and 1984 victories. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> in 1984 won 25 percent of Democrats and 63 percent of independent voters. But in the survey, just 13 percent of Democrats and 27 percent of independents said they would vote for him for a third term. Presidents are limited by Constitutional amendment to two four-year terms, and about 65 percent each of Republicans, Democrats and independents favored maintaining that limit. But if <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> could run again, 60 percent of Republicans said they would vote for him, while 85 percent of Democrats and 67 percent of independents said they would not. The total was 32 percent for <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, 64 percent against. Majorities of conservatives, moderates and liberals alike said they would not want a third <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> term. Women and poorer Americans were more likely to oppose the idea. Respondents overwhelmingly attached importance to the office: Eighty-nine percent said it matters who is elected president. The same percentage said they would not want the job, and 46 percent would not want their child to become president. Forty-one percent would. The Media General-Associated Press poll consisted of telephone interviews April 29-May 8 with a randomly selected sample of 1,204 adults across the nation. <ORGANIZATION> Media </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, a communications company based in <LOCATION> Richmond </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, publishes the Richmond Times-Dispatch, the Richmond News Leader, the Tampa -LRB- <LOCATION> Fla </LOCATION> -RRB-. Tribune and the <LOCATION> Winston-Salem </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> N.C. </LOCATION> -RRB- Journal, and operates TV stations <ORGANIZATION> WXFL </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Tampa </LOCATION>, WCBD in <LOCATION> Charleston </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> S.C. </LOCATION>, and <ORGANIZATION> WJKS </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Jacksonville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880613-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-13-88 0128EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Iran-ContraQ&amp;A     06-13 0913</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Iran-Contra Q&amp;A,0941</SECOND>
<HEAD>Iran-Contra Case Filled With Legal Complexities</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By JAMES ROWLEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The legal complexities in the Iran-Contra prosecution of former <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> aide <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> North </PERSON> and three co-defendants are sometimes as perplexing to the lawyers and the judge as they are to the general public. A continuing legal battle is being fought on several fronts between independent counsel <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Walsh </PERSON> and lawyers for <PERSON> North </PERSON>, former national security adviser <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Poindexter </PERSON> and arms dealers <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Hakim </PERSON> and <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> V. </PERSON> <PERSON> Secord </PERSON>. Here are some answers to a number of questions about the case: Q. Who is charged with what? A. All four defendants are charged with conspiring to defraud the government, theft of government property and wire fraud in the diversion of profits from the U.S.-Iran arms sales to the Nicaraguan rebels. <PERSON> Poindexter </PERSON> and <PERSON> North </PERSON> are both charged with lying to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. North also faces charges of obstructing a presidential inquiry, with pocketing $ 4,300 in travelers' checks a Contra leader gave him to cover expenses, with accepting an illegal gratuity in the form of a $ 15,000 high-security fence around his home, with obstructing an <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> inquiry into the fence, and with conspiring to illegally use a tax-exempt foundation to raise money to help arm the Contras. <PERSON> Secord </PERSON> and <PERSON> Hakim </PERSON> are charged with conspiring to py illegal gratuities to North by setting up a $ 200,000 fund for North's family and by arranging installation of the fence Q: When is the case going to trial? A: That is still up in the air. But <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> Gerhard </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gesell </PERSON> said last week that the defendants should be tried individually so that he could ensure they each get a fair trial. <PERSON> Gesell </PERSON> said he would decide major pre-trial issues by July 1. The first trial likely will begin during the fall presidential campaign. Q. Who goes first? <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Walsh </PERSON> designated <PERSON> North </PERSON> as the leadoff defendant, to be followed by <PERSON> Poindexter </PERSON>. Q. Why did <PERSON> Gesell </PERSON> order four separate trials? A. The judge was presented with a unique problem because three of the four defendants _ <LOCATION> North </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Poindexter </PERSON> and <PERSON> Hakim </PERSON> _ testified last year before congressional hearings under grants of limited immunity from prosecution. As a rule, <PERSON> Walsh </PERSON> is prevented from using the testimony of the defendants against them as evidence. Q. What does that have to do with holding four separate trials? <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gesell </PERSON> ruled that each defendant has a right to present a co-defendant's immunized testimony as evidence of his innocence. If a joint trial were held, <PERSON> Gesell </PERSON> would have to choose between protecting, say, <PERSON> Poindexter </PERSON>'s Fifth Amendment right not to have his congressional testimony used against him and the Sixth Amendment right of <PERSON> Hakim </PERSON> and <PERSON> Secord </PERSON> to use <PERSON> Poindexter </PERSON>'s statements to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> as evidence of their innocence. <PERSON> Secord </PERSON> and <PERSON> Hakim </PERSON>, both say that testimony by <PERSON> North </PERSON> and <PERSON> Poindexter </PERSON> would help clear them of any wrongdoing by showing that they acted with the understanding their activities were approved by the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government. Q. Is <PERSON> Gesell </PERSON>'s order a blow to the prosecution? A. Prosecutors do n't generally like trying conspiracy cases against individual defendants. It's easier to show a jury how the actions of each member furthered an alleged conspiracy if all the defendants are being tried together. It means <PERSON> Walsh </PERSON>'s resources will be seriously stretched and the cases will take a long time to try. Q: What are the remaining issues before <PERSON> Gesell </PERSON> can set a trial date? A: The judge must decide whether the immunized congressional testimony of <LOCATION> North </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Poindexter </PERSON> and <PERSON> Hakim </PERSON> tainted the investigation of prosecutors. But his decision to hold four trials appears to foreshadow a decision that congressional immunity wo n't be a barrier to trying the case. <PERSON> Gesell </PERSON> also has to rule on whether procedures for handling 200,000 pages of classified documents collected during <PERSON> Walsh </PERSON>'s investigation will protect the defendants' rights to a fair trial Q. What are those? A. The Classified Information Procedures Act requires the defense to notify the prosecution before trial of any government secrets it expects to use as evidence in the case. Defense lawyers contend this will tip off the prosecution. Q. Can the court force the government to declassify secret documents needed for the trials? A. No. If there is a large enough volume of material that the government agencies wo n't release, <PERSON> Walsh </PERSON> would be forced to drop the case. If the government determines that a particular document is so sensitive it ca n't be made public, the law provides several ways for the information to be presented. The court can order a statement of what the document would prove, can substitute a statement of facts that a document would prove for the actual material, or the judge can also delete sensitive portions of the material. Q: What sorts of secrets are involved? A: The keepers of government secrets are especially sensitive about any document that reveals the source of foreign intelligence. The government also is anxious to protect information revealing that a foreign country provided information or was involved in a secret initiative with the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Gesell </PERSON> speculated at a hearing that the defendants may want to introduce evidence about other covert operations they engaged in to show that the procedures were no different than those followed in the Iran-Contra affair. The judge said evidence about other secret operations might help the defendants show they acted with authority or at least the belief they had the permission of higher officials.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880613-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-13-88 0104EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a PM-PollMethod     06-13 0472</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Poll Method,0495</SECOND>
<HEAD>With PM-Poll-Presidential Choices, Bjt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 This <ORGANIZATION> Media </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> General-Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> poll is based on telephone interviews April 29-May 8 with 1,204 adults in the continental <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. The phone numbers were selected randomly by computer and interviews were conducted with the adult who had the most recent birthday. The results were weighted to adjust for variations in the sample. The poll has a three-point margin of error, meaning the results theoretically would be within three points of the same 19 times out of 20 if every adult American were asked the same questions. The error margin is larger for subgroups _ five points for Republicans, for example. There are other sources of potential error in polls, including the wording and order of questions. These are the questions and responses in this poll: 1. Presidents now are limited to two four-year terms in office. Do you think it should be one-six year term, stay at two four-year terms, be three four-year terms, or four or more four-year terms? One six-year: 16 percent. Two four-year: 65 percent. Three four-year: 8 percent. Four or more four-year: 5 percent. None of these: 4 percent. Do n't know or no answer: 2 percent. 2. If <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> could run again, would you vote for him for a third term as president? Yes: 32 percent. No: 64 percent. Do n't know or no answer: 4 percent. 3. I'm going to read a few attributes that might be found in a candidate for president. Tell me if each would make you more likely to vote for that candidate for president, or less likely to vote for that candidate, or if it would n't matter. a. A woman. More likely: 10 percent. Less: 25 percent. Not matter: 64. DK-NA: 2 percent. b. A black. More likely: 5 percent. Less: 27 percent. Not matter: 66 percent. DK-NA: 3 percent. 4. Would you be more likely or less likely to vote for a ticket that has a woman candidate for vice president, or would n't it matter? More likely: 10 percent. Less: 14 percent. Not matter: 75 percent. DK-NA: 1 percent. 5. Would you be more likely or less likely to vote for a ticket that has a black candidate for vice president, or would n't it matter? More likely: 6 percent. Less: 18 percent. Not matter: 75 percent. DK-NA: 1 percent. 6. Do you think it matters who's elected president? Yes: 89 percent. No: 9 percent. DK-NA: 2 percent. 7. Would you want the job of president? Yes: 11 percent. No: 89 percent. DK-NA: 1 percent. 8. Would you want your child to grow up to be president? Yes: 41 percent. No: 46 percent. DK-NA: 13 percent. 9. Do you think it's possible your child could grow up to be president? Yes: 59 percent. No: 34 percent. DK-NA: 8 percent.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880613-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-13-88 0131EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-WhiteHouse-Tennis     06-13 0338</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-White House-Tennis,340</SECOND>
<HEAD>Celebrities Turn Out for White House Tennis Benefit</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By SUSANNE M. SCHAFER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
