<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880626-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-26-88 2322EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w AM-HelicopterCrash 1stLd-Writethru a0783 06-26 0172</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Helicopter Crash, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0783,140</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names of Crash Victims Released</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDs: SUBS last graf to CORRECT McKay's home</NOTE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corps </ORGANIZATION> on Sunday released the names of the seven Marines killed Saturday in a helicopter crash in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>. The CH-53D chopper crashed on <LOCATION> Shikoku </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> during a routine flight from the <ORGANIZATION> Marines </ORGANIZATION>' air station at <LOCATION> Iwikuni </LOCATION> to another corps air station at <LOCATION> Futenma </LOCATION>, where the craft was based. A <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corps </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman, Lt. <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> Kerstens </PERSON>, said the cause of the accident was under investigation. The victims, who were members of <ORGANIZATION> Heavy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Helicopter </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Squadron </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> 462 </ORGANIZATION>, were based at the <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corps </ORGANIZATION> air station at <LOCATION> Tustin </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, and on a six-month assignment in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Kerstens </PERSON> said. The seven were identified as Capt. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bermel </PERSON>, <PERSON> Cataldo </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION>; 1st Lt. <PERSON> Patrick </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Fleming </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mich. </LOCATION>; Staff Sgt. <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Yoder </PERSON>, <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bernardino </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>; Sgt. <PERSON> Eric </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Mau </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Bakersfield </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>; Sgt. <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> McKay </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Westlake </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>; Sgt. <PERSON> Jay </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Spirit </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>; and Cpl. <PERSON> Jason </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Chase </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Bayside </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880626-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-26-88 2339EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-NewCaledonia     06-26 0411</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-New Caledonia,0424</SECOND>
<HEAD>Two Sides Reach Agreement on Territory's Future</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PARIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The head of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Caledonia </LOCATION>'s separatist movement and the islands' conservative pro-French deputy reached agreement early Sunday on the future of the troubled territory, Prime Minister <PERSON> Michel </PERSON> <PERSON> Rocard </PERSON> announced. He said that under the accord, <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> will assume direct control of the <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> territory for the next 12 months, with <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Caledonians </LOCATION> voting in referendum in 10 years on the issue of self-determination. <PERSON> Rocard </PERSON> also said he would propose to President <PERSON> Francois </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitterrand </PERSON> that the French people be consulted in a referendum on new institutions to be set up to develop the territory. Tensions in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Caledonia </LOCATION>, an island group 1,000 miles east of <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION>, have remained high 21 people were killed in May when a French army assault team stormed a cave to free 23 hostages held by native Melanesian separatists. Thirty people have died in violence in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Caledonia </LOCATION> since April 22. The accord reached Sunday came after negotations in <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> involving <PERSON> Rocard </PERSON>, <PERSON> Jean-Marie </PERSON> <PERSON> Tjibaou </PERSON>, head of the <ORGANIZATION> Kanak </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Socialist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION>, and deputy <PERSON> Jacques </PERSON> <PERSON> LaFleur </PERSON>. The Kanaks, or Melanesians, represent about 43 percent of the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Caledonia </LOCATION>'s 145,000 residents, and most favor independence. The rest of the population comprises descendents of European settlers, Asians and Polynesians, most of whom prefer to remain French. <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> colonized the islands in 1853. <PERSON> Rocard </PERSON> brought <PERSON> Tjibaou </PERSON> and <PERSON> LaFleur </PERSON> together last week for their first meeting since 1982. He said they both would take the agreement to their respective constituencies and call for approval. Tjibaou called the agreement reached Sunday `` an important step'' but said the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Caledonia </LOCATION> problem has not been solved and native Melanesians will continue to demand independence. He said the talks were difficult because the demands of the two sides were contradictory and because of the tense atmosphere in the territory. `` Each side now is committed to halt bloodshed and end mourning for many families, `` Tjibaou said. A statement issued by <PERSON> Rocard </PERSON> called on the territory's inhabitants to `` be hopeful for a new page has been turned, not by arms but by dialogue and tolerance, by hard work and good will. <PERSON> Rocard </PERSON> made a solution to the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Caledonia </LOCATION> problem a priority after <PERSON> Mitterrand </PERSON> named him prime minister 45 days ago. The agreement seems likely to restore some of <PERSON> Rocard </PERSON>'s prestige, which was tarnished after the Socialists failed to win a majority in legislative elections that followed the May 8 presidential vote.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880626-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-26-88 2353EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-France-Crash 6thLd-Writethru a0402 06-26 0889</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-France-Crash, 6th Ld - Writethru, a0402,0913</SECOND>
<HEAD>New Jet Crashes During Air Show; At Least Three Dead</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: LEADS with 8 grafs to UPDATE with pilot telling newspaper he
could not increase power. Picks up 7th graf pvs, `A woman ... </NOTE>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto PAR9</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MULHOUSE, France (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A new <ORGANIZATION> Airbus </ORGANIZATION> jetliner carrying more than 130 people crashed into a forest Sunday during an air show demonstration flight, killing at least three people and injuring 98, officials said. Many victims were believed to be first-time fliers who paid for a ride on the twin-engine <ORGANIZATION> Airbus </ORGANIZATION> A320, which was delivered to <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> France </ORGANIZATION> only Thursday. Witnesses said the plane, which touts a state-of-the-art electronic flight system, had just passed over the airfield hosting the show when it crashed, tearing a nearly 500-foot path through the woods. Part of the plane caught fire. A control tower official said the jet appeared to lose power as it passed over the field in <LOCATION> Habsheim </LOCATION>, a village about 15 miles from the Swiss border. Monday's editions of the <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> daily newspaper L'Humanite quoted the jet's pilot as telling a rescue worker: `` I wanted to to increase the power but the aircraft did not respond.'' `` It was about 20 meters -LRB- 65 feet -RRB- above the ground with its flaps and landing gear down when it clipped some trees at the end of the runway and crashed in the forest,'' <PERSON> Bernard </PERSON> <PERSON> Labalette </PERSON>, an amateur pilot, was quoted by <PERSON> Agence </PERSON> <PERSON> France-Presse </PERSON> as saying. Visibility was perfect. A 25-year-old woman passenger who did not give her name was quoted by AFP as saying she heard trees brush against the fuselage. `` From then on things went fast,'' she said. `` The plane hit the ground hard and we had the feeling of an abrupt jolt. Then there was a fire in the front of the aircraft.'' Flight attendants deployed evacuation chutes and the woman said she and other passengers slid down and ran away, fearing an explosion. Rescuers worked throughout the afternoon to evacuate dozens of people trapped in the battered plane. The impact broke the plane's wings and smashed the cockpit windows The fuselage was blackened from smoke, <ORGANIZATION> AFP </ORGANIZATION> said. Local officials said 50 people were hospitalized. It was not clear how many were on the jet as there was no official passenger list. Authorities said at least 136 were aboard. Officials said the pilot, <PERSON> Michel </PERSON> <PERSON> Asseline </PERSON>, and the co-pilot, <PERSON> Pierre </PERSON> <PERSON> Mazieres </PERSON>, were not injured. Initial reports said four people were killed. The local officials, not named in accordance with <LOCATION> French </LOCATION> practice, later said they were able to confirm three deaths. They said some victims were badly burned. `` There was an explosion and a cloud of smoke. But from the control tower we could n't see,'' said the tower official, who did not give his name. He said about 1,000 people were at the show and that many on the plane were making their first flight. At such air shows, spectators are invited to participate in an `` air baptism,'' or take their first flight for a small fee. The plane made six flights on Saturday. The A320, built in <LOCATION> Toulouse </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> by a European consortium, went into service in April for <LOCATION> Air </LOCATION> <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> and <ORGANIZATION> British </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airways </ORGANIZATION>. It was conceived and certified for flight by a two-member crew, eliminating the navigator. Early this year, pilots and flight engineers of <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inter </ORGANIZATION>, the largest French airline, called a series of strikes to protest the use of only two cockpit members in A320s, saying it was unsafe. In <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> British </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airways </ORGANIZATION> suspended service on its two A320 aircraft as a precautionary measure pending information on the cause of the accident in <LOCATION> Habsheim </LOCATION>, which is just outside <LOCATION> Mulhouse </LOCATION> and 250 miles east of <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION>. Air <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> President <PERSON> Jacques </PERSON> <PERSON> Friedman </PERSON> said that as a precaution, the airline was replacing an A320 due to fly to <LOCATION> Dusseldorf </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> on Sunday night with a <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> 737 and canceling a Paris-Zurich flight. French Transport Minister <PERSON> Louis </PERSON> <PERSON> Mermez </PERSON> said a commission of inquiry would begin work Monday. The Airbus A320 can carry 168 passengers. Airbus Indusrie, its manufacturer, has orders to purchase 500 of the craft. Minneapolis-based <ORGANIZATION> Northwest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> agreed to buy some of the A320s for delivery in 1990 and 1991. `` I doubt -LRB- the crash -RRB- would have an impact on our decision to purchase from <ORGANIZATION> Airbus </ORGANIZATION>,'' <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Muncaster </PERSON>, staff vice president of corporate communications for <ORGANIZATION> Northwest </ORGANIZATION>, said Sunday. `` But obviously we would want to check into the cause of the crash.'' Air <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> has three of the aircraft, <ORGANIZATION> British </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airways </ORGANIZATION> has two and <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inter </ORGANIZATION>, the French domestic airline, has one, <ORGANIZATION> Airbus </ORGANIZATION> said. `` We are disturbed, shocked and saddened,'' said <ORGANIZATION> Airbus </ORGANIZATION> press spokesman <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Alizart </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Toulouse </LOCATION>. He said it was the first crash of an A320. <PERSON> Alizart </PERSON> said it was too early to say whether the future of the aircraft, which received its certification Feb. 26, could be in doubt. The plane has a range of about 3,700 miles and consumes 40 percent less fuel than similar two or three engine jets. It is the first civilian airliner equipped with a fully computerized flight-control system the manufacturer says permits safer, electronically controlled flight. Instead of the old control column in front of the pilot, there is a `` pistol-grip'' side stick linked to five computers that modify and relay the pilot's directions to wing and tail flaps
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880626-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-26-88 2359EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-WorldDrought     06-26 0771</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-World Drought,0793</SECOND>
<HEAD>U.S. Drought Could Cause Severe Drop In World Grain Stocks</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</NOTE>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By STEPHEN R. WILSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ROME (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Worldwide grain stocks could sink to their lowest levels of the decade and lead to possible food shortages if the crippling <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> drought continues for another two weeks, according to a <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> organization. But officials at the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Food </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> say favorable weather and crop prospects have created a brighter farm picture in most of the rest of the world. Before the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> drought took hold, the Rome-based <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> organization already was projecting that world grain production in 1988-89 would not match consumption and that stocks would drop close to the level the agency considers the minimum necessary to safeguard world food security. `` Now with the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> drought, the question is how much is <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> production going to be drawn down,'' <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Newhouse </PERSON>, chief of the agency's global information and early warning service, said in an interview Friday. `` It's still too early for firm projections. It all depends on the rain in the next two weeks,'' he said. The organization had projected June that the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> would produce 279 million tons of this year's targeted 1.67 billion tons of grain worldwide. But that was before the worst drought since the Great Depression parched the <LOCATION> Midwest </LOCATION>. `` If the present dry weather were to continue over the next couple of weeks, then there would be a severe shortfall in <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> crops, particularly maize -LRB- corn -RRB-,'' <PERSON> Newhouse </PERSON> said. `` We had already projected that with normal weather conditions, the stocks could fall close to the minimum level. Now if the drought continues, there's a distinct possibility it could fall below that.'' The <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> organization considers the minimum level to be 17 percent to 18 percent of the projected global consumption of wheat for the following year. The last time the level fell to the minimum level was in 1981. Stocks have not dropped below the minimum since the mid-1970s. They hit a low of 14 percent during the global food crisis of 1972-73. `` If stocks go below the mininum level, it would mean the world is more vulnerable than it should be and could face food supply difficulties,'' <PERSON> Newhouse </PERSON> said. `` We've still got a cushion ... but if the cushion is going to be used up, it looks like the food situation on a global level is going to be a lot tighter.'' <PERSON> Newhouse </PERSON> said the organization `` will have to be very vigilant'' in monitoring <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> cereal crops and those in <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>. `` Fortunately, harvest prospects outside the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> are generally favorable,'' <PERSON> Newhouse </PERSON> said. `` At this moment, we do n't see any widespread drought problems... nothing dramatic,'' said <PERSON> Rene </PERSON> <PERSON> Gommes </PERSON> of the agency's agro-meteorological The only country that produces more cereal crops than the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> is <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> with about 350 million tons annually. Third is the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> with 200 million tons. <PERSON> Newhouse </PERSON> said harvest prospects were good in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. In <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, drought has hit some areas and floods have hit others. `` But at this point we're not worried about <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>,'' he said. An important factor for world crop production is the monsoon season in <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Bangladesh </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>, which were hit by severe drought last year. `` The monsoon started in May on time this year, but it's still far too early to say what will happen,'' <PERSON> Newhouse </PERSON> said. One of the world's most serious food supply situations is occurring partly as a result of heavy rainfall in areas often prone to drought conditions. Swarms of migrating desert locusts, who breed in rainy conditions, have invaded the <LOCATION> Sahel </LOCATION> region of sub-Saharan <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>. The infestation `` is of unprecedented dimensions and will affect the food security of 15 African countries, from the <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ocean </LOCATION> to the <LOCATION> Red </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sea </LOCATION>,'' the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> group's director-general, <PERSON> Edouard </PERSON> <PERSON> Saouma </PERSON>, said Friday. In African countries such as <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mozambique </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Sudan </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Ethiopia </LOCATION>, civil war has aggravated crop failures. In <LOCATION> Ethiopia </LOCATION>, where drought and famine killed up to 1 million people in 1984-85, more than 7 million people are reported threatened by the drought and last year's crop failures. The crop planting season is now under way in <LOCATION> Ethiopia </LOCATION> so it wo n't be known until the end of the year whether the country can recover, <ORGANIZATION> Newhouse </ORGANIZATION> said. In <LOCATION> Latin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, northeast <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION> suffered severe drought last year but the weather has improved and <ORGANIZATION> Newhouse </ORGANIZATION> believes the harvest will recover. <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, however, is expecting a shortfall of more than 1 million tons in its wheat harvest, he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880626-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-26-88 2354EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-StormsRdp     06-26 0414</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Storms Rdp,0425</SECOND>
<HEAD>Storms Cause Tornadoes; Lightning, Trees Kill Two</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Thunderstorms battered scattered areas from <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION> Sunday night, causing tornadoes in at least three states and at least two deaths in <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>, including a boy on a bicycle hit by falling trees. The <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> storm produced lightning fires and toppled power lines, leaving one-third of the city of <LOCATION> Greensboro </LOCATION> temporarily in darkness, authorities said. Two falling trees fatally injured 8-year-old <PERSON> Tim </PERSON> <PERSON> Marshall </PERSON> while he was riding his bicycle to his <LOCATION> Greensboro </LOCATION> home about 6:45 p.m., Police Sgt. <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Deich </PERSON> said. `` It was just the worst possible timing,'' said <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Langerman </PERSON>, a witness. `` He was riding pretty fast, and if he had been two seconds faster or two seconds slower, nothing would have happened.'' Lightning struck and killed <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> <PERSON> Lynn </PERSON> <PERSON> Knox </PERSON>, 38, of <LOCATION> Mooresville </LOCATION> about 6:30 p.m. as he was headed for shore in a pontoon boat on <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Norman </LOCATION>, north of <LOCATION> Charlotte </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mecklenburg </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> Police said. About 7:30 p.m., the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Weather </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> reported a solid line of thunderstorms that stretched across northern <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> from <LOCATION> Elizabeth </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> across the <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> border north of <LOCATION> Rocky </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mount </LOCATION>, and southwest across the <LOCATION> northeast </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Piedmont </LOCATION> north of <LOCATION> Raleigh </LOCATION> to the <LOCATION> northwest </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Piedmont </LOCATION> south of <LOCATION> Greensboro </LOCATION>. The storms were moving at about 30 mph, but winds were reported as high as 55 mph. In southeast <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION>, two homes were destroyed by what witnesses described as a tornado and dozens of vehicles were damaged when winds ripped part of the roof off the <LOCATION> Dothan </LOCATION> airport. Thunderstorms across <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION> triggered heavy rains in some areas, a tornado in open country in <LOCATION> Adams </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> east of <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION>, and winds that blew windows out of a home near <LOCATION> Franktown </LOCATION>. One strong thunderstorm dropped 1.1 inches of rain and pea-sized hail in 35 minutes south of <LOCATION> Centennial </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Arapahoe </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>. That cloudburst caused local street flooding. Severe thunderstorms in <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> spawned at least one tornado in the south-central part of the state, the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Weather </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> said. A tornado touched down about 8 p.m. in a rural area just north of <LOCATION> Partridge </LOCATION>, said <PERSON> Joanne </PERSON> <PERSON> Angell </PERSON>, a supervisor with the <ORGANIZATION> Reno </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sheriff </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>. No damage or injuries were reported. A cluster of heavy thunderstorms also rumbled northwestward across the <LOCATION> Red </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> from northern <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> into southwestern <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION>, said <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Szatkowski </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Weather </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> forecaster. <PERSON> Szatkowski </PERSON> said the storms produced rainfall of up to an inch, but not enough to ease drought conditions.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880626-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-26-88 0022EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-Singleton     06-26 0326</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Singleton,0336</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bomb Explodes In Front Of Singleton's Home, Police Say</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TAMPA, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A small bomb was hurled at the home listed as the address of rapist-mutilator <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> <PERSON> Singleton </PERSON> on Saturday night, but the explosion caused no injuries or property damage, authorities said. The homemade bomb detonated in the front yard of the one-story home just before 9 p.m., said <LOCATION> Hillsborough </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> Sheriff's Lt. <PERSON> Ken </PERSON> <PERSON> Allen </PERSON>. `` <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> <PERSON> Singleton </PERSON> was not in the house, his whereabouts are still unknown at this time,'' <PERSON> Allen </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Singleton </PERSON>'s brother, <PERSON> Walter </PERSON>, and sister-in-law, <PERSON> Diane </PERSON>, were the only people in the home when the device exploded, leaving a heavy white cloud, the officer said. While many in the quiet <LOCATION> Forest </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hills </LOCATION> neighborhood heard the explosion, there were no witnesses to who threw the device, <PERSON> Allen </PERSON> said. Experts were examining bomb shards to determine what type of device it was. <PERSON> Singleton </PERSON> was convicted of raping a 15-year-old hitchhiker, chopping her arms off with an ax and leaving her for dead in a ditch southeast of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> in 1978. The gray-bearded 60-year-old former merchant seaman, who grew up in <LOCATION> Tampa </LOCATION>, spent eight years of a 14-year sentence in a <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> prison. He completed a year-long probation and is now a free man. During his probation, <PERSON> Singleton </PERSON> was forced to flee six <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> towns after residents objected to his presence. He ended up finishing his probation in a trailer on the grounds of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Quentin </LOCATION> prison. Two weeks ago, he listed the address with authorities as required of convicted felons under state law, but he has never been seen there. His brother has said <PERSON> Singleton </PERSON> lives `` about two hours away,'' but refuses to say exactly where. Angry area residents have held two meetings in the past month asking deputies to locate <PERSON> Singleton </PERSON> so they can stop living in fear. A local businessman and a radio station have each offered <PERSON> Singleton </PERSON> $ 5,000 if he will pack up and go anywhere else.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880626-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-26-88 0024EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Mexico-Drugs     06-26 0382</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Mexico-Drugs,0396</SECOND>
<HEAD>Baja Governor's Brothers Accused in Major Cocaine Smuggling Ring</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CANDICE HUGHES</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MEXICO CITY (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Two brothers of the state governor of <LOCATION> Baja </LOCATION> <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sur </LOCATION> are under arrest on charges they took part in a sophisticated drug ring that smuggled cocaine from <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION> to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, authorities said. Authorities also said they arrested four others who participated in the operation. The arrests were announced late Friday by the federal attorney general's office. Authorities said rancher <PERSON> Agustin </PERSON> <PERSON> Liceaga </PERSON> <PERSON> Ruibal </PERSON>, 48, and businessman <PERSON> Rene </PERSON> <PERSON> Liceaga </PERSON> <PERSON> Ruibal </PERSON>, 46, were part of a smuggling ring that operated clandestine air strips, safe houses and money-laundering businesses in several Mexican states. An emotional Gov. <PERSON> Victor </PERSON> <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Liceaga </PERSON> <PERSON> Ruibal </PERSON> called the case a `` family tragedy'' during a hastily called news conference in <LOCATION> La </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Paz </LOCATION>, the state capital, late Friday. He said he knew nothing of his brother's activities. `` I am completely clean,'' he declared. The governor said state authorities cooperated fully with the federal investigation and would continue to do so. Authorities said his brothers allowed at least one of their ranches to be used for clandestine air strips where drug-laden planes en route from <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION> to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> refueled. Investigators said they have tracked at least 10 flights. In addition to the governor's brothers, four other people were arrested: <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Pineda </PERSON> <PERSON> Trinidad </PERSON>, <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Alcantara </PERSON> <PERSON> Varela </PERSON>, <PERSON> Ramon </PERSON> <PERSON> Escamilla </PERSON> <PERSON> Vazquez </PERSON> and <PERSON> Maria </PERSON> <PERSON> Alicia </PERSON> <PERSON> Marquez </PERSON> <PERSON> Solis </PERSON>. <PERSON> Pineda </PERSON> <PERSON> Trinidad </PERSON>, who also used the name <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Ponce </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Leon </PERSON>, was identified as head of the ring. Authorities said he laundered drug profits through his money exchange house in <LOCATION> Guadalajara </LOCATION> and a real estate company. The profits were allegedly stashed in <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and Mexican banks and in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>, where authorities said they found $ 10 million in a single account. <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> has been recently reported to be a regional banking center for drug smugglers. In February, a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> grand jury in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> indicted its military ruler, Gen. <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>, on drug-trafficking charges. The attorney general's office said it has seized Pineada <LOCATION> Trinidad </LOCATION>'s property, which also included three homes and four ranches in the central state of <LOCATION> Jalisco </LOCATION>. Authorities did not say when or where the arrests were made, but said all six suspects were transferred to <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> to face a variety of drug charges.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880626-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-26-88 0042EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-RangersSuit     06-26 0414</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Rangers Suit,0424</SECOND>
<HEAD>Federal Park Rangers Held Libel For Drunken Driver's Accident</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CORPUS CHRISTI, Texas (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A judge awarded $ 7.5 million to a man who was seriously hurt in a collision with a drunken driver after ruling that <ORGANIZATION> Padre </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Island </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Seashore </ORGANIZATION> rangers were negligent in failing to arrest the driver earlier. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> Spencer </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> granted the award Friday to <PERSON> Randy </PERSON> <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Crider </PERSON>, 33, of <LOCATION> Corpus </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Christi </LOCATION>, a motorcyclist who lost an arm and a leg in the 1983 collision with a car driven by <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Landry </PERSON>, 23. The <ORGANIZATION> Interior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, which oversees federal parks, and the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> attorney's office will decide whether to appeal the decision within 60 days, said Assistant <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Attorney <PERSON> Wayne </PERSON> <PERSON> Campbell </PERSON>. `` We think that the $ 7.5 million is fair, but no amount of money can compensate for what <PERSON> Randy </PERSON> <PERSON> Crider </PERSON> has suffered,'' said his attorney, <PERSON> Ben </PERSON> <PERSON> Sley </PERSON>. `` This, however, will give him the chance at a meaningful life.'' <PERSON> Crider </PERSON> said park rangers <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Couser </PERSON> and <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Copeland </PERSON> had stopped <PERSON> Landry </PERSON> 10 hours before the accident for driving 40 mph in a 15-mph zone on a public road on <LOCATION> Padre </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION>. The rangers ticketed <PERSON> Landry </PERSON> and allowed him to continue, <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>, who was brought from <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jose </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, to <PERSON> Corpus </PERSON> <PERSON> Christi </PERSON> to hear the case, ruled March 17 that not arresting <PERSON> Landry </PERSON> was `` an act of negligence and that, as a consequence, an accident occurred.'' Evidence at the trial showed that <PERSON> Landry </PERSON> had consumed 7 or 8 ounces of liquor and had smoked several marijuana cigarettes in the three or four hours before he was stopped for speeding. <PERSON> Sley </PERSON> had argued that the marijuana could have impaired <PERSON> Landry </PERSON>'s actions for 12 to 24 hours and that the alcohol intensified the effects of the marijuana. <PERSON> Landry </PERSON>, who pleaded guilty to aggravated assault in the accident, was sentenced to eight years in prison. <PERSON> Sley </PERSON>, who had sought $ 75 million, said the case could lead authorities around the nation to tighten enforcement of drunken-driving laws. `` I think -LRB- the award -RRB- sends a message throughout the nation that authorities have to enforce the drunk-driving laws or face serious liability exposure,'' he said. However, <LOCATION> Padre </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> rangers have not changed enforcement of drunken-driving laws since the March ruling, said park Superintendent <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Hunter </PERSON>, the park's superintendent. `` We might seek a little more advice from the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> attorney, but our rangers are operating pretty much status quo,'' <PERSON> Hunter </PERSON> said, adding that the judgment places an unfair burden on his rangers.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880626-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-26-88 0049EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Haiti     06-26 0235</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Haiti,0244</SECOND>
<HEAD>Namphy Picks Duvalierist To Head Games Control Commission</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MICHAEL NORTON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> PORT-AU-PRINCE </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Haiti </LOCATION> -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> -RRB- _ The new military government has chosen as president of the important <ORGANIZATION> Games </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Control </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> a <PERSON> Jean-Claude </PERSON> <PERSON> Duvalier </PERSON> supporter who has kept a low profile since the dictator fled two years ago. The appointment of <PERSON> Abel </PERSON> <PERSON> Jerome </PERSON>, a retired army colonel, was announced over the state-run television station Friday night along with that of other new civil servants. They were selected by the new military government of Lt. Gen. <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> Namphy </PERSON>, who swept into power earlier this week after ousting civilian President <PERSON> Leslie </PERSON> <PERSON> Manigat </PERSON>. The weekly lottery, which generates hundreds of thousands of dollars, is a national passion. There are almost as many ticket stalls in the capital as grocery stores. The Games <ORGANIZATION> Control </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> is the body established to ensure the lottery is not rigged and that winners collect earnings. Under the <PERSON> Duvalier </PERSON> regime, the corrupt administrative body was a lucrative source of income for the dictators and their allies. <PERSON> Jerome </PERSON> is widely reported to have participated in the 1964 mass murders of a number of prominent families in <PERSON> Jeremie </PERSON>, a town in southwestern <LOCATION> Haiti </LOCATION>. He has gained a reputation for exceptional brutality after those and other killings. <PERSON> Jerome </PERSON> has maintained a low profile since the February l986 uprising that sent <PERSON> Duvalier </PERSON> into exile in <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>, ending 29 years of dictatorship by his family.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880626-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-26-88 0055EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Cuba-Crash 2ndLd-Writethru a0734 06-26 0112</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Cuba-Crash, 2nd Ld-Writethru, a0734,0111</SECOND>
<HEAD>25 Killed in Cuba When Train Hits Bus</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: LEADS with 1 graf to FIX style on time element</NOTE>
<DATELINE>MEXICO CITY (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A train slammed into a passenger bus near <LOCATION> Havana </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION>, Saturday, killing at least 25 people and injuring 40, the government news agency said. The accident occurred in the late afternoon when a train on the Havana-Matanzas line struck the bus in the city of <LOCATION> Guanabacoa </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Prensa </PERSON> <PERSON> Latina </PERSON> said in a dispatch monitored in <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. Police rushed to the scene to determine the cause of the crash and identify the dead, the report said. It said three children were among the dead.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880626-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-26-88 0057EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-FamilySlayings     06-26 0163</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Family Slayings,0168</SECOND>
<HEAD>Four Dead, 2-Year-Old Unharmed In Philly Murder-Suicide</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PHILADELPHIA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A man shot his wife, son and baby daughter in the head before turning the gun on himself Saturday night, but spared a 2-year-old daughter who survived the rampage uharmed, police said. <PERSON> Winston </PERSON> <PERSON> Coghiel </PERSON>, 33, shot his 30-year-old wife, June, as she sat on their living room couch, said police Lt. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Henwood </PERSON>. <PERSON> Coghiel </PERSON> then shot 3-year-old son <PERSON> Winston </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> and 9-month-old daughter <PERSON> Kimberley </PERSON>, who were also found in the living room, <PERSON> Henwood </PERSON> said. The man then shot himself with the .38 - caliber <PERSON> Browning </PERSON> All four were dead of gunshot wounds to the head when family members found them, the lieutenant said. There were no signs of a struggle. The surviving daughter, <PERSON> Celeste </PERSON>, was not hurt, but was taken to <LOCATION> Children </LOCATION><LOCATION> 's </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Henwood </PERSON> said. She was released later in the evening. Family members told police that <PERSON> Coghiel </PERSON> had been depressed and was convinced people were after him, <PERSON> Henwood </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880626-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-26-88 0135EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-UN-Disarmament     06-26 0245</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-UN-Disarmament,0251</SECOND>
<HEAD>U.N. Locked in Disarmament Squabble</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By VICTORIA GRAHAM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>UNITED NATIONS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A four-week-long <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> session on disarmament missed its deadline and dragged on into Sunday after bitterly divided delegates failed to agree on a formula for world peace. The session, which was scheduled to end Saturday night, was extended after delegates could not reach a consensus on issues ranging from missile defense systems known as `` Star Wars'' to monitoring land-based weapons. After the progress of the U.S.-Soviet summits, the failure of this first General Assembly session on disarmament in six years to meet its timetable put on public display the deep divisions that still exist between East and West. Delegates to the $ 7.4 million session, which has heard 135 speakers since it began May 31, could only agree to allow a negotiating committee to continue work Saturday night. Informal consultations were expected through the night before participants reconvened, possibly early Sunday. Delegates have been locked in intense, sometimes acrimonious debate in efforts to forge a final document settng forth an agenda for peace. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and some of its Western allies were at odds with most other nations on numerous issues, including priorities for nuclear and conventional disarmament, Third World disarmament and identifying <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> as regional offenders. Delegates and <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> officials said it was uncertain whether the world body would be able to adopt a final document by consensus and avoid a divisive vote.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880626-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-26-88 0142EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-LightningFatal     06-26 0203</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Lightning Fatal,0019</SECOND>
<HEAD>Eldorado Canyon Climbers Hit By Lightning, 1 Dies</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BOULDER, Colo. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A 25-year-old man was killed by lightning, and another climber was injured as they scaled a dangerous route in <LOCATION> Eldorado </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Canyon </LOCATION> <LOCATION> State </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Park </LOCATION> called the Naked Edge, authorities said. The 21-year-old survivor, who suffered burns and an ankle injury, was in stable condition at <LOCATION> Boulder </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Community </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION> on Saturday night, according to a statement by the <ORGANIZATION> Boulder </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sheriff </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>. Both climbers had to be lowered off the rock face by members of the <ORGANIZATION> Rocky </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mountain </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rescue </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Group </ORGANIZATION>, who had to work their way up the back side of the canyon wall to reach them. The identities and addresses of the climbers were not released pending notification of relatives. `` One climber had just reached -LRB- the top of the face -RRB-, but had n't quite gotten over it,'' said <PERSON> Alice </PERSON> <PERSON> Daubenbis </PERSON>, who lives in the canyon `` Then I heard the lightning, it hit on the Naked Edge.'' One man was at least 550 feet from the bottom of the canyon, and it took rescue workers about an hour to reach the climbers, <PERSON> Daubenbis </PERSON> said. The Naked Edge has `` some of the most dangerous, hard climbing in the world,'' she said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880626-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-26-88 0400EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i BC-Israel     06-26 0252</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Israel ,0260</SECOND>
<HEAD>Police Suspect Israeli Soldier Lied About Arab Attack</HEAD>
<DATELINE>JERUSALEM (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Authorities suspect that an <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> reserve soldier who claimed he was stabbed by four Arabs while hitchhiking lied because he was late returning to his base, a police spokeswoman said Sunday. On Saturday, a bomb exploded near an <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> bus as it headed to a Jewish settlement 37 miles north of <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION> in the occupied <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION>. It damaged the vehicle but caused no injuries. The 38-year-old soldier, <PERSON> Chaim </PERSON> <PERSON> Yosef </PERSON>, said the Arabs assaulted him and tried to grab his weapon Saturday as he hitchhiked at the Mesubim junction near the coastal city of <LOCATION> Tel </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Aviv </LOCATION>, an army spokesman had said. The Israeli <ORGANIZATION> Itim </ORGANIZATION> news agency said <PERSON> Yosef </PERSON> told police he was stabbed four times. However, <LOCATION> Tel </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Aviv </LOCATION> police spokeswoman <PERSON> Shlomit </PERSON> <PERSON> Herzberg </PERSON> said Sunday that <PERSON> Yosef </PERSON> had only scratches on his arm, not stab wounds. She said his version of events `` is suspect and we are checking whether it is correct.'' <PERSON> Herzberg </PERSON>, reached by telephone, said police believed the soldier may have made up the story to avoid punishment for failing to report on time for military duty. Police detained several Arabs for questioning immediately after the reported assault, but they were later freed, Mrs. <PERSON> Hertzberg </PERSON> said. Earlier Saturday, troops shot and wounded a Palestinian in the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> town of <LOCATION> Nablus </LOCATION>. A total of 211 Palestinians and four Israelis have died in the 6 -LCB- - month-old uprising in lands the Israelis seized in the 1967 Middle East War
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880626-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-26-88 0635EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-People-Mitchelson     06-26 0315</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-People-Mitchelson,0324</SECOND>
<HEAD>State Bar Accuses Famed Divorce Lawyer Of Misconduct</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Marvin </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitchelson </PERSON>, the celebrity divorce lawyer for such stars as `` Dynasty'' vixen <PERSON> Joan </PERSON> <PERSON> Collins </PERSON>, is facing misconduct allegations filed by the State Bar stemming from alleged mishandling of clients' money. The State Bar's trial counsel office filed documents Friday asking for a disciplinary hearing into allegations that <PERSON> Mitchelson </PERSON> failed to return unearned fees of up to $ 25,000 promptly after several clients fired him. `` We have in excess of 20 complaints against Mr. <PERSON> Mitchelson </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bar </ORGANIZATION> chief trial counsel <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bascue </PERSON> said. Among those who filed complaints were actress <PERSON> Julie </PERSON> <PERSON> Newmar </PERSON> and <PERSON> Eleanor </PERSON> <PERSON> Revson </PERSON>, sister-in-law of the founder of <ORGANIZATION> Revlon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cosmetics </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Mitchelson </PERSON>, 60, who made headlines by winning palimony payments for <PERSON> Michele </PERSON> <PERSON> Triola </PERSON>, the unwed, live-in girlfriend of actor <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Marvin </PERSON> in 1976, could face disciplinary actions ranging from a simple warning to disbarment. <PERSON> Mitchelson </PERSON> said he was surprised by the allegations, which he called `` a sudden attack.'' `` I'm highly visible so I may be a prime target, but nevertheless I will vigorously defend myself against these charges as I have defended every case I've ever had,'' <PERSON> Mitchelson </PERSON> said by phone from <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION>. `` All these complaints are old complaints and at least two of them have been previously rejected by the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bar </ORGANIZATION>,'' he said. Ms. <PERSON> Newmar </PERSON>, who starred as `` Catwoman'' on the 1960s TV series `` Batman,'' Ms. <PERSON> Revson </PERSON> and others complained that <PERSON> Mitchelson </PERSON> took retainers from them and delayed or refused to return unearned portions of the fees after they fired him for alleged deception, the <ORGANIZATION> Los </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Angeles </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> reported in today's editions. The Bar also charged that <PERSON> Mitchelson </PERSON> failed to deposit clients' funds in trust accounts, charged `` unconscionable'' fees, failed to perform promised work, lied to a client and twice improperly asked a client to withdraw her complaint to the State Bar over the return of unearned fees
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880626-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-26-88 0902EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i BC-Afghanistan     06-26 0234</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Afghanistan,0241</SECOND>
<HEAD>Kabul Airport Blaze Destroys Eight Soviet Jets; Guerrillas
Suspected</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ISLAMABAD, Pakistan (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A fire at the <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION> airport destroyed eight Soviet jet fighters and may have been the result of an attack by Moslem guerrillas, Western diplomatic sources said Sunday. The sources, speaking on condition of anonymity, said their counterparts in the Afghan capital first noted the fire on Friday. `` It looks like a -LRB- guerrilla -RRB- attack,'' said one western diplomat. He said that reliable sources in <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION> reported seeing two rockets hit the airport about two hours after the fire started. Diplomats said Soviet and Afghan government forces were fighting U.S.-backed guerrillas just west of the airport, on the northern outskirts of the capital. They said reports coming in late Saturday claimed eight Soviet Su-25 jet fighters exploded one after the other at the northwest end of the airport. A telex report from one Western embassy said: `` The loss is one of the largest soviet air losses of the war.'' Guerrilla activity was reported on the rise around <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION>, with insurgents frequently moving within rocket range of the city. Guerrillas claimed to have rocketed the airport last week but not on the day reported by diplomats. Soviet forces entered <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> in December 1979 to replace one Marxist government with another and battle the anti-communist insurgency. Soviet troops began withdrawing May 15 under the terms of a United Nations-sponsored peace accord.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880626-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-26-88 1006EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i BC-PlaneCrash 1stAdd   06-26 0064</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Plane Crash, 1st Add,a0748,0064</SECOND>
<HEAD>MULHOUS: sources said</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 The twin-engine aircraft, which has just gone into service, has a capacity of 150 passengers. The plane was carrying specially invited guests on a demonstration flight that was part of an air show. The officials in the district government office said there was substantial damage. Medical evacuation helicopters and ambulances rushed to the scene.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>MORE</NOTE>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880626-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-26-88 1130EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Brites     06-26 0577</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Brites,0598</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bright and Brief</HEAD>
<DATELINE>RALEIGH, Miss. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The world-record holder in long-distance tobacco spitting won his ninth accuracy title in the 34th annual National Tobacco Spitting Contest, but was upset in the distance contest by a novice. Restaurateur <PERSON> Jeff </PERSON> <PERSON> Barber </PERSON>, 27, of <LOCATION> Ocean </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Springs </LOCATION> hit three bull's - eyes in three attempts to take the accuracy title Saturday, proving he did n't bite off more than he But in the distance competition, <PERSON> Barber </PERSON>, nicknamed `` The Faucet,'' spat 27 feet, 5 inches, far short of his 33 feet, 7 -LCB- - inch effort listed in the Guinness Book of World Records Newcomer <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Singleton </PERSON>, 18, of <LOCATION> Raleigh </LOCATION>, took the 1988 distance title with a spit of 28 feet, 10 inches. Eschewing health warnings about the dangers of chew, 11 men turned out for the accuracy contest and an even dozen for the distance. In the women's contest, two showed up at <PERSON> Billy </PERSON> <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Crumpton </PERSON>'s farm 5 miles west of this <LOCATION> Smith </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> town. Defending champion <PERSON> Peggy </PERSON> <PERSON> Woods </PERSON>, 31, of <PERSON> Brandon </PERSON> took her third consecutive title with a spit of 15-2 -LCB- to win the women's title. An accuracy contest was not held for the women. <PERSON> Woods </PERSON> said she could have spat farther, but the heat brought on by the continuing drought had dried out her mouth.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>DECATUR, Ill. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 You could say <PERSON> Kenny </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> and <PERSON> Lisa </PERSON> <PERSON> Rhodes </PERSON> got married, but a better word for it might be hitched. The two truckers were married in traditional attire in a traditional church Saturday, but the entourage that waited outside consisted of 12 decorated tractor-trailers and 35 cars blaring their horns in a connubial convoy. After the ceremony, <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>, an employee of <PERSON> Owen </PERSON> <PERSON> Mathias </PERSON> <PERSON> Trucking </PERSON> of Assumption, jumped in his rig, `` Bar <PERSON> Hopper </PERSON>,'' with his bride, and the convoy was off. The group, chatting via <ORGANIZATION> CB </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> radio </ORGANIZATION>, trucked through downtown <LOCATION> Decatur </LOCATION>, turning heads and drawing laughs from passers-by, as well as honks from other motorists. `` This is all right,'' said the bride, a clerk for <ORGANIZATION> ADM </ORGANIZATION> Trucking in <LOCATION> Decatur </LOCATION> who gets her trucking license in July. `` It's definitely different.'' `` It's just neat,'' <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> said of the turnout. `` I ca n't believe it all happened. I did n't expect this many.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NASHVILLE, Tenn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION>'s new automobile license plates have given some county clerks a devil of a problem, but others are managing to exorcise the trouble. Several clerks have been fielding complaints from motorists who are unhappy that the number on their new three-letter, three digit tags is 666 _ which some believe is the mark of the devil. `` Most of them wo n't take it when they get it,'' said <PERSON> Davidson </PERSON> County Clerk <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Covington </PERSON>. `` You might draw the wrong kind of crowd.'' <PERSON> Covington </PERSON> said his office has withdrawn the 666 plates from <LOCATION> Davidson </LOCATION> <LOCATION> county </LOCATION>'s stockpile _ all 366 of them. `` The thought never entered out minds,'' said <PERSON> Danny </PERSON> <PERSON> Shelton </PERSON>, manager of <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION>'s license plate program of the 666 combination, which occurs every thousand plates. `` Registrants do not have to accept the plates when they're issued.'' Not all motorists have felt compelled to reject the number _ even one who's a man of the cloth. `` A lot of people mentioned it to me, especially since I'm a minister,'' said <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Miller </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Nashville </LOCATION>, pastor of the <ORGANIZATION> Tusculum </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Christ </ORGANIZATION>, who accepted a plate with 666. `` The beast is very, very evil. But it has nothing to do with what number is on your license plate or your Social Security card.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880626-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-26-88 1133EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i BC-PlaneCrash 2ndLd-Writethru   06-26 0306</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Plane Crash, 2nd Ld - Writethru,a0751,0310</SECOND>
<HEAD>New Jet Crashes During Air Show; Two Dead, 60 Hurt</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: UPDATES throughout with two dead, quote from passenger, other
details of crash; picks up 3rd graf pvs: An official...</NOTE>
<DATELINE>MULHOUSE, France (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An Airbus A320 jetliner carrying 127 people crashed during an air show in eastern <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>, killing at least two people and injuring 60, district government officials said. Witnesses said the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> France </ORGANIZATION> jet, which went into service a month ago, clipped some trees at the edge of an airport runway and crashed in a field nearby. An unidentified passenger, a 25-year-old woman, was quoted by <PERSON> Agence </PERSON> <PERSON> France-Presse </PERSON> as saying that she heard she heard tree branches rub against the plane's fuselage. `` Things started moving fast,'' she said. `` The plane hit the ground hard and we had the feeling of a abrupt jolt. Then there was a fire in the front of the aircraft.'' She was quoted as saying that the plane's evacuation chutes were deployed and many passengers aboard slid down and got off, running a distance from the plane because they feared an explosion. The twin-engine jet was taking part in an air show in overcast, humid weather. An official at the <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transport </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> said the accident occurred at 2:50 p.m. -LRB- 8:50 a.m. EDT -RRB- while the plane was on a low-altitude demonstration flight above the Mulhouse-Habsheim airport. He spoke on condition of anonymity. Medical evacuation helicopters and ambulances rushed to the airport, located about 18 miles north of the <LOCATION> Swiss </LOCATION> city of Bale. The new twin-engine plane can carry 163 people. It features a fully computerized flight-control system and went into service last month with <LOCATION> Air </LOCATION> <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> and <ORGANIZATION> British </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airways </ORGANIZATION>. The plane is manufactured by <ORGANIZATION> Airbus </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Industrie </ORGANIZATION>, a consortium of European aircraft companies led by its French and German partners.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880626-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-26-88 1212EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-China-Accident     06-26 0275</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-China-Accident,0283</SECOND>
<HEAD>Pakistani Foreign Minister's Car In Accident</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The car carrying Pakistani Foreign Minister <PERSON> Sahabzada </PERSON> <PERSON> Yaqub-Khan </PERSON> crashed into the back of a Jeep on Sunday and slightly injured a Chinese woman, Pakistani officials said. <PERSON> Yaqub-Khan </PERSON> expressed regret over the accident and concern for the woman when he met later with Chinese Foreign Minister <PERSON> Qian </PERSON> <PERSON> Qichen </PERSON>. <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> Embassy official <PERSON> Nisarullah </PERSON> <PERSON> Baluch </PERSON> said the jeep was ahead of the foreign minister's convoy, which was driving from the airport. The Jeep's driver misunderstood police signals to pull over and instead stopped, and the foreign minister's car struck it in the rear. A woman who was sitting in the back of the open-ended vehicle fell out, <PERSON> Baluch </PERSON> said. He said she was taken to a hospital with a slight head injury. <PERSON> Yaqub-Khan </PERSON> is the first Pakistani official to visit <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> since <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>'s President <PERSON> Mohammad </PERSON> <PERSON> Zia </PERSON> <PERSON> Ul-haq </PERSON> abruptly dissolved the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION> and dismissed Prime Minister <PERSON> Mohammad </PERSON> <PERSON> Khan </PERSON> <PERSON> Junejo </PERSON> and other ministers on May 29. <PERSON> Zia </PERSON> acted just as <PERSON> Junejo </PERSON> returned home from a trip to <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Yaqub-Khan </PERSON>, who resigned as foreign minister last year for personal reasons, has resumed the post in a caretaker government pending elections. In a speech prepared for delivery at a welcome banquet given by <PERSON> Qian </PERSON>, he said the fact that his first visit in office was to <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> showed the `` exception relationship'' between the two countries. <PERSON> Yaqub-Khan </PERSON> is scheduled to meet Monday with Chinese Premier <PERSON> Li </PERSON> <PERSON> Peng </PERSON>. Topics are likely to include <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>, where both countries long have pushed for the current Soviet withdrawal. <PERSON> Li </PERSON>, who took office in April, has promised his first trip abroad will be to <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880626-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-26-88 1214EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Drought-TheWinners Bjt   06-26 0805</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Drought-The Winners, Bjt,0826</SECOND>
<HEAD>Farmer Has 14,000 Bushels Of Wheat On Hand To Weather Drought</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BOB IMRIE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>STERLING, N.D. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Four steel bins filled with unsold grain are <PERSON> Mel </PERSON> <PERSON> Rodenburg </PERSON>'s hedge against a drought that wiped out his 1,300 acres of wheat, oats and rye this spring. As the drought drags on and grain prices soar, he's one of thousands of farmers who stand to make a tidy profit from selling their share of the billions of bushels of wheat and corn stockpiled around the nation. `` The drought makes it tough going, but, yes, we are going to get along quite comfortably,'' said <PERSON> Rodenburg </PERSON>. <PERSON> Rodenburg </PERSON>, 57, has 14,000 bushels of wheat stored in the bins on his 3,000-acre farm. The wheat is worth $ 3.85 a bushel, up $ 1.15 from a few weeks ago. The price likely will rise much more, perhaps as high as $ 7 a bushel, some have speculated. While some farmers worry whether they will have anything to sell at all this year, <PERSON> Rodenburg </PERSON> and his 26-year-old son, <PERSON> Alan </PERSON>, worry whether they will sell too soon. `` If you sold it this week and it made another $ 1 jump next week, it would make you feel sick,'' <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Rodenburg </PERSON> said. `` If you screw up a decision this year, you are screwing up. It just about gives you an ulcer trying to figure out what to do.'' The Rodenburgs represent a segment of the nation's farmers likely to withstand the worst drought since the Dust Bowl days of the 1930s. According to the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, farmers hold at least half of the 1.2 billion bushels of wheat and 5.6 billion bushels of corn in storage. In <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION>, the nation's second-largest wheat producer after <ORGANIZATION> Kansas </ORGANIZATION>, 300 million bushels of wheat are held in storage, an amount equal to the state's average annual yield, according to the state <ORGANIZATION> Wheat </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION>. `` People who do hold these stocks and do sell them are going to make a nice profit on it,'' said <PERSON> Brad </PERSON> <PERSON> Karem </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>'s farm program analyst. `` I think that's private enterprise,'' said <PERSON> Milton </PERSON> <PERSON> Hertz </PERSON>, head of the <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. Agricultural Stabilization and <ORGANIZATION> Conservation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>. `` It's terrible that a drought has to create something like that.'' Some of <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION>'s farmers have as much as 60,000 bushels of grain, mostly wheat, stored on their farms and under government loan, estimated <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Falk </PERSON>, an <ORGANIZATION> ASCS </ORGANIZATION> price support specialist in <LOCATION> Fargo </LOCATION>. Farmers stand to make a profit on the stockpiled grain, even if they have to pay off their government loans to get it out of storage, said <PERSON> Neal </PERSON> <PERSON> Fisher </PERSON>, deputy administrator of the state <ORGANIZATION> Wheat </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION>. At last year's loan rate, they could make $ 1.50 to $ 2 a bushel, he said. <PERSON> Rodenburg </PERSON> is hesitant to talk about his good fortune at a time the drought could drive some of his neighbors out of business. The most he will say is that his farm income could be half of normal: `` But I do n't know. Let's leave it like that.'' A combination of insurance, government help, good planning and plain good luck will offset his losses. Insurance covers the seed and fertilizer on the crops that were destroyed. His land payments are minimal, since he owns 2,000 acres of his farm free and clear. What debt he does have is covered by $ 37.50-an-acre government payments on 900 acres of highly erodible land he took out of production. An emergency measure by the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> let him cut the healthy crop of alfalfa on that land for hay. He'll lose some of his government payment on the land he hays, but the first field he cut produced about 1 -LCB- tons per acre, and he thinks hay may eventually sell for as much as $ 100 a ton. The potential income `` is going to be unreal,'' more than enough to pay for the baler he recently bought at a farm auction, he said. The government also may make up for the income <PERSON> Rodenburg </PERSON> lost when his crop was destroyed. Farm-belt members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> want the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration to pay farmers the price guaranteed them when grain prices were low. That subsidy could mean at least $ 10,000 to $ 15,000 more for <PERSON> Rodenburg </PERSON>. Years of `` hard work and reasonably good management'' allowed <PERSON> Rodenburg </PERSON> to pay off loans on the 2,000 acres of land he owns debt-free, but his fortunes could take a drastic turn if the drought lasts another season, he said. `` Next year, if we are standing here like this and under the same circumstances, I will be painting a far gloomier picture for us,'' he said, standing in the baking afternoon sun alongside his grain bins. `` I think I would be better off getting a good crop,'' the farmer said. `` I do n't believe you could ever have a drought where it indirectly really benefits you.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880626-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-26-88 1212EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w AM-SolarDisturbances     06-26 0392</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Solar Disturbances,400</SECOND>
<NOTE>For Release at 6:30 p.m. EDT</NOTE>
<HEAD>Record Solar Disturbances Possible</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RANDOLPH E. SCHMID</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Sunspot activity is increasing rapidly and, during the next few years, could lead to the most intense solar disturbances ever recorded, the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Oceanic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Atmospheric </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> said Sunday. Intense disturbances on the sun can have serious effects on <LOCATION> Earth </LOCATION>, including interference with broadcasting, damage to sensitive electronic systems in satellites and disturbances in electrical power and telephone transmissions. Some scientists also have speculated that activity on the sun could affect the climate on <LOCATION> Earth </LOCATION>, an idea that has prompted considerable controversy in the meteorological community. Changes in rainfall patterns have occurred roughly in parallel with changes on the sun over the years. However, proving that the two are connected has, so far, eluded science. Sunspots occur in cycles of approximately 11 years. Climatologists have found slight variations in rainfall patterns in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> over periods of 11 years in the central and western states and over 22 years in the eastern states. The current cycle began in September 1986 and already has seen record rates of increase in sunspots and radiation from the sun, according to <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Heckman </PERSON>, head of the <ORGANIZATION> NOAA-Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Space </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Environment </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Boulder </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Colo </LOCATION><LOCATION> . </LOCATION> The most active previous solar cycle occurred in 1958. Activity on the sun is already at about the same rate as in that year, but with somewhat more intensity. <PERSON> Heckman </PERSON> noted that in a typical cycle sunspots increase to their maximum in about 4.3 years and then take some 6.6 years to decline to a minimum again. But cycles with rapid increases, as in the current case, have higher and earlier maximum levels. Sunspots themselves do not affect the Earth, but are used as indicators of other solar activity which does, such as solar flares and geomagnetic storms, bombarding the Earth with radiation. Among the potential problems associated with an increase in solar activity, according to <PERSON> Heckman </PERSON>, are: _ Increasing activity by the aurora borealis or northern lights -LRB- also the aurora australis, or southern lights, in <LOCATION> Antarctica </LOCATION> -RRB- _ Interference with some kinds of radio communications and broadcasts _ Disturbances in electrical power transmission systems, pipelines and long-line telephone networks _ Damage to satellites' electronic systems _ Altered orbits of some satellites _ Radiation hazards to astronauts and aircraft passengers at high altitudes
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880626-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-26-88 1215EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Pope-EastBloc     06-26 0489</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Pope-East Bloc,0503</SECOND>
<HEAD>Pontiff Reaches Out to Eastern Europe's Catholics</HEAD>
<HEAD>With AM-Pope, Bjt</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KEVIN COSTELLOE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>VIENNA, Austria (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Pope <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> II </PERSON> has used his Austrian tour to reach out to those nearby Roman Catholics whose Eastern bloc countries he has not been able to visit. While most attention on the five-day trip has focused on the pope's remarks about Jews and the Holocaust, <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> has also been looking to millions of Catholics in <LOCATION> Yugoslavia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Czechoslovakia </LOCATION>. On Saturday, about 20,000 Yugoslav Catholics crossed the border to the nearby Austrian town of <LOCATION> Gurk </LOCATION> for an outdoor Mass. The day before, the pope said Mass for 80,000 Catholics, mostly Yugoslavs and Hungarians, in the town of <LOCATION> Trausdorf </LOCATION> near the Hungarian border. The pope has visited <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>, his Communist homeland, three times since he became head of the <ORGANIZATION> Roman </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> in 1978. But so far, Communist governments have imposed barriers that have kept him from visiting millions of Catholics in <LOCATION> Czechoslovakia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Yugoslavia </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. Czechoslovak Catholics in particular have been in conflict with Communist authorities, who until this year had not permitted any new bishops in their country since 1973. Earlier this month, <LOCATION> Prague </LOCATION> authorities finally allowed three new ones. The estimated 20,000 Yugoslav Catholics joined about 40,000 Italians and Austrians for the outdoor Mass on Saturday in <LOCATION> Gurk </LOCATION>. `` You all give testimony of the power of Christian faith to overcome boundaries,'' <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> said. `` Coming from several cultures, you as the people of God speak the one language of common belief.'' `` Unfortunately today in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, even in your regions, the ancient roots of faith are threatened in various ways,'' the pontiff said, changing briefly from German to Italian in his homily. He continued: `` Christians must, however, react as a community to this challenge. They must unite even more and stay even closer together.'' On Friday, he said his Mass for the 80,000 Catholics, mostly Yugoslavs and Hungarians, in <LOCATION> Trausdorf </LOCATION>. Several hundred Poles and several dozen Czechs also were on hand. Addressing the local Austrian Catholics, the pontiff said: `` This diocese and its bishop are well aware of their function as a link in particular with the peoples of <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>.'' `` You are ready to cultivate contacts with them and to share with them, materially and spiritually,'' he said. `` Must not the salvation <PERSON> Christ </PERSON> has given us again be spread to the farthest bounds of <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>?'' Some Austrian newspapers hailed the Mass as a major gesture toward Eastern <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>. `` Trausdorf: A Signal for the East Bloc,'' trumpeted <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Kleine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Zeitung </ORGANIZATION> daily newspaper in its Saturday editions Other newspapers, though, felt that the pontiff had kept his remarks deliberately low-key, possibly in hope of not upsetting any chances he may have of visiting any new Eastern European countries. `` He overcame barriers by not putting up any,'' said the conservative Die Presse daily newspaper of <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880626-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-26-88 1217EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p AM-BushSurrogates Bjt   06-26 0981</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Bush Surrogates, Bjt,900</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush `Truth Squad' Could Number 100 By Fall</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TOM RAUM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> calls it his `` truth squad,'' an army of Republican stand-ins with orders to take shots at opponent <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>. The Democrat's camp has a less charitable label: `` hit squad.'' No matter the name, the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> surrogates _ made up of senators and <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> members, governors, and other prominent Republicans _ are already having an impact on the 1988 presidential race. The surrogates are fanning out across the country and criticizing the all-but-certain <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> nominee, sometimes speaking in the same cities hours before or after <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, a technique the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> campaign calls `` bracketing.'' For a national campaign strapped for cash, the tactic is inexpensive and enables the vice president to get mileage from the sharp attacks without having to utter the words himself. The Republican strategy became apparent during a <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> swing through the South last week when Sen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> McCain </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Ariz </LOCATION>., spoke in <LOCATION> Nashville </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> a day ahead of <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, branding the <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> governor soft on crime and an opponent of the death penalty <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> called it negative campaigning and derided <PERSON> McCain </PERSON> as someone who `` does n't know beans from brown bread.'' But the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> footwork was not lost on <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> strategists. A few days later, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> delivered a strong law-and-order speech to the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sheriffs </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Louisville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ky. </LOCATION>. After the room cleared, one sheriff lingered near the press area Wearing a large `` Dukakis'' sticker, he was hard to miss. Sheriff <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Rufo </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Suffolk </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mass. </LOCATION>, which includes the city of <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>, suggested the vice president _ not <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> _ lacked a crime-fighter's record. `` At all these conventions, there are going to be very strong <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> supporters. They're not going to be shy,'' said <PERSON> Leslie </PERSON> <PERSON> Dach </PERSON>, communications director for the <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> campaign. But <PERSON> Dach </PERSON> said that, while <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> will have some surrogate speakers, he will not field anywhere near the number that <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> is using. `` Ultimately, this kind of tactic is not going to work. <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s problem is he has n't articulated his own vision of the future. And that's what people want in a president, they're not looking for somebody who can organize a hit squad,'' <PERSON> Dach </PERSON> said. Although surrogates have been used before, including elected <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> officials who spoke out vociferously in 1984 in behalf of President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s re-election effort, the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> campaign is seeking to turn the practice into a science _ carefully targeting speakers to subjects and audiences. `` We have about 10 out there now. By the fall, we'll have 100,'' said <PERSON> Alixe </PERSON> <PERSON> Glen </PERSON>, a <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> spokeswoman. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, who says the surrogate speakers will play a vital part in his campaign, told reporters last week that he thinks the differences between him and <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> remain out of focus _ and that's where the surrogate speakers will help. `` I've got to spell it out -LRB- the differences -RRB- and get surrogates _ those other people who believe as I do _ to spell it out,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said. Some of the surrogates have specific assignments. For instance, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Sununu </PERSON>'s marching orders are to chip away at <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' so-called `` <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> miracle,'' which the neighboring governor derides as the `` <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> mirage.'' On Friday, for example, <PERSON> Sununu </PERSON> told reporters no one should be surprised at <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' signing a $ 40 million cigarette tax into law because `` everytime he's had a problem, he's run to a tax increase _ even when he ran the first time and gave an iron-clad commitment there would be no tax increase.'' Former <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Ed </PERSON> <PERSON> King </PERSON> is also speaking on behalf of <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> with the same message, and <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON> and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Kean </PERSON> have also been active as surrogates. To counter his high negatives among women voters, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> is counting on a number of prominent GOP women, including Rep. <PERSON> Lynn </PERSON> <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> and Sen. <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> <PERSON> Kassebaum </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> to get out the word that he is concerned with issues that affect women. Vanquished GOP presidential rivals Rep. <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> and Sen. <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> are also busy on the surrogate circuit. <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> minority leader, `` has already been to nine state conventions and we will be to 20,'' said <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> aide <PERSON> Walt </PERSON> <PERSON> Riker </PERSON>. `` He's just crashing his way downfield.'' The <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> campaign and the <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> are sharing the expenses of the surrogate program. But one Republican skeptical of the ultimate value of the technique is <PERSON> McCain </PERSON>, the <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION> senator who dogged <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> in the South. `` The <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> people were clearly stunned by this,'' said <PERSON> McCain </PERSON>, noting that Democrats retaliated by attacking him at home for missing <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> votes while campaigning for <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. `` I was gone 24 hours. I missed five votes, all of which were either non-essential or carried by margins such as 92-to-3.'' <PERSON> McCain </PERSON> said that surrogate speakers have been used extensively in the past by both parties and that he believes the concept `` is helpful but only minimally'' to candidates. `` That's why I was intrigued at the way <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> and his people overreacted,'' <PERSON> McCain </PERSON> said. `` I think it's ridiculous that he responds by saying I do n't know the difference between beans and brown bread. What kind of response is that?'' <PERSON> McCain </PERSON>, who said he does know the difference, is turning down the <ORGANIZATION> RNC </ORGANIZATION>'s offer to pay for his trip. Sen. <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Simpson </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION>, who expects to speak extensively in the West, said the surrogate program is a chance to correct what he claims are misconceptions among voters that are hurting <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> in the polls. `` A lot of the polls show either two-fifths or three-fifths of the people polled said that <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> was more conservative than <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. That is n't a loss of focus, that's a loss of your eyeglasses,'' <PERSON> Simpson </PERSON> said. `` There is n't any way <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> is going to pull that one off.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880626-0025 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-26-88 1219EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p AM-Dukakis-Furlough Bjt   06-26 0858</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Dukakis-Furlough, Bjt,880</SECOND>
<HEAD>Massachusetts Furlough Program At Center Of Dukakis-Bush Crime
Debate</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN KING</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BOSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 As Republican <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> wages an aggressive effort to portray <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> as a liberal who is soft on crime, the man at the center of the vice president's pitch is behind bars in a <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION> prison. Convicted murderer and rapist <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Horton </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> is as much a part of the debate over crime this presidential campaign season as the opposite views on the death penalty espoused by the two candidates. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> now mentions <PERSON> Horton </PERSON> by name, in campaign rhetoric laced with attacks on a <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> furlough program that allowed <PERSON> Horton </PERSON> to be released from prison although he was serving a life sentence for murdering a 17-year-old boy. In 1987, during his 10th furlough, <PERSON> Horton </PERSON> fled to <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION>, twice raped a woman and assaulted her fiance. `` I think Governor <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> owes the people of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> an explanation,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said last week in <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION>. `` What did the Democratic governor of <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> think he was doing when he let convicted first-degree murderers out on weekend passes?'' A day earlier, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was told of <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' statement that 45 states and the federal prison system offer some form of furlough. The vice president responded that `` none, except <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION>, had furlough programs for first-degree murderers.'' But, according to several correctional associations and publications, at least 16 states offer furloughs to first-degree murderers. <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> no longer is among them: <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> reluctantly signed a law banning first-degree lifers from furloughs. `` <PERSON> Ralph </PERSON> <PERSON> Waldo </PERSON> <PERSON> Emerson </PERSON> said that foolish consistency is the hobgoblin of little minds,'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> said when he signed the bill in April. `` I try to listen; I try to learn.'' Since the <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> program began in 1972, 117,700 furloughs were granted to 10,553 inmates. Of the 426 escapes, 11 occurred during the 4,908 furloughs granted to first-degree murderers. `` <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> actually had a pretty good record,'' said <PERSON> Brian </PERSON> <PERSON> Bemus </PERSON>, a researcher at the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corrections </ORGANIZATION> data center in <LOCATION> Boulder </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Colo. </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has amended his attack on the furlough program, accurately saying in recent days that <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION>, until April, had the only furlough program in the nation for inmates sentenced to life without parole Campaign aides say the vice president will continue his attack. `` He finds this program of furloughing murderers with no-parole sentences represents the worst sort of approach to crime,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> spokeswoman <PERSON> Alixe </PERSON> <PERSON> Glen </PERSON> said Friday. `` The furlough issue is important because it shows how <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' record on crime contrasts with the vice president's positions. As this issue has been elevated, I think the <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> people are shocked at the <PERSON> Willie </PERSON> <PERSON> Horton </PERSON> example.'' Faced with growing criticism from <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and increased media attention on the furlough program, the <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> camp has fired back with national furlough statistics showing the <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> furlough-escape rate is below average and by invoking the name of <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s boss, President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, who as governor of <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> supported furloughs even after two convicts killed people while on furlough in the early 1970s. Like <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> inherited the furlough program from a governor of the opposition party. `` These are part and parcel of all kinds of responsible correction programs,'' says <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, who has spent much of the past week defending the <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> program, largely by citing a 14 percent drop in crime in his state over the past five years. `` Our view is that the vice president is trying, through the furlough issue, to obscure the facts,'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> issues adviser <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Herman </PERSON> said in an interview. `` The fact is that while crime is going up nationally, crime is dropping dramatically in <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION>. `` He also is using it to obscure the unenviable crimefighting record of the Reagan-Bush administration,'' said <PERSON> Herman </PERSON>, who spent much of last week researching furlough programs. `` <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> is reacting to this issue in a sense that tells me he's running scared.'' If the criticisms continue, aides say, look for <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> to adopt the strategy he used when former rival Sen. <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> criticized the <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> furlough program during the primary campaign. `` Al, the difference between you and me is that I have to run a criminal justice system. You never have,'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> said during an April debate in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>. That kind of response to <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> would fit in with the <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> strategy to attempt to characterize <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> as a do-nothing vice president. Among corrections officials and criminoligists, furloughs are considered an effective rehabilitation tool. `` Most knowledgeable correctional workers, prisoners and others interested in work furlough see it as a progressive correctional program,'' said a 1975 review of one program _ that of then-California Gov. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>. `` There is no way that we're ever going to be 100 percent able to give you a program where the parole board or the furlough program has fallen down,'' said Professor <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Fox </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> Northeastern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Criminal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION>. He also questioned the relevance of the furlough issue in presidential politics. `` If freeing a murderer on furlough is the issue, then it's moot because murder is, except for in rare cases, a state crime and the president does n't really deal with murderers,'' <PERSON> Fox </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880626-0026 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-26-88 1220EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Bangladesh-Rain     06-26 0174</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Bangladesh-Rain,0182</SECOND>
<HEAD>Nine Killed, Thousands Homeless In Rain</HEAD>
<DATELINE>DHAKA, Bangladesh (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Torrential rains in various parts of <LOCATION> Bangladesh </LOCATION> have killed nine people and left thousands homeless, officials and press reports said Sunday. Six people drowned Saturday when their boats sank in heavy rains on the overflowing Matamuhuri river near the port city of <LOCATION> Chittagong </LOCATION>, about 100 miles southeast of <LOCATION> Dhaka </LOCATION>, newspaper reports said. Two people died in northern <LOCATION> Sherpur </LOCATION> district and one in neighboring <LOCATION> Netrokona </LOCATION> district when more than 5,000 mud and straw huts collapsed during heavy monsoon rains, the <PERSON> Dainik </PERSON> <PERSON> Bangla </PERSON> said. About 25,000 people were left homeless. More than 200,000 people in <LOCATION> Sunamganj </LOCATION> district were trapped on the roofs and terraces of their homes, the reports said. The waters of the northeastern rivers <PERSON> Surma </PERSON>, Someswari and <PERSON> Muhuri </PERSON> rose above the danger point following the rains, the <ORGANIZATION> Dainik </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bangla </ORGANIZATION> reported. Relief officials in <LOCATION> Sherpur </LOCATION> said government rescue teams moved almost 10,000 people to shelters. Since last month, about 50 people have died in monsoon flooding in <LOCATION> Bangladesh </LOCATION>, according to press reports.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880626-0027 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-26-88 1221EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p AM-ConventionProblems     06-26 0858</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Convention Problems,850</SECOND>
<HEAD>Democrats Confront Problems As Clock Toward Convention Winds Down</HEAD>
<HEAD>With AM-Political Rdp, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID SIMPSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ATLANTA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 With less than a month to go before the Democratic National Convention, incomplete housing arrangements threaten the party's hopes for a smooth kickoff to its biggest media event of the year. But some of those who will be covering the gathering say they do n't expect problems severe enough to be noticed by the Democrats' real audience _ the millions of <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> voters who be will watching or reading about the convention across the country While the city has been sprucing up for the visitors, the host committee and party organizers sometimes have been slow to provide information to reporters and others who have to make arrangements of their own, said <PERSON> Jane </PERSON> <PERSON> Maxwell </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Cable </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Network </ORGANIZATION>'s vice president for special events. But she said the problems probably wo n't affect the picture <ORGANIZATION> CNN </ORGANIZATION> presents to the public. `` The fact is we have to be ready for the event because they are n't going to delay it for us,'' she said. Ms. <PERSON> Maxwell </PERSON> and her counterpart at <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Buksbaum </PERSON>, gave convention organizers good marks for helping with television coverage. The complaints from news organizations center on off-the-floor matters, especially housing. `` Hotel rooms are really a problem,'' said <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> producer <PERSON> Phil </PERSON> <PERSON> Alongi </PERSON>, who said the network has received only a few rooms in downtown hotels. `` I just ca n't find enough words to describe how much trouble they're going to be in,'' said <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Clark </PERSON>, the office manager of the <ORGANIZATION> Los </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Angeles </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION>' <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> bureau, who said housing arrangements started much later in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> than in previous convention cities. The convention has fared better on other fronts. A newly opened rapid rail station at <ORGANIZATION> Hartsfield </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Atlanta </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airport </ORGANIZATION> means delegates can reach downtown in 15 minutes for an 85-cent fare. Those traveling the route by car will have to contend with ongoing construction on the I-75-85 `` downtown connector,'' but the disarray has not proved a major problem to larger conventions. The city long ago gave up on Mayor <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> <PERSON> Young </PERSON>'s initial hope that a renovated Underground <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> entertainment district could open in time for the convention, but delegates will be offered excursions on a steam-powered train line newly extended to the Stone Mountain tourist attraction. Once the <ORGANIZATION> Atlanta </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hawks </ORGANIZATION> were defeated in the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Basketball </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> playoffs, workers began building the huge stage, network anchor booths and other fixtures of the convention at the Omni Coliseum. `` It does seem finally to be coming together and more and more of the details are slowly being revealed,'' said <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Cooper </PERSON>, associate editor of the <ORGANIZATION> Akron </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Beacon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Journal </ORGANIZATION> and deputy convention manager for <ORGANIZATION> Knight-Ridder </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON>, a senior producer at <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, said, `` We are on schedule and there's nothing new from any other convention in dealing with Democrats They always appear to be somewhat disorganized in the very beginning and then everything seems to fall in place.'' <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON> said his network has rejected some of its assigned hotel rooms because they are not close enough for key personnel. Some disputes were inevitable because some of the convention hotels are located in the suburbs. Ms. <PERSON> Clark </PERSON>, who has worked on six previous political conventions, said the situation was made worse when organizers started making assignments much too late. Overbooking can be expected, she said, leading to a last-minute scramble for canceled rooms. In <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>'s case, she said, `` They're going to have chaos. And if maintenance workers strike the <ORGANIZATION> Atlanta </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hilton </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; Towers, as threatened in a long labor dispute, delegates from <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION> will be looking for new rooms. Convention spokeswoman <PERSON> Ruth </PERSON> <PERSON> Berry </PERSON> said hotel managers were told in an April letter it would be July 11 before housing plans could be finalized. She said only three of 107 managers responded with questions about the arrangements. But one hotel manager who asked not to be named said, `` I ca n't even get the Democrats to return a phone call I've been calling them for a week. That tells me that they ca n't tell me anything because they're still confused.'' `` I think it's fair to say we're behind schedule,'' Ms. <PERSON> Berry </PERSON> said. `` We're in a different situation than <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> -LRB- site of the 1984 convention -RRB-. <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> had a lot more downtown hotel rooms. But everybody will get one.'' <PERSON> Wally </PERSON> <PERSON> Podrazik </PERSON>, co-director of media arrangements and facilities and a veteran of three previous conventions, says everything will be ready in time. <PERSON> Podrazik </PERSON> took over in late May, succeeding <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Ferrante </PERSON> who was dismissed after complaints that the media effort was disorganized. `` I was coming in just about when people were giving final answers or close to final answers'' on convention logistics, <PERSON> Podrazik </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Maurice </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>, superintendent of the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Photographers </ORGANIZATION>' Gallery, said efforts to coordinate coverage have been hampered because of delays in receiving plans for photographers. <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>, who has worked on four previous Democratic conventions in his current position and covered others as a news photographer dating back to 1948, said, `` They're usually hectic, but this is a lot worse than previous ones.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880626-0028 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-26-88 1221EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-SouthKorea     06-26 0475</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-South Korea,0490</SECOND>
<HEAD>Students Battle Riot Police Around Cathedral</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto SEL2,4</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BARRY RENFREW</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SEOUL, South Korea (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
