<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881026-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-26-88 2331EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-Reagan-MoscowEmbassy     10-26 0265</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Reagan-Moscow Embassy,250</SECOND>
<HEAD>Reagan to Recommend Moscow Embassy to be Razed and Rebuilt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> will recommend that the almost-complete <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> be destroyed and rebuilt because of fears it contains sophisticated eavesdropping devices, <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> reported in its Thursday editions. The newspaper quoted <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> sources as saying the president's decision was expected to be announced Thursday. It probably would cost $ 300 million and take five years to build a new eight-story embassy on the same site with materials imported from the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and kept under heavy guard after they arrived in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, the paper reported. <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> sources have said that Secretary of State <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> recommended the move to <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>. The <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration believes the embassy building, which was mostly completed by 1985, includes structural elements riddled with sophisticated devices that were intended for eavesdropping. However, details on those findings have not been released. The current plan, the <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> reported, is to fabricate the building's main elements in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, ship them to the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, keep them under heavy guard and have the building assembled by <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> workers taken to <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> for the construction project. The embassy building originally was to have been completed by 1983. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s recommendation would be made to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, and officials said they believed lawmakers would insist on a full study of the matter. <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> has adjourned for the year. <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> officials said that while the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> embassy is being constructed, Soviet officials in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> will be barred from occupying their long-completed embassy office building.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881026-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-26-88 2342EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-UrbanChildren 2ndLd-Writethru a0780 10-26 0875</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Urban Children, 2nd Ld-Writethru, a0780,770</SECOND>
<HEAD>Study Says Urban Children Face Bleak Future</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: INSERTS 2 grafs after 8th graf bgng: ``Among survey...'' to
add new study; picks up 9th graf pvs, bgng: ``Mann said...''
^By DENISE CABRERA</NOTE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The future is bleak for many children in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s cities unless the next president and <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> make a commitment to solving some of their problems, a <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> mayor said Wednesday. `` Too many children in our cities have no future, no future at all unless we, as a nation, act on the problems they face today,'' said <PERSON> Theodore </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Mann </PERSON>, mayor of <LOCATION> Newton </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mass </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Mann </PERSON> is chairman of the human development committee of the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conference </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mayors </ORGANIZATION>, which on Wednesday released `` A Status Report on Children in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s Cities.'' The report `` calls attention to our collective failure as a nation to respond to these problems'' <PERSON> Mann </PERSON> said of the 52-city survey of mayors and human service officials. The study identifies drug abuse, weaknesses in education systems, the lack of affordable child care, teen-age pregnancy and school dropouts as key problems which have grown worse in the last five years in 80 percent of the cities surveyed. Officials said low-income children are confronted with the additional problems of homelessness and the lack of access to medical and mental health care. <PERSON> Kevin </PERSON> <PERSON> Moriarity </PERSON>, director of human services for <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Antonio </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, recounted some of the survey's gloomier statistics: three of 10 children in the cities surveyed lived in poverty in 1986; one in five was on welfare and received food stamps; 38 percent dropped out of school between the ninth grade and their scheduled high school graduation in the class of 1988; 15 percent of the babies born in 1986 were born to teen-age mothers; and a 12.6 percent infant mortality rate plagued the cities during that year. Among survey cities <LOCATION> Irvine </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, had the lowest overall poverty rate and child poverty rate in 1986 at 4.1 percent and 3.3 percent, respectively. The city with the highest 1986 overall poverty rate and child poverty rate was <LOCATION> Camden </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.J. </LOCATION>, at 42.3 percent and 61.1 percent, respectively. Meanwhile, the <ORGANIZATION> Urban </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> released a study, based on 1979 data, that showed that 17.1 percent of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> children lived in families with income below the poverty level. The poverty rate for children was 5.1 percent in <LOCATION> Sweden </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Switzerland </LOCATION> and 8.2 percent in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> Urban </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> study said the high <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> poverty rate among children occurs because programs for the poor cover fewer people and provide fewer benefits than programs in other industrialized countries. Officials said the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>' relative standing had changed little, if any, since 1979. <PERSON> Mann </PERSON> said the mayors' conference was not interested in placing blame for the current problems but was calling for a national partnership between the business community and federal, state and local governments. However most speakers at Wednesday's session of the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conference </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Human </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> Officials, an affiliate of the mayors' conference, emphasized increasing the federal government's role, both financially and in providing policy direction `` We've got to have more federal assistance, not just in funding but in policy,'' said <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Moran </PERSON>, mayor of <LOCATION> Alexandria </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION> `` We feel that we have done as much as we can and sometimes more,'' <PERSON> Moran </PERSON> said. `` We are losing middle-class residents because of high property taxes'' used to pay for needed services he said. <PERSON> Moran </PERSON> said his community, a prosperous suburb of <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, faces a growing problem of homelessness fueled by a high dropout rate. He cited an 18.6 percent dropout rate in 1987 among teen-age girls due to pregnancy. Among the cities surveyed, <LOCATION> Norfolk </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, had the highest dropout rate in the class of 1988. Seventy-one percent of <LOCATION> Norfolk </LOCATION>'s 1988 class left school from the ninth grade and 37 percent of the rest of those eligible for graduation in 1988 left in the tenth grade. But <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Raiss </PERSON>, a spokesman for the <LOCATION> Norfolk </LOCATION> public schools, called the group's numbers `` completely erroneous.'' The study did not take into account <LOCATION> Norfolk </LOCATION>'s transient population _ the city is home to the world's largest naval facility _ and the study counted as dropouts students who actually transferred from one school to another, who transferred out of the district and those who were not promoted for academic reasons, among others. According to figures supplied to the state of <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Norfolk </LOCATION> had a dropout rate of 8.1 percent in 1988, which was down from 9.1 percent in 1987 and 15.8 percent in 1981. The average wait for subsidized child care among surveyed cities was almost 10 months, while the wait for non-subsidized child care was 18 weeks, with costs running an average of $ 78 weekly at a center-based facility. Nationally, half the children under 6 have mothers who work outside the home. The group did not identify a specific amount they thought was needed from the federal government to address children's problems but <PERSON> Mann </PERSON> noted that both presidential candidates had emphasized children's issues in their campaigns. `` We need to hear more from each of them on a commitment of dollars. We need to hear that they are willing to make the enormous investment that the problems demand, and the children deserve,'' <PERSON> Mann </PERSON> added.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881026-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-26-88 2353EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-TrappedWhales 5thLd-Writethru a0813 10-26 1029</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Trapped Whales, 5th Ld-Writethru, a0813,1056</SECOND>
<HEAD>After Superpower Cooperation, Two Trapped Whales Are Freed At Last</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: SUBS 9th graf, `Scientists and ..., with 3 grafs to UPDATE
with night work, plans for Thursday; ADDS 1 graf with President
Reagan's reaction.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>LaserPhoto staffing</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>By BRUCE BARTLEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BARROW, Alaska (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Two whales trapped for nearly three weeks in the arctic ice pack were freed Wednesday by Soviet and American icebreakers, superpower saviors who hacked a path to the open sea. `` The whales are loose and in the channel and headed out,'' said Lt. <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Haller </PERSON>, a spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> Alaska </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION>. `` They looked good all afternoon. To look at them, you'd have thought they had their bags packed and were ready to head south.'' `` They're in the main lead, and I ca n't help but think they'll keep on truckin' I do n't know how much more we can do,'' said rescue coordinator <PERSON> Ron </PERSON> <PERSON> Morris </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Oceanic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Atmospheric </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>. The work to free the migrating <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> gray whales progressed rapidly Tuesday when two Soviet ice-breaking vessels began smashing the ice that kept the pair imprisoned. A third trapped whale is believed to have died last week. <PERSON> Morris </PERSON>, who followed the whales by helicopter, landed a little after 4 p.m. -LRB- 9 p.m. EDT -RRB- to report that the whales had moved from the final man-made breathing hole to the slushy path the Soviet icebreaker <PERSON> Vladimir </PERSON> <PERSON> Arseniev </PERSON> cut Tuesday night. Rescue officials were worried that the whales would have trouble breaking air holes through the partly frozen cut, but around 4:30 p.m. rescue workers found the two whales had opened a small breathing hole and were sharing it. One of the whales was bleeding enough to stain the water red. Spectators watched anxiously for several moments, waiting for the whales to surface in the new waterway cut Wednesday by the Arseniev _ and cheered joyously when the whales broke the surface. As darkness fell, the whales were swimming back and forth in the channel. Officials halted helicopter surveillance at nightfall, but said they planned to meet Thursday and could check whether the whales had reached the sea. The Arseniev stayed in the channel Wednesday night, widening the passage to the open sea, officials said. Scientists and others involved in the rescue may never know the whales' fate. `` A lot of people really did n't want to know,'' said <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Harvey </PERSON>, a federal marine biologist, after officials decided not to put electronic tracking tags on the already stressed animals. <PERSON> Haller </PERSON> said plans were being made in <LOCATION> Barrow </LOCATION> to thank the Soviets with a party, but Soviet officers said they would wait until it was clear the whales were in the open sea before celebrating. Before the whales were freed, as the Soviet icebreakers drew near, the whales were `` acting in a very excited manner, almost like they can sense freedom,'' said Sgt. <PERSON> Ian </PERSON> <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON>, an <ORGANIZATION> Alaska </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> spokesman. By midday, the Soviet icebreakers were a quarter-mile from the line of breathing holes being cut by Americans working in the opposite direction, he said. Later Wednesday, rescuers began to use a gargantuan, tractor-like device propelled by pontoon augers to clear the ice cut by the icebreaker, <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> said. The breakthrough in the effort to free the migrating gray whales caught in an early freeze came after more than a week of delays and disappointments. `` We feel very good about it,'' said Rear Adm. <PERSON> Sigmund </PERSON> <PERSON> Petersen </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> NOAA </ORGANIZATION>. `` The cooperation has just been fantastic. The Soviets came in here with a very positive attitude and went to work immediately.'' On Tuesday, the Americans moved the huge mammals around a shoal that had stymied progress for three days. Eskimos with chain saws cut a detour in the ice so the whales could swim around the shallow water they had refused to pass. When the Eskimos started cutting the air holes, the whales `` followed the water right to the end. They like that deeper water,'' <PERSON> Petersen </PERSON> said. Working in the other direction, the Soviet icebreakers reduced to rubble the ice ridge standing between the whales and open water. The ridge, formed by colliding ice masses, was a jumble of ice blocks as big as small houses. `` The whales seemed to be doing fine,'' <PERSON> Petersen </PERSON> said. `` It's like they expected something to be happening Everything seems to be coming together.'' The whales, which normally migrate to the <LOCATION> Southern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> coast in the winter, were discovered off <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>'s northern coast three weeks ago, the ice closing in around them and leaving them only a few small breathing holes. The whales could not swim the four miles to open water without surfacing for air. A third whale disappeared Friday and is believed dead. The icebreakers _ the Admiral <PERSON> Makarov </PERSON> and the <LOCATION> Arseniev </LOCATION> _ began working shortly after their arrival Tuesday, flying the flags of the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> as a sign of cooperation between the nations. The ships had been returning to their home port of <LOCATION> Vladivostok </LOCATION> when they were diverted, said <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON> <PERSON> Patzevich </PERSON>, chief officer and second in command. Although the Admiral <PERSON> Makarov </PERSON> has been at sea for six months and `` everybody is tired,'' none of the crew of 78 has complained about the diversion, <PERSON> Patzevich </PERSON> said. `` It's very nice to work together,'' he said of the U.S.-Soviet effort. First Mate <PERSON> Vladimir </PERSON> <PERSON> Moroz </PERSON>, who said he was the ship's political officer, said the Soviets were happy to help. He said he spoke to a <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> newspaper by telephone. `` They're receiving many, many calls asking about the whales,'' he said. `` Our country is watching like everyone else. We love animals, just as everyone.'' The population of endangered <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> gray whales has risen to about 20,000, growing at an annual average of 2.5 percent for the past decade, officials said. The whales have one of the longest migration routes of all the mammals, some 6,000 to 8,000 miles from the <LOCATION> Arctic </LOCATION> to the warm water off <LOCATION> Baja </LOCATION> <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>. `` The human persistence and determination by so many individuals on behalf of these whales shows mankind's concern for the environment,'' President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said from the White House. `` It has been an inspiring endeavor.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881026-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-26-88 0001EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--DoctorSlain     10-26 0177</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Doctor Slain,0181</SECOND>
<HEAD>Comatose Child Dies, Surgeons Protest Her Doctor's Slaying</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOCRI, Italy (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A 4-year-old girl has died four days after the surgery that left her in a coma and also apparently led to the Mafia-style murder of her surgeon, Italian media reported. <PERSON> Caterina </PERSON> <PERSON> Giampaolo </PERSON>, who died Tuesday, was the daughter of <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Giampaolo </PERSON>, a reputed local Mafia boss and fugitive who was sentenced to 27 years in prison in 1986 for kidnapping. The dead girl's uncle, <PERSON> Vincenzo </PERSON> <PERSON> Giorgi </PERSON>, 25, is being held for questioning by police in connection with the murder of her surgeon. <LOCATION> Locri </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION> proclaimed a `` day of silence'' Tuesday to protest the killing of Dr. <PERSON> Gino </PERSON> <PERSON> Marino </PERSON>, who operated on the girl Friday. <PERSON> Marino </PERSON> died early Sunday of gunshot wounds to the head. His killers ambushed his car Saturday night, shooting out a tire to stop it and then shooting <PERSON> Marino </PERSON>, police said. Various operating wards at hospitals throughout the southern region of <LOCATION> Calabria </LOCATION> also closed Tuesday to protest the lack of police protection for doctors, according to news reports.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881026-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-26-88 0003EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-PresidentialPolls     10-26 0738</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Presidential Polls,730</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush Has Double-Digit Lead in Two Polls</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Political Rdp Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GARY LANGER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Two national polls have found <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> consolidating his lead in the presidential race, with fewer voters saying they may change their minds _ although many remain dissatisfied with their choices. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> held double-digit leads in the <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News-New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> and Gallup polls released Tuesday, further evidence of a surge for the <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> nominee since his debate with Democrat <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> on Oct. 13. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> led <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> by 13 points among probable voters in the <ORGANIZATION> CBS-Times </ORGANIZATION> poll, 54-41 percent, and by 50-40 among registered voters in Gallup's poll. He led by 14 points among Gallup respondents judged likely to vote. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> had led by a consistent but narrow margin _ four to seven points in most polls _ since late August. But the numbers started to move in his favor last week, and the new results continued that trend. In one key finding, the CBS-Times poll found clear success in <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s attacks on <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> on crime. Sixty-two percent said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was tough enough in dealing with crime and criminals; just 37 percent said the same of <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>. In another, 25 percent said the political commercials they had seen helped them decide whom to support, and more than half of that group went for <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. Still, 62 percent said commercials had not helped them decide. The polls found dissatisfaction with both nominees. In the <ORGANIZATION> CBS-Times </ORGANIZATION> poll, 64 percent wished they had other choices than <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>. And just 42 percent of Gallup's respondents had a strong preference, compared with about 60 percent at this stage in the 1984 election. The surveys nonetheless found voters more firm in their decisions. In Gallup's, 28 percent said they were undecided or could change their minds _ down from 37 percent before the debate. In the <ORGANIZATION> CBS-Times </ORGANIZATION> poll, 74 percent said their minds were made up, compared with 66 percent earlier. As in other polls, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> received disproportionate support from men. They favored him by 54 percent to 38 percent in the Gallup poll, while women backed him by a far tighter 46 percent to 42 percent margin. The poll demonstrated that voter choices were based on the top of the ticket: The Democrats trailed even though <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' running mate, Sen. <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, was rated far more favorably than was <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s, Sen. <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> was viewed favorably by 59 percent, unfavorably by 27 percent; for <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> it was 42-44. Fifty-nine percent in the Gallup poll said they had a favorable opinion of <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, to 35 percent unfavorable. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> did less well _ 50 percent favorable, 43 percent unfavorable. The small remainders did n't answer. The leads in the two polls were less than the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> advantage in the first full-sized survey conducted after the Oct. 13 debate, an <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News-Wall </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Street </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Journal </ORGANIZATION> poll that found him ahead by 17 points. No other poll has found a <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> lead that great. It was followed by <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News-Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> and <PERSON> Harris </PERSON> polls that found sizable but smaller <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> leads _ seven and nine points respectively. Last weekend a <ORGANIZATION> Newsweek </ORGANIZATION> poll, done by Gallup, put the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> advantage at nine points, 50-41. The new Gallup poll released Tuesday was conducted Friday through Sunday among 1,232 registered voters and had margin of sampling error of plus or minus three points. Of the total, 815 were considered to be likely voters; the result among that group had a four-point error margin. The CBS-Times poll was conducted Friday through Monday among 1,287 probable voters and had a three-point error margin. Meanwhile, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> took a slight lead over <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> in a statewide poll in <LOCATION> Rhode </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION>, which was long thought to be safe territory for the Democrat from nearby <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION>. The poll, conducted by <ORGANIZATION> Joseph </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fleming </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ; </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associates </ORGANIZATION> for WPRI-TV, found <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> with 46 percent support, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> with 41 percent and 13 percent not sure. The survey of 414 registered voters was conducted last week and had a nearly five-point margin of error, meaning the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> lead is just large enough to be statistically significant. In the Democratic stronghold of <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> led <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> 51 percent to 42 percent, <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> reported in today's editions The Post survey of 601 likely voters was conducted Tuesday through Saturday and had a margin of error of four percentage points.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881026-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-26-88 0009EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-ClosingArguments Bjt   10-26 0740</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Closing Arguments, Bjt,750</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHINGTON TODAY: Echoes of Closing Arguments Heard at End of 1988
Contest</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP News Analysis</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DONALD M. ROTHBERG</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Political Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 When presidential campaigns enter their closing days, it's a good bet the candidate denouncing the negative tactics of his opponent is running behind. The first candidate to demand the opposition stop lying about his record is probably in trouble. The Democrat who turns to populism is trying to turn the tide. The Republican who warns against big spending is trying to do the same. That is the pattern of campaigns past and present. Sometimes it works. Echoes of those closing arguments are being heard as the 1988 presidential campaign winds down. `` Full of lies and he knows it,'' says a new <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> ad denouncing the negative campaign tactics of <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. The television spot closes with this dose of populism: `` The real question is will we have a president who fights for the privileged few, or will we have a president who fights for you.'' The <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> commercial was not the first time a candidate who felt he was losing to <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> accused the vice president of distorting his record. One of the more memorable moments of the campaign for the Republican presidential nomination was the night of the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION> primary. <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>, whose dream of winning the nomination had been shaken by <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION> victory, was asked if there was anything he wanted to say to the vice president. <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> glared at the camera and snapped, `` Yeah, tell him to stop lying about my record.'' It was all downhill from there for the Kansan who thought he could have won in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION> if the oppposition had n't portrayed him as soft on tax increases. But the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> attacks probably harmed <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> less in the long run than his demand that they stop. The senator's demeanor during that televised instant resurrected memories of his ill-fated run as the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> vice presidential nominee in 1976, a race he later would admit did not serve him well. <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> Truman </PERSON> wrote the book on how to upset a favored Republican opponent with a strong dose of populist rhetoric. `` I'm going to fight hard,'' <PERSON> Truman </PERSON> recalled telling his running mate, <LOCATION> Kentucky </LOCATION> Sen. <PERSON> Alben </PERSON> <PERSON> Barkley </PERSON>. `` I'm going to give them hell.'' <PERSON> Truman </PERSON> set the tone at his opening rally on Labor Day. `` If in this next election you get a <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and an administration friendly to labor you have much to hope for,'' he told a rally made up largely of union members. `` If you get a <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and an administration unfriendly to labor you have much to fear.'' <PERSON> Hubert </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Humphrey </PERSON> tried the same sort of populist appeal in the closing weeks of the 1968 presidential campaign against <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON>. The Minnesotan succeeded in bringing many Democrats back to the fold and the election turned out much closer than anybody had predicted. But <PERSON> Humphrey </PERSON> fell 510,000 votes short of overtaking <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON>. Or this: `` He has campaigned with negativism, failing the <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> people by refusing to lay out for them worthwhile programs in major fields which for two months I have been discussing in frankness and detail.'' That appeal sounds a little like the theme <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> now is sounding. But it was used by <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> in 1960 and directed at <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>. <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> said <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> `` advocates a Niagara of spending which would in the end either raise their taxes or prices and would cheapen their insurance policies, pensions and Social Security.'' `` I've got news for those Republicans, we're going to be the ones celebrating on election night,'' is a favorite <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> campaign line. `` The pollsters and the Republicans are in for the biggest surprise of their lives,'' said <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Mondale </PERSON>, the day before he lost 49 states. In the closing days of the 1976 campaign, President <PERSON> Gerald </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Ford </PERSON> said, `` I think we are neck and neck and when you have momentum and the opposition is trying to put its finger in every dike to try and stop the erosion, obviously we have the momentum going and they are frantic, frustrated and frenzied. `` And, gee, I just feel good about it, just wonderful.'' <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> did have momentum at that stage of the campaign, but not enough to overtake Democrat <PERSON> Jimmy </PERSON> <PERSON> Carter </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>___</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Rothberg </PERSON> is the chief political writer of <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881026-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-26-88 0011EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-SenateMoney     10-26 0468</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Senate Money,460</SECOND>
<HEAD>Incumbents Enjoy Advantage Over Challengers in Fund-Raising, Study
Says</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Political Rdp Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JIM DRINKARD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Incumbents in the nation's <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> races have rolled to a 3-to-1 advantage over challengers in fund raising this year, underlining the need for campaign finance reform, says the lobbying group Common Cause. Senators seeking re-election collected $ 102 million to finance their campaigns as of Sept. 30, compared with just $ 38 million for challengers, according to the group's analysis of reports submitted to the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Election </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION>. The analysis showed that one of four dollars flowing to contenders in the nation's 33 <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> races comes from special-interest groups, and incumbents enjoyed a 5-to-1 edge in receipts from the political action committees, or PACs. `` Special-interst PACs are money machines for incumbents,'' said <ORGANIZATION> Common </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cause </ORGANIZATION> president <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> Wertheimer </PERSON> in a statement. `` The congressional campaign finance system is patently unfair to challengers.'' The self-styled citizens lobby has been waging an uphill fight for years to restrict PAC giving to campaigns and to impose overall spending limits to give incumbents less of a lock on a <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> or <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> seat. Campaign finance reform is expected to be near the top of the list of legislative priorities when the 101st <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> convenes in January. <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> candidates had raised $ 161.7 million by Sept. 30, according to the analysis. Nearly $ 39 million of that came from PACs. Their financial edge enabled incumbents to spend $ 2 for every dollar spent by challenges, on average, and still go into the final month of the campaign with a huge cash advantage. Cash on hand for the 27 incumbents totaled $ 33.3 million as of Sept. 30, compared with just $ 7.3 million for their opponents. On average, incumbents raised $ 3.7 million each while challengers averaged $ 1.4 million each, the study found. In the six races where there is no incumbent seeking re-election _ <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Vermont </LOCATION> _ contenders have raised a total of $ 21.4 million, $ 4.7 million of it from PACs, a slightly greater proportion than in the other contests. The top fund-raiser overall, according to the study, is incumbent Sen. <PERSON> Pete </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON>, R-Calif. <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> had collected $ 12.5 million toward his re-election bid, and also topped the spending list with $ 9.8 million in expenditures <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> is one of the most expensive media states in which to mount a campaign. <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON>'s opponent, Democratic Lt. Gov. <PERSON> Leo </PERSON> <PERSON> McCarthy </PERSON>, had raised $ 5.4 million and spent $ 3.4 million on his challenge. The largest recipient of PAC money was Sen. <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>, who is waging dual campaigns for re-election to his <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> seat and as <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> vice presidential candidate. <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>, also chairman of the tax-writing <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Finance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, pulled in $ 2.3 million from special-interest groups. <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> ranked second on that list, with $ 2 million.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881026-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-26-88 0014EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-ThreeMileIsland     10-26 0494</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Three Mile Island,480</SECOND>
<HEAD>Panel Opposes Plan To Put Nuclear Reactor Into Storage</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JEFF BARKER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The operator of the contaminated <LOCATION> Three </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mile </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> nuclear plant hopes to mothball the reactor next year, but a panel of citizens and scientists says more commitments to clean up the site are needed first. A spokesman for the <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> plant's operator said Tuesday that managers hoped to go ahead with the plan to place the crippled Unit 2 reactor into `` monitored storage'' by the end of 1989. Next year will mark the 10th anniversary of the nation's worst commercial nuclear accident at Three Mile Island on March 31, 1979. The storage plan calls for the reactor building to be locked up and unneeded systems deactivated. The plant would sit for perhaps 30 years while radiation decays inside. Although the damaged nuclear fuel and loose radioactive components would have been removed from the plant, radiation would remain in piping and other areas of the reactor building basement. The Advisory Panel for the Decontamination of Unit 2 told the <ORGANIZATION> Nuclear </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Regulatory </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> during a meeting Tuesday that nine of its 11 members had sided against the so-called `` Post Defueling Monitored Storage plan,'' which is known as PDMS. <PERSON> Arthur </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Morris </PERSON>, the panel chairman and the mayor of <LOCATION> Lancaster </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION>, said many in the group felt the plan was too vague. He said the panel believed the cleanup `` should proceed expeditiously.'' With no specific funding in place, <PERSON> Morris </PERSON> said there were concerns that the cleanup of the plant might not be completed, even after the storage phase ended. In addition, he said area residents were troubled by the uncertainty of not knowing exactly how many years the reactor would sit idle until it was decommissioned. `` The utility seems to have looked at this PDMS as a given, and sort of expected us to go along with it,'' said panel member <PERSON> Joel </PERSON> <PERSON> Roth </PERSON>. In the 1979 accident, Unit 2 was allowed to lose vital cooling water that normally covers it. The subsequent $ 1 billion cleanup has focused on water decontamination, waste shipment and removal of fuel from the damaged core. <PERSON> Doug </PERSON> <PERSON> Bedell </PERSON>, a spokesman for <ORGANIZATION> GPU </ORGANIZATION> Nuclear, the plant operator, said in an interview after Tuesday's meeting that the cleanup would likely stop at the end of next year. He said it was pointless to expose cleanup workers to additional risk after that because remaining radiation would be `` fixed in place,'' presenting no threat to the public. He said the utility envisioned letting Unit 2 sit idle until after its twin, Unit 1, ended its service life in about the year 2010. Then, both units would be dismantled together. <ORGANIZATION> GPU </ORGANIZATION> Nuclear would need an amendment to its Nuclear Regulatory Commission license before it could proceed with its storage plan. The decision on whether to grant the change would be made by the <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION> staff, although it is possible the commissioners themselves would get involved.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881026-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-26-88 0018EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Reagan-Nicaragua     10-26 0316</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Reagan-Nicaragua,310</SECOND>
<HEAD>Reagan Bars Nicaraguan Diplomats</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By SUSANNE M. SCHAFER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> has banned most Nicaraguan government officials from entering the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> in the latest round of a tit-for-tat diplomatic feud. Under a proclamation released Tuesday by the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> declared `` the unrestricted ... entry of officers and employees of the Nicaraguan government and the <ORGANIZATION> Sandinista </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION> ... to be detrimental to the interests of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>.'' The prohibition applies to all Nicaraguan government and party officials with the exception of those carrying out activities related to the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> or other international organizations. Family members of such officials are exempted as well. The diplomatic tussle began on July 11, when <LOCATION> Managua </LOCATION> expelled <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. Ambassador <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Melton </PERSON> and seven other <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> officials on grounds they interfered in <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>'s internal affairs. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> retaliated the next day by expelling Nicaraguan Ambassador <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Tunnermann </PERSON> and seven of his colleagues. Since then, the Sandinista government has not acted on <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> attempts to replace the expelled <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> envoys. `` We've been trying to get our people replaced, and we have n't gotten anywhere,'' <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Roman </PERSON> <PERSON> Popadiuk </PERSON> said A call placed to the Nicaraguan Embassy seeking comment was not returned. The president's action also comes in light of a new restriction placed on <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials in <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> last month. On Sept. 22, the Sandinista government imposed the new requirement that <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> diplomats based in <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> who leave the country, for whatever reason, must wait at least three weeks before they may return. The dispute was aggravated last month when the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration refused to allow <LOCATION> Nicaraguan </LOCATION> President <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON> to bring a delegation of 60 Nicaraguans on a proposed visit to the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> and to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> said the Nicaraguans applied too late for their visas, a claim the <ORGANIZATION> Sandinistas </ORGANIZATION> denied. <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON> canceled the trip.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881026-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-26-88 0021EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Radon-Homes     10-26 0476</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Radon-Homes,470</SECOND>
<HEAD>Builders Say No Insulation Changes Needed to Combat Radon</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GUY DARST</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Home </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Builders </ORGANIZATION> says it wo n't recommend any changes in insulation practices to combat the buildup of radon, which government officials say is probably the second-ranking cause of lung cancer. At a news conference Tuesday, an official with the association said it is telling its members to continue employing `` the same practices we have recommended for years for energy conservation.'' <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Spears </PERSON>, program manager at the association's national research center, said, `` We've found that energy conservation has little to do with radon concentration in the house.'' <PERSON> Spears </PERSON>' conclusion `` tracks with our preliminary results over the past few years for both new homes and existing homes,'' said <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Chris </PERSON> <PERSON> Rice </PERSON>. EPA is engaged in a cooperative research program with the center. But <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> says increased ventilation still may be useful in reducing radon buildup in particular homes. Last month <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> advised that everyone living on a second floor or below should have indoor air tested for radon. The <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> issued a `` health advisory,'' elevating indoor radon to the same status as smoking as a health threat. <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> believes radon ranks second only to smoking as a cause of lung cancer. Of the 130,000 annual deaths from lung cancer, about 85 percent are caused by smoking. <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> estimates radon could cause as many as 20,000 deaths, which if true would be roughly all those not caused by smoking. Radon is a radioactive gas emitted in some degree by all soils. It quickly decays into other substances, but its decay products are also radioactive and can lodge in the lung, irradiating the tissue for a lifetime. Indoor dust and smoke, and smoke from tobacco products, can carry these decay products into the lung. There are many techniques for reducing radon buildup, often the same techniques that are used to keep water out of basements such as careful sealing of joints, use of tight covers on sumps and a thick polyethylene barrier between the slab and the ground. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Ethier </PERSON>, litigation counsel for the association, said members were being advised that `` if they make a reasoned judgment that there may be high radon levels,'' they should `` rough in'' mitigation techniques such as under-slab ventilation pipes that may be ignored later if appropriate, or connected to a fan to divert radon-laden air around the basement. In states such as <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> with well-publicized instances of radon buildup, <PERSON> Ethier </PERSON> said he has found `` universal'' adoption of such precautions by builders. Builders report that the techniques may add as little as $ 100 to the cost of a home, if water barriers are already being used, but as much as $ 600 if they are not, he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881026-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-26-88 0021EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-NewDrugs     10-26 0564</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-New Drugs,560</SECOND>
<HEAD>New Cancer Drug Released, 87 New Cardiovascular Drugs Studied</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 New drugs in the medical war against cancer and cardiovascular disease are now available or on the way. <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Food </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Drug </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> announced Tuesday that a new drug to treat the crippling effects of intestinal cancer can now be marketed in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. In addition, the <ORGANIZATION> Pharmaceutical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Manufacturers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> said 47 companies are now working on a total of 87 new drugs to treat the cardiovascular diseases of high blood pressure, stroke and heart disease. The new cancer drug is a protein compound called octreotide acetate that is designed to stop the severe, unrelenting diarrhea that often takes the lives of patients suffering from intestinal cancer. <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> Commissioner <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Young </PERSON> said the new drug `` can dramatically improve life for these cancer patients, permitting many to pursue their normal lives for years, rather than be weakened and continually hospitalized.'' The new drug, marketed by <ORGANIZATION> Sandoz </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pharmaceuticals </ORGANIZATION> under the brand name <PERSON> Sandostatin </PERSON>, does not actually attack the cancer itself. Instead, it blocks production of a peptide that causes the diarrhea. <PERSON> Young </PERSON> said patients with malignant carcinoid tumors and vasoactive intestinal peptide-secreting tumors often can live 15 to 20 years before dying as a direct result of the slow-growing cancer. But because the cancer forces the secretion of peptides that cause the severe diarrhea, patients usually die sooner. <PERSON> Sandostatin </PERSON> prevents the diarrhea by blocking the secretion of the peptides. The drug does this by imitating the action of somatostatin, a natural hormone that regulates secretions from the body's organs. The drug is administered by injection. The <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> said the cancer is diagnosed in one to two people per million annually. <PERSON> Gerald </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Mossinghoff </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> Pharmaceutical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Manufacturers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, said a survey of the association members indicates there are 87 new drugs for cardiovascular disease treatment now in clinical trials or awaiting final <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> approval. `` No other disease is targeted by so many drugs in development or so much investment in research,'' said <PERSON> Mossinghoff </PERSON>. He acknowledged at a news conference that one of the reasons the companies are pouring so much investment into cardiovascular diseases is that there remains a huge market for such therapies even though doctors now realize they are among the most preventable illnesses for people who adopt healthy lifestyles in their early and middle years. Dr. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Beary </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>, senior vice president for science and technology for the trade association, noted that heart disease remains the nation's No. 1 killer and stroke No. 3. Even though the population is generally healthier, as well as older, than in years past, <PERSON> Beary </PERSON> said, `` at some point these diseases catch up with everyone.'' The pharmaceutical trade group's survey of its more than 100 members was designed to provide an overview of the scope of new drug development in various categories, rather than highlight any particularly promising `` breakthrough'' drugs. The trade association plans similar surveys in December for cancer drugs under development and in January for arthritis, Alzheimer's and other diseases of the aging. The cardiovascular disease survey found more medicines being developed for hypertension, or high blood pressure, than any other condition with all but three of the 38 drugs in that category in the final stages of testing. The pharmaceutical association said the second largest category, with 28 drugs under development, is congestive heart failure.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881026-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-26-88 0024EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-CommuterCrash     10-26 0707</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Commuter Crash,680</SECOND>
<HEAD>Investigators Blame Pilot For AVAir Crash</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By H. JOSEF HEBERT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A commuter airliner crash last February that killed all 12 people on board was caused mainly by an excessively rapid turn after the aircraft took off from <LOCATION> Raleigh-Durham </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.C. </LOCATION>, airport, federal investigators say. The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> on Tuesday blamed pilot error for the AVAir crash, but it said contributing factors were the commuter line's failure to act when it received information the pilot had previous flying problems and the government's inadequate monitoring of the airline, which had financial problems. The AVAir plane, flying as <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Eagle </ORGANIZATION> Flight 378, crashed shortly after it took off in dense fog on Feb. 19, l988, landing in wooded area about a mile from the airport runway. The Fairchild Metro III commuter was bound for <LOCATION> Richmond </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, with 10 passengers, a pilot and a copilot. The <ORGANIZATION> NTSB </ORGANIZATION> criticized the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aviation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> for not keeping a closer watch on AVAir's financial problems during a period of rapid expansion and not forwarding such information to the inspectors assigned to the airline. AVAir had undergone rapid growth in 1987 as a feeder for <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> at <LOCATION> Raleigh-Durham </LOCATION>. It was ranked the 30th largest commuter airline in the country last year carrying 351,522 passengers but met hard times in late l987. It filed for bankruptcy last January, resumed operation in February but sold its commuter operation to <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> in May. The <ORGANIZATION> NTSB </ORGANIZATION> said the probable cause for the Feb. 19 accident was `` the failure of the flight crew to maintain a proper flight path due to the first officer's inappropriate instrument scan, the captain's inadequate monitoring of the flight and the flight crew's response to a fault in the airplane's stall avoidance system. The investigation revealed that the copilot, <PERSON> Kathleen </PERSON> <PERSON> Digan </PERSON>, 28, who had been hired by AVAir in May 1987, had a spotty flying record and on a number of occasions had been the subject of critical evaluations by various AVAir captains. In July 1987 an AVAir captain wrote the airline's operations chief on hotel stationery that Ms. <PERSON> Digan </PERSON> had trouble on eight of 10 landings she flew during their trip together and that he considered her performance `` unacceptable.'' Two months later another AVAir captain reported in an evaluation that Ms. <PERSON> Digan </PERSON> had problems in clmb, cruise, descent and landing maneuvers. According to the <ORGANIZATION> NTSB </ORGANIZATION>, she was hired by AVAir, on March 5, 1987, when the airline needed scores of new pilots because of expansion plans. Ms. <PERSON> Digan </PERSON> was one of 123 pilots hired by AVAir in the second quarter of l987, according to the safety board. Ms. <PERSON> Digan </PERSON> had 2,080 hours of flying including a total of 450 hours on a Fairchild Metro II and Metro III at the time of the accident. Investigators determined that Ms. <PERSON> Digan </PERSON> was at the controls when the <ORGANIZATION> Metro </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> III </ORGANIZATION> commuter plane departed <LOCATION> Raleigh-Durham </LOCATION> on Feb. 19, although there was evidence that the captain, <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> Cole </PERSON>, 38, attempted to help keep the aircraft aloft in the final seconds. The flight was the first she had flown in instrument conditions in 4 -LCB- weeks, the report said. Flight 378 had been told by air traffic control to bank to the right as soon as possible after takeoff because of the heavy traffic loads at the time of the departure, investigators said. But Ms. <PERSON> Digan </PERSON>, flying in foggy conditions, banked the aircraft at only 200 feet and at a 40 degree angle, almost twice as sharp as would have been prudent, and likely became somewhat disoriented, allowing the plane to descend, the safety board said. The pilots were relying on instruments because of the poor visibility and the <ORGANIZATION> NTSB </ORGANIZATION> concluded that if the pilots had scanned their instruments adequately they would have known the bank was too sharp and at too low an altitude. The <ORGANIZATION> NTSB </ORGANIZATION> report said the pilots also might have been distracted by a light indicating that the aircraft's stall warning system had activated. The system automatically forces the nose down if the aircraft is approaching a stall. According to the investigation, the aircraft's performance indicated that the stall warning system actually had not deployed, and the problem stemmed from a false warning light.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881026-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-26-88 0038EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-BaseClosings     10-26 0364</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Base Closings,360</SECOND>
<HEAD>Senators Already Trying to Protect Home-District Bases</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JEFF BARKER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The ink was barely dry on the military base-closing law signed by President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> this week when 17 senators began trying to make sure their home-district bases are spared at the expense of others. The senators, from Northeastern and <LOCATION> Midwestern </LOCATION> states, claimed that the Sunbelt region has a disproportionate share of military installations and therefore should suffer the most cuts. The senators said in a letter Tuesday that a Pentagon-appointed commission should consider `` regional inequities'' as it decides which bases to close. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> had signed the base-closing bill just one day earlier. It authorizes the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> to close unneeded military bases to achieve savings of up to $ 5 billion per year. A 12-member commission is authorized to make the decisions and report on is conclusions by Dec. 31. <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> may veto the entire list but can not act to protect individual bases, as it often has in the past. `` We wish to prevent the further entrenchment of regional inequities stemming from the location of existing military facilities,'' said the letter from members of the <ORGANIZATION> Northeast-Midwest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coalition </ORGANIZATION>. The letter was addressed to <PERSON> Abraham </PERSON> <PERSON> Ribicoff </PERSON>, a former senator from <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION> who co-chairs the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> Secretary's <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> on Base Realignment and Closure. <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Abbee </PERSON>, spokesman for the base closing commission, laughed and said, `` So what's new?'' when told about the senators' letter. <PERSON> Abbee </PERSON> said he would not comment further until he had seen a copy. The senators said in their letter that <ORGANIZATION> Sunbelt </ORGANIZATION> states already enjoy an advantage in numbers of bases. The letter pointed to a report by congressional conferees on the base-closing bill that said geography should `` be carefully weighed during the commission's deliberations leading to its closure and realignment recommendations.'' However, that provision was dropped before the legislation was given final approval. <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Carlucci </PERSON> will have until Jan. 15 to accept or reject the list of recommended base closings. Signing the letter were the two senators each from <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION>, and Sen. <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Biden </PERSON>, D-Del., <PERSON> Claiborne </PERSON> <PERSON> Pell </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-R.I. </LOCATION>, and <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Lugar </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Ind </LOCATION>
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881026-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-26-88 0044EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FarmScene     10-26 0887</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Farm Scene,890</SECOND>
<HEAD>Government To Send `Dear Farmer Jones' Letters To Late Borrowers</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DON KENDALL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Farm Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 About 90,000 farmers who are behind in their loan repayments to the <ORGANIZATION> Farmers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Home </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> will be getting notices shortly after the Nov. 8 election telling them to start making arrangements for settlement. The <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> agency said Tuesday the notices will be an attempt to collect about $ 8.8 billion in past-due loans. Spokesman <PERSON> Marlyn </PERSON> <PERSON> Aycock </PERSON> said rules implementing new credit legislation will take effect Nov. 14 and that `` Dear Farmer Jones'' notices will start going out soon thereafter to the delinquent FmHA borrowers. <PERSON> Aycock </PERSON> said the notices will say: `` This is to inform you that you're seriously behind in your loan payments and to inform you of your options. Farmers who are more than 180 days late in making payments have several options.'' The notices will explain that the <ORGANIZATION> FmHA </ORGANIZATION> borrowers must notify the agency within 45 days if they intend to apply to make arrangements for settling their debts. Details regarding the options, including debt restructuring and write-offs, also will be provided. <PERSON> Aycock </PERSON> said the timetable for sending out the notices as promptly as possible took into consideration the months of rulemaking, periods for public comment and time for training FmHA people to handle the additional job load. <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> ordered <ORGANIZATION> FmHA </ORGANIZATION> to revise its lending practices in the Agricultural Credit Act of 1987. The agency is often called the farm lender of last resort because it makes loans only to those who can not qualify at banks or other commercial sources. The debt write-down, or forgiveness provision, is regarded as one of the most important parts of the 1987 law. It allows FmHA to reduce a farmer's delinquent debt to the recovery value of the collateral, which is usually land or farm equipment, depending on cash flow and other factors. Also, as the result of lawsuits, the <ORGANIZATION> FmHA </ORGANIZATION> is under court order to redo many of its loan regulations and to hold up on foreclosures and forced liquidations until those actions are completed. Estimates of the extent of <ORGANIZATION> FmHA </ORGANIZATION> loan delinquencies and numbers of farmers potentially threatened by foreclosure under the new rules have varied. Last May 23, when the new regulations were proposed, FmHA losses resulting from write-offs and other settlements were estimated at about $ 8.7 billion and that about 118,000 borrowers were delinquent. About 64,800 of those could be pushed into liquidation or foreclosure because they could n't qualify for help under the new law. Another major step was an interim rule announced on Sept. 14, including procedures for making debt restructuring and write-downs. Those were to take effect on Oct. 14 on an interim basis and called for final adoption on Nov. 14 after a 60-day period for public comments. In the September announcement, the earlier analysis was used again which referred to 118,000 delinquent borrowers, including about 65,000 who would be rejected for debt write-downs. The potential losses were said to be as high as $ 9.4 billion, although about $ 1 billion could be salvaged by the agency. <PERSON> Aycock </PERSON> said the current estimate of 90,000 delinquent borrowers was based on figures last fall, when <ORGANIZATION> FmHA </ORGANIZATION> delinquencies are historically lower than those in January, when the 118,000 were reported.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> scientists say that tiny beneficial worms, or nematodes, can be produced in a laboratory, dried out for storage and revived later to fight destructive pests in back yards. `` They're still living and breathing but they're dormant,'' says entomologist <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Lindegran </PERSON> of the department's <ORGANIZATION> Agricultural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> laboratory, <LOCATION> Fresno </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>. Lindegran and researchers at a <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> biotechnology firm, <ORGANIZATION> Biosys </ORGANIZATION>, found that the microscopic nematodes such as Steinernema feltiae can be dried, stored as a `` paste'' under refrigeration and then revived with water `` When you add water, the worms plump back up again,'' <PERSON> Lindegran </PERSON> said in a report issued here by the <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> agency. `` When they start moving around, they're ready to be sprayed onto plants, trees or soil.'' The beneficial nematodes attack pests that are in the larvaal or wormlike stage of development by entering through openings such as the mouth or breathing tubes, he said. `` Once inside a pest, the nematodes excrete a unique bacterium that kills the pest, is food for the nematodes and produces antibiotics that keep other bacteria at bay,'' <PERSON> Lindegran </PERSON> said. The nematodes are harmless to humans but lethal to a variety of pests, including carpenterworms, cutworms, armyworms, fruit flies and root maggots.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 _ <LOCATION> WASHINGTON </LOCATION> -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> -RRB- _ Exports of farm crops in the fiscal year that ended on Sept. 30 required the production from about 107 million harvested acres, according to the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>. That represented 36 percent of the 301 million acres of crops harvested in the 1987-88 year, the department's <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> said in a new outlook report on the nation's agricultural resources. Although the 1987-88 export acreage was up 11 percent from the previous year, it was far below the record high of 137 million acres in 1980, the report said. Of the 107 million acres needed to grow crops for export last year, food grains _ mainly wheat and rice _ led with 40 million acres, followed by oilseeds -LRB- mostly soybeans -RRB-, 30 million; feed grains -LRB- mostly corn -RRB-, 21 million; cotton, 11 million; and other crops, 11 million.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881026-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-26-88 0047EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-US-Chile     10-26 0435</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-US-Chile,440</SECOND>
<HEAD>US Eases Policy Toward Chile</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GEORGE GEDDA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration is preparing to support a loan request by <LOCATION> Chile </LOCATION> in the <ORGANIZATION> Inter-American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION>, indicating a policy shift that <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> officials say reflects improved human rights performance in that country. The bank was expected to take up <LOCATION> Chile </LOCATION>'s request for a $ 35 million loan for rural road repair today. The administration has invariably abstained on such requests in recent years as evidence of its displeasure toward the policies of the country's military government. According to the officials, <LOCATION> Chile </LOCATION>'s human rights record has improved substantially in recent months, with the lifting of a 15-year old state of emergency in August and a national plebiscite held three weeks ago. Chilean voters denied President <PERSON> Augusto </PERSON> <PERSON> Pinochet </PERSON> an additional eight-year term and open elections are scheduled for next year. Until recently, the administration had frequently criticized <LOCATION> Chile </LOCATION> on grounds that it was one of only a handful of hemispheric countries that had not moved toward democratic rule. The only exception to the administration's policy of abstaining on Chilean loan requests involved projects that offered direct benefits to the poor. The pending request before the <ORGANIZATION> IADB </ORGANIZATION> does not fall into that category. The <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> officials, insisting on anonymity, said the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> decision to support the road repair loan does not mean <LOCATION> Chile </LOCATION> can count on <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> backing for future loan requests. Those votes will be based on <LOCATION> Chile </LOCATION>'s future human rights record and on the viability of the project for which financing is sought. Abstentions cast by American delegates to the <ORGANIZATION> IADB </ORGANIZATION> and other international financial institutions on Chilean requests usually were symbolic because <LOCATION> Chile </LOCATION> was able to count on enough support from other bank members to ensure approval of its applications. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> is the principal contributor to the <ORGANIZATION> IADB </ORGANIZATION>, which was set up 30 years ago to promote development in <LOCATION> Latin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>. The administration policy to abstain on most Chilean requests generally was supported by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, which enacted a statute a decade ago barring the executive branch from assisting countries engaging in `` gross and consistent'' human rights violations. <LOCATION> Chile </LOCATION> was never placed in that category but the administration decided to show disapproval over the situation in <LOCATION> Chile </LOCATION> through the abstention policy. There are a number of other impediments to the restoration of normal relations between the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Chile </LOCATION>. For more than a decade, <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> has barred military aid and training to <LOCATION> Chile </LOCATION> as well as bilateral economic aid. The officials said no decision on lifting any of these sanctions is expected this year.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881026-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-26-88 0051EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Iran-Contra     10-26 0512</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Iran-Contra,500</SECOND>
<HEAD>Prosecutors Accuse North Of Commiting `Classic Fraud'</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JAMES ROWLEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> North </PERSON> and his co-defendants perpetrated `` a classic fraud on government'' when they diverted profits from the U.S.-Iran arms sales to help arm the Nicaraguan rebels, prosecutors said. Responding to <PERSON> North </PERSON>'s contention that he did not defraud the government, prosecutors said the four Iran-Contra defendants created a `` secret slush fund'' for activities `` outside the normal channels of governmental accountability.'' By overcharging <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> for weapons in the arms-for-hostage transactions, <PERSON> North </PERSON> and the others undermined President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s initiative to free Americans held in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> by pro-Iranian groups, independent counsel <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Walsh </PERSON> said in pleadings filed Tuesday North and former national security adviser <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Poindexter </PERSON> `` chose to advance their private, unauthorized ends at the cost of putting at hazard the ends they were supposed to be pursuing, including that of saving the lives of the Americans held hostage in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>.'' North, <PERSON> Poindexter </PERSON> and arms dealers <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Hakim </PERSON> and retired <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> Maj. Gen. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> V. </PERSON> <PERSON> Secord </PERSON> are charged with conspiring to defraud the government and theft by diverting more than $ 14 million in arms-sale profits to a criminal `` enterprise'' that secretly financed the Nicaraguan Contra rebels. North's lawyers contended in pleadings filed Oct. 11 that there was no fraud or theft because the government did n't own the weapons after they were sold to <PERSON> Secord </PERSON> and <PERSON> Hakim </PERSON>, who acted as middlemen in the transactions. But <PERSON> Walsh </PERSON> said the alleged scheme `` constitutes a classic fraud on the government.'' `` The thrust of the fraud is the breach of the public trust: <PERSON> Poindexter </PERSON>'s and <PERSON> North </PERSON>'s discharge of their official duties -LRB- e.g., execution of the <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> initiative -RRB- was driven by a concealed and wholly improper motive _ a desire to generate a slush fund for use in financing unauthorized activities designated by them.'' Prosecutors said <PERSON> North </PERSON>, a retired <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> lieutenant colonel, `` exploited his position to exact from Iranians a high selling price, while concealing from the government the nature of the price spread and his control over the excess profits.'' `` The goals of establishing improved relations with <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> and potentially securing the release of American hostages held by groups sympathetic to that country were undermined and put seriously at risk by the conspirators' private motive to charge prices well in excess of what otherwise might have been charged in order to secure additional profits,'' the prosecution said. `` Defendants <PERSON> Secord </PERSON> and <PERSON> Hakim </PERSON> agreed to hold funds generated by <PERSON> North </PERSON> and to apply them to purposes selected by <PERSON> North </PERSON> and <PERSON> Poindexter </PERSON> outside the normal challenges of governmental accountability,'' prosecutors said. <PERSON> Secord </PERSON> and <PERSON> Hakim </PERSON> `` reaped lucrative profits from the money <PERSON> North </PERSON> steered to them'' as middlemen in the transactions, prosecutors said. Prosecutors said they were not required to show that the defendants' activities undermined <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s effort to free the hostages. `` It is enough that it was reasonably foreseeable that they would have that effect, as it clearly was.'' No date has been set for the trial of <LOCATION> North </LOCATION>, the first of four trials ordered by <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> Gerhard </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gesell </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881026-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-26-88 0051EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-CastleberryRecall     10-26 0189</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Castleberry Recall,0192</SECOND>
<HEAD>Food Company Recalling Cans Of Corned Beef Hash</HEAD>
<DATELINE>AUGUSTA, Ga. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Castleberry </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Food </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> said Tuesday it is recalling 2,161 cases of canned corned beef hash because part of one day's production was improperly cooked. Only 35 cases actually are believed to be involved, but the company is recalling the entire day's production of the product from Sept. 21 `` to be on the safe side,'' said <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Lamb </PERSON>, director of personnel. The corned beef hash is packaged in 7.5 ounce single serving cans with pull-tops. The product is sold primarily in vending machines, but some is sold through convenience and grocery stores. <PERSON> Castleberry </PERSON>'s described as possibly non-sterile the product in cans under the code numbers 2J81CBV4 and 2J81CBV3. The food was distributed in <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION>. Of the more than 2,000 cases involved in the recall, 36 cases were distributed in <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION>. Consumers who have 7.5-ounce cans of the hash with either of the codes on the bottom of the cans were asked to return the product to the store where it was purchased for a refund.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881026-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-26-88 0052EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Grain-China     10-26 0231</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Grain-China,220</SECOND>
<HEAD>China Buys More US Wheat</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Private exporters have sold <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> an additional 400,000 metric tons of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> wheat at subsidized prices for shipment in December, according to the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>. The sales, equal to about 14.7 million bushels, were handled by six companies: <ORGANIZATION> Cargill </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, 50,000 tons; <ORGANIZATION> Continental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Grain </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, 110,000; <ORGANIZATION> Richco </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Grain </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, 40,000; <ORGANIZATION> Louis </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dreyfus </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, 120,000; <ORGANIZATION> Bunge </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, 40,000; and <ORGANIZATION> Mitsubishi </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, 40,000. <PERSON> Melvin </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Sims </PERSON>, general manager for the department's <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agricultural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>, said Tuesday the sales were part of 2 million tons of wheat authorized on Aug. 18 under the Export Enhancement Program. Although no selling prices or other details were announced, recent prices of wheat at farm points have averaged around $ 3.84 per bushel, indicating a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> farm value of about $ 56 million. A metric ton is about 2,205 pounds and is equal to 36.7 bushels of wheat. The program enables exporters to sell wheat and other designated commodities to specified countries at reduced prices in order to meet foreign competition. The exporters then collect free government surpluses of grain or other products as bonuses, or subsidies. <PERSON> Sims </PERSON> said the bonuses due the six exporters for the latest deal averaged $ 21.12 per ton of wheat, or about 58 cents per bushel. <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> has an additional 560,000 tons of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> wheat available under the Export Enhancement Program, he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881026-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-26-88 0437EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--MutinyTrial     10-26 0183</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Mutiny Trial,0187</SECOND>
<HEAD>Fisherman Accused Of Mutiny Pleads Guilty To Lesser Charge</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BROWNSVILLE, Texas (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A fisherman charged with mutiny for shooting the captain of a fishing boat while at sea because he was n't allowed to eat some of the day's catch has pleaded guilty to a lesser charge. <PERSON> Fredesvina </PERSON> <PERSON> Avila-Iscoa </PERSON>, 32, also had been charged with assault with intent to commit mutiny and a firearms violation for shooting Capt. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Palacio </PERSON> after an argument aboard the M-V <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> J </PERSON>. He pleaded guilty Monday in <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District court to assault with intent to commit bodily injury with a weapon and faces five to 20 years in prison and a fine up to $ 250,000. The original charges carried a maximum sentence of 35 years in prison and $ 750,000 fine. Prosecutors said the argument broke out July 23, about 250 miles offshore, when <PERSON> Avila </PERSON> was told not to eat fish the captain had caught. <PERSON> Avila </PERSON> shot Palacio in the leg with a 9 mm pistol after the captain refused to feed him other provisions and threatened to withhold his pay, according to witnesses.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881026-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-26-88 0113EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-People-Temple     10-26 0176</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-People-Temple,0185</SECOND>
<HEAD>Shirley Temple Black Calls President Reagan A Good Kisser</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Former child star <ORGANIZATION> Shirley </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Temple </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Black </ORGANIZATION> has a different sort of kiss-and-tell story than the White House insider books that have come out of <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> recently. She says <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> was really a good kisser. The two performed together in a nearly forgotten 1947 film `` That Hagen Girl.'' At the time, she was a teen-ager and he was the leading man. `` He was one of the best kissers,'' Ms. <PERSON> Black </PERSON> said Tuesday in an interview televised on the syndicated `` Entertainment Tonight.'' In the film, Ms. <PERSON> Black </PERSON>'s character feared that the teacher played by the future president was her illegitimate father. The film was `` probably one of the worst movies either one of us ever made,'' said Ms. <PERSON> Black </PERSON>, who is promoting her autobiography, `` Child Star.'' On New Year's Day, Ms. <PERSON> Black </PERSON>, 60, will be grand marshal of the 100th Annual Tournament of Roses Parade in <LOCATION> Pasadena </LOCATION>. She was grand marshal of the 50th annual parade in 1939 at age 10.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881026-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-26-88 0115EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-WhalesWorth     10-26 0783</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Whales Worth,0803</SECOND>
<HEAD>Saga Of Trapped Whales: Is All The Fuss Worth It?</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT DVORCHAK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP National Writer</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 The massive rescue effort to save two <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> gray whales wo n't make a difference to the survival of the species, but it's been a public relations dream for environmentalists trying to rouse the world to save its oceans `` What's the big deal? I do n't know. It all of a sudden exploded,'' said <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> <PERSON> Braham </PERSON>, director of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mammal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Laboratory </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION>, the chief <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> research center on whales. `` Only the individual can answer if it's worth it,'' <PERSON> Braham </PERSON> said. `` We're dealing with the human spirit. We allow some awfully damning things to go unchecked and then we reach out to something with a tear in our eye.'' The leviathan rescue has thrown together an unlikely army of would-be saviors: whale-hunting Eskimos, <ORGANIZATION> Greenpeace </ORGANIZATION> environmentalists, oil companies, the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and Soviet governments, wildlife experts, animal behavior specialists and chainsaw mechanics. An international cast of some 40 to 60 reporters keeps the world informed of any progress. The two surviving gray whales imprisoned by the ice are part of an endangered species, meaning they are thought to be in imminent danger of becoming extinct. But the population of grays is flourishing. There are about 21,000, which is near the historic peak of 25,000 reached before whale hunters slaughtered all but a few thousand around the turn of the century. The Soviets kill 169 gray whales each year to feed Eskimos under an exemption granted by the <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Whaling </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION>, and another 1,000 animals die of natural causes yearly, according to government estimates. Despite the losses, the population of grays increases by 2.5 percent a year, and the deaths of three wayward whales not yet old enough to breed would be insignificant, scientists said. `` There's no loss from a biological standpoint,'' said research biologist <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Withrow </PERSON> from the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mammal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Laboratory </ORGANIZATION>. But cold facts have no chance against heated emotions when human nature fights Mother Nature. The whales have names. Biologists call the two survivors <PERSON> Bonnet </PERSON> and Crossbeak. The Inupiat Eskimos who discovered them Oct. 7 call them <PERSON> Putu </PERSON> and <PERSON> Siku </PERSON> for Ice Hole and Ice. A third whale, Bone or Kanik for Snowflake, apparently died Friday. Television brought the whales into <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> homes. Nightly pictures of their battered and bleeding snouts protruding from a breathing hole cut like a harpoon into American hearts. `` These animals are turning out to be ambassadors for all marine life,'' said <PERSON> Susan </PERSON> <PERSON> Vernon </PERSON> of the Whale Museum in <LOCATION> Friday </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Harbor </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wash. </LOCATION> `` I do n't think it's overreaction. It's a catharsis. The helping hand was extended. And it was extended in good faith.'' Gray whales feed in the icy <LOCATION> Arctic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ocean </LOCATION>, then migrate 7,000 miles to breed off balmy <LOCATION> Baja </LOCATION> <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>. The three trapped whales were migrating for the first time. Even experienced bowhead whales, equipped with thick skulls to break through ice, get hemmed in. About 10 to 12 of them perish each year off northern <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>, biologists said. Some have questioned the expense of trying to save the whales _ which had reached upward of $ 600,000 and counting as of Monday _ while funding for <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> whale research has been cut. The annual budget for the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mammal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Laboratory </ORGANIZATION> is $ 2 million, down from $ 2.8 million in 1985. `` However much money they're spending on the rescue is fine,'' said <PERSON> Patty </PERSON> <PERSON> Warhol </PERSON>, director of the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cetacean </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Pedro </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION> `` That money might be better used in research, but you just ca n't buy that kind of public relations for whales,'' she said `` Today, there are people all over the country talking about whales who two weeks ago did n't know they existed or thought they were big fish.'' The mercy mission has melted hearts of grizzled oil field roustabouts from the bone-chilling North Slope, who also have reaped a public relations harvest of good will for their labors. <ORGANIZATION> VECO </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Prudhoe </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION> offered to send a 185-ton ice pulverizing hoverbarge to smash a pathway to the sea, with <ORGANIZATION> ARCO </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Alaska </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> donating fuel to the <ORGANIZATION> Alaska </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> helicopter that tried vainly to coax it to the whales. The barge got stuck in shallow water. `` It was a common cause to help the underdog. We're human too,'' said <PERSON> Marvin </PERSON> <PERSON> King </PERSON>, operations manager for <ORGANIZATION> VECO </ORGANIZATION>. `` It's not money. It's not headlines. We wanted to do what we could to help another mammal.'' `` We did what we should have done,'' said <PERSON> Ben </PERSON> <PERSON> Odom </PERSON>, senior vice president of <ORGANIZATION> ARCO </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Alaska </ORGANIZATION>. `` It's a sad sight to see them struggling to stay alive. What's that worth to help them? We're not discouraged by the naysayers.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881026-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-26-88 0111EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     10-26 0988</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,1035</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names In The News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>JERUSALEM (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Former Prime Minister <PERSON> Menachem </PERSON> <PERSON> Begin </PERSON> broke his customary silence to telephone his successor, <PERSON> Yitzhak </PERSON> <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON>, and wish him a happy birthday. <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON>, running for re-election in the Nov. 1 elections, celebrated his 73rd birthday Tuesday with a surprise party at his office. Aides prepared a cake decorated with iced flowers and the traditional Jewish blessing `` May you live until 120'' as well as a special wish that <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON> serve `` another four years'' as <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s prime minister Since Begin resigned without explanation in 1983, he has been a virtual recluse, emerging from his <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION> home only to attend annual memorial services for his late wife, <PERSON> Aliza </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>Eds: A version of the following item moved on sports wires.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>ROANOKE, Texas (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> <PERSON> Bradshaw </PERSON> says a 33-year-old softball injury created more anxiety than the countless injuries he sustained during his 14 years as a <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Football </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> League </ORGANIZATION> quarterback. Doctors discovered Monday that the old injury was to blame for chest pains that have plagued the <ORGANIZATION> CBS-TV </ORGANIZATION> football commentator in recent weeks. The diagnosis came amid a report by a <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION> TV station that the scar matter doctors found was a tumor. <PERSON> Bradshaw </PERSON>, 40, said Tuesday from his suburban <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION> home that he was about 7 years old when he was hit by a softball, breaking his sternum. He first noticed chest pains Oct. 11, prompting him to undergo tests. `` Not knowing what's wrong is the thing that drives you crazy,'' <PERSON> Bradshaw </PERSON> said. `` I've worried myself sick these past few weeks.'' <PERSON> Bradshaw </PERSON> led the <ORGANIZATION> Pittsburgh </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Steelers </ORGANIZATION> to an unprecedented four Super Bowl championships during an <ORGANIZATION> NFL </ORGANIZATION> career that ended in 1983.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A 12-year-old boy who was nearly killed six years ago in a fire set by his father met with <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> I. </PERSON> <PERSON> Koch </PERSON> but resisted the mayor's attempts to coax him back to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Rothenberg </PERSON>, whose plight was depicted Tuesday night in the <ORGANIZATION> ABC-TV </ORGANIZATION> movie `` <PERSON> David </PERSON>,'' remains disfigured by the burns he suffered March 2, 1983, when he was left in the flaming <LOCATION> Buena </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Park </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, motel room. His father, <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Rothenberg </PERSON>, said he wanted to kill his son and himself because he feared his ex-wife would n't let him see the child again. But the older <PERSON> Rothenberg </PERSON> fled the fire. <PERSON> Rothenberg </PERSON> pleaded guilty and comes up for parole next year. `` Can you really get used to <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>?'' <PERSON> Koch </PERSON> asked the boy, a former <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> resident, during a visit Tuesday at City Hall. `` I am,'' answered <PERSON> David </PERSON>, a drummer in a junior high school band in <LOCATION> Anaheim </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Koch </PERSON> predicted the boy would get bored with <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>. `` You do n't want orange juice. You want seltzer,'' the mayor told him. `` They have seltzer in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> David </PERSON> answered.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>FRANKFURT, West Germany (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Mathias </PERSON> <PERSON> Rust </PERSON>, the West German pilot who landed in Red Square last year and spent 14 months in prison for violating <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> air space, wants to return to visit <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> legally, a magazine reported. The weekly <PERSON> Goldenes </PERSON> <PERSON> Blatt </PERSON> said Tuesday that Rust, 20, had been denied a visa by the Soviet embassy in <LOCATION> Bonn </LOCATION> and now plans to write directly to <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>. `` I wanted to visit Red Square and see the city's sights with my mother. Other than the court and the cell, I saw little of <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>,'' Rust said. Rust caused a major shakeup of the Soviet military leadership after he flew his single-engine <ORGANIZATION> Cessna </ORGANIZATION> to the <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION> unhindered on May 28, 1987. Rust was convicted of illegally entering the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, violating international flight rules and malicious hooliganism, and sentenced to four years. He was released Aug. 4.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Australian novelist <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Carey </PERSON>, who won the coveted Booker Prize for fiction, says he wished he had been more optimistic about his chances of receiving the award. `` If I'd known I was going to win, I think I would have taken a bit more trouble with my handwriting,'' he said Tuesday as he stared down at his notes of an acceptance speech. Five judges announced the $ 26,250 prize for <PERSON> Carey </PERSON>'s love story `` Oscar and <PERSON> Lucinda </PERSON>.'' The winner came from 102 books published in <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> during the past 12 months. The Booker Prize is administered by Book Trust, an educational charity promoting books, and is sponsored by <PERSON> Booker </PERSON>, an international food and farming business.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>ATLANTIC CITY, N.J. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Songwriter <PERSON> Sammy </PERSON> <PERSON> Cahn </PERSON> has won five Oscars and an Emmy, but he says one of his biggest thrills will be performing at an <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> casino this weekend. `` When I get to <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, I'm going to laugh so loud at the marquee,'' said <PERSON> Cahn </PERSON>, 75, whose songs include `` Love and Marriage,'' `` High Hopes,'' and `` Call Me Irresponsible.'' `` To see my name in a place where so many performers have come to sing my songs. Do you know what a kick that will be?'' <PERSON> Cahn </PERSON>'s excitement also may be due to the fact that although he's been in show business 60 years, he's only been performing for about 15 years `` I always wanted to be a performer, but when I started out, vaudeville was phasing out,'' said <PERSON> Cahn </PERSON>. `` When I get on stage, I have a most unique show, and when I finish, they stand up and cheer,'' <PERSON> Cahn </PERSON> said. `` Not because I finished, but because it's a miracle.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>BLOOMINGTON, Minn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An undisclosed illness forced rock star <PERSON> Rod </PERSON> <PERSON> Stewart </PERSON> to cancel a concert here about 50 minutes after it was scheduled to start. At 8:20 p.m. Monday, a member of <PERSON> Stewart </PERSON>'s road crew announced to the audience of about 9,100 at the Met Center that the singer was ill. `` He can hardly talk,'' the aide told the audience He said <PERSON> Stewart </PERSON> had consulted with a doctor before the show. The concertgoers filed out of the stadium peacefully, but many were disgruntled. The concert's producers said they will try to reschedule the performance.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881026-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-26-88 0117EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-People-Iacocca-Jackson     10-26 0207</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-People-Iacocca-Jackson,0212</SECOND>
<HEAD>Music, Automaking Superstars Meet Backstage</HEAD>
<DATELINE>AUBURN HILLS, Mich. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 One made `` Bad.'' The other makes `` Ram'' pickup trucks. And <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> and <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Iacocca </PERSON> had a similarly brief exchange of words when the pop superstar met the <ORGANIZATION> Chrysler </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> chairman. <PERSON> Iacocca </PERSON> met <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> backstage shortly before the singer performed Monday night at the Palace of <LOCATION> Auburn </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hills </LOCATION>. The meeting was set up after one of <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s attorneys wrote to <PERSON> Iacocca </PERSON>. `` <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> had read <PERSON> Lee </PERSON>'s book -LRB- ` Talking Straight' -RRB- and, you know, <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> is mentioned in the book,'' <ORGANIZATION> Chrysler </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Guiniven </PERSON> said. `` There was a mutual interest in the meeting.'' But <PERSON> Guiniven </PERSON> said he had no idea what the two said to each other. In `` Talking Straight,'' <PERSON> Iacocca </PERSON> defended the $ 20.5 million he made in 1986 through salary and stock options, writing: `` $ 20 million sounds more like <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s income for a weekend than the annual pay of a guy who ca n't carry a tune in the shower.'' <PERSON> Iacocca </PERSON>'s estimate was off the mark if Monday night's show was anywhere near <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s standard. Net income from the concert was $ 125,000, an amount <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> donated Sunday to the Motown Museum, honoring the Motown Records label to which he and his brothers were signed in 1969.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881026-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-26-88 0030EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-TrappedWhales 2ndLd-Writethru a0782 10-26 0747</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Trapped Whales, 2nd Ld - Writethru, a0782,0763</SECOND>
<HEAD>Soviet Ships Arrive, Begin Breaking Ice</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Leads with 12 grafs to UPDATE with progress of Soviet
icebreaking, quotes from rescue commanders. Deletes outdated matter
and picks up 14th graf pvs `Gary Hufford....'</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By BRUCE BARTLEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BARROW, Alaska (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
