<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880508-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-08-88 2333EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Germany-Election     05-08 0312</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Germany-Election,0324</SECOND>
<HEAD>Social Democrats Win Majority in Schleswig-Holstein Election</HEAD>
<DATELINE>KIEL, West Germany (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Social </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> gained a firm victory in <LOCATION> Schleswig-Holstein </LOCATION> state Sunday, ending 38 years of rule by the conservative <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democrats </ORGANIZATION>. The special election was called after a `` dirty-tricks scandal'' rocked the state government last year. <PERSON> Bjoern </PERSON> <PERSON> Engholm </PERSON>, leader of the state's Social Democrats, and his supporters had failed to win a majority in elections last September. But on Sunday, projections said the <ORGANIZATION> Social </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democrats </ORGANIZATION> won 54 percent of the vote, assuring the party of 46 of the 74 seats in the legislature and that <PERSON> Engholm </PERSON> would be governor. The Christian Democrats were projected to receive about 33 percent, a loss of eight percent from September. <PERSON> Engholm </PERSON> was the target of a smear campaign last year involving allegations of improper sexual conduct. The campaign was blamed on then-Gov. <PERSON> Uwe </PERSON> <PERSON> Barschel </PERSON>, who was found dead in a <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> hotel in October. Authorities ruled his death an apparent suicide. Projected results also showed the <ORGANIZATION> Free </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, which was allied with the <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democrats </ORGANIZATION> in the state's coalition government, had failed to receive the necessary five percent of the vote to stay in the legislature and lost its four seats. West German Chancellor <PERSON> Helmut </PERSON> <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON> said Sunday night that the Social Democrats' victory would not negatively affect his conseravative coalition in the federal government with the Free Democrats. He attributed the Social Democrats' victory to the <PERSON> Barschel </PERSON> affair. `` We went into the election from an unusually difficult position,'' <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON> said. Last September, neither party could win enough seats to form a majority and elect a new governor. <PERSON> Barschel </PERSON> remained in office but then resigned when one of his aides disclosed details about the smear campaign against <PERSON> Engholm </PERSON> in late September. The <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democrats </ORGANIZATION> had entered <PERSON> Heiko </PERSON> <PERSON> Hoffmann </PERSON>, the state's justice minister, to run against <PERSON> Engholm </PERSON> in Sunday's balloting
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880508-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-08-88 2342EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lites     05-08 0547</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lites,0575</SECOND>
<HEAD>On The Light Side</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BOURG, La. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Build a better cage for an egg to crash in and the world may not beat a path to your door, but it wo n't scramble your eggs, either. And it could help your physics grade at <ORGANIZATION> South </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Terrebonne </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> High </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION>, says physics teacher <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>, whose 75 students at Friday's Egg Drop Competition used principles of mass, inertia, acceleration _ and toothpicks. The idea: build toothpick frames to cradle an egg during a 20-foot free fall, distribute the shock of a crash-landing and keep the egg from breaking. More than six dozen eggs did n't make the grade, including <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>'s, which splattered when its shapeless case hit the ground and smashed into, ah, toothpicks. `` I got the design from my friend in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> said. `` It worked for him. But I changed it up a little. I guess I should have stuck with the original design.'' Sixteen-year-old junior <PERSON> Casey </PERSON> <PERSON> Portier </PERSON>'s egg made it through its first drop into the center of a spherical array of interconnected triangles. `` Everyone was dropping theirs and it was flipping over and breaking,'' he said. `` I used symmetry so the weight was distributed evenly.'' <PERSON> Laurie </PERSON> <PERSON> Ledet </PERSON>, 17, a senior, was less systematic. Her project looked like a bent soda can with a crown on top. Nonetheless, it worked. On <PERSON> Casey </PERSON>'s second drop, the ball began to roll. It bounced off the pavement and the egg began to ooze. <PERSON> Laurie </PERSON>'s egg survived a second drop with a cracked shell, but the egg stayed inside. `` Well,'' said <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>, `` it looks like it's going to be easy to distribute the awards.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>HAMBURG, Mich. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Godzilla has been found. The 30-foot balloon dinosaur disappeared Saturday from the roof of hardware store in this southwestern <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION> community shortly after it was inflated. No rampages were reported in the surrounding countryside, and the thieves returned the creature early Sunday to the home of the store's owner, said <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Cammarata </PERSON>, owner of the rental company that provided the beast. `` I'm real pleased about it,'' he said. `` That thing's worth $ 7,800.'' <PERSON> Cammarata </PERSON> suspected pranksters from nearby <ORGANIZATION> Pinckney </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> High </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION>, but the suspects remain unknown. While it was gone, the creature `` made a mess of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION>, but that's about it,'' he said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>COLVILLE, Wash. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A 48-year-old athletic trainer says he's giving up his goal of outrunning a horse even though he has lost by only a few minutes in two 50-mile races against an Arabian stallion <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Misner </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Spokane </LOCATION> reached the finish, designated as the first stoplight in <LOCATION> Colville </LOCATION>, just four minutes behind <PERSON> Zeke </PERSON>, ridden by <PERSON> Becky </PERSON> <PERSON> Farrington </PERSON>. `` I wanted him so bad, you ca n't believe it,'' <PERSON> Misner </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Misner </PERSON> completed the grueling course in six hours, 44 minutes and 47 seconds after leaving the start in Deer Park. Last year, <PERSON> Misner </PERSON> lost to <PERSON> Zeke </PERSON> by six minutes. He said he decided to try to outrun a horse after watching an <ORGANIZATION> NBC-TV </ORGANIZATION> program called `` Sports Fantasies.'' `` I thought, ` Well golly, that would be interesting to race against a horse because <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Owens </PERSON> did that,''' he said. After the two attempts, he said, he's decided to give up the challenge. Parts of his race against <PERSON> Zeke </PERSON> will be shown May 22 on `` Sports Fantasies.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880508-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-08-88 2344EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-BRF--SeamanRescued 2ndLd-Writethru a0812orts 05-08 0126</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Seaman Rescued, 2nd Ld - Writethru, a0812,0123</SECOND>
<HEAD>Soviet Seaman Brought To Shore For Treatment After Accident</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: UPDATES seaman's condition; CORRECTS spelling of Soviet ship</NOTE>
<DATELINE>NEWPORT, Ore. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> boat brought a Soviet seaman ashore for medical aid after three of his fingers were crushed while he was aboard a 270-foot Soviet fishing vessel. <PERSON> Anatoly </PERSON> <PERSON> Randin </PERSON>, 42, was listed in good condition Sunday in <ORGANIZATION> Pacific </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Communities </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION>. Coast Guard Chief <PERSON> Chris </PERSON> <PERSON> Couch </PERSON> said a 44-foot motor lifeboat was dispatched to the Soviet vessel, Polevd, at 8:35 p.m. Saturday about 19 miles off <LOCATION> Newport </LOCATION>. Couch said he did n't know what caused the injury. The Polevd is among a number of Soviet boats that have been fishing off the coast, <PERSON> Couch </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880508-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-08-88 2348EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-VanGogh     05-08 0713</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Van Gogh,0730</SECOND>
<HEAD>Portrait Painted One Month Before Artist's Suicide Goes On Sale</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By CATHERINE CROCKER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A month before he killed himself, <PERSON> Vincent </PERSON> <PERSON> van </PERSON> <PERSON> Gogh </PERSON> painted a portrait in blue of his innkeeper's young daughter. The girl, <PERSON> Adeline </PERSON> <PERSON> Ravoux </PERSON>, 13, was on the terrace of the cafe in <LOCATION> Auvers </LOCATION>, a village outside <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION>, when the artist returned from the fields, his hands pressed to the bullet wound in his stomach. Two days later, July 29, 1890, <PERSON> van </PERSON> <PERSON> Gogh </PERSON> died. He was 37 years old. On Wednesday, `` Portrait of <PERSON> Adeline </PERSON> <PERSON> Ravoux </PERSON>'' will offered for sale at an auction of impressionist and modern paintings. <PERSON> Christie </PERSON>'s, the auction house, estimates that it will fetch more than $ 15 million. Experts say interest in the portrait is keen in part because of the story behind it. The adolescent girl who posed for the painting said in an essay published in 1956 that she considered it `` somewhat of a disappointment'' at first. But in her later years, <PERSON> Adeline </PERSON> <PERSON> Ravoux </PERSON> <PERSON> Carrie </PERSON> said she finally came to appreciate its insight into her character. Mrs. <PERSON> Carrie </PERSON> described <PERSON> van </PERSON> <PERSON> Gogh </PERSON>, who lived at her father's inn during the last 2 -LCB- months of his life, as a disciplined artist and `` a soft and calm'' man who always smoked a pipe and enjoyed playing with her little sister. She also recalled the last two days of the artist's life during which he slowly succumbed to the fatal bullet. A doctor came to dress the wound, police officers arrived to investigate the suicide and the artist's brother <PERSON> Theo </PERSON> arrived running from the train station, his face `` distorted by grief,'' she wrote. The portrait being auctioned Wednesday is one of three versions van <PERSON> Gogh </PERSON> painted. When last offered for sale, in 1980 at <ORGANIZATION> Sotheby </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION>, it brought $ 1.98 million from an anonymous buyer. Last year, three of <PERSON> van </PERSON> <PERSON> Gogh </PERSON>'s paintings fetched record multimillion - dollar prices that shocked the art world The artist sold almost nothing during his lifetime. In March 1987, <PERSON> van </PERSON> <PERSON> Gogh </PERSON>'s `` Sunflowers'' sold for $ 39.9 million at <ORGANIZATION> Christie </ORGANIZATION>'s in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> to a Japanese firm, <ORGANIZATION> Yasuda </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fire </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Insurance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>. Three months later, `` The Trinquetaille Bridge'' went for $ 20.2 million, also at <PERSON> Christie </PERSON>'s in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> It was bought by an unidentified collector living in <LOCATION> Switzerland </LOCATION>. Then in November, history was made when <PERSON> van </PERSON> <PERSON> Gogh </PERSON>'s `` Irises'' _ a richly-colored composition of purple flowers and green leaves set off by a single white iris _ sold at <ORGANIZATION> Sotheby </ORGANIZATION>'s in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> for $ 53.9 million to an anonymous buyer. It was the highest price paid at auction for any painting. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Rewald </PERSON>, the author of `` Post-Impressionism: From van <PERSON> Gogh </PERSON> to <PERSON> Gauguin </PERSON>,'' has said of `` Irises'': `` If a museum could have one painting by <PERSON> van </PERSON> <PERSON> Gogh </PERSON>, that's what it should get.'' <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Findlay </PERSON>, <PERSON> Christie </PERSON>'s senior vice president, said he did n't think `` Portrait of <PERSON> Adeline </PERSON> <PERSON> Ravoux </PERSON>'' would bring anywhere near the price paid for `` Irises.'' The special appeal of the portrait, aside from the painting itself, is its link to <PERSON> van </PERSON> <PERSON> Gogh </PERSON>'s last days, said <PERSON> Findlay </PERSON>. In the painting, <PERSON> Adeline </PERSON>, dressed in blue, sits in profile on a chair. Her blond hair is tied with a blue ribbon, her gaze is serene, her posture correct and her hands folded demurely in front of her. `` He observed her very deeply, and when he came to paint her, he painted both the grace and stiff awkwardness of an adolescent girl,'' <PERSON> Findlay </PERSON> said. He used `` brief flashing strokes'' and `` astonishing'' color; the background is `` almost an electric blue, a night blue,'' he said. Mrs. <PERSON> Carrie </PERSON>, who died in 1965 at age 88, had written: `` I admit that I was only moderately satisfied with my portrait; it was somewhat of a disappointment, for I did not find it was true to life.'' But she also told an interviewer, `` <PERSON> Monsieur </PERSON> <PERSON> Vincent </PERSON> divined not the young girl I was, but the woman I was to become.'' <PERSON> Van </PERSON> <PERSON> Gogh </PERSON> gave the first of his three versions of the portrait to the <PERSON> Ravoux </PERSON> family. More lifelike and detailed than the version up for auction, it is now in a private collection in <LOCATION> Switzerland </LOCATION>. A third version that shows only the face and whose colors are less brilliant is owned by the <ORGANIZATION> Cleveland </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Museum </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Art </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880508-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-08-88 2349EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-WritersStrike     05-08 0759</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Writers Strike,0783</SECOND>
<HEAD>No End In Sight For Screenwriters Walkout</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By RICHARD DE ATLEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>HOLLYWOOD (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Soap opera actors say their characters have started speaking `` See <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> run,'' <PERSON> Johnny </PERSON> <PERSON> Carson </PERSON> is actually tired of time off and <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Willis </PERSON> has taken up gardening as a scriptwriters strike enters week nine. Talks are suspended between the <ORGANIZATION> Writers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guild </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Alliance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Motion </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Picture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Television </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Producers </ORGANIZATION> following the <ORGANIZATION> WGA </ORGANIZATION>'s walkout March 7 over residuals and creative control. And there's no relief in sight, with producer <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> Cannell </PERSON>, who's also a member of the guild, saying things could drag on until January. `` The <ORGANIZATION> Writers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guild </ORGANIZATION> is a very militant union,'' Academy Award-winning writer <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Taradash </PERSON> said Friday. `` We believe in what we believe.'' <PERSON> Taradash </PERSON>, a former guild president and former president of the <ORGANIZATION> Motion </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Picture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Arts </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sciences </ORGANIZATION>, said the strike forced him to stop work on a nearly completed script about Polish labor leader <PERSON> Lech </PERSON> <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON>. A sequel to the movie `` Annie'' also reportedly has been orphaned by the strike. `` Annie II,'' planned for a Christmas release, could n't get final touches made on its script. <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, which had hoped for a comeback in the fall after an unprecedented third-place finish this season, announced April 28 that it would push back the start of the new season from early Septeber to late October at the earliest. Producers claim the strike has cost the industry more than $ 15 million in lost jobs and production time, with about 1,400 clerical workers, cast and crew members laid off. The union struck when producers wanted to reformulate residual payments for hour-long television shows sold into syndication. Producers claim the shows are not selling well. Writers also want an increase of residuals from foreign markets, and more control over changes in their scripts. After nine weeks of reruns, <PERSON> Carson </PERSON> returns Wednesday, writing his own monologue and otherwise ad-libbing his one-hour <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> show. <PERSON> Carson </PERSON>'s contract allowing him generous time off has been the subject of `` Tonight Show'' joking from time to time. But the strike-forced vacation became no laughing matter, <PERSON> Carson </PERSON> said, with longtime workers in his production company facing layoffs. Through a spokesman, <PERSON> Carson </PERSON> said that he was frustrated with efforts to reach an independent contract with the guild that would permit his scriptwriters to return. Talks with <PERSON> Carson </PERSON> and at least 80 other independent producers are continuing. Scriptwriters voted April 14 not to grant independent contracts until it had a number of them in hand to avoid the divisiveness of only a few members returning to work. <PERSON> Arthur </PERSON> <PERSON> Sellers </PERSON>, a member of the guild negotiating committee, said Friday that it was possible the membership `` may decide to move ahead and sign independent contracts this month.'' Meanwhile, the daytime soap operas have continued production. `` Scab scripts ai n't fun,'' said actress <PERSON> Norma </PERSON> <PERSON> Connolly </PERSON>, who plays <PERSON> Aunt </PERSON> <PERSON> Ruby </PERSON> on `` General Hospital.'' `` They make our days long and hard. They're illiterate,'' she said Wednesday as she walked a picket line with the guild. `` You have to continue,'' said <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Balme </PERSON>, one of the show's producers `` You owe it to the audience and to the network,'' he said, adding: `` We miss -LRB- the writers -RRB-. We want them back.'' The writing is `` getting to look like ` See <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> run,''' said actress <PERSON> Peggy </PERSON> <PERSON> McCary </PERSON> of `` Days of Our Lives.'' Labor-management relations can be unusual in <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION>. Striking scriptwriter <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Goethals </PERSON> said he is surviving on tuna fish sandwiches and loans from friends, who also happen to be producers. Producer <PERSON> Cannell </PERSON>, also a member of the <ORGANIZATION> Writers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guild </ORGANIZATION>, honors the strike and stays away from his typewriter. `` Since I was a writer first, I'm not going to scab during the strike,'' <PERSON> Cannell </PERSON> said. But he feels a conflict. `` I do n't think it's going to settle on the Writers Guild terms no matter what they think. I think it could go on to January if the wrong set of philosophies get used ... if they keep saying the companies are getting fat.'' Like many other producers, <PERSON> Cannell </PERSON> has cut paychecks in half as a means of keeping on staff. <ORGANIZATION> Cannell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Productions </ORGANIZATION> turns out such television series as `` Hunter,'' `` The A-Team,'' `` <ORGANIZATION> Hardcastle </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> McCormick </PERSON>'' and `` The Rockford Files.'' Meanwhile, `` Moonlighting'' star <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Willis </PERSON> has taken up gardening. His ABC-TV series shut down early because of a lack of scripts. Though he's not at work, <PERSON> Willis </PERSON> still has his problems. `` I'm having a lot of trouble with snails,'' <PERSON> Willis </PERSON> said recently as he surveyed a tiny bed of marigolds and snapdragons.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880508-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-08-88 2348EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-ArgentineGeneral 1stLd-Writethru a0829 05-08 0504</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Argentine General, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0829,0513</SECOND>
<HEAD>Retired Argentine General Admits Ordering Publisher's Arrest</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Leads with 5 grafs to UPDATE with police official declining
knowledge know about Suarez Mason's return. Pickup 3rd graf pvs
``In a...''</NOTE>
<HEAD>Precede LOS ANGELES</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BUENOS AIRES, Argentina (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A retired Argentine general arrested in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> reportedly has been sent back to <LOCATION> Argentina </LOCATION> Sunday to face murder charges but a police official here could not confirm his arrival. Gen. <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Suarez </PERSON> <PERSON> Mason </PERSON> had acknowledged ordering the 1977 arrest of publisher <PERSON> Jacobo </PERSON> <PERSON> Timerman </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Los </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Angeles </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> reported Sunday. It said he made the statement Saturday before he was extradited from <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> to face 39 murder charges in <LOCATION> Argentina </LOCATION>. Federal Police Chief Juan Angel Pirker, questioned by newsmen in <LOCATION> Buenos </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Aires </LOCATION> about the report, said: `` Officially, I know nothing.'' A <LOCATION> Buenos </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Aires </LOCATION> newspaper, <ORGANIZATION> Pagina </ORGANIZATION> 12, reported in its Sunday edition that <PERSON> Suarez </PERSON> <PERSON> Mason </PERSON> had been `` expected to arrive this morning'' at the capital's <ORGANIZATION> Ezeiza </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airport </ORGANIZATION>. But it said strict security measures in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> `` made it impossible to verify whether <PERSON> Suarez </PERSON> <PERSON> Mason </PERSON> did depart or on what flight, although it was certain that he left the -LRB- <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> -RRB- country jail for the airport yesterday -LRB- Saturday -RRB- at 10:30 am. local time.'' In a legal deposition, <PERSON> Suarez </PERSON> <PERSON> Mason </PERSON> discussed his role in <LOCATION> Argentina </LOCATION>'s military government during its `` dirty war'' against suspected subversives in the 1970s, The Los Angelest Times reported. The ex-general was interviewed Friday and Saturday by <PERSON> Joanne </PERSON> <PERSON> Hoeper </PERSON>, working on behalf of plaintiffs seeking damages in federal court for victims of the Argentine junta. The junta has been blamed for the deaths of thousands of people. <PERSON> Suarez </PERSON> <PERSON> Mason </PERSON>, 64, said he ordered <PERSON> Timerman </PERSON>'s arrest after a subordinate presented him with accusations that the publisher was `` friends with a man who owned a bank that funded guerrillas,'' the Times quoted the attorney as saying. It was believed to be the first time <PERSON> Suarez </PERSON> <PERSON> Mason </PERSON> had acknowledged his role in the arrest of <PERSON> Timerman </PERSON>, who described his imprisonment and torture in the 1981 book `` Prisoner Without A Name, Cell Without A Number.'' The newspaper quoted Ms. <PERSON> Hoeper </PERSON> as saying <PERSON> Suarez </PERSON> <PERSON> Mason </PERSON> `` knew <PERSON> Timerman </PERSON> was being interrogated. He said he listened to a tape-recording of an interrogation ...'' The military confiscated <PERSON> Timerman </PERSON>'s newspaper, La Opinion, which campaigned against the junta's anti-Semitic policies. <PERSON> Timerman </PERSON> spent 29 months in jail and under house arrest before being expelled to <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>, where he became a citizen. <PERSON> Timerman </PERSON> returned to <LOCATION> Buenos </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Aires </LOCATION> last year and has received $ 5 million from the government as compensation for the loss of his newspaper. <PERSON> Suarez </PERSON> <PERSON> Mason </PERSON> commanded the <ORGANIZATION> First </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corps </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Buenos </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Aires </LOCATION> from 1976 to 1979. He fled the country after a civilian government took over in 1983 and was arrested in January 1987 south of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION>, where he was living under an assumed name. A panel of <LOCATION> Argentina </LOCATION>'s civilian government has said at least 9,000 people disappeared during the nine-year rule by the military, including 5,000 in the region where <PERSON> Suarez </PERSON> <PERSON> Mason </PERSON> was commander.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880508-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-08-88 2350EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-SupermarketSitters     05-08 0416</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Supermarket Sitters,0431</SECOND>
<HEAD>Grocery Store Provides Babysitting Service For Customers</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PAUL DE LA GARZA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CARBONDALE, Ill. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Some kids call it the `` grocery-store school'' and some parents call it a godsend. It's a baby-sitting service at the supermarket that lets parents in peace, and leaves more room in the cart for groceries. `` It's definitely helpful, especially when a mother has only two hands and two children and -LRB- is -RRB- trying to grocery shop,'' said 35-year-old <PERSON> Karen </PERSON> <PERSON> Redfearn </PERSON>, who drives 17 miles from <LOCATION> Herrin </LOCATION> to shop at the Country Fair store in <LOCATION> Carbondale </LOCATION>. `` It's terrific,'' she said. Located at the front of the Country Fair store, the baby-sitting center has a color TV, a video cassette recorder, a 55-gallon aquarium, two bulletin boards, five bean bags, five plastic trucks and cars and stuffed animals. But if junior still gets bored, there's a 60-piece set of wooden building blocks, a xylophone, an Etch-a-Sketch, a toy telephone and a toy cash register. Safety scissors, glue and paint brushes, crayons, markers and paper complete the picture. The 18-by-16-foot area is a separate room from the store. It has brown carpeted floors and its walls are decorated with drawings by the children. Big windows allow parents to check in on their youngsters while they shop. `` My biggest problem is trying to get the kids to leave on time,'' said <PERSON> Sandy </PERSON> <PERSON> Overstreet </PERSON>, 23, coordinator of the <LOCATION> Carbondale </LOCATION> center. `` They like to go to grocery-store school _ some of the kids call it that.'' The child-care center opened in October and entertained its 6,000 th youngster this past week `` I've had a lot of positive comments from mothers, from customers,'' said store manager <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Schmutz </PERSON>. `` I've had a lot of older mothers tell me we should've done this 20 years ago.'' `` The kids enjoy themselves more so than they enjoy grocery shopping,'' said 32-year-old <PERSON> Connie </PERSON> <PERSON> Hirsh </PERSON> shortly after picking up her year-old daughter at the center. A minimum $ 25 purchase at the store entitles parents to up to two hours of free child care. After two hours, there's a $ 5-an-hour charge. To ensure safety, the same person who checks a child in must check him out, and parents must remain on the store premises while the child is at the center. Children from age six months to six years are accepted. The idea came from <PERSON> Pete </PERSON> <PERSON> Bradham </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Mount </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vernon </LOCATION>, owner of the five Country Fairs in the <LOCATION> Southern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> area. All but one offer the baby-sitting service.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880508-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-08-88 2351EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-LaunderingRing     05-08 0796</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Laundering Ring,0818</SECOND>
<HEAD>Retransmitting a0411 to fix byline</HEAD>
<HEAD>`Nice People' Who Bought Ranch Accused Of Money Laundering</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By GIL BROYLES</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ATOKA, Okla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The people who moved onto the <LOCATION> George </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ranch </LOCATION> late in 1985 made friends easily. Nobody in this rural area where a man's background is his own business questioned their claim to have bought the ranch with an inheritance. But the federal government alleges that the <LOCATION> Atoka </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> ranch north of <LOCATION> Stringtown </LOCATION> was a cover for laundering more than $ 1 million in proceeds from international drug trafficking by claiming the money came from cattle sales. Federal authorities also allege the isolated 2,889-acre property, since renamed the Junior Ranch, was bought as a refuge for <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Contreras </PERSON> <PERSON> Subias </PERSON>, a Mexican national wanted for questioning in the torture slaying of a <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Drug </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Enforcement </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> agent, the killings of nine Venezuelan national guardsmen and the slaying of a Mexican federal police officer. <PERSON> Contreras </PERSON> was arrested April 1 in <LOCATION> Salt </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> and is jailed in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>. Although federal officials now say they had been investigating the southeast <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION> ranch for two years, the lid started coming off when two Texans stumbled onto a nearby marijuana-growing operation in August. They accused the owner of that ranch of abduction and details started emerging at the subsequent trial. `` If he does n't bother you, then why bother him? Just because they came in with a lot of money?'' said <PERSON> Troy </PERSON> <PERSON> Gammon </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Atoka </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> clerk. When the Mexicans bought the ranch, it was viewed as a logical investment of their money. `` They told us they inherited it. We believed them and we welcomed them to the community,'' said <LOCATION> Atoka </LOCATION> City Manager <PERSON> Martha </PERSON> <PERSON> Yates </PERSON>. `` We are still in shock.'' Residents knew <PERSON> Contreras </PERSON> as <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> or <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Guillen </PERSON>. People interviewed last week said he was a model citizen who made friends easily because of his gentel ways. `` They were planting feed, not dope,'' said a businessman who would talk to a reporter only if his name were not used. `` They came here to make it their home.'' <PERSON> Contreras </PERSON> drove a hard bargain and wrote checks for purchases rather than paying cash, the businessman said. Most big-ticket items were financed. `` Does that sound like they were laundering money?'' he asked. But residents reported to be closely associated with <PERSON> Contreras </PERSON> now deny knowing him well. People who attended parties at the ranch threaten lawsuits if their names are mentioned in connection with <PERSON> Contreras </PERSON>. <PERSON> Contreras </PERSON>, 42, originally was arrested in 1985 in <LOCATION> Costa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rica </LOCATION> with Mexican drug king <PERSON> Rafael </PERSON> <PERSON> Caro </PERSON> <PERSON> Quintero </PERSON>. <PERSON> Quintero </PERSON> is awaiting trial in the 1985 slaying of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> DEA agent <PERSON> Enrique </PERSON> <PERSON> Camarena </PERSON>. <PERSON> Contreras </PERSON> was sent to jail in <LOCATION> Tijuana </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, to stand trial for the slaying of a Mexican federal agent. But he escaped in October 1985 after bribing his jailers, according to documents filed by <ORGANIZATION> DEA </ORGANIZATION> agents. Two months before his escape, a group of Mexicans negotiated to buy the <LOCATION> Atoka </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> ranch from rancher <PERSON> E.H. </PERSON> <PERSON> George </PERSON>, at a price of $ 900,000, plus $ 99,000 for the cattle and hay, according to an <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> affidavit. The $ 500,000 down payment originated as cashier's checks in <LOCATION> Tijuana </LOCATION> on Oct. 22, 1985, six days before <PERSON> Contreras </PERSON>' escape. Ten days after his escape, a checking account was opened at the <ORGANIZATION> Atoka </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> for <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Guillen </PERSON>. From November 1985 through September 1987, more than $ 1.4 million was deposited in the <LOCATION> Atoka </LOCATION> <LOCATION> State </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> account, according to a federal affidavit. Neither the bank nor its officers has been accused of wrongdoing. More money went into a bank in <PERSON> Durant </PERSON>. <PERSON> Contreras </PERSON>' alleged operation began to come unraveled in August, when two Texans rode their three-wheelers onto the Bar-20 Ranch. They said they were shot at, abducted and held in chains before they escaped. Police raided the ranch and discovered more than 6,700 marijuana plants. Ranch owner <PERSON> Elbert </PERSON> <PERSON> Lucien </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> and two co-defendants were convicted of running one of the state's largest marijuana farms. At the trial, testimony brought up small details linking the two ranches and the people associated with them. Among other things, authorities allege <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> provided the introductions for the Mexicans to buy the <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Ranch </PERSON>. `` We've been aware that they were there for a long time,'' <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Attorney <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> Hilfiger </PERSON> said of the Junior Ranch. He said <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>'s arrest `` let the cat out of the bag. The day after <PERSON> Contreras </PERSON>' arrest, federal authorities raided the Junior Ranch and another property near <LOCATION> Plano </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, and seized documents they are still studying. They also filed notice of intention to seize the ranch and other property as the proceeds of illegal drug transactions. No criminal charges have been filed related to the operation of the Junior Ranch, but a federal grand jury convenes May 31 in <LOCATION> Muskogee </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880508-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-08-88 2358EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-Deaths 1stLd-Writethru a0828 05-08 0516</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Deaths, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0828,0531</SECOND>
<NOTE>Eds: ADDS Sickman and Hogan deaths. An AM separate moved on
Sickman as a0849.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Costantino Nivola</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SOUTHAMPTON, N.Y. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Costantino </PERSON> <PERSON> Nivola </PERSON>, a sculptor whose work ranged from huge bas-relief murals for public buildings to female figurines on an intimate scale, died of a heart attack Thursday at age 76. A native of <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>, he moved to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> in 1939 and became an early champion of modern architecture. His commissions included a 110-foot-long mural for the <ORGANIZATION> Mutual </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Insurance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Hartford </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Conn. </LOCATION> -RRB- building; a war memorial in <LOCATION> Falls </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Church </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>; a sand-sculptured wall for the former <ORGANIZATION> Olivetti </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> showroom on <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>'s Fifth Avenue, now at <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION>, and numerous sculptures and wall paintings for playgrounds in and around <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>Cruz Luna</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SAN FRANCISCO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Flamenco dancer <PERSON> Cruz </PERSON> <PERSON> Luna </PERSON>, who learned his art in his native <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION> and launched his career at age 17 with appearances on television's <PERSON> Ed </PERSON> <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON> and <PERSON> Dave </PERSON> <PERSON> Garroway </PERSON> shows, died April 29. He was 50. <PERSON> Luna </PERSON> danced in an international tour with the <ORGANIZATION> Ballet </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nacional </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION> and in the Broadway show `` Ole! Ole!'' From 1960 to 1974, he operated <ORGANIZATION> Cafe </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Madrid </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION> and presented flamenco dancers from around the world.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>John H. Calhoun</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ATLANTA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>George Burns</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SCHENECTADY, N.Y. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Burns </PERSON>, a pioneer in industrial news photography and one of the combat photographers to shoot the raising of the American flag on Iwo Jima during World War II, died Saturday. He was 71. In 1939, <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Electric </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, which started the first news bureau in <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> industry, hired <PERSON> Burns </PERSON> to oversee it.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>Laurence Sickman</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>KANSAS CITY, Mo. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Laurence </PERSON> <PERSON> Sickman </PERSON>, former director of the Nelson Art Gallery in <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> and an internationally known authority on Chinese art, died Saturday at age 81. <PERSON> Sickman </PERSON> graduated from <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> in 1930 and began working as an agent for art purchases in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> in 1931, two years before the museum opened. In 1935 he became its first curator of Oriental art. He retired in 1977.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>Patrick Hogan</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Patrick </PERSON> <PERSON> Hogan </PERSON>, an abstract artist who had to use his mouth to hold a paintbrush because of a rare and progressive form of muscular atrophy, died of respiratory failure Thursday. He was 41. <PERSON> Hogan </PERSON>'s works were shown at such galleries as the <ORGANIZATION> Whitney </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Museum </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Art </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Guggenhem </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Museum </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Los </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Angeles </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Museum </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Art </ORGANIZATION>. He studied art at <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> at <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ridge </LOCATION>. His disease first appeared when he was 5 years old, and he used a wheelchair from the age of 10, when he was given only a few years to live.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880508-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-08-88 0108EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p AM-TexasElections 1stLd-Writethru a0702 05-08 0327</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Texas Elections, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0702,0332</SECOND>
<HEAD>Horse Racing Ballot Question Appears To Carry</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: UPDATES with final Lubbock returns and additional Dallas
returns, Austin mayoral results; fixes style of pari-mutuel
throughout. No pickup</NOTE>
<DATELINE>DALLAS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A ballot proposal to authorize horse racing and pari-mutuel betting was approved Saturday in <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> and, by a narrow margin, in <LOCATION> Lubbock </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, where church leaders opposed it. They were the only two <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> counties voting on the issue Saturday. Other counties voted in November, when residents statewide approved a proposal to let counties determine whether to allow wagering on horses. With 98 percent of the precincts reporting, the vote in <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> was 40,793, or 56 percent, for pari-mutuel betting and 31,626, or 44 percent, against. The final tally in <LOCATION> Lubbock </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> was 18,939, or 52 percent, for pari-mutuel betting, and 17,541, or 48 percent, against. Throughout the state, voters were also electing mayors, city councilmen and school trustees. The voting stirred limited interest in <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, where elections administrator <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Sherbet </PERSON> said he expected only about 10 percent of the registered voters to turn out. But <LOCATION> Lubbock </LOCATION> City Secretary <PERSON> Ranette </PERSON> <PERSON> Boyd </PERSON> said her telephone was kept busy with calls from people wanting to know where they could vote. She predicted a <LOCATION> Lubbock </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> turnout almost twice that of the last general election. Pari-mutuel betting was the most volatile issue on the ballot in the county since a narrow vote almost 20 years ago to legalize mixed-drink sales. Proponents of horse race betting tout it as a multimillion-dollar economic boon; opponents say it will lead to crime and compulsive gambling. Citizens Against Pari-Mutuel Gambling campaigned against the proposition largely through a mailing to 100 local churches, said <PERSON> Gene </PERSON> <PERSON> Glaeser </PERSON>, minister of <ORGANIZATION> Broadway </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Christ </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Lubbock </LOCATION>. In the <LOCATION> Austin </LOCATION> mayoral race, incumbent Mayor <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Cooksey </PERSON> came in second to former City Councilman <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Cooke </PERSON>, but six other candidates split enough votes to force a runoff.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880508-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-08-88 0130EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-DeadWhale     05-08 0194</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Dead Whale,0198</SECOND>
<HEAD>Dead Whale Found Under San Francisco Pier</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SAN FRANCISCO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A 40-foot adult gray whale was found dead and lodged under a pier in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION> on Saturday, officials said. <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Jane </PERSON> <PERSON> Schramm </PERSON>, a spokeswoman with the <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mammal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Sausalito </LOCATION>, said it was n't immediately known if the whale was dead when it washed under Pier 70, or if it died after getting under the structure. The whale had deep slash marks on its head, and some of them involved the animal's blow hole, which allows it to inhale and exhale, said <PERSON> Schramm </PERSON>. <PERSON> Schramm </PERSON> feared the marks could have been caused by a ship's propeller But she did not rule out the possibility they were made by a veterinarian who examined the dead whale after it was found. He could not be reached for comment. Whales often hug the <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> coastline while migrating between Arctic waters and the warmer <LOCATION> Baja </LOCATION> <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> waters from January through May, <PERSON> Schramm </PERSON> said. Authorities were relieved to learn that the dead whale was not the juvenile whale that was spotted several times in recent weeks frolicking around the bay, she said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880508-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-08-88 0224EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Hostage-Anderson     05-08 0231</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Hostage-Anderson,0237</SECOND>
<HEAD>Hostage Wife Appeals to Reagan to Act for His Release</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NICOSIA, Cyprus (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The wife of American hostage <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> has issued an appeal to President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> to help free him from captors in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Madeleine </PERSON> <PERSON> Bassil </PERSON> made a televised statement Saturday to <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, saying, `` Mr. <PERSON> President </PERSON>, you probably have never heard of me but you certainly know that <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON>, hostage in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> for over three years, has a family.'' Ms. <PERSON> Bassil </PERSON>, who is <LOCATION> Lebanese </LOCATION>, said their 2-year-old daughter <PERSON> Sulome </PERSON> `` can not accept my excuses any longer of why her daddy is only a picture.'' <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON>, chief <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> correspondent for the <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>, was kidnapped in <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> March 16, 1985. He has never seen his daughter. Ms. <PERSON> Bassil </PERSON>'s plea to <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> comes four days after three French hostages were released in <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> by the <ORGANIZATION> Islamic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Jihad </ORGANIZATION>, the same pro-Iranian group that claims to hold <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON>. `` Compromising now is the only solution,'' she told <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>. `` Are we to wait -LRB- for -RRB- an election before we see our loved one? We ca n't wait any longer, Mr. President. You must do something now before things get out of hand.'' Another American hostage, <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Sutherland </PERSON>, dean of agriculture at the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Beirut </ORGANIZATION>, is also believed held by Islamic Jihad. He was kidnapped in June 1985. <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> and <PERSON> Sutherland </PERSON> are among 18 foreign hostages, including nine Americans, being held hostage.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880508-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-08-88 0305EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i BC-Gulf-Attack     05-08 0161</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Gulf-Attack,0166</SECOND>
<HEAD>Iraq Announces Hits on Two Iranian Ships</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NICOSIA, Cyprus (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Iraqi warplanes attacked and hit two Iranian ships in the <LOCATION> Perisan </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Iraq </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> reported Sunday. The agency, monitored in <LOCATION> Nicosia </LOCATION>, said one of the `` maritime targets'' was large and one medium-sized. It said the hits were `` accurate and effective,'' and the attacking planes returned to base safely. <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> did not describe the ships further and did not say whether the attack took place late Saturday or early Sunday. There was no immediate word on the attack from <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>. The attack took place near the Iranian oil loading platform at <LOCATION> Lavan </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> in the southern gulf, the Iraqi agency said. `` This attack comes as part of our legal right to tear up all oil supply routes of the Iranian regime which uses the profits for its hostile and evil goals,'' the agency said. <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> have been at war for more than 7 -LCB- years.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880508-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-08-88 0333EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i BC-India-Sikhs     05-08 0229</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-India-Sikhs,0236</SECOND>
<HEAD>23 Die, 25 Wounded In Sikh Attacks</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CHANDIGARH, India (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Sikh gunmen fired into a group of migrant workers at a wedding celebration in <LOCATION> Haryana </LOCATION> state Saturday night, killing 13 people and wounding at least 25 others, police said. Sikh extremists were blamed for 10 other deaths late Saturday and early Sunday in the neighboring northern Indian state of <LOCATION> Punjab </LOCATION>, including a Hindu family of four and its two servants, the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> India </ORGANIZATION> reported. The extremists have been waging a guerrilla campaign since 1982 for more political autonomy or an independent homeland for Sikhs in <LOCATION> Punjab </LOCATION>. The latest killings raised to more than 940 the number of deaths blamed on the Sikh separatists since the start of the year. Most of the victims have been Hindus or moderate Sikhs in <LOCATION> Punjab </LOCATION> who oppose the radicals' guerrilla campaign. The migrant workers were killed near <LOCATION> Panipat </LOCATION>, 90 miles south of the joint <LOCATION> Punjab-Haryana </LOCATION> state capital at <LOCATION> Chandigarh </LOCATION>. Police said that six gunmen crossed from <LOCATION> Punjab </LOCATION> state into <LOCATION> Haryana </LOCATION> and fired AK-47 automatic rifles at the workers as they were celebrating a wedding. Sikhs, whose religion was founded about 500 years ago as an alternative to <LOCATION> Hinduism </LOCATION> and Islam, claim they are discriminated against by <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>'s majority Hindus. Sikhs make up less than 2 percent of <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>'s 800 million population but are a majority in <LOCATION> Punjab </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880508-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-08-88 0816EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i BC-Israel-Awad     05-08 0261</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Israel-Awad,0268</SECOND>
<HEAD>Court Delays Expulsion of Arab-American</HEAD>
<DATELINE>JERUSALEM (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> on Sunday delayed the deportation of <PERSON> Mubarak </PERSON> <PERSON> Awad </PERSON>, an Arab-American, and ordered the government to explain its decision, a court spokesman said. Justice <PERSON> Shoshana </PERSON> <PERSON> Netanyahu </PERSON> scheduled a hearing on <PERSON> Awad </PERSON>'s appeal for Monday morning, spokesman <PERSON> Shmaryahu </PERSON> <PERSON> Cohen </PERSON> told The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Awad </PERSON>, 44, an advocate of civil disobedience, was detained Thursday. The expulsion order was issued Friday and was to take effect at midnight Sunday. Prime Minister <PERSON> Yitzhak </PERSON> <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON> issued the expulsion order against <PERSON> Awad </PERSON>, alleging he incited violence during the 5-month-old Palestinian uprising in the occupied <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strip </LOCATION>. According to <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> figures, 184 Palestinians and two Israelis have been killed since the violence began Dec. 8. <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> has also accused <PERSON> Awad </PERSON> of being behind a leaflet issued last month that urged Palestinians to throw firebombs and rocks at Israeli targets. <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> radio said <PERSON> Awad </PERSON> filed an appeal against the deportation Sunday after his attorneys visited him in a <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION> jail, where he has been on hunger strike since his arrest. The Jerusalem-born Awad heads the Center for Non-Violent Studies in <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION>. Some of the methods preached by <PERSON> Awad </PERSON>, such as boycotts of Israeli goods, nonpayment of taxes and sit-ins, have been adopted by underground leaders of the uprising. Awad has said that unlike <ORGANIZATION> Palestine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> extremists, he advocates peaceful coexistence between Israelis and Palestinians. <PERSON> Awad </PERSON> is a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> citizen who has a home in <LOCATION> Wapakoneta </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>. The deportation order prompted protests from the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government, which urged <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> to reconsider the move.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880508-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-08-88 1202EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Brites     05-08 0829</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Brites,0864</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bright &amp; Brief</HEAD>
<DATELINE>FISHERS, Ind. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Clarence </PERSON> `` Cap'' <PERSON> Cornish </PERSON> celebrated the 70th anniversary of his first solo flight the same way he's marked the occasion every year _ flying high. The 89-year-old retired insurance executive took his wife, <PERSON> Lois </PERSON>, and daughter, <PERSON> Ruthanne </PERSON> <PERSON> Krieg </PERSON>, for a five-minute plane ride Friday. Through the years, <PERSON> Cornish </PERSON> has n't missed a single May 6 commemorative flight. Flying was different when the man who eventually became <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION>'s first aeronautics commissioner first took to the air as a 19-year-old. `` There were n't any navigational aids at all then and no charts. I flew with a Rand McNally road map,'' said <PERSON> Cornish </PERSON>. `` Those were the days before parachutes, too. If you made a serious error, you could end up dead and embarrassed.'' <PERSON> Cornish </PERSON> served during World War I in the aviation section of the <ORGANIZATION> Signal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corps </ORGANIZATION>, the precursor of the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Cornish </PERSON> took his first solo flight May 6, 1918, after just four hours and 20 minutes of instruction. He was then assigned to train other young airmen. `` I did n't know anything about fighting Germans in the air and neither did my students,'' he said. `` It was the blind leading the blind.'' <PERSON> Cornish </PERSON> served for eight years as <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION>'s first aeronautics commissioner following World War II.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>CHADBOURN, N.C. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Everyone was so busy marching and judging and eating strawberries that hardly anyone noticed the homemade shortcake had taken a big splat and had to be replaced with the store-bought variety. Beauty queens and high school bands marched through this town of 2,000 and judges tasted every variety of strawberry recipe as <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolinians </LOCATION> celebrated their 56th Strawberry Festival. The weekend fair, billed as the state's oldest agricultural festival, drew hundreds of entries and thousands of spectators. `` I do n't think anybody has noticed that the cakes were store-bought,'' said <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Yates </PERSON>. He was supposed to deliver 15 large sheet cakes baked by the women of his fraternal society, based in another town a few miles away. But the cakes fell out of the back of the pickup. <PERSON> Yates </PERSON> said he and a fellow lodge member `` heard something'' when a large truck passed them. `` We got out, went around and looked, and sure enough ... all the cake was in little pieces all over the highway.'' They beat it to a local supermarket and bought up as much pound cake as they could find _ enough to make the approximately 1,500 servings needed.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEWPORT NEWS, Va. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 When <PERSON> Theresa </PERSON> <PERSON> Earwood </PERSON> left <ORGANIZATION> Virginia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Speciality </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Stores </ORGANIZATION> to pick up lunch for a co-worker, she did n't plan to bring home a moral dilemma in the bag. Inside was a game piece for a new giveaway being test-marketed by <PERSON> Wendy </PERSON>'s in <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>. Ms. <PERSON> Earwood </PERSON> opened the piece, thinking <PERSON> Bernadette </PERSON> <PERSON> Barber </PERSON> would never notice. It was an instant $ 5,000 winner. Morals came out on top, and <PERSON> Ms. </PERSON> <PERSON> Earwood </PERSON>, 26, decided to slip the piece back in the bag and forget about it. `` I would have had to live with it for the rest of my life,'' she said. Ms. <PERSON> Barber </PERSON>, 39, found the open game piece in her lunch Thursday, but did n't realize she had won until a few hours later. `` Then when I did, I cried.'' <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Fields </PERSON>, district manager for <ORGANIZATION> Wendy </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION>, said the company had to wait for independent verification that Ms. <PERSON> Barber </PERSON>'s game piece was a winner, which should take about a week. After she pays taxes on the prize, Ms. <PERSON> Barber </PERSON> said she plans to pick up some `` odds and ends.'' She said she does not plan to split the money with Ms. <PERSON> Earwood </PERSON>, but will give her some kind of reward. `` It's a hard decision,'' she said. `` What would you do?''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>SALT LAKE CITY (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 It was with some trepidation that <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Bagley </PERSON>, cartoonist for <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Salt </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lake </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tribune </ORGANIZATION>, opened the package from retiring <LOCATION> Salt </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> Police Chief E. L. `` Bud'' <PERSON> Willoughby </PERSON>. After all, <PERSON> Bagley </PERSON> had lampooned the chief more than once about the day in 1980 when <PERSON> Willoughby </PERSON> popped a trash can over his head and gingerly carried a what looked like a bomb out of a bank. The `` bomb'' turned out to be a bundle of highway flares. The moment was captured on film and published in the newspaper, and there are those who believe to this day that <PERSON> Willoughby </PERSON> secretly wished he could have crawled underneath that can and stayed there until the cameras were gone. So it was n't surprising that <PERSON> Bagley </PERSON> took cover beneath his own trash can and cautiously peeled away the tape on the cardboard box. The precautions were unnecessary. So were <PERSON> Bagley </PERSON>'s concerns that maybe <PERSON> Willoughby </PERSON> did n't like him so well. The box contained one of <PERSON> Willoughby </PERSON>'s prized possessions _ the official <LOCATION> Salt </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> Bomb Squad `` helmet'' given him by thoughtful patrolmen after the bank incident. It's a gunmetal gray trash can, resplendent with official <ORGANIZATION> Salt </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lake </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION> patches, visor and a peephole.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880508-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-08-88 1207EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Psychiatrist-Fortune Bjt   05-08 1080</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Psychiatrist-Fortune, Bjt,1113</SECOND>
<HEAD>Prominent Psychiatrist Accused Of Unethical Conduct In Fortune
Squabble</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By WILLIAM C. HIDLAY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CHICAGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The president of the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Psychiatric </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> is accused in a probate dispute of exploiting a woman who gave him $ 80,000 a year in trusts and willed $ 5 million to a psychiatric institute she founded during a decade of psychoanalysis with him. The legal battle is between Dr. <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Pollock </PERSON>, one of <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>'s leading psychoanalysts, and <PERSON> Francis </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Lederer </PERSON> <PERSON> II </PERSON>, only child of <PERSON> Anne </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Lederer </PERSON>, who died in 1984 at age 78 <PERSON> Pollock </PERSON> denies any wrongdoing. Mrs. <PERSON> Lederer </PERSON> left most of her estimated $ 5 million estate to a non-profit institute she established four years earlier to promote psychiatric research and music. None of the money has been paid, however, because her son is contesting her will in <ORGANIZATION> Cook </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Probate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>. A trial is scheduled to begin July 5. <PERSON> Lederer </PERSON> accused <PERSON> Pollock </PERSON> of improperly using his influence while treating his mother for depression to urge her to create the institute and `` wrongfully inducing'' her to bequeath her fortune to it, according to court documents. <PERSON> Pollock </PERSON>, who was attending the annual meeting of the association in <LOCATION> Montreal </LOCATION>, referred calls for comment to his attorney, <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Tepper </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Tepper </PERSON> said he had advised <PERSON> Pollock </PERSON> not to discuss the case. But <PERSON> Pollock </PERSON> denied the allegations in an affidavit Dec. 4, 1986. `` I never made false representations to her for the purpose and with the intent of improperly controlling, dominating and misleading her and unduly influencing and wrongfully inducing her to execute her last will,'' <PERSON> Pollock </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Tepper </PERSON> said he saw `` no support or substantiation'' for claims that Mrs. <PERSON> Lederer </PERSON> was incompetent or unduly influenced. `` But anyone can file a lawsuit, and these days it has become a recognized means of social expression,'' he added. Dr. <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Strasburger </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> psychiatrist who reviewed <PERSON> Pollock </PERSON>'s conduct in Mrs. <PERSON> Lederer </PERSON>'s case at the request of her son's attorneys, contended in a deposition that there were grounds for a malpractice suit. He was paid $ 200 an hour as an expert witness. <PERSON> Strasburger </PERSON> said he reviewed Mrs. <PERSON> Lederer </PERSON>'s prescription records and found she was taking enough medication to become psychologically and physically addicted. <PERSON> Pollock </PERSON>, who will step down as president when the association's annual meeting ends Thursday, also is director of the <ORGANIZATION> Chicago </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Psychoanalysis </ORGANIZATION> and a <ORGANIZATION> Northwestern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> professor <PERSON> Pollock </PERSON> conducted up to five sessions a week with Mrs. <PERSON> Lederer </PERSON> from 1969 to 1980, when he transferred her case to two other psychiatrists, saying he needed more time for other professional duties, court documents show. <PERSON> Pollock </PERSON> continued prescribing medication for her until 1983, and records show he told the succeeding psychiatrists in a letter: `` Incidentally, I do hope that you are charging her a full fee for your housecalls and visits. She can well afford it.'' During the years Mrs. <PERSON> Lederer </PERSON> was a patient of <LOCATION> Pollock </LOCATION>: _ She established a trust fund that has paid <PERSON> Pollock </PERSON> $ 50,000 a year since 1976 and will continue paying him through 1993 She established a second trust that has paid <PERSON> Pollock </PERSON>'s family $ 30,000 a year since 1978. Court records are n't clear when the second trust expires. _ From 1969 until her death, Mrs. <PERSON> Lederer </PERSON> donated $ 601,330 to the <ORGANIZATION> Chicago </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Psychoanalysis </ORGANIZATION> Of that money, $ 60,233 went to a depression research fund controlled by <PERSON> Pollock </PERSON>. _ In 1980, she created the <PERSON> Anne </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Lederer </PERSON> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <PERSON> Pollock </PERSON> worked for a short time as a paid consultant to the institute, but said in his affidavit that `` there is no secret agreement'' for him to participate in its future operations. He also denied receiving any benefit from Mrs. <PERSON> Lederer </PERSON>'s will. _ Mrs <PERSON> Lederer </PERSON> dismissed her longtime attorneys when they expressed reservations about her institute and hired <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> lawyer <PERSON> Leonard </PERSON> <PERSON> Schanfield </PERSON>, a friend of <PERSON> Pollock </PERSON>. _ In 1982, she amended her will to leave $ 200,000 to her son, several thousand dollars to two grandchildren and the rest of her money _ estimated at $ 5 million _ to the <ORGANIZATION> Lederer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> She also named <PERSON> Pollock </PERSON>, <PERSON> Schanfield </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> Continental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Illinois </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ; </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Trust </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> as co-executors of her estate. <PERSON> Tepper </PERSON> said Mrs. <PERSON> Lederer </PERSON>'s son was worth about $ 2 million before her death and that when she died he inherited about $ 6 million from a trust established by her father, E.J. <PERSON> Pollock </PERSON>, vice president and comptroller of <ORGANIZATION> Sears </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Roebuck </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ; </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> in the 1930s. The two <PERSON> Pollock </PERSON> families are not related. Mrs. <PERSON> Lederer </PERSON> referred to her son's wealth to explain in her last will why she was leaving most of her money `` to my foundation.'' <PERSON> Schanfield </PERSON> said Mrs. <PERSON> Lederer </PERSON> told him that he was one of four lawyers referred to her by <PERSON> Pollock </PERSON> to review her estate planning and help her establish the research institute. `` Dr. <PERSON> Pollock </PERSON> played no role whatsoever in establishing that institute,'' <PERSON> Schanfield </PERSON> said Friday in a telephone interview. `` Mrs. <PERSON> Lederer </PERSON> set it up.'' In their briefs, attorneys for Mrs. <PERSON> Lederer </PERSON>'s son, <PERSON> Kevin </PERSON> <PERSON> Murnighan </PERSON> and <PERSON> Phil </PERSON> <PERSON> Doran </PERSON>, suggest she was dependent on <PERSON> Pollock </PERSON>. The attorneys contended that after Mrs. <PERSON> Lederer </PERSON>'s husband, a doctor, died in 1973, `` Dr. <PERSON> Pollock </PERSON> took the place of her husband and he constantly advised her on all facets of life, from where she was going to live, to what she was going to eat, to what medical treatment to get, to what raises to give the housekeeper.'' <PERSON> Tepper </PERSON> said Mrs. <PERSON> Lederer </PERSON> and <PERSON> Pollock </PERSON> were friends, and that the psychiatrist accepted her financial gifts `` because there was no reason not to accept'' them, a point of ethical debate. But <PERSON> Strasburger </PERSON> wrote: `` His acceptance of large gifts to his family, his institution and himself occurred in a pattern of conduct evidencing gross disregard for psychoanalytic principle and psychiatric propriety.'' Dr. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Weinstock </PERSON>, a psychiatrist and associate professor at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION> at <ORGANIZATION> Los </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Angeles </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION>, said he knew of no specific guidelines on ethics that prohibit psychiatrists from accepting gifts or donations from patients. `` I can say that it would be unusual while somebody is in treatment to accept large gifts,'' he said in a telephone interview. `` It's not standard to do that.'' The <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Psychiatric </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>'s principles of medical ethics do not contain a specific provision against accepting money or other gifts from patients beyond professional fees. But the principles do say a psychiatrist `` should not use the unique position of power afforded him by the psychotherapeutic situation to influence the patient in any way not directly relevant to the treatment goals.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880508-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-08-88 1208EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-TonyNominations     05-08 0777</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Tony Nominations,0808</SECOND>
<HEAD>Field Crowded In Many Categories As Tony Award Nominations To Be
Announced</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARY CAMPBELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Tony Awards nominating committee has a happy problem this year, more talent and worthy performances in some categories than can be squeezed into the customary four nominations. Contrary to what has happened in some recent seasons, this year there should be some interesting contests in Broadway's equivalent of <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION>'s Oscars. The nominations are due to be announced Monday. The winners of the 42nd annual awards, to be chosen by a vote by more than 600 theater professionals, will be announced June 5 in a program broadcast nationally on CBS. Three plays eligible for `` best play'' <PERSON> Tony </PERSON> contention are by playwrights who have previously won the Pulitzer Prize, <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Mamet </PERSON>, August <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> and <PERSON> Lanford </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON>. The last play to open before the <PERSON> Tony </PERSON> deadline was <PERSON> Mamet </PERSON>'s `` Speed the Plow,'' which got lavish media attention because it stars rock star-actress <PERSON> Madonna </PERSON> <PERSON> Mamet </PERSON>'s `` Glengarry <PERSON> Glen </PERSON> <PERSON> Ross </PERSON>'' won a Pulitzer in 1984. `` <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Turner </PERSON>'s Come and Gone,'' set early this century, is August <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON>'s latest in his series of plays about the black experience in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, each set in a different decade. His `` Fences,'' set in the 1950s, which won him a Pulitzer Prize last year, is still running. <PERSON> Lanford </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON>, who won the 1980 Pulitzer Prize for `` Talley's Folly,'' one of his cycle of plays about the <PERSON> Talley </PERSON> family on <LOCATION> Broadway </LOCATION>, has a contender this season that is n't in that series, `` Burn This. Three possible `` best play'' nominees are based on real happenings. `` M. Butterfly'' is about a <LOCATION> French </LOCATION> diplomat who had an affair with a <ORGANIZATION> Chinese </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> thinking the man is a woman. `` A Walk in the Woods'' shows an <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> and a <LOCATION> Russian </LOCATION> arms negotiator talking informally outside their conference room in <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION>. And `` Breaking the Code,'' which opened early in the season and is no longer running, is about <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Turing </PERSON>, who broke the German's code in World War II. In musicals, <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Webber </PERSON>'s `` The Phantom of the Opera'' is by far the season's hottest ticket and is almost assured a Tony nomination. It's not necessarily assured the <PERSON> Tony </PERSON>, since the Broadway community's <PERSON> Tony </PERSON> voters are proud of putting their artistic opinions ahead of box-office sales. Anything <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> Sondheim </PERSON> composes also is almost assured a Tony nomination. He won the Pulitzer Prize for drama in 1985 for `` Sunday in the Park with <PERSON> George </PERSON>.'' His `` Into the <PERSON> Woods </PERSON>,'' fairy tales with `` realistic'' endings, opened this season. There's also `` Chess,'' another American-Russian confrontation, with music by the two writers for the rock group <ORGANIZATION> ABBA </ORGANIZATION> and lyrics by <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Webber </PERSON>'s old partner, <PERSON> Tim </PERSON> <PERSON> Rice </PERSON>; `` Sarafina!'', a South African musical set in a terrorized schoolyard; and `` The Gospel at Colonus,'' the Oedipus story told in gospel music. Three which did n't run long are `` Roza,'' `` Mail'' and `` Teddy and <PERSON> Alice </PERSON>.'' The nominating committee's trouble with the best-actor category this year should be narrowing nominees down to four. <PERSON> Derek </PERSON> <PERSON> Jacobi </PERSON> was virtually a one-man show in `` Breaking the Code.'' <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Malkovich </PERSON>, no longer in the cast, was a bravura wild man in `` Burn This.'' <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Prosky </PERSON> plays the <LOCATION> Russian </LOCATION> negotiator, the meatier of the two parts, in `` A Walk in the Woods.'' <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Lithgow </PERSON> is the French diplomat in `` M. Butterfly.'' <PERSON> Christopher </PERSON> <PERSON> Plummer </PERSON> has the title role in `` Macbeth.'' <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Mantegna </PERSON> and <PERSON> Ron </PERSON> <PERSON> Silver </PERSON> costar in `` Speed the Plow.'' <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Langella </PERSON> had the showy title role in `` Sherlock's Last Case,'' which opened last August and ran into December. As usual, starring parts for women are fewer. <PERSON> Blythe </PERSON> <PERSON> Danner </PERSON>, who now has left the cast, was <PERSON> Blanche </PERSON> in `` A Streetcar Named Desire.'' <PERSON> Joan </PERSON> <PERSON> Allen </PERSON> played opposite <PERSON> Malkovich </PERSON> in `` Burn This.'' <PERSON> Prosky </PERSON> and <PERSON> Lithgow </PERSON> act opposite men in their plays. <PERSON> Glenda </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> is <PERSON> Lady </PERSON> <PERSON> Macbeth </PERSON>. <PERSON> Madonna </PERSON> is the third character in `` Speed the Plow.'' For performers in musicals, <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Crawford </PERSON> and <PERSON> Sarah </PERSON> <PERSON> Brightman </PERSON> sing the phantom and his obsession in `` The Phantom of the Opera.'' <PERSON> Patti </PERSON> <PERSON> LuPone </PERSON> and <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> <PERSON> McGillin </PERSON> sing <PERSON> Cole </PERSON> <PERSON> Porter </PERSON> in the revival of `` Anything Goes.'' <PERSON> Joel </PERSON> <PERSON> Grey </PERSON> stars again in the revived `` Cabaret.'' <PERSON> Len </PERSON> <PERSON> Cariou </PERSON> sang <PERSON> Teddy </PERSON> <PERSON> Roosevelt </PERSON> in the departed `` Teddy and <PERSON> Alice </PERSON>.'' <PERSON> Bernadette </PERSON> <PERSON> Peters </PERSON> opened but no longer plays in `` Into the Woods.'' <PERSON> Judy </PERSON> <PERSON> Kuhn </PERSON> forms the triangle on the chessboard of <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Carroll </PERSON> and <PERSON> Philip </PERSON> <PERSON> Casnoff </PERSON> in `` Chess.'' Longer shots for nominations are <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Rupert </PERSON>, starring in `` Mail,'' which he composed, and <PERSON> Georgia </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> singing <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON> <PERSON> Becaud </PERSON> songs in `` Roza,'' which was based on the movie `` Madame Rosa,'' starring <PERSON> Simone </PERSON> <PERSON> Signoret </PERSON>. The Tonies are named for actress <PERSON> Antoinette </PERSON> <PERSON> Perry </PERSON>, who was active in the American Theater Wing during the 1940s.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880508-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-08-88 1217EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a AM-BRF-PantsThief     05-08 0172</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF-Pants Thief,0176</SECOND>
<HEAD>Cabbie Catches Man Who Stole His Pants</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TACOMA, Wash. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Taxicab driver <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> Gibbs </PERSON> could n't believe his eyes. There was the man who stole his pants, asking for a ride home. `` He walked up, higher than a kite, and wanted me to take him home,'' <PERSON> Gibbs </PERSON> said Friday. `` He got a ride home, all right.'' <LOCATION> Pierce </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> sheriff's Sgt. <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Kemmerer </PERSON> confirmed that a man was in custody for investigation of armed robbery. <PERSON> Gibbs </PERSON>, 39, said he signaled a fellow cabbie to follow, took his passenger to an apartment near the gate of <ORGANIZATION> McChord </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Base </ORGANIZATION> south of town and then waited with the other driver until sheriff's deputies arrived and arrested the man Thursday night The man had hailed his cab in the same convenience store parking lot where he had accosted <PERSON> Gibbs </PERSON> with a sawed-off shotgun a week earlier, <PERSON> Gibbs </PERSON> said. In that incident, the robber demanded his pants after finding only $ 49 in his wallet. The pants and wallet were later found nearby.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880508-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-08-88 1209EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w AM-CrowdedAirports Bjt   05-08 0804</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Crowded Airports, Bjt,800</SECOND>
<HEAD>Overcrowding Stirs New Debate Over Airport Priorities</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ALAN FRAM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> effort to relieve runway congestion by increasing landing fees for small planes is evolving into a national debate over the role of major airports. What was a local dispute involving <LOCATION> Logan </LOCATION> <LOCATION> International </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION> has spilled over to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aviation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>. `` This is just the first foot over the line,'' said Rep. <PERSON> Sherwood </PERSON> <PERSON> Boehlert </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-N.Y. </LOCATION>, who has introduced legislation designed to block <LOCATION> Logan </LOCATION> from implementing the plan. `` There are airports all over the country sort of foaming at the mouth, just waiting to follow suit.'' But Rep. <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Markey </PERSON>, D-Mass., said that `` deteriorating air traffic gridlock'' justifies <LOCATION> Logan </LOCATION>'s goal of encouraging small aircraft to use other airfields in the area, saying, `` It's a balancing of equities. <LOCATION> Logan </LOCATION> faces a problem common to many airports: Air traffic and delays are growing, but expansion is unrealistic because of neighborhood opposition, a lack of available land and enormous construction costs. So the <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Port </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Authority </LOCATION>, or <ORGANIZATION> Massport </ORGANIZATION>, the state agency that operates <LOCATION> Logan </LOCATION>, has announced a plan it says will permit more efficient use of the airport by 23 million passengers annually. As of July 1, landing fees for private planes and commuter airlines will be increased from the current minimum of $ 25 to an average of close to $ 100. The costs for large airliners _ now hundreds of dollars _ will drop by varying amounts. `` <ORGANIZATION> Massport </ORGANIZATION> has concluded that the test of efficiency at <LOCATION> Logan </LOCATION> is not the number of airplanes landed per hour, but the number of people handled per hour with a minimum of delay,'' the agency's executive director, <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Davis </PERSON>, said when the plan was approved March 16 `` In other words, a 747 with 400 people on board deserves a higher priority than a <ORGANIZATION> Cessna </ORGANIZATION> with two people on board.'' The commuter airline, corporate aircraft and private plane industries say the <LOCATION> Logan </LOCATION> plan is unfair because they have as much right to use the government-supported airport as airlines do. And the higher fees will hurt their businesses, they say. `` We price our service at what we think the market will stand,'' said <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Fredericksen </PERSON>, executive vice president of the <ORGANIZATION> Regional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airline </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, which represents the nation's commuter carriers. `` If we thought that extra money was out there, we'd charge it. Officials of the small plane industry fear that <LOCATION> Logan </LOCATION>'s plan may be only the beginning of restrictions across the country. Although air traffic grows every year, the last major <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> metropolitan airport _ <ORGANIZATION> Dallas-Fort </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Worth </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> _ was completed in 1974. No new airports are under construction, although two cities _ <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Austin </LOCATION> _ are moving toward building new ones, and about a dozen others hope to add runways at existing airfields. Since new airports take at least four years to build _ and cost $ 1.5 billion to $ 2 billion _ existing fields are moving to make better use of what they have. Modern air traffic equipment will allow more frequent takeoffs and landings, but it is expensive and in many cases needs further development. As delays grow, more airfields are considering shunting some of their small plane traffic elsewhere by raising fees, particularly during busy morning and evening hours. The <ORGANIZATION> Port </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Authority </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION>, which operates <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, <LOCATION> LaGuardia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Newark </LOCATION> airports, is expected in September to impose slight rush hour increases in takeoff fees for small planes. <ORGANIZATION> Massport </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Champion </PERSON> declined to name airports that have contacted his agency but conceded, `` There are a lot of people watching us with great interest.'' Said <PERSON> Fredericksen </PERSON> of the regional airline group, `` Our concern is that airports will try to limit traffic, rather than expand capacity.'' <PERSON> Boehlert </PERSON>'s bill, and an identical <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> version co-sponsored by seven Northeastern lawmakers, face uncertain futures. The 1988 congressional schedule is a short one, and committee chairmen say they have not decided whether to even hold hearings for the legislation. But Rep. <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Carr </PERSON>, D-Mich., a private plane pilot, said he will try attaching an amendment to a spending bill this month that would kill the <LOCATION> Logan </LOCATION> plan and discourage other airports from adopting similar restrictions `` This is a national airspace system, and here we have one airport trying to make policy,'' he said. Opponents of the <LOCATION> Logan </LOCATION> program have opened other fronts. Small plane industry groups have filed federal lawsuits in <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> and also have asked the <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> to step in on their behalf. Supporters of <LOCATION> Logan </LOCATION>'s efforts say, however, that similar plans are inevitable. `` It's the wave of the future,'' said Rep. <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Schumer </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.Y. </LOCATION> `` As the skies get more crowded, rational pricing policies will be imposed at other airports, and <LOCATION> Logan </LOCATION> is blazing the trail.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880508-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-08-88 1210EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w AM-ArmsTreaty Bjt   05-08 0735</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Arms Treaty, Bjt,720</SECOND>
<HEAD>Questions Remain On Missile Pact As Senate Nears Debate</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LAWRENCE L. KNUTSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> is expected to open debate on the new U.S.-Soviet missile treaty this week, provided the White House and the Kremlin can resolve last-minute questions over verification provisions and the use of futuristic technology. `` We're still conferring with the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> and hope to come to a resolution by Tuesday evening,'' an administration official said. `` We have discussed this with the Soviets and ... we feel confident it can be resolved,'' said the official, who asked not to be identified. While only a handful of senators are on record as opposed to the treaty, it is an open question whether there is time to ratify it before President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and Soviet leader <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> open their <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> summit meeting on May 29. <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Majority leader <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON> of <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>, resisting appeals from <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, has said he will not be driven by the approaching summit or by any other outside factor. Last month, <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON> set Wednesday as a tentative date for the opening of debate on the Intermediate-range Nuclear Forces or INF treaty if the outstanding issues can be resolved. On Monday and Tuesday the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> will consider legislation authorizing $ 299.5 billion in spending for the Pentagon. The bill also calls for increased spending on non-nuclear weapons in the <ORGANIZATION> North </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Atlantic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Treaty </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> to help reduce Soviet superiority in such arms. Three <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> committees _ Intelligence, <ORGANIZATION> Armed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> and Foreign Relations _ will spend Monday and Tuesday looking for ways to resolve the four outstanding issues: _ Futuristic weapons: <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON> wants a legally binding, written commitment from the Kremlin setting out the extent to which the new treaty covers medium-range weapons using laser rays, particle beam generators or other technology still on the drawing boards _ Futuristic weapons verification: <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON> wants a <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Intelligence </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> report on the ability of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> intelligence agencies to verify a ban on futuristic weapons _ Verification: <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON> wants the Soviets to make clear they will live up to treaty terms that require intrusive on-site inspection to detect cheating Some Soviet officials have been quoted as saying certain practices would not be allowed on Soviet soil. <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON> told reporters recently he wants to make sure the Soviets are not backing away from treaty requirements. _ Intelligence: <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON> wants a <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration commitment that it will significantly increase long-range spending for <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> intelligence efforts to monitor Soviet compliance with treaties, including obtaining more effective spy satellites <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> signed the INF treaty in a White House ceremony last Dec. 8. Since then, the pact has been subjected to intense scrutiny by the <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Relations </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, which has primary jurisdiction over treaties, as well as by the <ORGANIZATION> Armed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Intelligence </ORGANIZATION> panels, each focusing on their areas of expertise. If it goes into effect, the pact would require the elimination of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and Soviet ground-launched missiles with ranges between 300 and 3,400 miles. A leading sticking point in the controversy over whether or not futuristic weapons are included in the medium-range weapon ban is the fact the treaty contains no definition of exactly what constitutes a `` weapon delivery vehicle.'' <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> negotiators testified that they and their Soviet counterparts made no attempt to define terms that had a generally understood meaning and that the word `` weapon'' fell into that list. <PERSON> Maynard </PERSON> <PERSON> Glitman </PERSON>, the chief <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> negotiator, testified that while the subject of futuristic weapons was never specifically raised in the negotiations, the term `` weapon delivery vehicle'' covers any medium-range missile _ however armed _ if it is able to destroy a target. An initial Soviet attempt last month to resolve the issue went awry in confusion over differences in two translations of a letter from <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> Foreign Minister <PERSON> Eduard </PERSON> <PERSON> Shevardnadze </PERSON> to Secretary of State <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON>. During the defense bill debate, amendments are likely to both increase spending for <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> and also call for <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> allies in the 16-nation alliance to pay more of <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION>'s costs. Also expected are proposals providing advice to <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> from both conservative Republicans and liberal Democrats about the arms control policies he should follow in the last six months of his administration. The <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> is expected to give final approval Wednesday to its Pentagon bill. Similar action by the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> will send the separate measures to a <ORGANIZATION> House-Senate </ORGANIZATION> conference committee to reconcile the differences.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880508-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-08-88 1209EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-BRF--China-Paper     05-08 0135</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--China-Paper,0139</SECOND>
<HEAD>Chinese Paper Crunch Creates Textbook Shortage</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Thousands of Chinese schoolchildren will go without textbooks this fall because of a worsening paper shortage, an official newspaper reported Sunday. The English-language <ORGANIZATION> China </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> said the crunch resulted from the rising cost of making paper, hoarding by speculators who resell it for profit, and a state-ordered cut in imports. It also said many manufacturers are reluctant to make the kind of paper used in newspapers, magazines and textbooks because the government keeps the factory sale price unprofitably low. The <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s cabinet, has ordered local governments that publish and distribute textbooks to increase subsidies to encourage publication. It also gave publishers permission to raise prices, the report said. <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> uses about 13 million tons of paper each year, the newspaper said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880508-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-08-88 1210EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-BRF--Soviet-Nuclear     05-08 0116</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Soviet-Nuclear,0119</SECOND>
<HEAD>Soviets Hold Nuclear Test on Arctic Island</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MOSCOW (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> conducted an underground nuclear test Sunday on an Arctic island to upgrade its military technology, <ORGANIZATION> Tass </ORGANIZATION> said. The blast at <ORGANIZATION> Novaya </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Zemlya </ORGANIZATION> island north of the <LOCATION> Arctic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Circle </LOCATION> measured from 20 to 150 kilotons, the official news agency said. Twenty kilotons, the equivalent of 20,000 tons of <ORGANIZATION> TNT </ORGANIZATION>, was the force of the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> atomic bomb dropped on <LOCATION> Hiroshima </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, in 1945. The last Soviet nuclear test was on May 4 at the <LOCATION> Semipalatinsk </LOCATION> range in <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kazakhstan </LOCATION>. Soviet officials have proposed a ban on nuclear tests, but the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> disagrees with the Soviets on how to enforce it.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880508-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-08-88 1210EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Sudan-Relief     05-08 0249</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Sudan-Relief,0255</SECOND>
<HEAD>Red Cross to Undertake Relief Project in Sudan</HEAD>
<DATELINE>KHARTOUM, Sudan (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION> will undertake an operation to help civilians in war zones where four relief groups were banned earlier this year, one of its directors said. <PERSON> Andre </PERSON> <PERSON> Pasquier </PERSON>, operations director of the <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> the </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION>, said his group was trying to arrange safe conduct for the project with Prime Minister <PERSON> Sadek </PERSON> <PERSON> Mahdi </PERSON> and the rebel <ORGANIZATION> Sudan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION> expected to begin shipping in food and medical supplies from neighboring <LOCATION> Kenya </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Uganda </LOCATION> and distributing them in southern <LOCATION> Sudan </LOCATION> by the end of May. He said the prime minister had pledged to help the operation. In the past, there have been tensions between relief organizations and the government, which bans contacts with rebels. They took up arms against the government of this <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> nation in 1983, demanding more autonomy and economic reforms. Since then, fierce fighting has forced hundreds of thousands of southerners to flee to towns and cities, where they depend on relief food. Government officials who banned the four relief groups said they were no longer needed. But other sources said the government acted mainly because the groups had contacted rebels to arrange for transport of food supplies to civilians caught in the cross fire. The rebels, who control more than 90 percent of the southern countryside, have been attacking relief convoys. They claim the government uses them to transport military troops and supplies.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880508-0025 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-08-88 1210EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-BRF--Taiwan-Dissident     05-08 0141</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Taiwan-Dissident,0146</SECOND>
<HEAD>Authorities Force-Feed Jailed Taiwan Dissident</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TAIPEI, Taiwan (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
