<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880422-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-22-88 2349EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-ElevatorExplosion 3rdLd-Writethru a0804 04-22 0602</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Elevator Explosion, 3rd Ld - Writethru, a0804,0613</SECOND>
<HEAD>Grain Elevator Complex Explodes, Killing At Least Two People</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: LEADS with 7 grafs to CORRECT in 1st and 6th grafs pvs to
four silos sted six; picks up 7th graf pvs, ``It's gone...</NOTE>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto CX7</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BRENDA C. COLEMAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>JOLIET, Ill. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Two explosions ripped through a riverside grain elevator complex Friday, killing at least two people, injuring three others and leveling four grain silos and an office building, authorities said. Three more people were reported missing at the <ORGANIZATION> ADM </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Growmark </ORGANIZATION> complex, along the <LOCATION> Des </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Plaines </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> about 40 miles southwest of <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>, said <PERSON> Lynn </PERSON> <PERSON> Behringer </PERSON>, a spokeswoman for the <ORGANIZATION> Will </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Emergency </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Disaster </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION>. Officials on the scene confirmed that two people died and at least three others were injured, Ms. <PERSON> Behringer </PERSON> added. `` It shook this building like a truck or something had hit the back of this building,'' said <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Vanderlinden </PERSON>, a worker at nearby <ORGANIZATION> Stonitsch </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Construction </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> `` It was quite a big explosion.'' Authorities suspect grain dust may have caused the first explosion about 11 a.m., which ruptured a natural gas main and touched off a second blast moments later, said Fire Chief <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Plese </PERSON>. Granaries pose an explosion risk because of highly flammable grain dust. The explosions leveled the complex's 100-feet tall concrete silos, which hold a total of about 100,000 bushels, said <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Burket </PERSON>, a spokesman for the granary. Initial reports said six silos were destroyed, but <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Munchalfen </PERSON>, a security guard at the facility, said there had been four silos at the site, and only a sheet-metal covered grain dryer remained standing. One silo crushed the adjacent one-story office building. `` It's gone, totaled, level complete _ just like dynamite,'' said <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Butterfield </PERSON>, 64, a <LOCATION> Wilmington </LOCATION> farmer who said he saw metal and concrete flying through the air after the blast. `` I ran about 30 feet when I fell and rolled. It just came down in a big pile,'' said <PERSON> Butterfield </PERSON>, who witnessed the blast while he was leaving the complex after unloading a truckload of grain. Rescue workers used dogs, bulldozers and a crane to search for two people believed missing in a 25-foot-high pile of concrete chunks and twisted steel mixed with corn and soybeans, authorities said. Disaster officials also sent four boats to search the river after a witness reported seeing a third person fall off a barge nearby, Ms. <PERSON> Behringer </PERSON> said. The explosion shattered windows in homes east of the elevator complex and sprayed grain and rubble, burying a tractor-trailer rig. The <ORGANIZATION> ADM </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Growmark </ORGANIZATION> elevator is a joint venture between Decatur-based <ORGANIZATION> Archer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Daniels </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Midland </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> and Bloomington-based <ORGANIZATION> Growmark </ORGANIZATION>, a regional cooperative that sells farm supplies and markets grain. <ORGANIZATION> ADM </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Burket </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Decatur </LOCATION> said the complex receives grain hauled by truck and transfers it to river barges. The <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> accident brought to five the number of people killed in elevator explosions so far this year in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, said <PERSON> Juan </PERSON> <PERSON> Gomez </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>. Department statistics show 222 workers were killed and 839 were injured in 489 grain-dust explosions from 1958 through 1985. Data for the last two years was not immediately available. Authorities identified the dead as <PERSON> Dale </PERSON> <PERSON> Brent </PERSON> <PERSON> Slatton </PERSON>, 28, of <LOCATION> Newark </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ill. </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Stewart </PERSON>, 20, of Anchor. Both worked at the elevator, <PERSON> Stewart </PERSON> part-time while he studied agriculture at <ORGANIZATION> Joliet </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Junior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION>. One person was in fair condition at <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Joseph </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> and another was treated and released, said spokeswoman <PERSON> Phyllis </PERSON> <PERSON> Oudt </PERSON>. A third person was treated at <LOCATION> Silver </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Cross </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION> and released, said spokeswoman <PERSON> Julie </PERSON> <PERSON> Grant </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880422-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-22-88 0044EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-APArts:RiveraMural     04-22 0770</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AP Arts: Rivera Mural,0787</SECOND>
<HEAD>Diego Rivera Mural In Post-Quake Museum</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By JAVIER PICHARDINI</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MEXICO CITY (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 There once was a time when people could sit in the bar of the old Hotel <PERSON> Del </PERSON> <PERSON> Prado </PERSON> and enjoy looking at <PERSON> Diego </PERSON> <PERSON> Rivera </PERSON>'s mural, `` Dream of a Sunday Afternoon in <LOCATION> Alameda </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Park </LOCATION>.'' The once elegant hotel is now an earthquake-damaged hulk waiting to be demolished, and the mural is in its own museum pavilion across the street. The delicate transfer of the mural has been completed. It escaped damage in the Sept. 19, 1985, earthquake that killed thousands and devastated large parts of the city. The famous mural is open to the public again, like a window opened on <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>'s rich history. It shows figures from the Mexican political and art worlds and from daily life all on parade in the park. An explanation at the entrance to the new museum says the decision was made to transfer the mural from the hotel after the extent of the damage there became clear. `` It should be linked to the <LOCATION> Alameda </LOCATION>, for having been painted on that theme and for the place itself,'' the plaque from the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Arts </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> says. The <LOCATION> Alameda </LOCATION>, the downtown park across the street and down a block from the mural's old home, also was expanded through earthquake reconstruction programs. A `` Solidarity Garden'' recalling the victims of the 1985 disaster was built on the site of the cleared, adjoining block that once held a department store and the Hotel Regis. The mural's pavilion is built on the site of the hotel's parking garage, which was badly damaged and demolished after the quake. The <ORGANIZATION> Fine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Arts </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> said that no room could be found in any of its buildings close to the <LOCATION> Alameda </LOCATION>, `` because of the colossal dimensions of the work. ... That's why it was decided to take advantage of the possibility of constructing an appropriate building.'' In place of the old hotel's comfortable cocktail lounge, viewers now can sit on three simple benches placed in front of the mural or just stand for a while in the large but sparsely decorated room. Diagrams, with keyed numbers on the outline of each figure, tell who 73 of the people shown in the mural are. Among the figures is a fat boy with large eyes and a round face, a self-portrait _ something <PERSON> Rivera </PERSON> often put in his works. In the foreground is Spanish conqueror <PERSON> Hernando </PERSON> <PERSON> Cortes </PERSON>. On a park bench an elderly man dreams of President <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Lopez </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Santa </PERSON> <PERSON> Anna </PERSON>, giving American Gen. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Scott </PERSON> the keys to <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION> and other lands that once belonged to <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>. Farther back, a former military man, now poor, dreams of the emperors <PERSON> Maximilian </PERSON> and <LOCATION> Carlota </LOCATION>. A drunken tramp, next to an old woman, dreams with his mouth open of miltiary glories, at the side of <PERSON> Benito </PERSON> <PERSON> Juarez </PERSON>, who holds the reform laws he put into effect as <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>'s great 19th century president. Near the center is dictator <PERSON> Porfirio </PERSON> <PERSON> Diaz </PERSON> and his wife, <PERSON> Carmen </PERSON> <PERSON> Romero </PERSON> <PERSON> Rubio </PERSON>. <PERSON> Diaz </PERSON> appears full of his fame and power, with a chest full of ribbons on his uniform. At the right, a street vendor offers typical Mexican food to a middle-class youth and three students, who dream of Gen. <PERSON> Victoriano </PERSON> <PERSON> Huerta </PERSON>. Official history says <PERSON> Huerta </PERSON> had <PERSON> Francisco </PERSON> <PERSON> I. </PERSON> <PERSON> Madero </PERSON>, who started the 1910-21 Mexican revolution, killed. <PERSON> Rivera </PERSON> completed the 49 -LCB- foot by 13 foot painting for the then fashionable <PERSON> Del </PERSON> <PERSON> Prado </PERSON> in 1948. Along with <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Alfaro </PERSON> <PERSON> Siqueiros </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Clemente </PERSON> <PERSON> Orozco </PERSON>, <PERSON> Rivera </PERSON> was one of <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>'s three great muralists and one of the most important Latin American painters in the art world. He died in 1957. Among his other best known murals are those in the National Palace of the Spanish conquest, the Mexican revolution and other events from the country's history. `` The composition is memories of my life, of my childhood and my youth, from 1895 to 1910,'' <PERSON> Rivera </PERSON> wrote after finishing the mural. `` I do not believe that this work has alarmed or can alarm anyone. The contemporary figures in the fresco, as figures in dreams, are not portraits.'' It was an apparent reference to the phrase, `` God Does Not Exist,'' a quote attributed to Juarez adviser <PERSON> Ignacio </PERSON> <PERSON> Ramirez </PERSON> and written on a piece of paper by <PERSON> Ramirez </PERSON> in the mural. Eight years after the mural was completed, <PERSON> Rivera </PERSON> changed the paper to read, `` Conference in the Academy of <LOCATION> Letran </LOCATION>, the year 1836.'' The phrase refers to the date and place where <PERSON> Ramirez </PERSON> made his controversial comment.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880422-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-22-88 0044EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Dukakis-HealthCare     04-22 0535</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Dukakis-Health Care,0549</SECOND>
<HEAD>Dukakis Signs Universal Health Care Bill</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Dukakis-VP, Bjt</HEAD>
<HEAD>Laserphoto BX1</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DUNCAN MANSFIELD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BOSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION>' first step towards universal health care insurance may be a first step towards a national health care plan, says Gov. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>. `` What we do here today can and must be done all over the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>,'' the Democratic presidential front-runner said Thursday, signing the nation's first law to make health insurance available to all Bay Staters by 1992. `` We have made a great start,'' he told about 2,000 supporters crowded onto the Statehouse steps for the signing ceremony. `` Now we must make it work. And then we must carry the message of health care for all across all this country.'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> said universal health care was under discussion in <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> for nearly two years before it passed the <ORGANIZATION> Legislature </ORGANIZATION>, it has been 40 years since <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Truman </PERSON> proposed it for the nation. `` As an American, I do n't want my country to stand alone with <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> as the only two industrialized nations that do not provide basic health security for their citizens,'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> supports a bill by Sen. <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, D-Mass., calling for minimum health care guarantees `` as the first step towards providing health insurance to all Americans,'' said <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> campaign spokesman <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Akey </PERSON> The governor also supports states taking their own initiative to offer universal health care, <ORGANIZATION> Statehouse </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> press </ORGANIZATION> secretary <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Dorsey </PERSON> said. The <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> bill was the outcome of a nine-month legislative struggle and comes two years after <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> voters voted 2-1 for a non-binding referendum urging <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to enact a national health care program. Dr. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> U. </PERSON> <PERSON> Himmelstein </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION>, spokesman for Physicians for a <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Program </ORGANIZATION>, called the health care bill a first step but `` a Band-Aid approach when major surgery is needed.'' On Wednesday, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> estimated that the law's cost to taxpayers would be $ 645.2 million through fiscal 1992, less about $ 22.5 million in projected cost-cutting in Medicaid. Other estimates put the cost to the state government in the next four years as high as $ 1.2 billion. The law would provide coverage to about 600,000 <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> residents under age 65 currently without health insurance, or roughly one of every 10 people in the commonwealth. This would be done in stages and through a variety of approaches, from extending Medicaid benefits for disabled adults and children to state-brokered, pooled insurance for small businesses and individuals. By 1992, all employers with more than five full-time employees must offer health insurance coverage or pay an unemployment surcharge to help the state provide this coverage to the uninsured. Under the proposal, the state also would take control of a $ 300 million-a-year pool for indigents that is funded from hospital surcharges on the insured. <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ways </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Means </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Patricia </PERSON> <PERSON> McGovern </PERSON>, who proposed the idea of universal health care in <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> more than a year ago, acknowledged that risks were involved in the undertaking. `` In the end I think we regret what we have never done _ not what we've tried and we've failed but what we've never tried,'' she said. `` This whole effort is about the ability to take a risk.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880422-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-22-88 0049EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Hijack-Aftermath     04-22 0782</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Hijack-Aftermath,0805</SECOND>
<HEAD>Anti-Hijack Ideas Abound, But They Have Flaws</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By MARCUS ELIASON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Kuwait </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airways </ORGANIZATION> hijack has spawned plenty of proposals from governments, anti-terrorism experts and the public on how to tackle air piracy, but each idea invariably contains a serious pitfall. They range from a West German lawmaker's suggestion that knockout gas be pumped into hijacked planes, to the <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transport </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>'s call for an international brigade to fight terrorism. The hijack drama, which ended in <LOCATION> Algiers </LOCATION> on Wednesday, left a bittersweet taste around <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, where it unfolded daily through live TV broadcasts. The anguish and frustration it engendered was reflected in calls to radio talkshows and letters to newspapers proposing various anti-hijack strategies. There was rejoicing that the ordeal ended peacefully and that <LOCATION> Kuwait </LOCATION> apparently stood firm against demands for the release of 17 jailed pro-Iranian terrorists. Experts noted that hijackings have fallen from 95 in 1969 to fewer than 20 a year in the 1980s. They also pointed to the difficulty the hijackers had in landing the Kuwaiti jumbo jet, saying it showed that the refusal of airports to deal with air pirates is almost universal. But there was outrage that the nine hijackers, having killed two passengers and put others through a horrifying ordeal, apparently escaped unpunished. `` At the risk of sounding churlish, the ending of one of the longest hijackings in aviation history is not an occasion for unrestrained rejoicing,'' commented The Independent, a <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> newspaper. Experts say the biggest problem is airport security. Some airports are extremely strict, such as in <LOCATION> Tel </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Aviv </LOCATION> where departing passengers are interrogated, while others are dangerously lax. <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Sheppard </PERSON>, security chief at the <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Civil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aviation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION>, likens security to `` a great spider web over the whole world, and there's no way of plugging up every single gap. The chain of security is only as strong as its weakest link.'' Authorities in <LOCATION> Bangkok </LOCATION>, where the airliner was parked before the hijacking, say guns could have been smuggled aboard before the plane reached <LOCATION> Thailand </LOCATION>. But they are investigating suspicions that Thai catering staff were bribed into helping the hijackers. `` Ground staff are very poorly paid in Third World countries,'' says <PERSON> Ian </PERSON> <PERSON> Geldard </PERSON> of the Institute for the Study of Terrorism. `` And if people there can be bribed, hijackers are going to go for Third World countries.'' One measure proposed by <PERSON> Geldard </PERSON>'s <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> institute is to store passengers' passports in the baggage hold, thus making it difficult for hijackers to identify hostages for execution by nationality. The Israeli newspaper <ORGANIZATION> Maariv </ORGANIZATION> reported that a <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> rabbi was in <LOCATION> Tel </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Aviv </LOCATION> selling a hijack survival kit containing a false passport, ID and credit card to Israelis who have good reason to conceal their identities from hijackers. Maariv said the kit costs a hefty $ 165. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Clutterbuck </PERSON>, an English anti-terrorism expert, proposes issuing a fingerprinted clearance card entitling bona fide passengers to clear airports speedily, while those with no card would be searched. But <PERSON> Geldard </PERSON> says the system wo n't work, because states that sponsor terrorism will have little trouble obtaining the clearance cards. West German lawmaker <PERSON> Johannes </PERSON> <PERSON> Gerster </PERSON> suggests a gas to `` put the hijackers and the passengers to sleep lightning-quick.'' The danger, some experts say, is that if the gas failed to work instantly, it would leave the hijackers enough time to detonate explosives. <PERSON> Clutterbuck </PERSON> says sophisticated machinery is being developed to detect explosives thermally or by neutron bombardment. But the problem, he acknowledged in an interview, is that it is expensive. The Geneva-based <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transport </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, representing 168 airlines in 114 countries, proposes new international courts to try hijackers and an international commando brigade. But <PERSON> Geldard </PERSON> called this `` a utopian dream,'' saying in an interview: `` It's difficult enough to get collaboration even with firmest allies. In a lot of countries the different intelligence agencies do n't even cooperate among themselves.'' <ORGANIZATION> IATA </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Kyd </PERSON> recalled the 1978 summit at which the seven leading industrial democracies threatened sanctions against countries that fail to bring hijackers to justice. The threat has only once been implemented, against <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>, he told <ORGANIZATION> British </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Broadcasting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> radio, adding: `` One wonders why it has n't been applied more often.'' <PERSON> Clutterbuck </PERSON> said: `` In a perfect world it would of course have been far better if the hijackers had n't been released. But I think that would have been too much to expect.'' But <PERSON> Kyd </PERSON> said that by releasing the hijackers, <LOCATION> Algeria </LOCATION> had set itself up as `` a soft touch'' for terrorists. He said hijackers should be punished, `` whatever that takes. If it means prolonging the suffering of other hostages aboard an aircraft, then so be it.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880422-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-22-88 0050EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-NATO-Denmark     04-22 0618</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-NATO-Denmark,0640</SECOND>
<HEAD>Ban On Nuclear-Armed Warships Raises NATO Frustration With Denmark</HEAD>
<HEAD>AP News Analysis</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT J. WIELAARD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BRUSSELS, Belgium (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Denmark </LOCATION>'s move to bolster its ban on visiting nuclear-armed warships has focused attention on a <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> ally that already suffers from a reputation as an unreliable comrade-in-arms. <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> long has complained that <LOCATION> Denmark </LOCATION> does not pull its weight in the <ORGANIZATION> North </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Atlantic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Treaty </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION>. Its annual defense spending _ 2.2 percent of its gross national product in 1987 _ is the lowest of <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION>'s European members except for <LOCATION> Greece </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>. For 31 years, <LOCATION> Denmark </LOCATION> has had a general policy banning nuclear arms from its soil in peacetime. Until now, Danish officials took the position of assuming that visiting warships would obey. Last week, <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION> voted to demand that warships be told they can not carry nuclear arms into Danish ports. At <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> headquarters here, officials say the measure, if implemented, would render <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION>'s reinforcement strategy for <LOCATION> Denmark </LOCATION> useless. The measure led Danish Prime Minister <PERSON> Poul </PERSON> <PERSON> Schlueter </PERSON>'s minority government to call for early elections May 10. The center-right government opposes the nuclear-armed warship measure and maintains <PERSON> Danes </PERSON> remain loyal to <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION>. One Danish <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> official said that in a marriage, `` it behooves either partner not to be confrontational.'' `` We should not exaggerate the situation but accept there are differences of opinion within <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION>,'' said the official, who spoke on condition of anonymity. Such comments do little to calm the nerves of <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> officials whose primary concern is to maintain an iron-clad consensus about defense, notably nuclear arms. <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> members <LOCATION> Norway </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION> both prohibit the stationing of nuclear arms on their soil during peacetime. But neither requires visiting <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> warships to declare whether they are carrying such arms. In 1984, the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> broke off military cooperation with <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Zealand </LOCATION> after that country began insisting that warships say whether or not they carry nuclear weapons. `` We know that in some cases allied warships carried nuclear arms into our ports,'' said the Danish official. `` This, of course, was not allowed but we closed one eye,'' said the Danish official. To tell visiting warships they can not carry nuclear arms into Danish ports would, said <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> Secretary General <PERSON> Lord </PERSON> <PERSON> Carrington </PERSON>, `` run counter to the basis of <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> strategy and the principles of shared burdens and benefits'' of alliance membership. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>, which would rush to <LOCATION> Denmark </LOCATION>'s aid in times of crisis with troops and materiel, have a policy of never saying whether their warships have nuclear arms. A <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> official said this week that the stricter anti-nuclear stand, if taken to its logical conclusion, would mean <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> allies can not reinforce <LOCATION> Denmark </LOCATION> during a crisis before the outbreak of war. Failure to reinforce <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION>'s choke-point on the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>'s Baltic fleet would affect not just <LOCATION> Denmark </LOCATION> but also neighboring <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> `` It's clear this is not a Danish-American or Danish-British problem, but a matter for all of the alliance,'' said a senior West German <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> source, also speaking privately. The controversy led <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> to move next week's <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> defense ministers meeting from <LOCATION> Denmark </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Brussels </LOCATION>. The meeting will focus on nuclear defense issues. In 1985, <PERSON> Mchael </PERSON> <PERSON> Hesseltine </PERSON>, then <ORGANIZATION> British </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> defense </ORGANIZATION> secretary, warned <LOCATION> Danes </LOCATION> not to expect British soldiers to come to their aid if they do n't do more for their own defense. Last March, Danish Lt. Gen. <PERSON> Poul </PERSON> <PERSON> Thorsen </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION>'s top commander for the <ORGANIZATION> Baltic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Approaches </ORGANIZATION>, resigned and said he could no longer `` represent <LOCATION> Denmark </LOCATION> in a reasonable manner.'' He said Danish defense was being `` maltreated'' through gross underfinancing.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Wielaard </PERSON> is bureau chief for <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Brussels </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880422-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-22-88 0052EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-WritersStrike     04-22 0484</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Writers Strike,0497</SECOND>
<HEAD>Producers Claim Writers Strike Causing $15 Million In Losses So
Far</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RICHARD DE ATLEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Hollywood scriptwriters' strike has cost their industry more than $ 15 million, producers say, blaming much of the loss to production halts on such hit series as `` The Cosby Show'' and `` <LOCATION> L.A </LOCATION>. Law.'' Directors, actors, production crew workers and secretaries were among thos hit by the <ORGANIZATION> Writers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guild </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION> strike, <PERSON> Herb </PERSON> <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON>, a spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> Alliance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Motion </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Picture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Television </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Producers </ORGANIZATION>, said Thursday. He said about 1,400 employees who work in production areas other than writing have been laid off as a result of the seven-week-old strike. The 9,000-member guild went on strike March 7 over issues of residuals from movies and television shows distributed in foreign countries and a producers' proposal to restructure residual payments for hourlong television shows sold into syndication. `` We have no way of verifying the information they put out,'' said <ORGANIZATION> Guild </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman <PERSON> Cheryl </PERSON> <PERSON> Rhoden </PERSON>. `` However, we do question whether they have taken into consideration the normal seasonal layoffs that have occurred because of -LRB- the television season -RRB- hiatus.'' <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON> said the layoffs and costs tabulated by the producers were chiefly from 22 regular season television episodes from shows such as `` L.A. Law'' and `` The Cosby Show,'' which were not produced because of lack of scripts. `` This has nothing whatsoever to do with the seasonal layoffs,'' said <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON>. `` It has nothing to do with the hiatus.'' Two federally mediated sessions on April 18 and March 14 ended without resumption of negotiations. No new talks are scheduled. The strike curtailed the seasons of several television shows and could threaten the start of the fall television season if it continues into the summer. According to statistics gathered by the alliance, a bargaining organization of more than 200 studios and producers, the strike thus far has cost 1,062 cast and crew members an estimated $ 12.7 million in salaries and benefits. Some 210 secretaries and other officer staffers have been laid off as a result of the strike, and lost an estimated $ 756,000 in salaries. The strike also has affected 207 so-called `` writer hyphenates,'' who have lost fees, salaries and benefits worth an estimated $ 2.2 million. A writer hyphenate is generally a writer-producer, someone who is developing a television show or movie. Because they are on strike as writers, they can not advance work on scripts or ideas. <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON> said the alliance's analysis concludes that 45,000 person-days have been lost as a result of the strike. `` If the Alliance wants to see a speedy end to the strike the best way to assure that would be to return to the table and continue a dialogue that can resolve the outstanding issues,'' Ms. <PERSON> Rhoden </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON> said the last 20-minute meeting between the new sides had been requested by the writers, but the union had no new offers.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880422-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-22-88 0053EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Dukakis-VP Bjt   04-22 0765</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Dukakis-VP, Bjt,760</SECOND>
<HEAD>Dukakis Urged To Pick Southerner or Westerner As Running Mate</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DONALD M. ROTHBERG</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Political Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Democratic front-runner <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> is getting loads of advice on where to turn for a running mate, with many party leaders urging him to avoid <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> and turn to a Southern senator. But the <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> governor indicated Thursday he wants maximum breathing room as he searches for someone to fill the No. 2 spot on the Democratic ticket. `` Obviously you look at regions where you could use some help,'' said former Gov. <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Robb </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>. `` The South and West are the regions. You also look at a philosophical segment where you could use some shoring up and I guess that would be with moderate conservative voters.'' <PERSON> Robb </PERSON>, who had urged Sen. <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> <PERSON> Nunn </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION> to run for president, said he would like to see <PERSON> Nunn </PERSON> as the vice presidential candidate, but only if the senator were offered the opportunity to serve as secretary of defense at the same time. Party chairman <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kirk </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> predicted that the vice presidential nominee would be `` a senator from the <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> or Southwest.'' `` I would n't make that judgment at all,'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> said in an interview with The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>. He also rejected suggestions that if <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> finishes second in the race for the presidential nomination, he ought to be given the No. 2 spot on the ticket. `` If I were to finish second, it would n't entitle me to anything more than consideration, period,'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> said. The discussion of potential <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> running mates began to intensify after the <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> governor's strong victory in the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> primary established him as the likely Democratic presidential nominee. `` I have spent literally zero time thinking about it. And I will not, unless and until I have either won the nomination, or it looks as if it's pretty well in hand,'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> insisted. `` If that happens, then I will begin what I hope will be a thoughtful and thorough process of selecting a running mate. But I'm not going to do anything on that _ quite literally _ until the <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> primaries are over.'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> said the paramount concern in choosing a running mate ought to be a candidate's ability to serve as a `` first-rate president if, God forbid, something happened to the president.'' `` All else pales by comparison,'' he said. The <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> governor, who has been faulted in the campaign for his lack of experience in foreign affairs, disputed the view that he needs to select a running mate with experience in international issues. `` You pick a secretary of state to be your key foreign policy adviser, and a national security adviser and secretary of defense,'' he said, adding that `` you do n't necessarily need another secretary of <ORGANIZATION> state </ORGANIZATION>'' as vice president. There were mixed opinions on the value of <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> as a running mate. <PERSON> Robb </PERSON> said <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> `` does n't fill in the kind of strengths he -LRB- <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> -RRB- needs.'' `` Both <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> on the ticket together is not the best political decision you can make,'' said <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Beckel </PERSON>, campaign manager for <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Mondale </PERSON> when he was the Democratic presidential nominee in 1984. `` I think everybody fully expects to see a Southerner this time,'' said <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> Lapierre </PERSON>, executive director of the <ORGANIZATION> Alabama </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>. He said <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> on the ticket would hurt <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> because there still are many people who will not accept a black. `` The sad part is, not voting for him because of disagreement on issues or lack of experience in government, that's OK, that's what politics is all about. The race thing, you hate to say it, but it's there. At a news conference Wednesday, <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> said, `` I need his -LRB- <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> -RRB- support base to win. He needs my support base to win. Together we can win.'' Asked if he were talking about a Dukakis-Jackson ticket, the candidate said, `` No. It's just the challenge we have to pull together our constituencies.'' `` He's not running for vice president and I did n't sign on with him for vice president,'' <PERSON> Willie </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>, the national chairman of <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s campaign and the speaker of the <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Assembly </LOCATION>, said Thursday. But, <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> said, `` I think a Dukakis-Jackson -LRB- ticket -RRB- would be good. I think a Jackson-Dukakis would be the best for the Democrats.'' `` I think <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> has worked hard and perhaps earned it if he wants it,'' said <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> member from <LOCATION> Coffeyville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Kan. </LOCATION> `` It does n't bother me if a black is on the ticket,'' he added. `` People want to win.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880422-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-22-88 0111EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-O'sWoes     04-22 0610</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-O's Woes,0625</SECOND>
<HEAD>From Hypnosis To Positive Thinking, Oriole Fans Offer Suggestions</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By ANNE FITZHENRY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BALTIMORE (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 What do <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> and the <ORGANIZATION> Orioles </ORGANIZATION> have in common? Both wear a glove for no apparent reason. That's one of the jokes making the rounds about the winless team that's also known as the Zer-O's. Fans of the <ORGANIZATION> Baltimore </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Orioles </ORGANIZATION> are laughing on the outside, but crying on the inside as they watch their team soar _ like a stone. `` They need to get psychotherapy,'' banker <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Swensen </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Baltimore </LOCATION> said Thursday. `` I'm not going to watch the games until they start winning. I ca n't handle it. I get nauseous.'' Wednesday's loss to the <ORGANIZATION> Milwaukee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Brewers </ORGANIZATION> gave the <ORGANIZATION> Orioles </ORGANIZATION> the dubious distinction of being the first major league team in history to lose 14 games at the start of the season. They continued their losing ways Thursday, falling 7-1 to the <ORGANIZATION> Brewers </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Milwaukee </LOCATION>. But fans in <LOCATION> Birdland </LOCATION> say it will take more than a string of losses to kill the pride they have in the team that won the World Series five years ago and six pennants from 1966 to 1983. `` I think they're the best,'' said <PERSON> Chris </PERSON> <PERSON> Slowinski </PERSON>, 28, a sales representative for a beer company. `` People around here are Bird fanatics. It's embarrassing, because there is a winning tradition here in <LOCATION> Baltimore </LOCATION>. I have season tickets. I go to the games expecting them to win.'' Disc jockey <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Rivers </PERSON>, who vowed to stay on the air at WIYY-FM until the <ORGANIZATION> Orioles </ORGANIZATION> break the skid, was a trifle grouchy Thursday after broadcasting for more than 58 hours. He has napped briefly between music sets since Tuesday. `` I'm a little irritable. I'm a little cranky. ... I can see the bags under my eyes,'' he said. `` But I'm holding up my commitment.'' <PERSON> Patty </PERSON> <PERSON> Waters </PERSON>, an administrative assistant in the <ORGANIZATION> Orioles </ORGANIZATION>' public relations office, said the telephones have been ringing off the hook as fans called to offer encouragement and suggestions. `` One lady wanted to hold a mass positive thinking seminar for the fans and the club,'' Ms. Waters said. `` One lady recommended hypnosis. She said if she hypnotized all of them, and let them know how good they are,'' the streak would end. `` We have a group of letters from a local school. I do n't know if the teacher was making fun of us, but the kids' letters suggested -LRB- the players -RRB- chew gum and stick it on the end of their bats to help make contact, or put it in their gloves so they might catch a ball,'' Ms. Waters said. A regular caller to her office this week has been <PERSON> Baltimore </PERSON> <PERSON> Joe </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> man who changed his name to reflect his affection for the city. `` He's calling to say hi. He's apparently taking a lot of ribbing from friends who support the <ORGANIZATION> Yankees </ORGANIZATION>,'' Ms. Waters said. <PERSON> Chuck </PERSON> <PERSON> Litty </PERSON>, 42, a lifelong fan and member of the <ORGANIZATION> Orioles </ORGANIZATION> Advocates, a baseball promotion and volunteer civic organization in <LOCATION> Baltimore </LOCATION>, figures the odds are with the team at this point. `` Besides the fact that they're playing bad, they're snakebit,'' <PERSON> Litty </PERSON> said. `` As each game progresses, the more these guys are putting pressure upon themselves. Once they get this victory _ and I know they will get it _ maybe things will straighten out and they will become a competitive team. `` I ca n't understand it. I know this is a better ballclub than what we're showing. We've had a long history of being a successful ballclub. I'm just dealing with it day to day and hoping they break out of it.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880422-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-22-88 0113EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Gore     04-22 0615</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Gore,610</SECOND>
<HEAD>`Didn't Work Out Exactly The Way I Planned,' Gore Says</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By WILLIAM M. WELCH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrat <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> made his exit from the 1988 presidential race with this succinct analysis of his debt-burdened bid: `` I was doing great until I turned 40.'' <PERSON> Gore </PERSON>'s departure Thursday narrowed the Democratic presidential race down to two _ front-runner <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>. It was forced by <PERSON> Gore </PERSON>'s failure to score a breakthrough in any state of the <LOCATION> North </LOCATION>, ending with <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> on Tuesday. The <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> senator ran much of his campaign burdened by the notion that at age 39 he was too young, and expressed relief upon turning 40 at the end of March. But by then the high point of his campaign had come and gone _ the Super Tuesday contests six weeks ago when he won five Southern primaries. He never fared better than a 17 percent showing in <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION> after that. `` Things did n't work out exactly the way I had planned,'' <PERSON> Gore </PERSON>, flanked by his wife, parents and children, told supporters jammed into a <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> office building. `` I lost this race, and that is a disappointment,'' <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> said. `` But some things matter to me more than winning _ helping my party, serving my country, knowing when to keep fighting and knowing when I've been licked.'' <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> technically left his campaign in a suspended state. While acknowledging he would n't be the nominee or campaign any more, <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> maintains a candidacy that permits all his delegates to attend the Democratic National Convention. <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> amassed 423 Democratic National Convention delegates during his campaign, according to The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> count. Under party rules, delegate slots he has already won but for which people have not yet been chosen could have been awarded to other candidates, had he not remained technically a candidate. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> would have gained 34 of <PERSON> Gore </PERSON>'s delegates immediately, while <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> would have gotten 29. <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> Sen. <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Simon </PERSON>'s decision to suspend his campaign denied <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> another 47 delegates he would have inherited in this manner <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> said he spoke with both <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> and that both were `` comfortable'' with his decision to hold onto the delegates since neither would have gained significantly. He said the move would protect <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> leaders who backed him in states where delegates had not yet been chosen, naming <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION> as an example. He said he planned no endorsement and repeated his oft-stated contention that he has `` no interest'' in the vice presidential nomination, though he left that door open. `` I'm not trying in any way to broker a convention that is not going to be brokered anyway,'' he said. In departing, <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> delivered some of the most eloquent lines of his campaign. He offered praise for his <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> opponents during the long campaign, saying that each had taught him something. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, he said, taught him that `` a successful president must be both a chief executive and a preacher.'' It was a line that recalled the criticism he leveled at <LOCATION> Jackson </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> two weeks ago, when <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> said the nation was choosing a president not a preacher. He excoriated President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and Vice President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, saying they had brought `` the most selfish generation of leadership'' in American history. `` We have been subjected for eight years to a man who quotes our heroes against us,'' he said. `` But <PERSON> Franklin </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Roosevelt </PERSON> does not belong to a man who does not even see the homeless on our streets.'' He promised support for the eventual Democratic nominee. `` I want no part of a stop-Jackson or a stop-Dukakis movement,'' <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> said. `` The only man I want to stop is <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880422-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-22-88 0114EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lites     04-22 0589</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lites,0611</SECOND>
<HEAD>On The Light Side</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LYNN, Mass. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 For awhile, <PERSON> Holly </PERSON> <PERSON> Lavalla </PERSON> and <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Morelli </PERSON> thought about what they could do with their $ 13,615 refund check from the <ORGANIZATION> Internal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Revenue </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>. Unhappily, they decided to send it back. `` When it's that big you send it back, because you know they'll hunt this down,'' <PERSON> Lavalla </PERSON> told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Beverly </ORGANIZATION> `` It's a very, very tempting thing, when you look at five digits, with your name on the check.'' However she added, `` I need a couple more zeroes to hide all that guilt.'' Their check for $ 13,615, more than 25 times the approximately $ 500 refund they expected, was nearly half of the couple's combined yearly income. `` ` Whattaya mean we're going to send it back?''' <PERSON> Lavalla </PERSON>, a hospital worker, recalled her husband saying. But she replied, `` Let's get back to earth now, <PERSON> Dan </PERSON>.'' The couple's attorney informed <ORGANIZATION> Internal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Revenue </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> officials of the check, which was returned Thursday. `` After she told them the amount of my check there was a very lo-o-o-ong pause,'' said <PERSON> Lavalla </PERSON>. `` They were flabbergasted by the amount.'' <PERSON> Anita </PERSON> <PERSON> Castro </PERSON>, spokeswoman for the <ORGANIZATION> IRS </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Andover </LOCATION>, said the the refund check `` is kind of extreme. That's not the norm.'' She added, `` It could be a keypunch error, but it's got to be more than that.'' She declined to comment further until she has reviewed the case.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>CHARLESTON, S.C. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 There's no denying that <PERSON> Grandma </PERSON> <PERSON> Jane </PERSON> and <PERSON> Nosey </PERSON> <PERSON> Rosie </PERSON> are fat cats. And that was before the felines inherited an estimated $ 250,000 estate. <PERSON> Jane </PERSON>, who weighs in at 13 pounds, and 15-pound <PERSON> Rosie </PERSON> received the lion's share of the estate of <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Starkey </PERSON>, whose will stipulates that his house be maintained and the cats allowed to roam freely there until their deaths. At that time, the house and remainder of the estate will establish a trust fund for the <ORGANIZATION> Dorchester </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION> for the Prevention of Cruelty to Animals. <PERSON> Starkey </PERSON>, who worked as a field engineer for <ORGANIZATION> Lockheed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Missiles </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Space </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, and his wife, <PERSON> Imogene </PERSON>, always had animals around, said <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Inman </PERSON>, the administrator of <PERSON> Starkey </PERSON>'s will. <PERSON> Stuckey </PERSON> died last December and his wife died in 1986. <PERSON> Inman </PERSON>'s wife <PERSON> Doris </PERSON> said all the photos she's been able to find of the Stuckeys show them with their pets. She said they would buy gifts for their animals and put gifts under the tree at Christmas. `` They did for their animals what we did for our children,'' said <PERSON> Inman </PERSON>'s wife, <PERSON> Doris </PERSON>. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Messervy </PERSON>, the attorney for the estate, said it will be several years before the <ORGANIZATION> SPCA </ORGANIZATION> receives the funds. He said about $ 50,000 of the estate will also go to establish a trust fund for the <ORGANIZATION> SPCA </ORGANIZATION> in <PERSON> Starkey </PERSON>'s hometown of Guymon, <LOCATION> Okla </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>OKLAHOMA CITY (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 In what may rank as one of the great political compromises, the <ORGANIZATION> Oklahoma </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> came up with a way to name the same bridge for two people. A resolution adopted Thursday by the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> asks the state <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> to name the span's two directions for two legislators, Rep. <PERSON> Lonnie </PERSON> <PERSON> Abbott </PERSON> and Sen. <PERSON> Kelly </PERSON> <PERSON> Haney </PERSON>. The new bridge crosses the <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Canadian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION>, which is the dividing line between <LOCATION> Pontotoc </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, represented by <PERSON> Abbott </PERSON>, and <LOCATION> Seminole </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, which is included in <PERSON> Haney </PERSON>'s district. So, when traveling south on <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION> 99, motorists will cross the the Haney-Abbott bridge. When coming the other way, they'll see a sign designating that same bridge as the <LOCATION> Abbott-Haney </LOCATION> bridge. `` We just reached a compromise,'' said <PERSON> Haney </PERSON> with a chuckle.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880422-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-22-88 0115EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-AlcoholWarnings     04-22 0447</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Alcohol Warnings,460</SECOND>
<HEAD>Alcohol Producers Opposing Labeling Bill</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JAMES HANNAH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Beer and liquor producers say requiring alcoholic beverage containers to carry health warning labels will do little to solve problems of abuse. `` Labels are not education, and they do n't really help solve the problem of abuse,'' <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Sanders </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> Beer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION>, said Thursday. `` We think it's really a false solution to a real problem.'' He called legislation to require such labels `` an emotional overreaction.'' Earlier, a bipartisan group of <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> lawmakers held a news conference to outline their labeling legislation. `` The most harmful drug in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> is alcohol,'' said Sen. <PERSON> Strom </PERSON> <PERSON> Thurmond </PERSON>, <PERSON> R-S.C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Thurmond </PERSON>, who introduced his bill in February, said alcohol abuse costs the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> economy about $ 120 billion a year, including increased medical expenses and lost productivity. Alcohol-related traffic accidents claim 18,000 lives each year, he added. `` It's a very rare family in this country today that has not been hit by some of the ravages of alcoholism one way or another,'' said Sen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Ohio </LOCATION>, a cosponsor of the bill. <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Governmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Affairs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, said the panel has scheduled a series of hearings on the alcohol problem. The legislation would require the placement of one of five alternating labels on each alcoholic beverage container. Rep. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Conyers </PERSON>, D-Mich., who introduced the House version of the bill Thursday, said the labels would warn about the dangers of drinking and driving, of drinking while pregnant and of combining alcohol with other drugs In addition the labels would say that alcohol may be addictive and that its consumption can increase the risk of developing hypertension, liver disease and cancer. <PERSON> Susan </PERSON> <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON>, an actress on the television series Falcon Crest, said her father was an alcoholic, but that he would have wanted his children to know the dangers of alcohol. `` It seems to me incredible that we do not have these warning labels on alcohol bottles when it is such a dangerous drug,'' said Ms. <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON>. <PERSON> Christine </PERSON> <PERSON> Lubinski </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> representative for the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> on </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Alcoholism </ORGANIZATION>, said the primary source of alcohol information available to the American public comes from $ 2 billion in advertising aimed at depicting alcohol as `` a glamorous, magic potion.'' Ms. <PERSON> Lubinski </PERSON> said the warning labels will institutionalize public health messages about the risks associated with alcohol consumption. But <PERSON> Janet </PERSON> <PERSON> Flynn </PERSON>, spokeswoman for the Distilled Spirits Council of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, said the group opposes warning labels. `` We believe that the warning labels for alcohol beverage containers are unnecessary,'' said Ms. <PERSON> Flynn </PERSON>. `` And they are unnecessary because the claims concerning the risks of alcohol consumption are well known.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880422-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-22-88 0008EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Israel Bjt   04-22 0786</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Israel, Bjt,0814</SECOND>
<HEAD>Display Of Military Might On Israel's 40th Anniversary</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KARIN LAUB</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>RAMAT GAN, Israel (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 F-16 fighter jets swooshed across the sky and paratroopers performed precision jumps as <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> displayed its military might in a 40th Independence Day celebration marred by the Palestinian uprising. Foreign Minister <PERSON> Shimon </PERSON> <PERSON> Peres </PERSON> visited troops in the occupied <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> town of <LOCATION> Bethlehem </LOCATION> and called for restraint in quelling Arab protests in the occupied lands, saying excessive force would only radicalize Palestinians. `` If we act with restraint, they -LRB- the Arabs -RRB- will realize that violence leads them nowhere, and they will have to look for a solution, and we're ready to talk about a solution,'' said <PERSON> Peres </PERSON>, head of the center-left <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>. But Prime Minister <PERSON> Yitzhak </PERSON> <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON>, <PERSON> Peres </PERSON>' political rival, took a hard stand, saying: `` The Arab side is still not ready for peace.'' <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON>, head of the right-wing <ORGANIZATION> Likud </ORGANIZATION> bloc, told <ORGANIZATION> Israel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> radio </ORGANIZATION> that peace talks `` should n't take place under the -LRB- threat -RRB- of stone-throwing and violence.'' The fundamentalist <ORGANIZATION> Moslem </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Brotherhood </ORGANIZATION>, which has growing support in the territories, issued an underground booklet calling for a stepped-up struggle against <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>. `` Our style of resistance is according to what <PERSON> God </PERSON> told us: Kill them wherever you find them. This is the solution for those who follow the Koran,'' the Moslem holy book, the booklet said. Few clashes were reported Thursday in the occupied <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strip </LOCATION>, the lands <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> captured from <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION> in the 1967 Arab-Israeli war. General strikes paralyzed towns and cities Thursday in the occupied lands, where about 400,000 Arabs, nearly a third of the population there, remained under curfew for a fifth day. For a second day, the army closed <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> to <PERSON> Arab </PERSON> residents of the occupied lands. The security measure for Independence Day was to remain in effect until after Moslem prayers today. Journalists were barred from most parts of the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION>. In the Arab village of <LOCATION> Isawiya </LOCATION> north of <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION>, police fired rubber bullets at Palestinians who threw stones and raised black flags to mourn slain <ORGANIZATION> Palestine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> military commander <PERSON> Khalil </PERSON> <PERSON> Wazir </PERSON>. New details emerged about Saturday's assassination of <PERSON> Wazir </PERSON>, who was gunned down at his home in a suburb of the Tunisian capital, <LOCATION> Tunis </LOCATION>. A Tunisian report said the job was done by an elite Israeli commando squad and <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> sources, speaking privately to <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>, agreed. The Israeli sources also have told the <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> that the team operated under the direct command of Chief of Staff Lt. Gen. <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Shomron </PERSON> and stole documents during the raid at <PERSON> Wazir </PERSON>'s home. The sources said the government approved the operation on two previous occasions in recent weeks but canceled it at the last minute for technical reasons. <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s government has refused comment, and <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON> said Thursday: `` I do n't think anyone has anything to say about this.'' Meanwhile, <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> topped off its Independence Day celebrations with a military show watched by about 40,000 people at <LOCATION> Ramat </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gan </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Stadium </LOCATION> near <LOCATION> Tel </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Aviv </LOCATION> and broadcast live on television. Fighter planes spewing blue-and-white steam, the flag colors, flew loops and circled in formations spelling the numeral 40. U.S.-made F-16s crossed the sky and paratroopers in white jumpsuits performed precision freefall jumps from 45,000 feet. One waved an Israeli flag as he glided toward the stadium floor. `` We all love the army and our soldiers,'' said <PERSON> Yossi </PERSON>, a police officer deployed at one of the stadium gates. `` It's a day that unites the country.'' <PERSON> Yossi </PERSON>, who would not give his last name, said the <PERSON> Arab </PERSON> uprising dampened his joy, adding: `` We want to live in peace with the Arabs, but they are not ready to accept this.'' Since the Dec. 8 start of the anti-occupation protests, 169 Palestinians and two Israelis have been killed. `` <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> stayed independent because it has been able to protect itself,'' said one of the cheering spectators, <PERSON> Sheila </PERSON> <PERSON> Schlussel </PERSON>, 50, of <LOCATION> Teaneck </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.J. </LOCATION> `` <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> is getting a bad press because of what is happening in the territories. We came here to express our support.'' Elsewhere, Israelis celebrated the anniversary with picnics, hikes, fireworks and the annual international Bible quiz, in which 17-year-old <PERSON> Jeremy </PERSON> <PERSON> Weider </PERSON>, of <LOCATION> Monsey </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION>, tied for first place. As an Independence Day present to <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> signed the most comprehensive pact to date between the two countries, formalizing economic and military agreements. The agreement, signed in <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION> by <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON> and <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. Ambassador <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Pickering </PERSON>, will be binding for future administrations. `` This is the most friendly administration we have ever worked with,'' said <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON>. `` They are determined that the strong friendship and cooperation will continue and even be strengthened despite the differences that crop up from time to time.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880422-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-22-88 0131EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     04-22 0918</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0955</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in The News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SAN FRANCISCO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Shirley </PERSON> <PERSON> Temple </PERSON> <PERSON> Black </PERSON>, the dimpled, curly-haired child star turned diplomat, will observe her 60th birthday on Saturday by cooking dinner at her mansion and celebrating her soon-to-be-released autobiography. `` I had 19 years in the film industry and 19 years in government service, so I've had equal careers at the moment,'' said Mrs. <PERSON> Black </PERSON>, speaking from the Tudor-style home south of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> where she has lived for 27 years. By age 5, the world adored <PERSON> Shirley </PERSON> <PERSON> Jane </PERSON> <PERSON> Temple </PERSON>, the moppet whose 35 films, including `` <PERSON> Rebecca </PERSON> of Sunnybrook Farm,'' `` Curly Top'' and `` Poor Little Rich Girl,'' bolstered the spirits of Depression-era audiences. She won an Oscar at age 6, retired at 12 with millions and by 22 married <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> A </PERSON>. <PERSON> Black </PERSON>, son of the former head of <ORGANIZATION> Pacific </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Gas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ; </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Electric </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, and settled down as a suburban housewife. Mrs. <PERSON> Black </PERSON>, a former ambassador to <LOCATION> Ghana </LOCATION>, flies to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION>, once a month to serve as vice president of the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Diplomacy </ORGANIZATION> along with former secretaries of state <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> Kissinger </PERSON> and <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON> <PERSON> Haig </PERSON>. Her autobiography, `` Child Star,'' took eight years to write and will be released in October.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>SANTA BARBARA, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Julia </PERSON> <PERSON> Child </PERSON>, television's `` French Chef,'' was enjoying French bread that she said was like `` a breath of spring'' during her hospital stay for a broken hip, a hospital spokeswoman said. The 75-year-old Mrs. Child fractured her hip Monday at her <LOCATION> Montecito </LOCATION> condominium and was expected to be at <ORGANIZATION> Cottage </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION> for another week, said spokeswoman <PERSON> Janet </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Neill </PERSON>. Mrs. Child was in good condition Thursday. `` She's not eating much, but our executive chef did send her up some French bread. She said it was like a breath of spring. He told her he has some fresh salmon anytime she's ready,'' Ms. <PERSON> O'Neill </PERSON> said. Mrs. Child and her husband of 41 years, <PERSON> Paul </PERSON>, live in <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION>, but since 1981 have spent their winters in <LOCATION> Montecito </LOCATION>, for decades a fashionable enclave in the <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Barbara </LOCATION> area along the <LOCATION> Southern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> coast.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actor <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Garner </PERSON> was in satisfactory condition after undergoing quintuple bypass surgery to alleviate a heart problem he attributed to cigarettes. `` He had five hours of surgery in which the coronary arteries of his heart were bypassed. The surgery went very smoothly,'' <PERSON> Ron </PERSON> <PERSON> Wise </PERSON>, spokesman for <ORGANIZATION> Cedars-Sinai </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>, said Thursday. <PERSON> Garner </PERSON>, 60, entered the medical center, sometimes called `` hospital to the stars'' for its celebrity patients, on Monday for tests. He has blamed his heart problem on cigarette smoking. Doctors had planned to perform surgery for an aneurysm, or ballooning, of his aorta, the main artery carrying blood from the heart. But a series of tests conducted this week determined that <PERSON> Garner </PERSON> should have a quintuple bypass. `` The aneurysm will be taken care of at a later date,'' said Wise, who gave <PERSON> Garner </PERSON>'s condition as satisfactory.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Police officer <PERSON> Steven </PERSON> <PERSON> McDonald </PERSON>, paralyzed by an assailant's bullet in 1986, was made an Irish citizen by Irish Prime Minister <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Haughey </PERSON>, who called him a symbol of `` courage, dedication and loyalty.'' `` Through him, we want to honor all the Irish-Americans who have made contributions to the building of this great nation,'' <PERSON> Haughey </PERSON> said during the ceremony Thursday. <ORGANIZATION> McDonald </ORGANIZATION>, who donned green slacks for the occasion, was accompanied at the ceremony by his wife, <PERSON> Patti </PERSON> <PERSON> Ann </PERSON>, and their 15-month-old son, <PERSON> Conor </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Drake </PERSON>, best known for his role as <PERSON> Benny </PERSON> <PERSON> Stulwicz </PERSON>, the middle-aged mentally retarded office boy on <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` <LOCATION> L.A. </LOCATION> Law,'' does n't want his portrayal to be considered a role model `` I do n't believe in propaganda,'' <PERSON> Drake </PERSON> said in a recent interview. `` I just want <PERSON> Benny </PERSON> to be a person. I was glad this past season when he stopped being noble and got crusty, a little nasty, with his girlfriend.'' The <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> for Retarded Citizens of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> recently commended <PERSON> Drake </PERSON> for his portrayal, which he realizes may be the closest many people get to a retarded person. `` People treat them either as pets or try to ignore them or hate them,'' he said. `` I think the hate factor is going ... but it should n't be there at all. They're just people.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>OTTAWA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Theft and fraud charges have been filed against the interior decorator who renovated Prime Minister <PERSON> Brian </PERSON> <PERSON> Mulroney </PERSON>'s official residences, the <ORGANIZATION> Royal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Canadian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mounted </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION> said. The charges against <PERSON> Giovanni </PERSON> <PERSON> Mowinckel </PERSON>, an Italian citizen whose clients also included the former speaker of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commons </ORGANIZATION>, allege that he took $ 81,000 for personal gain from his bankrupt <LOCATION> Ottawa </LOCATION> design company. At the time, the company owed creditors more than $ 243,000, police Inspector <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Kaine </PERSON> said Thursday. A warrant has been issued for <PERSON> Mowinckel </PERSON>'s arrest, but the designer has returned to <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION> where the warrant is not valid, <PERSON> Kaine </PERSON> said. He said justice department officials will decide later whether to seek his extradition.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>PALM SPRINGS, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 When <PERSON> Sonny </PERSON> <PERSON> Bono </PERSON> presided over his first meeting as mayor of this desert resort town, the public and city officials were confused over what to call the entertainer-restaurateur. The city clerk called him Mr. <PERSON> Mayor </PERSON>. His name plate said Mr. <PERSON> Bono </PERSON> and one citizen addressed him as `` your worship.'' `` I just got elected mayor, not king,'' <PERSON> Bono </PERSON> replied Wednesday. <PERSON> Bono </PERSON> was elected mayor of this community of 38,000 on April 12, one day after his ex-wife <PERSON> Cher </PERSON> won an Oscar for her role in `` Moonstruck.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880422-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-22-88 0133EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-BudgetDeficit     04-22 0515</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Budget Deficit,480</SECOND>
<HEAD>Budget Deficit Surges In March</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVE SKIDMORE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The federal budget deficit grew more than expected in March, but the cumulative red ink in the first six months of the fiscal year is still 3.5 percent smaller than a year ago, the government says. The <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> said Thursday that the March deficit was $ 29.1 billion, up from $ 23.9 billion in February and 2.7 percent larger than March 1987. Economists had been predicting a monthly deficit of $ 24 billion to $ 26 billion. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Evans </PERSON>, head of an economic forecasting service in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, said some federal spending was probably deferred to March from February, when outlays were somewhat smaller than expected. Analysts also said the budget imbalance is usually higher in March than in other months because people who owe taxes generally wait until April to pay, while those due a refund normally file early. For the first half of the 1988 fiscal year, the government has run a deficit of $ 118.9 billion, 3.5 percent lower than the red ink incurred for the same period a year ago. For the entire fiscal year, which ends Sept. 30, the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration is projecting a deficit of $ 146.7 billion, down 2.4 percent from the $ 150.4 billion deficit in 1987. However, the <ORGANIZATION> Congressional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Budget </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> estimates the deficit will climb to $ 157 billion. Last year, the deficit fell sharply because of an unexpected $ 28 billion windfall in tax payments made by people who sold off long-term assets before the capital gains rates were increased under the new tax law. Some analysts say there could be a second, smaller windfall this year if people end up owing more in taxes for 1987 than they would have under the old tax law. `` April is the big question mark with the tax returns coming in,'' <PERSON> Evans </PERSON> said. In March, government revenue totaled $ 65 billion, while spending totaled $ 94.1 billion. For the first half of the year, revenues total $ 412.0 billion while spending amounted to $ 530.9 billion. As usual, the largest spending categories in March were the military followed by Social Security, interest on the national debt and other programs in the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Human </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION>. Military spending totaled $ 25.8 billion last month and $ 142.3 billion for the fiscal year so far, up 5.6 percent from the same period a year ago. Spending for Social Security totaled $ 18.4 billion last month and $ 105.0 billion for the past six months, up 5.6 percent from the same period in the 1987 fiscal year. Social Security is exempted from budget limitations under the Gramm-Rudman law and is therefore generally showing faster spending increases than the other categories. The other HHS programs, including <ORGANIZATION> Medicare </ORGANIZATION> and Medicaid, spent $ 14.2 billion in March and $ 77.5 billion so far this budget year, a 5.9 percent increase over 1987. Interest on the $ 2.5 trillion national debt _ nearly one fifth of total government spending _ was $ 14.4 billion last month and $ 105.2 billion so far this fiscal year, an increase of 9.6 percent over the same period last year.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880422-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-22-88 0147EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-SuperCollider     04-22 0319</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Super Collider,330</SECOND>
<HEAD>House, Senate Subcommittees OK $8 Million SSC Funds Transfer</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TIM BOVEE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Congressional permission to transfer $ 8 million in <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> money from administration to the superconducting super collider avoids delays in the physics research project, the department says. Most of the money will be used to prepare environmental impact statements on prospective sites, <PERSON> Phil </PERSON> <PERSON> Keif </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> spokesman, said Thursday. `` We have to go through that in order to select a site, so it keeps us on schedule,'' <PERSON> Keif </PERSON> said. Had the transfer of money been rejected, `` it just would have delayed things,'' he said. Rep. <PERSON> Carl </PERSON> <PERSON> Pursell </PERSON>, R-Mich., said the transfer was cleared by an agreement between <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> subcommittee chairmen concerned with funding for the $ 4.4 billion project, which physicists plan to use to study the basic structure of matter `` Obviously, this approval demonstrates a certain level of support for the project within the subcommittee leadership which, as an advocate of the project, I'm delighted to see,'' said <PERSON> Pursell </PERSON>, a member of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> energy appropriations subcommittee. Requests to transfer money that has already been appropriated require the consent of the chairman and ranking minority member of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> appropriations subcommittees handling the money. The $ 8 million had been appropriated for the 1988 fiscal year. The committees last month had denied the <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>'s request to transfer the money amid substantial congressional opposition to the project Seven states have been selected as potential sites for the super collider, which will include a 53-mile-round particle accelerator. The finalists are <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>. President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> has asked <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to approve $ 363 million for the project for fiscal 1989, although <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> supporters have said they would seek $ 100 million because of budget-balancing concerns. The project is expected to create 4,000 permanent jobs and have an annual budget of $ 280 million.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880422-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-22-88 0021EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Poland-Sobibor Bjt   04-22 0756</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Poland-Sobibor, Bjt,0777</SECOND>
<HEAD>Death Camp Survivor Returns from America to Sobibor</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY4</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN DANISZEWSKI</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SOBIBOR, Poland (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An American survivor of the 1943 escape from <ORGANIZATION> Sobibor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nazi </ORGANIZATION> death camp, who has waged a lonely fight to have it preserved as a memorial, returned this week and wept at the sound of <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s national anthem. <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Blatt </PERSON>, surrounded by a small group of friends, joined them in singing the Hatikvah, or The Hope. They stood next to the grass-covered mound of ashes and bones which likely contains the remains of both of <PERSON> Blatt </PERSON>'s parents and of his little brother. `` I could never imagine that I could stand here someday and hear singing of the Hatikvah in this spot,'' said <PERSON> Blatt </PERSON>, 60, of <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Barbara </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION> `` I hope there is another world and that all the people, from <LOCATION> Holland </LOCATION>, from <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> -LRB- who also died at <LOCATION> Sobibor </LOCATION> -RRB- are listening too,'' he said. It was a day of vindication for <PERSON> Blatt </PERSON>. He was accompanied by a Polish official who confirmed publicly that <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> would replace an erroneous sign at the camp's entrance which lists the 250,000 victims as Soviet prisoners of war, Jews, Poles and Gypsies. `` Here the victims were all Jews,'' said <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Kagan </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> Holocaust </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sites </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Preservation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, founded by <PERSON> Blatt </PERSON>. <PERSON> Blatt </PERSON>, a Polish Jew, was 15 when he arrived at <LOCATION> Sobibor </LOCATION> in April 1943. He watched as his mother, father and brother were marched off to their deaths. He was spared by the caprice of the camp commander, who needed a shoeshine boy. Six months later, <PERSON> Blatt </PERSON> took part in the camp's successful uprising, in which most of the Nazis were killed and 300 prisoners escaped. About 50 of those escaped prisoners survived the war. The story was the topic of a CBS television movie last year, `` Escape from <LOCATION> Sobibor </LOCATION>.'' <PERSON> Blatt </PERSON> survived the war, fighting with partisans against the Germans, and eventually emigrated to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. He has revisited the camp many times and has repeatedly protested its unkempt condition and the misleading sign. <PERSON> Kagan </PERSON> thanked <PERSON> Jacek </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilczur </PERSON>, a historian with <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>'s Main Commission for the Investigation of <ORGANIZATION> Nazi </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> War </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Crimes-Institute </ORGANIZATION> of National Remembrance, for agreeing to change the inscription. Noting that <LOCATION> Sobibor </LOCATION> was the site of the only successful mass uprising at a concentration camp, <PERSON> Kagan </PERSON> said: `` We would like to thank you for restoring a page in Jewish history. There are still people who think Jews went like sheep into places like this. And it's not true. Here, at the site of their biggest revolt, I'd like to thank you.'' <PERSON> Blatt </PERSON> obtained the promises from Polish officials to correct the sign and make other improvements in a meeting last August. When he returned to the camp Wednesday, he found flowers planted in front of the mound, a fresh coat of paint along the borders and a glass exhibition case at the entrance showing an architect's plans for the camp Among the changes planned are fencing in the camp, reshaping pathways, erecting exhibits that would tell the story of <LOCATION> Sobibor </LOCATION>, and encircling the mound with Jewish cemetery tombstones, which were torn down by the <ORGANIZATION> Nazis </ORGANIZATION> for use as paving. Polish workers will make the improvements with money raised by the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>. The project is expected to cost $ 375,000. <PERSON> Blatt </PERSON> had another suggestion for the architect. Walking to a field near the mound, where the camp crematoriums were located, he reached at random into the dirt and sifted pieces of human bone through his fingers. He said that the field is used by farmers to graze cattle and should be covered with a concrete slab to protect the remains. <PERSON> Wilczur </PERSON>, in his remarks to the group of about 20 people, said Polish Jews and non-Jews alike shared a common awful fate at the hands of the <ORGANIZATION> Nazis </ORGANIZATION>. `` The died for the same reason: Because one was a Jew and the other a Pole,'' he said. Referring to the 3 million Polish Jews killed in the Holocaust, about the same number as non-Jewish Poles who died under the <ORGANIZATION> Nazis </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Wilczur </PERSON> said: `` They were truly our brothers, in life, in the moment of dying, and now in their graves.'' <PERSON> Wilczur </PERSON> added: `` Any kind of chauvinism, nationalism, totalitarianism, leads in the end to a <LOCATION> Treblinka </LOCATION> or a <LOCATION> Sobibor </LOCATION>. One they call <LOCATION> Sobibor </LOCATION>, another they call <LOCATION> Katyn </LOCATION>,'' the site in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> where about 4,000 Polish officers were found executed in World War II. `` Murder is murder. The blood of innocents is the blood of innocents.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880422-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-22-88 0152EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-PainRelief Bjt   04-22 0534</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Pain Relief, Bjt,0549</SECOND>
<HEAD>Study: Morphine Self-Dosing Reduces Use By Cancer Patients</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MALCOLM RITTER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Science Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Cancer patients who got morphine at the touch of a button to relieve pain stopped using the drug sooner, and used little more than half the narcotic than patients who got a continuous infusion, a researcher says. `` These patients do n't even come close to developing addiction,'' said <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Chapman </PERSON>, associate research director at the <ORGANIZATION> Pain </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> the </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> and director of the pain and toxicity research program at the <ORGANIZATION> Fred </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hutchinson </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cancer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION>. The shorter time on the drug is important because it means an earlier end to confusion, sedation and other unpleasant reactions that accompany morphine treatment, he said. `` In order to cope you need all your marbles. You ca n't be coping effectively when you're on the drug,'' he said. He spoke in a recent interview about research done with <PERSON> Hutchinson </PERSON> colleagues including <PERSON> Harlan </PERSON> <PERSON> Hill </PERSON>, <PERSON> Costantino </PERSON> <PERSON> Benedetti </PERSON> and others. They studied hospitalized patients who had undergone bone marrow transplantation as part of cancer therapy. As a result of cancer treatment, such patients commonly suffer pain for two or three weeks in the mouth and through the digestive tract, and sometimes in the hands and feet and elsewhere, <PERSON> Chapman </PERSON> said. In the study, 32 patients got a continuous infusion of morphine through an intravenous line, the standard treatment, <PERSON> Chapman </PERSON> said. Twenty-six others got doses by pushing a button on an electric pump hooked up to an intravenous line. The pump was programmed to give no more than one milligram of morphine every 10 minutes. For each group, the decision to stop treatment was made jointly between the patient and medical staff, <PERSON> Chapman </PERSON> said. Patients who controlled their morphine used the drug an average of about 13 days, while those who received a continuous intravenous infusion averaged more than 17 days. The self-administering group also used only 53 percent as much morphine as the other patients. While the study was not designed to look for addiction, no self-adminstering patient reported cravings for the drug after the treatment stopped, <PERSON> Chapman </PERSON> said. Self-administration of drugs might be useful for prolonged pain of serious burns or terminal stages of cancer, he said. It would not be suitable for pain that lasts for years, such as some cases of low back pain, he said. So-called `` patient-controlled analgesia'' has been studied extensively for short-term pain like that following surgery. But the new work is the first large-scale study involving long-term pain, said <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Payne </PERSON>, associate professor of neurology at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cincinnati </ORGANIZATION>. The study is important because it shows patients can safely control the amount of drug they get, gaining relief without overdosing, he said. <PERSON> Chapman </PERSON> said results of the study have been submitted for publication in a scientific journal. He spoke while in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> to receive a $ 50,000 pain research grant to the university from the Bristol-Myers Co.. Other pain grants were awarded to the Memorial Sloan-Kettering Cancer Center in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Ann </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Arbor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Veterans </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Branch </ORGANIZATION> at <LOCATION> Galveston </LOCATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medicine </ORGANIZATION>
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880422-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-22-88 0153EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-MilitaryManpower     04-22 0647</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Military Manpower,580</SECOND>
<HEAD>Women in Military at Post-War High</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By NORMAN BLACK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Military Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The number of women in the military has climbed to 10.3 percent of the total force, a post-World War II high, according to a <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> report. At the same time, the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> continues to see improvement in the educational levels of its active-duty personnel. It also posted a small increase last year in the number of civilian workers on the payroll, and is paying out pensions to more than 1.5 million individuals. And by all measures, <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> continues to lead the nation in the number of individuals working for the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>. Those and other statistics are contained in the latest edition of an annual <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> study entitled `` Selected Manpower Statistics.'' The new edition, published Thursday, consists of 222 pages of tables and covers fiscal 1987, which ended Sept. 30. The annual report offers the most comprehensive view available of <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> employment patterns, as well as indicators of where that force lives and how age, sex, education and family patterns are changing. The latest edition shows that as of Sept. 30, the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> had 2,160,727 men and women on active duty; another 13,490 men and women in the three military academies, and 1,174,826 civilian employees around the world, including foreign nationals. The active-duty total was essentially static compared to fiscal 1986 _ up about 5,100 _ while `` DoD civilian personnel increased by about 21,800'' during the fiscal year, the report shows. Both the active-duty and civilian employment figures are declining this year and will continue to fall to accommodate cuts in the fiscal 1989 budget. In a section on active-duty trends, the report discloses that there are now 222,338 female officers and enlisted personnel and another 1,467 women in the various military academies, for a total of 223,805. That represents 10.3 percent of the military force and is the highest level recorded since 1945 when World War II ended with 266,256 women in the military. The report also shows that women managed to increase their presence slightly at the military academies, where new officers are trained. In fiscal 1985, females comprised 10.33 percent of the academy students. In fiscal 1986, the figure climbed to 10.63 percent and last year, to 10.9 percent. The report says 53.35 percent of all military personnel are now married _ down slightly from the 54.6 percent reported in fiscal 1986 _ and military personnel are supporting 2.8 million dependents, also down slightly from the previous year. Every service _ the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corps </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> _ continues to have more military dependents than it does active-duty personnel, the report shows. On the educational side, the percentage of enlisted personnel in the military who have completed high school increased by almost a full percentage point last year _ from 96.5 percent to 97.2 percent. Earlier reports have shown a dramatic increase in the number of new recruits with a high-school degree; the manpower study, however, covers all enlisted personnel and not just recruits. The study also shows there are now 1.53 million `` military annuitants'' supported by the Pentagon. An annuitant is an individual who has either retired with a pension after a minimum 20 years of service, retired with benefits because of a disability, or is a family entitled to survivor benefits. Most of the annuitants _ about 1.2 million _ are regular pensioners. In 1950, there were only 58,752 such retirees. The increase has already prompted <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to revise the pension system with an eye toward cutting future costs. <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> easily held down its longstanding No. 1 ranking in <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> employees, with 206,495 military personnel and 137,677 civilians for a total of 344,172. It was followed by <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> with 208,588 military and civilian workers combined, then <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> with 202,027; <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> with 110,952; <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> with 109,057, and <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION> with 103,140.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880422-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-22-88 0026EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a Anti-AcneDrugLinkedtoHundredsofBirthDefectsAM-HongKongGoldovernmentofficialsareconsideringremovingapopularanti-acnedrugfromthemarketbecausetheyestimateithascausedmorethan900babiestobebornwithseverebirthdefects
TheNewYorkTimesreportedFriday.   04-22 0520</FIRST>
<SECOND>Anti-Acne Drug Linked to Hundreds of Birth Defects in Babies</SECOND>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
