<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880502-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-02-88 2350EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-HelicopterCrash 1stLd-Writethru a0728 05-02 0565</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Helicopter Crash, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0728,0575</SECOND>
<HEAD>City Awaits Report of Whether Rivalry Impeded Rescue</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: SUBS grafs 6-9 ``A police'' with 5 grafs to UPDATE with
police and fire commissioners' comments. Picks up 10th graf pvs
``Mayor Edward.'' DELETES outdated 12th graf pvs ``Fire
Commissioner.''</NOTE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 City officials have asked for reports on whether police prevented Fire Department divers from joining the search for a victim trapped in a sightseeing helicopter that crashed and sank in the <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION>. A fire lieutenant was quoted as saying he had eight divers at the scene Sunday morning, but police kept them away at a time when only two police divers were in the water. It took 90 minutes to find the helicopter in the river's murk and free the trapped passenger, <PERSON> Takashi </PERSON> <PERSON> Oyama </PERSON>, a Japanese businessman. <PERSON> Oyama </PERSON>, 29, was taken to <LOCATION> Bellevue </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION>, where he died nine hours later. The pilot and three other passengers, none seriously injured, escaped to the surface and were taken to hospitals. The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> also said it would look into the issue of whether rescue was impeded by police-firefighter rivalry if it received information that such a dispute had occurred. Police Commissioner <PERSON> Benjamin </PERSON> <PERSON> Ward </PERSON> said two police divers were in the water by 10:37 a.m., 14 minutes after the first report of the crash. By 10:45, nine divers were conducting a pattern search of the area, he said. Fire Commissioner <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Bruno </PERSON> said two Fire Department divers were there at 10:37 and that eight were on the scene by 10:45. <PERSON> Ward </PERSON> dismissed as a personal opinion an earlier statement by Fire Lt. <PERSON> Patrick </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rescue </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> 1 that the search was impeded because his divers were not allowed to join it. `` It was the feeling of the police commander on the scene and in fact the common practice of all experienced water rescuers that uncoordinated search teams in the water at the same time is dangerous and unproductive,'' <PERSON> Ward </PERSON> said in explaining why the <ORGANIZATION> Fire </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>'s offer was declined. <PERSON> Bruno </PERSON> said the rescue effort was `` within the purview of the Police Department and I have no problem with that. I do have a problem with reports saying we are not needed and unnecessary. Our feeling is that if resources were available, they should be utilized.'' Mayor <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> I. </PERSON> <PERSON> Koch </PERSON> said he has asked for a report to `` find out whether all of the assistance on the scene was properly used.'' The mayor said he would not speculate before he got the information. In line with rules laid down by <PERSON> Koch </PERSON> last year to end jurisdiction disputes, police were in charge at Sunday's crash site, a non-fire emergency. The Fire Department calls the shots at fire emergencies. First Deputy Mayor <PERSON> Stanley </PERSON> <PERSON> Brezenoff </PERSON> said `` The only question is were there enough divers in the water'' to make the rescue without using fire divers. The crashed helicopter, a Bell Jet Ranger operated by <ORGANIZATION> Island </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Helicopter </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Garden </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, plunged from 1,400 feet after a 15-to-20-minute tour of <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Ghiorsi </PERSON>, chief of the federal safety board's <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> office, said particular attention would be given seat belts and the pontoons, which separated from the craft on impact. <PERSON> Oyama </PERSON> was snarled in his belt and had to be cut free, said <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Rivadeneyra </PERSON>, one of divers who found the helicopter in 35 feet of water.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880502-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-02-88 0057EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--O'KeeffeThieves     05-02 0168</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--O'Keeffe Thieves,0173</SECOND>
<HEAD>Popular Art Show Prints Disappearing</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CHICAGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 People have been stealing poster ads on commuter-train platforms promoting an art exhibit of <PERSON> Georgia </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Keeffe </PERSON>'s work, authorities said. `` They keep bringing them in here, razor-bladed out,'' said <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Dilger </PERSON>, service director with <ORGANIZATION> Winston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Network </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, the billboard company that installs the posters. `` People must find it very attractive if they will take the time to cut the things out.'' Posters of the painting `` Red Poppy'' have been displayed in many parts of the city to advertise a showing of the late Ms. <PERSON> O'Keeffe </PERSON>'s work at the <ORGANIZATION> Art </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chicago </ORGANIZATION>. At least 35 of 200 posters on rapid-transit platforms are missing. When cut, only white borders and the words `` <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION> O'Keeffe 1887-1986'' remain. <PERSON> Norman </PERSON> <PERSON> Baxter </PERSON>, a vice president of <ORGANIZATION> Southwestern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, which is sponsoring the exhibit, said he considers the thefts a form of flattery for the artist, who was known for her large and precise designs of flowers and the skulls of animals.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880502-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-02-88 0002EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-ChicagoMayor     05-02 0730</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Chicago Mayor,0750</SECOND>
<HEAD>Chicago's Political Picture Muddled Since Death Of Mayor
Washington</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</NOTE>
<NOTE>Eds: Lu is cq in 14th graf, `There'll be ...'</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By JAMES LITKE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CHICAGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Image is everything in the rough-and-tumble world of <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> politics, says Mayor <PERSON> Eugene </PERSON> <PERSON> Sawyer </PERSON>. But after four months surrounded by the trappings of power, he admits his image is n't what it should be. His enemies gripe about his willingness to reward friends. And his friends gripe about his unwillingness to punish enemies. `` I might become a little more aggressive, harder than I used to be, but that's because the job will make me so,'' the soft-spoken mayor said during a recent interview. `` Everything you do or say in this office is political, or somebody will couch it that way and force you to respond in a political manner. You try to be a statesman, but hey, you better be a politician, too,'' he added. `` Otherwise you wo n't be around very long.'' `` People have all kinds of plans for you, and I just say that if I'm going to make a mistake, it will be one I made myself, not something that somebody suggested to me,'' said <PERSON> Sawyer </PERSON>, 58. <PERSON> Sawyer </PERSON> became embroiled in a new controversy this weekend when religious leaders accused mayoral community liaison aide <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Cokely </PERSON> of repeatedly using racial and religious slurs against Jews and Christians in a series of tape-recorded lectures to followers of Nation of Islam leader <PERSON> Louis </PERSON> <PERSON> Farrakhan </PERSON>. Mayoral spokesman <PERSON> Monroe </PERSON> <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> said <PERSON> Sawyer </PERSON> planned to ask <PERSON> Cokely </PERSON>, 35, to `` tune down his rhetoric,'' but did not plan to fire him. <PERSON> Sawyer </PERSON> became mayor following the death in November of <PERSON> Harold </PERSON> <PERSON> Washington </PERSON>, who became the city's first black mayor in 1983 and had consolidated his power over the <ORGANIZATION> Cook </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>. <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> had served only eight months of his second term and <PERSON> Sawyer </PERSON> must at some point face an election if he wants to stay in office. But the date of the next mayoral election is up in the air. The <ORGANIZATION> Chicago </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Election </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commissioners </ORGANIZATION> ruled last week that an election would be held in 1989 if City Clerk <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> Kozubowski </PERSON> declared the mayor's office vacant. <PERSON> Kozubowski </PERSON> said he would n't do so unless ordered by a court. His opposition virtually assures the controversy will be resolved in court. Already, competing lawsuits arguing for either a 1989 or 1991 election are pending. <PERSON> Sawyer </PERSON> has said he is prepared to run whenever the next election is scheduled. No matter what the date, observers say, the absence of a political giant like <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> or the late Mayor <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Daley </PERSON> will show how splintered this city's once-vaunted Democratic machine has become. `` There'll be so many people running _ black, white, green ... that nobody will know what to do,'' said black activist <PERSON> Lu </PERSON> <PERSON> Palmer </PERSON>, credited with organizing the grass-roots campaign that elected <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> to his first term. `` And there's scores of people talking about running for everything from dogcatcher to mayor and nobody's got the power to tell them no,'' he continued. `` Machines move with precision. If there was a chief like <PERSON> Harold </PERSON>, things would still be done with precision,'' he said. `` But now you've got a lot of little chieftains and everybody's throwing things in the way.'' <PERSON> Sawyer </PERSON> has had a difficult time shouldering the mantle since he was elected by a <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> coalition made up mostly of white, anti-Washington aldermen. `` Some people were with <PERSON> Harold </PERSON> because they believed in him, some because they feared him and some because he proved he could win,'' said <PERSON> Alderman </PERSON> <PERSON> Danny </PERSON> <PERSON> Davis </PERSON>. `` Everybody knew there would be some slippage after he died,'' added <PERSON> Davis </PERSON>, `` but nobody knew how much.'' The coalition that put <PERSON> Sawyer </PERSON> in office already has shown a tendency to fray at the seams. His bloc held together long enough to pass <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>'s record budget, but grumbling set in almost immediately afterward and many of <PERSON> Sawyer </PERSON>'s legislative proposals are languishing in the council. And during the primary elections in March, several black aldermen who were among <PERSON> Sawyer </PERSON>'s most identifiable supporters got clobbered in races for party committeeman positions. Normally, aldermen are shoo-ins for those posts. `` What that told me is that the voters in my ward do n't like him,'' said <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Beavers </PERSON>, one of the aldermen, `` and they may not be crazy about me standing behind him either.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880502-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-02-88 0003EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-MississippiWorkfare     05-02 0631</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Mississippi Workfare,0646</SECOND>
<HEAD>Mississippi Welfare Officials Turn Workfare Jobs Into Paying
Employment</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By KATHY EYRE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>JACKSON, Miss. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Welfare officials celebrating the first anniversary of <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION>'s workfare program say they've shown that even the nation's poorest state can take those who have never had a steady job or who have n't worked in years off the dole. While <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> debated the most comprehensive welfare reform bill in 50 years, <ORGANIZATION> Mississippi </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Welfare </ORGANIZATION> officials lauded their program for turning workfare jobs into paying employment for 109 of the 765 food stamp recipients participating so far. Welfare recipients, they said, may be pulling themselves up by their own bootstraps largely because of the state's poverty. `` We're not distressed by the current economic situation. In fact, I get a personal kick from trying to do more with less,'' Welfare Commissioner <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Brittain </PERSON> said. <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> has the lowest per capita income in the nation at $ 10,204; 20 percent of its residents rely on food stamps. `` A lot of people, including some who work here in this department, said workfare ca n't work in <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Brittain </PERSON> recalled. `` The reasons they gave me for that is it's a rural-based state, that we have high unemployment.'' But <PERSON> Brittain </PERSON> said he knew workfare could work in <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> because, although local governments and private non-profit groups were short of revenue for needed services, there were `` tremendous numbers of people on welfare who in my opinion were able to work.'' <PERSON> Gloria </PERSON> <PERSON> Rutledge </PERSON>, a regional food program specialist in the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION>'s <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> office, agreed that <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION>'s poverty has contributed to its workfare success. `` I do n't know that this would have worked so well in some other place,'' <PERSON> Rutledge </PERSON> said of the program, which requires clients to work for government the number of hours times the minimum wage that equals the value of their food stamp allotment. She said because so many <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> agencies ca n't afford to hire people to perform necessary tasks they'll give workfare participants doing those jobs more responsibility and training than they would otherwise. She also noted that <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> workfare participants can more easily be recommended to private industry as solid, proven employees because they work an average of six months before <PERSON> Brittain </PERSON> personally presents their resumes at a meeting of local business owners and managers in their community. <PERSON> Rutledge </PERSON> said that with 16 counties participating so far, <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> probably has the largest-scale food stamp workfare program in the Southeast. <PERSON> Brittain </PERSON> said he hopes to include all of the state's 82 counties within a few years. Each county's board of supervisors must opt to join <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION>'s version of the federally authorized program. Participating counties pay $ 12.50 monthly to cover each workfare client's travel and other miscellaneous expenses, with the federal government matching that amount. Food stamp recipients in participating counties must sign up for workfare, Job Find or educational programs. In the past year, 1,972 of 5,448 clients in the participating counties opted to discontinue receiving food stamps rather than meet the requirements of one of the three options. Forty-four states have a workfare program tied to the Aid to Families with Dependent Children program, according to federal officials in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. Among the workfare success stories provided by <PERSON> Brittain </PERSON> is the case of <PERSON> Cecil </PERSON> <PERSON> Walker </PERSON>, a longtime unemployed off-shore oilfield worker. <PERSON> Walker </PERSON> began his workfare assignment as a novice in the Welfare Department's printing office. His workfare training later allowed him to select from among several print shop job offers _ at what he said is a livable salary. `` It's something when your children say, ` I want this and I want that, Daddy,''' <PERSON> Walker </PERSON> said. `` Now, I ca n't get everything they want, but I get everything they need and some of the things they want.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880502-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-02-88 0006EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Afghanistan-Soldiers     05-02 0727</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Afghanistan-Soldiers,0749</SECOND>
<HEAD>At Military Base, Soviets Surround Themselves With Signs Of Home</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By CAROL J. WILLIAMS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>KABUL, Afghanistan (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Except for the thunder of aircraft taking off and the showers of flares overhead, Soviet soldiers serving at a base near <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION> airport could almost convince themselves they are in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. The corrugated metal huts and wooden barracks are typical of bases in their native land. Beside each cot in the bunkhouses are tubes of Soviet toothpaste, Soviet soap and Soviet mirrors, purchased at the base store. Russian women like <PERSON> Oksana </PERSON> <PERSON> Okulova </PERSON> serve breakfast, lunch and dinner to the soldiers on Soviet crockery. Afterward, the women wash up while the men go off to train Afghan government troops and help them defend the city against attack by anti-communist rebels. The hearty breads cherished by Soviets are baked at the base each day, and familiar foods like ham, cheese and apples are flown in for the soldiers, who eschew the spicy Afghan dishes. But the flares, which are released by aircraft to deflect heat-seeking Stinger missiles, serve as a reminder that the soldiers are in danger, even inside the closely guarded confines of the base. `` Of course it's dangerous flying here,'' <PERSON> Tiit </PERSON> <PERSON> Tommela </PERSON>, an army major from <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Estonia </LOCATION>, told visiting foreign journalists. `` We have to take precautions against your Stingers.'' Afghan guerrillas, who have been fighting the pro-Soviet government for 10 years, use the U.S.-supplied missiles effectively against government aircraft. Ms. <PERSON> Okulova </PERSON>, a 25-year-old who sought an escape from the industrial Russian city of <LOCATION> Voronezh </LOCATION>, said the aviation dangers are the only aspect of her life in <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> she finds frightening. `` We hardly ever leave the base, so it's easy to just keep occupied and not think about the fact that there is a war going on,'' she said. `` We are forbidden to go to the markets, and when we go on touring trips we travel as a group.'' Officers refused to say how many soldiers serve at the sprawling complex that provides security for the capital, <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION>, and the aircraft serving it. It appears to house at least 1,000 Soviets. On Saturday, as the noon sun burst through rainclouds in the mountains ringing <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION>, a squad of Soviet paratroopers in camouflage jumpsuits lined up on the sports field to teach Afghans the art of hand-to-hand combat. Nearby, soldiers worked with two German shepherds trained to sniff out explosives hidden in items like canteens and matchboxes. `` There are occasional problems with the men,'' Ms. <PERSON> Okulova </PERSON> admitted when asked how she and several dozen other service workers deal with so many lonely soldiers far from home. But several factors limit the potential for romantic problems. Strict rules forbid intimate relationships, there is little privacy in the dormitories and barracks, and the women must work long hours, Mrs. <PERSON> Okulova </PERSON> said. The Soviets plan to start pulling out of <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> on May 15, under an accord signed last month in <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION>. However, the <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION> base may be one of the last closed by the Soviets. Because there is no firm exit date, the soldiers at the base have a business-as-usual attitude, although they admit to being eager to return home. `` We will go when we are told to go,'' said <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON> <PERSON> Alexandrov </PERSON> of the Ukrainian city of <LOCATION> Kharkov </LOCATION>. `` Everything here is normal for the time being, although we are of course happy that a settlement has been reached in <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION>.'' Soviet soldiers intervened in December 1979 to support the government, and about 115,000 remain in <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>. In keeping with <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>'s official contention that <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>'s army is now strong enough to defend the country without <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> fighting power, the soldiers had high praise for the forces loyal to President <PERSON> Najib </PERSON> `` They will resolve their own problems,'' said <PERSON> Andrei </PERSON> <PERSON> Tarelkin </PERSON>, a paratrooper from the Russian city of <LOCATION> Ivanovo </LOCATION>. He was one of several decorated heroes turned out in full parade uniform Saturday for the benefit of the visitors. `` The Afghan army is young, but it should be able to defend itself.'' Some Western observers here expect the rebel forces based in <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> to move north and take control of parts of <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> as the Soviets retreat. <PERSON> Najib </PERSON>'s regular army numbers only about 40,000 soldiers, many of them underage conscripts likely to flee if government positions becomes indefensible.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880502-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-02-88 0001EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-DysonAide 3rdLd-Writethru a0816 05-02 0663</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Dyson Aide, 3rd Ld - Writethru, a0816,0673</SECOND>
<HEAD>Congressman's Aide Plunges to Death After Critical Story</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: SUBS 11th graf ``The newspaper'' to add that aide was
unidentified to avoid implying he was aide named in 12th graf.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The top aide to a <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION> congressman jumped to his death from a hotel window Sunday after <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> reported he had made bizarre demands of male staff members, including asking one to do a striptease. <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Pappas </PERSON>, 46, chief assistant to Rep. <PERSON> Roy </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Dyson </PERSON>, fell 18 stories to a seventh-floor roof of the Helmsley Palace Hotel, said police spokesman Lt. <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> Davis </PERSON>. The death appeared to be a suicide, <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Pappas </PERSON> left a note on hotel stationery, he said, but he declined to disclose its contents. The Post article quoted former staff members as saying <PERSON> Dyson </PERSON> had ceded control of his <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> office to <PERSON> Pappas </PERSON>. The newspaper said <PERSON> Pappas </PERSON> used money from <PERSON> Dyson </PERSON>'s re-election campaign to recruit for a company <PERSON> Pappas </PERSON> owned, offering salaries up to $ 50,000 for single young men, then coerced them to socialize with him. <PERSON> Dyson </PERSON>, a 39-year-old Democrat, was registered in a different room from Pappas Sunday at the hotel, <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> said. The congressman was interviewed by detectives, who would not comment on the questioning. A hotel operator said a <PERSON> Roy </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Dyson </PERSON> was registered but was not answering his phone. <PERSON> Dyson </PERSON> was elected to the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> in 1980, unseating Rep. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bauman </PERSON>, a conservative Republican who was caught in a scandal when the <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> reported he was seen in public with young male prostitutes. The Post's front-page article about <PERSON> Dyson </PERSON> Sunday came as the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Election </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> investigates allegations his campaign disclosure reports concealed $ 6,650 in payments to <PERSON> Pappas </PERSON>. <PERSON> Pappas </PERSON>, paid $ 72,200 as <PERSON> Dyson </PERSON>'s administrative assistant last year, also owns a company, <ORGANIZATION> Pappenbauer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associates </ORGANIZATION>, that received $ 119,642 in fees and expenses since 1980, a revised <PERSON> Dyson </PERSON> campaign reports shows. <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Frazer </PERSON>, Republican chairman in <PERSON> Dyson </PERSON>'s district, told the Easton -LRB- Md. -RRB- Star-Democrat he filed the complaint that led to the <ORGANIZATION> FEC </ORGANIZATION> investigation, but it was the Post that had raised questions about sexual discrimination and what <PERSON> Frazer </PERSON> called `` the apparently established preference for young males in the recruiting and hiring practices.'' The newspaper quoted <PERSON> Dyson </PERSON> staff members as saying <PERSON> Pappas </PERSON> told one male employee that he would have to perform a striptease at a 1987 office retreat. The unidentified aide refused. <PERSON> Scott </PERSON> <PERSON> Ourth </PERSON>, was quoted as saying that when he was recruited to be <PERSON> Dyson </PERSON>'s press secretary in December 1986 he was told he could not date for a year and should devote all his time to the office. Ourth quit within six months. The article also quoted <PERSON> Andy </PERSON> <PERSON> Hira </PERSON>, 22, a special assistant to <PERSON> Pappas </PERSON>, as saying he was fired for refusing to stay at a party in <PERSON> Dyson </PERSON>'s <LOCATION> Annapolis </LOCATION> hotel suite last November, after <PERSON> Dyson </PERSON> announced he would run for re-election in 1988. Fellow staff member <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Fox </PERSON> quit because of similar demands, <PERSON> Hira </PERSON> was quoted as saying. The newspaper quoted a memo from <PERSON> Pappas </PERSON> dated Nov. 14 as saying, `` ... it is important for everyone on this staff to remember that <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Pappas </PERSON> is the chief of staff, responsible for everyone's paycheck When he expresses a wish, however slight, it should be taken seriously.'' Those interviewed were quoted as saying they did not believe the pressure went beyond attending dinners and parties organized by <PERSON> Pappas </PERSON>. Former aides also were quoted as saying <PERSON> Pappas </PERSON> excluded female staff members from his social activities. The newspaper said <PERSON> Pappas </PERSON> issued a statement saying <PERSON> Dyson </PERSON>'s office `` has been run in an efficient and well-structured manner The office has been managed in a way which has served the people of the 1st Congressional District of <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION> well for many years.'' Neighbors and former staff members told the <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> that <PERSON> Dyson </PERSON> frequently stays at <PERSON> Pappas </PERSON>' large frame house in <LOCATION> Accokeek </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Md. </LOCATION>, about 20 miles south of <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Dyson </PERSON>'s residence is further south in <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mary </LOCATION><LOCATION> 's </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880502-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-02-88 0013EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-MitchellsHouse Bjt   05-02 0664</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Mitchells House, Bjt,0681</SECOND>
<HEAD>Atlanta Debates Saving `GWTW' Author's Apartment</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARC RICE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ATLANTA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON> called it `` The Dump.'' And in its current state, the apartment where she wrote much of `` Gone With The Wind'' shows the effects of care by those who, frankly, could n't give a damn. The three-story brick and stucco building sits in the middle of a muddy lot in midtown <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>. Its windows are broken or boarded, its roof is sunken and torn, its walls are sooty. But a group with $ 850,000 in financial backing wants to save the 74-year-old building, saying it represents possibly the last chance for <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> to properly honor one of its most celebrated residents. Developers, on the other hand, say `` The Dump'' ca n't be restored and should be razed to create a park to complement a recent flurry of construction in the neighborhood. Miss <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON> and her husband, <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Marsh </PERSON>, rented a first-floor apartment at what was then called <ORGANIZATION> Windsor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Apartments from 1926 to 1932. She was killed in a 1949 automobile accident 13 years after her epic novel of the Old South and Reconstruction was published. The fate of the building is in federal court. <ORGANIZATION> Trammell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Crow </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, which purchased the property in 1985, sued the city in January after Mayor <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> <PERSON> Young </PERSON> refused to sign a demolition permit for the apartment building. Young had said he would support demolition as a last resort, but the preservationist group came along and <PERSON> Young </PERSON> agreed to try to save the building. <PERSON> Trammell </PERSON> <PERSON> Crow </PERSON> had begun landscaping work around the building. Meanwhile, the group, <ORGANIZATION> Mitchell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, is drumming up support for a Mitchell memorial project. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON>, president of the group, says most of the other <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> sites where Miss <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON> lived have been destroyed, leaving few physical reminders of the writer. ` This is one of our last opportunities,'' he said. <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON> said wants to restore the building to the way it was in Miss <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON>'s time, display the apartment where she did her writing and establish a writer-in-residence program. While previous attempts at `` Gone With The Wind'' attractions focused on the popular 1939 movie, <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON> said the apartment project would emphasize Miss <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON>'s book. `` We'd like to keep the literary aspect in the forefront,'' he said. The literary emphasis also would keep the project from becoming merely a tourist attraction, he said, though the lack of a major `` Gone With The Wind'' center in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> is a major impetus for the effort. <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON> said the restoration effort has raised about $ 850,000 in cash, pledges and pledged services. He said it also has the endorsement from <ORGANIZATION> Miss </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mitchell </ORGANIZATION>'s only remaining heirs _ two nephews. Among the opponents are those who were acquainted with <PERSON> Miss </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON> and say she would be against the memorial. `` I'm opposed to saving what she called ` The Dump' because <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON> herself told me on several occasions that she wanted no museums or landmarks preserved in her memory,'' columnist <PERSON> Celestine </PERSON> <PERSON> Sibley </PERSON> wrote recently in The Atlanta Constitution. But <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON> said there are many misconceptions about Miss <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON>, and the project would offer a chance to clarify her background. And the recent announcement that a `` Gone With The Wind'' sequel is being written by a <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> author will generate even more interest, he added. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Decker </PERSON>, marketing principal at <PERSON> Trammel </PERSON> <PERSON> Crow </PERSON>, said the developer sponsored two studies of the site before deciding that restoring the apartment was not feasible. One study, he said, found that the deterioration of the building was worse than expected. The other concluded that the funds needed for the project _ an estimated $ 2 million _ would not be available. If <PERSON> Trammel </PERSON> <PERSON> Crow </PERSON>'s plans proceed, the park would have a historical marker designating the site as the location of Miss <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON>'s one-time residence, <PERSON> Decker </PERSON> said. Any surviving or significant items from the building would be saved for inclusion in a possible traveling museum of `` Gone With The Wind'' memorobilia, he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880502-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-02-88 0016EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--Japan-Shell     05-02 0142</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Japan-Shell,0144</SECOND>
<HEAD>Old Japanese Army Shell Kills 9-Year-Old Boy</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A World War II artillery shell that a boy had kept in his toy box for six months exploded when he took it out to play, and police said the blast killed him, injured his father and destroyed their home. The Japanese <ORGANIZATION> Imperial </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> shell exploded on Sunday, blowing out the walls and windows of the boy's home in <LOCATION> Obihiro </LOCATION> in northern <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>. The boy _ 9-year-old <PERSON> Takahiro </PERSON> <PERSON> Shibuya </PERSON> _ died from head injuries, and his father, <PERSON> Satomi </PERSON>, 38, was injured in the stomach and one hand when fragments of the shell hit him as he was walking outside the home. Policeman <PERSON> Shinobu </PERSON> <PERSON> Kusakabe </PERSON> said the boy had kept the rusty 5-by-2 inch shell in his toy box since October. It not known where the boy found the shell.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880502-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-02-88 0020EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-NewChocolate     05-02 0228</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-New Chocolate,0235</SECOND>
<HEAD>New Chocolate Doesn't Melt In Heat</HEAD>
<DATELINE>COLUMBUS, Ohio (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A new chocolate that wo n't melt in 90-degree temperatures has been developed in the high-technology kitchens of the Columbus-based <ORGANIZATION> Battelle </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Memorial </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION>, a spokesman said. Food technologists at <PERSON> Battelle </PERSON>'s laboratory in <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Switzerland </LOCATION>, are licensing rights to the new chocolate formulation, said laboratory spokesman <PERSON> Bernard </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Vollerin </PERSON>. `` Chocolate should melt in your mouth at approximately 37 degrees Celsius -LRB- 98.6 degrees Fahrenheit -RRB- but it should not melt or become fluid at outside temperatures at the same level,'' he said. The development would be a boon to candy distributors, who can not deliver chocolate during warm weather without expensive refrigerated trucks, and it could keep chocolate sales steady through the summertime and in hot-weather areas. <PERSON> Vollerin </PERSON> said consumers should not notice any difference in appearance or taste. There's no secret ingredient other than `` some traces of natural compounds,'' <PERSON> Vollerin </PERSON> said. `` It's the way we put them in. That's the secret. The process has been patented and licensed to a Japanese company for marketing in the Orient, and negotiations are under way for the licensing of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and European rights, <PERSON> Vollerin </PERSON> said. If all goes well, test marketing could begin next year, he said. <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION>'s food technology program also has developed new cookie-baking techniques that spare heat-sensitive fillings such as fresh fruit, nuts or chocolate chips, he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880502-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-02-88 0038EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-TestBanTest     05-02 0588</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Test Ban Test,0603</SECOND>
<HEAD>Soviet Scientists Leave U.S. Assured Test Ban Treaty Is
Cheat-Proof</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TOM GARDNER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>RENO, Nev. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Soviet scientists toasted their <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> colleagues and then headed home after recording simulated low-yield nuclear bomb blasts that both sides said showed cheating on a test ban treaty could be detected. The successful weekend experiments in the <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION> desert and similar ones last September in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> used delicate seismographs to detect minuscule shock waves from the explosions of 10 - and 15-ton charges of dynamite, a fraction of the strength of most nuclear weapons tests, from as far as 400 miles away The experiments are expected to show that `` any chances for cheating are about excluded'' under a test ban, <PERSON> Evgeni </PERSON> <PERSON> Velikhov </PERSON>, vice president of the <ORGANIZATION> Soviet </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION> and an adviser to Soviet leader <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>, said Sunday. After seismometers detected the first detonation of 10 tons of <ORGANIZATION> TNT </ORGANIZATION> on Friday, <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Archambeau </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Colorado-Boulder </ORGANIZATION> geophysics professor, said the experiments mean `` that we can more accurately gauge the numbers and distribution of stations that will be required to verify a low-threshold treaty.'' <PERSON> Velikhov </PERSON>, wearing a sweatshirt that said, `` Arms are for Hugs,'' called a comprehensive test ban `` very important. It is extremely important to stop the arms race.'' The Soviets offered toast with vodka and beer on May Day, a communist holiday. Scientists said they would turn to learning how to determine the difference between nuclear weapons detonations and industrial explosions by conducting more tests. <PERSON> Archambeau </PERSON>, head of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Resources </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>'s seismic monitoring advisory committee, said he hoped both governments would sponsor further experiments The multimillion-dollar experiments in this country and in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> were conducted by the council, a private group, and by the <ORGANIZATION> Soviet </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sciences </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Archambeau </PERSON> and other scientists in the project had been concerned that after the success of last year's research near the Soviet test site, efforts here might be thwarted by <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION>'s fault-riddled geology, which soaks up sound waves He said he was relieved by the success of Saturday's final test. `` This is quite a strong signal. It's highly valuable,'' he said after a 15-ton explosion 100 miles east of <LOCATION> Carson </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> on Saturday sent seismic needles quivering at the joint U.S.-Soviet monitoring station in <LOCATION> Deep </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Springs </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, 210 miles away. On Friday, 10 tons of <ORGANIZATION> TNT </ORGANIZATION> were detonated beneath the desert 100 miles north of <PERSON> Reno </PERSON> and another 10-ton shot was set off 50 miles south of the <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION> Test Site. They were monitored at the joint station in Deep Springs, midway between <PERSON> Reno </PERSON> and <LOCATION> Las </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vegas </LOCATION>, and at two permanent <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> installations closer to the Test Site 110 miles north of <LOCATION> Las </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vegas </LOCATION>, where all <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> underground nuclear detonations are conducted. One hundred forty additional temporary monitoring stations were set up across <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION>. Friday's first test barely moved the seismometers at <LOCATION> Deep </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Springs </LOCATION> and the second was not detected, but both showed up on more sensitive digital instruments, said <PERSON> Holly </PERSON> <PERSON> Eissler </PERSON>, research geophysicist at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Diego </LOCATION>. She noted that a limited nuclear test ban treaty passed by the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> last week forbids detonations larger than one kiloton, 100 times stronger than the 10-ton TNT blast. <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Cochran </PERSON>, senior staff scientist for the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> and a co-director of the test ban verification project, said the council had spent about $ 3.5 million on the effort since it began two years ago. He estimated the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> group's share of the weekend's testing at about $ 300,000
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880502-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-02-88 0031EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-WeatherpageWeather 2ndLd-Writethru a0820thesecondset
05-02 0824</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Weatherpage Weather, 2nd Ld-Writethru, a0820,0842</SECOND>
<HEAD>May Day Snowstorm Over Parts Of The Rockies</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: SUBS 1st graf with one graf and grafs 6-7 ``In eastern'' with
two grafs to UPDATE with a second death and CORRECT that two facing
pileups were involved sted one.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 A wintry storm moved into <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION> Sunday, piling snow up to a foot deep in and west of the <LOCATION> Rockies </LOCATION>, whipping winds to 60 mph and triggering a blinding dust storm blamed for two fatal traffic pileups. Strong thunderstorms struck parts of <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>. Northwestern Wyoming got 8 inches of wet snow, closing the eastern and southern entrances to Yellowstone National Park in the morning. South of the park, 5 inches of snow was reported in <LOCATION> Moose </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, where wet snow accumulating on power lines caused some blackouts, the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Weather </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> said. Up to 14 inches of snow was reported in the mountains and foothills of south-central <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION>. Snow also was widespread over eastern sections of <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION> and northern <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION>. Parts of eastern <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION> got 5 inches of snow overnight. Up to 8 inches of snow was reported at <LOCATION> Tooele </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION>, with 7 inches at the Snowbird ski resort and 5 inches at <LOCATION> Alta </LOCATION>. In eastern <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION>, 50 mph winds spawned the dust storm, which dropped visibility to zero and caused the pileups on Interstate 70 near <LOCATION> Seibert </LOCATION> about 45 miles west of the <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> border, said <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Holmstedt </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Colorado </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Patrol </ORGANIZATION>. Two motorists were killed, and 17 people injured, authorities said. The incidents occurred in east - and westbound lanesof I-70 between <PERSON> Limon </PERSON> and <PERSON> Seibert </PERSON> Nearly 45 miles of the highway was closed for more than two hours before visibility improved. High trucks and trailers were banned from Interstate 80 at <LOCATION> Wendover </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION>, because of strong, gusty wind. <ORGANIZATION> Bryce </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Canyon </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION>, reported gusts near 60 mph. In <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, winds gusted to 80 mph in <LOCATION> Ruidoso </LOCATION> and 60 mph in <LOCATION> Albuquerque </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Ruidoso </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> Sierra </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Blanca </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Regional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airport </ORGANIZATION> was closed. The northern and central high Plains also had gusty wind, with gusts to more than 50 mph throughout the Dakotas and gusts to 60 mph in central <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION> at <LOCATION> Gunnison </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Trinidad </LOCATION>. A day before, the difference in pressure between that storm and a high-pressure front 700 miles off the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Coast </LOCATION> generated 65 mph wind in <LOCATION> Southern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, generating waves that destroyed a municipal pier and stranded 1,400 tourists on <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Catalina </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION>. `` Whenever winds blow, it's due to a pressure difference, from high to low, just like water running downhill,'' said <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Grebe </PERSON> of the weather service. On Sunday, the body of a man believed to be a boater who jumped from a disabled craft in wind-tossed seas Saturday washed ashore near the <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> suburb of <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Segundo </LOCATION>, said <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> Lifeguard Sgt. <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Hargett </PERSON>. Another man knocked off a boat five miles north of <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Catalina </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> on Saturday was missing Sunday, said <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> Petty Officer <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Embleton </PERSON>. When the wind slammed 12-foot surf into the <LOCATION> Redondo </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION> Municipal Pier on Saturday, a 155-foot section of the pier collapsed, said city spokesman <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Graham </PERSON>. A restaurant also was damaged. An estimated 78,000 utility customers in <LOCATION> Southern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> had power outages Saturday and some 1,400 tourists had to spend the night on <LOCATION> Catalina </LOCATION> when the wind closed <LOCATION> Avalon </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Harbor </LOCATION> to the boats that ferry island visitors. Hotels were full so tourists were sent to a local church. The pastor farmed people out to parishioners, a high school gym and a movie theater, said <PERSON> Donna </PERSON> <PERSON> Hunsucker </PERSON>, administrative assistant at the <ORGANIZATION> Chamber </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION>. Boats resumed running Sunday, she said. Strong thunderstorms rumbled across <LOCATION> Southern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> and the Keys on Sunday, with three-quarter-inch hail and gusts up to 63 mph reported near Marathon and Conch Key. Elsewhere, central <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> had light showers. <PERSON> Monroe </PERSON>, <LOCATION> La. </LOCATION>, posted a record low Sunday with a cool 43 degrees, four degrees off the former mark set in 1965. Temperatures around the nation at 3 p.m. EDT ranged from 27 degrees at <ORGANIZATION> Yellowstone </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Park </ORGANIZATION> to 86 at <LOCATION> McAllen </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>. The low for the day was 10 degrees at <LOCATION> Truckee </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>. For Monday, occasionally heavy snow was forecast over central and eastern <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION>, south-central <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION> and the northern <ORGANIZATION> Colorado </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rockies </ORGANIZATION> Scattered showers and thunderstorms were forecast from the <LOCATION> northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Plains </LOCATION> through <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> into northwestern <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>. Widespread showers were forecast across the northern <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Coast </LOCATION> region, with scattered showers across northern <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION>. Highs only in the 30s were predicted across much of <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION>; in the 40s and 50s from the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Northwest </LOCATION> to the northern and central Rockies, and across central and northern <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>; in the 80s from central and eastern <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> through the lower <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Coast </LOCATION> region to southern <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>, and in the <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION> deserts; in the mid 90s to 100 across inland areas of southern <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>; and in the 60s or 70s across much of the rest of the nation.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880502-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-02-88 0045EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--Korea-Strike     05-02 0129</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Korea-Strike,0132</SECOND>
<HEAD>South Korea's No. 2 Car Plant Opens After 19-Day Strike</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SEOUL, South Korea (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The nation's second largest automaker today resumed operations after a 19-day strike in which workers won a nearly 20 percent increase in their salaries. The automaker, <ORGANIZATION> Daewoo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Motor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, is a 50-50 joint venture with <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Motors </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Daewoo </ORGANIZATION>'s 6,000 employees returned to work after accepting an 11-point settlement that gave them, among other things, a 19.6-percent pay increase and some additional fringe benefits, company officials said. They said the settlement increased the workers' monthly average salary to $ 565, including fringe benefits. <ORGANIZATION> Daewoo </ORGANIZATION>'s assembly line workers went on strike April 12 and to demand a 26.6-percent pay increase. <ORGANIZATION> Daewoo </ORGANIZATION> reached agreement with labor leaders over the weekend.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880502-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-02-88 0046EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-NoCharisma Bjt   05-02 0866</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-No Charisma, Bjt,860</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHINGTON WIRE: On Lack of Charisma, Dukakis and Bush Sound Alike</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP News Analysis</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TOM RAUM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 When <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> says seven years of charisma in the White House was enough, <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> would be the first to acknowledge it's probably not a reference to him. `` You do n't know how hard it's been to keep my own charisma in check these past seven years,'' the vice president tells audiences, tongue in cheek. On one subject, both <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> front-runner, and <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, who locked up the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> presidential nomination earlier this week, seem to agree. Both concede they are viewed as bland. And both insist it's fine with them. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>: `` What's wrong with being a boring sort of guy?'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>: `` Maybe it's time for a little competence.'' Are <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> really that boring? No, say the candidates themselves, not really. Both say their wives do n't think so, either. Yes, says <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Sears </PERSON>, a political consultant who ran President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s 1976 campaign and the early part of his 1980 race. `` It's true at the moment. They're both saying they're managers. That sounds pretty boring. We're looking for leaders here,'' he said. In defense of <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Sears </ORGANIZATION> adds: `` In terms of one's ability to compel deep feeling, the vice presidency is not an office in which you can gain that.'' In defense of <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Beckel </PERSON>, who was <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> Mondale </PERSON>'s campaign manager in 1984, says: `` It's a good example of a guy who understands his limitations and maximizes his assets He did n't try to make himself something he was n't.'' Neither <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> nor <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> has been able to evoke the kind of passionate responses from audiences that, say, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> or Democratic contender <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> do regularly. The <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> governor has been known to scratch jokes out of prepared speeches. The vice president has a half dozen standard jokes he uses regularly, but sometimes he muffs the delivery. Both are widely viewed as pragmatists, not ideologues. And when talking about themselves, the two men likely to be rivals in the fall sound remarkably alike. `` People are not looking for a lot of pizazz out there. They're looking for someone who's stable, whose had some experience, a record of achievement, has values they can identify with ... Running for president is serious business.'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>? No, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. Here's <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>: `` The fact is, after seven years of charisma, it's time for accomplishment and a record.'' Even when the candidates are insisting they really are n't all that boring, they sound alike. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>: `` My wife does n't think that -LRB- I'm boring -RRB-. I do n't know about Mrs. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, what she thinks. Or Mrs. <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>. ... I think that I'm a scintillating kind of guy.'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>: `` People say I'm not a passionate guy. ... My wife thinks I'm passionate and so does <ORGANIZATION> Playgirl </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Magazine </ORGANIZATION>.'' The publication had put the <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> governor on a list of best-dressed males. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> also is fond of pointing out that the word charisma, like himself, is of Greek ancestry. He does n't usually elaborate, but the implication is that there must be a little charisma in him. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> says he does n't plan to change his image. He recently told reporters he wo n't `` kind of suddenly get my hair colored and dance up and down in a miniskirt or do something to show that I've got a lot of jazz out there and drop a bunch of one-liners.'' <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Schneider </PERSON>, a political analyst with the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Enterprise </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION>, says both candidates are indeed boring _ and should leave it at that. Efforts to appear otherwise come off as sounding silly, <PERSON> Schneider </PERSON> suggested. `` Boring politicians do pretty well in this country,'' he said. `` <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> was pretty boring. <PERSON> Jimmy </PERSON> <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> was boring. <PERSON> Lyndon </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> seemed boring, at least in comparison with <PERSON> Barry </PERSON> <PERSON> Goldwater </PERSON>. And we elected <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> with a lot of reservations. He was too interesting. But he was elected because of our desperate desire for a change.'' With two boring candidates running, that personality trait should cancel itself out, <PERSON> Schneider </PERSON> suggested. But are they equally boring? `` Between them? <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> is a little more boring,'' <PERSON> Schneider </PERSON> said. `` <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has more of a tendency to say foolish things. In that sense, he's not boring. But the only way for him to make himself not boring is by making himself into a joke.'' <PERSON> Stuart </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Eizenstat </PERSON>, who was <PERSON> Carter </PERSON>'s domestic affairs adviser, said a presidential candidate with charisma is `` the exception rather than the rule.'' `` In 1976, <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> and <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> were not exactly accused of being charismatic candidates,'' <PERSON> Eizenstat </PERSON> said. However, <PERSON> Eizenstat </PERSON> said it may be too early to rule out the charisma factor entirely. `` Candidates take on a certain charisma, which will come out when they're anointed as nominees of their parties, they may not have now. All the hoopla of national conventions invests people with a certain halo effect.'' In any event, <PERSON> Eizenstat </PERSON> said he personally does n't find either <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> or <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> boring. Dull, perhaps, but not boring. `` I do n't, because what turns me on are public policy issues and people who are interested in discussing them.''
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 EDITOR'S NOTE: <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Raum </PERSON> is covering the presidential campaign for <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880502-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-02-88 0053EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lites     05-02 0602</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lites,0624</SECOND>
<HEAD>On The Light Side</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SELINSGROVE, Pa. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The stakes in world-champion banana-split making got a bit higher _ er, longer _ thanks to the determined residents of this central <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> town. Using 33,000 bananas, 2,500 gallons of ice cream and 150 gallons of chocolate syrup, <LOCATION> Selinsgrove </LOCATION> made a 4.5-mile-long banana split Saturday in a bid to regain a place in the Guinness Book of World Records. `` It's something for the town to say, ` When we work together, anything is possible,''' said <PERSON> Kelly </PERSON> <PERSON> Stoops </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Selinsgrove </LOCATION> teacher who organized the event to raise money for a community development organization. About 24,000 people standing and sitting in front of one-foot sections of the 12.6 million-calorie dessert dug in at 4:30 p.m. Each paid $ 2 for the privilege. `` It was getting pretty soupy after a while,'' said <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Linn </PERSON> of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION>, who was standing near the middle of the giant split, made in three sections up Market Street through the center of this town of 5,500 residents. Selinsgrove set the record for the world's longest banana spilt in 1982 with a 1.5-mile concoction, winning a place in the 1983 Guinness Book. But in 1983, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> high school students created a banana split a tenth of a mile longer. <LOCATION> Selinsgrove </LOCATION> on Saturday outdid <ORGANIZATION> Zeta </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Beta </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sorority </ORGANIZATION> at <ORGANIZATION> Bowling </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Green </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, which created a 4-mile banana split in 1985, organizers said. A surveying company would verify the length of the banana split and send the results to <ORGANIZATION> Guinness </ORGANIZATION>. Six hundred captains each produced 40-foot sections of the dessert, made in a cardboard trough from empty carpet rolls. In addition to the ice cream, bananas and chocolate sauce, organizers sprinkled on 600 pounds of chopped nuts, 150 gallons each of strawberries and pineapples and 24,000 cherries.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>ATLANTIC CITY, N.J. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 If all the quarters given away to casino customers here last year were combined in one roll, the package would stretch from <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> to the outskirts of <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Louis </LOCATION>, more than 917 miles. Customers received more than $ 218.4 million, or 10.9 million pounds, in complimentary quarters last year just for walking in the doors of the city's 12 casinos, according to financial reports the gaming halls filed with the state <ORGANIZATION> Casino </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Control </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION>. That translates into more than 873.6 million quarters _ more quarters than the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Mint made in 1978, the year the first casino opened here. `` No wonder we ca n't get change people,'' one casino official, speaking on condition of anonymity, quipped, referring to the industry's difficulty in finding enough workers to sell coins on casino floors.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>COLLINSVILLE, Ill. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 They tasted, tossed, and generally touted horseradish at an outdoor bash in this Southern <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> community to honor the tangy root. `` We grow one-half to two-thirds of the world's crop in this area. We think that's something,'' said <PERSON> Craig </PERSON> <PERSON> Keller </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> Tri-County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Vegetable </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Growers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, which sponsored the first International Horseradish Festival on Saturday to promote <LOCATION> Madison </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> as the horseradish capital of the world. Both horseradish connoisseurs and novices strolled past the food booths and displays in a <LOCATION> Collinsville </LOCATION> park. `` I love horseradish,'' said <PERSON> Melvin </PERSON> <PERSON> Lytle </PERSON>, 67, of <LOCATION> Edwardsville </LOCATION>. `` It clears the sinuses. And they say it's an aphrodisiac.'' `` Honey and horseradish makes a good cough medicine,'' added his wife, <PERSON> Helen </PERSON>, 66. In addition to tasting recipes made with horseradish, some people participated in the Horseradish Olympics _ which included a root toss, where contestants tried to lob foot-long horseradish roots farther than anyone else, and a hot dog eating contest. The dogs, of course, were slathered with horseradish.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880502-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-02-88 0056EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-LaRoucheChairman Bjt   05-02 0622</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-LaRouche Chairman, Bjt,0641</SECOND>
<HEAD>LaRouche Supporter Takes Over Stripped-Down County Chairmanship</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RUTH RENDON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>HOUSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A supporter of extremist <PERSON> Lyndon </PERSON> <PERSON> LaRouche </PERSON> is taking over the nation's second-largest local <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, but concerned party members have stripped the post of most of its power and even its office. <PERSON> Claude </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> stunned <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>' <LOCATION> Harris </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> by winning election March 8 as chairman. <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>, who was scheduled to take office today, blames his lack of clout within the party on `` Democratic elitists'' who he says are more concerned about their status than the party itself. `` There are some people in the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> that are n't being very democratic,'' he said The group's bylaws were changed by the party's 34-member steering committee three days after the election, when <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> narrowly defeated incumbent <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Veselka </PERSON>. The unanimous final approval of the bylaw changes came April 15 by the 664-member executive committee, made up of precinct chairmen. <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> tried to thwart the vote, but a state district judge denied his request for a temporary restraining order. Embarrassed <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> leaders say <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> was elected to the 2-year-old post by accident because of his common name and the race's obscurity. <PERSON> Veselka </PERSON>, an attorney, was unable to campaign in the weeks before the election because he was involved in a trial outside <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> says he won because he worked hard pushing <PERSON> LaRouche </PERSON> issues that `` finally hit a nerve.'' His election shocked party leaders, who face working under a chairman associated since 1975 with a perennial presidential candidate who claims the Queen of <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> is involved in drug trafficking and has called for a quarantine of all AIDS patients. <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>, whom <PERSON> Veselka </PERSON> defeated in 1986, said his sole occupation is working for <PERSON> LaRouche </PERSON>. He staffs solicitation booths the LaRouche organization sponsors at airports and other public places. <LOCATION> Harris </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, which includes <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION>, trails only <ORGANIZATION> Illinois </ORGANIZATION>' Cook County, which includes <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>, in size as an election district <LOCATION> Harris </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> will send more delegates to the Democratic National Convention this summer than 17 states. When <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> assumes his limited duties, he'll have no office at the party's headquarters. Quarters that <PERSON> Veselka </PERSON> used are occupied by another staffer, said <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Ramsey </PERSON>, the party's executive director. `` Mr. <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> will have access to any records he needs. He just wo n't be able to come in and tell staffers what to do,'' <PERSON> Ramsey </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Scott </PERSON> <PERSON> Ramsey </PERSON>, <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>' attorney, says the new bylaws prohibit his client from performing his statutory duties, such as record-keeping and handling the party's primary. But <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Webb </PERSON>, the party's general counsel, counters that the chairman's duties under the law are to handle the county primary, which involves accepting applications and certifying the candidates. Under the old rules, the chairman raised funds for Democratic candidates in the district and largely determined how that money was spent. Now only the party's secretary and treasurer have access to the money. `` Not very many people are going to give money if <PERSON> Claude </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> is in control,'' <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Ramsey </PERSON> said. He said <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> might not be able to deliver the votes or might not want to support a mainstream Democrat. <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> also will have little power to set priorities for the local party. `` He will carry the title and preside over the meetings, but he wo n't set the agenda. He ca n't stray from the agenda, either,'' <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Ramsey </PERSON> said. For now, <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> said he is n't sure of his plans except that he wants to bring more people into the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> during his term. His attorney says they have n't ruled out a possible return to court. Despite the squabbles, <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> has done one good thing, says <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Stanley </PERSON>, a past county chairwoman: `` He has united the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Harris </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION>.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880502-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-02-88 0110EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-LaRoucheCandidate     05-02 0642</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-LaRouche Candidate,0667</SECOND>
<HEAD>LaRouche Victory In Pa. Congressional Primary Stuns Democrats</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-LaRouche Chairman, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JAN GEHORSAM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PHILADELPHIA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> officials in suburban <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION>'s 5th Congressional District are stuck with a candidate they do n't want: a backer of political extremist <PERSON> Lyndon </PERSON> <PERSON> LaRouche </PERSON>. One official said party leaders were focusing on other campaigns when <PERSON> LaRouche </PERSON> backer <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Hadley </PERSON> defeated <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Houchins </PERSON>, a little-known candidate endorsed by the party, in Tuesday's congressional primary <PERSON> Hadley </PERSON>, a sales representative from <LOCATION> Drexel </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION>, will face Rep. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Schulze </PERSON>, a well-financed Republican, in November's election. <PERSON> Houchins </PERSON> has blamed his loss on the Democratic organization in <LOCATION> Montgomery </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Chester </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Delaware </LOCATION> counties, which make up the district, and on voters, whom he accused of ignorance. `` <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Manson </PERSON> could run for office and get elected,'' he said Friday. `` The county committees did not take <PERSON> LaRouche </PERSON> seriously, the area leaders did not take him seriously and the committee people did not take him seriously. ... So ultimately the voter did n't take the LaRouche threat seriously.'' Party leaders agreed. `` Of course, it's our party's responsibility and obviously we failed,'' said <ORGANIZATION> Delaware </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> Chairwoman <PERSON> Dianne </PERSON> <PERSON> Merlino </PERSON>. `` We should have exercised our maximum effort to promote <PERSON> Houchins </PERSON>.'' On Friday, <ORGANIZATION> Montgomery </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Philip </PERSON> <PERSON> Berg </PERSON> called for <PERSON> Hadley </PERSON> to step down to let a `` legitimate candidate run.'' <PERSON> Berg </PERSON> said he would rather see <PERSON> Schulze </PERSON> win. `` It would be better than having a LaRouchian,'' he said. <PERSON> LaRouche </PERSON>, a perennial presidential candidate, has promoted a quarantine of AIDS victims and the colonization of Mars, and has charged that <PERSON> Queen </PERSON> <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> II </PERSON> of <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> is a drug dealer. He is on trial in <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> with six aides and five of his political groups on charges they conspired to obstruct a federal grand jury investigation. The grand jury was probing allegations that more than $ 1 million was raised for <PERSON> LaRouche </PERSON>'s 1984 presidential campaign through credit card and loan fraud In an interview with the <ORGANIZATION> Delaware </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Hadley </PERSON> said he openly identified himself with <PERSON> LaRouche </PERSON> and won the election because of voters' dissatisfaction with mainstream Democratic candidates. But <PERSON> Berg </PERSON> and other Democrats contend that <PERSON> Hadley </PERSON> concealed the affiliation. `` I do n't believe there was anything indicating he was a LaRouchian published by him. I think he was more surprised than other people that he even won,'' <PERSON> Berg </PERSON> said. `` No one could even get a hold of him. I never saw him, I never met him, he was never at any meetings held by the <ORGANIZATION> Montgomery </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>. I never received one phone call from him, not one piece of literature from him.'' <PERSON> Hadley </PERSON> said he was in the streets daily `` talking face-to-face with people, talking about why they're trying to railroad <PERSON> LaRouche </PERSON>, why they're trying to keep him out of politics.'' `` I told them what we've got to do to get the economy in shape. ... That's what people are interested in.'' Ms. <PERSON> Merlino </PERSON> said <PERSON> Hadley </PERSON> won because he was first on the ballot, the candidates' names were similar and the victor made misrepresentations. `` I did n't think the problem would be so big that we could n't overcome it in <LOCATION> Delaware </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>,'' she said `` I should have done more. I should have been more aware.'' <LOCATION> Delaware </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> was the only one of the three that carried <PERSON> Houchins </PERSON>. Overall, <PERSON> Hadley </PERSON> had 10,667 votes, or 53 percent, and <PERSON> Houchins </PERSON> had 9,298 votes, or 47 percent, with 99 percent of the vote counted. Democrats in the Republican stronghold were busy backing candidates in other races, Ms. <PERSON> Merlino </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Berg </PERSON> and Ms. <PERSON> Merlino </PERSON> said their committees will not back him. State party Chairman <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Yatch </PERSON> said he and his aides are studying what measures to take in the election. <PERSON> Dana </PERSON> <PERSON> Scanlon </PERSON>, a spokeswoman for the LaRouche for President campaign, said <PERSON> Hadley </PERSON> is unlikely to receive much funding but will get help from LaRouche supporters.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880502-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-02-88 0110EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-IndianEducation Bjt   05-02 0616</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Indian Education, Bjt,600</SECOND>
<HEAD>Government Giving Indian Children Weak Education, Report Says</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GUY DARST</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 American Indian children educated in schools run by the federal government score worse on standardized tests than 79 percent of students nationwide, a new report says. The report is the first such compilation of test scores at schools run by the <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Indian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Affairs </ORGANIZATION>, an <ORGANIZATION> Interior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> official said. It was compiled by the bureau itself and has been released to tribes and others for comment. The report blames many shortcomings on a lack of leadership _ sometimes actual lack of leaders, as shown by a 33 percent turnover rate among principals, use of acting directors of the <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Indian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Education </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Programs </ORGANIZATION> for five out of the past six years and 11 vacancies on the 40-person headquarters staff. Bureaucratic turf battles also contribute to the problems, it says. `` Collegiality, the act of putting aside vested interests and working for the good of the whole, is found in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s best educational institutions but is often missing in the <ORGANIZATION> BIA </ORGANIZATION> system, where administrators are sometimes more interested in shoring up and expanding their administrative domain,'' the report says. The 260-page document asks tribal leaders, school boards and others to consider an `` effective schools'' strategy including steps to hold <ORGANIZATION> BIA </ORGANIZATION> educators more accountable for their students' performance It also suggests expanded authority to waive Indian hiring preferences, and loans to educate prospective teachers that would be increasingly forgiven the longer the teachers stayed at work in a bureau school. The report says pressure to hire <LOCATION> Indian </LOCATION> teachers _ now 41 percent of the teaching staff _ means some are poorly trained and `` deficient in the basic reading, writing and mathematical skills they were expected to teach.'' Some of those checked for the study had failed state certification tests, which all teachers now are supposed to pass. `` Matters of budgets, personnel, facilities and other administrative tasks, rather than education itself, preoccupy too many principals,'' the report added. `` Some <ORGANIZATION> BIA </ORGANIZATION> teachers seem to begin with the expectation that their students will do poorly. ... Too many responsible officials in <ORGANIZATION> BIA </ORGANIZATION> education do not seek to lead but merely get by from day to day.'' The bureau educates 37,917 Indian students, about 10 percen of the nation's young Indians. About 30 percent attend boarding schools and about 30 percent are in schools run by tribes under contract with the bureau. The best schools barely approach average national scores. Overall the bureau's students ranked in the 21st percentile on standardized tests _ that is, they did worse than 79 percent of all children taking the test. Only one of the bureau's district offices had a single grade above the national median, the 50th percentile. The 27 second-graders of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Pueblo </LOCATION> district averaged in the 52nd percentile. Tribal leaders and school boards have had access to their own scores before, but the report provides the first opportunity for one tribe or area to compare its standing with another, said an <ORGANIZATION> Interior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> official who discussed the document on condition that he not be identified. The worst scores were recorded in the <LOCATION> Chinle </LOCATION> district of <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION>, where 202 fourth-graders and 154 fifth-graders, mostly from rural <LOCATION> Navajo </LOCATION> families, wound up in the 7th percentile. The report highlights some success stories, but at the same time says the positive developments need to be pointed out more effectively to other schools and areas. For instance, the Dilcon and <LOCATION> Chuska </LOCATION> boarding schools for <LOCATION> Navajo </LOCATION> in the <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Defiance </LOCATION> district use a special curriculum requiring students to write something every day. Their eighth-graders do well, with <PERSON> Dilcon </PERSON>'s two months ahead of the national average.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880502-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-02-88 0117EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-MathMiscalculation     05-02 0318</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Math Miscalculation,0328</SECOND>
<HEAD>Error Causes Change In Winner Of Statewide Math Contest</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NORMAL, Ill. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A numerical error led officials to crown the wrong team winner of a state high school math contest, but a rival suburban <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> school reclaimed the honors after a recount, officials said. Officials of the <ORGANIZATION> Illinois </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Teachers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mathematics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Math </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Contest </ORGANIZATION> considered the appeal of <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Trier </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> High </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION>'s coach and found he was right Final score: New Trier 992, <LOCATION> Evanston </LOCATION> Township High 979. A clerk tabulating the scores gave New Trier of <LOCATION> Winnetka </LOCATION> only three points in one event Saturday when it should have received 33 in the competition at <ORGANIZATION> Illinois </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. `` We regret it was announced that <LOCATION> Evanston </LOCATION> was the first-place winner,'' said <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Shilgalis </PERSON>, a contest official. `` It's really nice to win, it's gratifying to win, but winning is n't why you do it,'' said <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Benson </PERSON>, coach of <LOCATION> Evanston </LOCATION>'s math club. `` It's not football.'' Some <LOCATION> Evanston </LOCATION> students were disappointed. `` We all started cheering and jumping up and down,'' senior <PERSON> Catherine </PERSON> <PERSON> Epp </PERSON> said Sunday. `` We were in first place for the first time, which was really fantastic.'' Still, <PERSON> Epp </PERSON>, the individual winner in the geometry event, said, `` I think that having fun and learning good math is a lot more important than whether we win state.'' Saturday's win brought New Trier its eighth consecutive crown in the contest and also pitted two schools whose rivalry is fierce _ in the classroom and the playing field. <PERSON> Rhoad </PERSON> called this year's event the `` battle of the giants'' because <LOCATION> Evanston </LOCATION> and New Trier placed high in a national written math contest in March. Of the 14,000 schools entered, <LOCATION> Evanston </LOCATION> placed first, a Canadian school placed second and <PERSON> New </PERSON> <PERSON> Trier </PERSON> was third. At the weekend contest here, students competed in 13 events, including a relay in which each member of a four-student team worked on one-fourth of the problem.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880502-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-02-88 0119EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Jackson Bjt   05-02 0641</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Jackson, Bjt,670</SECOND>
<HEAD>Jackson: Campaign a Success, With or Without Nomination</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RITA BEAMISH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>DUBLIN, Ohio (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> gazed from a balcony over the sunny, riverfront lawn party where a well-dressed crowd sipped wine. `` No one ever told us it was going to be easy,'' <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> shouted to the 300 partygoers. But the candidate wanted his predominately black audience to remember something: `` When you consider what we came from, we do n't have the ability to get tired `` This is not just <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>. This is from the back of the bus in <LOCATION> Montgomery </LOCATION> to being within one of three to being the next president.'' It is a theme that has become increasingly prominent for <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> in recent days after his heavy losses in the <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> primaries. He is sounding a twofold message as he trails <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> down the home stretch of the primary season: First, he vows to fight on to win the nomination and raise issues. But second, <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> highlights the historic aspect of his candidacy, casting it in terms that spell victory whether he wins or loses the nomination. In the face of a new poll showing <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> with a 40-point lead in <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, whose primary is Tuesday, <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> appeared to be dwelling increasingly on this over the weekend. By pointing to his unquestioned successes and the wide acceptance his candidacy has received, <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> paints his effort as an outgrowth of the civil rights struggles of the 1960s and another step on the road to full equality for blacks. He contrasts his bid for the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> with the grim days more than two decades ago when people died fighting for just the right to vote. So as he campaigns across <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, he tells church crowds and rallies that his candidacy is far more than a journey from the <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> caucuses in February to this summer's Democratic convention in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>. It's a journey that began when blacks began rebelling in <LOCATION> Montgomery </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ala. </LOCATION>, against being forced to ride in the back of the bus, he said. And it's a mission that must be carried forward by people like the well-heeled crowd at the estate of physician <PERSON> Alfred </PERSON> <PERSON> Jefferson </PERSON> in this <LOCATION> Columbus </LOCATION> suburb, he told them. He said reporters are asking him after his string of losses, `` How can you go on?'' <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s answer: `` Do you know how far we've come? ... We're almost to the top of the hill We've come too far. We must press forward.'' The crowd laughed with acknowledgement when he pointed to the strides they have made financially, saying, `` Most of us standing here today are one generation out of chitlins.'' To dramatize his point, <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> related as he often does the story of his humble <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> beginnings _ born to a teenage mother and the married man next door, living in a house with wallpaper for warmth not decoration, waiting to eat Thanksgiving dinner until his mother came home with leftovers from the table of the white people whose meal she had prepared. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> sometimes seems amazed himself as he tells the story. `` When I win, there are no more impossible dreams,'' he often says. But in keeping with his portrayal of his candidacy as part of a historical continuum, he told his <LOCATION> Dublin </LOCATION> audience that he expects them to carry on the movement. He said they must `` translate this movement'' into demands for blacks in positions of authority at banks and universities and corporations where there are still barriers, as well as in government. `` When I shake apples from the tree, you must pick up these apples and make them into jelly and take them to the market,'' he said. `` To have continuity in our struggle we must establish a heritage of success in the government for all coming generations.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880502-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-02-88 0143EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FarmScene     05-02 0695</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Farm Scene,690</SECOND>
<HEAD>Soviet Grain Goal Questioned</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DON KENDALL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Farm Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>'s grain production target for 1988 is unrealistic, despite <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>'s well-publicized `` intensive technology program'' to boost agricultural output, according to an <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> analyst. Christian J. Foster of the department's <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> said this year's Soviet target is 235 million metric tons, including wheat, corn and other grains. `` This total is unrealistic, even though it is only 2 million tons above the 1987 goal,'' <PERSON> Foster </PERSON> said. `` Soviet plans continue to call for unlikely grain output goals of 250 million to 255 million tons by 1990 and 260 million to 280 million by 1995.'' A major part of Soviet strategy is the intensive technology program, which means greater use of better-quality fertilizers, pesticides, seed and farm equipment. It also means use of these production items should be concentrated on the best soils. <PERSON> Foster </PERSON> said that in 1986 almost 73 percent of the area planted to wheat and other `` small'' grains was fertilized, a record. The application rate per hectare -LRB- 2.47 acres -RRB- was up 20 percent from 1985 and nearly 70 percent from 1980. `` Moreover, the fertilizers, which have often benefited mainly weeds, have been increasingly supplemented by herbicides and other plant protection agents -LRB- PPAs -RRB-,'' he said in the May issue of Agricultural Outlook magazine. `` To compensate for lower quality domestically produced PPAs, emphasis has been placed on imports of more potent chemicals from the West.'' By 1990, <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> plans to use intensive technology on as much as 50 million hectares, `` despite the fact that constraints to broadening the program are already appearing in its slowing rate of expansion,'' <PERSON> Foster </PERSON> said. The area for intensive technology rose about 10 million hectares in 1986 from less than 19 million hectares in 1985, he said. But the increase slowed to about 6 million hectares in 1987 and is planned to increase only 4 million in 1988. `` Furthermore, the additional grain production from intensive technology in 1987 was a reported 25 million tons, only 1 million more than in 1986,'' <PERSON> Foster </PERSON> said. `` This is in spite of a reported 20 percent increase from 1986 in the area under the program.'' Last year's Soviet grain output was 211.3 million tons, up only 1 percent from 1986, but <PERSON> Foster </PERSON> noted that it was the first time ever that two consecutive grain crops of more than 200 million tons had been harvested. Bad weather hurt the quality of 1987 grain, although the average yield of 1.83 tons per hectare was second only to the record 1.85 tons harvested in 1978. A metric ton is about 2,205 pounds. <PERSON> Foster </PERSON> said the 1988 winter grain crop, which includes winter wheat, rye and barley, was planted under favorable conditions last fall and is thought to have suffered below-average winterkill. `` A concern of Soviet farmers in the New Lands this spring is the lack of high-quality seed for spring grain,'' he said. `` The quality of seed stocks was below average in the areas with harvesting problems last year _ the Urals region, the <LOCATION> Volga </LOCATION> region, northern <LOCATION> Kazakhstan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Siberia </LOCATION> and the Non-Black Soil Zone.'' A chronic problem for Soviet planners _ partly related to climate and geography _ is the production of milling wheat, the high-quality grain desired for bread, pasta and other food products. `` Their problems persist despite plans calling for self-sufficiency in food grains, and despite wheat production twice the size of food needs,'' <PERSON> Foster </PERSON> said. As a result, the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> has looked to foreign sources for high-quality wheat to augment its own vast harvests of lower quality grain. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, particularly since subsidized prices have been available under <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION>'s Export Enhancement Program, or <ORGANIZATION> EEP </ORGANIZATION>, has been the main beneficiary. In the international marketing year that will end June 30, the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> will import around 22 million tons of wheat, with the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> providing about half, up from less than 1 percent just two years ago. `` The expected increase in the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> share of Soviet wheat imports in 1987-88 likely will be at the expense of other primary suppliers _ <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> EEC </ORGANIZATION> -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> European </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Community </ORGANIZATION> -RRB-, <LOCATION> Argentina </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Foster </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880502-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-02-88 0158EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-People-HerbigResigns     05-02 0318</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-People-Herbig Resigns,0326</SECOND>
<HEAD>Detroit Symphony Orchestra Conductor Quits, Cites Contract
Violations</HEAD>
<DATELINE>DETROIT (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Gunther </PERSON> <PERSON> Herbig </PERSON> said he planned to resign as conductor of the <ORGANIZATION> Detroit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Symphony </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Orchestra </ORGANIZATION> because of numerous violations of his contract, a newspaper reported today. <PERSON> Herbig </PERSON>, the orchestra's conductor since 1984, told musicians about his plans during intermission of Saturday night's concert. On Sunday, he declined to discuss his resignation, effective when his contract expires in 1990, The <ORGANIZATION> Detroit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> said. Several musicians told newspaper that <PERSON> Herbig </PERSON> cited several complaints, many of them related to the orchestra's financial troubles. Among <PERSON> Herbig </PERSON>'s complaints, they said, were cancellation of a 1989-90 tour of the Far East; refusal to guarantee frequent domestic tours; reduction of the number of guaranteed musicians from 103 to 97; and refusal to promise the orchestra will move in 1989-90 from <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Auditorium </ORGANIZATION> to Orchestra Hall. `` <PERSON> Herbig </PERSON> told us that virtually the only thing they honored in the contract was payment, and that even that was sometimes late,'' said <PERSON> Maxim </PERSON> <PERSON> Janowsky </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> DSO </ORGANIZATION> bassist. Orchestra board Chairman <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> McCarthy </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> said in a statement Sunday that the orchestra's financial troubles caused the board to fail to meet some terms of <PERSON> Herbig </PERSON>'s contract. But it was the board's `` intention and hope to honor Maestro <PERSON> Herbig </PERSON>'s contract in every detail,'' the statement said. <PERSON> Herbig </PERSON> said he would complete a second three-year term under a contract he signed in 1987, leaving 28 months to work with management in finding a replacement. The orchestra in November, while musicians were in the midst of a 12-week work stoppage, announced a deficit of $ 1.4 million for the 1986-87 season, raising its cumulative deficit to $ 4.1 million against an annual budget of $ 14 million. A deficit reduction campaign has been launched. But The News, citing an unidentified source close to the orchestra, said musicians were told last week an additional deficit of $ 400,000 was anticipated for this season.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880502-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-02-88 0225EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-DunneAllegations     05-02 0518</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Dunne Allegations,0535</SECOND>
<HEAD>Cook County Board President Denies Jobs-for-Sex Allegation</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Note contents.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By LINDSEY TANNER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CHICAGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
