<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880821-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-21-88 2323EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-FireDeaths 5thLd-Writethru a0735 08-21 0515</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Fire Deaths, 5th Ld-Writethru, a0735,0527</SECOND>
<HEAD>Seven Die in Social Club Basement Blaze</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Deletes outdated 4th graf `Traces of...'</NOTE>
<HEAD>LaserPhotos NY48, NY53</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MEG THOMAS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Fire gutted a packed <LOCATION> Bronx </LOCATION> social club Sunday afternoon, killing seven people and injuring more than 30, and firefighters' efforts were hampered by screaming people trying to get to relatives, authorities said. `` It was sheer panic,'' said firefighter <PERSON> Dennis </PERSON> <PERSON> Fennell </PERSON>. The inside of the basement club was burned out and `` it looked like people tried to claw out all of the walls,'' he said. Fire marshals were testing for the presence of flammable liquids, said <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Mulligan </PERSON>, a spokesman for the Fire Department. The origin was considered suspicious because of the fire spread so quickly, he said. The streets were filled with screaming people who tried to pull equipment from firefighters and get to their friends, <PERSON> Fennell </PERSON> said. `` There were people running around crazy ...,'' said firefighter <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Kisonas </PERSON>. `` When we went to go do our job, people were trying to fight the tools away from us. It was crazy. They wanted to pull us one way and then another way trying to get us to the people trapped in the basement.'' Firefighters said five bodies were found in the club, some still in chairs. Another person died shortly after the fire at a hospital and the seventh died about eight hours later at <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital-Cornell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>, a spokeswoman said. Most of the injured, including six firefighters and two <ORGANIZATION> Emergency </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> technicians, were suffering from smoke inhalation and were taken to hospitals. <PERSON> Mulligan </PERSON> described the club as about 50 feet by 75 feet with 7-foot ceilings. Between 60 and 100 people were packed inside. Mayor <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> I. </PERSON> <PERSON> Koch </PERSON>, who toured the blaze aftermath, described the club as a `` rabbit warren.'' `` If people were running for their lives, they'd run down blind alleys and be trapped,'' said <PERSON> Koch </PERSON>, who described the space as confined and made up of small, partitioned cubicles. `` It's clear that it should have never been opened in the first place,'' he said of the club. <PERSON> Philip </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Burns </PERSON>, a deputy fire chief, said the private bar known to neighbors as `` the hole'' was illegal because bars in basements are prohibited and the exits were inadequate. A resident of the area, <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Govia </PERSON>, 25, said the club operated 24 hours a day. `` Police often raided the place,'' he said. Authorities said they have trouble keeping illegal clubs closed because there are hundreds in the city. The fire was reported about 12:30 p.m. and firefighters were `` met by hysterical civilians streaming up the staircase,'' <PERSON> Mulligan </PERSON> said. `` One firefighter told me he literally had to fight his way down the stairs,'' <PERSON> Mulligan </PERSON> said. Most escaped through the club's front door and narrow staircase, but others were able to break through a wall near the back. A second door on the side of the club was locked, <PERSON> Mulligan </PERSON> said. Eighteen engine companies, nine ladder units and about 150 firefighters brought the five-alarm blaze under control about 3:15 p.m., <PERSON> Mulligan </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880821-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-21-88 2357EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Sudan-Floods     08-21 0871</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Sudan-Floods,0898</SECOND>
<HEAD>Flood Victims Still Isolated, Unaided</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</NOTE>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DIDRIKKE SCHANCHE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>KHARTOUM, Sudan (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Omar </PERSON> <PERSON> Abakr </PERSON> <PERSON> Idris </PERSON> removes his shoes before wading through the knee-deep fetid water left behind by the worst rains on record in this desert capital. Each step across what used to be a dusty dirt road unleashes an overpowering stench. The vast expanse of water is contaminated with excrement from overflowing pit latrines and from dogs, goats and donkeys living in the village. <PERSON> Idris </PERSON>' village of <LOCATION> Mayo </LOCATION>, a shantytown of about 50,000 on <LOCATION> Khartoum </LOCATION>'s southeastern fringe, was among the areas hardest hit by the deluge Aug. 4-5. `` We are struggling with life here now,'' said <PERSON> Idris </PERSON>, 48. `` We are without water, without food, without homes, without transport, without anything.'' The storm dumped 8.4 inches of rain in 14 hours, six times the amount that fell in all of 1987. For the past 30 years, annual rainfall has not exceeded 4.3 inches. At least 58 people died, most as their mud huts collapsed on them. Up to 1.5 million people _ more than a third of <LOCATION> Khartoum </LOCATION>'s nearly 4 million inhabitants _ were left homeless and more than 150,000 dwellings were destroyed, according to government figures Most vulnerable were the people living in <LOCATION> Mayo </LOCATION> and 22 other squatter camps around <LOCATION> Khartoum </LOCATION>. The illegal settlements hold 500,000 to 700,000 people who fled <LOCATION> Sudan </LOCATION>'s southern civil war and widespread drought. The vast camps of mud huts and burlap-covered shacks are desperately poor and occupy the worst land. The Moslem-dominated government, at war with the Christian and animist south, long has tried to discourage further settlement in the squatter areas. It denies the areas any social services and forbids the displaced people living there from digging wells. Official neglect threatened to leave most of the displaced people beyond the reach of international relief after the storm. The government initially refused aid but ultimately relented in the face of the sheer magnitude of the disaster and the threat of epidemics sweeping from the camps. Many relief workers still worry the unplanned areas will receive less than their fair share of government aid. `` There will be a natural built-in bias towards planned areas,'' said <PERSON> Bryan </PERSON> <PERSON> Wannop </PERSON>, resident representative of the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> development program which is helping coordinate non-government relief. Emergency aid has yet to reach most of those affected by the flood, many of whom live in areas isolated by stagnant lakes which have nowhere to drain. Nearly all the mud huts in <LOCATION> Marzuk </LOCATION>, an unplanned area of about 15,000 people in <LOCATION> Omdurman </LOCATION> across the Nile river from <LOCATION> Khartoum </LOCATION>, were destroyed or damaged by the rains. The people said they needed plastic sheeting and tents. `` They are very important because the children now are sleeping outside,'' said <PERSON> Abdullahim </PERSON> <PERSON> Kody </PERSON>, a resident. `` Once I had two rooms,'' <PERSON> Kody </PERSON> said, pointing to a mound of hardening mud. `` Unfortunately, they have fallen down.'' <PERSON> Kody </PERSON>, <PERSON> Idris </PERSON> and others interviewed nearly two weeks after the disaster said they received no help from anyone and were desperately in need of food, shelter, and medicine. Health officials are predicitng deadly epidemics of water-borne diseases as people cut off from drinking water supplies are forced to drink from the pools left behind by the rainstorm. Thousands already have developed diarrhea. Malaria and typhoid also are on the rise, and cholera is an imminent risk. Dr. <PERSON> Nicholas </PERSON> <PERSON> Ward </PERSON>, a world health organization expert on diarrheal diseases an immunization, predicted 400,000 people, mostly children, will get sick and at least 4,000 will die. Without treatment, as many as 40,000 will perish, <PERSON> Ward </PERSON> estimated. But he said emergency health clinics established in response to the disaster should forestall the worst. Diarrhea kills the young and the weak primarily through dehydration and is treatable with a simple rehydrating mixture of salt, sugar and water. But lack of fresh water supplies make even this basic therapy difficult. Sudanese authorities blame insufficient supplies for delays in granting relief. More than 2,000 tons of tents, blankets, medicine, plastic sheeting, food and other items have poured into <LOCATION> Sudan </LOCATION>, but officials have said it is about a tenth of what is needed. Disorganization and the dilapidated infrastructure of this North African nation of 23 million also have hampererd the relief operation. The rains knocked out telephones, disrupting coordination between the army-run operation and non-governmental agencies. The downpour also created mud bogs of roads already strewn with potholes from years of neglect. Another threat comes from the swollen <LOCATION> Nile </LOCATION> <LOCATION> river </LOCATION>, which already has swamped some island villages and is brimming near street level in the capital. Officials are not sure when or whether the river might overflow into the city. A pair of British cartographers working with government surveyors has begun work on a contour map which will help determine how much higher the Nile would have to rise before spilling into <LOCATION> Khartoum </LOCATION>'s streets. In the meantime, relief efforts will continue. And people like <PERSON> Osman </PERSON> <PERSON> Geragandi </PERSON> <PERSON> Koko </PERSON>, who lives in a settlement built on a garbage pile in north <LOCATION> Khartoum </LOCATION>, will do what they must to find food and shelter. `` Previously there was drought and we got through that,'' he said. `` We hope to get through this too.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880821-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-21-88 2357EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Korea-AmericansDeported     08-21 0285</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Korea-Americans Deported,0291</SECOND>
<HEAD>Two American Activists Arrested In South Korea</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SEOUL, South Korea (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Two American activists who addressed a student rally last week were arrested and ordered expelled for taking part in radical political meetings, the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> said today. The two were identified as <PERSON> Susan </PERSON> <PERSON> Bailey </PERSON>, 31, a secretary in the history department at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Maryland </ORGANIZATION>, and <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Scheiner </PERSON>, 37, a <LOCATION> White </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Plains </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION>, computer salesman. A <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> consular officer said Ms. <PERSON> Bailey </PERSON> and <PERSON> Scheiner </PERSON> were arrested late Saturday leaving a meeting with other activitists. Both had tourist visas that prohibited them from any political activity, said a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> official who spoke on condition of anonymity. The two were held overnight by <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION> Immigration authorities and ordered to leave the country `` for activities inconsistent with their visa status.'' There were no available flights Sunday, so <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials said the two spent Sunday night at the airport and would leave today. Both Ms. <PERSON> Bailey </PERSON> and <PERSON> Scheiner </PERSON> spoke to a rally at <ORGANIZATION> Yonsei </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> Aug. 15 for some 3,000 students assembled to march to the border truce site of <LOCATION> Panmunjom </LOCATION> for talks with North Korean student delegates on reuniting the divided <LOCATION> Korean </LOCATION> peninsula. The government banned the march and riot police arrested 200 students. The Americans said they were here at the invitation of the <ORGANIZATION> Korean </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Peace </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> to attend an international peace conference. Ms. <PERSON> Bailey </PERSON> said that she represented the People's <ORGANIZATION> Anti-War </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mobilization </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Movement </ORGANIZATION> based in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION>, which she described as `` a guerilla movement which wants the government to spend money on social causes, not defense.'' <PERSON> Scheiner </PERSON> said he represented a group called <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mobilization </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Survival </ORGANIZATION> which wanted <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military forces pulled out of all foreign nations.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880821-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-21-88 2358EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Mexico-Illegals     08-21 0924</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Mexico-Illegals,0958</SECOND>
<HEAD>Small Mexican Town Still Source Of Illegal Aliens In United States</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By CAM ROSSIE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SANTA MARIA DEL ORO, Mexico (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 When the new <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> immigration law went into effect last year, this town in <LOCATION> Durango </LOCATION> cattle country 500 miles south of <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Paso </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, feared for its future. For nearly half a century, it had supplied Mexicans who worked legally or illegally in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and sent home the dollars that helped keep the town going. But the catastrophe <ORGANIZATION> Santa </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Maria </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> del </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Oro </ORGANIZATION> braced for 14 months ago has n't happened. Thousands of dollars still pour in every day, in money orders sent by residents' relatives working, most of them illegally, in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. Mayor <PERSON> Epifanio </PERSON> <PERSON> Carreon </PERSON> had feared the flow of dollars would dry up and, worse, hundreds of young men would come home looking for jobs that do n't exist. `` We would have seen at least some economic affects of the law by now, but everything is totally normal,'' <PERSON> Carreon </PERSON> says now. `` The dollar continues being the most important source of income in this region,'' said <PERSON> Roberto </PERSON> <PERSON> Acosta </PERSON>, assistant manager of <ORGANIZATION> Banco </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Internacional </ORGANIZATION>, the only bank in the area people that cashes dollar checks. `` Some people returned because of fear before they knew what was going to happen with the law. But now things are back to normal.'' One young man in town said, however, he's waiting to see what happens with the law _ the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Immigration Control and Reform Act _ before he attempts his first crossing. `` If it were n't for the law I'd already be in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>,'' said <PERSON> Rocky </PERSON> <PERSON> Rocha </PERSON>, 18, who just graduated from a technical school here. He said two of his brothers already there had applied for amnesty under the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> law and fear they'll lose out if they harbor him as an illegal alien. `` If my brothers will let me, I'll go in spite of the law,'' said <PERSON> Rocha </PERSON>. `` Here you work so hard and you do n't make much.'' <PERSON> Santa </PERSON> <PERSON> Maria </PERSON> <PERSON> del </PERSON> <PERSON> Oro </PERSON> has supplied the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> labor market with a steady stream of workers since World War II. Many residents went to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> as farm workers under the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> bracero program of 1942, said Mayor <PERSON> Carreon </PERSON>. By now, some have gained <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> citizenship or legal residency. By the time the program was dropped in 1964, many local residents had grown accustomed to having a steady job and earning dollars. Besides, said <PERSON> Carreon </PERSON>, the local gold and mining operations were winding down and there was n't much left to do here but work in the fields or raise cattle. The only major employer around these days is a lumber company, which has about 300 workers. <PERSON> Miguel </PERSON> <PERSON> Angel </PERSON> <PERSON> Salinas </PERSON>, the municipal clerk, estimates that more than 30 percent of the town's 14,000 people still go back and forth to jobs in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. Authorities estimate the percentage of people on surrounding farms and ranches with relatives working in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> is as high or even higher. <PERSON> Carreon </PERSON> said the steady flow of dollars _ as much as $ 60,000 a week _ has helped <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Maria </LOCATION> <LOCATION> del </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Oro </LOCATION> weather <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>'s 6-year-old economic crisis. Indeed, by Mexican standards <PERSON> Santa </PERSON> <PERSON> Maria </PERSON> <PERSON> del </PERSON> <PERSON> Oro </PERSON> is well off. The main streets are filled with late-model <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and Mexican pickup trucks, many bearing <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> license plates. There are no beggars on the streets. Many of the homes and businesses were financed with dollars. Residents and public officials here say the law has helped those who hve been in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> for a long time and wanted to stay there. <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Sanchez </PERSON> returned several years ago and bought a butcher shop with the money he earned as an undocumented worker in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>. His brother, a <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> butcher, stayed and has applied for amnesty, the provision of the law allowing foreigners who meet certain requirements to seek legal residency. `` He feels a lot safer knowing that when he leaves the house -LRB- in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> -RRB- he'll return,'' <PERSON> Sanchez </PERSON> said. Illegal aliens caught in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> most often are deported immediately. For others who did n't qualify for amnesty under the law or just did n't bother to apply, it's business as usual: a sundown trek across the border. `` We'll stay as long as there's work. When there's not we'll come back crying,'' said <PERSON> Jesus </PERSON> <PERSON> Chavez </PERSON>, 29, who has worked in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> as an undocumented worker for a decade `` Right now the work is there waiting for us,'' said <PERSON> Chavez </PERSON>, one of three brothers working without documents at a <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> construction company. <PERSON> Chavez </PERSON>, home on vacation, said the $ 21 an hour he earns makes the risk of crossing as an illegal alien worthwhile. Similar work in <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> probably would pay him about $ 12 a day. `` Right now it -LRB- the law -RRB- has n't affected us at all,'' said <PERSON> Luis </PERSON> <PERSON> Chavez </PERSON>, <PERSON> Jesus </PERSON>' 18-year-old brother who began working illegally in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> when he was 14. The toughest provision of the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> law went into effect this past June 1, making it illegal for most employers to knowingly hire undocumented workers. The law calls for stiff fines and even jail sentences for violators. Agricultural workers now in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> have been given an extension to Dec. 1 to get their papers in order or leave. Although crossing the border without legal documents is the risky part, those who've worked in the same job in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> since before 1982 do n't have to show employers their documents.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880821-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-21-88 2359EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Gulf-Analysis     08-21 0859</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Gulf-Analysis,0886</SECOND>
<HEAD>Iran And Iraq Count Cost Of Eight-Year War</HEAD>
<BYLINE>AP News Analysis</BYLINE>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By ED BLANCHE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NICOSIA, Cyprus (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 As the smoke clears in the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> war with a U.N.-sponsored truce, <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> are counting the cost of a conflict that killed an estimated 1 million people but ended with no victor. Peace talks scheduled to start Thursday in <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> are likely to be long and tough. <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> are ancient enemies, and eight years of war have only deepened old hatreds. Both countries, bled by the war, face mammoth tasks in rebuilding their economies despite the oil wealth they used to bankroll their military machines. <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> also faces the prospect of political turmoil as hardliners such as Interior Minister <PERSON> Ali </PERSON> <PERSON> Akbar </PERSON> <PERSON> Mohtashemi </PERSON>, a vociferous critic of `` defeatist'' diplomatic efforts to end the war; and more pragmatic leaders, particularly Parliament Speaker <PERSON> Hashemi </PERSON> <PERSON> Rafsanjani </PERSON>, battle for supremacy. <PERSON> Rafsanjani </PERSON>, considered the most powerful figure in <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> after <PERSON> Ayatollah </PERSON> <PERSON> Ruhollah </PERSON> <PERSON> Khomeini </PERSON>, is widely seen as the man who engineered <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION>'s unconditional acceptance of the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> cease-fire resolution last month when he realized <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'s military machine was weakening after a string of battlefield defeats this year. <PERSON> Khomeini </PERSON> endorsed <PERSON> Rafsanjani </PERSON>'s decision, widely seen as the speaker's biggest political gamble, although the ailing patriarch stressed that for him, ending the war was `` worse than drinking poison.'' So far, no senior <LOCATION> Iranian </LOCATION> leader has publicly challenged that decision, which most Iranians have welcomed after eight years of appalling human loss. But <PERSON> Rafsanjani </PERSON>, who also has made clear he seeks to end <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'s isolation, faces an increasingly strong array of radicals led by <PERSON> Mohtashemi </PERSON> and the prosecutor-general, <PERSON> Mohammad </PERSON> <PERSON> Khoeinihia </PERSON>, leader of the militants who seized the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION> in November 1979, who oppose his pragmatist policies They consider his efforts to end a war he clearly believed <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> could never win flies in the face of the revolution's aim of spreading Islamic fundamentalism. Analysts say the internal struggle for supremacy after <PERSON> Khomeini </PERSON>, which has been swelling over the last two years as the patriarch's health deteriorated, has only been intensified by <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION>'s acceptance of the On the ground, the two belligerents wound up virtually where they started in September 1980, when <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> invaded <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>, the map unchanged after one of the longest conventional wars this century. <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>'s President <PERSON> Saddam </PERSON> <PERSON> Hussein </PERSON>, whose 1980 invasion is seen by military analysts a major blunder, has emerged at least for now more solidly entrenched in power in <LOCATION> Baghdad </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>, which spent as much as $ 10 billion a year on its war effort, is as much as $ 85 billion in debt, according to Western economists. That makes it one of the world's biggest debtor nations. The war cost <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> an estimated $ 400 billion. Although it still has about $ 5 billion in foreign reserves, its economy is in tatters, its industry, particularly its oil installations, pounded by <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>'s powerful air force. <PERSON> Khomeini </PERSON>, whose hatred of <PERSON> Hussein </PERSON> turned the war into a bloody vendetta, remains the unchallenged authority in <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>. But his surprise decision last month to accept the cease-fire, despite his exhortations to `` fight to the last drop of blood'' to topple the <LOCATION> Iraqi </LOCATION> leader, has dented the 88-year-old religious patriarch's credibility. The Iraqis, armed with superior weaponry and technology, won something simply by surviving <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'s human-wave offensives and wearing down the numerically superior Iranians, although <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> used outlawed chemical weapons and hammered <LOCATION> Iranian </LOCATION> cities with bombers and missiles. <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>, virtually friendless and starved of the arsenal of high-tech weaponry the Iraqis employed, can claim that it repelled the invaders and fought them to a standstill. The war undoubtedly helped cement <PERSON> Khomeini </PERSON>'s 1979 Islamic revolution. Opponents of the cleric-dominated <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION> regime charge that the fundamentalists deliberately perpetuated the conflict to consolidate the infant republic and <PERSON> Khomeini </PERSON>'s stern brand of Islam. With an end to the war now a possibility, the Arab countries of the oil-rich gulf who were caught in the crossfire, and the rest of the Moslem world, are heaving a collective sigh of relief. But an end to the war will have strategic repercussions far beyond the gulf. <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> fears that <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>, which has participated to some extent in every Arab-Israeli war over the last four decades, eventually will turn its combat-hardened military machine again on the Jewish state. Defense Minister <PERSON> Yitzhak </PERSON> <PERSON> Rabin </PERSON> said last month that although he did not see any danger of an imminent <LOCATION> Iraqi </LOCATION> attack, the military buildup by <PERSON> Arab </PERSON> states spawned by the gulf war could be used against <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>. With the gulf war out of the way, the <PERSON> Arab </PERSON> states are expected to refocus their attention on efforts to solve the older <LOCATION> Arab-Israeli </LOCATION> conflict. If <PERSON> Rafsanjani </PERSON> and his supporters, such as Foreign Minister <PERSON> Ali </PERSON> <PERSON> Akbar </PERSON> <PERSON> Velayati </PERSON>, succeed in out-maneuvering their hard-line opponents in <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'s relations with the West are likely to improve. That, in turn, has raised hopes that <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> can be persuaded to use its influence with pro-Iranian Shiite extremists in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> to free foreign hostages, including nine Americans.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Ed </PERSON> <PERSON> Blanche </PERSON>, based in <LOCATION> Nicosia </LOCATION>, is The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>' Middle East news editor.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880821-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-21-88 2359EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Philippines-Aquino     08-21 0791</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Philippines-Aquino,0814</SECOND>
<HEAD>Five Years After Assassination, Doubts Remain</HEAD>
<HEAD>AP News Analysis</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT H. REID</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MANILA, Philippines (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Five years after dissident leader <PERSON> Benigno </PERSON> <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON> was killed, the slaying remains unsolved and his goal of a peaceful, stable democracy unfulfilled in the turbulent country now governed by his widow. On Aug. 21, 1983, the senator stepped from a <ORGANIZATION> China </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> jet and into Philippine history, gunned down moments after returning from the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> to challenge President <PERSON> Ferdinand </PERSON> <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> for leadership of the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION>. The killing outraged the nation and emboldened a fragmented opposition, paving the way for the uprising that toppled <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> and propelled <PERSON> Corazon </PERSON> <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON> to the presidency on Feb. 25, 1986. Now, statues of `` Ninoy,'' the senator's nickname, stand in major cities, and the airport where he died bears his name. Mrs. <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON> has said repeatedly that if it were not for his death, she never would have risen to power. But the trial of 40 defendants charged in the assassination drags on nearly 16 months after it began, bogged down in a complex legal system. In September 1986, the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> voided acquittals handed down by a Marcos-era tribunal and ordered a retrial. The slow pace of the trial typifies the unfinished agenda of an administration made possible by the Aquino slaying. The political turbulence that made such a killing possible haunts the country. For many, the lofty hopes that <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON>' ouster alone would restore stability and prosperity have given way to frustration. `` Five years after <PERSON> Ninoy </PERSON>'s death, the <PERSON> Cory </PERSON> government has become the government it warned us against,'' wrote columnist <PERSON> Conrado </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Quiros </PERSON> in the <ORGANIZATION> Philippine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Globe </ORGANIZATION>, a frequent critic of the administration. Critics in the freewheeling <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION> press often ignore Mrs. <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON>'s accomplishments, preferring instead to hold her to the idealistic promises of justice, domestic peace and social reform she espoused. Despite the insurgency and right-wing coup plots, her administration drafted a new constitution, restored a bicameral legislature and held national and regional elections in its first two years. The administration reversed three years of economic decline and posted a 5.5 percent growth in the gross national product in its first full year. But for millions of Filipinos, more than 60 percent of whom live in poverty, the slow pace of change has done little to improve their daily lives. Inflation in the <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION> area, triggered by increases in prices of food and fuel, is approaching 10 percent. Allegations of continuing corruption have been raised not only by the press but by <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION> Archbishop <PERSON> Cardinal </PERSON> <PERSON> Jaime </PERSON> <PERSON> Sin </PERSON>, the country's best known cleric and an Aquino supporter. Communist rebels still wield power in rural areas, and urban guerrillas have escalated street assassinations in the capital itself. Right-wing `` death squads'' have retaliated with their own attacks against labor activists and suspected leftists. `` If the principal element of -LRB- <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON>'s -RRB- death was violence, it is only fitting that the people who were shocked by the incident and who felt sorry for the late senator should now shun violence and work to strengthen the rule of law,'' said The <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION> Bulletin in an editorial Sunday. `` Violence still stalks the land, because many do not respect the rule of law.'' Growing disaffection prompted Vice President <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Laurel </LOCATION> this month to accuse the administration of incompetence, failing to stem the rebellion and tolerating corruption on the scale of <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON>. Laurel called on Mrs. <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON> to resign and call new elections. Although Laurel's allegations were similar to those of some of Mrs. <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON>'s supporters, his charges won little public support, mostly because of the vice president's reputation as a political opportunist. `` But if -LRB- Laurel's -RRB- purpose was to jolt <PERSON> Cory </PERSON> <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON> into waking up from her dream presidency and facing the nightmare it has become for the Filipino people, then it certainly deserves a fair and just assessment,'' wrote columnist <PERSON> Nestor </PERSON> <PERSON> Mata </PERSON> in The <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION> Standard. Mrs. <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON>'s strongest supporters frequently dismiss criticism as attempts by her opponents to undermine her government. Pro-Aquino columnists claim the latest round of criticism is part of a right-wing plot to tarnish her reputation among the public. `` Under the Aquino regime, blame is immediately being heaped on faceless, nameless people who are ` out to destabilize the government,''' wrote columnist <PERSON> Ninez </PERSON> <PERSON> Cacho-Olivarez </PERSON> in the Philippine Daily Inquirer. `` It is the insecure and paranoid who see goblins at every turn.'' Meanwhile, Mrs. <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON> herself has become more isolated from the Philippine press. She rarely gives press conferences or interviews. Recently, the presidential palace banned `` ambush interviews,'' where reporters would shout questions at the president as she walked to her office every morning.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Reid </PERSON> is chief of <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> bureau in <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880821-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-21-88 0102EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-GuardWaitingList     08-21 0231</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Guard Waiting List,0235</SECOND>
<HEAD>National Guard Says No Proof Of Waiting List</HEAD>
<DATELINE>INDIANAPOLIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 No evidence existed of a waiting list to get into the <ORGANIZATION> Indiana </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> headquarters unit Sen. <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> joined in May 1969, Guard officials said Saturday. `` The existence or non-existence of any ` waiting list' as to HHD -LRB- <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>'s unit -RRB- can not be verified due to the fact that no such list can be found. Units were not required to maintain such lists if they were under-strength and personal memories do not recall such a list,'' two former top officers said in a statement released Saturday. The statement was from <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> N. </PERSON> <PERSON> Owens </PERSON>, former adjutant general of <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION>, and <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Moorhead </PERSON>, former commander of the 38th Infantry Division. Since <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> was nominated as the <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> vice presidential candidate, questions have been raised as to whether he used family influence to gain entrance to the Guard. <PERSON> Owens </PERSON> and <PERSON> Moorhead </PERSON> point out that records show the headquarters unit <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> joined had vacanies the month before, the month of and the month after the senator's enlistment. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>'s unit had an authorized strength of 138 soldiers but had 134 people in April, 132 in May and 133 in June, Brig. Gen. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Barney </PERSON>, deputy commander of the <ORGANIZATION> Indiana </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Area </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Command </ORGANIZATION>, said at a news conference Saturday. Neither <PERSON> Owens </PERSON> nor <PERSON> Moorhead </PERSON> could recall any inquiries on behalf of <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880821-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-21-88 0234EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-India-Quake 3rdLd-Writethru a0623 08-21 0428</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-India-Quake, 3rd Ld-Writethru, a0623,0440</SECOND>
<HEAD>100 Feared Dead In Earthquake That Hits Nepal And Eastern India</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Leads with 5 grafs to UPDATE with Indian officials measuring
quake at 6.5 on Richter scale. Pickup 5th graf pvs ``Press
Trust...''; SUBS final graf ``A quake...'' with one graf to ADD
background.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>KATMANDU, Nepal (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A strong earthquake hit the Himalayan kingdom of <LOCATION> Nepal </LOCATION> and parts of eastern <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> on Sunday morning, triggering landslides and collapsing buildings. First reports said 100 people may have died. <LOCATION> Nepal </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Geology </ORGANIZATION> said the earthquake struck at 4:54 a.m. -LRB- 7:09 p.m. EDT Saturday -RRB- and measured 5.7 on the <PERSON> Richter </PERSON> scale. The department said the quake was centered near <LOCATION> Udayapur </LOCATION>, a town near the Indian-Nepalese border and 100 miles southeast of <LOCATION> Katmandu </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Nepal </LOCATION>'s capital. Officials said the temblor lasted about 40 seconds. In <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Delhi </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Seismologoical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Observatory </ORGANIZATION> said the quake measured 6.5 on the <PERSON> Richter </PERSON> scale. The state-run <ORGANIZATION> Radio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nepal </ORGANIZATION> said at least 27 people were killed in the towns of <LOCATION> Bhaktapur </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Dharan </LOCATION> when they were buried by collapsing houses. <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Trust </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> India </ORGANIZATION> news agency said that in addition to 100 feared dead in <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Nepal </LOCATION>, 1,000 people were injured in the Indian states of <LOCATION> Bihar </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Sikkim </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bengal </LOCATION>. A Nepalese journalist in <LOCATION> Dharan </LOCATION>, 130 miles southeast of <LOCATION> Katmandu </LOCATION>, said by telephone that `` 20 people have already died. A large number of injured were being taken to local hospitals and a rescue operation is under way. Men of the <ORGANIZATION> Royal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nepal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>, police, social workers and other local inhabitants are taking part in the rescue operation.'' The journalist added that `` 90 percent of the house of <LOCATION> Vijapur </LOCATION> area of <LOCATION> Dharan </LOCATION> collapsed.'' Police reported seven people died in <LOCATION> Bhaktapur </LOCATION>, an ancient town seven miles east of <LOCATION> Katmandu </LOCATION>, while 20 others suffered injuries. The quake was also felt in the Indian capital of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Delhi </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Calcutta </LOCATION>, but there was no report of any casualties. One hard-hit Indian city was <LOCATION> Dharbhanga </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Bihar </LOCATION> state, where 14 children were believed killed when their school hostel collapsed. Dharbhanga, with a population of 200,000, is 550 miles east of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Delhi </LOCATION>. Several homes in the residential areas of <LOCATION> Dharbhanga </LOCATION> have collapsed, killing an unspecified number of people. The Richter scale is a gauge of energy released by an earthquake, as measured by ground motion recorded on a seismograph. Every increase of one number means the ground motion is 10 times greater. A quake of magnitude 5 can cause considerable damage in populated areas while one measuring 6 can cause severe damage.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880821-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-21-88 0402EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i BC-Lebanon-CarBomb 1stLd-Writethru a0625 08-21 0328</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Lebanon-Car Bomb, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0625,0337</SECOND>
<HEAD>Car Bomb Explodes In West Beirut; At Least 15 Wounded</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: UPDATES casualties, corrects name of district where bombing
occurred, no pickup. ADDS byline.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By RIMA SALAMEH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BEIRUT, Lebanon (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A car bomb exploded next to a Syrian army checkpoint in Moslem west <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> on Sunday morning, wounding at least 15 people, police said. Police said a Syrian soldier at the checkpoint was among the casualties. Most of the other wounded were Lebanese civilians, including women and children. A cream-colored Mercedes packed with 88 pounds of <ORGANIZATION> TNT </ORGANIZATION> blew up at 8:40 a.m. -LRB- 1:40 a.m. EDT -RRB-, only two yards from the checkpoint opposite a restaurant in the seaside <LOCATION> Raouche </LOCATION> district, police reported. At least eight cars parked nearby were destroyed. Police said the car had been parked Saturday evening near the restaurant which perches atop a cliff overlooking the <LOCATION> Mediterranean </LOCATION>. They could not determine who owned the Mercedes. Syrian troops, armed with rocket-propelled grenades and automatic rifles, sealed off the blast scene. <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION> ambulances evacuated the casualties as the <ORGANIZATION> Syrians </ORGANIZATION> fired in the air to make way for them. A police officer, speaking on condition of anonymity, said most of the wounded were passers-by. He said none of the restaurant's staff or customers was hurt The corniche where the bomb exploded is popular with Sunday morning strollers. Twisted metal and glass shards from a nearby six-story apartment building, the <PERSON> Mayfair </PERSON> casino, and another restaurant were strewn for 150 yards around the scene of the explosion. `` I heard a powerful explosion that hurled me several meters. Pieces of glass rained on me,'' said a 28-year-old casino employee who declined to be named. The car bombing was the eleventh in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> this year. The last car bomb blew up in west <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Cola </LOCATION> district July 22, killing seven people and wounding 48. More than 130,000 people have been killed in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>'s 13-year-old civil war between Moslems and Christians
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880821-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-21-88 0835EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i BC-India-NepalQuake 1stLd-Writethru a0626 08-21 0698</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-India-Nepal Quake, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0626,0711</SECOND>
<HEAD>Quake Along India-Nepal Border Reportedly Leaves More Than 200
Dead</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: New thruout to UPDATE with more deaths in Nepal, U.S.
Geological Survey reading, details and quotes. No Pickup.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>NEW DELHI, India (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A strong earthquake triggered landslides and destroyed houses in the mountainous India-Nepal border region early Sunday, killing at least 237 people and injuring more than 1,500, officials and news reports said. Seismologists said it was the deadliest earthquake to strike the Himalayan region since 1950. More than 100 people died when the quake rumbled through the eastern Indian state of <LOCATION> Bihar </LOCATION>, officials said. In <LOCATION> Nepal </LOCATION>, authorities said at least 137 people were dead. Officials in both countries predicted the death toll would rise after they received reports from remote areas which were hit harder. `` The tolls have come in only from urban areas,'' said V.K. <PERSON> Sharma </PERSON>, deputy secretary in the <LOCATION> Bihar </LOCATION> government. The temblor also jolted parts of northern <LOCATION> Bangladesh </LOCATION> and the capital of <LOCATION> Dhaka </LOCATION>, but there were no immediate reports of casualties or damage. Witnesses said windows and doors rattled, buildings cracked and people roused from their sleep ran screaming from their homes as objects tumbled from shelves and tables. `` My bed rattled, then it began swinging,'' said R.N. <PERSON> Rudra </PERSON>, a resident of <LOCATION> Patna </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> Bihar </LOCATION> capital. `` My dogs began barking and I rushed out of the house.'' At least 1,000 people were injured when the quake triggered landslides and house collapses in <LOCATION> Bihar </LOCATION> and the surrounding states of <LOCATION> Uttar </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Pradesh </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bengal </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Orissa </LOCATION>, all heavily populated, largely agricultural areas. The quake also was felt in <LOCATION> Sikkim </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Tripura </LOCATION>, located in the <LOCATION> Himalayan </LOCATION> <LOCATION> foothills </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Trust </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> India </ORGANIZATION> news agency said. In <LOCATION> Nepal </LOCATION>, a <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> official, <PERSON> Shailendra </PERSON> <PERSON> Kumar </PERSON> <PERSON> Upadhyaya </PERSON>, said more than 500 people were injured and thousands of houses collapsed from the quake's impact. `` Most of them -LRB- were -RRB- buried alive under collapsed houses,'' said <PERSON> Indra </PERSON> <PERSON> Shrestha </PERSON>, a social worker involved in the rescue operation in <LOCATION> Dharan </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bazar </LOCATION>, a township of about 100,000 people about 18 miles from the Indian border. <PERSON> Shrestha </PERSON> said rescue operations were being hampered by the monsoon rains, which hit the subcontinent in late June and usually last through September. Both countries were rushing emergency medical teams to the area. The Red Cross of <LOCATION> Nepal </LOCATION> issued urgent appeals for blood donations. In <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Bihar </LOCATION> state, communications with <PERSON> Darbhanga </PERSON>, which appeared to be the worst-hit area, were disrupted. The <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Trust </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> India </ORGANIZATION> said a school hostel in the town collapsed, killing at least 17 children. It said more bodies were feared buried under the debris. The quake damaged most of the houses in <LOCATION> Darbhanga </LOCATION>, the news agency said, quoting P.K. <PERSON> Patnaik </PERSON>, the top civil administrator in the district. Deaths were also reported in the neighboring towns of <PERSON> Munger </PERSON>, <PERSON> Keoti </PERSON> and <LOCATION> Narpatnagar </LOCATION>. The tremor also was felt in the eastern city of <LOCATION> Calcutta </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Trust </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> India </ORGANIZATION> said. There were no immediate reports of casualties but residents were quoted as saying windows of several homes vibrated and doors rattled. The <ORGANIZATION> Seismological </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Observatory </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Delhi </LOCATION> said the quake hit at 4:40 a.m. -LRB- 7:10 p.m. EDT Saturday -RRB- and was centered 40 to 50 miles northeast of the town of <LOCATION> Darbhanga </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Bihar </LOCATION> state, along the India-Nepal border. Observatory Director H.N. <PERSON> Srivastava </PERSON> said the quake measured 6.5 on the <PERSON> Richter </PERSON> scale. <PERSON> Srivastava </PERSON> said the quake lasted about one minute and aftershocks continued for about an hour. Seismologists warned aftershocks could continue for days. The <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Geological </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Survey </ORGANIZATION> said its initial seismograph readings placed the center of the quake 100 miles southeast of <LOCATION> Katmandu </LOCATION>, the capital of <LOCATION> Nepal </LOCATION>. Geological Survey monitors in <LOCATION> Golden </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Colo. </LOCATION>, recorded the earthquake at a preliminary magnitude of 6.7 on the <PERSON> Richter </PERSON> scale. The Richter scale gauges the energy released by an earthquake as measured by the ground motion recorded on a seismograph. A quake of magnitude 6 is capable of causing severe damage. Earthquakes are common in the Himalayan region. On Aug. 6 a quake of magnitude 7.3 shook the states of <LOCATION> Assam </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Manipur </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bengal </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Bihar </LOCATION>. Four people were killed. <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>'s worst earthquake was in 1950, when at least 30,000 people were killed in <LOCATION> Assam </LOCATION> state.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880821-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-21-88 1112EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-StateFairs-Drought Bjt   08-21 0817</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-State Fairs-Drought, Bjt,0846</SECOND>
<HEAD>Midways Open in Heat and Drought with Reeling Livestock, Melting
Ice Cream</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BERNARD SCHOENBURG</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Reeling livestock, sizzling sidewalks, ice cream through a straw _ these are a few of the added detractions at <LOCATION> Midwest </LOCATION> state fairs in a summer of killing heat and devastating drought. The fairs still feature Ferris wheels and funhouses, midway crowds of farmers in coveralls, girls in summer dresses, swarms of eager kids _ and traditional summer fare like corn on the cob, butterfly porkchop sandwiches, cotton candy and snow cones. But it's not the same. `` You do n't feel like eating,'' said <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Carlson </PERSON>, 66, of <LOCATION> Belvidere </LOCATION>, at the <ORGANIZATION> Illinois </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fair </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Springfield </LOCATION>. `` You want something, but you do n't.'' `` And the ice cream melts so fast,'' said his wife, <PERSON> Vi </PERSON>. The parched, hot summer that has turned city lawns brown and urbanites crabby has been a disaster for the <LOCATION> Midwest </LOCATION>, where growers grimly contemplate shriveled fields in autumn colors and deep cuts in projected grain harvests. At the fairgrounds, it makes for smaller produce and livestock _ and even some casualties. On Tuesday, when the temperature hit 102 degrees in <LOCATION> Indianapolis </LOCATION>, `` there were four fatals in the poultry division, and they were chickens,'' said <ORGANIZATION> Indiana </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fair </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Jeff </PERSON> <PERSON> Fisher </PERSON>. The owners, he noted, had left their entries in cars `` with the windows rolled up.'' By Thursday, five rabbits, two hogs and eight chickens died from the 97-degree heat, and livestock exhibitors were taking extra precautions to keep their animals comfortable in fairground barns. `` They're packing some down with ice, they're putting ice in front of fans to blow cool air,'' <PERSON> Fisher </PERSON> said. `` They're coming up with some ingenious ways to handle the heat stress.'' Although state fairs in the heartland traditionally draw millions of people each year, attendance is down somewhat this summer in some states. Fairgoers cheer or challenge in contests ranging from horse-racing to horseshoes, from husband-calling to hog-calling. They relax with rock music and symphonies; they scrutinize blue-ribbon displays of produce or livestock or home crafts; they ride the rides or line up to try the midway games of skill for pink pandas or funny hats; they inspect displays of new farm machinery. Some forget their troubles _ for the moment. `` It is a time that you can just go and forget all about the corn ... or other headaches that you have,'' said <PERSON> Dana </PERSON> <PERSON> Trimble </PERSON>, manager of a company that grows seed corn. Trimble plays drums and his farmer father, <PERSON> Gene </PERSON>, plays trumpet with a band of strolling players _ in clown gear _ at the <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> fairgrounds every year. `` People kind of want to get away from the farm. It's been a tough year,'' said <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Ward </PERSON>, board president for the <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION> fair. At the 18-day <ORGANIZATION> Ohio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fair </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Columbus </LOCATION>, which drew 3.5 million last year, attendance was down 7 percent for the first 12 days. Free tickets went out to some drought-stricken farmers to squelch rumors of cancellation. Missouri State Fair director <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Waddell </PERSON> said rain would help the state reach its goal of 350,000 visitors to the 11-day fair that ends Aug. 28 at <LOCATION> Sedalia </LOCATION> _ with air-conditioning for indoor activities. Relentless hot weather `` could hurt us, but it always seems to rain during the fair,'' <PERSON> Waddell </PERSON> said. Officials of the <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION> State Fair, which begins its 140th run Friday, said entries were down only slightly. `` We've set aside an area with a large tent and nice cool water and lemonade,'' said fair manager <PERSON> Bernie </PERSON> <PERSON> Lennon </PERSON>. `` It will be a little oasis.'' Officials at the <ORGANIZATION> Iowa </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fair </ORGANIZATION> were optimistic about attendance as the fair began its 11-day run Thursday. <PERSON> Butch </PERSON> <PERSON> Webb </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Wichita </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Kan. </LOCATION>, working in 104-degree heat Wednesday to prepare the fairgrounds, said that while this summer was `` a little bit extreme, I do n't remember setting up ... and not being covered with sweat.'' Spokeswoman <PERSON> Kathie </PERSON> <PERSON> Swift </PERSON> recalled a 108-degree reading at <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>'s 1983 fair The <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION> State Fair, which ended Aug. 14 at <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Allis </LOCATION>, drew 821,819 people _ down nearly 6 percent from last year. The <LOCATION> Kentucky </LOCATION> State Fair, which began Thursday, has 14 acres of air-conditioned space, said spokeswoman <PERSON> Brenda </PERSON> <PERSON> Frank </PERSON>, who predicted that teen-agers would be outdoors on the midway, whatever the weather. `` I do n't think they know how hot it is,'' she said. `` We wo n't tell them that. The too-hot, too-dry growing season was a disappointment for some produce exhibitors, who ruefully displayed unusually small contenders. <PERSON> Tony </PERSON> <PERSON> Misich </PERSON> of <PERSON> Clinton </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, said the potatoes, cucumbers, peppers and onions are the smallest from his garden he's shown in 10 years at the fair. `` This is sure disappointing _ you're not a-kiddin','' he said. Flowers also suffered. In <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION>, dahlia entries were down 50 percent, said fair spokeswoman <PERSON> Julie </PERSON> <PERSON> Carlson </PERSON>. `` Those flowers were not out there blooming,'' she said. `` We did have a lot of ribbons left over.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880821-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-21-88 1114EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Lebanon     08-21 0497</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Lebanon,0513</SECOND>
<HEAD>Car Bomb Wounds 18</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RIMA SALAMEH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BEIRUT, Lebanon (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A Mercedes packed with explosives blew up Sunday near a Syrian army checkpoint in Moslem west <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>, wounding 18 people and damaging cars and buildings, police said. No group immediately claimed of responsibility for the bombing in the seaside <LOCATION> Raouche </LOCATION> district, which came during a confrontation between pro-Syrian forces and hard-line pro-Israel Christians over the election of a new president. The cream-colored Mercedes, packed with an estimated 88 pounds of <ORGANIZATION> TNT </ORGANIZATION>, detonated at 8:40 a.m. only six feet from the checkpoint opposite a fish restaurant, police said. It was not known whether the bomb was detonated by remote control or a timing device. Police said three Syrian soldiers at the sandbagged checkpoint were among the casualties. Most of the other wounded were Lebanese civilians, including women and children. At least eight cars parked nearby were destroyed. The restaurant's glass front was blown in and windows in several neighboring buildings were shattered. Hours later, police said another car rigged with two rockets was safely defused in south <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>'s seaside <LOCATION> Ouzai </LOCATION> district. The car was parked in front of a bakery about 50 yards from a <LOCATION> Syrian </LOCATION> checkpoint. Police said the 107mm rockets were equipped with a timing device but did not say when they were set to go off. Police said the Merecedes that exploded was parked Saturday evening near the restaurant, atop a cliff overlooking the <LOCATION> Mediterranean </LOCATION> on a winding hilltop road popular with morning strollers. Several unexploded hand grenades and a mortar shell were found in the wreckage of the car, police said. `` Had they exploded, it would have been a real disaster,'' said a police officer at the scene who spoke on condition of anonymity. Nervous Syrian troops armed with rocket-propelled grenades and automatic rifles sealed off the blast scene, firing in the air to make room for <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION> ambulances rushing victims to hospitals. Glass shards from the Mayfair Casino and a string of oceanside fish restaurants littered a radius of 150 yards around the blast scene. `` I heard a powerful explosion that hurled me several meters. Pieces of glass rained on me,'' said a 28-year-old casino employee who declined to be named. The car bombing was the 11th in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> this year. By police count, 103 people have been killed and 353 wounded in the 10 previous car bombings. The attacks have been a byproduct of <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>'s 13-year-old civil war between Moslems and Christians, which has claimed more than 130,000 lives since it broke out in 1975. Fears of of a new outbreak of violence have been fueled by a presidential election deadlock that threatens to create a power vacuum after President <PERSON> Amin </PERSON> <PERSON> Gemayel </PERSON>'s six-year term in office expires Sept. 23. Christian hardliners backed by the Lebanese Forces, the nation's main civil war militia, prevented the election of Syrian-backed warlord <PERSON> Suleiman </PERSON> <PERSON> Franjieh </PERSON> Thursday by boycotting the election session in parliament, blocking a quorum for a vote
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880821-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-21-88 1116EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-Economy'sFuture Bjt   08-21 0764</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Economy's Future, Bjt,730</SECOND>
<HEAD>Economists Fear Economy May Turn Sour Next Year</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARTIN CRUTSINGER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 While the Republicans almost certainly will be blessed with a buoyant economy through Election Day, inflation and rising interest rates could shove the country into a recession as early as next spring, some economists are warning. A few analysts are forecasting a downturn for next year, and many who are n't say it will take luck to avoid a recession. Ironically, one of the things that has them worried is that economic growth has been so robust lately. A boom in <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> export sales has helped push the nation's unemployment rate down to 14-year lows The gross national product has expanded at an annual rate of 3.1 percent during the first six months of the year and there are indications that the economy may be growing even faster in the current July-September quarter. This rapid growth in demand is beginning to push up against supply restraints because of tight labor markets and high operating rates in many industries. This often translates into rising inflationary pressures as workers demand higher wages and businesses boost product prices. To nip inflation before it gets out of hand, the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reserve </ORGANIZATION> since late March has been pushing up interest rates to dampen demand. Earlier this month, it boosted its discount rate one-half percentage point to 6.5 percent. An increase in the discount rate is the most dramatic signal the central bank can send of its inflation-fighting intentions. That is what worries economists. Most recessions in this country are brought on by a credit squeeze. While the central bank does n't set out to create a downturn, it often finds it difficult to walk the fine line between dampening demand to cool inflationary pressures and tightening so much that a new recession is triggered `` The famous soft-landing for the economy has proven very difficult to manage in the past,'' said <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Dederick </PERSON>, chief economist for the <ORGANIZATION> Northern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Trust </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Dederick </PERSON> said he believed the current expansion, now in its peacetime record 69th month, will head into a new slump by the end of next year. Economists at the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> investment firm of <ORGANIZATION> Merrill </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lynch </ORGANIZATION> said in their latest forecast that growth could stall by next summer as higher interest rates and a loss of export momentum take their toll. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Wyss </PERSON>, an economist with <ORGANIZATION> Data </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Resources </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, said next spring will be the beginning of the danger time for the economy, given the six to nine month lag between increases in interest rates and their greatest impact on borrowing. `` We are forecasting that we will be able to avoid a recession next year and just have a slowdown, but the risk of a recession is certainly there if the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reserve </ORGANIZATION> gets carried away with tightening,'' he said. Under some optimistic scenarios, the expansion will moderate as higher interest rates cut into consumer and business demand, but strong export sales will provide a boost to manufacturing and prevent a recession. Another theory sees inflation rising at a faster clip, forcing the <ORGANIZATION> Fed </ORGANIZATION> to take stronger action which will send such key interest-rate sensitive sectors as housing into a tailspin, with the weakness then spreading to the rest of the economy. With mortgage rates climbing lately, the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Home </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Builders </ORGANIZATION> has already complained that the <ORGANIZATION> Fed </ORGANIZATION>'s credit tightening threatened to make the housing industry a `` sacrificial lamb.'' While the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration expressed its disappointment at the <ORGANIZATION> Fed </ORGANIZATION>'s recent discount rate hike, economists said the credit tightening so far should not cause any appreciable slowdown before the Nov. 8 election, good news for <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> presidential candidate <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, who hopes continued signs of prosperity will translate into votes. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Penzer </PERSON>, an economist with the <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION>, said he believed interest rates would keep rising until next February, when the <ORGANIZATION> Fed </ORGANIZATION> would reverse course after seeing signs that its tightening was having the desired effect of slowing GNP growth. `` We have a fairly rosey scenario in which the <ORGANIZATION> Fed </ORGANIZATION> lucks out,'' he said. Economists who are not ready to write the obituary for the expansion say the current recovery from the 1981-82 downturn has proven remarkably resilient and may have a couple of more years of life. `` This expansion has had nine lives,'' said <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Jasinowski </PERSON>, chief economist of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Manufacturers </ORGANIZATION>. `` It has rebounded from a flood of imports in the mid-1980s, high real interest rates and the loss of $ 1 trillion of wealth during the 1987 stock market collapse.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880821-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-21-88 1117EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w AM-ThirdWorldRoads     08-21 0372</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Third World Roads,350</SECOND>
<HEAD>Third World Needs $90 Billion for Roads, Report Says</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CARL HARTMAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Third World countries need $ 43 billion worth of repairs to their roads, including many of their key thoroughfares, because over the last decade they failed to spend $ 12 billion or less to maintain them, the <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> says in a report. The largest sum _ $ 11 billion _ is needed in <LOCATION> Latin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Caribbean </LOCATION>, followed by $ 9.3 billion in <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION>, and another $ 9.3 billion in the poorer countries of the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>. The bank's experts said they were talking about a third of all paved roads outside of towns and a quarter of the unpaved roads in 85 countries. They found that 40 percent of the paved roads will need repair in the next 10 years, at a cost of another $ 40 billion. In 1984, the most recent year for which the report gives figures, the countries concerned put out $ 6.5 billion for repair and maintenance. `` But if these countries do not improve the management of roads, the eventual cost of restoration could easily increase two - to threefold, and the cost to users could rise even more,'' the report warned <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION>, owned by 151 countries, is the biggest single source of loans to help poor countries raise their living standards. It has lent about $ 15.5 billion for roads since it was founded at the end of World War II. Routine maintenance can cost as little as $ 480 a mile, while rebuilding can cost more than $ 480,000 a mile, the report said. The experts found the hard core of the problem in southern <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>. They took 61 Third World countries all over the world and found that 16 of them had budgets too small to pay for the roads they need. Of those 16, there were 11 where citizens' incomes have been declining. Nine of the 11 are south of the <LOCATION> Sahara </LOCATION>. They found a different problem in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Bangladesh </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Burma </LOCATION>. Many of their roads were built long ago in ways that do not suit today's traffic, and should simply be replaced, the report said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880821-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-21-88 1116EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-BRF--50DollarDonor     08-21 0142</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--50 Dollar Donor,0143</SECOND>
<HEAD>Third Time in Three Days, Mystery Man Hands Out $50 Bills</HEAD>
<DATELINE>DETROIT (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 It's beginning to look like a daily habit _ a man in a white tuxedo hops out of a limousine and spends a couple of minutes handing out $ 50 bills to passersby before being driven off. But on Saturday, there was a slight difference. This time, the limo pulled up outside a <LOCATION> Greektown </LOCATION> bar, instead of grocery stores in <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Northville </ORGANIZATION> where apparently the same man appeared Thursday and Friday. `` He was in and out in 30 seconds,'' said bar patron <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Godin </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Belleville </LOCATION>. `` At first I turned it -LRB- the money -RRB- down because I did n't know what it was.'' But, <PERSON> Godin </PERSON> had second thoughts and took one of the bills. It was unclear how much money the man has given away.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880821-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-21-88 1122EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Britain-Pubs Bjt   08-21 0756</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Britain-Pubs, Bjt,0778</SECOND>
<HEAD>Cheers To All-Day Drinking In British Pubs</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LESLIE SHEPHERD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The bartender's dreaded cry of `` last orders'' will not ring out in English pubs Monday afternoon for the first time since World War I. Instead, thanks to new laws that permit all-day drinking, pubs that open at 11 a.m. can continue serving beer and spirits until closing time at 11 p.m. `` We're hoping for a big crowd,'' said <PERSON> Mick </PERSON> <PERSON> McCoy </PERSON>, assistant manager of the Hog In The Pound pub near the <LOCATION> Oxford </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Street </LOCATION> shopping district. `` We're stacked up -LRB- with beer -RRB-. We've taken on a couple of extra people, just in case.'' Other pub owners who have lost trade to fast-food restaurants will expand their lunch menus. One even plans to sell tea and scones. Under the old system, pubs were forced to close from 3 p.m. until 5:30 p.m. The bartender's warning at 2:50 p.m. created a rush for one last pint, and 10 minutes later, to the cry of `` time, gentlemen, please,'' the fun was over. The government imposed the rule in 1915 to curb drinking by munitions workers. <LOCATION> Scotland </LOCATION> went to all-day drinking in 1977, but the restriction held in the 68,000 English and Welsh pubs until Monday. The British <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> opposes the extended hours, fearing increased alcohol-related illness and drunken-driving accidents. But no increase in alcohol abuse or surge in consumption was detected in <LOCATION> Scotland </LOCATION>. Home Secretary <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON> <PERSON> Hurd </PERSON>, the Cabinet minister responsible for liquor laws, likened the old restriction to a `` corset, a straitjacket, which has no particular rhyme or reason.'' Parliament agreed, and voted overwhelmingly in April to do away with the 2 -LCB- - hour afternoon dry period on Monday through Saturday, which has frustrated Britons and tourists alike A controversial amendment slipped in by the unelected <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lords </ORGANIZATION> extends opening times by one hour on Sunday, which has always had shorter drinking hours. Sunday hours were noon to 2 p.m. and 7 p.m. to 10:30 p.m. They are now noon to 3 p.m. and 7 p.m. to 10:30 p.m. Next to TV-gazing, dropping into the neighborhood pub is <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s most popular leisure activity, said <PERSON> Kenneth </PERSON> <PERSON> Dunjohn </PERSON>, spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> Brewers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION>, representing most of <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s 117 breweries The pub is where neighbors, still more men than women, congregate to play darts, work the slot machines and argue about soccer and politics. It's also the original fast-food outlet. In addition to a smorgasbord of beer, from light lagers to strong, dark ales, and other alcohol, pubs serve traditional English food like steak-and-kidney pie and bangers and mash. But pub attendance has been falling since 1979, when a recession hit <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s heavy industries and cut blue-collar spending power, <PERSON> Dunjohn </PERSON> said. Faced with competition from fast-food chains and wine bars, which arrived in <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> in the same period, the beer market has gone flat. Beer consumption fell to 190 pints per capita a year in 1986 from 208 pints in 1976, although measured in terms of pure alcohol, consumption rose to 9.2 liters in 1986 from six liters in 1966. Pub managers and breweries, which own or have exclusive sales agreements with thousands of pubs, hope the new hours will revitalize business. Pubs will expand their food service to meet the afternoon trade, predicted <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Boyle </PERSON>, marketing manager for brewers <ORGANIZATION> Ind </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coope </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Taylor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Walker </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ltd. </ORGANIZATION>, which operates more than 700 pubs in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>. The British <ORGANIZATION> Tourist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Authority </ORGANIZATION> expects 50,000 new jobs will be created in pubs and the catering trade. The <PERSON> Sherlock </PERSON> <PERSON> Holmes </PERSON> pub near <LOCATION> Trafalgar </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Square </LOCATION> plans to serve full cream teas _ scones, <LOCATION> strawberry </LOCATION> <LOCATION> jam </LOCATION>, the works _ every afternoon. `` As far as I can see, the house -LRB- pub -RRB- will be more of a coffee shop in the afternoon than a drinking house,'' said <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>, who manages the pub with his wife, <PERSON> Jean </PERSON>. `` I do n't think the average British person, after the initial shock, is going to be affected. It's more of a touristy thing.'' Only those pubs in busy tourist or commercial areas are expected to take advantage of the new hours, while those in residential areas will continue to close in the afternoon. The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Licensed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Managers </ORGANIZATION>, which represents 13,000 pub managers, had feared increased overhead costs would push up beer prices if all pubs had to open in the afternoon. Beer prices have risen three to four pence -LRB- 5 cents -RRB- recently, but the breweries insist it's not because of the new hours. The going price for a pint of beer is 85 pence -LRB- $ 1.50 -RRB-.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880821-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-21-88 1145EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-TownBands     08-21 0569</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Town Bands,0584</SECOND>
<HEAD>Hills Are Alive Again with Sounds of Polkas, Waltzes, Military
Marches</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CAROLYN LUMSDEN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SPRINGFIELD, Mass. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The hills of <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> are alive again with the sounds of polkas, waltzes and military marches as town bands make a comeback in once-abandoned band shells and gazebos. Retired musicians, teen-agers and middle-age mothers who have n't played an instrument since high school are jumping on the bandwagon `` You have no idea how much fun it is,'' said <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> Voisin </PERSON>, a former first trumpet of the <ORGANIZATION> Boston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Symphony </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Orchestra </ORGANIZATION> and a third-generation town band musician. His grandfather conducted the municipal band in the French city of Angers. The legacy continues. <PERSON> Voisin </PERSON>'s 15-year-old granddaughter, <PERSON> Jennifer </PERSON> <PERSON> Roy </PERSON>, sits behind him in the <PERSON> Great </PERSON> <PERSON> Barrington </PERSON> band shell that was built last year to replace the 1904 bandstand that had disappeared from its spot in front of Town Hall in the 1940s. `` Every once in a while I'll do a solo or a particularily difficult piece and I'll feel a little pat on my back, as if to say, ` Good job, Grandpa,''' he said. Band shells sprung up in parks across the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> in the 1800s, but fell victim to radio, movie theaters and television sets in the middle of this century. Several band shells were destroyed; others simply were abandoned. One of the few towns that managed to keep the tradition going despite the lure of other pasttimes was <LOCATION> Shelburne </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Falls </LOCATION>, which boasts the second-oldest continuously operating town band in the nation. The band has played every summer since its founding in 1835. Its secretary, <PERSON> Shirley </PERSON> <PERSON> Donelson </PERSON>, believes the band may be the oldest. The 30-member <ORGANIZATION> Shelburne </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Falls </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Military </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Band </ORGANIZATION> includes one player with at least a half-century of service and three players with more than 40 years in the group. Among the players are a farmer, a retired fire chief, a college music professor and a few high school students. The band even has uniforms, a luxury among most bands. The 40-member Montague Community Band provides shirts but asks that musicians bring their own chairs. Mrs. <PERSON> Donelson </PERSON>, 54, said she took up the saxophone she had left behind in high school and joined the band as soon as her children grew up. `` I did n't have time when I was raising a family,'' she said. Her husband, <PERSON> Walt </PERSON>, 55, has beat the bass drum for the group every summer since 1952. A carpenter, he designed and built the town band shell in 1970. `` I do it for the fun of it,'' he said. `` If I did it for the money, I'd be done years ago.'' Like all town bands, the <LOCATION> Shelburne </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Falls </LOCATION> band depends mostly on the generosity of the board of selectmen to keep going, but it also raises money by charging fees for marching in other communities. The 50-member <ORGANIZATION> Pulaski </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Brass </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Band </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Webster </LOCATION> celebrated its 99th year on Aug. 14 by marching a few blocks from its headquarters, the <ORGANIZATION> Polish </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Citizens </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ' </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Club </ORGANIZATION>, to <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Joseph </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION>, where it was started by five men. The band has missed only a few summers, during World War II, since its beginning and has never had trouble recruiting, members say. `` We have no dues and no auditions,'' <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> Motyka </PERSON>, a 37-year veteran of the group, told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Worcester </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Telegram </ORGANIZATION>. `` We had a fellow once who really had no musical ability, so we let him crash the cymbals.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880821-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-21-88 1150EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-NicaraguanContras Bjt   08-21 0958</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Nicaraguan Contras, Bjt,0987</SECOND>
<HEAD>Contra Retreat Threatens Survival Of Force To Oust Sandinistas</HEAD>
<HEAD>RETRANSMITTING a0639 to fix category code.</HEAD>
<HEAD>AP News Analysis</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BRYNA BRENNAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MANAGUA, Nicaragua (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The retreat of Contra rebels and supporters to remote Honduran base camps threatens the survival of the insurgency to oust <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>'s leftist Sandinista government. The action also reverses months of political and military advances. Officials at the rebel camps said more than 14,000 Contra troops and civilians crossed the <LOCATION> Coco </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> border in the past four months into <LOCATION> Yamales </LOCATION> in the steep Honduran mountains. Rebel officers estimate that no more than 2,000 fighters remain in the northern Nicaraguan hills. The rebels blame the withdrawal on the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, which on Feb. 29 cut off military aid _ a bargaining chip, they say, for discussions to end the war that began in 1981. <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> has voted to grant only non-lethal aid distributed in <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION>. `` Our forces ca n't stay in <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> _ surrounded by Sandinista troops _ without bullets in their rifles,'' <PERSON> Enrique </PERSON> <PERSON> Bermudez </PERSON>, the rebel commander and member of the Contra political directorate, said recently. `` Military aid must be a threat to the <LOCATION> Sandinistas </LOCATION> to continue negotiating. We need to convince <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> we enter from a position of strength.'' Thousands of troops, many in new <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> uniforms, wait at the base camps, occasionally falling into formation. They buoy each other's morale, playing baseball and checkers on homemade boards with toothpaste caps. Makeshift tents of wood stakes covered with plastic or ponchos dot the hillsides. The population of the refugee camps swelled from 8,000 at the start of 1987 to more than 13,000 at the end of June. <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION> claims that up to 200,000 Nicaraguans live illegally in its territory. At one of the camps, new arrivals, their clothes tattered from more than a month of walking, worked under the tropical sun to clear the brush. Many of the civilians said they followed the troops because they would suffer Sandinista repression without Contra protection. `` If we had aid, all our troops would be inside <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>,'' said a 37-year-old Contra official whose nom de guerre is Commander <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>. `` It will take a long time to get back to where we were.'' The first Contras came from the ranks of the national guard under dictator <PERSON> Anastasio </PERSON> <PERSON> Somoza </PERSON>, who was ousted in a 1979 revolutionary war that brought the Sandinisatas to power. A dozen rebels received training in <LOCATION> Argentina </LOCATION> in 1981 and others were taught by CIA-contracted Argentine instructors at Honduran base camps. The <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> was also held responsible for air drops of weapons, food and other supplies. The Contras' reputation as an unsavory band of ragtag thugs whose troops murdered civilians and kidnapped youths began changing in 1986. Peasants and young people joined their ranks, which swelled above 10,000. <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> approved a $ 100 million military and humanitarian aid package in June 1986. By the following spring, the rebels, well-armed and many trained in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, moved out of their Honduran base camps into <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>. The Sandinistas accused the Contras of forcing recruitment and of a record number of human rights abuses. Asked about the abuses, <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> acknowledged: `` There are still revenge killings by both sides, but it's not a policy of our organization.'' The rebels had their greatest battlefield and political gains against the Soviet-backed Sandinista government in 1987. They became more popular when the government drew increasing criticism for the failing economy, mandatory recruitment and repression. But the rebel advances of last year suffered setbacks in recent months. In a surprise move three weeks after <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military aid ended Feb. 29, the <ORGANIZATION> Sandinistas </ORGANIZATION> and the Contra civilian directorate signed an agreement to seek a negotiated settlement to the war. The cease-fire plan prohibited the fighters from receiving any militery aid, but allowed non-lethal supplies to be distributed inside <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> by a neutral international organization. <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, citing the pact, withheld further military aid and in March allocated $ 15.5 million for supplies ranging from food to uniforms and $ 17.7 million for medical aid to child war victims. The supplies were to be distributed in <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION> by the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION>. At about the same time, deep divisions emerged among the rebels. Some Contra commanders who signed the peace plan charged commander-in-chief <PERSON> Enrique </PERSON> <PERSON> Bermudez </PERSON> with corruption and called for a barracks uprising. The dissidents were purged and the troops rallied around <PERSON> Bermudez </PERSON>, who opposed the cease-fire. <PERSON> Bermudez </PERSON>, a former colonel in <ORGANIZATION> Somoza </ORGANIZATION>'s national guard, was elected in July to the seven-member Contra political directorate and was said to have resigned his post as the military commander-in-chief. However, he clearly remains in control. <PERSON> Bermudez </PERSON>, who recently visited the camps, listened as soldiers complained about the diet of rice and beans. Many of the ew arrivals are to start military training in September, while some of the civilians and fighters will head for nearby refugee camps run by the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION>. But rebel officials said thousands of other fighters and civilians were expected to cross the border into <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION> soon. <PERSON> Felix </PERSON> <PERSON> Mendoza </PERSON>, a Honduran farmer who allows the Contras to use his land, said `` incredible numbers'' of rebels had entered in recent days. `` Nicargua will soon be empty,'' said <PERSON> Mendoza </PERSON>. <PERSON> Bermudez </PERSON> called the cutoff of <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> aid `` a tragedy for Central America'' and said he will seek support from other governments or private donors. Commander <PERSON> Augustin </PERSON>, 29, a company leader who has been fighting for seven years, said: `` I did n't want to come back here. We still have some bullets but we needed clothes, boots and food.'' `` We're willing to fight until the last drop of blood. We want liberty in our country,'' said the officer.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR's NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Bryna </PERSON> <PERSON> Brennan </PERSON> is The Associated Press' correspondent in <LOCATION> Managua </LOCATION>
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880821-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-21-88 1150EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-FuneralMuseum Bjt   08-21 0750</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Funeral Museum, Bjt,0775</SECOND>
<HEAD>Funeral Museum Draws the Curious, the Bereaved and Students of
Death Process</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto MH1</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By A.J. DICKERSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>HOLLYWOOD, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Death may be a constant but the rituals change with the times, as a museum dedicated to dying and bereavement illustrates. Old embalming tools, a 1917 Ford Model-T hearse that doubled as an ambulance, intricately braided wreaths of human hair and a 1,500-pound glass casket are some of the memorabilia in <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> Hunter </PERSON>'s funeral museum, one of a handful in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. `` If we can teach a little to a student, and help families understand the history, that death is natural ... this helps them understand there's a heritage to this process. The whole funeral process is a part of growing, of letting go,'' said <PERSON> Hunter </PERSON>. <PERSON> Hunter </PERSON> is president of National Selected Morticians, a 965-member trade group. A third-generation funeral director and antique enthusiast, <PERSON> Hunter </PERSON> inherited some displays from his father and grandfather. After he bought a large collection in 1986, there was no longer room to show them off at his business. The museum opened last year next to <PERSON> Hunter </PERSON>'s funeral home. The 1,200 visitors have included mourners who stopped by after a funeral, tourists who have stumbled upon it and students from local high schools or community colleges. `` A lot of times, people sitting here will see the museum and we'll open it for them. It answers a lot of questions,'' said <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Plescia </PERSON>, grief counselor at Hunter's. Learning funeral history is a good way to brace for the future, said <PERSON> Roberta </PERSON> <PERSON> Halporn </PERSON>, director of the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> City-based </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Thanatology </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Education </ORGANIZATION>, a non-profit group that studies dying, death and grieving. `` This is a death-denying culture. So when it happens, the pain is almost double. People without experience tend to want to eliminate everything _ no funeral. But each part of the ritual has significance,'' she said. `` When these rituals are established and practiced, it starts the bereavement process going in a healthy way,'' <PERSON> Halporn </PERSON> said. <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> career guidance teacher <PERSON> Kay </PERSON> <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> agrees. She has taken <ORGANIZATION> Piper </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> High </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> students considering allied health careers on field trips to <PERSON> Hunter </PERSON>'s for years. `` As weird as it sounds, it really is a good learning experience. Part of managing a career is understanding death. It's a good thing, because kids at this age have no experience with death,'' she says For <PERSON> Hunter </PERSON>, the museum reflects the changes in American culture. `` The way funerals changed mirrors the way families changed.'' At the turn of the century funerals were still family reunions. Morticians visited homes to prepare the body, often laid out in parlors, and built made-to-measure coffins. `` On the day of the funeral, he would come again with his coffin and put the body in it and go to the church,'' <PERSON> Hunter </PERSON> said. As people moved to cities, wakes moved out of houses and funeral homes were born. Coffins used to be tapered on the ends and their inner metal liners were soldered. They are no longer tapered and now have self-sealing rubber gaskets. During the Victorian era, wreaths were fashioned from hair, generally that of the deceased, and a family might weave a huge multi-hued wreath over several generations. Hearses once regularly doubled as ambulances, a practice that ended with regulations that ambulances be painted white. That was hardly appropriate for a funeral vehicle, <PERSON> Hunter </PERSON> said, stroking his gleaming black Model-T, which won first prize _ as an ambulance _ at the <ORGANIZATION> Antique </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Automotive </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Club </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s 1982 show. Not all industry innovations caught on, like the solid glass casket on display. `` You take the 1,500 pounds and add another 175 pounds and we put that in a Model-T hearse and you've just flattened the tires,'' <PERSON> Hunter </PERSON> said. `` It's like one giant <ORGANIZATION> Coke </ORGANIZATION> bottle.'' Other funeral museums around the nation include a small display owned by <PERSON> T.J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Beggs </PERSON> and Sons Funeral Home of <LOCATION> Madison </LOCATION>, near <LOCATION> Tallahassee </LOCATION>, and a traveling museum run by the <ORGANIZATION> Illinois </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Funeral </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Director </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Springfield </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Hunter </PERSON>'s museum also houses a collection of 1900-era anatomy books for student morticians, yellowing funeral bills and complete issues of the trade journal `` The Casket'' dating back to 1892. <PERSON> Hunter </PERSON> sees industry changes ahead, such as more cremations, people paying for funerals in advance and the terminally ill opting to die in their own beds instead of in hospitals. `` The death pattern is changing,'' he said. `` We go to homes more often than we did five years ago.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880821-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-21-88 1157EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-Eliana-AIDS Bjt   08-21 0716</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Eliana-AIDS, Bjt,0739</SECOND>
<HEAD>Adoptive Mother: Disappointed Over `Glass Cage,' Will Continue
Fight</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PAT LEISNER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>TAMPA, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
