<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880526-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-26-88 2342EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-WritersStrike 1stLd-Writethru a0827 05-26 0611</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Writers Strike, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0827,0626</SECOND>
<HEAD>TV, Movie Writers Claim to Split Ranks of Producers</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Leads with 17 grafs to UPDATE with exact tally of producers
that have signed independent contracts; identifies major
independents that have signed; ADDS comment from alliance
spokesman; picks up 11th graf: `Nearly 180 ...</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By GEORGE GARTIES</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Striking TV and movie scriptwriters claimed they had split management ranks Thursday after 64 producers, including the makers of `` The Cosby Show'' and <PERSON> Johnny </PERSON> <PERSON> Carson </PERSON>'s talk show, signed independent contracts with the writers' union. Several of the firms that signed with the <ORGANIZATION> Writers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guild </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION> produce successful television programs for <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> Alliance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Motion </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Picture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Television </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Producers </ORGANIZATION>, representing the industry's biggest producers, downplayed the signings, which represent a significant break in the 12-week strike. The walkout has forced delays in the start of the fall television season and reruns of such shows as `` Late Night with <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Letterman </PERSON>'' and `` The Tonight Show starring <PERSON> Johnny </PERSON> <PERSON> Carson </PERSON>.'' The 9,000-member <ORGANIZATION> Writers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guild </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION> was scheduled to vote Thursday night in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> on contracts with smaller, so-called independent producers. Voting results would n't be known until Friday, said union spokeswoman <PERSON> Cheryl </PERSON> <PERSON> Rhoden </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>. `` We're anticipating ratification,'' Ms. <PERSON> Rhoden </PERSON> said. `` We see it strategically as a good move at this time to break the logjam with the alliance.'' Ms. <PERSON> Rhoden </PERSON> released the names of the independent producers and the terms of their three-year contract with the <ORGANIZATION> WGA </ORGANIZATION> before members gathered to vote on the proposal. The contract includes increases in foreign residual payments and provides writers with greater creative input. The list of 64 production companies includes the <ORGANIZATION> Carsey-Werner </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Company </ORGANIZATION>, which produces two of the most popular shows on television, `` The Cosby Show'' and `` A Different World.'' The makers of `` Tonight'' signed a contract and the producers of `` Late Night'' have agreed to a contract but have n't signed, said union President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Kirgo </PERSON>. Others signing were producers of `` Alf'' and `` The Muppets.'' Also on the list are <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Landon </PERSON> <PERSON> Productions </PERSON>, which makes `` Highway to Heaven'' and You and Me Kid Productions, the maker of the now-cancelled `` The Days and Nights of <PERSON> Molly </PERSON> <PERSON> Dodd </PERSON>.'' Most of the producers appear to be film companies, such as <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Gaby </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Film </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Group </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, and some, such as <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Keyes </PERSON> Productions, produce TV specials. None of the 217 big producers who belong to the alliance have signed independent contracts, management spokesman <PERSON> Herb </PERSON> <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON> said Thursday. The large producers, whose ranks include such big-time moviemakers as <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pictures </ORGANIZATION> and such TV giants as <ORGANIZATION> MTM </ORGANIZATION> and <PERSON> Lorimar </PERSON>, employ 80 percent of the industry's writers and supply 84 percent of prime-time TV, he noted. `` The alliance producers are holding strong,'' <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON> said. `` This is all very, very interesting, but it has no impact on the new season or on the contract negotiations,'' <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON> said. `` What they're talking about makes no change in the point of conflict, which are the deficits for productions of one-hour prime-time TV shows and the depressed market for those shows in syndication.'' Nearly 180 producers had discussed independent agreements, which meet the writers' demands on residual payments they receive when shows are rerun and for consultation on script changes made during filming, she said. Those are the main points of contention in the strike, which began March 7. On Monday, both sides sat down with a federal mediator for the first time since April 8. The talks at alliance headquarters in the <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> suburb of <LOCATION> Sherman </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Oaks </LOCATION> failed to produce agreement on any issue. Negotiators agreed to meet in small groups Saturday and set another full bargaining session Tuesday.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880526-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-26-88 2343EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-SchoolShootings     05-26 0424</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-School Shootings,0436</SECOND>
<HEAD>Police Arrest Friend of Dann's on Harassment Charges</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WINNETKA, Ill. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A friend and ex-roommate of <PERSON> Laurie </PERSON> <PERSON> Dann </PERSON>, the woman who fatally shot a child and wounded six people, was charged with making harassing telephone calls and committed to a psychiatric ward, police said Thursday. <PERSON> Sheri </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON>, 34, of suburban <ORGANIZATION> Highwood </ORGANIZATION> was arrested late Wednesday by members of a county task force investigating last Friday's shootings by Ms. <PERSON> Dann </PERSON>, said <ORGANIZATION> Winnetka </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION> Chief <PERSON> Herbert </PERSON> <PERSON> Timm </PERSON>. `` We are in the process of determining the extent of Ms. <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON>'s involvement with <PERSON> Laurie </PERSON> <PERSON> Dann </PERSON>,'' who killed herself after the shootings, <PERSON> Timm </PERSON> said at a news conference. Investigators want to know if Ms. <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON> was recently in contact with Ms. <PERSON> Dann </PERSON> or involved in her violent rampage in this affluent suburb north of <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>, said Assistant State's Attorney <PERSON> Randy </PERSON> <PERSON> Stewart </PERSON>. Ms. <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON> is accused of threatening the life of her ex-husband, <PERSON> Scott </PERSON> <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON>, and their children, who live with their father, <PERSON> Stewart </PERSON> and <PERSON> Timm </PERSON> said. She also was arrested for failing to appear on a drunken driving charge in <LOCATION> Evanston </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Stewart </PERSON> said in a telephone interview. <PERSON> Stewart </PERSON> said authorities were alarmed to discover Ms. <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON> had a valid <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> firearms ownership card and had purchased a .357 - caliber Magnum pistol within the past The gun was found during a police search of her apartment, he said. <PERSON> Stewart </PERSON> said Ms. <PERSON> Dann </PERSON> and Ms. <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON> had been roommates about a year ago. After her arrest, <PERSON> Timm </PERSON> said, the woman was involuntarily committed to a psychiatric unit at Rush-Presbyterian-St. <PERSON> Luke </PERSON>'s Medical Center in Last Friday, Ms. <PERSON> Dann </PERSON> started a small fire in a home, shot six children at <ORGANIZATION> Hubbard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Woods </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Elementary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION>, killing one, and then shot and wounded a 20-year-old man at a nearby house, where she later shot and killed herself. Ms. <PERSON> Dann </PERSON> also sent or delivered about two dozen packages of snacks and juice laced with arsenic to acquaintances. The <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> said Thursday that Ms. <PERSON> Dann </PERSON> apparently acted alone in sending the poisoned food and drinks. `` Nobody else has surfaced as an accomplice,'' said <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Steinmetz </PERSON>, supervisor of the Madison office of the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION>, where Ms. <PERSON> Dann </PERSON> obtained the poison. At <LOCATION> Evanston </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION>, shooting victim 8-year-old <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Teborek </PERSON> was released Thursday while another victim, <PERSON> Lindsay </PERSON> <PERSON> Fisher </PERSON>, 8, was upgraded to fair condition. <PERSON> Kathryn </PERSON> <PERSON> Miller </PERSON>, 7, and <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Trossman </PERSON>, 6, were in good condition. At <LOCATION> Highland </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Park </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Munro </PERSON>, 8, and <PERSON> Philip </PERSON> <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON>, 20, _ who was shot when Ms. <PERSON> Dann </PERSON> took over his family's home _ were in fair condition.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880526-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-26-88 2346EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Panama 2ndLd-Writethru a0874 05-26 0822</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Panama, 2nd Ld-Writethru, a0874,0844</SECOND>
<HEAD>Noriega Says U.S. Gave Him Ultimatum And `Mocked' Canal Treaties</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: INSERT 3 grafs after 5th graf pvs, The general ... UPDATING
with Guatemalan offer to mediate. Picks up 7th graf pvs, Noriega
appeared ...</NOTE>
<HEAD>With AM-Panama Repression Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOSEPH B. FRAZIER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PANAMA CITY, Panama (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Gen. <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> said Thursday that talks with the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> about his future broke down when the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> envoy presented him with an ultimatum that the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> terms be accepted immediately. <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>, speaking to a cheering crowd that packed the 500-seat National Assembly, accused the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> of `` political, economic and military'' aggression against <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>. `` The world must know that the conversation sustained with the envoy of President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> broke down when he presented us with an ultimatum in which <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> had to immediately accept his last offer,'' said <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>, who as head of the 15,000-member military is the de facto leader of the country. `` I know it and I say so because I was there. -LRB- <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Secretary of State -RRB- <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> was n't there,'' he told the crowd. Hundreds more listened outside near a loudspeaker. The general did not elaborate. He said <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> had accepted several <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> proposals, but added: `` Even this was n't sufficient. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> desired an ultimatum.'' In <LOCATION> Guatemala </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, President <PERSON> Vinicio </PERSON> <PERSON> Cerezo </PERSON> <PERSON> Arevalo </PERSON> offered Thursday to act as mediator between the two countries. He told reporters <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> was experiencing `` a radicalization against the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> that is dangerous for the region and that moreover is causing grave damage to the Panamanian nation.'' The Guatemalan chief executive said he had spoken with <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and Panamanian officials on the issue. He did not identify them. <ORGANIZATION> Cerezo </ORGANIZATION> met Thursday with <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Michel </PERSON>, the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> ambassador to <LOCATION> Guatemala </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> appeared in the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION> to answer questions about what the government insists were `` conversations,'' not negotiations, on a possible arrangement under which he would leave power. The speech was attended by 39 of the assembly's 67 members. Those absent included the 20 representatives of opposition parties. <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> said <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> had become a pawn for candidates in the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> political campaign. They `` are using the flag of <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> in whatever way is convenient for them'' and some candidates want `` to bury files that weigh on their shoulders,'' said <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>, who commands <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s military and police He did not identify them. <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> repeated his conditions for leaving power: Extra troops sent to <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> bases in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> must be withdrawn and the position of <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Solis </PERSON> <PERSON> Palma </PERSON>, whom he installed as president, must be guaranteed. He said the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> `` must respect <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>.'' `` I refer the North American people and their candidates who are using the flag of <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> to win votes to the words of one of their philosophers, <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Jefferson </PERSON>, when he said the politician thinks of the next elections, the statesman of the next generations,'' the general said. Referring to the <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Canal </LOCATION> treaties of 1977, <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> said: `` The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has mocked what has been signed. It has mocked the signing of the Torrijos-Carter treaties.'' Gen. <PERSON> Omar </PERSON> <PERSON> Torrijos </PERSON>, <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>'s predecessor and mentor, reached the accord with President <PERSON> Jimmy </PERSON> <PERSON> Carter </PERSON>. <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> wants <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>, who is under <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> indictment on drug charges, to leave the country and <PERSON> Eric </PERSON> <PERSON> Arturo </PERSON> <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON> to return as president in exchange for lifting economic sanctions and possibly dropping the drug charges. <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> dismissed <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON> on Feb. 26, the day after <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON> had tried to fire the general as commander of the <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> Defense Forces. <PERSON> Solis </PERSON> <PERSON> Palma </PERSON> told a women's organization earlier Thursday that American negotiators told <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> in March to be out of the country within 48 hours or face the consequences. After <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> refused, he said, the Americans softened their manner. He said talks failed because the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> would not promise to keep him on as president or to help with <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s economic crisis, which stems partly from the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> sanctions. The final deal would have dropped the drug charges in return for <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> giving up command of the armed forces Aug. 12 and leaving the country in September, <PERSON> Solis </PERSON> <PERSON> Palma </PERSON> said, but added: `` When we talked to them about the need for them to give guarantees and proofs that they would look for ways to recover in part the economic damage caused to the Republic of <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> they came back with promises but never followed through.'' According to <PERSON> Solis </PERSON> <PERSON> Palma </PERSON>, the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> would promise to release $ 50 million in Panamanian assets frozen in American banks only if he chose a national unity Cabinet that in turn would pick a president `` who could not be <PERSON> Solis </PERSON> <PERSON> Palma </PERSON>.'' <PERSON> Ricardo </PERSON> <PERSON> Arias </PERSON> <PERSON> Calderon </PERSON>, president of the opposition <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democrats </ORGANIZATION>, said Thursday the negotiations failed because of a growing division in the military and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> should have been aware of it. `` Errors by the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> were not the only factor although they were a factor,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880526-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-26-88 0012EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p AM-PoliticalRdp 3rdLd-Writethru a1000 05-26 1131</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Political Rdp, 3rd Ld-Writethru, a1000,1,100</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush Lashes ``Liberal Elite,'' Dukakis and Jackson Debate</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: LEADS with 20 grafs to UPDATE with more debate material;
picks up 14th graf pvs, bgng, The Massachusetts</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By DONALD M. ROTHBERG</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Political Writer</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Vice President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> lashed out Wednesday at political liberals, accusing them of destroying a bipartisan consensus toward the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, while Democratic presidential front-runner <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s advocacy of the death penalty for drug dealers was `` the height of hypocrisy.'' During a one-hour debate in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> pressed his Democratic rival for specific budget details as well as on his policy toward <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>. But the two Democrats saved their strongest comments for criticism of the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration for its dealings with <LOCATION> Panamanian </LOCATION> military leader <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>. After the debate, <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> and <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> met privately. With President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> en route to a <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> summit, the two Democrats said they hoped the superpowers would move toward less reliance on military solutions to world problems. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> said the superpowers were `` wandering around the world like lonesome cowboys'' intervening militarily. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> said he wished <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> `` godspeed and a good astrologist, as he believes in both'' and added he hoped the superpowers would `` look beyond the arms race.'' The debate _ their first in more than a month _ took place only hours after Secretary of State <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> announced the failure of negotiations aimed at getting <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> to relinquish power in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> said no new talks were scheduled. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said the fact the negotiations had broken down `` does n't depress me. `` I'm convinced <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> will be out of power,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> told reporters in <LOCATION> Lakehurst </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.J. </LOCATION> `` We'll have to go back and figure it out.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has advocated the death penalty for drug kingpins. When <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> was asked if he supported that position, he replied, `` I do not. I do not think we have the moral authority to execute in that sense. We have the obligation to take them off the streets and above all, do not deal with them and give them sanctuary and put them on the <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> payroll.'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> then interjected, `` It's the height of hypocrisy for people in the administration to be advocating the death penalty for drug pushers while they are doing business with <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> and funneling aid to the Contras through convicted drug dealers. `` I do n't know of anything phonier than that kind of policy.'' Questioned about his opposition to the death penalty, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> said, `` You do n't have to be for the death penalty to be tough on crime.'' He said views on the death penalty would not be a standard for judges he would appoint as president. `` I do n't apply ideological litmus tests,'' he said. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> said trying to forumlate a detailed budget plan so far in advance would be `` a serious mistake.'' <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> kept pressing him, however, saying that `` the governor is laying out a budget of prommises but not a budget of numbers.'' When <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> asked <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> if he would use military force against <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> governor replied that he would press for more effective sanctions. When <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> kept pressing him, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> said, `` Yes, one aspect of a tough anti-terrorist policy is the use of military force against terrorist base camps. But there are many ways to attack terrorism.'' The <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> governor expects to lock up the Democratic presidential nomination on June 7, when <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> hold primaries, the last major contests of the long pre-convention campaign. During a stop at the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Capitol before he flew west, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> picked up endorsements from 18 members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> who will be `` super delegates'' to the Democratic National Convention in July. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, at <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Point </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION>, told cadets at the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Military </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION> commencement ceremony that the `` liberal elite'' had abandoned what he called the bipartisan consensus for maintaining a strong national defense. Aides billed the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> speech as non-political. Standing under a small canopy in the pouring rain, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> never mentioned <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> or <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, but left no doubt of his targets. `` I'm sure they'd claim it is n't so and they're all in favor of a strong defense,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said. `` They look the part, sober and measured in their gray suits, moving their hands on the Sunday talk shows with just the right amount of gravity and earnestness.'' `` But what are we to think, when they say they're for a strong defense but they oppose every new weapons system that would preserve that strength?'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> asked. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> spoke only hours after President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> departed for <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> and a superpower summit in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>. He cautioned against allowing summit meetings to lead toward complacency toward the Soviets. `` We must be confident that those who will lead our country understand what it means to stand up to a challenge and meet our commitments,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said. `` We must be confident that they will pursue negotiations with the Soviets realistically.'' He said that under <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> presidents <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> Truman </PERSON> and <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> and then under <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> President <PERSON> Dwight </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Eisenhower </PERSON> there was bipartisan agreement on the need to deal with the Soviets from a position of strength. `` There are some today who have abandoned those principles,'' he said. `` The liberal elite do not understand _ they never understood _ the common sense behind the consensus.'' Later, the vice president called for the naming of an independent counsel to study recent alleged financial irregularties surrounding <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Speaker <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>. `` If they want to talk about -LRB- Attorney General <PERSON> Edwin </PERSON> -RRB- <PERSON> Ed </PERSON> <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>, how about talking about the speaker?'' he said. <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>'s legal problems have been frequently raised by the Democrats. While in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> met with a former rival, Democratic Sen. <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION>, a private meeting he later described as `` very cordial.'' They met in <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' hotel room and <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> still withheld any endorsement of the apparent nominee. The senator wrote to his delegates last week and urged them to stay loyal for the time being. <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> has nearly 400 delegates. The 18 congressional delegates <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> picked up moved his total to nearly 1,700. He needs 2,081 for a convention majority. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> has less than 1,000 in the latest <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> survey. During meetings at the Capitol, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> said, `` We are not going to concede one single state to the Republicans in the fall.'' One of his sessions was with Western members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and he said, `` The strategy is to win the West.'' He said it was `` one of the great political paradoxes'' that while Democrats run well in the region in contests for <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, governor and other offices, the party's candidates have been virtually shut out there in recent presidential elections. The last Democratic presidential candidate to carry the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> was <PERSON> Lyndon </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> in 1964.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880526-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-26-88 0737EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-StElsewhere     05-26 0436</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-St Elsewhere,0446</SECOND>
<HEAD>`St. Elsewhere' _ It Was All in Our Minds</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KATHRYN BAKER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Television Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 After a boldly existential ending, `` St. Elsewhere'' exists no more. The show, which won a dozen Emmy Awards, concluded Wednesday night with a surprise conclusion revealing the entire six years of the critically acclaimed series as the fantasy of an autistic child. `` We've had the ending for a number of years,'' said <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Paltrow </PERSON>, one of the show's executive producers. `` We were looking for the metaphor for all of us to have created this fiction. To place the entire six years into the imagination of boy who could not communicate with the outside world, but had this staggeringly exciting inner life was we thought an excitingly existential end to the series.'' When it made its debut six season ago, `` St. Elsewhere'' was part of a wave of creativity from <ORGANIZATION> MTM </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Productions </ORGANIZATION> that revolutionized stodgy network programming in the 1980s. `` St. Elsewhere'' followed `` Hill Street Blues'' onto <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> and was inevitably compared to the earlier show's groundbreaking style, overlapping dialogue and hand-held cameras. But `` St. Elsewhere'' went beyond `` Hill Street'' in social satire. At times serious, at times hilarious, it took on politics, religion, AIDS, heterosexual and homosexual rape, cancer, drug abuse, the afterlife, corporate indifference, its own network and previous shows from <ORGANIZATION> MTM </ORGANIZATION>. One entire episode revolved around a male patient's insistence that he was <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Richards </PERSON> from `` The <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Tyler </PERSON> <PERSON> Moore </PERSON> Show.'' The `` St. Elsewhere'' writers had wanted to go all out in the final episode, but prohibitive costs kept their script, a futuristic view of <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Eligius </ORGANIZATION> at the edge of apocalypse, from being filmed. In the end, prohibitive costs knocked down not only the intended final episode but the show itself. `` St. Elsewhere'' was produced at a loss by <ORGANIZATION> MTM </ORGANIZATION> at a time when hour-long series are not selling well in syndication. The show will be seen in reruns, but <ORGANIZATION> MTM </ORGANIZATION> will not release details of its syndication sales. In an apparently personal, inside joke in the dialogue of the final script, Dr. <PERSON> Wayne </PERSON> <PERSON> Fiscus </PERSON> -LRB- <PERSON> Howie </PERSON> <PERSON> Mandel </PERSON> -RRB-, says of his years at <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Eligius </LOCATION>, `` Grueling hours, bad food, egomania, death and moral confusion. It'll be hard to leave.'' The producers of the show have long since left and are busy on a new series for <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, `` Tattinger's,'' an offbeat romantic comedy set in a popular <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> restaurant. It is being shot on location here and stars <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> Collins </PERSON>, <PERSON> Blythe </PERSON> <PERSON> Danner </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Stiller </PERSON>. The show is on <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s fall schedule in the time period that `` St. Elsewhere'' is leaving.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880526-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-26-88 0019EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p AM-Taxation-Representation     05-26 0318</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Taxation-Representation,0327</SECOND>
<HEAD>Senate Republicans Lock Themselves In Room During Tax Hikes</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN DIAMOND</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BOSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Massachusetts </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Republicans locked themselves in a room in protest Wednesday night as <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> senators adopted two tax increase measures totaling more than $ 100 million. The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> quickly approved a $ 70 million income tax loophole closing measure and a 5 percent sales tax on cigarettes designed to raise nearly $ 40 million and sent the measures to the House. As the vote took place, six <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Republicans sat in a locked room with the telephones either in use or off the hook. The Republicans said they were caucusing and were hoping to delay action on the tax increase proposals while at the same time drawing media attention to the tax bills. The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>, with many Democrats also absent from the chamber, approved the bills on a voice vote. `` For a $ 100 million bill to go through the <ORGANIZATION> Massachusetts </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> without a roll call is outrageous,'' said Sen. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Locke </PERSON>, who led the <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> caucus. <PERSON> Locke </PERSON> and fellow Sen. <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Cellucci </PERSON> are top officials in Vice President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> presidential campaign. Gov. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, the likely Democratic presidential nominee, has called for additional revenue and spending cuts to balance the $ 11.8 billion state budget, but has maintained it can be done without raising cigarette taxes. He has campaigned for president, in part, on his ability to balance the state's budget and on his success in reducing taxes over the past six years. Senate President <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Bulger </PERSON> derided the Republicans' move as a publicity stunt. `` The minority party was well aware of what's been going on,'' <PERSON> Bulger </PERSON> said. He said that after several attempts to call the Republicans failed, a court officer knocked on the door and informed the Republicans that a vote was taking place. Two of the eight Republicans in the 40-member <ORGANIZATION> Massachusetts </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> were absent.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880526-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-26-88 0740EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--Philippines-Slaying     05-26 0104</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Philippines-Slaying,0107</SECOND>
<HEAD>Wealthy Fish Farmer Slain In Philippines</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MALOLOS, Philippines (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Gunmen killed a wealthy fish farm owner as he returned home after inspecting his ponds in central <LOCATION> Luzon </LOCATION> island, police said. Police identified the victim as <PERSON> Mamerto </PERSON> <PERSON> Borlongan </PERSON>, 60, who also served as a neighborhood ward leader in this town 20 miles north of <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION>. The gunmen who staged the attack on Wednesday escaped, police said. Communist rebels operate in the area and have in the past claimed responsibility for killing Filipino businessmen and landowners. <PERSON> Borlongan </PERSON> owned hundreds of acres of fish ponds in the central provinces of <LOCATION> Bulacan </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Pampanga </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880526-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-26-88 2353EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-Marcos     05-26 0332</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Marcos,0341</SECOND>
<HEAD>Marcos Leaves Hospital, Asks To Return to Philippines</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CHRISTINE DONNELLY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>HONOLULU (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Former Philippine President <PERSON> Ferdinand </PERSON> <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> ended two-day's hospital treatment for chest pains Thursday, saying he will ask <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials to let him return to his homeland for the funeral of his mother. `` I'd like to go home and preside over the funeral rites of my mother,'' <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> said from a wheelchair during a news conference before he was discharged from <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Francis </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> said his application for permission for him and his family go to the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION> and return to the <LOCATION> Unites </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> at will would be submitted Thursday or Friday at the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Immigration and Naturalization office in <LOCATION> Honolulu </LOCATION>. When asked whether the application would be a request to return permanently to the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> replied, `` Well, what else? I would like the ordinary rights of a citizen.'' President <PERSON> Corazon </PERSON> <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON>, saying <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> poses a threat to national security, has repeatedly rejected his pleas to return for the funeral of his mother, <PERSON> Josefa </PERSON> <PERSON> Edralin-Marcos </PERSON>, who died May 4 at age 95. <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> said Mrs. <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON> should reconsider because, `` I've told them I will not bother them ... but will hold back the people from starting violence. She alone will not be able to hold them back.'' <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> is under `` a prevent departure notice,'' which means he needs permission to leave the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, said <ORGANIZATION> INS </ORGANIZATION> district director <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Craig </PERSON>. <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> said he did not know how long it would take for the <ORGANIZATION> INS </ORGANIZATION> and <LOCATION> Philippine </LOCATION> government to respond to his latest request. He said no date has been set for the funeral. <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> was accompanied by his wife, <PERSON> Imelda </PERSON>, several aides, a nurse and his physician, Dr. <PERSON> Azucena </PERSON> <PERSON> Ignacio </PERSON>, who said <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> would be able to travel. <PERSON> Ignacio </PERSON> said <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON>' chest pains were caused by arthritis or inflammation in the area of the left sixth rib. She said <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> improved dramatically by resting and was being treated with painkillers.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880526-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-26-88 0741EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--Spain-Terror     05-26 0115</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Spain-Terror,0118</SECOND>
<HEAD>Restaurant Owner Killed In Northern Spain</HEAD>
<DATELINE>EIBAR, Spain (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A restaurant owner was shot and killed in this Basque town near <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sebastian </LOCATION> in what provincial government officials said appeared to be the work of the Basque separatist group <ORGANIZATION> ETA </ORGANIZATION>. According to witnesses, one or two men shot and killed <PERSON> Sebastian </PERSON> <PERSON> Azpiri </PERSON>, 38, as he walked to his restaurant on Wednesday night. <ORGANIZATION> ETA </ORGANIZATION> has claimed responsibility for the deaths of three policemen and a retired general so far this year. Since taking up arms in 1968, the separatist group has claimed more than 600 killings in its campaign to seek independence from <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION> for the three-province Basque region in northern <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880526-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-26-88 0741EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Circus-Japan     05-26 0362</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Circus-Japan,0376</SECOND>
<HEAD>Circus To Go To Japan For First Time</HEAD>
<DATELINE>VENICE, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Greatest Show On Earth will venture across the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> for the first time as <ORGANIZATION> Ringling </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bros. </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Barnum </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <ORGANIZATION> Bailey </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Circus </ORGANIZATION> goes on tour in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, circus officials announced Wednesday. The 175 artists with the circus will be performing under a tent for the first time in three decades for practical reasons, said <PERSON> Kenneth </PERSON> <PERSON> Feldman </PERSON>, owner, president and producer of the circus. `` You could never fit an elephant in the doors'' of most Japanese arenas built mainly for sumo wrestling, he said. Since 1956, the circus has performed in indoor arenas on its <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> tours. `` I would never go if I could n't keep the same standards I have in this country,'' <PERSON> Feld </PERSON> said. Those standards include the star attraction, an animal billed as a `` living unicorn.'' Animal rights organizations say the circus animal is a goat with a bull horn surgically implanted in its head. The 16-week engagement will start July 3 in <LOCATION> Sapporo </LOCATION> and include a seven-week run in downtown <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION> with performances in <LOCATION> Osaka </LOCATION>. The tour is the first Far East engagement in the 118-year history of the circus. The show also features <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Medina </PERSON> inside The Globe of Death on a supercharged motorcycle, The <ORGANIZATION> Carrillo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Brothers </ORGANIZATION> high-wire artists and the Flying Espanas, who execute triple somersaults in midair. Ninety-five trucks will carry the circus from city to city. <PERSON> Feld </PERSON> was to announce details of the tour Thursday in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, where the circus has its corporate headquarters. Winter headquarters are in <LOCATION> Venice </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Feld </PERSON> said the Japanese people have more leisure time since switching from a six-day work week to a five-day work week. `` I expect receptions like we get in every city in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> where children of all ages are thrilled,'' he said. Organizing the massive transportation project with contingents of elephants, horses and camels was an undertaking twice the size of what <PERSON> Feld </PERSON> had anticipated but was worth the effort. `` I would n't have done it if I did n't love it,'' he said. The domestic tour of 85 <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> cities by two other circus units will be unaffected by the Japanese engagements.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880526-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-26-88 0216EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Casino10Years     05-26 1074</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Casino 10 Years,1103</SECOND>
<HEAD>Atlantic City: 10 Years And 12 Casinos Later</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By JOYCE A. VENEZIA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ATLANTIC CITY, N.J. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Ten years after <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> started its gamble with legalized gaming, it has won a giant new industry but lost its innocence. Even skeptics wo n't deny the resort has seen a dramatic economic turnaround since the first casino opened May 26, 1978, and turned the island into the most visited tourist destination in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. The casinos provide year-round jobs, tax benefits for the state's elderly and disabled and a percentage of gaming revenues for rebuilding <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> neighborhoods. But even the most optimistic observer can find flaws in how the `` experiment'' turned out, particularly in the deteriorated neighborhoods and shuttered shop windows just steps from the casino hotel lobbies. Before 1978, the saying was, `` The last one to cross the bridge turns out the lights,'' recalls <ORGANIZATION> Atlantic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION> Chief <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Pasquale </PERSON>. The city was dying. Then, in a honky-tonk burst of flashing lights and ringing bells, <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> was reborn. Hundreds of buses and cars now squeeze down narrow streets each day. Big-name entertainers are returning to the showrooms, and Convention Hall throbs with trade shows, heavyweight fights and other extravaganzas. <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Steven </PERSON> <PERSON> Norton </PERSON>, executive vice president of <ORGANIZATION> Resorts </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Casino </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hotel </ORGANIZATION>, recalls the `` exhilarating rush'' when his casino opened as the city's first legal gaming hall. Thousands of people lined up outside, waiting for a chance to drop quarters into slot machines and slap bills onto green felt. Last year, <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> reported more than $ 2.8 billion in gaming revenues and more than 30 million visitors. Twelve casino hotels tower over the city's <LOCATION> Boardwalk </LOCATION> and the once-barren marina section. The <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> gaming industry is the focus of high-stakes Wall Street business deals. And with more than 40,000 casino employees, unemployment in the region has declined to record lows. Yet many tourists cluck in dismay at the decaying houses that still line the city's streets _ thoroughfares made famous by the Monopoly game board. The crime rate also causes concern. In 1976, the <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> to <ORGANIZATION> Rebuild </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Atlantic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> promised that casino gaming would reduce violent crime in the resort. Murders, rapes, assaults and armed robberies actually increased from 10.3 per 1,000 residents in 1977 to a high of 32 in 1981. But when adjusted to account for the millions of visitors and thousands of non-resident employees, the figures settle down to an overall reduced rate. State gaming regulators beam with pride at having kept the casinos relatively free of organized crime's corruption, although some critics feel they wield too much control over the city. Others suggest <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> needs more control _ specifically, a regional or state authority to run city government. The current power struggle among state, county and local officials has delayed two important projects: a proposed new convention center and a larger airport. `` The city itself has not redeveloped as quickly as everyone hoped,'' said Casino Control Commissioner <PERSON> Valerie </PERSON> <PERSON> Armstrong </PERSON>. `` There was a great deal of optimism in 1976 when the referendum passed that things would move quickly, but it's disappointing to see what is potentially a beautiful city not go anywhere.'' <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> was languishing, the victim of broadening travel horizons made possible by cheaper airfares, when the notion of legalized gaming surfaced as a way to rebuild. A referendum to legalize gambling statewide failed in 1974; a second ballot question, limiting gaming to <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, was approved by <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> voters Nov. 2, 1976. The casinos have generally found <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> profitable. But the city never revitalized enough to improve its appearance beyond the casinos. While the suburbs are booming with shopping centers and housing developments, <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> still has no movie theater that is n't pornographic and only one well-worn supermarket Houses on prime waterfront lots are dilapidated, owned mostly by speculators who hoped a decade ago _ and still hope _ to reap huge profits. And what development has taken place has not pleased everyone. The Rev. <PERSON> Dudley </PERSON> <PERSON> Sarfaty </PERSON>, an original member of the `` Casinos: No Dice!'' anti-gambling group, still believes that `` a lot of the local people gambling was supposed to save were driven away.'' Others want to preserve the old <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> of grand seaside hotels, the <ORGANIZATION> Miss </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pageant </ORGANIZATION>, Boardwalk rolling chairs and ocean breezes. `` The worst thing to happen to <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> was perhaps the failure to properly plan and protect the <LOCATION> Boardwalk </LOCATION> frontage architecturally so there would have been something other than solid masonry walls,'' said <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> historian <PERSON> Adrian </PERSON> <PERSON> Phillips </PERSON>. In a similar vein, former Gov. <PERSON> Brendan </PERSON> <PERSON> Byrne </PERSON>, who ushered in casino gambling, said <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> needs to focus more attention on becoming an overall resort instead of just a casino town. `` <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> has contributed to the new, exciting image of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> as a state that's not just a turnpike between <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>,'' he said. `` But <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> needs to become a fun place to visit even if you're not going to a casino.'' Ten years ago, local business owners believed they would profit from the casinos next door. Most did not, primarily because the casinos became self-contained cities. `` Competitors in the wagering business argued that it was n't safe for people to visit <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>,'' said <PERSON> Norton </PERSON> of Resorts `` But we found that as long as you could provide a safe, indoor environment, we could create whatever atmosphere we wanted inside.'' Despite the competition, some local businesses survived. <PERSON> Arnold </PERSON> <PERSON> Orsatti </PERSON>, a restaurateur, said he discovered `` there's room for everybody.'' `` There are too many people who think negatively,'' he said. `` We're doing very well. A lot of the big spenders would rather go outside of the casino than wait in line.'' <PERSON> Cora </PERSON> <PERSON> Boggs </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Community </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organizations </ORGANIZATION>, recalled that `` too many people in <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, including myself, were resentful for a long while of the casinos because we could n't see anything else happening.'' But now that funds from the <ORGANIZATION> Casino </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reinvestment </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Authority </ORGANIZATION> are beginning to rebuild beleaguered neighborhoods, Mrs. <PERSON> Boggs </PERSON> said, `` The attitude is changing.'' Former Mayor <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Lazarow </PERSON> helped push through the gambling proposal. `` I'm proud of what I've done,'' <PERSON> Lazarow </PERSON> said. `` There's a lot more opportunity here now, a lot of decent jobs. Maybe they're not all the best in the world, but a family can make a living here now. `` I think we revived a fast-dying city.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880526-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-26-88 0801EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     05-26 0951</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0999</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in The News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actress <PERSON> Priscilla </PERSON> <PERSON> Presley </PERSON> says she's incensed over reports that her ex-husband <PERSON> Elvis </PERSON> <PERSON> Presley </PERSON> is alive and in seclusion. Such claims by `` supposedly reputable journalists,'' she said, are nonsense and harmful to herself and 20-year-old daughter, <PERSON> Lisa </PERSON> <PERSON> Marie </PERSON>, <PERSON> Elvis </PERSON>' only child. <PERSON> Miss </PERSON> <PERSON> Presley </PERSON>, who was married to <PERSON> Elvis </PERSON> from 1967 to 1972, said Wednesday she was referring to <ORGANIZATION> KABC-TV </ORGANIZATION>'s four-part series called `` Is Elvis Alive?'' The report mentioned <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> author <PERSON> Gail </PERSON> <PERSON> Giorgio </PERSON>, whose book, `` The Most Incredible Elvis Presley Story Ever Told,'' purports the King of Rock' n' Roll may still be swinging. Ms. <PERSON> Giorgio </PERSON> claims she has an audio tape of <PERSON> Elvis </PERSON> speaking in 1980. Presley died in 1977, four years after <PERSON> Priscilla </PERSON> <PERSON> Presley </PERSON> divorced him. `` It infuriates me that certain journalists have decided to exploit <PERSON> Elvis </PERSON> <PERSON> Presley </PERSON>'s death merely for the sake of newspaper sales and higher ratings,'' Miss <PERSON> Presley </PERSON> said. The <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> station's news director, <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> <PERSON> Crofoot </PERSON>, said, `` It is n't <ORGANIZATION> KABC </ORGANIZATION>'s claim that <PERSON> Elvis </PERSON> is alive. It would be ludicrous for us to say that.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>INDIANAPOLIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Ryan </PERSON> <PERSON> White </PERSON> does n't have his driver's license yet, but the 16-year-old AIDS victim happily accepted the keys to his own car as he was honored for his `` ennobling'' courage. <PERSON> Ryan </PERSON> received the black 1987 Chevrolet Cavalier from the <ORGANIZATION> Indiana </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Independent </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Automobile </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dealers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> on Wednesday. `` <PERSON> Ryan </PERSON> has shown that the ordinary things in life can be ennobling. He has the kind of courage that I think most of us would like to have,'' said the association's president, <PERSON> Fritz </PERSON> <PERSON> Kreutzinger </PERSON>. `` I just want to tell everybody thanks,'' <PERSON> Ryan </PERSON> said. When asked what he planned to do with the car, he replied, `` Drive it. I'm going to go anywhere and everywhere. <PERSON> Ryan </PERSON>, who contracted AIDS through blood products used in the treatment of his hemophilia, won a long legal battle to stay in public school after officials in <LOCATION> Kokomo </LOCATION> banned him from classes in 1985. He has completed driver's education classes and plans to get his license June 9.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Jade </PERSON> <PERSON> Jagger </PERSON>, the 16-year-old daughter of <ORGANIZATION> Rolling </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Stone </ORGANIZATION> rock singer <PERSON> Mick </PERSON> <PERSON> Jagger </PERSON> and his ex-wife <PERSON> Bianca </PERSON>, was expelled from her English boarding school for allegedly sneaking off for a nighttime meeting with her boyfriend. <PERSON> Mavis </PERSON> <PERSON> Hunter </PERSON>, deputy headmistress of <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mary </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> at <LOCATION> Calne </LOCATION>, said Miss <PERSON> Jagger </PERSON> and another 16-year-old at the all-girls school were reported missing from their dormitory in the early hours Wednesday. Police were called to the school but the two returned a short time later, Miss <PERSON> Hunter </PERSON> said. `` They have been expelled for a flagrant breach of rules,'' she said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Ivana </PERSON> <PERSON> Trump </PERSON> may have already made her fortune in the land of opportunity, but the transition from immigrant to <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> citizen was n't complete until she stood before a judge with 141 other naturalized citizens. With her at Wednesday's ceremony was her husband, billionaire developer <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Trump </PERSON>, who listened as Judge <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Haight </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> told the new citizens that `` by your presence, <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> is vastly enriched.'' `` I'm very proud of my wife,'' a beaming <PERSON> Trump </PERSON> said. `` I'm very proud of my country. It's a great country and that's where a great woman should be. Now they're both matched up perfectly.'' Mrs. <PERSON> Trump </PERSON>, a 38-year-old Austrian-born, former Czechoslovakian national, came to this country 10 years ago after working as a model in <LOCATION> Montreal </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>OAKLAND, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Mother </PERSON> <PERSON> Teresa </PERSON>, the 77-year-old `` saint of the gutters,'' gave a spiritual lift to AIDS patients during a visit to a day center opened by her religious order to help victims of the disease. `` The disease should not make us bitter or angry,'' said the Yugoslav-born Roman Catholic nun and founder of the <ORGANIZATION> Missionaries </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Charity </ORGANIZATION>, which in October opened `` The Center'' in one of <ORGANIZATION> Oakland </ORGANIZATION>'s most crime-plagued neighborhoods `` We must accept -LRB- AIDS -RRB- ... make use of it, not as a punishment, but as a thing that gives us peace,'' she said during the visit Wednesday. The center offers alternative healing, prayer groups, counseling and some in-home care. <PERSON> Mother </PERSON> <PERSON> Teresa </PERSON> won the 1979 Nobel Peace Prize for her worldwide effort on behalf of the poor and rejected.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>ST. LOUIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 `` Spuds Mackenzie'' may not be there, but <ORGANIZATION> Anheuser-Busch </ORGANIZATION>, the world's largest brewery, has enlisted celebrities like <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Tucker </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jill </PERSON> <PERSON> Eikenberry </PERSON> of `` L.A. Law'' to discuss responsible drinking on a new video. `` This is a special effort to educate the public about responsible alcohol consumption using top-flight <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION> entertainers,'' <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> LaMonica </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Anheuser-Busch </ORGANIZATION>'s senior vice president for industry affairs, said Wednesday. The 27-minute program, titled `` Your Alcohol IQ: Celebrities Challenge the Moderation Generation,'' will be distributed to 25,000 stores nationwide for free loan to customers. Other celebrities who plan to appear are <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Dysart </PERSON>, <PERSON> Allyce </PERSON> <PERSON> Beasley </PERSON>, <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Bosson </PERSON>, <PERSON> Patrick </PERSON> <PERSON> Duffy </PERSON>, <PERSON> Marla </PERSON> <PERSON> Gibbs </PERSON>, <PERSON> Arte </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>, <PERSON> Lisa </PERSON> <PERSON> Hartman </PERSON>, <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Walden </PERSON> and <PERSON> Mickey </PERSON> <PERSON> Dolenz </PERSON>. <PERSON> Spuds </PERSON> <PERSON> Mackenzie </PERSON>, the charismatic canine from the company's `` Bud Light'' commercials, was not among those listed by the company.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actress <PERSON> Ali </PERSON> <PERSON> MacGraw </PERSON> and actor-director <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Landon </PERSON> were among 200 coastal residents who cheered as a commission gave preliminary approval for a measure creating the City of <LOCATION> Malibu </LOCATION>. Residents of the exclusive beach community, which is part of <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>, have tried three times since 1976 to incorporate as an independent city. During testimony, <PERSON> Miss </PERSON> <PERSON> McGraw </PERSON>, honorary mayor of the community 30 miles west of downtown and a 15-year resident, said she believes <LOCATION> Malibu </LOCATION> residents should have control of development. The <ORGANIZATION> Local </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Formation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> voted 6-1 Wednesday to approve residents' petition to incorporate as the City of <LOCATION> Malibu </LOCATION>. The measure also must be approved by the <ORGANIZATION> Los </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Angeles </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supervisors </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880526-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-26-88 0258EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Communist-McDonalds     05-26 0590</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Communist-McDonalds,0608</SECOND>
<HEAD>Communist McDonald's Workers Can't Stand Heat; Get Out Of Kitchen</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By DUSAN STOJANOVIC</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BELGRADE, Yugoslavia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The first McDonald's to open in a communist country has run into an unexpected problem: Trained employees are quitting because they find they have to work like Westerners and get paid like east Europeans. Since the American fast food chain opened its outlet in <LOCATION> Belgrade </LOCATION> in March, 40 employees _ about one-third of its workers _ have voluntarily left their jobs despite a high unemployment rate in <LOCATION> Yugoslavia </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Predrag </PERSON> <PERSON> Dostanic </PERSON>, managing director of the restaurant, blames illusions about the West gleaned from <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> movies shown on Yugoslav TV for the dropout rate. `` That is all a result of a drastically incorrect concept about international businesses, implanted in people's minds by such American TV series as ` Dynasty,''' <PERSON> Dostanic </PERSON> said. `` Those who have left us thought they would earn high wages only by virtue of working for an American enterprise,'' said <PERSON> Vesna </PERSON> <PERSON> Milosevic </PERSON>, an official of <ORGANIZATION> Genex </ORGANIZATION>, the <LOCATION> Yugoslav </LOCATION> state enterprise that entered into a joint venture agreement with <ORGANIZATION> McDonald </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION>. `` Those young people who quit probably also expected they could do their jobs the Yugoslav way _ relax at work but still receive wages,'' <PERSON> Dostanic </PERSON> added. According to a recent domestic survey, average Yugoslavs work efficiently for only half of their eight-hour workday. The rest of the time is spent reading newspapers, conducting private business or having interminable private chats with collegues over coffee. The fast-food outlet, located on a downtown square, has drawn huge crowds since it opened March 23 to post a European record for <ORGANIZATION> McDonald </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> restaurants by selling an average 6,000 meals daily for the first month of operation. The only other European branch matching the <LOCATION> Belgrade </LOCATION> record is the McDonald's in <LOCATION> Budapest </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>, which opened a month after the Yugoslav outlet. With demand growing fast, it is serving about 6,000 people a day. Employees are so overworked that store manager <PERSON> Agnes </PERSON> <PERSON> Rapalics </PERSON> decided the only way to cope was to close at 8 p.m., three hours early. Her decision swiftly prompted moans from Hungarians, including a sour reader who wrote to the <ORGANIZATION> Magyar </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hirlap </ORGANIZATION> newspaper asking, `` Does every wonder only last three days?'' When the <ORGANIZATION> McDonald </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> restaurant opened in <LOCATION> Belgrade </LOCATION>, police were called in to keep watch on the lines of customers snaking around the bloc and to limit the number of people entering the premises to avoid overcrowding. `` The work was so hard that I could not stand it any more,'' said a former employee, who asked not to be identified. `` If my salary was adequate to the work, I might have stayed.'' The restaurant employees, mostly young people trained to work on counters and in the kitchen, receive about $ 170 a month, which is slightly above the Yugoslav average. `` We have no problem replacing those who have quit with new staff, except that the newcomers have to get their training while doing their work,'' said <PERSON> Milosevic </PERSON>. About 1.1 million people, or about 15 percent of the work force, are registered as unemployed in <LOCATION> Yugoslavia </LOCATION>. In <LOCATION> Belgrade </LOCATION> alone, about 80,000 are looking for jobs. `` Maybe there is something good in all these unexpected staff problems,'' said <PERSON> Milosevic </PERSON>. `` Only the best workers will survive,'' she added. <ORGANIZATION> McDonald </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Genex </ORGANIZATION> contributed $ 1 million each for the flagship restaurant. They also share the profits equally, even though it is managed by Yugoslavs. The American corporation plans to open five more restaurants in <LOCATION> Yugoslavia </LOCATION> in the next five years.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880526-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-26-88 0258EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Summit-Amerika     05-26 0767</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Summit-Amerika,0787</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bridging The Gap: Pepsi, Jeans Show US Influence On Soviet Society</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By ANDREW KATELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MOSCOW (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Images of <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> dancing to rock music in a <ORGANIZATION> Pepsi </ORGANIZATION> commercial flicker across the Soviet television screen, and <PERSON> Levi </PERSON>'s jeans hug the hips of young Russians in a crowded subway car. Amerika, as the Soviets call it, has arrived. `` Far behind the Iron Curtain, we were able to develop a pro-Western mentality, and what, tell me, could be more Western than <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>?'' emigre author <PERSON> Vasily </PERSON> <PERSON> Aksyonov </PERSON> wrote about his youth in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> of the 1950s. Even the Cyrillic alphabet has n't prevented what the Russians call <LOCATION> Amerikanizatsia </LOCATION>. `` Jeansi,'' `` stop,'' `` break dance,'' `` OK'' and one of the latest signs of the times _ `` stress'' _ are now part of the Russian lexicon. Soviet Communist Party General Secretary <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> has encouraged his people to learn more about <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>. To demonstrate his sincerity, he has allowed more travel to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, ended the jamming of <ORGANIZATION> Voice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION> broadcasts and removed barriers to joint business deals. In April, a record 1,200 Soviets, most of them Jews, were allowed to visit relatives in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. An additional 1,000 Soviets traveled there on official business. Before <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>, only a handful of Soviets visited the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> monthly. The 1985 <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> summit gave an official stamp of approval to cultural agreements and `` people-to-people'' exchanges. Under the agreements, Soviet and <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> lawyers, doctors, students, musicians, scientists and teachers have visited each other. In some instances, the exchanges reflect a Soviet desire for American help in tackling social problems such as alcoholism and drug addiction, problems the government previously denied existed. At the grass-roots level, Soviets need little encouragement to talk about things American. When introduced to an American, many Soviets immediately start with the questions, on everything from war and peace to the availability of hamburgers. A taxi driver's reaction when a passenger introduced himself as an American was to run down the American authors she loved _ <PERSON> Ernest </PERSON> <PERSON> Hemingway </PERSON>, <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Twain </PERSON>, <PERSON> Ray </PERSON> <PERSON> Bradbury </PERSON>. Collections of these authors in translation occupy prominent places on the bookshelves in some Soviet apartments. More contemporary American authors are lesser known because their works still are n't available in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Levi </PERSON>'s jeans are required attire in certain circles. And some of those who manage to get an American candy bar, soft drink or pack of cigarettes proudly display the empty packaging in their living rooms. Many Soviets are turning to videotapes for a glimpse of <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>. Tapes of movies such as `` Police Academy'' and `` Rambo,'' dubbed in Russian, are passed among friends in a thriving black market where blank cassettes cost at least 50 rubles -LRB- $ 80 -RRB-, or one quarter of an average monthly salary. The black market also feeds on young Soviets' thirst for American rock music. Records of <PERSON> Madonna </PERSON> and <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> fetch exorbitant sums. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s music videos have appeared on Soviet television, and his <ORGANIZATION> Pepsi </ORGANIZATION> commercials hit the airwaves in mid-May during broadcast of a five-part series on the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. Officially sponsored concerts by American musicians such as <PERSON> Billy </PERSON> <PERSON> Joel </PERSON>, <PERSON> Dave </PERSON> <PERSON> Brubeck </PERSON> and the <ORGANIZATION> Doobie </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Brothers </ORGANIZATION> have become major happenings. At the same time, some Soviet rock stars are traveling to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Boris </PERSON> <PERSON> Grebenshchikov </PERSON>, the hippy-like leader of the <LOCATION> Leningrad </LOCATION> rock band Aquarium, is scheduled to record an album in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> this summer. The end of Soviet jamming of Voice of <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> broadcasts in May 1987 opened a new source of information about life in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. Satellite television discussions with American studio audiences also have given Soviets a chance to learn first-hand about life in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. Soviet television's widely watched evening news program `` Vremya'' has shown features on child care, automobiles and sports in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, and in mid-May Soviet television broadcast a series moderated by former <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> resident <PERSON> Vladimir </PERSON> <PERSON> Posner </PERSON>. But even though Soviet media coverage about the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has become more balanced under <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>, reports about crime, unemployment, racism and the poor are still common. In politics, Americans and Soviets still have sharp differences. But for many of the Soviets who viewed <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> as a warmonger a few years ago the rhetoric has eased since he signed an agreement with <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> last December to eliminate all medium-range nuclear missiles. `` We have no propaganda of hatred toward Americans, no disrespect of Americans,'' <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> told a group of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> teachers of Russian who met with him at the <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION> last August. `` One can not find them here, either in politics or in teaching.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880526-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-26-88 0802EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lites     05-26 0664</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lites,0689</SECOND>
<HEAD>On The Light Side</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: ``Plimouth'' in first item cq.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>PLYMOUTH, Mass. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 It's been more than 300 years since this town saw so much struggle over restraint, but Plimoth Plantation visitors could soon be drinking beer and wine after a brief spell of temperance at the tourist spot. For a while, it looked like the prudish reputation of those early settlers had come back to haunt the village, which offers a glimpse of 17th century life after <LOCATION> Plymouth </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rock </LOCATION>. But Tuesday night, after several go-rounds, the <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Selectmen </ORGANIZATION> approved a limited liquor license for the plantation. The board twice rejected requests for a license to serve all types of liquor year-round or for one-day licenses. The license approved Tuesday applies only from April to November, when the plantation visitor center is open. It still requires state approval. The 41-year-old private, non-profit tourist spot first served alcohol four years ago at a snack bar. But that license was discontinued when the snack bar was torn down. With the opening of a new visitors center and 200-seat restaurant, the plantation management hoped to draw more business by opening in the off-hours for business conferences, during which guests would expect alcohol on the menu. In the past, some residents objected that alcohol was not in keeping with the Pilgrim spirit. But in fact, the Pilgrims cooked with wine and regarded beer as more healthful than water, plantation officials said. However, plantation spokeswoman <PERSON> Sarah </PERSON> <PERSON> Mann </PERSON> said most of the arguments against a comprehensive liquor license came from nearby restaurants and bars.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>ALBANY, N.Y. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The state <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> agreed with the saying, `` you ca n't take it with you,'' and approved a bill that would allow elderly lottery winners to receive their jackpots sooner than younger winners. The bill approved Wednesday and sent to the Assembly would allow jackpot winners older than age 65 to take their earnings in one lump sum or in periodic payments during their expected lifetime. `` The usual 20-year payoff on a lottery prize will not always result in a total benefit to the winner who is over 65, as he may not live to receive the full benefit,'' said a memo on the bill. `` The fact that the unpaid balance would be paid to his estate is of little consolation to many elderly winners who may wish to fully enjoy the fruits of their good fortune,'' it said. But <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Quinn </PERSON>, director of the state Lottery Division, said he opposes the bill because it would substantially reduce jackpots. For example, he said, the jackpot up for grabs Wednesday was $ 3 million, but `` I do n't have $ 3 million to give them, I have $ 1.4 million. The difference is interest money.'' A winner currently would receive 21 annual payments of $ 114,000 after taxes, said <PERSON> Quinn </PERSON>. If someone opted to take the prize in a $ 1.4 million lump sum, they would owe about $ 580,000 in taxes, he said. <PERSON> Quinn </PERSON> said he did n't believe any state lotteries offer the lump-sum option. The average million-dollar lottery winner in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> is 49 years old, said <PERSON> Quinn </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WEAVERVILLE, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 There are no traffic lights in all of peaceful <LOCATION> Trinity </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> _ and it's going to stay that way, despite a state suggestion one is needed near a proposed shopping center. When an environmental impact report was prepared for a 140,000-square-foot mall east of <LOCATION> Weaverville </LOCATION>, the state <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> said it `` would have some definite traffic impacts,'' and suggested that `` the future need for a traffic signal should be considered at this time.'' But that's not how the <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> county sees it. In fact, says <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Miller </PERSON>, county director of planning and public works, the lack of traffic lights `` is a source of local pride.'' The county adopted a regional study in 1986 that makes the feelings of its 12,500 residents clear: No traffic signals and no widening of Highway 299, the main drag through <LOCATION> Weaverville </LOCATION>, the county seat.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880526-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-26-88 0259EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--Israel-Accident     05-26 0167</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Israel-Accident,0171</SECOND>
<HEAD>Three Israeli Workers Killed In Ship Accident</HEAD>
<DATELINE>JERUSALEM (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Three Israeli longshoremen were killed and one was badly injured by poisonous gas in the hull of a Belgian coal ship they were cleaning in <LOCATION> Hadera </LOCATION> port, <ORGANIZATION> Israel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Television </ORGANIZATION> said. The <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> named a commission of inquiry to investigate the accident on Wednesday aboard the vessel <ORGANIZATION> Orinocco </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Antwerpen </ORGANIZATION>, it said. The vessel had been docked at <LOCATION> Hadera </LOCATION>, 30 miles north of <LOCATION> Tel </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Aviv </LOCATION>, since Sunday to unload its cargo of Australian coal. The dock workers were descending into one of the nine storage tanks to prepare it for reloading. `` The door was open and one went down. We did n't hear him from the top so a second went down. After him a third, a fourth. Finally the fifth realized something was wrong and alerted the ship's crew,'' <PERSON> Uri </PERSON> <PERSON> Binder </PERSON>, manager of the cleaning company, told <ORGANIZATION> Israel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Television </ORGANIZATION> It was not immediately clear what type of gas was involved or where it came from.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880526-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-26-88 0033EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-LeopardAttack     05-26 0248</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Leopard Attack,0255</SECOND>
<HEAD>Entertainer's Leopard Escapes And Kills 2-Year-Old Daughter</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NASHVILLE, Tenn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A leopard owned by a rock singer who uses animals in his nightclub act escaped from its cage Wednesday and killed the entertainer's 2-year-old daughter, officials said. Five leopards escaped from <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Savage </PERSON>'s home on 200 acres near <LOCATION> Ashland </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, but all were captured by Wednesday night, said police Lt. <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Blackmore </PERSON>. <PERSON> Nikka </PERSON> <PERSON> Savage </PERSON>, mauled in her family's front yard, died at <ORGANIZATION> Vanderbilt </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> as a result of blood loss and massive injuries to her head and neck, said hospital spokeswoman <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> <PERSON> Humphrey </PERSON>. The leopard involved in the attack was tranquilized by wildlife officials, and died while being transported away, <ORGANIZATION> Metro </ORGANIZATION> <LOCATION> Nashville </LOCATION> police said. Savage, who performs heavy metal rock music in leather and wild make-up, uses the leopards in his nightclub act. Savage was in <LOCATION> Las </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vegas </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Nev. </LOCATION>, but police said he was on his way back to <LOCATION> Nashville </LOCATION> after being informed of the attack. A police helicopter, a professional wildcat handler and about 40 police officers joined in the search before the last escaped animal, a 40-pound black leopard, was captured Wednesday night. Earlier, Police Chief <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Casey </PERSON> urged parents to keep their children indoors, saying, `` They tell us it's not dangerous but they said that about the animal that killed the little girl.'' Savage was treated at a <LOCATION> Nashville </LOCATION> hospital in 1984 after a boa constrictor choked him during an act in which he wrapped snakes around his neck.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880526-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-26-88 0821EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-SummitSpruce-Up     05-26 0867</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Summit Spruce-Up,0887</SECOND>
<HEAD>Moscow Dresses Itself Up For Superpower Summit</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By MARK J. PORUBCANSKY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MOSCOW (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 If the white satellite dishes pointing west from the Rossiya Hotel past the Kremlin's ancient church domes did n't indicate something unusual was going on, the new paint and pavement along Vorovsky Street might <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> is being inundated with <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> officials and Western correspondents bringing the latest technology to cover President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s five-day visit, beginning Sunday. And in age-old tradition, officials are painting, paving and otherwise sprucing up to ensure that <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and those accompanying him get the best possible view of the Soviet capital. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> left <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> on Wednesday for a three-night stopover in <LOCATION> Helsinki </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Finland </LOCATION>, before flying to the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> for his summit with <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION> leader <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>. He comes to <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> at a time when the city traditionally is trying to right itself after another long, cold winter. The truck traffic that roars along the Garden Ring Road slows to a crawl as workers fill another spring crop of potholes, and scaffolding goes up on buildings everywhere. Red tulips planted in squares and along boulevards are in bloom, as are the lilacs bordering sidewalks and apartment buildings around the city. Stately chestnut trees are in bloom on the <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION> lawns. The sun rises about 5 a.m. and does n't set until almost 10 p.m., leaving a purple glow in the sky until almost midnight. But this year the spring cleaning has taken on a particularly urgent air around several of the places <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> will visit. The short street leading from the Garden Ring Road to <ORGANIZATION> Spaso </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> ambassador's residence where <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> will stay, has been repaired for the first time in years. Pavement torn out months ago has been replaced, and almost all the barricades that narrowed traffic for two blocks have been removed. Vorovsky Street also is undergoing a major facelift. Nearly every building along the street from the <ORGANIZATION> Writers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION>, which <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> is scheduled to visit, to the <ORGANIZATION> Soviet </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> building several blocks away appears to have been given a new coat of paint. The Foreign Ministry press center, where <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>'s most important press conferences are held, has been undergoing repairs for weeks to improve the seats and the acoustics. Officials promised last week that it would be finished in time for the summit, and a pre-summit news conference was held there this week. When a reporter asked one of the speakers for a specific example of changes wrought by <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s reforms, however, the microphones and armchair earphones installed for simultaneous translation suddenly failed, forcing a premature end to the session. The <ORGANIZATION> Tass </ORGANIZATION> news agency said newspapers and magazines from around the world will be available at the press center next week, not just the usual selection of papers from the Soviet bloc. At the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION>, some last-minute painting was going on, and workers cleared out the courtyard in front of the empty chancery in the new red-brick compound. The building has been the source of dispute between the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> since <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials discovered that it was honeycombed with Soviet listening devices. It never has been put into use. At stores, Soviet citizens said they had noticed no increases in supplies to cut down on the lines that gather in the streets. One young woman joked that closer to <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s arrival, `` maybe they'll even bring out sugar'' which has been in short supply in the capital and rationed elsewhere in the country because of moonshining, hoarding and price increase <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Gennady </PERSON> <PERSON> I. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gerasimov </PERSON> said in an interview with the newspaper <ORGANIZATION> Vechernaya </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Moskva </ORGANIZATION> that about 3,000 foreign journalists are expected for the summit, half from print media and half from radio and television. <PERSON> Gerasimov </PERSON> said the <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Communications </ORGANIZATION> could not handle the demands of the Western television companies, so they wre permitted to bring in satellite dishes and other sophisticated equipment normally under strict government control. The American television networks have crammed room after room of the mammoth Rossiya Hotel with shiny silver equipment cases, preparing to broadcast their evening news programs from the Soviet capital. With some 5,000 Soviet and foreign journalists accredited to cover the event, the summit press corps is the largest to gather here since the 1980 Olympics, Soviet officials say. <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> dissidents say they have noticed another similarity between the two events: Many deemed `` undesirable'' by the authorities were forced to leave town. Eight years ago, they included prostitutes, speculators and other criminals, as well as dissidents. Father <PERSON> Valery </PERSON> <PERSON> Lapkovsky </PERSON>, a Russian Orthodox priest from the Crimean city of <LOCATION> Kerch </LOCATION>, arrived in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> last Friday and was told by authorities the next day to leave, said Russian Orthodox activist <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON> <PERSON> Ogorodnikov </PERSON>. <PERSON> Lapkovsky </PERSON> was put into a mental hospital and diagnosed as schizophrenic in 1966 after approaching the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Embassy with an appeal to then-President <PERSON> Lyndon </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> to help him leave the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. Soviet officials also have set up roadblocks at the edge of the city to inspect automobiles. The aim is to keep down the number of broken-down cars on the streets of <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> during the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> visit.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880526-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-26-88 0312EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-StarStudent     05-26 0406</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Star Student,0418</SECOND>
<HEAD>High School Dropout Ends Up As Valedictorian</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WHEATON, Md. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A high school dropout who saw two of her sons quit school as teen-agers has graduated from college with straight A's. <PERSON> Janet </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>, 43, of <LOCATION> Wheaton </LOCATION>, earned a perfect 4.0 grade average and was valedictorian at Tuesday's commencement for the <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Education </ORGANIZATION> at the University of <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION>. `` I ca n't come down yet. It's the highest point of my life so far,'' she said Wednesday. She had quit high school at age 16 to get married and have a family. Years later, she earned a high school equivalency degree. Mrs. <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> had worked as a teacher's aide and secretary before deciding it was n't too late to try for a college degree in elementary education. She received an associate's degree after attending night classes at <ORGANIZATION> Montgomery </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Rockville </LOCATION> for three years. `` When I went to the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Maryland </ORGANIZATION>, I won a $ 5,000 scholarship and all these wonderful things started happening,'' she said. `` It's been fabulous.'' In her graduation address, she thanked her fellow students for including her in activities and treating her as one of them. `` They'd say, ` Come on, <PERSON> Janet </PERSON>, we're going to have something to eat together.' They wanted me to go. That felt good. They did n't make me feel different. Her two older children, ages 25 and 26, dropped out of high school but also received high school equivalency degrees. Her third son is 15. Her husband retired with a disability after working as a firefighter. She also has a young grandchild. `` It was a struggle without my income for the past two years, but we said, ` We can do it' and we did,'' she said. `` It was hard especially with the family. There were things I could n't do for the children that I wanted to.'' Mrs. <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> hopes her scholastic success will motivate her youngest son to try harder in school. `` It did seem to have an effect on him. I really want him to continue his education,'' she said. Mrs. <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> has a contract with the <LOCATION> Montgomery </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> school system to teach in an elementary school this fall. She is now working as a substitute teacher at Head Start. `` I put a lot of effort into it, and worked a little harder,'' she said. `` Being a little bit older and just living, you learn. And I did n't have to worry about toga parties and sororities.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880526-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-26-88 0310EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Summit-Parallels Bjt   05-26 0738</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Summit-Parallels, Bjt,740</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHINGTON WIRE: Eisenhower Like Reagan Sought Arms Pact as Final
Legacy</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By W. DALE NELSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The president, nearing the end of his eight years in office, hoped to leave an arms accord as his final legacy after a summit meeting with the leader of the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. The Soviet leader, under attack by conservatives in his own country for reforms he was attempting, responded sharply to what he described as confrontational statements from <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. The year was 1960. The president was <PERSON> Dwight </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Eisenhower </PERSON>. The Soviet leader was <PERSON> Nikita </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Khrushchev </PERSON>. The summit ended in failure. There are some obvious differences between that summit and next week's meeting between President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION> leader <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>. What wrecked the 1960 summit, or at least contributed to its collapse, was the furor that arose after an American U-2 spy plane was forced down in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> and its pilot was captured. There is nothing like that on the horizon now, although the Soviets are as adamant against <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s Star Wars missile defense system as they were against <PERSON> Eisenhower </PERSON>'s `` open skies'' plan to give the superpowers access to each other's air space. Still, the resemblances are haunting. <PERSON> Eisenhower </PERSON>, hoping for a comprehensive ban on all nuclear testing, told French President <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Gaulle </PERSON>, `` What a splendid exit it would be for me to end up ... with an agreement between East and West.'' <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> hopes for a pact by the end of his term to curb the intercontinental ballistic missiles that have flourished since <PERSON> Eisenhower </PERSON>'s day. <PERSON> Khrushchev </PERSON>, who had unmasked the excesses of <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Stalin </PERSON> in his landmark `` secret speech,'' was making modest economic and political reforms in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> and urging dialogue with the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. Similarly, <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> has pushed his policies of `` glasnost,'' or openness, and `` perestroika,'' or reconstruction. `` My father was the first to ` shake' the Soviet bureaucratic society,'' <PERSON> Khrushchev </PERSON>'s son, <PERSON> Sergei </PERSON>, told the Yugoslav daily <ORGANIZATION> Vjesnik </ORGANIZATION> in an interview published this month. `` I hope <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> succeeds where my father did not.'' Like <PERSON> Khrushchev </PERSON>'s, the reforms initiated by <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> appear to have encountered resistance from the old guard in the Kremlin. Both Soviet leaders reacted sharply to statements by their <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> counterparts. After <PERSON> Eisenhower </PERSON> acknowledged the U-2 flights, <PERSON> Khrushchev </PERSON> said the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> president appeared to be `` boasting arrogantly about what the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> could do and would do'' and demonstrating that the Americans `` did n't give a damn about anyone else, that they would pursue only their selfish goals.'' And when <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> accused the Soviets of continued expansionism abroad and repression at home in a speech in <LOCATION> Springfield </LOCATION><LOCATION> , </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mass. </LOCATION>, last month, <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> responded, `` We have so far been showing restraint, but if we reciprocate _ and we can do so over a wide range of issues _ the atmosphere in Soviet-American relations can become such that it will make it no longer possible to solve any further issues.'' Some observers have interpreted <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s remarks as a deliberate display of toughness designed for Soviet as well as American audiences. `` Quite possibly there are people around him in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> who do n't like the many concessions he has made to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>,'' said <PERSON> Vladimir </PERSON> <PERSON> Petrov </PERSON>, professor emeritus of international affairs at <ORGANIZATION> George </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> In 1960, too, some suspected the Soviet leader's blustering was an attempt to bolster his strength at home. Retired Gen. <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> <PERSON> Goodpaster </PERSON>, a top aide to <PERSON> Eisenhower </PERSON>, said, `` I do recall that we thought at the time that he might just be vulnerable because of meeting with <PERSON> Eisenhower </PERSON> and the favorable attitude he had toward <PERSON> Eisenhower </PERSON> and this might have put him in some danger and put him under some pressure in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>.'' The arms control issue, as well as the status of <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION>, had been on the agenda for a four-power summit meeting _ the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> _ in <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> on May 16. It broke up in disaster. <PERSON> Khrushchev </PERSON>, pounding a table so hard he upset a bottle of mineral water, denounced the U-2 flights and `` the lackeys of imperialism.'' He also withdrew his invitation to <PERSON> Eisenhower </PERSON> to visit the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> the following month. <PERSON> Eisenhower </PERSON>, disappointed in his hopes for an East-West agreement, later said he might have been `` lulled into overconfidence.''
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Dale </PERSON> <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON> has covered the White House for The Associated Press since 1984.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880526-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-26-88 0311EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-NearCollision Bjt   05-26 0602</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Near Collision, Bjt,600</SECOND>
<HEAD>Passenger Jets Came Within 300 Feet Of Each Other</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By H. JOSEF HEBERT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
