<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880717-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-17-88 2326EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p AM-CVN--Parties 1stLd-Writethru   07-17 0793</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-CVN--Parties, 1st Ld-Writethru,820</SECOND>
<HEAD>Party Faithful Take Time to Party</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: TOPS with 13 grafs to UPDATE with Sunday evening parties;
PICKS UP 6th graf pvs bgng, `The biggest'</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By CAROLYN S. CARLSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ATLANTA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The air-conditioned walkway was the extravagance most appreciated by the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> political leaders and <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> media elite lingering by the mock newsstand bars at the <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> newspapers' welcoming party Sunday night. `` Even the <ORGANIZATION> Ringling </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Brothers </ORGANIZATION>' tent is n't air conditioned,'' one guest marveled at the <ORGANIZATION> Cox </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Enterprises </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> party on the eve of the Democratic National Convention. Dozens of invitation-only affairs and 56 parties for individual state delegations kept thousands of delegates and journalists entertained on the hot and humid day. Prospective Democratic presidential nominee <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> and his family attended <PERSON> Ted </PERSON> <PERSON> Turner </PERSON>'s crowded party at <ORGANIZATION> CNN </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>, next door to the convention site, before joining a family reunion hosted by his cousin, <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> restaurateur <PERSON> Pano </PERSON> <PERSON> Karatassos </PERSON>. <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> Sen. <PERSON> Ted </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, dining at a separate party at <PERSON> Karatassos </PERSON>' 103 West, stopped by to greet the families of <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> and his vice presidential choice, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> Sen. <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>. Meanwhile, <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s fans jammed the ornate Fox Theater for a fund-raising jazz and gospel concert, listening to music by <PERSON> Nat </PERSON> <PERSON> King </PERSON> <PERSON> Cole </PERSON>'s brother <PERSON> Freddie </PERSON>, an <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> resident, and others for three hours before <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> and his family arrived to rally the faithful. Frigid air pumped into a tent spanning the short walkway between the <ORGANIZATION> Woodruff </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Arts </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> and the High Museum of Art cooled the 3,000 politicians and media honchos attending `` A Special Edition Of <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospitality </ORGANIZATION>,'' hosted by the parent company for <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Atlanta </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Journal </ORGANIZATION> and The Atlanta Constitution. The media chain, founded by 1920 Democratic presidential nominee <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Cox </PERSON>, apparently spared little expense for its party, filling the tent and the lobbies of both buildings with bars and tables overflowing with home-grown delicacies such as peach cheesecake. Sunday's partying completed a weekend of carousing by about 35,000 journalists, lobbyists, staffers, elected officials and political junkies who have descended on <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> for the convention, which opens Monday. All night Saturday, hotels were hopping, bars were packed and lines extended out of dozens of nightclubs and restaurants along <LOCATION> Peachtree </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Street </LOCATION> long past the normal closing time of 2 a.m. The horse-drawn carriages in the downtown hotel district were doing a booming business as hundreds of people wandered streets normally occupied in the early morning hours by the now-scarce homeless. An overflow crowd from a heavy metal nightclub spilled onto nearby railroad tracks, halting a train loaded with revelers. But neither party missed a beat as the train retreated. Private parties ranged from a formal dinner-dance at the home of <PERSON> Anne </PERSON> <PERSON> Cox </PERSON> <PERSON> Chambers </PERSON>, former <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> ambassador to <LOCATION> Belgium </LOCATION> and chairwoman of <ORGANIZATION> Atlanta </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Newspapers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, to an old fashioned `` stump speakin''' with a real stump, mint juleps and ham biscuits, given by <PERSON> Betty </PERSON> <PERSON> Talmadge </PERSON>, former wife of former Sen. <PERSON> Herman </PERSON> <PERSON> Talmadge </PERSON>, and <PERSON> Liz </PERSON> <PERSON> Carpenter </PERSON>, former press secretary to <PERSON> Lady </PERSON> <PERSON> Bird </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>. The biggest affair was a rock' n' roll extravaganza for about 10,000 journalists at the <ORGANIZATION> Georgia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>, featuring plenty of free liquor and dozens of dishes, ranging from hot dogs and egg rolls to <LOCATION> Brunswick </LOCATION> stew and jambalaya. Bandstands scattered throughout the huge exhibition hall showcased such acts as jazz artist <PERSON> Grover </PERSON> <PERSON> Washington </PERSON>, rhythm-and-blues duo <PERSON> Ashford </PERSON> and <PERSON> Simpson </PERSON> and folk rocker <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> Stills </PERSON>. In a brief greeting, Mayor <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> <PERSON> Young </PERSON> extended a special welcome to the kid reporters for the Children's Express, whom he called `` the only uncorrupted, honest, unbiased'' journalists in the hall. Clearly he had missed seeing the Express reporter who raided a fruit display, plopping whole pineapples into a plastic bag. `` We might get hungry later,'' the boy said. <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>'s black community hosted a party for more than 250 black elected officials from across the country at the white-columned mansion of <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> businessman <PERSON> Nathaniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Goldston </PERSON>. Many of those revelers then joined former <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> Mayor <PERSON> Maynard </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> on his `` Midnight Train To <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION>,'' a fund-raiser on the state-owned <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Georgia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Railroad </ORGANIZATION> to benefit <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s 1989 campaign for another stint as mayor. Baseball stars <PERSON> Hank </PERSON> <PERSON> Aaron </PERSON> and <PERSON> Willie </PERSON> <PERSON> Stargell </PERSON> were among the `` celebrity conductors'' at a pre-ride party at the historic <ORGANIZATION> Georgia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Freight </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Depot </ORGANIZATION>, one of the city's few surviving pre-Civil War buildings, before the train chugged out of the depot for an 18-mile loop around the city. During the trip, the crowd from <ORGANIZATION> Metroplex </ORGANIZATION>, a heavy metal nightclub near, spilled onto the tracks. Rather than break up a good party, the train turned around. Few at <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s party noticed the difference. The `` in event'' Saturday probably was former President <PERSON> Jimmy </PERSON> <PERSON> Carter </PERSON>'s party for what he called `` my old friends _ and I use the word carefully _ in the White House press corps.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880717-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-17-88 2331EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-HeatRdp     07-17 0685</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Heat Rdp,0704</SECOND>
<HEAD>Record Heat Bakes Both Coasts</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Record-breaking heat scorched both coasts Sunday, wilting several major league pitchers and sending residents in the normally cool <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION> area streaming to the beaches. The mercury soared to a record 103 degrees in downtown <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION>. It was the city's highest temperature since record keeping began 125 years ago, exceeding the previous mark of 102 degrees set on Oct. 5, 1987. On the <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Coast </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION> hit a record high for the date of 102 degrees, which was also a record fifth day in a row of triple-digit highs. Downtown Baltimore set a record high for the date of 103 degrees. In <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, the heat heightened the danger of fire and and led officials to close <LOCATION> Mount </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Diablo </LOCATION> <LOCATION> State </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Park </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Contra </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Costa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, east of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION>, and parts of <LOCATION> Mount </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Tamalpais </LOCATION>, northwest of the city, officials said. By noon, the parking lot at <LOCATION> Marin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Stinson </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION> was jammed, and motorists inched along several miles of roads leading to the area. <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Weather </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> forecasters said tempertures wo n't fall to normal levels in the 80s until Thursday. Forecaster <PERSON> Daryl </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> blamed the heat on a high-pressure area over the southwestern <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, which he said is keeping cooler <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> air out of the area. Temperatures also soared above 100 in the inland valleys of southern <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, sending many to the beaches despite chilly and overcast coastal conditions. About 100,000 people hit the sands at <LOCATION> Zuma </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION>, where the temperature was about 70 degrees on the beach and in the water, said lifeguard <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Renaud </PERSON>. Crowds also were heavy at <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Monica </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Venice </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Will </PERSON> <PERSON> Rogers </PERSON> and Topanga beaches despite morning temperatures of around 69 degrees and fog that reduced visibility to a mere 100 years, said lifeguard Lt. <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Heineman </PERSON>. `` It was so hot in the valley areas, they just came to the beach anyway,'' he said. In <LOCATION> Baltimore </LOCATION>, two major league baseball teams were able to score nine runs despite the searing heat, and the visiting pitcher refused to take off his long-sleeved undershirt during the game, saying he was superstitious. <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Viola </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Minnesota </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Twins </ORGANIZATION> became the first <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> League </ORGANIZATION> pitcher to win 15 games this season by surviving the minimum five innings and leading his team to a 7-2 victory over the <ORGANIZATION> Baltimore </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Orioles </ORGANIZATION>. `` That was the hottest situation I've ever pitched in,'' <PERSON> Viola </PERSON> said. Starting pitchers in <LOCATION> Oakland </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, and <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> also tired early in the heat. Other record highs were 97 at <LOCATION> Allentown </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION>; 100 at <LOCATION> Charleston </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> W. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>; 100 at <LOCATION> Newark </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.J. </LOCATION>; 98 in downtown <ORGANIZATION> Oakland </ORGANIZATION>; 97 at <LOCATION> Raleigh </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.C. </LOCATION>; and 107 at <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jose </LOCATION> and 104 at <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rosa </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION> `` Lemonade Lassies'' in shorts will be dispensing cool drinks on street corners in <LOCATION> Bluefield </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> W. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, again Monday after the Appalachian town sweltered through a weekend with highs of over 90 <LOCATION> Bluefield </LOCATION> bills itself as `` Nature's Air-Conditioned City'' and hands out free drinks whenever the mercury tops 90. The <ORGANIZATION> Chamber </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> has gone whole summers in past years without doling out a drop of lemonade, but this summer the heat is sending the civic group to the poorhouse, chamber member <PERSON> Eddie </PERSON> <PERSON> Steele </PERSON> said. `` We've had to do it about five or six times, which is the most we've had in 10 or 15 years,'' <PERSON> Steele </PERSON> said. `` It costs about $ 100 a time to serve it.'' <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> officials blamed high heat as the likely cause of last week's death of a 2-year-old girl whose body was found in a sweltering attic. <LOCATION> Lorain </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> deputy coroner Dr. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Buchannan </PERSON> said the body of <PERSON> Ashley </PERSON> <PERSON> Kasubienski </PERSON> was discovered by her parents Friday. Initial tests showed the child was `` severely dehydrated,'' and the death appeared to be heat-related, he said. In <LOCATION> Pasadena </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, authorities confiscated dozens of rabbits, pigeons, chickens and geese after finding about 20 animals that had died after having been purchased at an auction and stuffed inside cardboard boxes for a sweltering truck ride, police said. Authorities were investigating possible animal cruelty charges against three unidentified people, police Sgt. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Olquin </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880717-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-17-88 2353EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p AM-CVN--Dukakis 4thLd-Writethru a0856 07-17 0763</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-CVN--Dukakis, 4th Ld-Writethru, a0856,800</SECOND>
<HEAD>Dukakis Dismisses Last-Minute Controversies as `Stuff of Politics'</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: ADDS 2 grafs with Dukakis-Bentsen dinner at restaurant owned
by cousin of Dukakis</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By DONALD M. ROTHBERG</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Political Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ATLANTA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Democratic presidential nominee-in-waiting <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, declaring that `` for the last 17 months I've had <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION> on my mind,'' arrived with his running mate on Sunday after dismissing last-minute convention controversies simply as `` the stuff of politics.'' His first public appearance in the convention city was at a party across the street from the hall where he will become his party's presidential nominee. `` We're going to come out of this convention a unified party, an inspired party,'' he said. `` We're going to need your help, we're going to need <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON>,'' he added in a pointed reference to <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, who, so far, has withheld an endorsement of <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> and his designated running mate, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> Sen. <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> canceled appearances scheduled for Monday morning and the expectation was he would be meeting with <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> in an effort to resolve their differences. `` We have come a long, long way together,'' said <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>. `` And now we're in the final stretch.'' When he arrived at the <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> airport, the <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> governor predicted `` a good convention and a strong and unified party.'' `` We're delighted to be here,'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> said as he and <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> and their families flew in on a charter flight from <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>, via <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, on <ORGANIZATION> Presidential </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airways </ORGANIZATION>. `` We hope and expect to launch a winning campaign,'' said the man who will lead the Democrats against <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> in the fall. <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> was predicting as much, saying that the Democrats had more unity now than any time in the past 20 years and adding, `` The tide is really moving with us.'' The <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> plane stopped in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> just long enough for the <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> senator and his wife B.A. to board the plane. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> has chosen <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> as his running mate and he introduced the silver-haired politician as the `` next president of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>,'' before quickly correcting himself to say `` vice president.'' On the eve of the opening of the Democratic National Convention, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> expressed confidence that <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> will be a member of his team but emphasized that it will have only one quarterback _ the presidential nominee. `` You ca n't have two quarterbacks,'' he told a <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> news conference before leaving for <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>. He rejected the idea that he was angered or frustrated by <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s reaction to the selection of <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> had openly sought the vice presidential nomination. `` This is the stuff of politics,'' he said. `` I'm on my way to a convention where, if everything goes well, I'm going to be the Democratic presidential nominee. That's never happened to me before. `` I'm looking forward to the week.'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> said he and <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> talked by telephone Sunday morning, but he refused to discuss the conversation or speculate on when they would sit down together in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>. `` We know each other, we like each other, we respect each other,'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> said of his relationship with <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>. `` No Democratic convention would be a Democratic convention without a little controversy,'' he said, trying to minimize the prospects for disruption by the <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> forces. The <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> governor said he still has no idea whether <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> will challenge his choice of <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>. `` I would hope it would n't be,'' he replied when asked if <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s name would be offered to the convention as an alternative to <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> so far has refused to rule out such a possibility. `` He's a member of the team,'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> said of <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> `` and a good Democrat besides. An important member of the team.'' But, he said, `` Every team has to have a quarterback. That's the nominee.'' As for a meeting with <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> would only say, `` We meet when we decide to meet.'' `` We've had a remarkably good relationship,'' he said. `` This has been as quiet and as happy a Democratic race as any I can remember.'' He said <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s involvement `` as an active campaigner would be a tremendous asset.'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> also completed action on state budget matters, including using his line item veto to delete $ 138 million in spending. The action enabled the governor to head for <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> with his state budget in balance. In the evening, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> and their families celebrated their first night in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> at a dinner hosted by a cousin of <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, local restaurateur <PERSON> Pano </PERSON> <PERSON> Karatassos </PERSON>. <PERSON> Karatassos </PERSON> is a second cousin of <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, said <PERSON> Elaine </PERSON> <PERSON> LaMontagne </PERSON>, a spokeswoman for the restaurant, 103 West. Their grandmothers were first cousins, she said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880717-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-17-88 2359EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-ContraAid Bjt   07-17 0709</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Contra Aid, Bjt,700</SECOND>
<HEAD>Another Fight Looms on Contra Aid</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP News Analysis</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JIM DRINKARD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Escalating strife in <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> is sending familiar ripples through <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, where <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> appears headed for yet another fractious confrontation over <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> policy in the region. Riding a crest of anti-Sandinista sentiment in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Minority Leader <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>, R-Kan., introduced legislation last week to provide a new $ 47 million in aid _ $ 20 million of it in weapons _ to the Contra rebels fighting the leftist regime in <LOCATION> Managua </LOCATION> The rebels have been without new <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military aid since February, and have been making do with the $ 17 million for food and clothing that <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> provided in earlier legislation. The humanitarian aid was designed to enhance peace talks which collapsed June 9. The talks have not gotten back on track. The <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration's strategy appears to be to get some version of the Dole aid bill passed in the more favorable climate of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>, as an amendment to a Pentagon money bill. That could happen soon after <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> returns July 26 from its break for the Democratic National Convention. The measure then would go to a <ORGANIZATION> House-Senate </ORGANIZATION> negotiating committee, where the Contra aid amendment would be among the items subject to bargaining. Members of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> negotiating team, such as Reps. <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Chappell </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Fla </LOCATION>., and <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Murtha </PERSON>, D-Pa., look more favorably on Contra aid than the full <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, and are seen as likely to accept the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> That would mean <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> members, who have narrowly rejected Contra military aid in the last several showdowns, would be faced with a vote on an entire <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> spending package that includes aid to the rebels as a small section of the bill. Democratic strategists concede the aid is far more likely to pass in that form, since it would be easier to get a yes vote from the three dozen or so `` swing'' members _ most of them Democrats _ who traditionally hold the balance of power on the issue. House Speaker <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Texas </LOCATION>, the leading congressional critic of the administration's Contra policy, was seeking to arrange a resumption of the peace talks. He said while he would not oppose an extension of humanitarian aid to the rebels, `` I do n't think there exists in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> a desire to resume the war. But chances for the new military aid could be enhanced even further if conditions inside <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> continue to deteriorate. Last week's moves by the Sandinista government to suppress opposition demonstrations and close independent media outlets brought virtually unanimous condemnation from <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, in the form of harshly worded resolutions. Since the resolutions were passed, the government has sentenced opposition leaders arrested at a rally to six months in jail, and has confiscated a sugar plantation that was the country's largest private business. <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> also expelled <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. Ambassador <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Melton </PERSON> and seven colleagues last week. The outcome of the newest Contra aid push will depend largely on what the <ORGANIZATION> Sandinistas </ORGANIZATION> do in the weeks ahead, said Rep. <PERSON> Tony </PERSON> <PERSON> Coelho </PERSON>, D-Calif., the party's chief <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> vote counter If <LOCATION> Managua </LOCATION> begins to restore democratic freedoms, `` the shrillness, the sharpness of the bitterness will have calmed down,'' <PERSON> Coelho </PERSON> said recently. The Sandinista crackdowns have demonstrated a lack of concern about the peace process in the region, <PERSON> Coelho </PERSON> said. `` If it looks like they're thumbing their noses at the process, you're going to have people supporting some alternative.'' <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>'s bill includes $ 20 million in military aid for the rebels, but makes it more palatable to congressional moderates by leaving the aid in escrow. It would flow only if requested by President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, and only if <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> passes another bill authorizing the weapons money. The <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration bitterly opposed such a congressional `` trigger'' in the last aid battle, but now believes the mere threat of lethal aid may be enough to drive the <ORGANIZATION> Sandinistas </ORGANIZATION> to concessions, according to one senior administration official. The official also pointed out that the prospects for new aid may be further enhanced because the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> vice presidential candidate, Sen. <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, is a consistent supporter of Contra military aid.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>EDITOR'S NOTE: Jim Drinkard covers foreign affairs on Capitol</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Hill </PERSON> for The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880717-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-17-88 1212EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-LegalCocaine 1stLd-Writethru a0718 07-17 0343</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Legal Cocaine, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0718,0348</SECOND>
<HEAD>New Jersey Plant Nation's Only Legal Importer Of Cocaine</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: SUBS graf 10th pvs, `The name ...' to CLARIFY that Coca-Cola
says cocaine was never intentionally put in the drink.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By HENRY STERN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MAYWOOD, N.J. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 In the midst of the nation's war on drugs, a plant in this suburban community quietly imports coca leaves and processes them into medicinal cocaine and a non-narcotic flavor extract for <ORGANIZATION> Coca-Cola </ORGANIZATION>. Workers at the <ORGANIZATION> Stepan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> plant, the nation's only legal importer of cocaine, must undergo strict background checks, and agents from the <ORGANIZATION> federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Drug </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Enforcement </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> frequently visit, said plant manager <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Brien </PERSON>. <ORGANIZATION> DEA </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Milton </PERSON> <PERSON> Smilek </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Newark </LOCATION> said there have n't been any security problems at the plant just west of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. He said it processes hundreds of tons of cocaine each year. The company imports coca leaf from <LOCATION> Peru </LOCATION> and to a lesser extent from <LOCATION> Bolivia </LOCATION>, <PERSON> O'Brien </PERSON> said. Part of what <PERSON> Stepan </PERSON> extracts from the coca leaf is sold to <ORGANIZATION> Mallinckrodt </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, a <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Louis-based </LOCATION> pharmaceutical company. <ORGANIZATION> Mallinckrodt </ORGANIZATION> further purifies the extract into pharmaceutical grade cocaine hydrochloride, used as a local anesthetic by eye, ear and nose specialists, said company spokeswoman <PERSON> Roxanna </PERSON> <PERSON> Motchan </PERSON>. <ORGANIZATION> Mallinckrodt </ORGANIZATION> also is subject to stringent DEA requirements, including background checks of employees, she said. <PERSON> Carlton </PERSON> <PERSON> Curtis </PERSON>, a spokesman for <ORGANIZATION> Coca-Cola </ORGANIZATION> in its <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> headquarters, said use of the coca extract in the soft drink is common knowledge, although the company closely guards its secret formula, first developed in 1886. `` We've been openly talking about that for 102 years,'' <PERSON> Curtis </PERSON> said. <ORGANIZATION> Coca-Cola </ORGANIZATION>, whose name is derived from the company's use of the coca extract, has said that before the refining process was modernized around the turn of the century, traces of cocaine may have made it into some drinks. Mayor <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Steuert </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> said he's unsure if most of the town's 9,900 residents know the plant processes cocaine `` It's the kind of publicity I'm sure they try to avoid if they can,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880717-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-17-88 1213EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p AM-CVN--Lance     07-17 0686</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-CVN--Lance,710</SECOND>
<HEAD>Lance Once Again a Key Convention Player</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RITA BEAMISH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ATLANTA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Bert </PERSON> <PERSON> Lance </PERSON> has no official role at the Democratic convention, but <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> will make sure there is a place at the table for the burly <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION> politician declared persona non grata four years ago. `` He's one of <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON>'s kitchen cabinet,'' said longtime <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> adviser <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON>. <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON> said <PERSON> Lance </PERSON>'s public support of <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> helped give the Democratic presidential runner-up to <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> ` tremendous credibility among ` Democratic established officials' and Southerners in particular.'' Lance talks as often as four times a day to <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON> said, and his advice is `` sometimes accepted, sometimes not,'' but `` always candid and frank,'' and `` extremely helpful to the candidate.'' Beyond that, <PERSON> Lance </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> have a close personal relationship that has been nurtured over the past four years of political hills and valleys for both men. `` It's a brother relationship,'' <PERSON> Lance </PERSON> said in an interview. `` It's not so much a political relationship as it is a real friendship. ... We're really close in the sense that we can joke with each other and be very frank with each other.'' The alliance between the unlikely pair _ one a fiery black preacher and civil rights activist, the other the epitome of a white Southern insider _ helped <PERSON> Lance </PERSON> make something of a political comeback from troubles that began when he was director of the <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Management </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Budget </ORGANIZATION> under President <PERSON> Carter </PERSON>. `` He got rehabilitated politically, and there's nothing wrong with that,'' said <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON>. <PERSON> Lance </PERSON> left the <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> administration under a cloud of alleged past banking irregularities, then was acquitted of those charges by a federal jury. But he was dogged by a negative image that resurfaced at the Democratic National Convention in 1984. <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> Mondale </PERSON>, thankful for <PERSON> Lance </PERSON>'s help in the <LOCATION> South </LOCATION>, courted him during the convention to head up the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, then in the face of party protest summarily dumped him all within a matter of ill-timed days. Lance ultimately stepped down as chairman of both <PERSON> Mondale </PERSON>'s 1984 campaign and of the <ORGANIZATION> Georgia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>. But today it's a different story. <PERSON> Lance </PERSON> is sought out by those looking for an inside track on the candidate who will walk into the <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> convention with some 1,200 delegates in his pocket. In rare appearances on the campaign trail, <PERSON> Lance </PERSON> invariably was buttonholed by reporters eager for his insight. He gamely sang <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s praises on TV news programs, giving early assurances that <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> was not a disruptive force but a loyal Democrat. And when <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s campaign needed a public display of establishment acceptability as his campaign was catching fire, it was largely through <PERSON> Lance </PERSON>'s efforts that a meeting with <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> leaders was arranged in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. Their friendship goes back to 1983 when <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> began his presidential bid. <PERSON> Lance </PERSON> had already proven himself by organizing Southern state chairmen to go to <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s home base of <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> and campaign for <PERSON> Harold </PERSON> <PERSON> Washington </PERSON>, who became the city's first black mayor in a bitter election against <PERSON> Jane </PERSON> <PERSON> Byrne </PERSON>. It was <PERSON> Lance </PERSON> whom <PERSON> Mondale </PERSON> turned to as a liaison to <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> in trying to deal with <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s various complaints about party workings. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Beckel </PERSON>, who ran <PERSON> Mondale </PERSON>'s 1984 campaign, recalls an early negotiating meeting with <PERSON> Lance </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>. `` It was a chemistry that worked right away. They talk a lot of grits and gravy with each other. They talk South,'' with a natural affinity since <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> is from <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Beckel </PERSON> said. `` The two of them sit there and they'll go face to face and disagree with each other. I've never seen two guys fight through smiling the way those two guys do.'' <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> politician <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Hooker </PERSON> said their affinity stems in part from rejection at the hands of their own party. `` Their relationship was born in pain. Here were two men who had walked on the hot coals and felt that they had not been dealt with fairly ... There's no question in my mind that <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> is a hero of <PERSON> Bert </PERSON> <PERSON> Lance </PERSON> and <PERSON> Bert </PERSON> <PERSON> Lance </PERSON> is a hero of <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>,'' said <PERSON> Hooker </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880717-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-17-88 1214EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Gulf-Airliner     07-17 0268</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Gulf-Airliner,0276</SECOND>
<HEAD>Iran Asks Airbus Help In Search For Flight Recorders</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NICOSIA, Cyprus (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> has asked the European Airbus consortium for help in its search for flight recorders from an Iranian jetliner that was shot down by an American warship. The official <ORGANIZATION> Islamic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> said Sunday that <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Civil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aviation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> made the request. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Alizart </PERSON>, a spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> Airbus </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Industrie </ORGANIZATION> consortium in the French city of <LOCATION> Toulouse </LOCATION>, said the company received a telex Wednesday from <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> asking where to buy or rent equipment to help find the flight recorders. The A300 was shot down by the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> missile cruiser <LOCATION> Vincennes </LOCATION> on July 3, and <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> said all 290 aboard were killed. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military authorities said the plane was mistaken for an attacking F-14 jet fighter. The Pentagon said information gathered by the cruiser showed the plane was descending in altitude on an `` attack profile,'' but <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> said the plane was climbing. Discovery of the plane's two flight recorders in the waters of the Strait of <PERSON> Hormuz </PERSON> could help determine the truth. Each of the black boxes containing the recorders has a radio beacon that can transmit for 12 to 30 days after a crash. <PERSON> Alizart </PERSON> says <ORGANIZATION> Airbus </ORGANIZATION> does n't manufacture the beacons, so the company is tracking down an agency of the British-based beacon manufacturing company that could provide <ORGANIZATION> Iran </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> with the equipment it needs to detect the black boxes. The Iranian news agency, monitored in <LOCATION> Cyprus </LOCATION>, said Iranian frogmen have searched for the recorders since the plane was shot down. So far, 179 bodies have been recovered, the agency reported.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880717-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-17-88 1234EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Iraq-Hussein     07-17 0529</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Iraq-Hussein,0546</SECOND>
<HEAD>Iraq's President Urges Iran To Accept `Honorable' Peace</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By SALAH NASRAWI</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BAGHDAD, Iraq (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Saddam </PERSON> <PERSON> Hussein </PERSON> said Sunday that a string of Iraqi victories on the battlefield should persuade <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> to accept an `` honorable'' peace and end the war between the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> nations. <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> later said its forces withdrew from an Iranian border area after ridding it of enemy troops and bombed industrial targets in southern <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>. `` <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'s rulers have to accept the peace road, they have to abandon their unjust dreams and foolish mottos and slogans, their hollow illusions after their defeats,'' the <LOCATION> Iraqi </LOCATION> leader declared in a speech broadcast on <LOCATION> Baghdad </LOCATION> radio. <PERSON> Hussein </PERSON>'s speech came on the 20th anniversary of his seizure of power. He proposed that <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> sign a peace accord, exchange prisoners, return to their respective borders and vow not to interfere in each other's internal affairs. <PERSON> Hussein </PERSON> first listed his peace plan in an open letter to the Iranian leadership in August 1986. A military communique issued shortly afterward said Iraqi forces withdrew from the Iranian town of <LOCATION> Dehloran </LOCATION>, which they seized Tuesday. The Iraqis advanced 30 miles into <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> to capture Dehloran after chasing Iranian forces out of the Zubaidat region on their side of the border. Military communiques said at the time that <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> did not wish to hold onto Iranian territory and would withdraw from <LOCATION> Dehloran </LOCATION> after clearing the border area of enemy troops and destroying their bases. The <ORGANIZATION> Iraqi </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> reported that <LOCATION> Iraqi </LOCATION> warplanes bombed fuel storage tanks near the southern Iranian city of <LOCATION> Ahvaz </LOCATION>, scoring `` destructive hits.'' There was no immediate Iranian comment on the Iraqi reports. <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>'s victories in <LOCATION> Zubaidat </LOCATION> and Dehloran were the latest in a series of Iraqi triumphs this year that chased Iranian troops out of almost all the <LOCATION> Iraqi </LOCATION> territory they had seized since 1982. The Iraqis began recapturing their lost territories in April. They said they seized about 133 strategic heights in the northern region of the 730-mile long front. Simultaneously, they launched assaults in the south, recapturing the southern <LOCATION> Faw </LOCATION> <LOCATION> peninsula </LOCATION> in April and the <LOCATION> Shalamcheh </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Majnoon </PERSON> islands in May and June. <PERSON> Hussein </PERSON> said these victories could lead to a peace settlement and urged <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> to accept the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> call for a cease-fire in the 8-year-old war. <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> accepts the July 1987 resolution, but <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> maintains the conflict can not end until <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> is branded the aggressor in the war. `` <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> stands now on victorious ground ... confident today and in the future. Iraqis and the noble Arabs now stand on victorious peaks while the rulers of <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> are in the trench of defeat and shame,'' <PERSON> Hussein </PERSON> said. `` <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> extends the hand of honorable peace and calls on the Iranian rulers to draw lessons from their defeats,'' he said. <PERSON> Hussein </PERSON> stressed Sunday that any settlement should guarantee <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>'s navigation rights along the Shatt al-Arab waterway, which forms the southernmost border with <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>, as well as through the Strait of <LOCATION> Hormuz </LOCATION>, the narrow entrance to the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>'s only access to the gulf along the <PERSON> Shatt </PERSON> <PERSON> al-Arab </PERSON> has been blocked by <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> since the outbreak of fighting.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880717-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-17-88 1235EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-MassacreAnniversary     07-17 0642</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Massacre Anniversary,0659</SECOND>
<HEAD>Memories Linger As College Rises At Site</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto GO1</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CAROLYN CALLISON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SAN YSIDRO, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Every time policeman <PERSON> Miguel </PERSON> <PERSON> Rosario </PERSON> drives down <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ysidro </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Boulevard </LOCATION> near the Mexican border he remembers how it felt to be pinned down by a fusillade of bullets from an deranged man's submachine gun. And he wishes he'd been the officer who fired the shot that ended <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> <PERSON> Huberty </PERSON>'s 77-minute rampage in a <ORGANIZATION> McDonald </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> restaurant four years ago Monday <PERSON> Huberty </PERSON> killed 21 people and injured 19 before being slain. The restaurant was razed after the July 18, 1984, massacre _ the nation's worst one-day mass murder by a single gunman _ and a <ORGANIZATION> Southwestern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> building is taking shape on the lot. `` Every time I go by, I look at the spot and the area where I laid for about an hour,'' said <PERSON> Rosario </PERSON>, who was the first officer on the scene. The 10-year <ORGANIZATION> San </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Diego </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> veteran said in a recent interview that the first call was for an assault with a deadly weapon. He expected to find a victim of a domestic argument. He parked his car and began walking toward the postal building where the victim had been reported. `` I looked over and I see people hiding behind cars, crouched behind cars,'' he said, `` and I got this funny feeling in my stomach that something was really wrong, deadly wrong.'' `` At that time, an older guy pointed to <ORGANIZATION> McDonald </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> and I was standing right dead in the middle of the parking lot.'' He spotted a man with an Uzi 9mm submachine gun in the doorway. `` We made eye contact and he brought it up in an aiming position and I looked for cover,'' <PERSON> Rosario </PERSON> said. `` There was this truck right to my right there, a big truck, thank God, because I got right behind it and it saved me. `` He was shooting over me, and trying to get the rounds through the truck. At one point he tried to skip the rounds off the ground.'' Inside the restaurant, <PERSON> Huberty </PERSON>, 41, ordered the four dozen patrons to lie on the floor. Armed with a small arsenal of weapons and more than 400 rounds of ammunition, the unemployed security guard systematically shot his victims, pausing occasionally to sip a soft drink. The massacre ended when police sniper <PERSON> Chuck </PERSON> <PERSON> Foster </PERSON> fired one shot through <PERSON> Huberty </PERSON>'s chest. `` I would've loved to be the one,'' said <PERSON> Rosario </PERSON>. `` And I did have him in my sights for about 10 seconds. But by the time I did what I had to do he had moved.'' Soon afterward, <ORGANIZATION> McDonald </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> had the restaurant razed and donated the three-quarter-acre lot a mile from the Mexican border to the city, with the stipulation that no restaurant be built there. For three years, the land was occupied only by a makeshift shrine to the victims. Some argued a park should be built as a permanent memorial on the site, about 20 miles south of downtown <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Diego </LOCATION>. It finally was sold for about $ 136,000 to <ORGANIZATION> Southwestern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION>, a community college with about 14,000 students. School officials expect a one-story classroom and administration building to be completed in time for the fall semester. The agreement calls for the school to dedicate a 300-square-foot area in front of the building for a permanent memorial to the victims. The college's students were invited to submit designs for the memorial and a committee is selecting one from about 30 entries, said school spokesman <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> Carvell </PERSON>. Councilman <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Filner </PERSON>, whose district includes the community of about 17,000 people, said selling the land to the college seemed appropriate. `` I think because we did something positive, the anniversary is less of a negative thing now than it would have been,'' he said. `` People now see something positive going to happen there.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880717-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-17-88 1247EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w AM-Meese-Intrigue Bjt   07-17 0679</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Meese-Intrigue, Bjt,670</SECOND>
<HEAD>Negative Information Leaked About Two Former Meese Aides</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LARRY MARGASAK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Controversy follows Attorney General <PERSON> Edwin </PERSON> <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON> everywhere he goes _ even out the door. The latest installment involves the leaking of unfavorable information about two former <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> officials who have been invited to testify before a <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> panel about their former boss. Committee sources and sources close to the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> say the leaks were an attempt to discourage the two men from testifying. <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>'s resignation by itself may have convinced one of the men, former Deputy Attorney General <PERSON> Arnold </PERSON> <PERSON> I. </PERSON> <PERSON> Burns </PERSON>, to resist the committee's invitation to testify about <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>. <PERSON> Burns </PERSON> reportedly believes <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>'s stewardship is now `` ancient history.'' But former criminal division chief <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Weld </PERSON>, who along with <PERSON> Burns </PERSON> suddenly announced his resignation March 29, is still expected to appear July 26 before the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Judiciary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Burns </PERSON> and <PERSON> Weld </PERSON> left March 29 when <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> was under intense scrutiny from independent counsel <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> McKay </PERSON>, who was investigating <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>'s conduct on a number of ethics matters. The Democratic-controlled <ORGANIZATION> Judiciary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> invited both men to tell why they left, but neither would consider the request before <PERSON> McKay </PERSON> completed his work. <PERSON> McKay </PERSON> submitted his still-secret findings on July 5 and, on the same day, <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> announced that he would resign in late July or early August. The committee then committee asked <PERSON> Burns </PERSON> and <PERSON> Weld </PERSON> to testify on July 26. <PERSON> McKay </PERSON>'s report was expected to made public on Monday. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> J </PERSON>. -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> Duke </ORGANIZATION> -RRB- Short, a committee aide to Sen. <PERSON> Strom </PERSON> <PERSON> Thurmond </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-S.C. </LOCATION>, said he was asked by the committee's <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> staffers after <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>'s resignation announcement to check whether <PERSON> Burns </PERSON> and <PERSON> Weld </PERSON> were coming. According to <PERSON> Short </PERSON>, <PERSON> Burns </PERSON> told him `` the <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> story is now ancient history, but if I'm subpoenaed, of course, I would testify.'' A subpoena is highly unlikely, and as of now, <PERSON> Burns </PERSON> is not expected to come. <PERSON> Weld </PERSON> described his conversation with Short in a startling letter to the committee. <PERSON> Weld </PERSON> said that <PERSON> Short </PERSON> `` asked me whether there was an internal <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> investigation of me in 1986 or 1987, based on an anonymous letter alleging that I had smoked marijuana at a wedding in 1982, and if so, whether that might not ` complicate''' the testimony. <PERSON> Weld </PERSON> pointed out an internal <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> investigation found the allegation `` lacked merit,'' and in subsequent interviews emphatically denied the marijuana incident. <PERSON> Short </PERSON> said he received a call about the marijuana allegation and `` asked <PERSON> Weld </PERSON> about it.'' Asked if he was attempting to hint to <PERSON> Weld </PERSON> that he avoid testifying, <PERSON> Short </PERSON> said in an interview, `` Absolutely not. Not under any circumstance.'' Furthermore, <PERSON> Short </PERSON> said, he made the calls to <PERSON> Weld </PERSON> and <PERSON> Burns </PERSON> at the request of the Democratic committee staff because both men are Republicans and <PERSON> Short </PERSON> knew them personally. <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Gitenstein </PERSON>, chief counsel for the committee's Democratic majority, supported Short. `` I do n't believe <PERSON> Duke </PERSON> tried to discourage <PERSON> Weld </PERSON> from testifying,'' he said. `` I do n't believe that was his intention.'' But last week, the <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> carried a news story about the marijuana allegation, and had previously published several stories about <PERSON> Burns </PERSON>' efforts to get his former law partner a federal judgeship. A <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> spokesman, <PERSON> Patrick </PERSON> <PERSON> Korten </PERSON>, said he had `` no idea who is responsible for making any of that information available.'' As to the conflict-of-interest allegations, <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> Markman </PERSON>, the assistant attorney general in charge of screening judicial candidates, said <PERSON> Burns </PERSON> was above board in his efforts on behalf of his former partner, <PERSON> Stuart </PERSON> <PERSON> Summit </PERSON> _ now a nominee for the 2nd U.S. <ORGANIZATION> Circuit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appeals </ORGANIZATION>. `` Obviously his name came to our attention because of his relationship to Mr. <PERSON> Burns </PERSON>,'' <PERSON> Markman </PERSON> said. `` Mr. <PERSON> Burns </PERSON> probably bent over backwards to make sure he was n't viewed as pushing the candidate to the exclusion of other candidates. `` Mr. Summit went through the normal procedures _ the regular interview process, the regular background process, and final approval by the attorney general. The attorney general was aware that Summit was a partner of <PERSON> Arnie </PERSON> <PERSON> Burns </PERSON>. <PERSON> Burns </PERSON>' relationship with Summit was quite open.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880717-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-17-88 1306EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Philippines     07-17 0421</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Philippines,0438</SECOND>
<HEAD>Guerrilla Leader Says Communists Willing To Open Talks</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MANILA, Philippines (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A guerrilla commander said Sunday that communist rebels are willing to open new peace talks with President <PERSON> Corazon </PERSON> <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON>'s government. But <PERSON> Gregorio </PERSON> <PERSON> Rosal </PERSON>, a leader of the <ORGANIZATION> Meliton </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Glor </ORGANIZATION> communist rebel faction on the main <LOCATION> Luzon </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION>, said the offer must not be considered an act of surrender. <PERSON> Rosal </PERSON> said the military has been sabotaging reconciliation efforts by both the rebels and the government. `` We are ready to hold talks for the pursuit of long-lasting peace, but never for surrender,'' <PERSON> Rosal </PERSON> said. `` The present government is prone to saddling -LRB- us -RRB- with terms unacceptable for free-wheeling talks, with the military ... acting as saboteurs to any peaceful effort.'' The representative of the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>, the outlawed armed branch of the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, made the statement in a tape-recorded message sent to news agencies. <PERSON> Rosal </PERSON> did not say on what terms the rebels were willing to negotiate. <PERSON> Rosal </PERSON> also represents the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION>, a 12-member umbrella group that includes the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> and its army. The communists, who claim 25,000 guerrillas are fighting for them, have been waging a war for 19 years to establish a Marxist state in the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION>. About 10,000 people Sunday celebrated the second anniversary of the founding of <ORGANIZATION> Alsa </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Masa </ORGANIZATION> -LRB- People's Uprising -RRB-, an anti-communist vigilante group. Chanting anti-communist slogans, the demonstrators burned effigies of the rebels. Five communists and a provincial leftist leader were killed and eight soldiers were wounded in separate insurgency-related clashes in the past four days, the state-run <ORGANIZATION> Philippine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> reported. It said government troops Saturday killed five guerrillas in a gunfight on the outskirts of the town of <LOCATION> Magalona </LOCATION> on <LOCATION> Negros </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION>, about 300 miles southeast of <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION>. In <LOCATION> Bacolod </LOCATION>, the main city on <LOCATION> Negros </LOCATION>, about 6,000 people gathered Friday in front of the Sacred Heart Seminary to protest alleged communist infiltration of the <ORGANIZATION> Roman </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION>, the agency reported. It said the crowd demanded the resignation of <PERSON> Bacolod </PERSON> <PERSON> Bishop </PERSON> <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Fortich </PERSON>, an outspoken advocate of human rights _ including those of the rebels _ and refused to allow the prelate and about 100 others to leave the building Also in <LOCATION> Bacolod </LOCATION>, unidentified men Thursday gunned down <PERSON> Nilo </PERSON> <PERSON> Piccio </PERSON>, the local chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Patriotic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Alliance </ORGANIZATION>, a leftist group. The assailants escaped. In another incident, the agency said eight soldiers were wounded Friday when their vehicle struck a land mine on <LOCATION> Panay </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION>. It said troops captured two rebels in a brief firefight after the incident.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880717-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-17-88 1316EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-India-Sikhs     07-17 0213</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-India-Sikhs,0220</SECOND>
<HEAD>Three Sikhs, Three Police Killed In Shootout</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CHANDIGARGH, India (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Sikh militants clashed with police Sunday in a gunfight that left three Sikhs and three police officers dead, authorities said. The shooting began at about 3:30 a.m., after police tried to break into a house in <LOCATION> Chandigarh </LOCATION> believed occupied by Sikh militants, said police Superintendent <PERSON> R.P </PERSON>. <PERSON> Singh </PERSON>. The militants opened fire, killing Inspector <PERSON> Jagjit </PERSON> <PERSON> Singh </PERSON> and injuring two police officers, who later died, the superintendent said. Three militants were killed in the return fire. Chandigargh is the capital of <LOCATION> Punjab </LOCATION> state, where Sikh militants are fighting to establish a Sikh homeland. In another incident in <LOCATION> Punjab </LOCATION>, three state employees were shot and killed Saturday night near the city of <LOCATION> Amritsar </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Trust </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> India </ORGANIZATION> news agency reported. The victims included one Sikh and two Hindus. Three moderate Sikhs were also killed by suspected militants in other areas of <LOCATION> Punjab </LOCATION> on Saturday night, the agency said. The killings raise to 1,517 the number of people killed in <LOCATION> Punjab </LOCATION> this year in the Sikhs' violent campaign. Sikhs form just 2 percent of <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>'s 800 million people but are a majority in <LOCATION> Punjab </LOCATION>. Radical Sikhs claim they are discriminated against by the Hindus, who make up 80 percent of <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>'s population.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880717-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-17-88 1330EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-SnailHunt Bjt   07-17 0644</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Snail Hunt, Bjt,0661</SECOND>
<HEAD>Snails Sought To Revive Ancient Ritual</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY4</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ALLYN FISHER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>JERUSALEM (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Orthodox Jews are scouring <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Mediterranean </LOCATION> beaches for a rare snail that produces a blue dye they say is needed to revive a religious ritual abandoned 1,500 years ago The snail hunt was prompted last week by Rabbi <PERSON> Menachem </PERSON> <PERSON> Burstin </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION>, who is trying to recreate a process once used to dye a single thread of the Jewish prayer shawl in accordance with a biblical command. Jews were forced to abandon the practice in the fifth century, <PERSON> Burstin </PERSON> said, when Roman authorities banned all but the ruling class from wearing colored clothing. The recipe for the dye they used was lost. `` Now we are looking for it,'' said <PERSON> Burstin </PERSON>, of the prestigious Mercaz Harav religious seminary. `` We want to revive the mitzva -LRB- biblical command -RRB-.'' <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s chief rabbis, who rule on religious issues, have not given the go-ahead to renew the ancient practice and are awaiting <PERSON> Burstin </PERSON>'s findings before they consider it, said <PERSON> Zalman </PERSON> <PERSON> Quittner </PERSON>, a spokesman for the rabbis. Interest in the mollusk mystery was roused when <PERSON> Burstin </PERSON> appealed in a religious newspaper, `` Erev Shabat,'' for seminary students to seek out the rare snail, known as the Janthina or `` violet snail'' because of its purple-blue color. <PERSON> Burstin </PERSON> said he has been deluged with reports of snail sightings. But he has so far collected only a tenth of the `` bucketful'' he says is needed to extract enough dye to test his theory. The 33-year-old rabbi is trying to validate a claim made in 1920 by the late Chief Rabbi <PERSON> Yitzhak </PERSON> <PERSON> Isaac </PERSON> <PERSON> Halevy </PERSON> <PERSON> Herzog </PERSON>, father of President <PERSON> Chaim </PERSON> <PERSON> Herzog </PERSON>. In a doctoral thesis at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> London </ORGANIZATION>, the elder <PERSON> Herzog </PERSON> suggested the original dye used came from the Janthina snail. But he noted the the snail seldom made it to <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> shores. This summer, however, the snails have been sighted along with schools of jellyfish that have been plaguing beaches, <PERSON> Burstin </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Hank </PERSON> <PERSON> Mienis </PERSON>, curator of the <ORGANIZATION> Hebrew </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Jerusalem </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mollusk </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Collection </ORGANIZATION>, said there are five species of the Janthina. The largest are 1 -LCB- inches in diameter, he said. The ancient Jewish practice involved coloring one of eight strands of a prayer shawl as a sign of devotion to God. The white prayer shawls have been worn under clothing by devout Jewish men since the ancient Israelites roamed the desert with <PERSON> Moses </PERSON> during their exodus from <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION>. It is customary to kiss one of the fringes during portions of morning prayers. The Old Testament says that God ordered Moses: `` Speak to the children of <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> and tell them to make for themselves fringes on the corners of their garments throughout their generations, and to put on the fringe of each corner a blue thread. `` You shall have it as a fringe, so that when you look upon it you will remember to do all the commands of the Lord, and you will not follow the desires of your heart and your eyes which lead you astray.'' The Talmud, which interprets Jewish law, explained how the blue fringe should be dyed but did not give the source of the dye. Jewish sages have speculated about the recipe, but only began trying to revive the custom about 100 years ago in <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Burstin </PERSON> said. He said a Hasidic rabbi, <PERSON> Gershon </PERSON> <PERSON> Hanoch </PERSON> <PERSON> Leiner </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Radzin </LOCATION>, maintained the dye came from a squid. About 17,000 followers of <PERSON> Leiner </PERSON> used the method, he said, and many died at the hands of the <ORGANIZATION> Nazis </ORGANIZATION> during World War II. <PERSON> Herzog </PERSON> differed with <PERSON> Leiner </PERSON>'s followers by suggesting the Janthina snail, and not the squid, was the true source of the dye. `` I am checking <PERSON> Herzog </PERSON>'s method to the end,'' said <PERSON> Burstin </PERSON>, who has been studying the issue for 14 years. `` We can not push this mitzva forward until we solve this.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880717-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-17-88 1330EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p AM-CVN--Hispanics     07-17 0300</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-CVN--Hispanics,300</SECOND>
<HEAD>Democratic Hispanics Establish Political Group To Boost Unity,
Clout</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By SCOTT McCARTNEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ATLANTA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 About 150 Hispanic Democrats founded a political group of their own Sunday in an effort to galvanize the clout of the nation's fastest-growing minority. `` We're here to demonstrate to the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> that we are a community once and for all united,'' Rep. <PERSON> Esteban </PERSON> <PERSON> Torres </PERSON> of <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, a co-chairman of the group, told the Sunday morning gathering. `` We're coming together here for the first time and it will not be the last.'' The group, called <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hispanic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democrats </ORGANIZATION>, is made up of Mexican-Americans, Puerto Rican-Americans and Cuban-Americans. About 200 of the 4,200 delegates to this week's Democratic National Convention are Hispanic. Hispanics have drawn acute attention from both parties this year because their growing vote is concentrated in key states like <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>. Both Democratic presidential candidate-to-be <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> and his Republican counterpart <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> have already pledged to appoint a Hispanic cabinet member if elected. The group said it hopes to capitalize on that interest. `` What we have here is the most serious effort in recent times to focus the Hispanic agenda,'' <PERSON> Torres </PERSON> said. `` Our challenge is not the differences sometimes created by national origin or regional bias but the similarities which over shadow our differences.'' In the past, organizers said, differences among the different segments of the Hispanic population have kept its clout fragmented. The new group has agreed to disagree on some issues, but agrees on the need for improvements in education, jobs, health care and crime fighting as well as mobilizing the Hispanic vote in November. `` The time is right for this to work,'' said co-chair <PERSON> Marife </PERSON> <PERSON> Hernandez </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> activist from <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>. `` We're going to make sure that we're heard.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880717-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-17-88 1340EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p AM-CVN--ConventionStakes 1stLd-Writethru a0738 07-17 0960</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-CVN--Convention Stakes, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0738,900</SECOND>
<HEAD>Michael Dukakis, Struggling with Jackson to Control the Convention</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Adds 6th graf with Dukakis remark bgng ``This is...</NOTE>
<HEAD>An AP News Analysis</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JONATHAN WOLMAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ATLANTA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 On the eve of the Democratic National Convention, with 4,162 delegates watching to see what he's made of, <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> is still struggling with <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> for control of a prime-time spotlight that ought to be his without question. Through weeks of pre-convention jockeying, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> has never been able to get <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> to quit gnawing at his ankle. If it is n't one thing _ the vice presidency, a platform plank, a mediator, partnership _ it's another `` It's supposed to be his convention,'' someone mentioned to <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> on Sunday. `` That's an illusion,'' he responded. `` This is a convention of the people. It's the delegates' convention. They will determine who the nominee will be.'' The nominee will be <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> because <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> beat <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> every Tuesday for months on end. Now the <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> people want the payoff: televised unity that will provide a campaign boost in the fight against Republican <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. `` This is the stuff of politics,'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> said Sunday in minimizing the prospects for convention chaos. `` No Democratic convention would be a Democratic convention without a little controversy.'' But <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> has been running for president for five years _ drawing large and adoring crowds that <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> can only dream of _ and he is hard put to give up the limelight. He seems reluctant to even share it. The week could go two ways. At this late date, the best <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> can do -LRB- and it's pretty good -RRB- is a convention that looks like this: Monday: <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> makes a neighborhood anti-drug appearance, pressing one of his key issues against <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> does some quiet missionary work and wins private assurances from key <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> supporters. A summit is arranged, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> emerging with broad grins and little to say. <PERSON> Garrison </PERSON> <PERSON> Keillor </PERSON> sings the national anthem and millions of TV viewers wonder if this is n't going to be a Democratic year Tuesday: <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> does a zillion interviews by satellite with local TV anchors. They want to know about <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> and he tells them Democrats are united on the key economic issues. OK, so there's a floor fight on the platform. The <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> people oppose three <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> planks _ no tax hike and no freeze on military spending and no <LOCATION> Palestinian </LOCATION> state _ and they relish and win a showdown. The story of the day is <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s speech and what a speech. Hands that pick cotton will pick a president. The crowd is going crazy _ how else to describe it? _ and <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> is somewhere fidgeting a little, when the hysteria ends with a dramatic encore: <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> returns to the podium and endorses the Dukakis-Bentsen ticket. Wednesday: It is nomination day and delegates pack the hall after <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> and <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> attend an emotional ceremony at the Martin Luther King Center. The roll call is a loose, bantering competition between <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> people and <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> stalwarts. <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> or <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> _ two key states with 48 electoral votes between them _ compete to put <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> over the top. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> makes a surprise appearance, with <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> at his side, and nomination night becomes unity night, too. Thursday: The <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> roll call is anti-climatic after all the delicious speculation of a Jackson challenge. <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> follows his victory with a speech that lays out the case against <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. I beat him once and I ca n't wait to beat him again, <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> says. He tells that wonderful <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> joke: `` I like <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> because we're both Texans I'm from <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Worth </LOCATION> and he's from <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kennebunkport </LOCATION>.'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> takes to the podium and looks taller than he is. His is a vision of the future, upbeat. He is the son of immigrants, proud of the path he has traveled, insistent <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> can have change for the better. For the first time in months he does not _ not _ deliver the standard lines about good jobs at good wages, and the need for `` a real war, not a phony war'' on drugs. That's the message, but delivered in new, more dramatic rhetoric. Then `` A Fanfare to <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>,'' music by <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>, orchestra led by <PERSON> Kitty </PERSON>'s dad, <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> Ellis </PERSON> <PERSON> Dickson </PERSON> of the <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Pops </LOCATION>. That assumes <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> will stop biting <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' ankle. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' worst nightmare _ a <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> convention _ looks like this: Sunday: On the eve of the Democratic National Convention, <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> is acting more like <PERSON> Rodney </PERSON> <PERSON> Dangerfield </PERSON> than <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> His arrival is overshadowed by <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> appearances in which he tells supporters they `` deserve respect, not just an apology.'' <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Brountas </PERSON> delivers an apology, his 16th. Monday: <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' anti-drug appearance is overshadowed by a <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> foray into one of <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>'s toughest neighborhoods, where he leads a spontaneous rally which sweeps dealers and degenerates off the street to cheers of `` Down with dope, up with hope.'' Tuesday: <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s speech sends his 1,100 delegates, and most of <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>', into a frenzy. He pushes every Democratic button with a revivalist style that simply takes over the convention. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> people stand with <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> supporters and wave a common banner: Dukakis-Jackson'88. Wednesday: Nomination day. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> wins. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> veep fever running high. Thursday: <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> is nominated, but so is <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> _ he could n't stop the draft-Jackson movement if he tried But things have gone far enough _ <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> takes to the podium, endorses <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> and calls for acclamation. He has controlled the convention from the beginning to now. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> speaks. Viewers wonder _ if <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> can control <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' convention, will he control his campaign, his presidency?
</TEXT>
<HEAD>___</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Jonathan </PERSON> <PERSON> Wolman </PERSON> is assistant bureau chief for <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880717-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-17-88 1340EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-AliensOverboard     07-17 0144</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Aliens Overboard,0146</SECOND>
<HEAD>Aliens Jump Ship In Front Of Coast Guard Station</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MIAMI BEACH, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A group of Dominicans apparently trying to sneak into the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> picked the wrong place to jump ship, splashing into the water in front of the <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> station, an official said. `` The barge was inbound to <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> when 12 people jumped overboard and swam for shore opposite the <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> base, not the best of all possible places,'' said <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> Chief <PERSON> Lou </PERSON> <PERSON> Parris </PERSON>. `` Two off-duty -LRB- guardsmen -RRB- were fishing on the docks opposite the base and spotted the swimmers.'' Five of the men were captured Saturday, still swimming, and were turned over to the Immigration and <ORGANIZATION> Naturalization </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>. The seven others from the Dominican-registered barge and tugboat scrambled ashore in an area lined with freight docks and were at large late Saturday, <PERSON> Parris </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880717-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-17-88 1341EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-India-DamBurst     07-17 0145</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-India-Dam Burst,0147</SECOND>
<HEAD>Dam Bursts, Air Force Called In</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW DELHI, India (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A 75-foot-high dam burst Sunday in western <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>, stranding hundreds of villagers and isolating some towns, the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> India </ORGANIZATION> reported. The report said air force helicopters and police boats were called in to rescue people. The news agency said contact could not be made with the village of <LOCATION> Trambau </LOCATION> because it was isolated by waters from the burst dam. It said 500 villagers were reported to be stranded on a hill. No loss of life was reported, <ORGANIZATION> UNI </ORGANIZATION> said. The dam burst in the Rann of <LOCATION> Kutch </LOCATION>, a marshy area in <LOCATION> Gujarat </LOCATION> state near <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>. It frequently dries out in the spring but becomes almost an inland sea during the rainy season, which is currently sweeping across <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>. The dam burst at <LOCATION> Mithi </LOCATION> in western <LOCATION> Kutch </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> UNI </ORGANIZATION> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880717-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-17-88 1342EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-People     07-17 1128</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-People,1181</SECOND>
<HEAD>People in the News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY44</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ARLINGTON, Vt. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Their relationship did n't work out in the script, but in real life they clicked. Actor <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> J </PERSON>. <PERSON> Fox </PERSON> and his one-time TV girlfriend <PERSON> Tracy </PERSON> <PERSON> Pollan </PERSON> were married at a country inn over the weekend. <PERSON> Fox </PERSON>, 26, and <PERSON> Pollan </PERSON>, 27, were wed Saturday, his publicist, <PERSON> Nanci </PERSON> <PERSON> Ryder </PERSON>, said Sunday. <PERSON> Pollan </PERSON> was <PERSON> Fox </PERSON>'s former girlfriend on <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Family Ties. <PERSON> Fox </PERSON>'s agent had announced the impending marriage on Friday but would n't say where or when it would take place. Word leaked out that it would be at the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mountain </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Inn </LOCATION>, sending about 40 photographers and reporters and six helicopters to stake out the country inn. No details of the couple's honeymoon plans were given. <PERSON> Fox </PERSON> plays wise-guy <PERSON> Alex </PERSON> <PERSON> Keaton </PERSON> on `` Family Ties'' and starred in the film `` Back to the Future,'' the top-grossing film of 1985.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Princess <PERSON> Diana </PERSON> was in the audience, but singer <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> went ahead anyway and sang his hit `` Dirty <PERSON> Diana </PERSON>,'' about a woman of loose morals. The 27-year-old princess smiled. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> had been expected to leave the song out of his concert at <ORGANIZATION> Wembly </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Stadium </ORGANIZATION> because of the princess' presence Saturday night, but an aide said the singer `` felt the fans would feel let down.'' <PERSON> Diana </PERSON>, an avid pop music fan, and <PERSON> Prince </PERSON> <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> met backstage with <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> before the start of his third sell-out concert. `` I was so excited at meeting the royal couple,'' <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> said. `` I am very, very happy that they have come to watch me perform. I thought the princess was just wonderful.'' <PERSON> Charles </PERSON>, who prefers classical music and opera, asked <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> how he learned to dance so well, and joked, `` Could you teach me to dance?'' <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, who will make $ 26.6 million from his 13-concert British tour, donated $ 240,000 to a program set up by <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> to promote employment of young people in inner cities and $ 166,000 to a children's hospital. The singer also gave the royal couple four black jackets with the word `` Bad'' _ the name of his top-selling album _ for themselves and their sons, <PERSON> William </PERSON>, 6, and <PERSON> Harry </PERSON>, 3.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Spanish tenor <PERSON> Placido </PERSON> <PERSON> Domingo </PERSON>'s impassioned singing drew such fervent cheers and wild clapping from a <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> audience that the star marveled, `` They sound as if they are Latin.'' `` It's extraordinary,'' <PERSON> Domingo </PERSON> said after singing selections from Italian opera and Spanish popular music in his Chinese debut at the <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> Concert Hall. `` They are so enthusiastic.'' After each song, Sunday's standing-room-only crowd erupted in a roar of cheers and applause. Western opera was banned in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> during the 1966-76 Cultural Revolution on the grounds that it was bourgeois, but it has returned to official favor in the past decade. Later in the week, <PERSON> Domingo </PERSON>, 47, will join with the <LOCATION> Spanish </LOCATION> company <ORGANIZATION> Antologia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> de </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> la </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Zarzuela </ORGANIZATION> in performing zarzuela, a traditional Spanish mix of songs, dances and pageantry that resembles opera.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> McCartney </PERSON> says he wants to crown his 30-year music career with a concert in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. But first the former Beatle is releasing an album only in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> called `` Back In The <ORGANIZATION> USSR </ORGANIZATION>,'' a collection of rock' n' roll classics from the'50s and'60s `` I would love to play in <LOCATION> Russia </LOCATION>. It would be an interesting gig,'' <PERSON> McCartney </PERSON> said Sunday. `` The first thing is to bring out the record. Then I would like to go and see how the record is received.'' <PERSON> McCartney </PERSON>, 46, was frowned upon by the Soviet authorities during the 1960s when <PERSON> Beatlemania </PERSON> swept the West. But Beatles records were smuggled in and became popular among Soviet youngsters, who bought them on the black market. `` The record is in the spirit of some of the friendship that -LRB- Soviet leader <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> -RRB- <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> and -LRB- President -RRB- <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> have got going,'' said <PERSON> McCartney </PERSON>. `` It is just my gesture to the <LOCATION> Russian </LOCATION> people saying this peace stuff looks like a good idea _ which is something I have believed for years. Now we are actually seeing a little bit of it happening.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>MONTREAT, N.C. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Evangelist <PERSON> Billy </PERSON> <PERSON> Graham </PERSON>, back home after trips to <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, says he wrote a sermon on hope after witnessing changes in those two countries. `` I think these two experiences we've had have given people some hope,'' said <PERSON> Graham </PERSON>. `` People ca n't live without hope. I think of all the people in the world who are starving, who live in war zones, who are in prison, without any hope at all hardly _ and I pray for them daily. <PERSON> Graham </PERSON>'s three-week visit to <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> in April was his first to that country, where his wife, <PERSON> Ruth </PERSON>, was born to missionary parents and lived the first 17 years of her life. In June, the 69-year-old evangelist visited the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> for the fourth time, helping to celebrate the 1,000 th anniversary of Christianity in that land
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>CAPE CANAVERAL, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Former astronaut <PERSON> Edwin </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> `` Buzz'' <PERSON> Aldrin </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> took a trip down memory lane when he visited the launch pad from which he and two others began the first moon-landing flight 19 years ago. `` It brought back a lot of memories,'' <PERSON> Aldrin </PERSON> said of his stop at Launch Pad 39A on Saturday. <PERSON> Aldrin </PERSON>, <PERSON> Neil </PERSON> <PERSON> Armstrong </PERSON> and <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Collins </PERSON> started their historic trip aboard a giant <ORGANIZATION> Saturn </ORGANIZATION> 5 rocket on July 16, 1969. Four days later, <PERSON> Armstrong </PERSON> and <PERSON> Aldrin </PERSON> landed their lunar module Eagle on the moon. Pad 39A and sister pad 39B have since been converted for space shuttle launches. <PERSON> Aldrin </PERSON> now heads a research and engineering consulting firm in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEWPORT, R.I. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Princess <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON>, sister of <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s Queen <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> II </PERSON>, dazzled a charity ball at her only public appearance during her first visit here She wore a rasberry-colored silk taffetta dress and diamond brooch to a $ 300-per-person benefit Saturday at the Breakers, the former <ORGANIZATION> Vanderbilt </ORGANIZATION> mansion on this city's Millionaire's Row. She was scheduled to end her five-day visit and return home on Sunday.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>SAN FRANCISCO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The lurid marital battles of the celebrated lawyer <PERSON> Melvin </PERSON> <PERSON> Belli </PERSON> and his wife, <PERSON> Lia </PERSON>, have been put to music. Sung to the tune of the late Beatle <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Lennon </PERSON>'s `` Ballad of <PERSON> John </PERSON> and <PERSON> Yoko </PERSON>,'' the parody goes: `` Geez, ya know this is sleazy. I know divorce can be hell. But if we leave it to <PERSON> Lia </PERSON>, she's gon na crucify <PERSON> Mel </PERSON>.'' The `` Ballad of <PERSON> Mel </PERSON> and Lia'' is sung by <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Bleu </PERSON>, a morning disc jockey at radio station <ORGANIZATION> KYUU </ORGANIZATION>. The lyrics were written by the station's sportscaster, <PERSON> Whitey </PERSON> <PERSON> Gleason </PERSON>. Mrs. <PERSON> Belli </PERSON>, 39, has accused her 80-year-old husband of physically abusing her and falsely accusing her of having extramarital affairs. He has denied the allegations. The couple married in 1972.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880717-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-17-88 1402EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Nicaragua     07-17 0798</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Nicaragua,0826</SECOND>
<HEAD>Sandinistas Mark Ninth Year Facing Unprecedented Public Discontent</HEAD>
<HEAD>AP News Analysis</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BRYNA BRENNAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MANAGUA, Nicaragua (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 On the eve of its ninth anniversary, the leftist <ORGANIZATION> Sandinista </ORGANIZATION> government confronts unprecedented discontent brought on by civil war, a shattered economy and unfulfilled promises. The Sandinistas have put the brakes on recent moves to restore basic freedoms and have cracked down on opponents with a vengeance. The measures came just days before July 19 anniversary ceremonies being held in the city of <LOCATION> Juigalpa </LOCATION>, 85 miles east of the capital. The government began easing restrictions on civil liberties to comply with a regional peace plan signed in August by the presidents of <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Guatemala </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Costa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rica </LOCATION>. The plan, aimed at ending the war here and guerrilla wars in <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Guatemala </LOCATION>, called on signatory nations to grant amnesties, negotiate cease-fires and undertake democratic reforms. To comply, the <ORGANIZATION> Sandinistas </ORGANIZATION> in January lifted a 6-year-old state of emergency. Discontent started surfacing immediately. Opposition news media that had been shuttered or censored under the emergency law reappeared and harshly attacked the government. Anti-Sandinista marches, which had been prohibited, began. With their more liberal policies, the <ORGANIZATION> Sandinistas </ORGANIZATION> achieved their main goal: <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> voted down a request by President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> to renew military aid to the Contra rebels fighting the Nicaraguan government. But last week, the <ORGANIZATION> Sandinistas </ORGANIZATION> lashed out, indicating they had had enough and would n't take any more. President <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON> and his cabinet also came under pressure from party hard-liners opposed to the concessions, which included the previously taboo step of opening negotiations with the Contras. In a series of quick moves, the government expelled <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. Ambassador <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Melton </PERSON> and seven other American diplomats July 11, a day after police beat up opponents at an anti-government demonstration. It jailed three dozen opposition figures, closed the <ORGANIZATION> Roman </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Radio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Catolica </ORGANIZATION> and a private news program, and ordered <ORGANIZATION> La </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Prensa </ORGANIZATION>, the only opposition newspaper, to suspend publication for 15 days. The <ORGANIZATION> Sandinistas </ORGANIZATION> said the crackdown was a response to a destabilization plan fostered by the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> and increasing rebel attacks. But they offered little proof to back up their accusations. Barricada, the newspaper of the <ORGANIZATION> Sandinista </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION>, published a list Saturday of dates on which <PERSON> Melton </PERSON> and the other <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> diplomats met with opposition groups. The headline read, `` Subversive Itinerary of <PERSON> Melton </PERSON> and the <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION>.'' The <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> called the visits normal. The Sandinistas have become increasingly frustrated by their inability to end the Contra war, which is wrecking the economy and fueling public discontent. In a move that took <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> off guard, <ORGANIZATION> Sandinista </ORGANIZATION> and rebel leaders signed a cease-fire agreement March 23, but since then they have made almost no headway in discussions to achieve a permanent truce. The initial cease-fire, extended for 30-day periods by tacit agreement on both sides, has been wearing thinner and thinner in recent weeks, with the government recently reporting almost daily rebel attacks. Opposition leaders said the crackdown was motivated by the government's fear that the usually fragmented opposition was unifying. Some claimed the crackdown showed the true face of the <ORGANIZATION> Sandinistas </ORGANIZATION>. `` The mask came off and the people did n't see smiling faces. They saw gas masks,'' said <PERSON> Virgilio </PERSON> <PERSON> Godoy </PERSON>, a former <ORGANIZATION> Sandinista </ORGANIZATION> labor minister and now president of the <ORGANIZATION> Independent </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, referring to the opposition protest July 10 which police broke up with tear gas. When the <ORGANIZATION> Sandinistas </ORGANIZATION> came to power in a 1979 revolution that ousted the rightist, pro-American dictatorship of <PERSON> Anastasio </PERSON> <PERSON> Somoza </PERSON>, they promised a better life to a poverty-stricken people. They enjoyed widespread support. `` We knew they were Marxists, but we thought they were different Marxists who would deal realistically with the situation here,'' <PERSON> Godoy </PERSON> said. `` Many people felt deceived.'' In 1981, the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> cut off all economic aid to <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>, claiming the <ORGANIZATION> Sandinistas </ORGANIZATION> were exporting revolution to the rest of <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> and serving as a Communist beachhead in the region. A U.S.-imposed trade embargo followed in 1985. The measures, together with <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> support for the Contras and Sandinista government mismanagement and corruption, almost scuttled the economy. About half of <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>'s budget now goes to the fight against the Contras. `` The economic situation, the hunger, the misery has gathered momentum by all citizens, and we were tapping it,'' said another opposition leader, <PERSON> Enrique </PERSON> <PERSON> Bolanos </PERSON>, head of the <ORGANIZATION> Superior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Private </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Enterprise </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>. Meanwhile, supermarket shelves stand bare. The nation that once exported rice and cotton has now turned to foreign donations for basic food staples. Children rummage through trash piles seeking scraps of food and the average worker does n't earn enough to feed his family.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Bryna </PERSON> <PERSON> Brennan </PERSON> is an <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> correspondent in <LOCATION> Managua </LOCATION> who has been covering Central American affairs since 1984.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880717-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-17-88 1411EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p AM-CVN--Richards     07-17 0229</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-CVN--Richards,240</SECOND>
<HEAD>Richards Promises `Very Direct' Keynote Address</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ATLANTA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> State Treasurer <PERSON> Ann </PERSON> <PERSON> Richards </PERSON> on Sunday tried out the podium she will use for Monday night's keynote address to the Democratic National Convention, and promised a `` very direct'' message in her own homespun style. `` It's my speech. No one has seen it, and no one has given me advice,'' she said. `` I want to lay it all out and put it on a level that everyone will understand.'' <PERSON> Richards </PERSON> said she will direct her address to her parents in <LOCATION> Waco </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, and to a family in the same area who recently wrote her a letter about their economic problems and concerns about <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s national pride. The 20-minute speech will be simple and will be sprinkled with `` Texanisms,'' she said, adding, `` I wish I were <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Jennings </PERSON> <PERSON> Bryan </PERSON> or <PERSON> Mario </PERSON> <PERSON> Cuomo </PERSON>, but I'm not.'' <PERSON> Richards </PERSON>, the highest woman elected official in <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> and a likely candidate for governor in 1990, is a staunch feminist, and said her selection to deliver the high-profile keynote address has jangled her nerves. `` I think it's one of the most difficult things I carry with me all the time,'' she said. `` I feel very strongly that I do n't want to fail. I always want to do well because then they'll think, ` Well, she can do it, maybe some other women can, too.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880717-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-17-88 1428EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-Plane-Fistfight 1stLd-Writethru a0716 07-17 0220</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Plane-Fistfight, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0716,0224</SECOND>
<HEAD>Passenger Removed For Fighting Flight</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: UPDATES throughout with passenger reporred to have argued
over correct change. No pickup.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>HUNTSVILLE, Ala. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
