<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881005-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-05-88 2345EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w AM-DC-Prisons 1stLd-Writethru a0827 10-05 0497</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-DC-Prisons, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0827,460</SECOND>
<HEAD>Justice Department Goes To Court Against D.C. Plan To Bar New
Inmates</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Edits throughout to capitalize District when specifically
referring to thecity</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By LISA M. HAMM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> sought a temporary restraining order Wednesday in an attempt to stop the <LOCATION> District </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION> from barring newly sentenced prisoners from its overcrowded jail facilities. The department filed suit in <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> after the district failed to accept the federal government's offer of short-term help to alleviate jail overcrowding in exchange for a commitment by the district to quickly increase its space for housing prisoners. The offer by Associate Attorney General <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Keating </PERSON> would have assigned to federal prison facilities up to 200 newly sentenced people. That offer would have lasted until Oct. 14, and the city would have resumed accepting prisoners Oct. 17. Under the offer, the people temporarily housed in federal facilities from Oct. 4 to Oct. 14 would have been returned to the district by Jan. 1. The city had until 3:30 p.m. Wednesday to accept the offer and did not do so, said a statement issued by the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>. Federal prisons now hold nearly 2,000 city prisoners. The crisis was triggered last Thursday, when <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bryant </PERSON>'s ordered the <ORGANIZATION> Corrections </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> to comply with a court-ordered inmate cap at the jail. He gave the District a five-day grace period before the decree took effect at noon Tuesday. An appeals court decision, handed down the same day as <PERSON> Bryant </PERSON>'s ruling, requires the <ORGANIZATION> Corrections </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> to bring the population at the overcrowded Central Facility at <LOCATION> Lorton </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION> in line with a court-ordered cap by Nov. The <ORGANIZATION> D.C. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corrections </ORGANIZATION> closed its overcrowded prison system to new inmates Tuesday to comply with the court order, and placed responsibility for housing them in the hands of the attorney general. In a six-page letter to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> Mayor <PERSON> Marion </PERSON> <PERSON> Barry </PERSON>, <PERSON> Keating </PERSON> said the pace of new prison construction in the <LOCATION> District </LOCATION> `` has been totally inadequate.'' `` The District has been unwilling to take the obvious emergency measure of placing on vacant sites within the District the modular facilities which other jurisdictions have used to provide quick accommodations for excess prison populations,'' said <PERSON> Keating </PERSON>. The city submitted a report to <LOCATION> Bryant </LOCATION> on Wednesday morning explaining its plan for reducing the jail population, a spokeswoman for <PERSON> Bryant </PERSON> said. In addition to closing the prison system, the city announced plans to release 350 inmates early, transfer 130 to penal institutions in other states, and hire contractors to post bond for some indigent inmates awaiting trial. District of <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION> and federal officials met for hours Wednesday in an unsuccessful effort to resolve their differences. Meanwhile, the <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION> police department's traffic branch holding cell was turned over to the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corrections </ORGANIZATION> to house some prisoners temporarily, according to police spokesman <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Gentile </PERSON>. And police station houses were placed on alert to prepare to accept overflow prisoners.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881005-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-05-88 2330EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p AM-Bentsten 1stLd-Writethru a0684 10-05 0515</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Bentsten, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0684,490</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bentsen Says `I Did Fine' Against Quayle</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDs: Top 7 grafs new to update with Bentsen comments after debate;
picks up 6th graf pvs, ``Bentsen arrived xxx''</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By STEVEN KOMAROW</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>OMAHA, Neb. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> said he thought he `` did fine'' in Wednesday night's vice presidential debate, and that Republican opponent <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> did not adequately explain what he would do if he suddenly became president. <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> received a telephone call from Democratic presidential nominee <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> immediately after the debate, then left for a rally at a nearby hotel. There, the Democratic vice presidential nominee was cheered by 700 supporters. A large sign declared, `` And the winner is <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>.'' Asked if he thought he had won the debate, <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> said, `` I think I did fine, and I enjoyed it. I had fun. I think we made our points.'' <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> referred to the repeated questioning of <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> about the <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> vice presidential nominee's qualifications to assume the presidency. `` I stood up there for 90 minutes listening to Senator <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> say what he was going to do if he was president of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, and I still did n't know. Finally I realized all he was going to do was go back to that script again,'' <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> called <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> to wish him well before the debate. The Democratic ticket planned a reunion Thursday at a steel plant rally near <LOCATION> Longview </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> arrived in <LOCATION> Omaha </LOCATION> on Tuesday night after four days of intense preparations, first in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> and then in <LOCATION> Austin </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>. He took time to spend with his wife and three children and planned to work out in the hotel gym to help him relax before the debate. B.A. <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> accompanied her husband to the private tour of the debate site Wednesday afternoon. Afterward, according to press secretary <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> McCurry </PERSON>, <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>, 67, picked up his wife and carried her off the stage. `` She looked like she was willing to go with him anywhere,'' he said. Much of his preparation was devoted to making <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> comfortable with the format of the debate, which limited the candidates to two-minute answers and one-minute responses, aides said. `` It's a matter of taking the language of the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> and putting it in a form that's suitable for television,'' <PERSON> McCurry </PERSON> said. Although his advisers admitted helping <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> `` frame his answers,'' <PERSON> McCurry </PERSON> said, `` we have not armed him with a lot of cute one-liners. That's not really his style.'' `` I think we'll leave the one-liners to <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> Ailes </PERSON> and <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>,'' said <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> aide <PERSON> Leslie </PERSON> <PERSON> Dach </PERSON>, referring to the Republican media strategist who has been coaching the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> candidate. <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> and other Democrats have tried to exploit public uneasiness about <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>'s qualifications for the job, and public polls show <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> is a drag on the Republican ticket. A strong performance by the 41-year-old <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> could turn that around. `` I do n't think people are going to judge this just by the fact he does n't stumble,'' <PERSON> Dach </PERSON> said. He said <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> needed `` an extremely strong performance'' to overcome the public's doubts.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881005-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-05-88 2331EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p AM-DebateReaction     10-05 0448</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Debate Reaction,460</SECOND>
<HEAD>Reaction Typically Partisan to Vice Presidential Debate</HEAD>
<HEAD>With AM-Debate Rdp Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DONALD M. ROTHBERG</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Political Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Republicans declared that <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> exceeded expectations in the vice presidential debate Wednesday night, while Democrats said the confrontation demonstrated <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>'s experience and qualifications for president As expected, reaction to the 90-minute debate held in <LOCATION> Omaha </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Neb. </LOCATION>, and broadcast nationally, was strongly partisan, with backers of Republican <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> praising <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>'s performance, and supporters of Democrat <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, declaring <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> the victor. White House spokesman <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> described President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> as `` gratified'' by the outcome and said the president called <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> to congratulate him. Democratic Sen. <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> said, `` Neither scored a knockout, but <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> looked and sounded more presidential.'' `` I do n't think there's any question <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> made himself an asset to the ticket tonight,'' said Sen. <PERSON> Mitch </PERSON> <PERSON> McConnell </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Kentucky </LOCATION>, a national co-chairman of the <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> campaign. `` Prior to tonight he was not.'' <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>'s jibe at <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> when the <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION> senator compared his experience to that of <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> drew a mixed reaction. `` <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> was a friend of mine,'' the <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> Democrat told <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>. `` Senator, you're no <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>.'' `` That was uncalled for, senator,'' retorted <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>. `` It threw a chill over the whole debate, a sour note,'' said Atlanta-based pollster <PERSON> Clairbourne </PERSON> <PERSON> Darden </PERSON>. `` It changed from then on, the way you looked at <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>.'' But Democrats said <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> looked bad when he tried to compare himself with <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>. `` I think <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>'s worst moment was when he tried to cpmpare himself to <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>,'' said Democratic Sen. <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Cranston </PERSON> of <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>. `` He -LRB- <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> -RRB- was forced to think for himself and it did n't go over,'' said Sen. <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, D-Tenn. <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Teichner </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> pollster, said he saw no clear winner `` Because of the low expectations for <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>, the polls will probably show that <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> probably won,'' said <PERSON> Teichner </PERSON>. `` As for whether the debate will help in the overall race, I think it's a wash.'' <PERSON> Merle </PERSON> <PERSON> Black </PERSON>, a political scientist at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> North </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Carolina </ORGANIZATION>, said, `` I think <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> did a better job I think the <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> ticket ought to be helped by his performance.'' But he also praised <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> who, he said, `` performed well enough that the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> campaign will not have to engage in extensive damage control after tonight. But I think he was out-debated by <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>.'' <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> <PERSON> Neuman </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> League </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Women </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Voters </ORGANIZATION>, called the debate a draw. `` I do n't see that one outshone the other particularly,'' she said. `` I think they came off pretty well as they intended. Whether the voters won, I'm still trying to figure out.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881005-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-05-88 2342EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Haiti     10-05 0449</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Haiti,0462</SECOND>
<HEAD>Haitian Merchants Block Dominican Consulate; Priest Applauds
Reform</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MICHAEL NORTON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> PORT-AU-PRINCE </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Haiti </LOCATION> -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> -RRB- _ About 100 Haitian merchants blocked the <LOCATION> Dominican </LOCATION> consulate Wednesday, claiming Dominican soldiers were confiscating their goods, Radio Haiti-Inter reported. In another development, the <ORGANIZATION> Roman </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> priest who escaped injury when thugs massacred his parishioners three weeks ago made his first public comment on the attack Wednesday and applauded the Haitian soldiers' rebellion. The merchants, who in <LOCATION> Haiti </LOCATION> resell merchandise bought in the <LOCATION> Dominican </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Republic </LOCATION>, claim the incidents occurred from Sept. 26 to Oct. 1. Most of the incidents occurred at <LOCATION> Barahona </LOCATION>, a small town in southwestern <LOCATION> Dominican </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Republic </LOCATION> near the Haitian border. The merchants claimed the Dominicans said it was `` a special control'' measure ordered by Dominican President <PERSON> Joaquin </PERSON> <PERSON> Balaguer </PERSON>. An unidentified witness alleged the soldiers pointed their rifles at them and confiscated the goods to sell them. In a recorded radio address broadcast by local stations, the Rev. <PERSON> Jean-Bertrand </PERSON> <PERSON> Aristide </PERSON> paid tribute to the 13 parishioners who died and the more than 70 who were wounded Sept. 11 when men with guns, machetes and metal skewers attacked his St. <PERSON> Jean </PERSON> <PERSON> Bosco </PERSON> church. `` Like <PERSON> Jesus </PERSON> <PERSON> Christ </PERSON>, the victims of the massacre of <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Jean </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bosco </ORGANIZATION> fell in a bloodbath of love for the liberation of their country,'' <PERSON> Aristide </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Aristide </PERSON>, an advocate of Marxist liberation theology who has been condemned by the church hierarchy, saluted `` the valiant soldiers who have decided to continue the house-cleaning operation.'' But he did not praise Lt. Gen. <PERSON> Prosper </PERSON> <PERSON> Avril </PERSON>, the country's new leader, associating him with other officiers linked to the <PERSON> Duvalier </PERSON> regimes of the past. `` The people do not trust you; -LRB- the people -RRB- should consider all bigshot Duvalierists as big-time criminals until they prove the contrary for the rest of their lives,'' he said in remarks addressed to <PERSON> Avril </PERSON>. Rank-and-file soldiers of the Presidential Guard, upset by the church massacre and other government-sponsored violence, overthrew military ruler Lt. Gen. <PERSON> Henri </PERSON> <PERSON> Namphy </PERSON> on Sept. 17 and sent him into exile in the <LOCATION> Dominican </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Republic </LOCATION>. They named <PERSON> Avril </PERSON> as his successor and accused <PERSON> Namphy </PERSON> and <LOCATION> Port-au-Prince </LOCATION> Mayor Mayor <PERSON> Franck </PERSON> <PERSON> Romain </PERSON> of masterminding the massacre. The enlisted men ousted many of their unpopular commanding officers in the week following the coup, while the general populace hunted down, stoned to death and burned a number of Tonton Macoutes believed responsible for the church massacre. The Macoutes are former members of the private militia of the <PERSON> Duvalier </PERSON> family dictatorship that ruled <LOCATION> Haiti </LOCATION> for 29 years until <PERSON> Jean-Claude </PERSON> <PERSON> Duvalier </PERSON> was ousted and exiled in February 1986. <PERSON> Avril </PERSON> has been identified for years as a staunch <ORGANIZATION> Duvalierist </ORGANIZATION> and became a multimillionaire as financial advisor to the dictator's family
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881005-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-05-88 2344EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p AM-Quayle 3rdLd-Writethru a0860 10-05 0632</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Quayle, 3rd Ld-Writethru, a0860,640</SECOND>
<HEAD>Public Told It Will `See the Real Dan Quayle'</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: INSERTS 8 grafs after 6th graf pvs bgng, `Thank you,' to
UPDATE with Quayle at rally, new quotes</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By EILEEN PUTMAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>OMAHA, Neb. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Republican vice presidential nominee <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> said Wednesday night that he did `` great'' in his debate with <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> and said he was pleased at being grilled three times about his qualifications for higher office. `` We were delighted that they brought it up three different times because it gave us three different times to talk to the <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> people about what I'll do for the country,'' <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> said as he left the Civic Auditorium where the debate was held and headed toward a post-debate rally. Asked about his performance, <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> smiled at reporters and said, `` Great.'' <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Prosperi </PERSON>, <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>'s spokesman, said <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> received congratulatory calls after the debate from Vice President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Republican leader <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>. He quoted <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> as telling his running mate, `` You did great.'' `` Thank you very much,'' <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> told <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, according to <PERSON> Prosperi </PERSON>. At the rally at an outdoor park following the debate, <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> asked 2,000 flag-waving supporters, `` Did we win the debate?'' They shouted back: `` Yes.'' Referring to Wednesday's <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> League </ORGANIZATION> playoff game in which the <ORGANIZATION> Oakland </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Athletics </ORGANIZATION> beat the <ORGANIZATION> Boston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sox </ORGANIZATION> 2-1, <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> said, `` This afternoon, the team from <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> lost, and tonight, the man from <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> lost.'' Democratic presidential nominee <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> is governor of <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> said <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> had made `` absolutely no response to the fact that <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> is simply out of step with mainstream <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>.'' `` After tonight, <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> has a little better picture of the road that we want to take right into the 21st Century,'' <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> said. As he was leaving the rally to head for his hotel room, <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> was asked by reporters about <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>'s comment during the debate that `` You're no <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>.'' `` It was uncalled for,'' <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> said. Before the debate, <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>, in a jocular mood, had admonished the press to `` Watch us carefully. Take good notes. Good news stories now.'' `` I feel good,'' <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> said as he left his hotel for the debate. Earlier Wednesday, the <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION> senator, wearing makeup for his morning rehearsal before the cameras and tour of the Civic Auditorium stage with his top aides, looked confident and relaxed. `` We're ready,'' <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> told reporters as he emerged from his hotel. Asked if he was nervous, <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> replied, `` Not yet.'' `` The mike works. That's very important to make sure the mike works and ours is working well,' he said as he left the debate hall. As for <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>, his Democratic counterpart, <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> joked, `` I just hope he shows up.'' <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> had a low-key day as he prepared for the debate. He spent the afternoon relaxing in his hotel room, except for a brief walk outside. When reporters asked about his debate strategy, <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> said, `` We do n't want to give any strategies away.'' But, he said: `` You're going to see <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> as he really is. You're going to see the real <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>.'' <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> and his aides telegraphed his strategy days ago, saying the focus would be on <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> rather than <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>, who the Republicans say is closer to them than the Democrats on many issues. `` <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> is running for president, and he's the one I'm very concerned about becoming president,'' <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> told reporters Tuesday. `` It would be a very troubling notion for many Americans.'' <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> took part in two mock debates this week with Sen. <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Packwood </PERSON>, R-Ore., who played <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>, and has had dozens of issues briefings He said <PERSON> Packwood </PERSON> and his briefing team `` thought of every tough question you could possibly think of'' during the rehearsals. `` I gave brilliant answers,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881005-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-05-88 2348EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p BC-DebateExcerpts 2Takes   10-05 1092</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Debate Excerpts, 2 Takes,1,000-2,000</SECOND>
<DATELINE>OMAHA, Neb. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are excerpts from Wednesday night's debate between vice presidential candidates Sen. <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Texas </LOCATION>, and Sen. <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>, R-Ind
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 Question: Why do you think that you have not made a more substantial impression on some of these people who have been able to observe you up close? Quayle: ... Qualifications for the office of vice president or president are not age alone ... Let's look at the three biggest issues that are going to be confronting <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> in the next presidency. Those three issues are national security and arms control, jobs and education, and the federal budget deficit. On each one of those issues I have more experience than does the governor of <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION>. ... <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>: This debate tonight, is not about the qualifications for the vice presidency. No, the debate tonight, is a debate about the presidency itself, and a presidential decision that has to be made by you. The stakes could not be higher. Question: If you had to step in to the presidency, who's agenda would you pursue? Yours, or -LRB- <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' -RRB-? <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>: ... We agree on so many things, and the vast majority of the issues. We agree on the fact that we have to cut this deficit ... Governor <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> and I agree that we ought to have a trade policy for this country, that we've seen this administration more than double the national debt, that they've moved this country from the No. 1 lender nation in the world to the No. 1 debtor nation in the world under their administration, that they have not had a trade policy, that they've let trade be a handmaiden for the foreign policy objectives of the country, that this country has exported too many jobs and not enough products. ... Quayle: ... Governor <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, one of the most liberal governors in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, ... raised taxes five times. He just raised taxes this last year, and that's why a lot of people refer to him `` Tax Hike <PERSON> Mike </PERSON>.'' That's why they refer to the state of <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> as Taxachusetts. ... Question: ... Are n't you and Gov. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> using -LRB- Social Security -RRB- politically, rather than dealing with it responsibily? <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>: ... We have a contract with the <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> people on Social Security, and <ORGANIZATION> Social </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> is an issue where Sen. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> voted eight times to cut the benefits on Social Security. ... Now, when you talk about Social Security the people that are going to protect it are the Democrats who brought forth that program. ... Quayle: Sen. <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>, you know that I did not vote to cut Social Security benefits eight times. What I have voted for, and what Sen. <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> has voted for, is to delay the cost-of-living adjustments. ... You're right, they use this for political advantage. What they try to do time and time again is to scare the old people of this country. ... Question: ... Do you consider yourself an environmentalist? And, if you do, how do you reconcile that with your voting record? Quayle: I have a very strong record on the environment in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>. ... I have voted for the major pieces of environmental legislation that have come down and been voted on in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>. ... If you bring up the environment, you ca n't help but think about the environmental policy of the governor of <LOCATION> Massachsetts </LOCATION>. ... The <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Harbor </LOCATION> which is the dirtiest waterway in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>. ... What has the governor of <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> done about that? Virtually nothing. ... <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>: ... We're the authors, the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, of <ORGANIZATION> Clean </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION>, of Clean Water, of the Superfunding. I'm one who played a very major role in passing the Superfund legislation. And every environmental organization that I know, every major one has now endorsed the Dukakis-Bentsen ticket. ... Question: I'd like for you to ... explain ... your votes against the school breakfast program, the school lunch program and the expansion of the child immunization program. Quayle: ... I have a very good record and a commitment to the poor, to those that do n't have a family, want to have a family. This administration and a <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration will be committed to eradicating poverty. ... The poverty program we are going to concentrate on is creating jobs and opportunities so that everyone will have the opportunities that they want. <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>: ... What also frustrates me ... is the kind of votes he's cast against child nutrition programs, the fact that he has voted against money that we needed for further immunization, the denial of polio shots to kids where the parents could n't afford to get that kind of a shot. Now I do n't really believe that is identifying with the concerns of people in poverty. Question: ... You and <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> seem to be diametrically opposed on -LRB- Contra aid -RRB-. <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>: Gov. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> and I have disagreed on the Contra program ... But my big difference with this administration is they look at the Contra aid program as the only way to resolve that problem. ... I believe that you have to work with the leaders of those other Central American countries to try to bring about the democratization of <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> ... Quayle: There's no doubt, in a <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> administration that the aid would be cut off to the democratic resistance in <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> and that is unfortunate. ... Question: Governor <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> has tried to make ethics a major issue in the campaign. And he has you as a running mate, a man who leads the league, at last count, in the receipt of PAC money ... Do you find that embarrassing, Senator? <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>: No, I do n't ... Wwhat I've done in PAC money is just what my opponent in my campaign has done in his campaign. ... So what you have to do is comply with the laws as they are ... I have been for campaign reform and have pushed it very hard. ... But I've noticed that the senator from <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION> has opposed that campaign reform and voted repeatedly against it ... Quayle: Senator <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> is the number one PAC raiser. As a matter of fact, he used to have a $ 10,000 Breakfast Club. ... It only cost high-paid lobbyist special interests in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> to come down and have breakfast with the chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Finance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committe </ORGANIZATION> _ the one that oversees all the tax loopholes in the tax code _ $ 10,000. I'm sure they were n't paying to have Corn Flakes.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>MORE</NOTE>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881005-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-05-88 2348EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p AM-Bush-Debate 1stLd-Writethru a0812 10-05 0314</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Bush-Debate, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0812,270</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush Praises Quayle's Performance in Debate</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDs: INSERTS 3 grafs after 3rd graf bgng, `Asked if,' to UPDATE
with Bush calling Quayle after debate ends</NOTE>
<DATELINE>FORT WORTH, Texas, (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> praised running mate <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>'s performance in the nationally televised debate Wednesday night with rival <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>, saying <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> hit a `` home run'' on his first answer. `` He's doing good, good opening, strong opening, right out of the ball park, the <PERSON> Canseco </PERSON> of American politics,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> told reporters, referring to <ORGANIZATION> Oakland </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> A </ORGANIZATION>'s baseball player <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Canseco </PERSON>. `` He hit it the first answer, home run.,'' Asked if the question to <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> _ a <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> senator from <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION> _ on criticisms of his qualifications was a fair one, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> replied, `` Everything's fair in this business ... I'd like to get a slow ball like that in the first one. It's easy.'' After the debate, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> called <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> to congratulate him, according to <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Prosperi </PERSON>, <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>'s spokesman. He quoted <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> as telling his running mate, `` You did great.'' `` Thank you very much,'' <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> told <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, according to <PERSON> Prosperi </PERSON>. The vice president, who had arrived at his hotel here in time to watch <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> take on <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> senator from <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, had invited reporters to watch the first question with him. `` Deja vu ... same podiums we used,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> commented, referring to his debate with Democratic presidential nominee <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, the governor of <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION>. His concern with staging was evident as he commented on <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>'s position when he shook hands with <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> `` Full-faced, looks good,'' he said, then added, laughing, `` Full-face, turn, it's a very important thing.'' Earlier Wednesday, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> had taken some time out from campaigning to telephone <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> and wish him well in the debate, according to <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s chief of staff, <PERSON> Craig </PERSON> <PERSON> Fuller </PERSON>. During the 10-minute conversation, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> told <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>, `` Relax, I know it will go well.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881005-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-05-88 2352EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p AM-RatingtheDebate     10-05 0877</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Rating the Debate,790</SECOND>
<HEAD>Debate Panel Calls Bentsen Winner Over Quayle</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CHRISTOPHER CONNELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> panel of veteran debate judges called <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> the winner by a wide margin over <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> in their vice presidential debate Wednesday night. An instant <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> poll also gave the victory to the Democratic nominee. ABC News polled 637 registered voters immediately after the debate. Fifty-one percent said <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> had won, 27 called <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> the winner and 22 percent said it was a tie. The debate also swayed some undecided voters over to the Democratic ticket. In a survey prior to the debate, 50 percent said they favored <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> while 45 percent picked <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> and 5 percent were undecided. After the debate, the same people favored <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> with 50 percent, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> received 48 percent and 2 percent were unsure. Eighty-seven percent said <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> was qualified to become president, 12 percent said he was n't and 1 percent was undecided. Asked whether <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> was qualified to assume the presidency, 48 percent said yes, 49 percent said no and 3 percent were undecided. The poll had a margin of error of plus or minus 4.5 percent. The AP panel of six debate judges, unanimous in calling <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> the winner, scored the contest 148-125 for the <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> senator. Some panel members pointed to <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>'s statement that <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> was `` no <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>'' as the turning point of the debate. <PERSON> Melissa </PERSON> <PERSON> Maxcy </PERSON> <PERSON> Wade </PERSON>, the director of forensics at <ORGANIZATION> Emory </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>, scored it 24-22 for <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>. `` I thought <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> really held his own until we got to the <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> question,'' she said. `` It was like a father putting down a child. I thought the momentum turned then.'' `` Up to that point <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> had not answered the breakfast club questions well. But after that, it was almost like he got more confidence,'' said <PERSON> Wade </PERSON>. `` It was almost like the <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> question fueled <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> for the rest of the debate.'' <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Unger </PERSON>, director of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forensics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> at <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> and chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> panel, picked <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> 25-17. He said, `` <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> generally lived down to his expectations. <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> lived up to and even above his. In fact, <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> made a better case for <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> than <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> has.'' <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Copeland </PERSON>, national executive secretary of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forensic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> League </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Ripon </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wis. </LOCATION>, said itwas the best of any of the presidential or vice-presidential debates since 1976. <PERSON> Copeland </PERSON>, who scored it 25-22 for <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>, said <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> `` chose to ignore questions that were being asked and instead to attack <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> and to bring in political themes of his own choosing.'' He said some of <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>'s `` slash-and-burn attacks were reminiscent of Sen. -LRB- Bob -RRB- <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>'' in the 1976 vice presidential debate against <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> Mondale </PERSON>. <PERSON> Copeland </PERSON> said <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>, with his `` very avuncular manner,'' stuck closer to the debate format. But he added that the panel of reporters also gave <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> `` as harsh a grilling as I have ever seen.'' <PERSON> Steven </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Mancuso </PERSON>, director of intercollegiate forensics for the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Michigan </ORGANIZATION>, scored it 23-20 for <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>. `` I felt <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> failed to answer the question that was asked him three times about what he would do if he had to assume the presidency,'' said <PERSON> Mancuso </PERSON>. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Southworth </PERSON>, director of forensics and professor of speech at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Redlands </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, scored it 26-24 for <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>, but said, `` I thought <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> won a large majority of the issues, but I'm not convinced he will come out looking as if he did.'' He said he was not sure how viewers will take <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>'s <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> crack <PERSON> Donn </PERSON> <PERSON> Parson </PERSON>, director of graduate study in the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Kansas </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ' </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Communication </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Studies </ORGANIZATION>, rated <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> a 25-20 winner. `` The difference was <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>'s inability to cite specifics,'' said <PERSON> Parson </PERSON>. `` One of the best examples was on the environment. He answered by saying <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> will take on the problem.'' In the Sept. 25 debate between <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> and <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, the AP panel picked <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> as a narrow winner on points, 144-141. The judges watched the debate on television and used a scorecard modeled after the one used in collegiate and scholastic debates. They awarded one to five points in each of six categories: reasoning, evidence, organization, refutation, cross-examination and presentation. A 1 was poor; 2 fair; 3 average; 4 excellent, and 5 superior. Each judge could award a maximum of 30 points. A perfect score would have been 180. Here are the candidates' combined scores:
</TEXT>
<HEAD>Debate Scorecard</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 19 Reasoning 24
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 21 Evidence 27
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 22 Organization 23
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 19 Refutation 23
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 21 Cross-Exam. 24
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 23 Presentation 27
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 125 TOTAL 148
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881005-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-05-88 0036EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-GulfMines     10-05 0573</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Gulf Mines,0587</SECOND>
<HEAD>Mine Threat Serious But Ignored, Military Sources Say</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By RICHARD PYLE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MANAMA, Bahrain (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Governments with a stake in the oil-rich <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> should give urgent priority to the threat from mines, Western military and diplomatic officials say. Even though there is a cease-fire in the Iran-Iraq war, `` the mines do n't know there's a cease-fire,'' said <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> Capt. <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Miller </PERSON>. <PERSON> Miller </PERSON>, who has commanded the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> mine-sweeping contingent in the gulf for the past few months, said Monday, `` They're out there, cocked and ready to fire. If we do n't deal with them on our terms, we'll have to deal with them on theirs.'' At least seven mines have been found in the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> since the truce went into effect 45 days ago, and military sources speak of a `` statistical probability'' that a ship will hit one of the explosives. American intelligence assessments say there are 150 to 200 mines still in the gulf, concentrated in the north. Most are believed to have been laid by <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> and some by <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>, officers say, but neither country has provided data on the locations. These officers have predicted that the problem will worsen as winter storms cause more of the long-submerged explosives to break loose and follow prevailing currents down the western coast of the gulf. Military sources, speaking on condition they not be identified, said the mines threaten not only shipping but the fishing industry, underwater oil pipelines and children who sometimes find the odd-looking globes washed up on beaches. Several coastal fishing dhows have been sunk or damaged by mines. One source recalled that two <LOCATION> Bahrain </LOCATION> children were killed by a mine last year, and said another was found recently in <LOCATION> Qatar </LOCATION>. Between 12 and 50 mines are known to have been sunk, unexploded, by local naval units off the coast between <LOCATION> Kuwait </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arab </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Emirates </LOCATION>, one source said. `` If those are n't found and destroyed, one of them bumping against a pipeline and exploding could create an immense pollution problem,'' he said. Progress toward a coordinated effort to clear the mines is impeded by political concerns within the six-member <ORGANIZATION> Gulf </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cooperation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>, the military and diplomatic sources said. The countries _ <LOCATION> Saudi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arabia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Kuwait </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Bahrain </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Qatar </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arab </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Emirates </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Oman </LOCATION> _ remained nominally neutral during the war but supported <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> against non-Arab <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>. Now, say Western diplomats, the council states are reluctant to undertake any action that either <LOCATION> Baghdad </LOCATION> or <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION> might interpret as hostile. `` As long as the <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> peace talks remain stalled, nobody wants to do anything that could be seen as ` anti-anybody,' said one diplomat. The mine threat, one said, `` is n't something they're paying a lot of attention to, and they're not likely to until things start to go bang in the night.'' Although council states privately welcomed the foreign warships sent to the gulf last year to escort tankers, their presence remains a touchy political issue and the governments might not recognize the mine problem before anti-mine vessels leave the gulf, one Western source said. There now are at least 16 foreign mine sweepers in the gulf region, including six <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION>, three British, two Italian, two French, one Belgian, one Dutch and one or more Soviet. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officers say there are no plans for the 30-year-old, wooden-hulled American craft to leave and suggest some might remain indefinitely.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881005-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-05-88 0038EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-StolenBaby     10-05 0203</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Stolen Baby,0209</SECOND>
<HEAD>Newborn Kidnapped From Hospital Found Healthy A Week Later</HEAD>
<DATELINE>GRASSE, France (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A 9-day-old baby taken from his mother's hospital room last week has been found in the home of a woman depressed following a recent miscarriage, police said <PERSON> Ali </PERSON> <PERSON> Salah </PERSON> appeared to be in perfect health when he was found Tuesday, polce said. <PERSON> Daniele </PERSON> <PERSON> Imbert </PERSON>, 43, and her common-law husband identified only as Mr. Lazur were being held for questioning but were not immediately charged. Police sources, speaking on condition of anonymity, said she at first claimed the boy was her own, but under questioning admitted she had taken him from his mother's hospital room, three days after his birth. The mother, <PERSON> Latifa </PERSON> <PERSON> Salah </PERSON>, reported that <PERSON> Ali </PERSON> disappeared last Wednesday from his cradle in her room in the maternity ward at the <LOCATION> Grasse </LOCATION> hospital while she was taking a shower. Witnesses reported seeing a woman who appeared to be in her 40s carrying a baby out of the hospital at about that time, and police distributed a composite sketch. Neighbors of <PERSON> Daniele </PERSON> <PERSON> Imbert </PERSON> spotted the resemblance and alerted authorities. Police sources said the woman in custody had a miscarriage in June, and wanted a child desperately.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881005-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-05-88 0039EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-BRF--Silva-Sentence     10-05 0141</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Silva-Sentence,0145</SECOND>
<HEAD>Driver in Crash That Killed Actor Trinidad Silva Given 10 Years</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A man who pleaded guilty to causing the traffic accident that killed actor <PERSON> Trinidad </PERSON> <PERSON> Silva </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> was sentenced Tuesday to 10 years in state prison. <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON> <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Owen </PERSON>, 35, of <PERSON> La </PERSON> <PERSON> Habra </PERSON>, who pleaded guilty last month to vehicular manslaughter, drunken driving and hit-and-run charges, was given the maximum sentence allowable by law, said prosecutor <PERSON> Dinko </PERSON> <PERSON> Bozanich </PERSON>. <PERSON> Silva </PERSON>, who appeared on the television series `` Hill Street Blues'' and in the movies `` Colors'' and `` The Milagro Beanfield Wars,'' was thrown from his truck and killed when <PERSON> Owens </PERSON>' car ran a red light and collided with <PERSON> Silva </PERSON>'s truck at a <LOCATION> Whittier </LOCATION> intersection July 30. <PERSON> Silva </PERSON>'s wife, <LOCATION> Sofia </LOCATION>, and 2-year-old son, <PERSON> Samuel </PERSON>, suffered minor injuries. <PERSON> Owens </PERSON> will be eligible for parole in five years, <PERSON> Bozanich </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881005-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-05-88 0042EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FarmScene     10-05 0935</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Farm Scene,930</SECOND>
<HEAD>Farmers' Share of Food Dollar Lowest in 75 Years</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DON KENDALL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Farm Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 New government figures show that farmers last year got the smallest portion of the food shopper's dollar since the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> began compiling such figures 75 years ago. According to revised figures by the department's <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>, the `` farm value'' of the retail cost of a market basket of food sold in grocery stores in 1987 was 30 percent, down for the third straight year from 35 percent in 1984. The farmer's share of the food dollar dropped to 32 percent in 1985 and to 31 percent in 1986. Earlier <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> estimates had put those readings even lower: to 31 percent in 1985, 30 percent in 1986 and 29 percent in 1987. Department records show the farm share of each consumer food dollar averaged 46 percent in 1913, when recordkeeping began. Until the figure fell to 31 percent in 1986, the record low mark had been 32 percent in both 1932 and 1933 during the Depression. The high was more than 50 percent in World War II and for a few years thereafter. The market basket contains average quantities of domestically produced food bought in grocery stores, excluding non-alcoholic beverages, and fish and seafood. One reason for the slippage in the farm value of grocery items has been a general weakening of prices for some raw commodities. But the situation varies greatly from item to item. And it depends on how much processing is involved. `` Only a slight amount of raw milk is lost, for example, as it is handled and processed for sale in cartons to consumers,'' the report said. `` Therefore, the farm value of the retail price per half-gallon is just a little more than the price that milk producers receive per half-gallon.'' The report added: `` In contrast, nearly 2.4 pounds of live animal are needed to yield one pound of Choice beef on the meat counter. The payment the cattle producer receives for that large quantity of live animal is the gross farm value in the price of one pound of retail beef.'' With the 1987 farm value of groceries at 30 cents of each consumer food dollar, that means 70 cents went to non-farmers, the people who buy, transport, process and sell food at wholesale and retail. Each time the farmer's share declines, it means a greater `` farm-retail'' share for the others. <PERSON> Ralph </PERSON> <PERSON> Parlett </PERSON>, a food economist in the agency, says the trend to a smaller share for farmers also is the result of a growing consumer preference for a greater degree of processing in food. When the farmer's share of the food dollar was 45 cents to 49 cents in the early 1950s, there was less processing. People bought raw food, took it home and cooked or preserved it. Now, <PERSON> Parlett </PERSON> said in a recent telephone interview, supermarkets display the latest in the processor's art. `` The products we have today are n't the same,'' he said. `` Microwave products are an example. We did n't have those at all a few years ago.'' Also, he said, the `` efficiencies of farmers have picked up,'' meaning that greater yields are resulting from the same acreages, more meat from the same amount of feed.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Fears of a decade ago that city sprawl might consume farmland by the millions of acres annually have not materialized, according to a new study by the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Marlow </PERSON> <PERSON> Vesterby </PERSON> and <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Brooks </PERSON> of the department's <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> estimated that urban areas grew at the rate of about 740,000 acres a year during the 1970s `` Concern continues about the survival of farms in high-growth, rural-urban fringe areas and about the adequacy of cropland for future food and fiber production,'' they said in the latest issue of Agricultural Outlook magazine. `` However, ERS calculations based on aerial photographs show that urbanization of agricultural land is not occurring as rapidly as previously thought.'' In January 1981, just before the <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> administration left office, a report by the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agricultural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lands </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Study </ORGANIZATION> said new intiatives were needed to protect farmland and to ensure that the nation would have enough productive capacity. The study estimated that the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> was losing agricultural land at the rate of about 3 million acres a year, including about 1 million acres from the nation's cropland base. Other experts at the time questioned the study's figures as misleading. They asserted that the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> was in no danger of running out of cropland. The study also estimated that American farmers would have to plant between 84 million and 143 million additional acres by the year 2000 `` in order to meet anticipated domestic and foreign demands for agricultural products.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Agriculture Department says farmers soon will be getting about $ 1.2 billion in cash payments for participating in the Conservation Reserve Program. <PERSON> Milton </PERSON> <PERSON> Hertz </PERSON>, executive vice president of the department's <ORGANIZATION> Commodity </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Credit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, said Tuesday the payments are rental fees for land contracts signed in the 1986, 1987 and 1988 fiscal years Under the program, farmers agree to take highly erodible cropland from production for 10 years. In return, <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> helps pay for planting the land with protective grass or trees and provides annual rental payments over the 10-year contract period. The goal under the program is to take 40 million to 45 million acres of highly erodible land from crop production by 1990. More than 25.5 million acres have have been enrolled officially, and an additional 3.4 million acres were offered by farmers in a recent signup.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881005-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-05-88 0030EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     10-05 0931</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0975</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names In The News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SACRAMENTO, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actress <PERSON> Raquel </PERSON> <PERSON> Welch </PERSON> has been hospitalized, but she instructed hospital officials not to say why. `` <PERSON> Raquel </PERSON> <PERSON> Welch </PERSON> is here and that's the only information I can verify,'' <PERSON> Diana </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON>, a spokeswoman for <ORGANIZATION> Sutter </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Memorial </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION>, said Tuesday. <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON>, who declined to say when the actress was admitted, said no additional information was being released `` per her -LRB- Miss <PERSON> Welch </PERSON>'s -RRB- request.'' <PERSON> Sylvia </PERSON> <PERSON> Gold </PERSON>, a spokeswoman for the actress, did not immediately respond to a request for information. Miss <PERSON> Welch </PERSON>, 48, appeared in such movies as `` Fantastic Voyage,'' `` One Million Years B.C.'' and `` <PERSON> Myra </PERSON> <PERSON> Breckinridge </PERSON>'' in the 1960s and early 1970s. More recently, she starred in the <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> made-for-TV movie `` Right to Die.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LA QUINTA, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A desert mansion under construction for TV producer-turned-businessman <PERSON> Merv </PERSON> <PERSON> Griffin </PERSON> was heavily damaged by fire, authorities said. Tuesday's blaze caused about $ 1 million in damage to the $ 1.75 million home, fire officials said. Its cause was not determined. The house, more than 100 miles east of <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> near <LOCATION> Palm </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Springs </LOCATION>, was 80 percent complete, `` and a little more than half of it was destroyed,'' said <LOCATION> Riverside </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> Fire Capt. <PERSON> Brenda </PERSON> <PERSON> Seabert </PERSON>. <PERSON> Griffin </PERSON>, who has numerous homes, is in the process of building another one atop a mountain in <LOCATION> Beverly </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hills </LOCATION>. In between house building, he is attempting to buy the Resorts International hotel-casino in <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.J. </LOCATION>, from <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> developer <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Trump </PERSON>. <PERSON> Griffin </PERSON>, 63, taped his last `` <PERSON> Merv </PERSON> <PERSON> Griffin </PERSON> Show'' in September 1986, ending 24 years as a television talk show host. Later, he created such TV shows as `` Wheel of Fortune'' before selling his TV production company to the <ORGANIZATION> Coca-Cola </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>. Fortune magazine has estimated his worth at $ 300 million
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Prince <PERSON> Charles </PERSON>, an outspoken critic of stripped-down modern architecture, will narrate a television documentary he wrote on the subject, the program's producer said. `` The Prince of <LOCATION> Wales </LOCATION> has done more than anybody to bring architectural issues into the public arena,'' said producer <PERSON> Christopher </PERSON> <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> of the program, `` A Vision of <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>.'' The 70-minute show, part of the <ORGANIZATION> British </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Broadcasting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Omnibus'' series, is scheduled for broadcast Oct. 28, <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> said A Buckingham Palace spokesman, speaking on condition of anonymity, confirmed the report Tuesday. The 39-year-old heir to the British throne has taken potshots at the modern architecture sprouting up among <LOCATION> Great </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s classical Georgian and Gothic Victorian edifices In one speech, he accused modern architects, planners and developers of causing more harm to <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>'s skyline than the <LOCATION> German </LOCATION> air force did during the World War II blitz.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>OMAHA, Neb. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The daughters of comedian <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Benny </PERSON> and movie star <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Cooper </PERSON> say they have fond memories of growing up with their famous fathers. <PERSON> Joan </PERSON> <PERSON> Benny </PERSON> said Tuesday she told one of her sons, `` I wish you had known him. You could learn one important thing from him: humility. <PERSON> Maria </PERSON> <PERSON> Cooper </PERSON> <PERSON> Janis </PERSON> said the only thing that seemed to set her parents apart from less famous folk was the way they were treated in places like <PERSON> Maxim </PERSON>'s, the <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> restaurant. Ms. <PERSON> Benny </PERSON> and Mrs. <PERSON> Janis </PERSON>, both only children of the legends, opened the 25th season of the Omaha Women's Town Hall lecture series with reminiscences of their youth. Ms. <PERSON> Benny </PERSON> said she grew up in <LOCATION> Beverly </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hills </LOCATION>, attending public and private schools and ultimately <ORGANIZATION> Stanford </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> before moving to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> to start a career in modeling and acting. After failing to achieve much success, she said, she returned to <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, where rearing four children became her career. Ms. <PERSON> Benny </PERSON>, who is divorced, now lectures on the evolution of comedy. Mrs. <PERSON> Janis </PERSON>, a graduate of the <ORGANIZATION> Chouinard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Art </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>, said she tries to convey her feelings in her art.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDs: Note language in 2nd graf.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>ATLANTIC CITY, N.J. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Perry </PERSON> <PERSON> Como </PERSON> says the `` awful novelty songs'' that his concert audiences still demand have been haunting him since the 1930s, when he sang with <PERSON> Ted </PERSON> <PERSON> Weem </PERSON>'s big band. `` Me and <PERSON> Sinatra </PERSON> and all the rest of the singers used to talk about all the crap we had to sing,'' <PERSON> Como </PERSON> said. Como, 76, said he still winces when performing such million-selling hits as `` Papa Love Mambo'' and `` Do n't Let the Stars Get in Your Eyes.'' `` ` A Hubba-Hubba-Hubba' was another sick one and another gold record,'' said <PERSON> Como </PERSON>, who performs this week at <ORGANIZATION> Bally </ORGANIZATION>'s Grand Hotel and Casino. `` I still do them onstage once in a while because the audience wants it, but I say ` yech' afterwards.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>ROSLYN, N.Y. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A beaming <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> hugged two <LOCATION> Korean </LOCATION> children she brought to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> for life-saving heart surgery five years ago, and declared `` they look wonderful'' during a reunion. Mrs. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> took the shy-looking youngsters by the hands Tuesday while visiting other young heart patients at <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Francis </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION>. `` They speak perfect English, too,'' she said. The children had returned for their annual checkups at <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francis </LOCATION>, where they underwent open heart surgery in 1983. Both received a clean bill of health. Mrs. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> had learned about the children _ <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Kil </PERSON> <PERSON> Woo </PERSON>, then 4, and <PERSON> Ahn </PERSON> <PERSON> Hi </PERSON> <PERSON> Sook </PERSON>, then 7 _ through the <ORGANIZATION> Rotary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Club </ORGANIZATION>'s Gift of Life program while she was visiting <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> with her husband in November 1983. She arranged to bring them back on Air Force One, and has since followed their progress. The youngsters were adopted by an American couple four years ago and live in <LOCATION> Flagstaff </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ariz </LOCATION>. The Gift of Life program provides expenses for childrens' heart surgery at participating <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> hospitals.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881005-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-05-88 0054EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-NuclearSafety Bjt   10-05 0848</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nuclear Safety, Bjt,790</SECOND>
<HEAD>`National Security' Kept Mishaps Secret at U.S. Nuclear Plant</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BRYAN BRUMLEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 For three decades, serious mishaps at the <LOCATION> Savannah </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> nuclear weapons plant were kept secret for national security reasons and in some cases not reported to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, according to federal officials who are trying to change that attitude. One senior <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> official has compared the approach to safety at the <LOCATION> Savannah </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Plant </LOCATION>, near <LOCATION> Aiken </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> S.C. </LOCATION>, to that which led to the explosion of the shuttle Challenger on Jan. 28, 1986. And one member of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> says the facility, which has been closed since August, should not be allowed to reopen until the situation improves. An <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> spokesman, <PERSON> Will </PERSON> <PERSON> Callicott </PERSON>, said that since the federal government began making atomic weapons in World War II, `` there has always been a mind set, a culture, that we are doing work that is important for national security and perhaps that may override any obligation toward public accountablility. `` People have historically not been sensitive to the importance of disclosing things,'' <PERSON> Callicott </PERSON> said. `` Clearly, there is a lot of information that did not make it up the chain to top management here at headquarters.'' Without a detailed review of the record, he said, it would be impossible to determine exactly what information had reached <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> and what had been released to the public. Energy Secretary <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Herrington </PERSON>, since taking office in 1985, `` has given heightened attention to the area of environmental safety and health,'' and for the first time placed these issues in the hands of an assistant secretary, <PERSON> Callicott </PERSON> said. The <LOCATION> Savannah </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> facility produces plutonium and tritium, which are used in making nuclear weapons. It is run by E.I. du <ORGANIZATION> Pont </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nemours </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ; </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> under contract from the <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>. A <ORGANIZATION> Du </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pont </ORGANIZATION> inspector, G.C. <PERSON> Ridgely </PERSON>, wrote in a recently released August 1985 memorandum that 30 `` reactor incidents of the greatest significance'' occurred there. None, however, were as serious as the May 1986 disaster at Chernobyl in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, according to congresssional aides. One of the most serious mishaps at <LOCATION> Savannah </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> was the melting in November 1970 of a rod used to start an atomic chain reaction, causing radioactive contamination of an adjacent room. It took 900 people three months to clean up the contamination, according to the memo. `` Serious radiation exposure could have occurred because no outside alarm existed'' and an `` alarm was ignored for two hours,'' the memo said. Last Friday, <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> officials said the department had not been informed of the incidents, but on Monday senior department spokesman <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Anson </PERSON> <PERSON> Franklin </PERSON> said those statements were incorrect and that the incidents had been reported to the department's regional office in <LOCATION> Aiken </LOCATION> He said the information apparently had not been relayed to headquarters in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> from the regional office. The reactors at <LOCATION> Savannah </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> were closed down after the most recent incident, in August, and had been scheduled to reopen Tuesday. But <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> officials assured members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> last week that production would not resume until safety was assured, possibly after 30 days to 45 days. `` If they restart those things without having briefed us and without having convinced us they have solved the safety and health issues, they will be in serious trouble in the <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>,'' said Rep. <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Synar </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Okla </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Synar </PERSON>, chairman of the Energy, Environment and Natural Resources subcommittee of the Government Affairs Committee, held hearings on the <LOCATION> Savannah </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> facility last Friday He reacted angrily Tuesday to assertions that national security considerations ever justified keeping mishaps secret at <LOCATION> Savannah </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION>. `` Just because they claim it is national security does n't make it national security,'' he said. `` I did n't know that the health and safety of the workers and the surrounding citizens was a national security issue.'' <PERSON> Synar </PERSON> agreed that the department had an institutional problem, but challenged assertions that <PERSON> Herrington </PERSON> had changed the situation. `` They have set up a system that rewards managers in the field for keeping the lid on bad news,'' <PERSON> Synar </PERSON> said. `` I think that there are good people at the <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> that want to make safety a priority,'' he said. `` That attitude starts at the top. And I have n't seen it. It is very clear that headquarters has not been supportive of that. There has not been a system set up that made the operational or field offices accountable.'' The most blistering charge last week came from <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Starostecki </PERSON>, deputy assistant secretary for safety, health and quality assurance, in a memorandum discussing the most recent incident, a small power pulse in August. `` The issue was not whether the reactor was out of control; this time it was not,'' <PERSON> Starostecki </PERSON> said in the memo, which was released at a congressional hearing. `` The more serious issue deals with an institutional problem and attitudes toward safety,'' <PERSON> Starostecki </PERSON> said. `` There are currently some managers within the department with an attitude toward production reactor safety, which on the face seems to be similar to that which existed in the space program prior to the Challenger accident,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881005-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-05-88 0055EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-USPopulation     10-05 0325</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-US Population,310</SECOND>
<HEAD>Immigration, Natural Growth Propel Population Past 245 Million</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RANDOLPH E. SCHMID</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> now has more than 245 million residents thanks to strong immigration and an increase in the natural growth of the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> population, the <ORGANIZATION> Census </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> says. As of Jan. 1 the national population was 245,110,000, the bureau said, up from 242,825,000 a year earlier. The largest part of the increase was from natural growth _ 1.7 million people. That resulted from 3.8 million births minus 2.1 million deaths. In addition there were an estimated 600,000 immigrant arrivals, the bureau said. At 0.9 percent for the year, the overall increase is consistent with long-term trends, the agency reported. The nation's population has been growing at about 1 percent annually since about 1960. Births last year averaged 15.6 per 1,000 people, up from 15.4 in 1986 but below the 15.7 rate of 1985. While this is well above the all-time low of 14.5 recorded in 1976, there has been no consistent trend in recent years. Population experts note that the giant post World War II Baby Boom generation currently has produced many women in their prime childbearing ages, thus producing more potential mothers to raise the birth rate. Even so, the birth rate is nowhere near the high rate set in the wake of the World War II, when births climbed to a record 26.5 per 1,000 in 1947. Deaths occurred at a rate of 8.7 per 1,000 people, and have been fluctuating in the 8.5 to 8.7 range since 1977 after declining from 9.4 in 1972. There were 2.5 net immigrants per 1,000 people, including an allowance for illegal arrivals, the bureau said. That's down from 2.7 in 1986 and well below the 3.7 mark of 1980, highest since World War II. The overall growth rate was 0.7 percent last year for whites and 1.5 percent for blacks, both down substantially since 1960.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881005-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-05-88 0056EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Scotus-Jurors     10-05 0396</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Scotus-Jurors,390</SECOND>
<HEAD>Court Considers Whether All-White Jury Was Unfair to Black
Defendant</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID FOX</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> is deciding whether excluding prospective jurors because of race violates a criminal defendant's right to a jury representing a cross-section of the community. The high court ruled in 1986 that racially motivated disqualifications violate equal-protection provisions of the law. However, <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> attorney <PERSON> Patricia </PERSON> <PERSON> Unsinn </PERSON> asked the justices Tuesday to expand on that decision by ordering a new trial for <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Teague </PERSON>, a black man convicted of armed robbery and attempted murder. An all-white jury found <PERSON> Teague </PERSON> guilty in August 1978 after a <LOCATION> Cook </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> prosecutor used all of his peremptory challenges _ the disqualification of potential jurors without stating a reason _ to exclude 10 blacks from the jury. The <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> ruled on April 30, 1986, in a case called <PERSON> Batson </PERSON> vs. <ORGANIZATION> Kentucky </ORGANIZATION>, that a defendant's right to equal protection would be violated if prosecutors disqualified potential jurors based on their race. It later held that the ruling does not apply to convicted criminals who had exhausted direct appeals in state courts prior to the announcement of the <PERSON> Batson </PERSON> decision. While the <PERSON> Batson </PERSON> ruling came too late to help <PERSON> Teague </PERSON>, his attorney argued that the exclusion of blacks also violated her client's Sixth Amendment right to a jury representing a cross-section of the community. `` Because the prosecutor took affirmative action to destroy the representative makeup of that jury, we did not get the protection that the Sixth Amendment guarantees,'' <PERSON> Unsinn </PERSON> said. Assistant Illinois Attorney General <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bindi </PERSON> argued that it is impossible to ensure a representative cross-section of the community for every trial and said the fact that <PERSON> Teague </PERSON>'s jury was all white did not necessarily deny him a fair trial. `` Cross-sectionalism is not the litmus test of impartiality,'' <PERSON> Bindi </PERSON> said. `` To equate jury impartiality with some form of mix on the jury ... is to take a dangerous step toward saying that juries be filled by quotas.'' The 7th U.S. <ORGANIZATION> Circuit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appeals </ORGANIZATION> ruled in May 1987 that past <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> decisions make clear the fair cross-section requirement of the Sixth Amendment does not apply to the jury itself, but only to the pool of potential jurors from which the jury is chosen. The <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> is expected to rule on the case sometime next year.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881005-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-05-88 0056EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lites     10-05 0423</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lites,0440</SECOND>
<HEAD>On The Light Side</HEAD>
<DATELINE>GEORGETOWN, Colo. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 When <PERSON> Kenny </PERSON> <PERSON> Walters </PERSON> used 3,000 $ 1 bills to pay the county taxes on his tool-rental business, he thought his feelings were clear and the matter was closed. But Clear Creek County Treasurer <PERSON> Geraldine </PERSON> <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON> may have upstaged <PERSON> Walters </PERSON>. She returned his change of $ 110 mostly in nickels, dimes and pennies. `` I guess he was just trying to make a statement,'' said <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON>. `` I just gave him all the change I could dish out. I mean, turnabout is fair play.'' <PERSON> Walters </PERSON> said he enjoyed <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON>'s response to his `` silent protest.'' He said he was trying to make a point when he paid his $ 2,890 in taxes in person with an old gunpowder crate full of $ 1 bills. `` I do n't mind paying my property taxes,'' said <PERSON> Walters </PERSON>. `` But sometimes they -LRB- county officials -RRB- have a tendency not to realize how much money they're taking from people. `` I only get to see $ 3,000 twice a year _ once when I borrow it to pay my income taxes and once when I borrow to pay my property taxes.'' <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON> said she has known <PERSON> Walters </PERSON> for about seven years and realized he has an `` ornery'' sense of humor. She said it could have been worse: `` He could have undone the bundles and just thrown them at me.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>GREENVILLE, Ind. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 At first, teacher <PERSON> Shirley </PERSON> <PERSON> Cooley </PERSON> was n't sure what her third grade students at <ORGANIZATION> Greenville </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Elementary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> could learn from a truckload of pumpkins But her experiment turned out to be a lesson in entrepreneurship for the youngsters. Ms. <PERSON> Cooley </PERSON> lent her class $ 100 to start their own business, called the Pumpkin Patch. She then persuaded her brother-in-law, orchard owner <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Huber </PERSON>, to give the class more than 300 pumpkins. Ms. <PERSON> Cooley </PERSON>'s loan covered the cost of paint and brushes, which the children use to draw goblin faces on the pumpkins. The youngsters then sold their handiwork back to <PERSON> Huber </PERSON> at $ 1.50 each. He, in turn, sells them to the public. The students already have made enough to pay off their loan. Ms. <PERSON> Cooley </PERSON> expects the class to turn a profit of about $ 500, which will be used to pay for several field trips. Extra money will be given to the school to purchase playground equipment, she said. `` At the beginning of the year, many of these kids had a difficult time calculating the value of money and being able to make the right change, but this project has really gotten through to them,'' Ms. <PERSON> Cooley </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881005-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-05-88 0058EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Scotus-NCAA     10-05 0488</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Scotus-NCAA,490</SECOND>
<HEAD>Supreme Court Studies NCAA's Disciplinary Practices</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Prenoon EDT top planned.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By RICHARD CARELLI</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Basketball coach <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Tarkanian </PERSON>'s long feud with the <ORGANIZATION> NCAA </ORGANIZATION> is being refereed by the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> in a case testing the collegiate organization's disciplinary authority. The court's decision could affect, among other things, the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Collegiate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Athletic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>'s investigations into alleged drug use by some athletes. The justices, who granted an <ORGANIZATION> NCAA </ORGANIZATION> appeal last February, were to hear arguments in the case today. A decision is expected by July. <PERSON> Tarkanian </PERSON>, head coach at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nevada </ORGANIZATION> at <LOCATION> Las </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vegas </LOCATION> since 1973, is trying to preserve the victory he won in lower courts and avoid a two-year suspension for alleged <ORGANIZATION> NCAA </ORGANIZATION> violations. Following a 30-month investigation, <ORGANIZATION> NCAA </ORGANIZATION> officials said <PERSON> Tarkanian </PERSON> arranged for a student to get a `` B'' grade without attending class, provided free air fare to a student-athlete, encouraged individuals to give the <ORGANIZATION> NCAA </ORGANIZATION> false information to impede its probe, falsely certified <ORGANIZATION> UNLV </ORGANIZATION>'s program as complying with <ORGANIZATION> NCAA </ORGANIZATION> rules and failed to comport with high ethical standards. The <ORGANIZATION> Nevada </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> ruled that <PERSON> Tarkanian </PERSON> was denied due-process during the <ORGANIZATION> NCAA </ORGANIZATION> investigation that led to his suspension. But to reach that conclusion, the state court had to find that the <ORGANIZATION> NCAA </ORGANIZATION>, a private organization, acted with governmental power. The justices' handling of that larger issue will affect coaches and athletes at state-run <ORGANIZATION> NCAA </ORGANIZATION> member schools across the nation. Individuals and private organizations generally can not violate someone's constitutional rights. Only a government and its agents can do that because the Constitution protects against governmental _ not private _ wrongdoing. Courts call the concept the `` doctrine of state action.'' The <ORGANIZATION> NCAA </ORGANIZATION> is a private organization representing nearly 1,000 colleges and universities. But in the <PERSON> Tarkanian </PERSON> case, the state court said the <ORGANIZATION> NCAA </ORGANIZATION> was acting as a surrogate for <ORGANIZATION> UNLV </ORGANIZATION>, a state university. `` The right to discipline public employees is traditionally the exclusive prerogative of the state,'' the <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION> court said. `` <ORGANIZATION> UNLV </ORGANIZATION> can not escape responsibility for disciplinary action against employees by delegating that duty to a private entity.'' Because the <ORGANIZATION> NCAA </ORGANIZATION> investigators were acting as agents of a state school, the state court ruled, <PERSON> Tarkanian </PERSON> was entitled to more due process _ more opportunities to be heard and more information about the investigation. The <ORGANIZATION> NCAA </ORGANIZATION>, insisting its investigation was not `` state action,'' sought help from the nation's highest court. If the justices agree with the <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION> court, the <ORGANIZATION> NCAA </ORGANIZATION> will find itself in a curious position. It will have to afford more due-process rights to coaches and athletes at state-run schools than those who work for or attend private schools. The <ORGANIZATION> UNLV </ORGANIZATION> program was placed on two years' probation in 1977 for recruiting violations, and the <ORGANIZATION> NCAA </ORGANIZATION> that same year ordered the school to suspend <PERSON> Tarkanian </PERSON>. His court fight staved off the suspension, and won him the right to have the <ORGANIZATION> NCAA </ORGANIZATION> pay some of his legal fees.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881005-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-05-88 0100EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Scotus-Set-Aside     10-05 0632</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Scotus-Set-Aside,630</SECOND>
<HEAD>Court Hears Case On Minority Role In Public Works Projects</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Top planned after conclusion of arguments, scheduled for noon
EDT</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By JAMES H. RUBIN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The power of states and local governments to require minority participation in public works projects is being explored by the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> in a key affirmative action dispute. The justices were to hear arguments today over a <LOCATION> Richmond </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, program that set aside 30 percent of the value of all municipal building projects for minority participation. The court is expected to decide by July whether the plan should be reinstated. The plan was challenged successfully in a lower court by J.A. <ORGANIZATION> Croson </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, a building contractor. At stake could be similar set-aside plans established by most states and some 190 local governments. The case also is attracting widespread attention because of what it might foretell about the court's future approach to other forms of affirmative action and alleged reverse discrimination. Justice <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> is participating in his first case involving preferential treatment for minorities since joining the court last February. He replaced Justice <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Powell </PERSON>, who often cast the deciding vote on affirmative action issues in the closely divided court. Set-aside programs also have caused some deep divisions and seemingly contradictory views within the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration. President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, for example, said in 1984 he favored channeling billions of additional contract dollars to minority-owned firms. And the administration generally has looked upon public works set-asides more sympathetically than other affirmative action quotas it sternly opposes. But the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, responding to an invitation from the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> in a case similar to the <LOCATION> Richmond </LOCATION> dispute, challenged the constitutionality of set-asides. The <LOCATION> Richmond </LOCATION> plan was declared unlawful in September 1987 by the 4th <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Circuit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appeals </ORGANIZATION>. The appeals court said there is insufficient evidence that <LOCATION> Richmond </LOCATION> city officials discriminated against minority-owned businesses in the past. Also, the appeals court said the city's 30 percent quota appeared to be a completely arbitrary figure that `` simply emerged from the mists.'' <LOCATION> Richmond </LOCATION> adopted the plan in 1983 to require that a prime contractor on any city building project subcontract at least 30 percent of the value of the project to firms that are at least one-half minority owned. The minorities named in the plan are blacks, Hispanics, Orientals, Indians, Eskimos and Aleuts. The 4th Circuit court, in invalidating the program, relied heavily on a 1986 <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> ruling that struck down an affirmative action plan in <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION> designed to protect from lay-offs the jobs of minority teachers with less seniority than whites. The justices in that case said preferential treatment of minorities must be narrowly tailored to avoid hurting whites. The justices also restricted the power of employers to adopt affirmative action programs when there has not been proof the employers practiced past discrimination. But civil rights groups point to a 1980 <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> ruling that allows <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to earmark 10 percent of federal public works contracts for minority-controlled businesses. The court also has upheld other forms of affirmative action programs in a string of recent decisions. Minorities make up about half of <LOCATION> Richmond </LOCATION>'s population, and minority-owned businesses received less than 1 percent of the value of city contracts prior to adoption of the set-aside. The plan was challenged by J.A. <ORGANIZATION> Croson </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> after its bid _ the only one submitted to install stainless steel urinals and water closets at the city jail was rejected. City officials refused to award the contract even though <PERSON> Croson </PERSON> said there was only one minority contractor that could help on that project and <PERSON> Croson </PERSON> considered that company unqualified. <PERSON> Croson </PERSON> also said the cost of the project would rise by $ 7,663 if the minority contractor took part. The city then called for new bids.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881005-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-05-88 0102EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-InfantFormula     10-05 0620</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Infant Formula,610</SECOND>
<HEAD>Food Companies Deny Breaking International Guidelines On Baby
Formula</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JERRY ESTILL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Two of the world's largest food distribution companies have denied charges they failed to follow international guildelines for marketing infant formula in Third World countries. Both the Swiss-based <ORGANIZATION> Nestle </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> SA </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Home </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Products </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> responded quickly Tuesday when Action for Corporate Accountability announced it was renewing a boycott against <ORGANIZATION> Nestle </ORGANIZATION> products and extending it to <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Home </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Products </ORGANIZATION>. Leaders of the Minnesota-based group engineered a seven-year boycott against <ORGANIZATION> Nestle </ORGANIZATION> that ended in 1984 when the company agreed to an infant formula marketing code worked out with the <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> UNICEF </ORGANIZATION>, an arm of the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Boycott </PERSON> leaders said they were renewing their call for the marketplace action because <ORGANIZATION> Nestle </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Home </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Products </ORGANIZATION> were not abiding by the agreement. `` <ORGANIZATION> Nestle </ORGANIZATION> has worked diligently to ensure its marketing policies follow WHO recommendations,'' company spokesman <PERSON> Thad </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> said in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. He said the guidelines allow companies to provide free or reduced-price formula to hospitals in Third World nations for babies who `` have to be fed breast-milk substitutes.'' <PERSON> Carol </PERSON> <PERSON> Emerling </PERSON>, a spokewoman for <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Home </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Products </ORGANIZATION>, said, `` This whole activity is based on allegations that we violate the WHO code _ and we flat out deny it. `` The real issue is infant health,'' she said. `` Breast-feeding is best for infants; we've always said that. But every infant who is not receiving breast milk has the right to the best alternative available. That alternative is a scientifically formulated infant formula that is as close to breast milk as man can make it. And that is what our infant formula products are.'' <PERSON> Boycott </PERSON> leader <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>, chairman of <ORGANIZATION> Action </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corporate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Accountability </ORGANIZATION>, contended at a news conference that <ORGANIZATION> Nestle </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Home </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Products </ORGANIZATION> and _ to a lesser degree _ other formula distributors are interpreting the guidelines in a way that allows them to skirt the intent and encourage mothers who could breast feed their babies to use formula instead. Although <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> does not have a blanket objection to using infant formula, he maintains it is wrong for manufacturers to encourage its use in powdered form in Third World countries where most mothers typically do n't have the money, education and sanitary facilities to mix it properly. The result, he argues, is that thousands of Third World babies develop often fatal diseases because they drink from bottles with understrength formula that either does not give them the nutrients they need or infects them with various germs, or both. The fundamental issue is whether formula distributors effectively get babies and their mothers hooked on formula within days of birth by making their product available for free distribution at hospitals and other birthing facilities. `` In the hands of the poor, the feeding-bottle often becomes a passport to death for the young child,'' said Dr. <PERSON> R.K. </PERSON> <PERSON> Anand </PERSON>, a pediatrician from <LOCATION> Bombay </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>, present at the news conference. The physician said his practice has convinced him of three things: `` Bottle feeding continues to kill a large number of babies in <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> and other developing countries. Even poor mothers can produce enough breastmilk for their babies for at least the first four months of life. Restraint on the aggressive marketing of infant formula is essential. `` Otherwise,'' said <PERSON> Anand </PERSON>, `` more and more babies will be displaced from their mother's breast by big business.'' <PERSON> Janice </PERSON> <PERSON> Mantell </PERSON>, executive director of <ORGANIZATION> Action </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corporate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Accountability </ORGANIZATION>, estimated that about $ 6 billion in infant formula is sold worldwide each year, half of it in developing countries. She estimated <ORGANIZATION> Nestle </ORGANIZATION> has 40 percent to 50 percent of the market in the Third World and <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Home </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Products </ORGANIZATION> about 20 percent.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881005-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-05-88 0103EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-CleanAir Bjt   10-05 0795</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Clean Air, Bjt,760</SECOND>
<HEAD>Congress Fails Again To Update Clean Air Law</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID GOELLER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
