<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880707-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-07-88 2344EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-RoofCollapses 9thLd-Writethru a0836 07-07 0820</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Roof Collapses, 9th Ld - Writethru, a0836,0835</SECOND>
<HEAD>Roof Collapses at Department Store</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Leads with 4 grafs to UPDATE with 8 confirmed dead, later
figure on injured, digging under portable lights, quote about
hearing voices. Picks up 4th graf pvs `Rescuers cut.' SUBS 11th
graf `Police Lt.' with 4 grafs to add details, quote from rescuer.
Picks up 12th graf pvs `Poos said.'</NOTE>
<HEAD>LaserGraphic NY61, LaserPhotos BRO1,2, Others Upcoming</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOEL WILLIAMS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BROWNSVILLE, Texas (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A three-story department store crowded with people seeking shelter from torrential rains collapsed Thursday, killing at least eight people, injuring more than 40 and trapping others in the rubble, authorities said. `` It looks real bad,'' <LOCATION> Cameron </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> Sheriff <PERSON> Alex </PERSON> <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> said of the scene in the downtown area of this city across the <LOCATION> Rio </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Grande </LOCATION> from <LOCATION> Matamoros </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>. `` It's a disaster. It was just like a bomb hit that corner store there.'' The roof and front wall of <LOCATION> La </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Tienda </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Amigo </LOCATION>, known as the <ORGANIZATION> Amigo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Store </ORGANIZATION>, caved in at about 2:20 p.m. CDT. Emergency crews using portable lights continued into the night digging through mounds of broken cinderblocks, glass, twisted steel and merchandise to pull out survivors and look for victims. `` They thought they heard some voices and that's where they're digging now,'' city spokeswoman <PERSON> Pam </PERSON> <PERSON> Downing </PERSON> said about 10 p.m. Rescuers cut through a wall inside a <ORGANIZATION> Woolworth </ORGANIZATION>'s store next door to reach some of those trapped Witnesses said they heard screams from the wreckage. Linens and clothing blown from the store by high winds were being used to wrap the wounds of the injured. Police Sgt. Dean <PERSON> Poos </PERSON> said shortly after 7 p.m. that `` we do n't really think there are going to be any more live people coming out of there. Ambulances and rescue personnel were hampered in reaching the scene by floodwaters from the downpour. <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzgibbons </PERSON>, acting assistant city manager, said some local businesses had volunteered front-end loaders and cranes to help. The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Weather </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> said the collapse could have been caused by the weight of the rainwater, which dumped more than 2 inches in less than 30 minutes. The store was half a block from the international bridge, and sheriff's Lt. <PERSON> Johnny </PERSON> <PERSON> Castillo </PERSON> said that when the storm began, a large number of Mexican nationals `` were running there to get out of the rain. The store was packed.'' <PERSON> Poos </PERSON> said store owner <PERSON> Bernard </PERSON> <PERSON> Levine </PERSON> told him that when the roof collapsed, `` he jumped under a table, and all he knows is that when everything settled, he looked up and there was blue sky above him.'' <PERSON> Levine </PERSON> said he escaped with three employees and three customers. <PERSON> Poos </PERSON> said six bodies had been removed from the rubble and identified, and <PERSON> Johnny </PERSON> <PERSON> Economedes </PERSON>, head of one rescue team, said workers had found two more bodies. `` They've got two steel beams across them and about 20 or 30 tons of concrete'' on them, <PERSON> Economedes </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Poos </PERSON> said eight people were admitted to hospitals and another 34 were treated at three hospitals in <LOCATION> Brownsville </LOCATION> and nearby <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Benito </LOCATION>. Authorities said they could only guess at the number of people who might have been trapped inside. <PERSON> Poos </PERSON> estimated it would be no more than 50 and <PERSON> Castillo </PERSON> speculated it could be as many as 125. <PERSON> Poos </PERSON> said the dead included a woman who was apparently crushed as she sat in a car with Mexican license plates in front of the building. Two others were killed as they stood under a canopy in front of the store. `` All of a sudden, I hear a noise kind of like a boom and I was looking directly at the store and I see this tan-colored, sandy-colored wall that filled the whole front of the store,'' said <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON> <PERSON> Padilla </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Brownsville </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Herald </ORGANIZATION> photographer who was shooting weather photos in front of the store when the roof collapsed. `` It was coming forward, then the windows, the entire storefront, the windows just exploded out,'' he said. `` Glass just went out. People just went like this, covered their heads, kind of ducked down, and in the next instant, the whole thing just came down. `` The people I had been looking at were just covered with rubble,'' he said, adding one woman's hand was pinned to a parking meter after a steel I-beam collapsed and left her surrounded with cinder blocks. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Border Patrol officials and other law enforcement agencies, including Mexican authorities, assisted in the rescue operation. An emergency treatment center was set up at a civic center about two blocks away and authorities blocked off the area. A meteorologist with the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Weather </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Antonio </LOCATION> who asked not to be identified said that in the kind of storm that hit the area, `` the drops are very large and very heavy, and the fact that the storm system was n't moving very fast _ only about 10 miles an hour _ can cause heavy flooding.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880707-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-07-88 2356EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-DroughtRdp 2ndLd-Writethru a0776 07-07 1343</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Drought Rdp, 2nd Ld - Writethru, a0776,1370</SECOND>
<HEAD>Water Restrictions Tighten, Mississippi Still Blocked</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Subs 6 grafs for 3rd graf, ``Rain fell ...'' to UPDATE with
possibility of diverting water to Mississippi River, Perpich's
comments after returning from Washington, and crop analyst's
comments. Picks up 4th graf pvs, ``Temperatures hit ...'' INSERTS 2
grafs after 6th graf pvs `The temperature ...'' for details on
circus train. Picks up 7th graf pvs, ``Salt concentrations ...''
INSERTS one graf after 10th graf `Cooper, deputy' to explain impact
on plants. SUBS 19th graf pvs, ``Leonard made ...'' to conform.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By ROGER PETTERSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 A federal official warned Thursday that two more months of drought could close plants along three rivers in <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION>, as temperature records continued to fall, and circus elephants were taken to a river to cool off in 101-degree <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION>. One official in drought-stricken <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> warned Thursday of likely statewide water restrictions. Low water again kept barges from moving on the lower <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> and part of the <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> was closed. An official of the <ORGANIZATION> Minnesota </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Natural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Resources </ORGANIZATION> said the river dipped closer Wednesday to a level that would trigger a recommendation to divert water from lakes in northern <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Rudy </PERSON> <PERSON> Perpich </PERSON>, upon returning from <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> Thursday night, said he persuaded <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Agriculture Secretary <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Lyng </PERSON> to allow farmers to donate their hay on Conservation Reserve Program land without forfeiting any of their payment's under it `` This is a very critical time for livestock and dairy farmers. These people are on the verge of bankruptcy,'' <PERSON> Perpich </PERSON> said at the Minneapolis-St. Paul International Airport `` But it wo n't work unless we get the farmers to donate the hay and the private and commercial truckers to donate the transportation. I'll contribute my time and drive one of those trucks.'' Private crop analyst <PERSON> Conrad </PERSON> <PERSON> Leslie </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Leslie </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Analytical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> said corn yields from irrigated fields of <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION> and parts of <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> could be good, but some other fields in the <LOCATION> Midwest </LOCATION> already are `` beyond recovery.'' `` This is a disaster under development,'' said <PERSON> Leslie </PERSON>. `` We're in uncharted waters The great difficulty is that we do n't know what the moisture situation will be a year from now and whether we can make a recovery.'' Rain fell on some dry sections of <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION>, but <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> officials declared a statewide drought watch Thursday, triggering voluntary reductions in water use and a ban on open fires in state parks and forests. Temperatures hit record highs for the date Thursday in at least 28 cities from the <LOCATION> Great </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lakes </LOCATION> to the <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Coast </LOCATION>, including 102 at <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Wayne </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ind. </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Weather </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> said. <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION>'s high of 100 degrees toppled a record that had been on the books since 1874, when thermometers reached 97. In the normally cool mountains of <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Elkins </ORGANIZATION> hit a record 93, the ninth record temperature there since June 1. The temperature at <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION> hit a record 101 degrees and four elephants from the <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION> Temple Shrine Circus were taken to the <LOCATION> Allegheny </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> for a cooling wallow. Only one of the animals, natives of hot climates, got in and rolled around in the water. The drought also knocked the steam out of the annual railroad journey transporting vintage, restored circus wagons to <LOCATION> Milwaukee </LOCATION> for the city's Circus Parade. Officials said Thursday that the steam locomotive used to pull the train wo n't make the run this year because of the danger of setting track-side fires from sparks. Salt concentrations in <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> water climbed higher Thursday at drinking water intakes of the nearest downriver suburb of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION>, and officials of <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bernard </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Parish </LOCATION> began reserving barges to float in fresh water. The river's reduced flow is not strong enough to push the dense salt water back into the <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>. Lower Plaquemines Parish is already bringing fresh water by barge to mix with the salty flow at its intakes 30 miles downriver from <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION>. The salt concentration there is already strong enough to taste. A continuation of the drought for two more months could threaten municipal water supplies and close plants along three major rivers in <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION>, Lt. Col. <PERSON> Garry </PERSON> <PERSON> Cooper </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corps </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Engineers </ORGANIZATION> said Thursday. <PERSON> Cooper </PERSON>, deputy district engineer for the Corps' Mobile District, addressed a drought management meeting of the <ORGANIZATION> Apalachicola-Chattahoochee-Flint </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Drought </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Management </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, made up of the <ORGANIZATION> Corps </ORGANIZATION>, the three states and other organizations. The committee announced that navigation on <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Apalachicola </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> would virtually end on July 13 because of low water. <PERSON> Cooper </PERSON> referred to both plants that use water to run turbines and generate electricity and those that use water for industrial purposes, such as rinsing textiles and cooling machinery. The lack of rain already has forced <ORGANIZATION> Alabama </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Power </ORGANIZATION> to shut down nearly all hydroelectric production and have coal-burning plants make up the difference. The <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> remained closed at <LOCATION> Black </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hills </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Miss. </LOCATION>, about 20 miles south of <LOCATION> Natchez </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Miss. </LOCATION>, where water had been as low as five feet. `` Hopefully by this weekend we will have the river open if somebody does n't mess up,'' L.C. Fumbanks, chief of navigation for the <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corps </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Engineers </ORGANIZATION>, said in a radio-telephone interview from aboard the dredge <PERSON> Jadwin </PERSON>. The <PERSON> Jadwin </PERSON> worked south of <LOCATION> Greenville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Miss. </LOCATION>, where traffic resumed Wednesday, while another dredge pumped sand from the blockage at <LOCATION> Black </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hills </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> decided Thursday to close the <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> at <LOCATION> Mound </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ill. </LOCATION>, for 12-hour shifts to clear a build-up of sand and silt from the channel, said <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> Lt. j.g. <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Clifton </PERSON>. He said the affected two-mile stretch would be opened for six hours Friday morning, closed for 12 hours, then reopened for six hours. `` It will just alternate back and forth like that until they get it cleared through,'' <PERSON> Clifton </PERSON> said, adding that he had no estimate how long that would take. Traffic on the <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> is normal, although barges are carrying lighter loads, thanks to reservoirs upstream, said <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnston </PERSON>, director of public affairs for the <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corps </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Engineers </ORGANIZATION> at <LOCATION> Omaha </LOCATION>, Neb. <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> Lt. Gov. <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Leonard </PERSON> said Thursday that voluntary water conservation measures are not working. `` Most of the cities we're checking with regularly indicate the program is not paying dividends,'' <PERSON> Leonard </PERSON> said in <LOCATION> Dayton </LOCATION>. `` My guess is that if the drought continues for another two weeks to 30 days, we're going to need -LRB- statewide -RRB- mandatory water restrictions.'' <PERSON> Leonard </PERSON> made his remarks before leaving for <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, where he, like <PERSON> Perpich </PERSON> and officials from seven states met with <PERSON> Lyng </PERSON>. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Shank </PERSON>, director of <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION>, has asked the state's 2,500 largest water systems to aim for a a minimum 25 percent reduction in water use by all customers, and some cities have already banned lawn sprinkling. <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Natural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Resources </ORGANIZATION> fined <LOCATION> Gwinnett </LOCATION> and Cobb counties $ 75,000 each Wednesday for taking too much water in June and told them they must cut consumption, possibly including round-the-clock bans on outdoor water use. Up to 1.5 inches of rain fell on parts of west-central and northern <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION> late Wednesday and early Thursday, somewhat easing drought conditions, the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Weather </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> said today. `` Every little bit helps,'' said <LOCATION> Clay </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> extension agent <PERSON> Eddie </PERSON> <PERSON> Bernhardson </PERSON>. However, he added: `` the rain's been really limited in most areas of the county, and high temperatures are complicating'' the situation. Wheat, <LOCATION> Clay </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>'s biggest crop, `` is getting to the point where in some areas they'll get 8 to 10 bushels an acre maximum'' compared to a normal average of 40 to 50 bushels, he said. Approximately 545 bales of hay from <ORGANIZATION> Elon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> N.C. </LOCATION>, arrived Thursday at <LOCATION> Shelbyville </LOCATION>, Ky. It was a `` gesture of thanks'' for the 2,300 tons of hay <LOCATION> Kentucky </LOCATION> farmers sent by train to <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> two years ago, said <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> Nesbitt </PERSON>, a spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> Kentucky </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION>. `` I gave about 50 bales two years ago. Now it's my turn to receive,'' said O.L. <PERSON> Jeffries </PERSON>, who farms near <LOCATION> Shelbyville </LOCATION>. `` I do n't know which way to turn. It's pitiful.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880707-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-07-88 2359EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-OilRig 3rdLd-Writethru a0773 07-07 0995</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Oil Rig, 3rd Ld-Writethru, a0773,1018</SECOND>
<HEAD>166 Feared Dead in World's Worst Oil-Rig Disaster</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDS: LEADS with 17 grafs to UPDATE with one more body recovered;
joint police and Occidental statement giving latest figures as 17
dead, 149 missing and feared dead, 64 survivors, totaling 230
involved in incident; edits to conform and delete outdated
material. PICKS up 17th graf pvs bgng, Six NATO warships...</NOTE>
<HEAD>LaserPhotos LON8,11,18,19, AB12</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BEN DOBBIN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ABERDEEN, Scotland (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Rescuers on Thursday night found two more survivors of an explosion and towering fire that consumed the <ORGANIZATION> Piper </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Alpha </ORGANIZATION> platform and killed up to 166 people in the world's worst oil rig disaster The search was suspended for the night, to resume at daylight Friday. But authorities said there was little hope of finding anyone else alive in the <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sea </LOCATION>'s frigid waters. The <LOCATION> Piper </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Alpha </LOCATION> oil rig, 120 miles off <LOCATION> Scotland </LOCATION>, is owned by <ORGANIZATION> Occidental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Petroleum </ORGANIZATION>. A joint statement issued by <ORGANIZATION> Occidental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Petroleum </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Mathys </PERSON> in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> and police in <LOCATION> Aberdeen </LOCATION> at 4:15 a.m. Friday -LRB- 11:15 p.m. EDT Thursday -RRB- said: `` In all, 230 personnel were involved in the incident. This was made up of 227 on Occidental facilities and three in a small rescue boat. Seventeen bodies have been recovered. Total survivors to date are 64, and 149 are unaccounted for.'' Those numbers tooks into account body recovered early Friday. <PERSON> Mathys </PERSON> said initial confusion as to the number of survivors resulted in earlier discrepancies in the figures. Asked whether rescuers had given up hope of finding more survivors, <ORGANIZATION> British </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> minister <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Morrison </PERSON> said: `` To be honest, yes. At this stage there is very little hope indeed.'' The rig owners said the probable cause of the conflagration was a gas leak, which a survivor said was `` screaming like a banshee'' seconds before the blast Wednesday night. Survivors told of having to choose between trying to survive the flames in hopes aid would come and plunging 150 feet into a blanket of burning oil that covered water cold enough to kill. `` It was a case of fry and die or jump and try,'' said <PERSON> Roy </PERSON> <PERSON> Carey </PERSON>, 45, who jumped. Rescue pilots described flames up to 400 feet high. The fire still flickered nearly 24 hours later. Prime Minister <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON>'s government promised `` a very, very deep and far-reaching inquiry.'' Questions arose about safety stadards in the high-risk industry, and opposition politicians claimed safety was neglected. <ORGANIZATION> Occidental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Petroleum </ORGANIZATION> said it believed a gas leak was to blame, but days or weeks would be needed to determine what caused and ignited it. <ORGANIZATION> Occidental </ORGANIZATION> said the three-quarters of the 649-foot-high rig was destroyed. <PERSON> Derek </PERSON> <PERSON> Ellington </PERSON>, a 45-year-old rigger, said he was in a workshop near the control center when he heard the scream of `` two gas leaks almost simultaneously, and about 30 seconds later there was the first explosion. It wiped out the control room and that was it. Our nerve center was gone.'' <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> <PERSON> Sneddon </PERSON>, a university lecturer on offshore engineering in <LOCATION> Aberdeen </LOCATION>, said: `` We can only assume there was a leak of some sort. Basically, you are sitting on top of two highly flammable products _ oil and gas. A leak or a spill is a potential hazard. It is extremely difficult to say what could have set it off.'' The number of men still missing and the dim prospects for finding them alive seem certain to make the <ORGANIZATION> Piper </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Alpha </ORGANIZATION> explosion the worst oil rig disaster, surpassing the 123 deaths when the <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kielland </PERSON> platform capsized in <LOCATION> Norway </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sea </LOCATION> waters in March 1980. Police said the overwhelming majority of those on the <ORGANIZATION> Piper </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Alpha </ORGANIZATION> were Scottish, but the domestic <ORGANIZATION> British </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> news </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> agency </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> said workers from the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>, continental <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> also were aboard. Authorities said no list of dead would be released until families were notified. Six <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> warships, led by the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> destroyer Hayler, diverted from maneuvers to join a multinational flotilla of rescue vessels. Helicopters criss-crossed the smoke-filled skies. <PERSON> Armand </PERSON> <PERSON> Hammer </PERSON>, chairman of <ORGANIZATION> Occidental </ORGANIZATION>, said he would leave immediately for <ORGANIZATION> Aberdeen </ORGANIZATION> to oversee care the care of injured workers and families of the missing, said spokesman <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> Gillot </PERSON> at the company's <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> headquarters. Survivors were taken to <ORGANIZATION> Aberdeen </ORGANIZATION> Royal Infirmary and officials said 20 were hospitalized, most with burns. Distraught families clustered outside waiting for news of loved ones. <PERSON> Parkinson </PERSON> insisted safety standards were strict, including week-long government inspections annually. He said the <ORGANIZATION> Piper </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Alpha </ORGANIZATION> inspection took place two weeks ago. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Prescott </PERSON> of the opposition <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> claimed in <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION> that rig inspection and maintenance had been reduced in recent years, too little money was spent on training, and health and safety legislation did not apply fully to the <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sea </LOCATION> oil and gas industry. In reply, <PERSON> Parkinson </PERSON> said serious <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sea </LOCATION> accidents had fallen from 101 in 1986 to 59 last year. He added: `` That is too high a figure and we wish to keep the pressure on to ensure that improvement is maintained.'' <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Cryer </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> said an explosion on the <LOCATION> Piper </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Alpha </LOCATION> four years ago slightly injured four men, and claimed the investigators' report was kept secret Parkinson's department said the report was not published because investigators found no negligence and did not recommend prosecutions. The disaster Wednesday night began at about 9.30 p.m., just after a 12-hour shift had ended, and many of the men were in bed. `` I was just going to bed and there was a bang,'' said <PERSON> Dave </PERSON> <PERSON> Lambert </PERSON>, 38. `` They came in and said there was a fire and to get out. The sprinklers were on. We could see them, but there was n't sufficient volume to put down the fire. Rigger <PERSON> Tony </PERSON> <PERSON> Sinnett </PERSON>, watching from a supply vessel, told the <ORGANIZATION> Aberdeen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Evening </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Express </ORGANIZATION>: `` It was like the platform had been hit by an atomic bomb. There was massive mushrooms and flames shooting into the air. I just thanked God I was n't on board.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880707-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-07-88 0002EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--Germany-Juice     07-07 0117</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Germany-Juice,0120</SECOND>
<HEAD>West Germans Are World's Biggest Fruit Juice Consumers</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BONN, West Germany (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 West Germans may be the world's greatest beer lovers, but now they're tops in fruit juice consumption, too According to the Bonn-based <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> German </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fruit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Juice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Industries </ORGANIZATION>, West Germans drank 33.5 quarts of fruit juice per capita in 1987. This represents an 11-percent increase over 1986 and is the highest worldwide. In second place in national juice consumption is neighboring <LOCATION> Switzerland </LOCATION>. In 1987, the average Swiss drank 29.6 quarts. Fruit juice drinking in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> was given as 27.6 quarts per capita. The West German fruit juice industry had around $ 1.65 billion in sales last year, the association reported.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880707-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-07-88 0003EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-MeeseSuccessor Bjt   07-07 0786</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Meese Successor, Bjt,770</SECOND>
<HEAD>Senators Lobbying on Meese Successor</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LARRY MARGASAK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Senators are weighing in with their favorite candidates for attorney general, while the man who's leaving the job predicts his successor will not be `` a clone of anybody else.'' President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> launched his search Wednesday for <PERSON> Edwin </PERSON> <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>'s replacement and one of his first steps in the process was to meet with the departing attorney general. A lightning rod of controversy because of his conservative policies and his personal legal problems, <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> announced Tuesday he would be gone in a few weeks. He declared himself vindicated by an 830-page report on his official conduct compiled by independent counsel <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> McKay </PERSON>, although he acknowledged he had not yet seen it. The report has not been released by a special federal court. While sources have said the report recommends against a criminal indictment, its conclusions on <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>'s ethical conduct remain unclear. While no names of possible successors were volunteered at the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, senators made sure that a steady list of possibilities kept drifting from <LOCATION> Capitol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION> to the White House. Some lawmakers made telephone calls to administration officials. Others allowed their message to be carried by news reporters. All agreed that the window for confirmation would be short. Majority Democrats control the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> schedule. Recesses already are scheduled during the two national political conventions in July and August, and <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> might adjourn early during the presidential campaign. Two members of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Judiciary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, ranking Republican <PERSON> Strom </PERSON> <PERSON> Thurmond </PERSON> and <PERSON> Democrat </PERSON> <PERSON> Dennis </PERSON> <PERSON> DeConcini </PERSON>, suggested former Republican Sen. <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Laxalt </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION> as <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>'s successor. <PERSON> Laxalt </PERSON> was considered the president's closest <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> ally before retiring. <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Loranger </PERSON>, a spokesman for <PERSON> Laxalt </PERSON>, quoted the former senator as saying, `` There is absolutely no truth to the rumors about my going to the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>.''' <PERSON> Laxalt </PERSON>'s secretary at his <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> law office, <PERSON> Janene </PERSON> <PERSON> Assuras </PERSON>, said her boss was `` not interested'' in the job, but did n't know what he would do if <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> asked. <PERSON> DeConcini </PERSON>, of <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION>, also recommended former <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Republican leader <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Rhodes </PERSON> from his home state. <PERSON> Thurmond </PERSON>, of <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>, also had other suggestions: former Democratic Attorney General <PERSON> Griffin </PERSON> B. <PERSON> Bell </PERSON>, who served under <PERSON> Jimmy </PERSON> <PERSON> Carter </PERSON>; and <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s first attorney general, <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> French </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>. Responding to a reporter's question, <PERSON> Thurmond </PERSON> said former <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> `` would make an excellent attorney general.'' Her husband, <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Minority Leader <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>, R-Kan., suggested that former White House chief of staff <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> and <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> lawyer <PERSON> Judith </PERSON> <PERSON> Richards </PERSON> <PERSON> Hope </PERSON>, daughter-in-law of comedian <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Hope </PERSON>, would qualify <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> resigned as chief of staff, effective June 30, to return to private law practice in <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION>. Mrs. <PERSON> Hope </PERSON>'s nomination to succeed <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bork </PERSON> on the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appeals </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> the </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION> has not yet been acted upon by the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>. Sen. <PERSON> Orrin </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Hatch </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Utah </LOCATION> and a <ORGANIZATION> Judiciary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> member, favors acting Deputy Attorney General <PERSON> Harold </PERSON> <PERSON> Christensen </PERSON>, of <LOCATION> Salt </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. A newcomer to the department, <PERSON> Christensen </PERSON>'s confirmation hearing for the deputy's job is set for July 27. Conservative Republican Sen. <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Symms </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION> rcommended <PERSON> Eugene </PERSON> <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Boise </LOCATION>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bar </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> in 1986-87. `` He does n't have any scars and has an impeccable record,'' <PERSON> Symms </PERSON> said. Sen. <PERSON> Alfonse </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> D'Amato </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-N.Y. </LOCATION>, suggested a homestate judge, <PERSON> Sol </PERSON> <PERSON> Wachtler </PERSON>, chief judge of the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appeals </ORGANIZATION>. His term on the state court expires in January 1999. <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Patrick </PERSON> <PERSON> Korten </PERSON> said Wednesday that he believed <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> has `` weighed in'' on the question of his successor. Interviewed on <ORGANIZATION> Cable </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Network </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> was asked what kind of person he thought should succeed him. `` I do n't think anybody would be a clone of anybody else,'' he said. But <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> said he hoped the person selected is `` someone who subscribes to the principles of <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and his administration.'' White House spokesman <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> conceded that administration officials had no contingency plan to find a replacement, even though <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> indicated some time ago he might leave before the end of the administration. `` We had an attorney general up until yesterday,'' <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said. `` We do n't compile lists for positions where they're already filled.'' <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> had said earlier that <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> told <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> `` some time ago that he might want to leave before the end of the administration. The president left the timing up to him.'' <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> `` briefly discussed'' a successor for <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> with White House chief of staff <PERSON> Kenneth </PERSON> <PERSON> Duberstein </PERSON> and general counsel A.B. <PERSON> Culvahouse </PERSON>, the spokesman said. If a new attorney general has not been confirmed by the time <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> leaves, <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said, the administration probably would install Solicitor General Charles Fried in the job on an acting basis.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880707-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-07-88 0004EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Drought-Congress Bjt   07-07 0757</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Drought-Congress, Bjt,750</SECOND>
<HEAD>No Big Jump In Food Prices, Ag Official Says</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MIKE ROBINSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Increases in food prices should remain moderate this year despite the drought as the nation begins to draw on its large grain reserves, says the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>'s top economist. `` The immediate problem is not one of food shortage or food price inflation, except in certain specific instances, but rather the problem is one of responding in a compassionate way to the losses faced by American farmers,'' Assistant Secretary of Agriculture <PERSON> Ewen </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> said Wednesday. Appearing before three <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> subcommittees, <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> forecast tight supplies of soybeans and oats. He also acknowledged that while the winter wheat harvest is actually ahead of schedule, there has been severe damage to spring wheat and much of the corn crop is in bad shape. He said, however, that <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> soybeans will be available to meet <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> needs and added that reserves of wheat and feed grains are ample to ensure that Americans will not have to endure any calamitous food shortage. The testimony came as <LOCATION> Capitol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION> began to focus more intently on food prices, with lawmakers saying there was no immediate reason to warrant major increases. Rep. <PERSON> Byron </PERSON> <PERSON> Dorgan </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.D. </LOCATION>, called on the congressional <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Accounting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> to monitor food prices in the next six months. He expressed concern that food processors and others might engage in `` price gouging.'' `` It simply would n't wash with economic reality to cite the drought as a reason for a quick runup of food prices,'' he said in a statement. `` It would be inexcusable for any company to use the drought as a way to make a quick buck.'' <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> did say that prolonged drought would send wheat prices higher, guaranteeing `` some additional pressure on retail prices of bakery products and cereals'' but not a major increase. He said, however, that farm-level prices account for only 8 percent of the retail value of cereal and bakery products. `` If wheat prices for the entire season average 30 percent above last year, this alone would translate into a 2.4 percent rise in the retail price of bakery and cereal products,'' <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> said. He said any increases would be `` moderate'' in scale. <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> said that while no major shortages were in sight, there could be a squeeze in the supply of some crops. He also said grazing conditions on June 1 were rated 68 percent of ideal and that hay prices are up 22 percent from last year. But 65 percent of the winter wheat crop, which amounts to three-quarters of all <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> wheat production, already has been harvested and progress is `` well ahead of normal,'' <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> said. In contrast, `` the spring wheat crop is in bad shape with almost two-thirds of the crop rated in poor to very poor condition due to the drought,'' he said. Wheat reserves at the start of the year totaled 1.27 billion bushels, well above the average of the last decade, <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> said. He said that amount plus winter wheat already in the bins from the current harvest add up to a 10-month supply. That includes wheat for export, he said. The greatest production loss is in durum wheat, which is used for pasta, he said. The condition of hard red spring wheat also is generally poor, but stocks equal to 80 percent of annual use are available, he said. Turning to feed grains, he said, corn is generally in fair condition. In 10 of the 17 major producing states, 25 percent or more of the crop is rated poor or very poor, he said. In six of the 11 major sorghum-producing states, at least 25 percent of sorghum acreage is rated poor or very poor, he said. There are no weekly reports on the condition of oats and barley, <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> said. But he noted that more than half the nation's barley and one-third of its oats come from the Grain Belt where the drought is worst. Nonetheless, corn stocks on hand as of Sept. 1 are projected to equal 50 percent of annual use and sorghum stocks 90 percent of annual use. <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> said corn supply should be ample to prevent any serious shortage. `` Even with a very pessimistic scenario you end up with a carryover of a billion bushels,'' he said. <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> said the soybean crop is generally rated fair to poor. In 11 of the 19 major producing states, `` anywhere from one-fourth to more than one-half of the crop is rated poor or worse,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880707-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-07-88 0014EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Jackson     07-07 0450</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Jackson,450</SECOND>
<HEAD>Jackson Criticizes Bush Stance On Plane Downing</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By VICTORIA GRAHAM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>UNITED NATIONS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> is calling for a period of mourning for the victims of the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> missile attack on an Iranian jetliner, and urging the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> to pay reparations to the victims' families. He also criticized Vice President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> for statements the likely Republican nominee made this week in response to the deaths of 290 people in the downing of the Iranian commercial jet. `` I thought it was a bit in bad taste, if not downright vulgar, to be running around on July 4, getting applause lines, talking about the honor of the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>, as if it were in question, and not expressing the profound sense of humanity that the <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> people have and our sense of sharing the grief of the tragedy,'' <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> said at the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> expressed his deep regrets on Monday as he campaigned through the <LOCATION> Midwest </LOCATION>, saying, `` Obviously, as we celebrate our great national holiday our hearts go out to the loved ones and families of those who were lost and also -LRB- hearts -RRB- go out to those kids, those young Americans who are defending freedom halfway around the world.'' However, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> also said he could identify with the captain of the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> cruiser, who made the decision to fire because he believed his ship was in danger. And <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said he did not believe <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> policy in the region would change as a result of the incident. `` Life goes on,' the vice president said. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, who met with <PERSON> Arab </PERSON> leaders at the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION>, emphasized that the downing of the Iranian plane was `` an accident, an error ... No one assumes that the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> is without compassion, that it moved to engage in an act of war.'' `` We should say to <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> that we sincerely regret the accident occurred, that we offer reparations or compensation to the families of the victims, if they will accept them,'' said <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, repeating a call he made over the holiday weekend in the wake of the incident. At the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> met with envoys of the <ORGANIZATION> Arab </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> League </ORGANIZATION>, including <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Djibouti </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mauritania </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Sudan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Libya </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Somalia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Yemen </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Saudi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arabia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Oman </LOCATION>, Democratic <LOCATION> Yemen </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Algeria </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Morocco </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Qatar </LOCATION>. He repeated his plea for the release of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> hostages and all other captives in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> also said he favored a new international naval peacekeeping force in the gulf. `` I hope the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> will hav a much more prominent rule in the gulf in the future,'' <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> said. Earlier, when asked if he had any interest in becoming <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> ambassador to the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> replied, `` None whatsoever.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880707-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-07-88 0028EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Dukakis-Homefront     07-07 0802</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Dukakis-Homefront,800</SECOND>
<HEAD>Dukakis Faces Deficit and Confidence Problems at Home</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CHRISTOPHER B. DALY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BOSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Gov. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, who has been highly critical of the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> adminsitration's deficit spending in his Democratic presidential campaign, has a deficit problem of his own. Two weeks before his certain selection as the Democratic presidential nominee, the <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> governor faces a $ 450 million deficit on an $ 11 billion budget in the just-ended fiscal year and has yet to sign a budget for the new one. And according to a new poll, the <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> governor's favorability rating is declining _ although residents of his home state still heavily favor him over Republican <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> aides insist that the budget problems will be resolved in short order and that the governor's home-state popularity will rebound. But the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> campaign is already making the fiscal woes into a campaign issue. `` It could turn out to be the Achilles heel of the <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> presidential campaign,'' said state Sen. <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Cellucci </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> coordinator for the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> campaign. The state government's new fiscal year began last Friday, and <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> has yet to close a $ 450 million deficit for last year and still must shepherd a 1989 budget to his desk. Faced with an unexpected revenue shortfall, the governor is scaling back his spending plans and pushing for a package of narrowly targeted tax and fee increases. On Wednesday, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> was forced to ask the Legislature for $ 81 million in emergency spending authority to avoid having to renege on the state payroll and welfare checks. The House approved the measure. `` The putting together of budgets is not a pleasant process to watch _ never has been, never will be,'' said <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> DeVillars </PERSON>, the governor's deputy chief secretary. `` There is obviously a great deal more attention to the process this year, in part because of unanticipated events that have led to less revenue than expected and in part because the chief executive is running for national office.'' According to a telephone survey last week of 400 likely <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> voters, 56 percent said <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> has not been an effective governor while campaigning for president and 47 percent said he should resign now or immediately after the Democratic convention July 18-21. In addition, the governor's unfavorable rating has more than doubled _ to 36 percent _ since a similar poll in January 1987, before <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> declared his intention to run. His favorable rating dropped from 71 percent to 55 percent. Still, the survey said <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> was favored over <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, 51 percent to 37 percent. The poll was conducted for <ORGANIZATION> WBZ-TV </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Boston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Herald </ORGANIZATION> by <ORGANIZATION> KRC </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Communications </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> DeVillars </PERSON> said <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> has devoted well over 100 hours in recent weeks to the state's budget problems while at the same time focusing on the selection of a vice presidential running mate. But he has not dominated the budget process as he has in past years. Based on June tax collections, the government is technically about $ 450 million in deficit for fiscal 1988, according to legislative leaders. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> has offered a 20-point program to close that gap through bookkeeping changes and borrowing, but the state <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> has balked at several unpopular features. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> and his legislative allies argue that the deficit was the unforseeable result of a downturn in income tax receipts combined with $ 92 million in court-ordered corporate tax abatements. At the same time, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> has been forced to retreat from the $ 12 billion spending goal for fiscal 1989 that he announced in January, and he has agreed with top <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> lawmakers to reduce the spending target. A conference committee negotiated a compromise late Wednesday of $ 11.75 billion, which <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> is expected to sign next week. A principal sticking point has been nervousness about revenues for the coming year. After five years of double-digit revenue growth, tax collections fell nearly flat last year. Nevertheless, the administration projects a comeback in fiscal 1989 of 12 percent, a figure that many legislators question. In order to buttress revenues, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> has turned to taxes. He recently signed a $ 40 million tax on cigarettes, and more than $ 200 million in other new taxes are moving toward his desk. One would raise personal taxes on the wealthy by bringing the state code back into conformance with federal law, another would end a corporate loophole that allows multistate companies to write off their out-of-state losses, and a third would capture some $ 24 million a year in unclaimed bottle deposits that now stay in the hands of bottlers. <PERSON> Cellucci </PERSON> blames <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> for over-spending during his second term. `` You ca n't have budgets that rise at twice the rate of inflation and add 10,000 new state employees and not have a day of reckoning. This is the day of reckoning that they're trying to postpone until after November.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880707-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-07-88 0058EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Reagan'sPollster     07-07 0429</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Reagan's Pollster,430</SECOND>
<HEAD>Presidential Pollster Says Democrats Would Do Well To Pick Glenn
For Veep</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DONALD M. ROTHBERG</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Political Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s pollster says <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> Sen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON> is `` far and away'' the strongest choice for the Democratic vice presidential nomination. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Wirthlin </PERSON>, more accustomed to giving advice to Republicans than to Democrat <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, told reporters at a luncheon Wednesday that <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON> would help <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> `` play the patriotic theme'' in the general election campaign. He contended the question of the <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> vice presidential choice was less clear for Vice President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. Among the prospects he cited were Sen. <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> and his wife, former <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>, as well as Gov. <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> and former Gov. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Wirthlin </PERSON>, who has done polling for <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> for more than 20 years, worked for <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> during the <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> senator's unsuccessful bid for the 1988 GOP presidential nomination. He said he thought <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> would help <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> in the <LOCATION> Midwest </LOCATION> farm belt and among blue collar workers. But he conceded that <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>'s acerbic personality could be damaging if he went on the attack. <PERSON> Wirthlin </PERSON> also said he thought it would be a mistake to have President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> on the stump attacking <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>. `` People do not approve of an incumbent president attacking a candidate trying to succeed him,'' he said. In addition, he said, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> `` is not a good attack candidate.'' <PERSON> Wirthlin </PERSON> also said the resignation of Attorney General <PERSON> Edwin </PERSON> <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON> does n't erase the `` sleaze factor'' for <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> in the fall presidential campaign, but makes it easier for him to deal with it. During a luncheon session with reporters, <PERSON> Wirthlin </PERSON> said only about 3 percent of the voters he has surveyed cite ethics in government as the most important issue, a figure that is no higher than a year earlier. The issue that outstrips all others in importance in the minds of voters is drugs, said the pollster. `` There are now 21 percent who tag drugs as the single most important problem facing the nation,'' he said. No other issue was named by more than 10 percent of people interviewed. While <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> was under investigation by independent counsel <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> McKay </PERSON>, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was peppered with questions about whether he thought the attorney general should resign. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> aides at one point described <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> as a `` liability,'' a description the vice president disavowed. <PERSON> Wirthlin </PERSON> said the departure of <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> would put the ethics issue `` in a different context'' and would `` enable <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> to talk about ethics without implicitly criticizing <PERSON> Ed </PERSON> <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880707-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-07-88 0059EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-ConventionProtests Bjt   07-07 0583</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Convention Protests, Bjt,570</SECOND>
<HEAD>Demonstrators of All Stripes Get Soapbox Time At The Convention</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOSEPH B. FRAZIER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ATLANTA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 When the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Convention </ORGANIZATION> opens here this month, protesters from animal rights activists to AIDS victims will be on hand to try to grab a bit of the spotlight. But convention organizers, who carefully orchestrate many of the events inside the convention hall, are also seeking to bring order to what could otherwise be a chaotic crush of demonstrations. The city is supplying a stage across the street from the convention site that will serve as a soapbox for a variety of causes. Protesters are being offered two-hour time slots over five days to air their views. The city will provide a stage and sound equipment in the lot, which authorities estimate can hold about 30,000 people. The demonstrators will be within sight and earshot of the delegates as they arrive and depart during the gathering July 15-18. However, the plan is being challenged in federal court by a coalition of groups seeking expanded space for demonstrations. A decision was possible as early as today. Generally, potentially antagonistic groups have not been scheduled together, although a gay rights group follows a white supremacist organization onto the stage one afternoon. By Wednesday, 25 of the 40 slots were filled, four of them by one organization, the Committee for Fair Elections. At least four other groups with ties to that committee also have reserved time. The group is the vehicle for the independent presidential campaign of <PERSON> Leonora </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Fulani </PERSON>, who says she will bring 10,000 backers to the convention. She has qualified for the ballot in all 50 states and is eligible for federal matching funds. Demonstrations coinciding with those on the stage supplied by the city will be permitted in the parking lot, but their organizers can not use powerful sound equipment. Local organizations with demonstration time include a neighborhood group that opposes the construction of a domed stadium in the neighborhood near the convention site. The Nationalist Movement, a Mississippi-based white supremacy group, has been given a parade permit and a two-hour slot on Sunday afternoon in conjunction with its annual convention. Other groups given protest time in the parking lot include: _ The <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> on <LOCATION> Latin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, a liberal Washington-based foreign policy lobby. _ No Business As Usual, which opposes the Strategic Defense Initiative, known as Star Wars. _ Disabled In Action, a group advocating better access for the handicapped, which has ties to the <PERSON> Fulani </PERSON> campaign. _ <ORGANIZATION> U.S.-Congo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Friendship </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, which opposes the regime of President <PERSON> Mobuto </PERSON> Sese Seko of <LOCATION> Zaire </LOCATION>. _ Rep. <PERSON> Gus </PERSON> <PERSON> Savage </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> congressman from <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>. _ <ORGANIZATION> Castillo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cultural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Centers </ORGANIZATION>, a <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> City-based performing arts group specializing in working-class history and progressive politics. _ The <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Independent </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Club </ORGANIZATION>, a <LOCATION> Bronx </LOCATION>, N.Y.-based pro-Fulani organization. _ People With AIDS Coalition and March on AIDS. _ <ORGANIZATION> Arts </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pluribus </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Unum </ORGANIZATION>, an <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> artist and activist group specializing in liberal political performances. _ Compassion Campaign ` 88, an animal rights organization. _ LEGAL, a national gay rights organization. _ Greater <ORGANIZATION> Lowell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Campaign </ORGANIZATION>, a Massachusetts-based group specializing in hazardous waste issues. _ <ORGANIZATION> Illinois </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Solidarity </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, a former splinter <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> group now run by <PERSON> Fulani </PERSON> backers. _ Prisoners of War @ Missing in Action, which advocates further investigation into cases of servicemen listed as missing from the <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> war. _ The <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Alliance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, a national group that led the drive to get Ms. <PERSON> Fulani </PERSON>'s name on the ballot.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880707-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-07-88 0100EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Dukakis     07-07 0542</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Dukakis,540</SECOND>
<HEAD>Dukakis Keeps Up Attack On Administration Ethics Despite Meese
Move</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN KING</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BOSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, resuming his criticism of <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration ethical standards, said the nation regained `` a measure of self-respect'' through the resignation of Attorney General <PERSON> Edwin </PERSON> <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>. But he said <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>'s departure does not change the administration's record of ethical breaches. `` The way to clean up <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> is to clean out those people who are indifferent to breaches of the public trust and the public laws,'' the Democratic presidential nominee-to-be told a friendly audience of Greek Americans on Wednesday. `` Yesterday we lost an attorney general, but we gained a measure of self-respect,'' he said. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, the <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> governor, was spending most of today in his Statehouse office before heading West for three days of campaigning. Awaiting his review was a proposed fiscal 1989 budget compromise worked out Wednesday evening by legislators. Passage of that plan would help <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> at home, where budget problems have prompted questions about his ability to govern while seeking the White House. It would also make life easier for him on the campaign trail, where he has used competent fiscal management as a selling point. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> ended his day Wednesday with a speech to the <ORGANIZATION> Greek </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Orthodox </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ecumenical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. The presumed Republican nominee, Vice President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, was to address the same group today. `` Next year, if all goes well, we're going to have a president who will insist that those who accept the privilege of public service must understand the meaning of public service,'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> told the group. `` If someone in my administration is caught breaking the law, we wo n't make excuses for him, we'll prosecute him.'' Before that appearance <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> met for more than an hour with 20 national civil rights leaders, including <ORGANIZATION> NAACP </ORGANIZATION> executive director <ORGANIZATION> Benjamin </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hooks </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Urban </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> League </ORGANIZATION> President <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Jacob </PERSON>, the Rev. <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Lowery </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Leadership </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conference </ORGANIZATION> and <PERSON> Coretta </PERSON> <PERSON> Scott </PERSON> <PERSON> King </PERSON>, the widow of <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Luther </PERSON> <PERSON> King </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>. Several participants described the session as positive and more substantive than a meeting the same group had recently with <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> `` I can not recall an issue he disagreed with us on,'' <PERSON> Hooks </PERSON> said. Whether blacks will support <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> without <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> on the ticket is largely up to <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, <PERSON> Hooks </PERSON> said. `` I think that they basically will follow _ though some will be disappointed _ will follow his leadership,'' he said. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> began his day by meeting with <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION> Rep. <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Hamilton </PERSON>, the eighth potential running mate to meet face-to-face with <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>. One of them, <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION> Sen. <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> <PERSON> Nunn </PERSON>, took himself out of the running. After a 50-minute meeting with <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> at the <ORGANIZATION> Statehouse </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Hamilton </PERSON> fired back a quick `` yes'' when asked if he would accept the vice presidential nomination. <PERSON> Hamilton </PERSON> said he had a `` very relaxed and wide-ranging discussion'' with <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, with the main topics being the vice presidency and foreign policy. Others being considered for the No. 2 spot on the ticket are <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, Sens. <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION>, <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Graham </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>, and Rep. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Brountas </PERSON>, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' campaign chairman, was in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> through Friday, gathering information on the contenders and talking with party leaders.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880707-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-07-88 0100EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-People-Hefner     07-07 0359</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-People-Hefner,0369</SECOND>
<HEAD>Hugh Hefner's Former Girlfriend Alleges He Supplied Her With Drugs</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Hugh </PERSON> <PERSON> Hefner </PERSON>'s former girlfriend has accused the <ORGANIZATION> Playboy </ORGANIZATION> founder and celebrity divorce lawyer <PERSON> Marvin </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitchelson </PERSON> of supplying her with enough drugs to make her an addict. `` -LRB- <PERSON> Hefner </PERSON> -RRB- supplied me with almost every drug that I ever took in that house. He had for about two years,'' <PERSON> Carrie </PERSON> <PERSON> Leigh </PERSON>, 24, told the television show `` Entertainment Tonight'' in a two-part interview beginning Wednesday. `` I was addicted to pills ... painkillers, sleeping pills, Quaaludes and he had them under lock and key and he supplied me with these pills every day,'' she said. Miss <PERSON> Leigh </PERSON> filed a $ 35 million palimony suit against <PERSON> Hefner </PERSON> earlier this year, claiming he defrauded and deceived her by allegedly abandoning promises to support her and father a child. She later dropped the lawsuit. `` As the original palimony suit proved, <PERSON> Carrie </PERSON> <PERSON> Leigh </PERSON> had a very vivid imagination, and whatever she says, should be viewed with a certain amount of skepticism,'' <PERSON> Hefner </PERSON> said Wednesday. `` I spent the last three years of the relationship trying to curb her abuse of both drugs and alcohol, and she very well knows it,'' he said of their five-year relationship that ended earlier this year. `` Please remember that I had a stroke in March 1985 that dramatically changed the focus of my life. It ended my use of all recreational drugs.'' In Wednesday's segment, Miss <PERSON> Leigh </PERSON> accused <PERSON> Mitchelson </PERSON>, who represented her in the palimony lawsuit, of also supplying drugs and making a pass at her. `` At the time when I started the lawsuit, I was still addicted to some pills and he supplied me with them,'' Miss <PERSON> Leigh </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Mitchelson </PERSON>, who handled divorces of such celebrities as <PERSON> Joan </PERSON> <PERSON> Collins </PERSON> of `` Dynasty,'' is under investigation by the <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> State Bar for alleged misconduct. `` I completely deny all of the allegations. I do n't want to attack <PERSON> Carrie </PERSON> <PERSON> Leigh </PERSON>,'' <PERSON> Mitchelson </PERSON> told the television program. `` She told me during the case I was a wonderful lawyer. For the last 31 years, I've never heard any criticisms like these until recently,'' he said. `` I've spent my life defending women, not attacking them.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880707-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-07-88 0104EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-PoliticalRdp Bjt   07-07 0621</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Political Rdp, Bjt,630</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush Pledges Hispanic Cabinet Member; Dukakis Finds Some Budget
Relief</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT GREENE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> was finding some relief from a politically embarrassing budget crisis in his home state as Vice President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> pledged to right `` a wrong that has been out there for many years'' and appoint a Hispanic American to his Cabinet. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, the <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> governor, was spending most of today in his Statehouse office before heading West for three days of campaigning. He was preparing to review a proposed fiscal 1989 state budget compromise. <ORGANIZATION> Massachusetts </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> leaders agreed late Wednesday on a compromise budget of $ 11.75 billion that would increase state spending by about 4 percent. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> was forced to seek emergency spending authority this week to keep government functioning. <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> faces a $ 450 million deficit on an $ 11 billion budget in the just-ended fiscal year. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> has been highly critical of the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration's deficit spending, and Republicans are planning to make political hay of his troubles `` It could turn out to be the Achilles heel of the <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> presidential campaign,'' said state Sen. <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Cellucci </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> coordinator for the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> campaign. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, for his part, continued to attack the ethical standards of the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration, saying the resignation of Attorney General <PERSON> Edwin </PERSON> <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON> does not erase the administration's shoddy record. `` If someone in my administration is caught breaking the law, we wo n't make excuses for him, we'll prosecute him,'' he told a friendly audience of Greek Americans in <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was traveling to <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> tonight to address the same ethnic group at a Greek Orthodox diocesan dinner. Aides said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was going to talk about the importance of religion. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> was traveling to <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION> tonight to address a convention of the <ORGANIZATION> League </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Latin </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Citizens </ORGANIZATION>, the same group to whom <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> promised Wednesday he would make a Hispanic appointment. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said after addressing <ORGANIZATION> LULAC </ORGANIZATION>, the largest and oldest Hispanic American civic group, that he would not go around the country making the same promise to other special interest groups. `` Other groups have been represented in the Cabinet and Hispanics have not,'' said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. `` I will be very open-minded and broad-based in who I select to serve in my <ORGANIZATION> Cabinet </ORGANIZATION>, but I'm addressing myself to righting a wrong that has been out there for many years,'' he said. <PERSON> Oscar </PERSON> <PERSON> Moran </PERSON>, the group's president, said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> `` attracted the attention of some voters who already decided on <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>.'' But <PERSON> Tony </PERSON> <PERSON> Bonilla </PERSON>, an influential Democrat in the group, said it was `` a little patronizing'' for <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> to make such a statement after serving eight years in the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration without a Hispanic in the inner circle. Hispanics are a politically important group, especially in key battleground states like <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' command of Spanish gives him an advantage in competing for votes from those groups <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> met for more than an hour Wednesday with 20 national civil rights leaders, including <ORGANIZATION> NAACP </ORGANIZATION> executive director <ORGANIZATION> Benjamin </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hooks </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Urban </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> League </ORGANIZATION> President <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Jacob </PERSON>, the Rev. <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Lowery </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Leadership </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conference </ORGANIZATION> and <PERSON> Coretta </PERSON> <PERSON> Scott </PERSON> <PERSON> King </PERSON>, the widow of <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Luther </PERSON> <PERSON> King </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> `` I can not recall an issue he disagreed with us on,'' <PERSON> Hooks </PERSON> said. But whether blacks will support <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> without <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> on the ticket is largely up to <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, <PERSON> Hooks </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, meanwhile, met with <PERSON> Arab </PERSON> leaders at the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION>. Afterward he emphasized that the shooting down of an Iranian passenger jet by a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> ship in the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> was `` an accident, an error.'' <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> called for a period of mourning for the victims of the attack and urged the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> to pay reparations to the victims' families.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880707-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-07-88 0044EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     07-07 0950</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0992</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in the News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BEVERLY HILLS, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 What do you do when the company you founded is bought by foreigners for $ 310 million? If you're <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Tyler </PERSON> <PERSON> Moore </PERSON>, you keep working. And you make some charities very happy. Miss <PERSON> Moore </PERSON> said Wednesday the sale of <ORGANIZATION> MTM </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Entertainment </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, the production company she co-founded, will free her to boost contributions to the arts and to the fight against diabetes. A diabetic, <PERSON> Miss </PERSON> <PERSON> Moore </PERSON> is international chairman of the Juvenile Diabetes foundation. Just how much money does the 50-year-old actress get from the sale of the company that bears her initials to <ORGANIZATION> Television </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> South </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> PLC </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>? `` Enough so I do n't have to learn to type, after all,'' was all she'd say. Sale or no, <PERSON> Miss </PERSON> <PERSON> Moore </PERSON> is set to appear in a new MTM series slated to make its debut on CBS this fall, assuming the scriptwriters strike is settled. The as-yet unnamed romantic comedy will feature Miss <PERSON> Moore </PERSON> as a divorced mother working for a <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> politician. In the series, she marries a blue-collar worker from <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> with children of his own. `` These children are going to be real children,'' she promised. `` They're not going to be cartoon characters. They're not going to be little munchkins with quips.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>BARNSTABLE, Mass. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Joan </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, former wife of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Sen. <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, faces a hearing Aug. 5 on charges of drunken driving, a court official says. Attorney <PERSON> Patrick </PERSON> <PERSON> Butler </PERSON> entered a plea of innocent on behalf of Mrs. <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> in <ORGANIZATION> Barnstable </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> on Wednesday, said Clerk-Magistrate <PERSON> Omer </PERSON> <PERSON> Chartrand </PERSON>. Mrs. <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, 51, did not appear in court. A hearing was scheduled for Aug. 5, <PERSON> Chartrand </PERSON> said. <LOCATION> Centerville </LOCATION> police arrested Mrs. <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> Tuesday night after she drove into a chain-link fence along a road near the <LOCATION> Cape </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Cod </LOCATION> <LOCATION> beach </LOCATION>, according to Lt. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Arthur </PERSON>. Mrs. <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> was not injured in the accident, he said. Police towed and impounded the car. Mrs. <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, who joined Alcoholics Anonymous, was divorced in late 1983. She lives mostly in <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>SAN FRANCISCO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Lawyer <PERSON> Melvin </PERSON> <PERSON> Belli </PERSON> wants his Rumproast. Not the dish, the dog. <PERSON> Belli </PERSON>, who is in the midst of a heated marital dispute, returned to his mansion last weekend to collect some things. Little Rumproast, also affectionately known as `` Rumpy,'' was n't one of them. His estranged wife, <PERSON> Lia </PERSON>, said he could pack up three of the couple's pooches, but said their Italian greyhound was staying put. `` I just wanted to have a little watchdog here,'' she said, adding that she let her husband take the other dogs because he ca n't sleep without them. <PERSON> Belli </PERSON> said it's not fair. He said that because of concern about `` Rumpy's tears on being separated'' from the rest of his canine family, he'll take legal steps to get the dog back. `` All I want is that the dog be with the other dogs; the dogs hate her -LRB- Lia -RRB-,'' he said. `` I slept with those dogs for the past five or six years when I kicked her out of my bed.'' <PERSON> Lia </PERSON> <PERSON> Belli </PERSON> filed for a legal separation last week.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>INDIANAPOLIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Morton </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION>'s first dog, may be headed for stardom in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> after finding himself at the center of a feud between talk show host <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Letterman </PERSON> and <PERSON> Josie </PERSON> <PERSON> Orr </PERSON>, the wife of Gov. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Orr </PERSON>. The Orrs' Welsh Corgi may be offered an appearance on the `` Stupid Pet Tricks'' segment of `` Late Night with <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Letterman </PERSON>'' as part of settling the feud, which the Indianapolis-born comedian has mentioned on the air, said <PERSON> Becky </PERSON> <PERSON> Weiland </PERSON>, an aide to Mrs. <PERSON> Orr </PERSON>. <PERSON> Letterman </PERSON> also is expected to call Mrs. <PERSON> Orr </PERSON> during his program tonight or Friday. The feud began with an encounter with <PERSON> Letterman </PERSON> during the <LOCATION> Indianapolis </LOCATION> 500 on May 29, the governor said Tuesday. `` <PERSON> Josie </PERSON> told him that <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Morton </PERSON> can push a rock around the floor with his nose. But <PERSON> Letterman </PERSON> was n't interested,'' <PERSON> Orr </PERSON> said. `` He ignored her. Then he made some remark about, ` How did she get in here?' or something like that. That's the reason she's upset with him.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actress <PERSON> Ava </PERSON> <PERSON> Gardner </PERSON>, who suffered a mild stroke two years ago, is contemplating a return to the silver screen, her attorney says. `` She's fit as a fiddle, feels strong, feels great and is thinking about doing a picture,'' lawyer <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Caruso </PERSON> said Wednesday. The 66-year-old actress has `` recovered tremendously'' from the stroke in late 1986, for which she was hospitalized for two months, <PERSON> Caruso </PERSON> said. He did not say what kind of role Miss <PERSON> Gardner </PERSON> was considering. Miss <PERSON> Gardner </PERSON>, who has lived in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> for the past 20 years, was the daughter of a poor <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> tenant farmer. She became a leading lady in the 1940s and 1950s. She starred in 60 films, including `` The Snows of Kilimanjaro,'' `` The Barefoot Contessa'' and `` The Killers.'' She most recently was seen in the CBS-TV series `` Falcon Crest.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>HALIFAX, Nova Scotia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Princess <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON>, colonel-in-chief of this city's Princess <PERSON> Louise </PERSON> <PERSON> Fusiliers </PERSON>, inspected her regiment for the first time in three decades. The 57-year-old younger sister of <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s Queen <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> II </PERSON> presented new colors, or regimental flags, to the regiment Wednesday at the Garrison Grounds, a grassy field behind the downtown <ORGANIZATION> Halifax </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Citadel </ORGANIZATION>, a historic British fortress. <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON>'s eight-day tour of <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> was prompted by a request 18 months ago from the provincial capital's offical regiment for new colors. The princess ended her second day in <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> with a private reception at the Maritime Museum of the <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION>. She is scheduled to leave <LOCATION> Nova </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Scotia </LOCATION> on Friday for <LOCATION> Toronto </LOCATION>, where her tour ends July 12.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880707-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-07-88 0110EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-WritersStrike-Cable Bjt   07-07 0636</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Writers Strike-Cable, Bjt,0649</SECOND>
<HEAD>Cable, Public Television Reluctantly Hope for Benefits from Strike</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KATHRYN BAKER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Television Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Public television and cable channels are hoping to lure away network viewers as the lengthy writers strike wears on, delaying the fall season for the networks and the debut of new series. `` I must say, I have mixed emotions -LRB- about the strike -RRB-, because I hate to think about all those writers out of work, so it's nothing to jump up and down about On the other hand, I think it will help us quite a bit,'' said <PERSON> Suzanne </PERSON> <PERSON> Weil </PERSON>, senior vice president of national programming and promotion services for the <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Broadcasting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>. The strike, which began March 7, has forced the three major television networks to delay the traditional fall season when they launch new series. The guild rejected the most recent management offer last month. It voted Wednesday night on a model contract for independent producers. Results were to be announced this afternoon. When the strike ends, it will take weeks for producers to prepare new shows. <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> is considering buying programs from the <ORGANIZATION> British </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Broadcasting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> or re-shooting old TV shows with different actors to avoid reruns. Its `` The Cosby Show'' will continue in production under an independent contract, and it has the Summer Olympics in September. CBS is considering buying <ORGANIZATION> BBC </ORGANIZATION> shows. <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> plans to run the first 18 hours of its 30-hour miniseries `` War and Remembrance'' in November instead of February. PBS is immune from the strike because its programs are produced under a separate contract with the guild, and it also buys British programming. Cable channels that produce first-run programming are affected by the strike, though in most cases the effect has n't been noticed yet. Some first-run cable series, such as Showtime's `` Brothers,'' are at a standstill, just like network shows. Made-for-cable movies for this fall were already written and will go on as scheduled, but the strike had delayed development for next year. In the meantime, cable hopes its documentaries, musical specials and made-for-cable movies that go on this fall as scheduled will lure over some network viewers. Cable and <ORGANIZATION> PBS </ORGANIZATION> traditionally pick up viewers during the summer when the networks are in reruns and see a possibility of the seasonal advantage continuing into the fall. For the networks, the loss of viewers this fall could mean increased audience erosion in favor of cable alternatives and videocassettes. `` I think any time the cable networks can inch away a little more viewership, some of the viewership will remain on cable in a longer term,'' said <PERSON> Andy </PERSON> <PERSON> Orgel </PERSON>, senior vice president of programming for the <ORGANIZATION> Arts </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ; </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Entertainment </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Network </ORGANIZATION>, which hopes to lure new viewers with sophisticated programming alternatives this fall. At the end of the 1987-88 television season, most major cable channels increased viewership. <ORGANIZATION> HBO </ORGANIZATION>, for example, increased 5 percent, while overall network audience levels dropped 9 percent. Some of the drop is attributed to a change in <PERSON> A.C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Nielsen </PERSON>'s ratings technology, but the networks agree there is a decrease in network viewing Public television already staggers its series to attract viewers to alternative programming when network shows are repeats. For instance, `` Alive from Off Center,'' an avant-garde variety series, starts its new season on PBS next week. <PERSON> Weil </PERSON> said PBS is not concerned about potential competition if the networks buy <ORGANIZATION> BBC </ORGANIZATION> shows. She says most Americans are unaware there is plenty of mediocre British television they do n't usually see. But she said if an infusion of foreign product helps raise the level of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> television, that's fine, too. `` I never worry about somebody nibbling away at our turf, because I think we should always be moving ahead,'' she said. `` It's going to be a long time before the networks get to ` Alive from Off Center.'''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880707-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-07-88 0154EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Nielsens     07-07 0480</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nielsens,0493</SECOND>
<HEAD>ABC Suffers Lowest Rating Ever As Summer Doldrums Deepen</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Writers Strike-Cable, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KATHRYN BAKER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Television Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A combination of viewers away from their televisions and writers away from their desks handed <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> its lowest prime-time rating ever last week, according to figures from the <ORGANIZATION> A.C. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nielsen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co </ORGANIZATION>. The Fourth of July weekend is traditionally a period of low viewing for the networks, but the strike by the <ORGANIZATION> Writers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guild </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION> forced some programs into early reruns and that helped lower <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s average to 8.0, said <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Wurtzel </PERSON>, vice president for marketing and research. `` It's not only just summer doldrums, but also the fact that the writers' strike has really affected what people are able to see,'' he said. `` We went into a rerun mode earlier than we would have. We've been playing reruns now for an awful long time. `` Believe me, it's not a number anybody is happy about. It's just another reason strikes do n't benefit anybody. For the week ending July 3, <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> had a rating of 8.0. <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> won the week with an 11.7. <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> was second with a 9.6. The lowest previous rating for <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> was 8.7 two weeks ago and in July 1985. The rating is a percentage of the nation's estimated 88.6 million households with televisions. <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s first-run TV movie `` Nightingales'' was the top-rated show of the week and seemingly would have been off to a good start as a summer series, but there are no more episodes of the Aaron Spelling-produced show because of the strike, according to <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>. The four-month-long strike has delayed the networks' fall season. <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> maintains, however, that the current low viewing levels are typical of summer rerun programming and do not reflect effects of the strike, at least not yet. As a comparison of how low ratings have fallen, `` The Cosby Show,'' the No. 1 show last season, had an season-long average rating of 28.0 compared to 18.9 for `` Nightingales,'' the No. 1 show last week. The rest of the top 10 shows, all reruns, were: `` Night Court,'' `` Cheers,'' `` The Cosby Show,'' `` A Different World,'' `` <LOCATION> L.A. </LOCATION> Law,'' `` Golden Girls'' and `` ALF,'' all <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, `` Who's the Boss?'' on <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, and <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` The <PERSON> Hogan </PERSON> Family.'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s first-run summer series `` Hothouse'' premiered to a lowly 6.4 rating and was in 60th place. The lowest-rated prime-time shows of the week were: `` High Mountain Rangers,'' `` Star-Spangled Celebration,'' `` Hothouse,'' `` Sledge Hammer!'' `` CBS Summer Playhouse,'' `` Charmings Special,'' `` Hotel,'' `` Spot Marks the X,'' `` MacGyver,'' `` Rags to Riches,'' `` Supercarrier'' and `` Home Again.'' CBS remained in first place in the close news race, finishing the week ending July 1 with an average rating of 9.1 and a share of 20. <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> was second with a rating of 8.8 and a 20 share. <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> had an 8.4 and 19 share. The share is a percentage of sets in use.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880707-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-07-88 0155EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-NielsensList     07-07 0686</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nielsens List,0767</SECOND>
<HEAD>List of Week's Top-Rated TV Shows</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Nielsens</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the prime-time television ratings as compiled by the <ORGANIZATION> A.C. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nielsen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> for the week of June 27-July 3. Top 20 listings include the week's ranking, with full season-to-date ranking in parentheses, rating for the week, and total homes. An `` X'' in parentheses denotes one-time-only presentation. A rating measures the percentage of the nation's 88.6 million TV homes. 1. -LRB- 21 -RRB- `` Nightingales'' _ `` <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> Monday Night Movies,'' 18.9 rating, 16.7 million homes. 2. -LRB- 5 -RRB- `` Night Court,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 17.5, 15.5 million homes. 3. -LRB- 3 -RRB- `` Cheers,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 17.2, 15.2 million homes. 4. -LRB- 1 -RRB- `` The Cosby Show,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 16.6, 14.7 million homes. 5. -LRB- 2 -RRB- `` A Different World,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 16.5, 14.6 million homes. 6. -LRB- 13 -RRB- `` <LOCATION> L.A. </LOCATION> Law,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 15.4, 13.6 million homes. 7. -LRB- 4 -RRB- `` Golden Girls,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 15.1, 13.4 million homes. 8. -LRB- 12 -RRB- `` ALF,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 14.9, 13.2 million homes. 9. -LRB- 6 -RRB- `` Who's the Boss?'', <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 14.0, 12.4 million homes. 10. -LRB- 41 -RRB- `` The <PERSON> Hogan </PERSON> Family,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.8, 12.2 million homes. 11. -LRB- 17 -RRB- `` Brass'' _ `` CBS Sunday Movie,'' 13.6, 12.0 million homes. 12. -LRB- 15 -RRB- `` Amen,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.2, 11.7 million homes. 12. -LRB- 26 -RRB- `` Head of the Class,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.2, 11.7 million homes. 14. -LRB- 7 -RRB- `` Growing Pains,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.9, 11.4 million homes. 14. -LRB- 43 -RRB- `` Perfect Strangers-Tuesday,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.9, 11.4 million homes. 16. -LRB- 9 -RRB- `` Murder, She Wrote,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 12.7, 11.2 million homes. 16. -LRB- 27 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Hunter </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.7, 11.2 million homes. 18. -LRB- 7 -RRB- `` 60 Minutes,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 12.5, 11.1 million homes. 19. -LRB- 21 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Matlock </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.4, 11.0 million homes. 20. -LRB- 30 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Newhart </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 11.7, 10.4 million homes.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
