<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880224-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-24-88 0350EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>ting license.
   ___</FIRST>
<SECOND>   BALTIMORE (AP) _ Black &amp; Decker Corp. has sweetened a hostile</SECOND>
<TEXT>
 bid for <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Standard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> a second time, raising its offer to $ 68 from $ 65 per share and promising court action to block the target's recapitalization plan. The latest offer from <ORGANIZATION> Black </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> Decker </PERSON> on Tuesday _ worth about $ 2.11 billion _ surprised some analysts who said the bidding was becoming inflated.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Texaco </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> has agreed to pay $ 1.25 billion to the government to settle claims it overcharged customers for oil during the 1973-81 period of price controls. The nation's third largest oil company said Tuesday it would make a first installment of $ 400 million when the agreement was closed and pay the rest over the following 5 -LCB- years. The <LOCATION> White </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Plains </LOCATION>, N.Y.-based oil giant is the latest in a series of companies forced to pay billions to resolve charges they violated pricing restrictions on crude oil and refined products during the period of federal controls.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NIAGARA FALLS, N.Y. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A federal judge has ruled <ORGANIZATION> Occidental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chemical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> is liable for the estimated $ 250 million cost of cleaning up the Love Canal landfill that became synonymous with environmental disaster. After nine years of deliberations, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Curtin </PERSON> said Tuesday that <ORGANIZATION> Occidental </ORGANIZATION> produced the wastes that created the disaster and stored them in a way that would eventually result in toxic leakage. <ORGANIZATION> Occidental </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Green </PERSON> said the company was disappointed by the ruling but would not comment until its attorneys had studied the decision.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>MORE</NOTE>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880224-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-24-88 2342EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-StunGun     02-24 0354</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Stun Gun,0366</SECOND>
<HEAD>Police Officers Guilty in Queens Stun Gun Trial</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A former police sergeant and a suspended officer were convicted Wednesday of torturing a drug suspect with an electric stun gun three years ago. In addition, a former officer was convicted of beating of the man at his home, and a suspended lieutenant was found guilty of abetting the beating. The defendants were among several police officers from the same <LOCATION> Queens </LOCATION> precinct implicated in 1985 in the alleged torture of drug suspects with the stun gun, which delivers a powerful, temporarily disabling jolt of up to 40,000 volts. <PERSON> Everton </PERSON> <PERSON> Evelyn </PERSON> had testified that four officers beat him in his home in 1985, and that two of them had later used a stun gun on him at the station, holding him down and giving him shocks from the hand-held device. The 34-year-old taxi driver testified that the stun gun was used on his abdomen seven to 10 times for five seconds at a time. He has also filed a $ 50 million lawsuit against the city and the Police Department. Former Sgt. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Pike </PERSON> and suspended Officer <PERSON> Loren </PERSON> <PERSON> MacCary </PERSON> were convicted of assault, official misconduct and coercion and could receive up to seven years in prison. <PERSON> Jeffrey </PERSON> <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON>, a former officer, was convicted of the same charges in the beating. Suspended Lt. <PERSON> Steven </PERSON> <PERSON> Cheswick </PERSON>, who supervised the other three, was convicted of official misconduct and faces up to a year in jail. The jury had begun deliberating Monday afternoon. <PERSON> Pike </PERSON> was found guilty in both the beating and the stun gun attack; <PERSON> MacCary </PERSON> was convicted in the stun gun attack; and <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON> was found guilty in the beating. <PERSON> Cheswick </PERSON>, prosecutors said, had blocked <PERSON> Evelyn </PERSON>'s wife from aiding her husband during the beating and had not tried to stop the beating. The four defendants will be sentenced March 29. The trial was the second of four scheduled for officers of the 106th precinct who allegedly tortured suspects with stun guns in 1985. <PERSON> Pike </PERSON> and <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON> already are serving two to six years for their convictions in the first trial, in 1986.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880224-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-24-88 0905EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--MoneyRecovered     02-24 0125</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Money Recovered,0130</SECOND>
<HEAD>Money-Filled Suitcase Recovered From Crash Site</HEAD>
<DATELINE>HAMILTON TOWNSHIP, N.J. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A suitcase reportedly containing $ 30,000 has been recovered from a plane that crashed in the woods here, killing three people, authorities said. The suitcase of <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> <PERSON> Siegel </PERSON>, 66, of <LOCATION> Brookline </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mass. </LOCATION>, was found Saturday, said police Lt. <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Lentz </PERSON>. He would not discuss the contents, saying only that it contained personal belongings. The Press of <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> on Tuesday quoted sources as saying it contained $ 30,000. <PERSON> Siegel </PERSON>, owner of <PERSON> Siegel </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> Egg </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Company </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Roxbury </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mass. </LOCATION>, was flying to an <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> casino Friday when the plane crashed, killing him, the pilot and co-pilot. The <PERSON> Siegel </PERSON> family attorney is expected to arrive later this week to reclaim the bag, <PERSON> Lentz </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880224-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-24-88 0905EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--FallingIce     02-24 0127</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Falling Ice,0129</SECOND>
<HEAD>Worker's Car Crushed By Falling Chunk Of Ice</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LODI, N.J. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A 2-foot-long slab of ice fell from a 2,000-foot-high plane and crushed a car, authorities said. No injuries were reported. No other details were available about the plane involved in Monday's incident, said <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aviation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON>, who noted that about 600 planes fly daily over the area to <LOCATION> Newark </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION>. Workers at the <ORGANIZATION> Penske </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> GM </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Power </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> plant said they heard a thump and when they looked outside, saw the chunk of blue ice on the roof of employee <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Reid </PERSON>'s car. <PERSON> Reid </PERSON> said he recently spent $ 1,400 on a new engine for his 1979 <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> and joked that his insurance company would never believe what had happened.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880224-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-24-88 0011EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-CampaignMoney 2ndLd-Writethru a0896 02-24 0753</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Campaign Money, 2nd Ld-Writethru, a0896,660</SECOND>
<HEAD>Senate Filibuster Over Campaign Spending Limits Bill</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDs: INSERTS 2 grafs after 2nd graf pvs, bgng: ``The talking ...''
to UPDATE with motion to arrest absent senators.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By DAVID GOELLER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> launched a `` full-fledged filibuster'' Tuesday as Majority Leader <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON> ordered 24-hour sessions to subdue <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> opposition to a Democratic campaign financing bill. The talking, broken by occasional roll calls, began about 2 p.m. and continued into the night. Appointments were canceled, schedules revised, senators began catching up on paperwork and cots were set up in rooms near the chamber. Shortly after 11 p.m., the Democrats used their numbers to approve a rarely-used motion ordering the sergeant-at-arms to take to the streets to arrest senators who had been absent from a series of quorum calls. Democrats said the move was made because Republicans were taking turns holding the floor, forcing Democrats to stay close by the chamber to prevent the loss of a quorum, which would immediately end the session. <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON>, lacking the votes to prevent Republicans from stalling action on the legislation, threatened to keep the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> in session indefinitely. `` We've decided we'll just go around-the-clock,'' the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> Democrat said at midafternoon after <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> and Democratic negotiators reported making no progress on the central question of spending limits. `` We're going to talk or we're going to vote,'' said <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON>, warning that foes of the campaign finance legislation would have to keep control of the floor to prevent a vote. Democrats and Republicans have been at loggerheads for nearly a year over a Democratic bill with 52 co-sponsors that would set up a system of voluntary spending limits for <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> general election campaigns. The limit would be from $ 950,000 to $ 5.5 million, depending on a state's population. The bill's supporters say limits are needed to put a brake on the increasing cost of getting elected, up from an average of $ 600,000 in 1976 to $ 3 million in 1986. In larger states, growing numbers of candidates are spending more than $ 10 million to win a <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> seat, with increasing amounts of campaign funds being supplied by special-interest political action committees. A candidate observing the voluntary limit would get campaign funds from the <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> if the opponent exceeded the limit or an independent group spent large amounts of money against the candidate. Republicans, who have made opposition to limits a party issue, succeeded last year in preventing the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> from voting on the legislation, winning a record seven cloture votes during 22 days of floor time. <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON>, even with the support of three of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>'s 46 Republicans, is believed to be five votes short of the 60 needed to cut off debate and force a vote on the bill. `` The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> is in a full-fledged filibuster,'' said <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON>, adding that he would no longer confine debate to daylight hours. `` There's no point in continuing the casual, gentlemanly, good-guy filibuster because it will just turn out like it did last year,'' he said. ... Let's have it on the floor where the <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> people can see it.'' Four Democrats and four Republicans have been negotiating since last week. They reported progress on some facets of the bill but not on spending limits, which Republicans say will discriminate against them in states with a heavy Democratic edge in registered votes. The chief negotiators said their positions on the key issue were solid. A limit on spending `` is something this side is not going to agree to,'' said <PERSON> Mitch </PERSON> <PERSON> McConnell </PERSON>, R-Ky. `` That is not one of the negotiable items. His counterpart, <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Boren </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Okla </LOCATION>., was just as adamant: `` Any bill that does not limit campaign spending would not be real reform. <PERSON> Boren </PERSON> said, however, that Democrats are willing to discuss higher spending limits in states where their party enjoys a big advantage in registration or historically has dominated congressional elections. There was no public response from <PERSON> McConnell </PERSON>, who said Republicans were willing to discuss compromise on another Democratic demand: putting a ceiling on how much money a candidate can get from political action committees. <PERSON> Boren </PERSON> and <PERSON> McConnell </PERSON> said negotiators had neared informal agreement on other issues, including controling how much personal money a millionare can put into his or her campaign; requiring broadcasters to charge rock-bottom rates for political ads; better disclosure of money going to political parties; and getting controls on so-called `` soft money,'' which includes groups like labor unions supplying people to help candidates with canvassing and phone banks.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880224-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-24-88 0326EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-LifeAbroad-India     02-24 0814</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Life Abroad-India,0849</SECOND>
<HEAD>LIFE ABROAD: India _ Bullock Carts for the 21st Century</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</NOTE>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 This is one of a series of periodic reports by <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> correspondents on the way of life in other countries.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>By DILIP GANGULY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW DELHI, India (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> is taking the bullock-cart into the 21st century. At least 500 researchers in about a dozen government-aided institutes are at work modernizing the ancient, creaking, plodding carts, and even the <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> has donated funds. Carts of various shapes and designs, made of plastic and aluminum, are being tested or have been developed. `` There is nothing funny about our project,'' said <PERSON> Mittar </PERSON> <PERSON> Pal </PERSON> <PERSON> Dhir </PERSON>, director of the <ORGANIZATION> Road </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Delhi </LOCATION>. `` For us, animal-drawn carts are of great importance.'' <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> has an estimated 13 million bullock carts drawn by about 26 million of the neutered bulls, along with 2 million carts pulled by water buffaloes, camels, horses, mules and donkeys. The carts are seen most often in villages, where about 640 million of the <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>'s 800 million people live. But they also are seen on major highways and an estimated 3 million plod along city streets, often slowing engine-powered traffic and infuriating motorists. <PERSON> Bullock </PERSON> carts have even been used to pull MiG fighter jets to parades and earth satellites to launching pads. <PERSON> Dhir </PERSON> said it would be 50 years before <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> could eliminate animal-drawn carts, given their crucial role in Indian life. Capital investment in animal-drawn carts is put at $ 7.6 billion. More than 20 million Indians earn their living by driving, renting, and repairing the carts. `` The figure is striking given the fact that Indian railways, the fourth largest in the world, employ only 16.3 million people,'' said <PERSON> Rupinder </PERSON> <PERSON> Gupta </PERSON>, a mechanical engineer for the <ORGANIZATION> Road </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Gupta </PERSON> has designed six types of bullock cart for field trials. Each year, animal-drawn carts move 14.4 million ton-miles of freight. Dhir estimates that <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>'s animal-drawn carts provide about 40 million horse-power, equal to about 320,000 medium-duty trucks used in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> as city delivery vehicles. Without bullock carts, <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> also would have had to import an additional 6 million tons of fuel each year. It now imports 17 million tons of crude oil annually. One of the innovations is the replacement of the carts' wooden-spoke wheels with pneumatic tires Engineer <PERSON> Gupta </PERSON> said carts with pneumatic tires can pull 2.5 tons of weight against the maximum capacity of 1.5 tons for conventional carts. Researchers in the southern state of <LOCATION> Karnataka </LOCATION> also have come up with plastic bullock carts, and in neighboring <LOCATION> Andhra </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Pradesh </LOCATION> state a tire company has produced carts of lightweight aluminum. Another idea behind non-wooden carts is to reduce demand for lumber. An estimated 165,000 medium-sized trees are felled each year to make conventional carts. `` So you see, there is a solid logic behind metal carts,'' said <PERSON> Gupta </PERSON>. He listed other reasons for updating the carts. `` We want to increase tillage and output, reduce damage to roads and injury to animals so that the poor animals can have a longer lifespan,'' he said. To protect the animals, curved and padded yokes are being introduced. Studies have shown that some draft animals' lives are cut short by cancerous infections on the neck from unpadded and uncurved yokes. Reflectors are being added as another safety feature. Other new fittings are <PERSON> bush </PERSON> bearings, cast-iron springs, shock absorbers, draw bars that adjust for animals of different height, and mud scrappers. A fodder box can be put on carts that go long distances. As for road damage, director <PERSON> Dhir </PERSON> said the biggest culprit is wooden wheels. `` In monetary terms the annual damage is to the tune of 7,000 million rupees -LRB- $ 538 million -RRB- to the roads,'' he said. Farmers seem to like the idea of improving bullock carts. `` It is an excellent idea,'' said <PERSON> Jhandu </PERSON> <PERSON> Singh </PERSON>, 64, of <LOCATION> Jharsa </LOCATION>, a village 30 miles south of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Delhi </LOCATION>. `` But this should have had been done 25 years ago. We have suffered for long, and so did the animals.'' Officials, too, say the new carts are catching on, but this itself is creating problems. `` We do not have enough new types of carts for all,'' said <PERSON> Kalle </PERSON> <PERSON> Khan </PERSON>, project economist of the <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Jharsa </LOCATION>, whose office received only 16 new carts. `` There are more than 200 claimants. Even some gypsies saw the carts and were attracted. They wanted at least one. I told them no. These are for farmers.'' Another reason for high demand is that the government is subsidizing the price by about 35 percent. It is estimated that the largest of the old wooden carts costs the equivalent of about $ 300. Newer wooden carts, without the government subsidy, cost $ 270 to $ 460. The plastic and aluminum carts are 25 percent more expensive.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880224-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-24-88 0331EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-China-Yenan     02-24 0844</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-China-Yenan,0871</SECOND>
<HEAD>Old Revolutionary Base Struggles To Catch Up</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By KATHY WILHELM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>YENAN, China (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The town that was <PERSON> Mao </PERSON> <PERSON> Tse-tung </PERSON>'s civil war haven in remote northwest <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> is struggling to catch up with a revolution that left it behind when the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> leadership marched out 40 years ago to triumph. The caves <PERSON> Mao </PERSON> called home in <LOCATION> Yenan </LOCATION>'s arid mountains are preserved much as he left them, the spartan desks and bedstands still in place. Since then, <LOCATION> Yenan </LOCATION>'s population has grown from 10,000 to 80,000, and a smattering of eight - and 10-story concrete apartment blocks give the town an urban air But the lives of most of its residents have changed little compared with the rest of <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>. Two-thirds of <LOCATION> Yenan </LOCATION>'s people still live in caves in the steep brown cliffs overlooking two narrow rivers that meet at <LOCATION> Yenan </LOCATION>. The cave-dwellers fetch water from nearby wells and grind their grain using old-style millstones turned by donkey or by hand. They cook on coal stoves that also heat the family sleeping platform, the kang. The caves have electricity, but few people have major electrical appliances. The average annual per capita income of <LOCATION> Yenan </LOCATION>'s peasants is $ 59 _ less than half the national average and barely above the official poverty level of $ 54. Non-peasants average $ 108 a year, compared with a national figure of $ 248. The Communist revolution was intended to free the peasants from the whims of nature and those in power. But in <LOCATION> Yenan </LOCATION>, nature has been stingy and those in power are far away. `` We rely on heaven for food,'' said <PERSON> Lei </PERSON> <PERSON> Zhifu </PERSON>, a former guerrilla leader and retired <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> official, quoting an ancient saying about <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s dependence on nature. <PERSON> Mao </PERSON>, who arrived here in 1937 at the end of the Long March, a 6,000-mile retreat from <PERSON> Chiang </PERSON> <PERSON> Kai-shek </PERSON>'s Nationalist troops, left <LOCATION> Yenan </LOCATION> in 1947 as the country's civil war raged. He never returned. Premier <PERSON> Chou </PERSON> <PERSON> En-lai </PERSON> returned briefly in 1973, to attend the opening of a revolutionary museum. He ordered that small factories be set up with central government help to supplement the perennially drought-stricken area's meager agricultural income. The factories were built: fertilizer, steel, cement and textiles among others. But nothing was done to ensure that their products reached markets. Only one narrow, twisting road and three weekly flights link <LOCATION> Yenan </LOCATION> to the outside world. The nearest big city, <LOCATION> Xian </LOCATION>, is more than 185 miles to the south, an eight-hour trip by car. Since 1985, <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> has moved to end <LOCATION> Yenan </LOCATION>'s isolation by providing more than $ 54 million toward construction of a railroad. Tracks have been laid nearly halfway from <LOCATION> Xian </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Yenan </LOCATION>, and plans are to finish by 1990. There's a snag _ $ 43 million more is needed to build the final stretch. <PERSON> Li </PERSON> <PERSON> Guanhua </PERSON>, deputy director of <LOCATION> Yenan </LOCATION>'s planning commission, said he expected <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> to provide at least part. Even with a railroad, <PERSON> Li </PERSON>'s plans for <LOCATION> Yenan </LOCATION>'s future are modest. He envisioned gradual growth fueled by wider sales for the town's factories, especially its leading industry, cigarettes <PERSON> Lu </PERSON> <PERSON> Derong </PERSON>, the cigarette factory's deputy director, said they'll double production to 64 million packs a year once the railroad is finished The workers earn an average of $ 405 a year, making them the best paid in town. But the railroad is unlikely to help the 200-employee match factory next door, already hard hit by competition from larger, mechanized factories elsewhere. It shut down for 10 months last year because it had no money to buy wood for matches. <LOCATION> Yenan </LOCATION> officials finally loaned it $ 27,000 _ enough to reopen but not to buy modern machinery that would make it competitive. Elsewhere in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, state-owned factories that lose money are being closed or leased to entrepreneurs under top leader <PERSON> Deng </PERSON> <PERSON> Xiaoping </PERSON>'s decade-old program to stimulate the economy and reduce central controls. But <PERSON> Li </PERSON> said `` no one in <LOCATION> Yenan </LOCATION> has enough money'' to lease the match factory. And it ca n't be shut, officials said, because the workers need the jobs. <LOCATION> Yenan </LOCATION>'s agriculture also needs massive investment, in the form of irrigation canals, to significantly raise production. With less than 16 inches of rain annually, yields are less than half those in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s lush southeast. No efforts are made to encourage the one industry for which <LOCATION> Yenan </LOCATION> is historically equipped: tourism. More than 50 hotels are under construction in <LOCATION> Xian </LOCATION> alone as part of a nationwide tourism boom, but <LOCATION> Yenan </LOCATION> offers only five small guest houses. <LOCATION> Xian </LOCATION>, site of the ancient city of Chang-an, is known for its temples and tombs. Its biggest attraction is the thousands of life-size terra cotta warriors built more than 2,000 years ago to guard the tomb of Emperor <PERSON> Qin </PERSON> <PERSON> Shi </PERSON> <PERSON> Huangdi </PERSON>, who united <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>. Of the 80,000 visitors to <PERSON> Mao </PERSON>'s old headquarters every year, only about 500 are foreigners, who bring far more money than Chinese. <LOCATION> Yenan </LOCATION>'s dust-covered streets are uninviting and things are sleepy. Even a confirmed Marxist like <PERSON> Lei </PERSON> <PERSON> Zhifu </PERSON> said he attends ceremonies at the local <ORGANIZATION> Buddhist </ORGANIZATION> temple `` for excitement.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880224-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-24-88 0333EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-People-HastyPudding     02-24 0196</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-People-Hasty Pudding,0203</SECOND>
<HEAD>Steve Martin Get Hasty Pudding Award</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto BX7 of Feb. 23</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CAMBRIDGE, Mass. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actor-comedian <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> had a question as soon as he received the Hasty Pudding Club Man of the Year award at <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>: `` There is a cash prize for this, right?'' Appearing Tuesday in a rumpled, oversize tuxedo and rubber-soled suede shoes without laces, <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> delighted the audience of nearly 200 when he leaped like a game-show contestant, shouting, `` I won, I won.'' He received a brass pudding pot, but no cash. The nation's oldest undergraduate theatrical organization gave its annual award to <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> for `` his lasting and impressive contribution to the world of entertainment,'' said program co-producer <PERSON> Andrea </PERSON> <PERSON> Campbell </PERSON>. <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> said receiving the award made up for his movie `` Roxanne'' not being nominated for an Oscar this year. `` Yes it does, because it's such a prestigious award, and so few people have gotten one,'' he said. <PERSON> Martin </PERSON>'s first two comedy albums won Grammy awards and he has written and co-starred in such box-office hits as `` The Jerk'' and `` Pennies from Heaven.'' The Hasty Pudding Club awarded <PERSON> Lucille </PERSON> <PERSON> Ball </PERSON> its Woman of the Year award last week.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880224-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-24-88 0335EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-InnovativeJustice     02-24 1143</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Innovative Justice,1175</SECOND>
<HEAD>With Jails Crowded, Judges Look For Sentences To Fit The Crime</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT BARR</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 A judge in <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION> makes some convicts buy newspaper ads to apologize. Slumlords in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> are sentenced to live in their own buildings. In <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION>, executives convicted of securities violations are ordered to read up on ethics, and write reports. Such innovations are sometimes motivated by overflowing jails, but in other cases are intended to tailor the punishment to the crime. On Tuesday, for instance, Circuit Judge <PERSON> Stuart </PERSON> <PERSON> Nudelman </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> sentenced a white man convicted of threatening blacks to do 200 hours of community service with the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assocaition </ORGANIZATION> for the Advancement of Colored People. `` He's going to learn how to be a responsible human being,'' <PERSON> Nudelman </PERSON> said in sentencing <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Kalafut </PERSON>, 22, who was part of a group of whites and Hispanics who menaced two blacks with baseball bats and bottles last year. Last month, <LOCATION> Anne </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arundel </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION> joined a growing number of jurisdictions that are using electronic gadgets to enforce non-jail sentences. The county's program for repeat drunken driving offenders calls for them to continue working, but turn over one-fourth of their pay to the county and spend their free time exclusively at home. To make sure they do, television cameras are installed in the homes, and a jailer calls at random times to make sure the subject is at home. `` There simply is n't enough room in the detention center to lock everyone up,'' explains District Judge <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Curley </PERSON>, who envisions expanding the program to include those convicted of drug abuse, petty thievery or battery. `` The obvious selling point is the cost,'' said <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Grinter </PERSON>, president of <ORGANIZATION> Program </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Monitor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc </ORGANIZATION>. The Dallas-based firm contracts with government agencies to operate monitoring systems, and charges $ 7 per case per day. Program Monitor has only 45 cases in <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> now and is n't making money, <PERSON> Grinter </PERSON> said Tuesday, but he said a state commission estimated in 1986 that as many as 6,000 prisoners might be suitable for electronic monitoring. Program Monitor provided the hardware to monitor a <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> landlord, <PERSON> Morris </PERSON> <PERSON> Gross </PERSON>, who was convicted of multiple building violations and sentenced to live in one of his buildings in <LOCATION> Brooklyn </LOCATION>. He was released last week after spending eight days in his newly plastered and painted apartment in the rundown building. A similar sentence was imposed last year on Dr. <PERSON> Milton </PERSON> <PERSON> Avol </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Beverly </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hills </LOCATION> neurosurgeon convicted of numerous violations in buildings he owned. In other recent cases: _ Multimillionaire industrialist <PERSON> Victor </PERSON> <PERSON> Posner </PERSON>, who pleaded no contest to evading more than $ 1.2 million in federal taxes, was sentenced on Feb. 12 to work 5,000 hours of community service over the next five years. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> Eugene </PERSON> <PERSON> Spellman </PERSON> also ordered the 69-year-old financier to pay $ 4 million in back taxes and penalties, and contribute $ 3 million to programs for the homeless. The maximum sentence for the conviction was in excess of 40 years in prison. `` At your age, I doubt you'd be in jail more than six to nine months regardless of the sentence,'' <PERSON> Spellman </PERSON> said. _ A city judge in <LOCATION> Charleston </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> W. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, ordered a man convicted of destroying a newspaper vending box to spend the next month guarding its replacement <PERSON> Christopher </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>, 25, was sentenced to stand watch from 7 p.m. to 3 a.m. for 30 days. _ Last September, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> Dickinson </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Debevoise </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Newark </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.J. </LOCATION>, sentenced four former executives of a collapsed securities brokerage to read six books about suffering and afflicted people and submit reports after serving prison terms of up to 2 -LCB- years. The executives had pleaded guilty to charges in connection with the collapse of <PERSON> Bevill </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Bresler </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <ORGANIZATION> Schulman </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc </ORGANIZATION>. They testified against a fifth executive, who was convicted and sentenced to eight years in prison. Among the assigned books were <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Steinbeck </PERSON>'s `` The Grapes of Wrath,'' biographies of <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Washington </PERSON> and <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Luther </PERSON> <PERSON> King </PERSON>, and `` Working Your Way to the <LOCATION> Botton </LOCATION> _ The Feminization of Poverty.'' _ In <LOCATION> Lincoln </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ore. </LOCATION>, District Attorney <PERSON> Ulys </PERSON> <PERSON> Stapleton </PERSON> began a program two years ago requiring convicts to apologize for their crimes in community newspapers. One of the first ads was placed by a former sheriff's detective convicted of possessing a controlled substance. Sometimes the experiments do n't pan out. District Judge <PERSON> Dorothy </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Portland </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ore. </LOCATION>, gained national attention when she sentenced child molester <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bateman </PERSON> to post signs on his house and car warning, `` Dangerous Sex Offender. No Children Allowed.'' <PERSON> Bateman </PERSON>, 47, later dropped out of sight for three weeks, was rearrested and sentenced to 10 years in prison. <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION> won an `` innovation in government'' award from the <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION> last year in recognition of its comprehensive program to provide alternatives to jail time. The state has about 18,500 prison inmates, but 109,000 other convicts have been placed in programs ranging from basic probation to boot camp-style life in a diversion center, to 90-day `` shock incarceration'' for offenders aged 17 to 25. Shock incarceration is intended convince violators who have n't been in prison before that they do n't want to come back A study in 1986 found that 23 percent of those who went through shock incarceration committed further crimes, compared to 22 percent for the general prison population, said <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON>, coordinator of the state's diversion programs. `` At first blush you are prone to say there is no appreciable difference,'' <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> said Tuesday, `` but the other way of looking at it is that we can give someone a 90-day prison experience, as opposed to an experience that may last for years, and do no worse.'' In other words, the state gets the same results for less money. In the diversion centers, where the state can accommodate up to 750 people, prisoners work during the day, and pay $ 6.50 a day for board and room. Thus, the state's cost is $ 27.50 a day, compared to $ 37 day for each prison inamte, <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> said. The state also has an intenive probation program, in which probationers have to meet four times a week with an officer. That program is self-supporting, because judges may impose fees up to $ 50 a month as part of the sentence, <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> said. In 1982, <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> said, 63 percent of criminal convicts in <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION> received a probated sentence. In 1985, that had increased to 73 percent. `` If you look at 1981, the state of <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION> had the highest per-capita incarceration rate in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. It exceeded the incarceration rate of the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> and the Union of <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>,'' he said. `` We began putting our emphasis on alternative programs in 1982, and by 1985 we had dropped down to No. 11 in per-capita incarceration rates.'' `` The real issue now,'' he emphasized, `` is that we can not afford to build any more prisons.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880224-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-24-88 0335EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Networks-Reagan     02-24 0049</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Networks-Reagan,0051</SECOND>
<HEAD>Networks Covering Reagan News Conference</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> CNN </ORGANIZATION> all plan to televise President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s news conference tonight. <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> said it will interrupt its coverage of the Winter Olympics in <LOCATION> Calgary </LOCATION> to televise the news conference live at 8 p.m. EST.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880224-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-24-88 0002EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>b p AM-Dole-Minnesota     02-24 0036</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Dole-Minnesota,30</SECOND>
<HEAD>BULLETIN</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MINNEAPOLIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Sen. <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> defeated former television evangelist <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> to win <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION>'s Republican presidential caucuses Tuesday night, with Vice President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> a distant fourth behind Rep. <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880224-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-24-88 0337EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-ElleryQueen     02-24 0334</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Ellery Queen,0344</SECOND>
<HEAD>Mystery Collection Goes To Columbia</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By JERRY SCHWARTZ</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Two men were dead; valuable manuscripts had changed hands; false names were involved. The mystery was solved Tuesday as <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> announced that it had been given the papers of <PERSON> Ellery </PERSON> <PERSON> Queen </PERSON>, the dashing, upper-crust detective whose adventures helped elevate American detective fiction to an art form. <PERSON> Ellery </PERSON> <PERSON> Queen </PERSON> was created by Brooklyn-born cousins <PERSON> Frederic </PERSON> <PERSON> Dannay </PERSON> and <PERSON> Manfred </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Lee </PERSON>, who entered a 1928 mystery contest that required a pseudonym. They invented <PERSON> Queen </PERSON> and made him both author and protagonist, thinking an author would be better remembered if his name appeared throughout the book. More than 40 <PERSON> Ellery </PERSON> <PERSON> Queen </PERSON> novels were written before <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> died in 1971. His partner, <PERSON> Dannay </PERSON>, died in 1982, and <PERSON> Dannay </PERSON>'s sons <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> and <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON> gave the <PERSON> Ellery </PERSON> <PERSON> Queen </PERSON> papers to <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION>. The manuscripts show that <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> and <PERSON> Dannay </PERSON> often were at odds over their work, with intense disagreements and personality clashes. There are extensive revisions; in one case, 50 pages were deleted from a novel. `` We're not so much collaborators as competitors. It has produced a sharper edge,'' <PERSON> Dannay </PERSON> once said. The 25,000-item collection includes the only surviving manuscript of the first <PERSON> Ellery </PERSON> <PERSON> Queen </PERSON> novel, `` The Roman Hat Mystery,'' and the notes, outlines and corrected manuscripts of the last, `` A Fine and Private Place.'' Also included are letters and manuscripts of <PERSON> Dashiell </PERSON> <PERSON> Hammett </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Cornell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Woolrich </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Dickson </PERSON> <PERSON> Carr </PERSON>, <PERSON> Agatha </PERSON> <PERSON> Christie </PERSON> and others whose work already can be found in <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION>'s archive of mystery and detective writing. The <PERSON> Ellery </PERSON> <PERSON> Queen </PERSON> novels led to a series of movies, radio and television shows, and to <PERSON> Ellery </PERSON> <PERSON> Queen </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> Mystery </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Magazine </ORGANIZATION>, which first appeared in 1941 and is still published monthly. The <PERSON> Ellery </PERSON> <PERSON> Queen </PERSON> archives include the first issue of the magazine, along with manuscripts from such contributors as <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Faulkner </PERSON>. Selections from the archives will be on exhibit at <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION>'s Butler Library from March 3 to July 6
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880224-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-24-88 0341EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-HouseDetention     02-24 0681</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-House Detention,0700</SECOND>
<HEAD>County Launches Video House Detention Program For Drunken Drivers</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in report for Wednesday AMs.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By JOHN ROLL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ANNAPOLIS, Md. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Repeat drunken drivers convicted in a new program are being allowed to keep their jobs, but as soon as the whistle blows they must go home, stay home and stay sober. Big brother will be watching, and calling. <LOCATION> Anne </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arundel </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> has invested $ 15,000 in 30 video monitoring systems, which are installed in offenders' homes and linked by telephone lines to a master control in the county jail. Under the program launched Jan. 26, offenders are not watched all the time, but they never know when a jail officer will call and ask them to step before the camera. `` A lot of people say I got off easy, but you're stopped in your tracks at the front door,'' said one of the first four men sentenced under the program, a three-time offender who agreed to be interviewed on condition his name not be used. `` It's not exactly a slap on the wrist, but it's better than sitting in jail.'' For this offender, the hardest part of the program is turning over $ 336 a month _ one-fourth of his salary _ to the county during his 90-day sentence. `` It's a big dent in our pocket,'' said his wife. An operator at the the jail dials each offender once, and often twice, a night and instructs him to turn on the video equipment and stand in front of the camera. The county also has purchased hand-held breath analyzers to make sure the offender is complying with a judge's no-drinking stipulation. The equipment displays alcohol levels in bright red numerals that can be read over the TV monitor. House detainees also are required to turn over one-quarter of their take-home pay to the county. If an offender's home does n't have an adequate telephone jack, he has to pay for one Violation of any condition brings a jail sentence. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Sellers </PERSON>, government marketing coordinator for <ORGANIZATION> Mitsubishi </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Electric </ORGANIZATION>, said the VisiTel system has been used in several states to monitor probationers, but he said <LOCATION> Anne </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arundel </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> is apparently the first to use the system as an alternative to prison sentences. At least 11 manufacturers are marketing systems, according to the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION>. The program has been endorsed by the local chapter of Mothers Against Drunk Driving. <PERSON> Jean </PERSON> <PERSON> Heald </PERSON>, president of the group, said that when the program is combined with an alcohol counseling program it may help make highways safer. `` We're hopeful. Sending them to jail we know does n't work,'' said Ms. <PERSON> Heald </PERSON>, who said the program is in keeping with a philosophy of `` punishment for the crime, treatment for the disease and monitoring for the citizen.'' County officials plan to review the program in the next few weeks and decide whether to buy 90 additional monitors this smmer. District Judge <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Curley </PERSON> drug users, petty thieves and those convicted of minor battery charges are also likely candidates for house detention. Asked if he expects public opposition, <PERSON> Curley </PERSON> was frank: `` Are you kidding? Nothing is ever tough enough for them. But I have to live in the real world.'' House detention is an alternative to paying up to $ 40 a day to keep a prisoner in the county jail, as well as putting off the cost of constructing new prisons. `` There simply is n't enough room in the detention center to lock everyone up,'' said <PERSON> Curley </PERSON>. Electronically enforced home-detention programs have expanded rapidly since the first reported test in <LOCATION> Albuquerque </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.M. </LOCATION>, in 1983. As of last February, according to the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION>, an arm of the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, 53 house-detention programs in 21 states electronically monitored more than 800 offenders. Most programs rely on electronic bracelets that signal when an offender has strayed from home. The institute reported that offenders in such programs tended to be males under the age of 30. About one-third were convicted of serious traffic violations, particularly drunken driving. Another large category included parolees and probationers.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880224-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-24-88 0029EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Israel-Pipeline 1stLd-Writethru a0734 02-24 0730</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Israel-Pipeline, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0734,0745</SECOND>
<HEAD>Peres: No Need For Bribes Because Israel Supported Pipeline</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Leads with 7 grafs to UPDATE with Peres reportedly saying
Israeli was offered discount on oil from proposed pipeline. Pickup
6th graf ``The memo...''
^With AM-Israel, Bjt</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By KARIN LAUB</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NABLUS, Occupied West Bank (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Foreign Minister <PERSON> Shimon </PERSON> <PERSON> Peres </PERSON> on Tuesday denounced as `` complete nonsense'' a memo that described plans to funnel millions of dollars to his <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> for assurances that <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> would not bomb a proposed Iraqi pipeline. The 1985 memo, made public Monday, was addressed to <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Attorney General <PERSON> Edwin </PERSON> <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON> and written by <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Wallach </PERSON>, a longtime <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> friend and lawyer for Swiss oilman <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Rappaport </PERSON>, a partner in the pipeline project. The $ 1 billion pipeline was to have carried oil from <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> through <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION> to the Gulf of <LOCATION> Aqaba </LOCATION>, but was never built. <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> officials `` all agreed that we favored the laying of the pipeline. So why would anyone need to use bribes?'' <PERSON> Peres </PERSON> told reporters during a tour of the occupied <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION>'s largest city. `` I do n't understand this.'' However, <PERSON> Peres </PERSON> through a spokesman in <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION> acknowledged Tuesday that the Israeli government had been offered a discount on oil purchases amounting to $ 65 million to $ 70 million a year in return for approving the pipeline, <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> reported in Wednesday's editions. But the aide said that <PERSON> Peres </PERSON> did not take the offer seriously and failed to pass it on to colleagues, the newspaper said. He said the offer was made by <PERSON> Rappaport </PERSON> but there was no proposal for paying part of the discount to <PERSON> Peres </PERSON>' party, the Post reported. An Israeli military analyst on Tuesday told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> it would not have been in <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s interest to destroy the pipeline because <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> has sought a dialogue with <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> to counter growing hostility from <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>. The memo said <PERSON> Rappaport </PERSON> `` confirmed the arrangement with <PERSON> Peres </PERSON> to the effect that <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> will receive somewhere between $ 65 million and $ 70 million a year for 10 years out of the conclusion of the project.'' `` What also was indicated to me,'' <PERSON> Wallach </PERSON> wrote to <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>, `` and which would be denied everywhere, is that a portion of those funds will go directly to Labor.'' The memo is central to a criminal investigation of <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>. At issue is whether <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> knew of a possibly improper payment plan involving the <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> and, if so, why he did nothing about it. In a handwritten note from <PERSON> Peres </PERSON> to <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>, also made public Monday, the <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> leader said of the pipeline project: `` I would go a long way to help it out. But then discretion is demanded on our part.'' Asked about the Wallach-Meese memo, <PERSON> Peres </PERSON> said: `` No one said he gave the <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> anything or proposed anything to the <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>. As far as I'm concerned, it's complete nonsense.'' Earlier, a <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> aide close to <PERSON> Peres </PERSON> told The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>: `` Mr. <PERSON> Peres </PERSON> did not see a penny out of this, and neither did the <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>.'' `` We repeatedly have denied the whole story,'' he said, speaking on condition of anonymity. `` No money was offered to Mr. <PERSON> Peres </PERSON> and if it had been, he would have thrown the man out the window.'' Another ministry official told The <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> that several <ORGANIZATION> Cabinet </ORGANIZATION> ministers privately discussed the pipeline project, but no decision about <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s position was ever made. <PERSON> Dore </PERSON> <PERSON> Gold </PERSON>, a researcher at <ORGANIZATION> Tel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aviv </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Jaffee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Strategic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Studies </ORGANIZATION>, said bombing the project would not have been in <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s interest, but <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> probably `` sought as many assurances as possible regarding a pipeline that would come so close to Israeli borders.'' <PERSON> Gold </PERSON> said <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> has sought to open a dialogue with <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> to counter growing hostility from <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> following that country's 1979 Islamic fundamentalist revolution. For example, <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> several years ago made an offer to <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> to reactivate a pipeline built in the 1930s from the <LOCATION> Iraqi </LOCATION> city <LOCATION> Kirkuk </LOCATION> to the <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> port city of <LOCATION> Haifa </LOCATION>. Gold said <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> never responded to the offer. But <PERSON> Zeev </PERSON> <PERSON> Eytan </PERSON>, another <ORGANIZATION> Jaffee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> researcher, said <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> had good reason to oppose the <LOCATION> Iraqi </LOCATION> pipeline because it would have turned the Jordanian city of <LOCATION> Aqaba </LOCATION> into an oil port and destroyed the economic base of the neighboring <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> resort Elat. <PERSON> Said </PERSON> <PERSON> Eytan </PERSON>: `` We need this like we need stones in the -LRB- occupied -RRB- territories.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880224-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-24-88 0350EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-AbsenteeAdventists     02-24 0282</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Absentee Adventists,0289</SECOND>
<HEAD>Judge: Adventists, Others Can Cast Absentee Ballots In Saturday
Elections</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CLARKSBURG, W.Va. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 People who observe the Sabbath on Saturdays have the right to cast absentee ballots in elections held on Saturdays, a federal judge ruled. In a case arising from <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>'s March 5 constitutional amendment election, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kidd </PERSON> issued a preliminary injunction Tuesday in favor of two Seventh-day Adventists who had been told they could not submit absentee ballots for the Saturday voting. The ruling also affects Jews, Seventh-day Baptists, and members of other religious groups who believe that they should not participate in any civic, business, governmental or non-essential work on Saturdays. <PERSON> Karen </PERSON> and <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> <PERSON> Conner </PERSON>, school bus drivers in <LOCATION> Barbour </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, contended that because of their religious beliefs, they were being deprived of their right to vote on a proposed amendment that would establish a statewide property tax for education. <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> usually holds elections on Tuesdays, but moved this one to Saturday in hopes of boosting turnout. The election was set after a state court ruled that the state must equalize spending among school systems. The Conners were told by the secretary of state's office that they did not qualify for absentee voting under state law. They then filed suit in state court against Secretary of State <PERSON> Ken </PERSON> <PERSON> Hechler </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> Barbour </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Circuit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Clerk </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Jean </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Green </ORGANIZATION>. The state <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> earlier this month refused to hear the case, so the <PERSON> Conners </PERSON> took it to the federal court. <PERSON> Kidd </PERSON> ordered <PERSON> Hechler </PERSON> to submit by Friday a plan `` outlining measures to be taken to ensure that plaintiffs and members of this class are permitted to vote in the forthcoming election.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880224-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-24-88 0237EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     02-24 0801</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0830</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names In The News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NASHVILLE, Tenn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Radio personality Wolfman <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> has been named host of a new `` Rock' n' Roll Palace'' cable television show on The <ORGANIZATION> Nashville </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Network </ORGANIZATION>. The weekly 30-minute program beginning April 2 will feature music stars from the 1950s and 1960s, including the Coasters, the <LOCATION> Shirelles </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Del </PERSON> <PERSON> Shannon </PERSON>, the Diamonds, <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Revere </PERSON>, <PERSON> Bobby </PERSON> <PERSON> Vee </PERSON>, the Comets, and <PERSON> Joey </PERSON> <PERSON> Dee </PERSON> and the Starliters, <ORGANIZATION> TNN </ORGANIZATION> announced Tuesday. Wolfman <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> was host of the `` Midnight Special'' show on <ORGANIZATION> NBC-TV </ORGANIZATION> for nine years and now has various radio programs. He played himself in the movie `` American Graffiti.'' His new show will be taped at <LOCATION> Little </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Darlin </LOCATION>'s Rock' n' Roll Palace in <LOCATION> Kissimmee </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>Eds: Version of the following item moved on sports wires.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Basketball star <PERSON> Earvin </PERSON> `` Magic'' <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> told 1,200 teen-agers that he never should have dropped out of college and still intends to get his degree. <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>, who led the <ORGANIZATION> Los </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Angeles </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lakers </ORGANIZATION> to four <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Basketball </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> championships in his eight years with the club, spoke to a cheering throng Monday at <ORGANIZATION> Westchester </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> High </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION>, which has a 30 percent dropout rate. `` I am 40 hours short of my degree in telecommunications, but I intend to get it,'' he said. `` My first year of high school, I was hoopin' good,'' recalled <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> of his childhood in <LOCATION> Lansing </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mich. </LOCATION> `` But my grades were real low. My counselor pulled on my coattails and told me, ` You are getting Ds and Cs and Es. You wo n't go to college and play ball if you do n't pull'em up.'' There were a few gasps from the audience. `` If she did n't get to me I might not be standing here rapping to you. I might be somewhere else. It's never too late to get yourself together.'' Asked about his future, <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> said he hoped to play five or six more years with the <ORGANIZATION> Lakers </ORGANIZATION>, `` then I'd like to get into my businesses. Hopefully, I will own a building 18-20 stories high and maybe hire a few of you.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Jazz pianist-composer <PERSON> Billy </PERSON> <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON> says money spent sending <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> artists to festivals abroad is money well spent. `` In traveling to places like a jazz festival in <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>, I've seen <LOCATION> Russia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION>, sent their best,'' <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON> said Tuesday Other nations know about American music through records, but `` that knowledge is flawed if they do n't get some of our very best. We have to find measures to at least be competitive in this way.'' <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON> was attending an announcement by the <ORGANIZATION> Rockefeller </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Information </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Endowment </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> the </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Arts </ORGANIZATION> of a fund to support the sending of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> artists to international festivals and exhibitions. `` One of the things I find, traveling around the world, is that I become intensely patriotic,'' said <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Aston </PERSON> <PERSON> Martin </PERSON>, the U.S.-owned purveyor of expensive sports cars, kept up its ties with the <LOCATION> British </LOCATION> royal family by giving scaled-down cars to the young sons of Prince <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> and Princess <PERSON> Diana </PERSON>. Company chairman and chief executive <PERSON> Victor </PERSON> <PERSON> Gauntlett </PERSON> made the presentation Tuesday. But 5-year-old Prince <PERSON> William </PERSON> and 3-year-old Prince <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> may have to wait a while before getting behind the wheels. Asked if his children are ready to drive, the Prince of <LOCATION> Wales </LOCATION> said, `` Gracious, no.'' The 8.5-foot-long, 4 @ 7-scale <PERSON> Aston </PERSON> <PERSON> Martins </PERSON> each cost about $ 17,500. They are equipped with stereo radios and cassette players, electrically powered aerials, five-speed gearboxes, leather upholstery, headlights and turn signals. <ORGANIZATION> Aston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Martin </ORGANIZATION>, which is controlled by the American manufacturer <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION>, said the junior cars are like the <ORGANIZATION> Aston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Martin </ORGANIZATION> V-8 Volante that <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> drives in virtually every detail. Instead of a V-8 British-built engine capable of a maximum speed of 153 mph, however, they are powered by a <ORGANIZATION> Honda </ORGANIZATION> engine made in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> and tuned to reach 25 mph.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>ST. JOSEPH, Mo. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Norman </PERSON> <PERSON> Loyd </PERSON>, who plays the grandfatherly Dr. <PERSON> Auschlander </PERSON> in television's `` St. Elsewhere,'' has joined a hospital's drive to recruit nurses. `` I must say this is a little nicer than St. Elsewhere,'' the fictional inner-city <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> hospital featured in the <ORGANIZATION> NBC-TV </ORGANIZATION> series, <PERSON> Loyd </PERSON> observed Tuesday as he walked down the corridor at <LOCATION> Heartland </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION>. `` I think I'll ask them to change the set.'' <PERSON> Loyd </PERSON> will star in a 10-minute video to be distributed nationwide in <LOCATION> Heartland </LOCATION>'s search for nursing personnel. He took time between takes to shake hands with Heartland employees. `` Having him in it will be an attention getter _ something we hope will catch the eye of nurses who might be looking for a position,'' said <PERSON> Debi </PERSON> <PERSON> Yancer </PERSON>, associate director of patient care services. The video will be shown at career days, placement fairs and at recruitment dinners that have been spurred by the nationwide shortage of nurses.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880224-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-24-88 0027EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>b p AM-Dukakis-Minnesota     02-24 0044</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Dukakis-Minnesota,30</SECOND>
<HEAD>BULLETIN</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MINNEAPOLIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> won the <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION> Democratic presidential caucuses Tuesday night in a demonstration of voter appeal outside his native <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> and <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> were locked in a tight race for second-place.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880224-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-24-88 0316EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Nielsens     02-24 0381</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nielsens,0390</SECOND>
<HEAD>ABC Collects Ratings Gold for its Olympics Coverage</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JERRY BUCK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Television Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> has swept to victory and ratings gold with its coverage of the Winter Olympics. Its Olympic telecasts for the week that ended Sunday captured four of the top 10 place in the <ORGANIZATION> A.C. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nielsen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> ratings and won the week for <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>. <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> also moved ahead of <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> and into first place for the February sweeps and into second place ahead of CBS for the season-to-date. It kept its first-place position among the evening news shows. The `` CBS Evening News,'' which had dominated that category for the entire season until last week, finished second. <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, whose eight-hour miniseries `` Noble House'' managed to win only 16th place, was second for the week. Its highly rated comedy shows did well, but were pushed down a few notches by the Olympics. <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, which usually takes third place, won the <ORGANIZATION> A.C. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nielsen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> ratings for the week with an average of 19.4. <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> was second with 15.0 and <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> was third with 12.8. For the season-to-date, <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> now has a 16.3 rating, <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> 13.8, CBS 13.6. The rating is the percentage of the nation's 88.6 million households with televisions. It was only <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s third weekly victory of the season, which began in September. It won on Super Bowl and World Series weeks. Last week's top 10 shows were: <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s Tuesday Olympics; <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` The Cosby Show''; <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s Saturday Olympics; <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` A Different World''; CBS' `` 60 Minutes''; <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Cheers''; <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s Wednesday Olympics; CBS' `` Murder, She Wrote''; <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s Thursday Olympics; and <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Family Ties'' and `` ALF,'' which tied <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> was ahead in this month's <PERSON> Nielsen </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> Arbitron </ORGANIZATION> sweeps ratings. The sweeps are periods during which the ratings of the nation's television stations are measured. The <ORGANIZATION> Fox </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Broadcasting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, which has fewer stations than the three other commercial networks, also got good news. Its `` 21 Jump Street'' had its highest rating to date with 6.6, placing it ahead of the three lowest-rated network shows. `` Married With Children'' got a 5.7 rating, its highest ever, coming in higher than the two bottom network shows. `` Werewolf'' got its highest rating ever in its 8 p.m. time period, 5.1, which would give it a tie with the networks' lowest-rated show.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880224-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-24-88 0317EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-NielsensList     02-24 0564</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nielsens List,0630</SECOND>
<HEAD>List of Week's Top-Rated TV Shows</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Nielsens</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the prime-time television ratings as compiled by the <ORGANIZATION> A.C. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nielsen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> for the week of Feb. 15-21. Top 20 listings include the week's ranking, with full season-to-date ranking in parentheses, rating for the week, and total homes. An `` X'' in parentheses denotes one-time-only presentation. A rating measures the percentage of the nation's 88.6 million TV homes. 1. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Winter Olympics-Tuesday,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 25.5 rating, 22.6 million homes. 2. -LRB- 1 -RRB- `` The Cosby Show,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 23.6, 20.9 million homes. 3. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Winter Olympics-Saturday,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 21.3, 18.9 million homes. 4. -LRB- 2 -RRB- `` A Different World,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 20.3, 18.0 million homes. 5. -LRB- 8 -RRB- `` 60 Minutes,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 20.2, 17.9 million homes. 6. -LRB- 3 -RRB- `` Cheers,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 19.4, 17.2 million homes. 7. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Winter Olympics-Wednesday,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 19.3, 17.1 million homes. 8. -LRB- 9 -RRB- `` Murder, She Wrote,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 19.1, 16.9 million homes. 9. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Winter Olympics-Thursday,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 18.9, 16.7 million homes. 10. -LRB- 12 -RRB- `` ALF,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 18.6, 16.5 million homes. 10. -LRB- 13 -RRB- `` Family Ties,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 18.6, 16.5 million homes. 12. -LRB- 15 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Matlock </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 18.3, 16.2 million homes. 12. -LRB- 4 -RRB- `` Night Court,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 18.3, 16.2 million homes. 14. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Winter Olympics-Monday,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 18.1, 16.0 million homes. 15. -LRB- 6 -RRB- `` Golden Girls,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 18.0, 15.9 million homes. 16. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Noble House,'' Part 1, <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 17.9, 15.8 million homes. 17. -LRB- 11 -RRB- `` <LOCATION> L.A. </LOCATION> Law,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 17.2, 15.2 million homes. 18. -LRB- 18 -RRB- `` <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION>,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 17.1, 15.2 million homes. 18. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Winter Olympics-Sunday,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 17.1, 15.2 million homes. 20. -LRB- 21 -RRB- `` My Two Dads,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 17.0, 15.1 million homes.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 21. -LRB- 36 -RRB- `` Highway to Heaven,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 16.8. 21. -LRB- 25 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Newhart </PERSON>,'' CBS, 16.8. 23. -LRB- 18 -RRB- `` The Return of Desperado'' _ `` <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> Monday Night Movies,'' 16.0. 24. -LRB- 18 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Valerie </PERSON>'s Family,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 15.6. 25. -LRB- 31 -RRB- `` Knots Landing,'' CBS, 15.5. 26. -LRB- 29 -RRB- `` Designing Women,'' CBS, 15.3. 27. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Winter Olympics-Friday,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 15.1. 28. -LRB- 43 -RRB- `` Beauty and the <LOCATION> Beast </LOCATION>,'' CBS, 15.0. 28. -LRB- 15 -RRB- `` Bring the Head of <PERSON> Dobie </PERSON> <PERSON> Gillis </PERSON>'' _ `` CBS Sunday Movie,'' 15.0. 30. -LRB- 37 -RRB- `` <LOCATION> Falcon </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Crest </LOCATION>,'' CBS, 14.5. 30. -LRB- 34 -RRB- `` Kate & amp; <PERSON> Allie </PERSON>,'' CBS, 14.5. 32. -LRB- 23 -RRB- `` 227,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 14.2. 33. -LRB- 14 -RRB- `` Amen,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 14.0. 34. -LRB- 40 -RRB- `` <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> Vice,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.6. 35. -LRB- 27 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Hunter </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.5. 36. -LRB- 52 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Frank </PERSON>'s Place,'' CBS, 13.2. 37. -LRB- 35 -RRB- `` Facts of Life,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.0. 37. -LRB- 46 -RRB- `` St. Elsewhere,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.0. 39. -LRB- 44 -RRB- `` <PERSON> J.J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Starbuck </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.8. 40. -LRB- 48 -RRB- `` <ORGANIZATION> Simon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> Simon </PERSON>,'' CBS, 12.6. 41. -LRB- 39 -RRB- `` Magnum, P.I.,'' CBS, 12.4. 42. -LRB- 57 -RRB- `` Our House,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.0. 42. -LRB- 53 -RRB- `` A Year in the Life,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.0. 44. -LRB- 44 -RRB- `` <ORGANIZATION> Cagney </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> Lacey </PERSON>,'' CBS, 11.9. 44. -LRB- 50 -RRB- `` The Equalizer,'' CBS, 11.9. 44. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Disney's DTV Doggone Hits,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.9. 44. -LRB- 62 -RRB- `` Tour of Duty,' CBS, 11.9. 48. -LRB- 59 -RRB- `` Wiseguy,'' CBS, 11.4. 49. -LRB- 57 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Sonny </PERSON> <PERSON> Spoon </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.3. 50. -LRB- 53 -RRB- `` High Mountain Rangers,'' CBS, 10.2. 51. -LRB- 55 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Jake </PERSON> and The Fatman,'' CBS, 9.6. 52. -LRB- 70 -RRB- `` <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION> Knights,'' CBS, 9.3. 53. -LRB- X -RRB- `` 20th Anniversary of Clown College,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 8.8. 54. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` 21 Jump Street,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 6.6. 55. -LRB- 80 -RRB- `` West 57th,'' CBS, 6.2. 56. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` Married ... With Children,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 5.7. 57. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Decision ` 88: <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 5.4. 58. -LRB- 76 -RRB- `` 48 Hours,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 5.1. 58. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` Werewolf,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 5.1. 60. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` <PERSON> Tracey </PERSON> <PERSON> Ullman </PERSON> Show,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 3.2. 61. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` Duet,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 3.1. 62. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` Boys Will Be Boys,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 2.8. 63. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` Women in Prison,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 2.6. 64. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` The New Adventures of Beans Baxter,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 2.0. 65. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` Mr. President,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 1.9.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880224-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-24-88 0345EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-HijackingSuspect     02-24 0601</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Hijacking Suspect,600</SECOND>
<HEAD>Judge Criticizes FBI Inattention To Due Process</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JAMES ROWLEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> agents illegally interrogated a suspected Lebanese terrorist about a 1985 airplane hijacking when they kept him aboard a <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> ship four days after his arrest in the <LOCATION> Mediterranean </LOCATION>, a federal judge says. Sharply critical of the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION>'s arrest and interrogation of <PERSON> Fawaz </PERSON> <PERSON> Younis </PERSON>, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> Barrington </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Parker </PERSON> on Tuesday ruled that oral and written confessions were obtained illegally from the defendant. The judge suppressed the statements as evidence against <PERSON> Younis </PERSON>, who is charged with leading five armed men who hijacked a Royal Jordanian airliner on June 11, 1985, at <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> International Airport. The trial is scheduled to begin March 22 before <PERSON> Parker </PERSON>. The operation occurred after former <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> Director <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Webster </PERSON> had moved on to head the <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> and before <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Sessions </PERSON>, the bureau's current head, took office last fall. Defense lawyer <PERSON> Francis </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> said he was pleased with the decision but conceded it wo n't necessarily help <PERSON> Younis </PERSON>' case. Prosecutors have a variety of other evidence, including a videotape of <PERSON> Younis </PERSON> delivering a statement to reporters before the plane was blown up in the background. <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> <PERSON> Revell </PERSON>, the bureau's executive assistant director, participated in the arrest of <PERSON> Younis </PERSON> last Sept. 13 in waters off <LOCATION> Cyprus </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Parker </PERSON> concluded that fractures <PERSON> Younis </PERSON> suffered on both wrists were sustained when he was grabbed by two agents and slammed onto the deck of an FBI-chartered yacht, to which he had been lured by the prospect of a drug deal. Throbbing pain from the fractured wrists, sea sickness and the lack of proper medical treatment `` placed him at a distinct disadvantage where he could scarcely understand intelligently his rights as explained and translated to him, much less be able to voluntarily waive them.'' The <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> agents gave <PERSON> Younis </PERSON> the only warning of his constitutional right to remain silent shortly after he arrived seasick on the USS Butte, a munitions boat that steamed four days before meeting with the aircraft carrier USS Saratoga, <PERSON> Parker </PERSON> noted. `` They saw and knew that he was in a weakened state and susceptible to persuasion,'' <PERSON> Parker </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Younis </PERSON> was kept in a windowless overheated room during the voyage, which <PERSON> Parker </PERSON> called `` a clear abuse of the obligation to bring the defendant before a judicial officer immediately following his arrest.'' The ship's `` slow voyage across the <LOCATION> Mediterranean </LOCATION> appeared to serve only the government's purposes _ ample time to educe a confession,'' <PERSON> Parker </PERSON> said in his 47-page opinion. Only after his arrival in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> were <PERSON> Younis </PERSON>' fractured wrists `` correctly diagnosed and appropriately treated,'' the judge said. `` We are reviewing the decision carefully,'' <PERSON> Timothy </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Reardon </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>, principal assistant <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> attorney, said in a statement. <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> officials declined to comment on the decision, said spokeswoman <PERSON> Susan </PERSON> <PERSON> Schnitzer </PERSON>. The judge said he was also `` extremely troubled'' by the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION>'s failure to provide <PERSON> Younis </PERSON> with a lawyer during the interrogation, particularly since the operation to arrest him had been carefully planned `` The government was not just bringing another defendant into the station house for questioning,'' he said, also criticizing the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> for not using a video camera to record the interrogations. In addition to the videotape of <PERSON> Younis </PERSON> at the scene, the government also plans to present testimony from two Americans who were among the passengers and crew taken off the plane before its destruction. The <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> also can rely on the testimony of <PERSON> Jamal </PERSON> <PERSON> Hamdan </PERSON>, a one-time friend of <PERSON> Younis </PERSON> who lured him onto the yacht. <PERSON> Hamdan </PERSON>, who lived in <LOCATION> Cyprus </LOCATION>, secretly taped conversations he had with <PERSON> Younis </PERSON> about the hijacking.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880224-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-24-88 0346EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Women'sStatue     02-24 0500</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Women's Statue,510</SECOND>
<HEAD>What Next After a Women's Statue at Vietnam Memorial?</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto WX6</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT M. ANDREWS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Now that a sculpture of three battle-weary infantrymen stands near the <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> Veterans Memorial, some senators want to place a bronze statue of an <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> nurse nearby to honor the 10,000 women who served in the <LOCATION> Southeast </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION> conflict. Several leading veterans' organizations applaud the proposal by <PERSON> Sens </PERSON>. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Durenberger </PERSON>, R-Minn., and <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Cranston </PERSON>, D-Calif But <PERSON> Maya </PERSON> <PERSON> Lin </PERSON>, the young woman architect who designed the memorial, is n't happy. `` I can not see where it will all end,'' she said at a <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> hearing Tuesday. `` What is to stop someone from trying to add a female statue to the Iwo Jima Memorial?'' Ms. <PERSON> Lin </PERSON> was supported by others who warned that unless officials stop caving in to pressure for more additions, the <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> memorial will turn into a `` sculpture garden'' of special interests ranging from native Americans to scout dogs. <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Arts </ORGANIZATION> which rejected the women's statue proposal last October, said the original memorial _ now bearing the names of 58,156 war dead including eight nurses on its black granite walls _ symbolically includes all <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> veterans. He said the addition of the sculpture of three infantrymen triggered envy among other groups who felt left out. His commission believed that `` including a white, <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> nurse would only continue and exacerbate that process of exclusion,'' he said. At a crowded hearing by a <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Natural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Resources </ORGANIZATION> subcommittee, <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Doubek </PERSON>, former executive director of the Vietnam Veterans Memorial Fund, said a woman's sculpture would `` destroy the symbolism and aesthetics of the memorial.'' But <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Wheeler </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>, chairman of the private fund which raised $ 11 million to build the memorial, supported the nurse's statue and discounted `` the threat of a sculpture garden'' cited by critics <PERSON> Donna-Marie </PERSON> <PERSON> Boulay </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Minneapolis </LOCATION> lawyer who served in <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> as an <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> nurse, testified that the statue should be erected because nurses shared `` the intensity, the trauma, the carnage of war'' with infantrymen. She is chairman and co-founder of the Vietnam Women's Memorial Project, a non-profit organization founded in 1984. <PERSON> Durenberger </PERSON>'s bill, which has 56 <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> co-sponsors, specifies that after a woman's statue is placed at the 2.2-acre site near the Lincoln Memorial, `` the <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> Veterans Memorial will be complete and no further additions to the site should be authorized or undertaken.'' The bill, if enacted, would require the three agencies whose approval is required _ the <ORGANIZATION> Interior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, the fine arts commission and the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Capital </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Planning </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> _ to reconsider the proposal within 90 days. The statue has been approved by the <ORGANIZATION> Interior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> but rejected by the other two agencies. The memorial, which is administered by the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Park </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>, has become the most popular tourist attraction among all the federal monuments in the capital. An estimated 20 million people have visited the memorial since it was dedicated in 1982.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880224-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-24-88 0310EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-PublicWorks Bjt   02-24 0724</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Public Works, Bjt,720</SECOND>
<NOTE>For release 10:30 a.m. EST; time set by source</NOTE>
<HEAD>U.S. Falling Down on the Public Works Job</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By H. JOSEF HEBERT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s commitment to necessities such as transportation, water supply and waste disposal is barely adequate and will fall far short of future needs without sharply increased spending on public works, a federal council warned today. The report to the president and <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> calls for twice as much annual capital spending for public works projects over the next dozen years and suggests a broad range of possible money sources from higher federal fuel taxes to local `` impact fees'' on developers. `` In most cases we can not rely simply on wiser spending. We also must generate additional sources of funding,'' declared the report by the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> on </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Works </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Improvement </ORGANIZATION>. The council was established by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> four years ago to take a close look at the nation's problems with its `` infrastructure,'' a bureaucratic term covering a variety of public projects from highway and airport construction to water management and disposal of toxic wastes. `` The quality of <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s infrastructure today is barely adequate to meet current requirements and insufficient to meet the demands of future economic growth,'' the report concludes. The group acknowledged that major increases in spending for public works may be difficult amid growing federal budget pressures, and perhaps even impossible until the federal budget deficit is reduced. But it said such spending `` must rank high among our priorities.'' In a report card on each major type of public works, the council gave no failing grades but suggested that a far better job needs to be done in all areas. The country's battle to deal with toxic wastes was given a D, and a C or C-minus was awarded for coping with mass transit, solid waste disposal and waste water treatment needs. Managing water resources was given a B, the best grade, followed by B-minuses for aviation and water supply management. `` In general the aviation system has handled rapid increases in demand safely and effectively. ... Congestion is the system's primary problem,'' said the council Discussing hazardous wastes, the council said that while spending to clean up contaminated sites has increased fivefold in the last two years, `` only a small fraction of the 2 tons of waste per capita produced in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> each year is being treated safely.'' On water quality, the council suggested that governments at all levels have been fighting a losing battle. `` Despite -LRB- a -RRB- $ 44 billion federal investment in sewage treatment since 1972, water quality has not improved significantly. ... due in part to uncontrolled sources of pollution such as run-off from farmland and roadways,'' said the report. Overall capital spending for public works projects totaled $ 45 billion in 1985, the latest year for which figures were available. The council said the amount of spending by all levels of government and the private sector will have to double by the end of this century if future needs are to be met. The report said overall spending on public works has declined from 3.6 percent of gross national product in 1960 to 2.6 percent in 1985. While spending on operations and maintenance has kept pace with economic growth, capital spending has fallen from 2.3 percent of GNP to 1.1 percent. Government spending for public works at all levels has declined from 20 percent of total government spending in 1950 to 7 percent in 1984, the report continued. `` In effect we're drawing down past investments without making commensurate investments of our own,'' said the report. `` Failure to reverse this decline will exact a high price for the nation in the future both in the cost of deferred investment and in reduced economic competitiveness.'' The council endorsed the `` general principle'' that users and beneficiaries of public works projects, including developers, be required to pay a greater share of the cost of such projects. It also criticized the hoarding of money in various federal public works trust funds so that the federal budget deficit will appear smaller. In 1987 the unspent balances in the federal highway, transit, aviation and waterway trust funds totaled nearly $ 24 billion, the council said. `` Federal user fees paid in good faith by beneficiaries to preserve and protect public works systems -LRB- should -RRB- be spent for that purpose,'' the report said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880224-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-24-88 0320EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Panama'sPresident Bjt   02-24 0539</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Panama's President, Bjt,550</SECOND>
<HEAD>Delvalle May Be Ready to Break with Noriega, Sources Say</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GEORGE GEDDA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials say they are receiving signs that Panamanian President <PERSON> Eric </PERSON> <PERSON> Arturo </PERSON> <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON> may be ready to disassociate himself from military strongman <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>. Any such move would further weaken <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> and possibly hasten his demise as the dominant force in Panamanian politics, the officials said. The <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration looks upon <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> as the principal obstacle blocking its goal of an eventual transition to elected, civilian-led rule in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>. The officials, who asked not to be identified, said <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON> has privately expressed his intention for many weeks to distance himself from <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> but they recognize that such a step would require considerable courage. `` We get information from all sorts of sources, including friends and relatives, that he is about to do something along these lines,'' one official said. Congressional sources, also insisting on anonymity, said they have heard the same reports. Since last summer, the administration has been publicly encouraging <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s military officers to withdraw from politics as a means of promoting a return to rule by civilians. In the meantime, much of the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> aid program to <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> has been suspended and <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> has expelled all <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> aid personnel. Two federal indictments against <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> on drug trafficking charges added a new dimension to the already strained relationship. The indictments, handed down in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> earlier this month, portrayed <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> as a key member of an international drug smuggling conspiracy. In the <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, opposition to <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> spans the political spectrum. <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON> assumed the presidency in 1985 under circumstances which strongly suggested that <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> had forced his predecessor, <PERSON> Nicolas </PERSON> <PERSON> Ardito </PERSON> <PERSON> Barletta </PERSON>, from office. It was a constitutional succession but <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON> has been widely perceived as no more than <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s titular head. <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> has maintained that executive authority rests with <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON> and that <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> has achieved a full transition to democracy. <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> says his <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> critics are campaigning against him for the purpose of annulling the <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Canal </LOCATION> treaties, under which the waterway reverts to Panamanian control at the end of 1999. Attempts to obtain comment from the <ORGANIZATION> Panamanian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> on <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON>'s purported intentions were not successful. For the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, the stakes in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> are extraordinarily high. The administration believes that a democratic, politically stable <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> offers the best assurance for the continued efficient operation of the canal. The <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials noted that challenging <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> would not be an easy step for <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON>. They said <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON>'s extensive business interests and his family could be threatened if he breaks with <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>. In addition, <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON>'s health is said to be tenuous because of a heart operation. However, the officials said <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON> has become increasingly disturbed by his ties to <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> and that some of his friends have rebuffed him because of that association. <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON> also may be tempted to act because of <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s growing financial crisis. `` The country is falling apart all around him,'' said one source. <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> <PERSON> Chewning </PERSON> <PERSON> Fabrega </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Panamanian </LOCATION> diplomat who resigned recently in protest over <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>'s rule, said in an interview this week that the country's financial problems are so severe the government may not be able to meet its payroll next month.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880224-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-24-88 0320EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FBIInfiltration Bjt   02-24 0717</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-FBI Infiltration, Bjt,720</SECOND>
<HEAD>FBI Stung by Complaints of Vietnam-Era Spying</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LARRY MARGASAK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
