<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880611-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-11-88 0307EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Reagan-Panama     06-11 0423</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Reagan-Panama,420</SECOND>
<HEAD>Reagan Bans from US Those Panamanians Who Help Noriega's Regime</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> is barring from the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Panamanian </LOCATION> government and military officials known to support Gen. <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>. In a proclamation, the president Friday said <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> and his handpicked president, <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Solis </PERSON> <PERSON> Palma </PERSON>, `` are preventing the legitimate government of President <PERSON> Eric </PERSON> <PERSON> Arturo </PERSON> <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON> from restoring order and democracy in that country.'' `` I have determined that it is in the interests of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> to restrict the entrance into the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> as immigrants and non-immigrants of certain persons who formulate or implement the policies'' of <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> and <PERSON> Solis </PERSON> <PERSON> Palma </PERSON> said <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>. `` The proclamation is effective immediately and shall remain in effect until such time as the secretary of state determines that democracy has been restored in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>,'' the president said. The <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration has tried unsuccessfully to get <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>, who is under indictment on drug trafficking charges in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>, to yield power to <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>. A <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> official said the order might affect several hundred Panamanians. The move prompted a quick denunciation and a threat of retaliation by the Panamanian government. `` We could not care less about any lists made up by the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration,'' said <PERSON> Boris </PERSON> <PERSON> Moreno </PERSON>, director of the <ORGANIZATION> Panamanian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Information </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>, in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. `` The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> is free to make as many lists as it wants of Panamanians it does not want to admit there, just as we can make our lists of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> citizens we do not want in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>.'' Under the president's proclamation, Secretary of State <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> will designate those Panamanian nationals who, with their families, will be barred from entering the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> because of their role in aiding <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>'s regime. Panamanians on the list who attempt to come to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> would be stopped at <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> ports of entry or they would be denied visas at <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> consular offices, the official said. The president said the order would be enforce so as not conflict with international obligations of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> or prohibit the entry of individuals into the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> to submit to <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government legal proceedings. `` The purpose of the declaration is, in a very ungentle manner, to let <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>'s supporters know that their continuing support for him is not going to be without some personal cost,'' said a <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> official, asking not to be identified. The last time such a restriction was imposed occurred in 1985 when most non-immigrant Cubans were prevented from entering the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880611-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-11-88 0308EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-People-Savio     06-11 0341</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-People-Savio,330</SECOND>
<HEAD>`Aging Rabble-Rouser' Address Capital's Elite at Son's Graduation</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Mario </PERSON> <PERSON> Savio </PERSON> called himself `` not just an aging rabble-rouser but a parent also'' as the pioneer of the student movement of the 1960s spoke at his son's graduation from a prestigious <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> high school. The one-time <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION> at <LOCATION> Berkeley </LOCATION> firebrand who helped trigger the student power movement also described his change during college from being `` a most unpolitical son of unpolitical Italian immigrants.'' `` We came to view <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> as a racist and imperialist power ... -LRB- that -RRB- covered its tracks with a beguiling opportunity for self expression,'' the 45-year-old told the class at <ORGANIZATION> Sidwell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Friends </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION>. `` It was always right now in the'60s _ Freedom Now, <ORGANIZATION> Peace </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Now </ORGANIZATION>,'' he said. `` Did we not know that we could spoil the work by the way we dashed it off? We lived our lives as if we might not live to the ripe old age of 30. Even so ... we did not leave all our eggs in one basket. We bore children.'' <PERSON> Savio </PERSON>'s son, 18-year-old <PERSON> Nadav </PERSON> <PERSON> Savio </PERSON>, who plans to attend <ORGANIZATION> Wesleyan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION>, not <LOCATION> Berkeley </LOCATION>, told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> for a story in Saturday's editions that he has not become involved in political issues. `` Some of what happened -LRB- in the 1960s -RRB- was excessive,'' he said. `` There was random and rampant drug experimentation. ... Some people went overboard in various ways, but there was a lot of good feeling among people and between people and that's something that should be resurrected.'' <PERSON> Savio </PERSON>, who dropped out of <LOCATION> Berkeley </LOCATION> in the mid-1960s, finally received his bachelor's degree in 1984 from <ORGANIZATION> San </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Francisco </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. He is now a graduate student and part-time lecturer in physics at <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> <LOCATION> State </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Nadav </PERSON> <PERSON> Savio </PERSON> lives in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> with his mother, <PERSON> Suzanne </PERSON> <PERSON> Goldberg </PERSON>, a psychologist who is married to Dr. <PERSON> Sidney </PERSON> <PERSON> Wolfe </PERSON>, director of the <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Citizen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Group </ORGANIZATION>, a <PERSON> Ralph </PERSON> <PERSON> Nader </PERSON> organization. <PERSON> Savio </PERSON> is married for a second time and lives with his wife and their child in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880611-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-11-88 0328EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-US-Nicaragua     06-11 0405</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-US-Nicaragua,400</SECOND>
<HEAD>Contra Leader Calls for Renewed US Arms Aid</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A leader Nicaraguan resistance leader says Contra forces could face annihilation at the hands of the <ORGANIZATION> Sandinistas </ORGANIZATION> unless the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> resumes military aid to the rebels. The Contra leader, <PERSON> Adolfo </PERSON> <PERSON> Calero </PERSON>, said Friday at a news conference the aid was needed because of Sandinista threats to wipe out the insurgents if the latest round of peace talks did not produce a final settlement to the Nicaraguan war. Peace talks between the leftist Sandinista government and the Contras collapsed in <LOCATION> Managua </LOCATION> Thursday although both sides said a temporary truce would remain in effect. White House spokesman <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> was `` disappointed at the Sandinista rejection of the <ORGANIZATION> Nicaraguan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Resistance </ORGANIZATION> proposal to achieve democracy and an end to the war in <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>.'' The <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration blamed the Nicaraguan government for the breakdown in talks, but said no decision had been made about whether to ask <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> for more aid for the insurgents. `` I think that in view of the <ORGANIZATION> Sandinistas </ORGANIZATION>' actions here, their unwillingness to negotiate in good faith, their unwillingness to instill democratic reforms, you may well see a press for Contra aid from members of the Congress and from people in <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> and from other sources, but at this point we have made no decisions,'' said <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON>. Meanwhile, Rep. <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-N.Y. </LOCATION>, urged the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> to propose an aid package for the Contras that matches the amount of military assistance he said the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> provided to the Sandinista government during the first three months of this year. He put the amount at $ 105 million. <PERSON> Calero </PERSON>, indicated he felt that was a reasonable amount. The rebels have received no military aid since Feb. 29. The <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> rejected President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s last military aid request for the Contras on Feb. 3. But Rep. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Bonior </PERSON>, D-Mich., a leader of the anti-Contra forces in the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> said, `` This is no time to be talking of military aid. He called for additional efforts to achieve a peace settlement before a new military aid request is considered. The goal of the latest negotiating round, which began on Tuesday, was to end the war and install democratic reforms, in accordance with a preliminary peace plan signed on March 23 in <LOCATION> Sapoa </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>. The discussions had been described as the fourth and final round of a series which have taken place under an interim truce.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880611-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-11-88 0331EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Jackson     06-11 0697</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Jackson,700</SECOND>
<HEAD>Jackson Focuses On Economics</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By F.N. D'ALESSIO</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CHICAGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, back in his home territory for the weekend, says he hopes to help forge an economic alliance among farmers and industrial workers. `` We want to bring people beyond racism, beyond sexism and beyond anti-Semitism,'' said <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, in brief statements to reporters late Friday as he arrived in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> from a campaign swing in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> said he would unveil his new plans today in a speech at the headquarters of Operation Push, the civil rights group he founded. The candidate said his latest 40-day campaign plan would focus on economic proposals. `` We'll focus on ways to protect workers, farmers, the aged and the poor against the ravages of Reagonomics,'' he said. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> was asked about polls indicating he would hurt <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> as a running mate against the Republican ticket headed by <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. `` If we are within four points of <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> before the race begins, we have the capacity to win,'' <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> replied. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> came in second place to <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> in delegate and popular vote count in the Democratic primaries, but a survey published in <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> suggested he would hurt the ticket among groups whose support the <ORGANIZATION> Democrats </ORGANIZATION> need to win in the fall. And another poll, conducted for <ORGANIZATION> USA </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Today </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cable </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Network </ORGANIZATION>, indicated a Dukakis-led ticket with <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> as the running mate would lose to <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, 47 percent to 40 percent. Otherwise, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> would win, 45 percent to 39 percent, the survey suggested. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> has said only that <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> deserves to be considered, not that he has any special claim on the job. Confusion over <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s position on the matter has been heightened in recent days by a <ORGANIZATION> Cable </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Network </ORGANIZATION> report that quoted him as saying he wants to be vice president. `` Let's leave it at consideration,'' <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> said Friday in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> when asked to clarify the matter. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> has said he deserves to be offered a spot on the ticket, but the <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News-Post </ORGANIZATION> survey found that two-thirds of <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> voters believe the nominee has the right to `` choose anyone he wants'' as a running mate. Only three in 10 said the second spot on the ticket should automatically go to the second-place finisher in the primaries, the poll said. The ABC-Post poll said <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> was the vice presidential choice of 36 percent of all registered Democrats. However, nearly one-quarter of those surveyed said they would be less likely to vote for <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> if <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> were on the ticket. Only 12 percent said they would be more likely to vote Democratic with <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> in the No. 2 spot, the poll said. Earlier Friday, <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> said in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> that he has better credentials than anyone else in politics to be the Democratic vice presidential nominee. While others may be qualified, <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> said, none has shown ability to win 7 million votes as he did in the primary season or has his combination of regional and political strengths to balance a ticket headed by <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>. `` We meet virtually every stated qualification for serious consideration on the ticket,'' he said. `` No one else at this point that's active in politics has shown the breadth of support I have shown at the voting polls; no one else has shown the ability to impact on the country's tone and the party's priorities. `` They may have state credentials. They've not shown themselves to have national vote-getting potential,'' <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> told reporters who accompanied him to a two-day working vacation at the posh La Costa health spa north of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Diego </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> left La Costa Friday afternoon to head to return to <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>, where he planned to meet with civil rights leaders and continue plans for the convention. Although visibly tired and talking very softly after his long flight, <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> brought a touch of <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> casualness to the chilly <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> night. The often soberly dressed candidate was wearing blue jeans, leather sandals and a black jacket bearing the emblem of the <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Longshoremen </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Warehousemen </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION>. He also wore a silver pin in the form of a stevedore's pick _ a symbol of the union.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880611-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-11-88 0259EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w PM-Wright-Glance     06-11 0511</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Wright-Glance,510</SECOND>
<HEAD>With PM-Wright-Ethics Bjt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here, at a glance, are the possible violations of <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> rules by <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Speaker <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Texas </LOCATION>, which the <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> on </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Standards </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Official </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conduct </ORGANIZATION> said it would investigate:
</TEXT>
<HEAD>NEPTUNE OIL</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 _ `` Lobbying efforts on behalf of a constituent with whom he had an interest in a private gas well venture.'' This allegation refers to <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>'s actions in 1979 on behalf of <ORGANIZATION> Neptune </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Oil </ORGANIZATION>, owned in part by <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Moncrief </PERSON>. The speaker wrote to Egyptian President <PERSON> Anwar </PERSON> <PERSON> Sadat </PERSON> a letter on behalf of the company, whose assets were at issue during the Camp David accords. The speaker says his financial relationship with the <PERSON> Moncrief </PERSON> family was unrelated to <LOCATION> Neptune </LOCATION> and he had no personal financial stake in the outcome.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>TEXAS OIL &amp; GAS</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 _ `` Circumstances surrounding intervention in a matter before the Department of the <ORGANIZATION> Interior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> on </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> behalf </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Oil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ; </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Gas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>'' The speaker says published allegations that he owned stock in the company were incorrect, and he had no financial interest in the outcome of the federal decision on an <LOCATION> Arkansas </LOCATION> energy exploration.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>BOOK ROYALTIES</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 _ `` Whether campaign funds were used, directly or indirectly, to pay for publication of a book from which he received a 55 percent royalty.'' The speaker earned about $ 55,000, based on the generous royalty arrangement on a book published by his friend, businessman <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Moore </PERSON>. The company owned by <PERSON> Moore </PERSON> has done nearly $ 300,000 in work for <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>'s campaign. The speaker denies the favorable book contract was a way of repaying him for that business, or in any way a recycling of his campaign money for personal use.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>PERSONAL USE OF STAFF</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 _ `` Whether government resources were improperly used to complete work on a book from which he received royalties.'' This refers to the same book, `` Reflections of a Public Man.'' A member of <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>'s staff heled compile the paperback collection of the speaker's remarks and writings and <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>'s office used $ 2,000 in public money to send the aide to <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Worth </LOCATION> to work on the project. The speaker says the book work was in addition to the staff member giving the public full value for its money.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>FORT WORTH CONDOMINIUM</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 _ `` The use of a condominium in <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Worth </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>.'' <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> was given full use of a poolside condominium for his congressional district residence by the family of business partner <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Mallick </PERSON>. The speaker paid no monthly rent, but he paid expenses and a per diem when he used it. <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> says the owner has no interest in legislation, the per diem of $ 21.67 was at market rate, and the unit would have otherwise remained vacant. <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> said he recently bought the condominium for $ 58,500.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>TEXAS SAVINGS &amp; LOANS</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 _ `` The possible exercise of undue influence in dealing with officials of the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Home </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Loan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION>.'' The speaker allegedly sought special treatment from the chairman of the bank board for <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> savings and loans officials, including <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> campaign contributors. <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> insists he was only asking for fair hearings for his constituents.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880611-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-11-88 0300EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p PM-Politics-Quotes     06-11 0289</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Politics-Quotes,300</SECOND>
<HEAD>Quotes From the Presidential Campaign Trail</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are some comments Friday from the presidential campaign trail: <PERSON> JESSE </PERSON> <PERSON> JACKSON </PERSON>, saying he has the best credentials of anyone in politics to be the vice presidential nominee: `` We meet virtually every stated qualification for serious consideration on the ticket. No one else at this point that's active in politics has shown the breadth of support I have shown at the voting polls; no one else has shown the ability to impact on the country's tone and the party's priorities.'' <PERSON> MICHAEL </PERSON> <PERSON> DUKAKIS </PERSON>, asked whether he plans to respond to <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s attacks that he's an elitist by bringing up <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s own background, which includes <ORGANIZATION> Yale </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>: `` I really am not interested. I do n't think the American people are interested. I think that's a losing strategy.'' <PERSON> GEORGE </PERSON> <PERSON> BUSH </PERSON>, saying he finds it curious that <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> has accused him of dirty politics after he attacked <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' domestic and foreign policies: `` You're looking at a guy who's been getting hit for six months, guilt by association, and all kinds of personal attacks. What happens now, they raise the mudslinging thing. This is going to be a fun campaign.'' REP. <PERSON> WILLIAM </PERSON> <PERSON> GRAY </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION>, drafting committee chairman, hoping to craft a party platform that suits both <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>: `` As we go through the discussion of issues _ drugs, education, civil rights, health care ... hopefully they'll realize that their differences are not that great and begin to come to a consensus of their own.'' <PERSON> PAUL </PERSON> <PERSON> KIRK </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> chief, pushing his dream of a short and readable platform: `` I do n't think we'll end up with the Yellow Pages, an ad for every organized group.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880611-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-11-88 0300EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p PM-Candidates-Schedules     06-11 0187</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Candidates-Schedules,200</SECOND>
<HEAD>Presidential Candidates' Schedules</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are tentative schedules for the presidential candidates for the week beginning June 12. The information was provided by the candidates. Sunday, June 12 Democrats: <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Salt </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jackson </LOCATION> _ <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> Republican: <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION>; <ORGANIZATION> Wilberforce </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION> Monday, June 13: Democrats: <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jackson </LOCATION> _ <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> Republican: <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION> Tuesday, June 14: Democrats: <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jackson </LOCATION> _ <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> Republican: <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION> Wednesday, June 15: Democrats: <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jackson </LOCATION> _ open Republican: <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION> Thursday, June 16: Democrats: <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> _ deep <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> state -LRB- s -RRB- <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> _ open Republican: <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> _ open Friday, June 17: Democrats: <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> _ deep <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> state -LRB- s -RRB- <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> _ open Republican: <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> _ open Saturday, June 18: Democrats: <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> _ deep <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> state -LRB- s -RRB- <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> _ open Republican: <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> _ open Sunday, June 19: Democrats: <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> _ open <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> _ open Republican: <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> _ open
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880611-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-11-88 0305EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Israel-Nuclear     06-11 0287</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Israel-Nuclear,0295</SECOND>
<HEAD>Israel Allows Norwegian Inspection Of Heavy Water</HEAD>
<DATELINE>OSLO, Norway (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Norway </LOCATION> have agreed that Norwegian experts can inspect a shipment of Norwegian heavy water, a chemical used in the production of nuclear weapons. Foreign Trade Minister <PERSON> Kurt </PERSON> <PERSON> Mosbakk </PERSON> told <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION> on Friday that an agreement on the inspection was negotiated by <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Norway </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Oslo </LOCATION> earlier this week, the national news agency <ORGANIZATION> NTB </ORGANIZATION> reported. The news agency said <PERSON> Mosbakk </PERSON> told parliament that about half of the 20 tons of heavy water sold to <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> in 1959 had vanished through waste and evaporation. Norwegian experts would be allowed to inspect the remaining half, <ORGANIZATION> NTB </ORGANIZATION> said. When <LOCATION> Norway </LOCATION> sold <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> the water almost 30 years ago the contract stipulated that <LOCATION> Norway </LOCATION> had the right to inspect the water and that it could be used for peaceful purposes only. <LOCATION> Norway </LOCATION> did not raise the question of inspection until <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> nuclear technician <PERSON> Mordechai </PERSON> <PERSON> Vanunu </PERSON> told a British newspaper that <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> had used heavy water to produce plutonium for use in nuclear weapons. <PERSON> Vanunu </PERSON> is serving an 18-year prison term in <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> for treason. In three previous rounds of negotiations about the inspection issue, <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> rejected a <LOCATION> Norwegian </LOCATION> proposal to transfer its inspection right to the Vienna-based <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Atom </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION>. Since <LOCATION> Norway </LOCATION> started production of heavy water in the late 1930s, about 450 tons have been exported, mostly for scientific research. Ten countries, including <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>, received amounts large enough for use in nuclear reactors. Two nuclear powers, <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>, received heavy water from <LOCATION> Norway </LOCATION> on the condition that they did no re-export it. Seven other import countries have signed the nuclear non-proliferation treaty, which allows on-site inspection. <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> has not signed the treaty.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880611-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-11-88 0343EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Panama     06-11 0479</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Panama,0494</SECOND>
<HEAD>Panama Spurns U.S. Ban On Its Officials</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ELOY O. AGUILAR</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PANAMA CITY, Panama (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> shrugged off <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>'s move to ban from the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Panamanian </LOCATION> officials supporting Gen. <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> and warned that <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> could bar <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials also. The ban, announced Friday in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, was the latest in a series of steps the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has taken in recent months to show displeasure with <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s leader. President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s order bars from the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> top <LOCATION> Panamanian </LOCATION> government and military officials known to back <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>, the country's military commander and the power behind its civilian government. A <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> official said the order would probably affect several hundred Panamanians. <PERSON> Boris </PERSON> <PERSON> Moreno </PERSON>, director of <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Information </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>, responded to the order Friday by saying, `` We could not care less about any lists made up by the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration. `` The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> is free to make as many lists as it wants of Panamanians it does not want to admit there, just as we can make our lists of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> citizens we do not want in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>,'' he said. The <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration has imposed sweeping economic sanctions against <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> in an effort to force the ouster of <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>, who was indicted in February by a federal grand jury in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> on drug-trafficking charges. <PERSON> Romulo </PERSON> <PERSON> Escobar </PERSON> <PERSON> Bethancourt </PERSON>, president of the pro-government <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Revolutionary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, said Friday that the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> scuttled an offer by <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION> to provide $ 70 million in aid to help <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> through the financial crunch caused by the sanctions. He said the Panamanian government first negotiated with <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION> and when those discussions broke down, it turned to <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION>, which agreed to provide the money if it would be returned when U.S.-Panamanian relations improved. `` Then the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> insulted <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION> and blocked the negotiations by saying the Colombian money came from drug trafficking,'' <PERSON> Escobar </PERSON> <PERSON> Bethancourt </PERSON> said. About $ 50 million in <LOCATION> Panamanian </LOCATION> government assets has been frozen in <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> banks. <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> uses the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> dollar as its currency. In announcing the ban on Panamanian government officials, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> and his hand-picked president, <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Solis </PERSON> <PERSON> Palma </PERSON>, `` are preventing the legitimate government of President <PERSON> Eric </PERSON> <PERSON> Arturo </PERSON> <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON> from restoring order and democracy in that country.'' <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON> was deposed by the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION> in February the day after he tried to fire <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>. After he was ousted, his family took refuge in the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> ambassador's residence, and <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON> apparently spends much time there. He often meets there with English-speaking journalists, who are asked not to disclose the location. At other times, according to sources speaking on condition of anonymity, <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON> stays in safe homes provided by the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government at its military installations in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>. `` If they want him -LRB- <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON> -RRB- to re-establish democracy, as they say, let him come out of his little <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> in the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> bases here,'' <PERSON> Moreno </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880611-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-11-88 0344EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Korea-Auto     06-11 0347</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Korea-Auto,0357</SECOND>
<HEAD>Industry Suffers From Prolonged Labor Disputes: Ministry</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Korea</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By M.H. AHN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SEOUL, South Korea (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>'s automotive industry, gripped by prolonged labor disputes, has lost more than $ 1.5 billion in production and exports, the <ORGANIZATION> Trade </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Industry </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> reported today. The ministry said lost production of parts and automobiles was estimated at $ 1.32 billion since January. Car export goals for the period were down by 37,330 vehicles, worth $ 219 million. Ministry officials said they feared Korean auto exports may fall far short of a year-end goal of 756,000 vehicles if the labor problems continued. <ORGANIZATION> Hyundai </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Motor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, the country's largest automaker, has been struck since May 30 with its assemly plant in <LOCATION> Ulsan </LOCATION> on the east coast shut down completely. Strikers are demanding higher pay and better conditions. <ORGANIZATION> Hyundai </ORGANIZATION> officials said there was no immediate indication when suspended union-management wage talks would resume. They said both parties remained far apart on the extent of wage hikes. The union demanded an increase of 48 percent or about $ 180 a month, while the management offered a 25 percent raise or about $ 100. <ORGANIZATION> Daewoo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Motor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, the second biggest automaker, was hit by strikes at its main plant near <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION> in April. The automaker is a joint venture between Korean interests and <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Motors </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. Operations at the plants of <ORGANIZATION> Kia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Motors </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, partly owned by <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Motor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, and two other smaller companies were also reported suffering from prolonged wage disputes or a lack of key parts caused by strikes at parts suppliers. Production operations have been suspended or reduced at about 500 parts makers for many weeks due to labor strikes, sabotage or other problems, with 600 other companies in normal operation. Some of the affected parts makers have asked for emergency bailout loans saying they face bankruptcy, but monetary authorities were reportedly reluctant to comply with the requests citing the government's tight money policy to counter feared inflation. Last year, <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> produced one million cars and commercial vehicles and exported 540,000 of them.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880611-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-11-88 0345EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Japan-Bribery     06-11 0179</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Japan-Bribery,0185</SECOND>
<HEAD>Former Prime Minister's Office Official Arrested For Taking Bribes</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Japanese authorities have arrested a former public relations officer with the Prime Minister's Office for allegedly accepting bribes from an advertising company, authorities said today. Officials from the <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION> prosecutor's office on Friday arrested <PERSON> Shigeru </PERSON> <PERSON> Suzuki </PERSON>, 59, a former councilor in charge of government public relations, for accepting bribes in return for extending favors, said the official, who spoke on condition of anonymity. Also arrested were two men who allegedly offered the bribes to <PERSON> Suzuki </PERSON>: <PERSON> Saburo </PERSON> <PERSON> Toyama </PERSON>, 67, chairman of an Osaka-based advertising company, and <PERSON> Tsutomu </PERSON> <PERSON> Nishida </PERSON>, 56, head of its <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION> branch. The <ORGANIZATION> Asahi </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Shimbun </ORGANIZATION>, a nationally circulated daily, reported today that investigators found the two had entertained <PERSON> Suzuki </PERSON> with dinners in <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION> and golf outings costing a total of $ 7,200. The entertainment led to increased orders for television advertisements, the report said. The prosecutor's office refused to confirm or deny the report. Another former Prime Minister's Office official was arrested in May for allegedly accepting about $ 18,400 in bribes from advertising agents.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880611-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-11-88 0414EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--Malaysia-US     06-11 0153</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Malaysia-US,0158</SECOND>
<HEAD>Labor Leader Denies Asking United States to Drop Tariff
Preferences</HEAD>
<DATELINE>KUALA LUMPUR, Malaysia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A labor leader today denied asking <ORGANIZATION> AFL-CIO </ORGANIZATION> officials to press <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> to drop preferential tariffs to protest the government's alleged human rights violations. <PERSON> Vethamuthu </PERSON> <PERSON> David </PERSON>, head of the <ORGANIZATION> Malaysian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Trade </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Unions </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, said his union is `` fully convinced that labor and human rights problems in our country can be solved within the <LOCATION> Malaysian </LOCATION> context.'' Government officials attacked <PERSON> David </PERSON>, who also belongs to an opposition party, after reports last week that he had asked <ORGANIZATION> AFL-CIO </ORGANIZATION> officials for help. They said his reported requests to the <ORGANIZATION> AFL-CIO </ORGANIZATION> could hurt the <LOCATION> Southeast </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Asian </LOCATION> nation's economy. <PERSON> David </PERSON> was arrested and held without trial in October under the Internal Security Act for allegedly fanning racial tensions. He was released June 3. The government has used the act to arrest more than 100 people, including opposition leaders, in the past year.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880611-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-11-88 0430EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Mecham     06-11 0483</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Mecham,0498</SECOND>
<HEAD>Defense Rests In Mecham Criminal Trial</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LAURIE ASSEO</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PHOENIX, Ariz. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A jury will be asked to decide next week whether <PERSON> Evan </PERSON> <PERSON> Mecham </PERSON> and his brother committed a crime when they failed to itemize a $ 350,000 campaign loan _ a case the former governor insists is based on `` smoke and mirrors.'' The defense rested Friday in the trial of <PERSON> Mecham </PERSON> and his brother, <PERSON> Willard </PERSON>, without calling either defendant to the stand during the seven days of testimony. The <ORGANIZATION> Maricopa </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Superior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> jury is to hear final arguments on Tuesday before starting deliberations. `` I'm confident that the state has not proved its case,'' <PERSON> Mecham </PERSON>, 64, told reporters as he left the courtroom Friday. The former governor stopped short of predicting acquittal but said, `` I think the smoke and mirrors that this whole thing has been created by ... has been totally revealed to the world.'' However, co-prosecutor <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Cudahy </PERSON> said, `` I think the state position is even stronger after the witnesses called by the defense.'' Judge <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Ryan </PERSON> denied the Mechams' requests for a directed verdict, in which the judge would render a verdict without the case going to the jury. <PERSON> Evan </PERSON> and <PERSON> Willard </PERSON> <PERSON> Mecham </PERSON>, who was his brother's 1986 campaign treasurer, are charged with concealing the $ 350,000 campaign loan on financial reports required by the state. The defense contended the loan was properly reported as part of a $ 465,000 lump sum listed as a contribution from <PERSON> Mecham </PERSON>. The defense also said the failure to itemize the loan was an innocent mistake. But the prosecution maintained the <PERSON> Mecham </PERSON> campaign badly needed the $ 350,000 loan and feared disclosing that it came from developer <PERSON> Barry </PERSON> <PERSON> Wolfson </PERSON> because <PERSON> Mecham </PERSON>'s campaign theme was one of being `` beholden to no one.'' The <PERSON> Wolfson </PERSON> loan was not itemized on either <PERSON> Mecham </PERSON>'s campaign or personal financial disclosure forms. During Friday's testimony, <PERSON> Cudahy </PERSON> sought to establish that <PERSON> Evan </PERSON> <PERSON> Mecham </PERSON> was personally responsible for the failure to report the loan because he reported his finances as a candidate rather than a committee. Anyone who looked at <PERSON> Mecham </PERSON>'s financial reports would not know <PERSON> Mecham </PERSON> borrowed $ 350,000 from <PERSON> Wolfson </PERSON>, <PERSON> Cudahy </PERSON> contended while questioning Secretary of State <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Shumway </PERSON>, whose office is responsible for accepting such reports. `` Does the name <PERSON> Barry </PERSON> <PERSON> Wolfson </PERSON> appear anywhere on the post-general contribution and expenditure report filed by <PERSON> Evan </PERSON> <PERSON> Mecham </PERSON> at your office?'' <PERSON> Cudahy </PERSON> asked <PERSON> Shumway </PERSON>, a defense witness. `` I do n't see any contributor by that name,'' <PERSON> Shumway </PERSON> answered. <PERSON> Mecham </PERSON> is on trial on six felony counts of perjury, willful concealment and filing false documents, and faces up to 22 years in prison if convicted on all counts. His brother is charged with three similar counts and faces up to 9 -LCB- years in prison if convicted. <PERSON> Mecham </PERSON>, a Republican, took office in January 1987. He was removed from office April 4 when the state <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> convicted him of two unrelated impeachment counts.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880611-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-11-88 0445EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-SouthAfrica-Joseph     06-11 0235</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-South Africa-Joseph,0240</SECOND>
<HEAD>83-Year-old White Anti-Apartheid Activist Seriously Ill</HEAD>
<DATELINE>JOHANNESBURG, South Africa (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Helen </PERSON> <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON>, one of the first white South Africans ever banned by the government for anti-apartheid activities, is in serious condition at a hospital. Mrs. <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON>, 83, had been reported `` critical and sinking fast'' by a family friend Thursday. The <ORGANIZATION> Johannesburg </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION> said Friday she was in serious condition, but the family had asked that no further details be released. For the past three decades it has been illegal to quote Mrs. <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>. In 1957, Mrs. <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> received the first of several banning orders, which for 16 of the next 25 years prohibited her from leaving <LOCATION> Johannesburg </LOCATION>, attending political meetings, writing for publication and communicating with other banned people. In 1962, she became the first South African placed under house arrest, which required her to stay in her cottage north of <LOCATION> Johannesburg </LOCATION> from dawn to dusk, report to police daily and visit with no more than one person at a time. Born in <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> in 1905, <PERSON> Helen </PERSON> <PERSON> Fennell </PERSON> came to <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> from <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> in 1931, and, as a social worker, began participating in anti-apartheid campaigns at the age of 48. She helped found the Federation of South African Women, which in 1956 staged one of the biggest protests in the country's history _ a march by 20,000 black women on the government buildings in <LOCATION> Pretoria </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880611-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-11-88 0452EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-PoliticalBriefs     06-11 0366</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Political Briefs,350</SECOND>
<HEAD>Metzenbaum Predicts Glenn Will Be VP Candidate</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CLEVELAND (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> <PERSON> Metzenbaum </PERSON> says his fellow senator from <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON>, could well become the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> nominee for vice president this year. `` I have no reservation in hoping and predicting he -LRB- <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON> -RRB- will be the vice presidential nominee of <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>,'' <PERSON> Metzenbaum </PERSON> said Friday in a speech to the convention of the <ORGANIZATION> Ohio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> AFL-CIO </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Metzenbaum </PERSON> predicted that <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON> and <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, the <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> governor who has apparently wrapped up the Democratic presidential nomination, would defeat Vice President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> in the November presidential election.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>___</HEAD>
<HEAD>Remaining Ohio Democratic Delegates Are Chosen</HEAD>
<DATELINE>COLUMBUS, Ohio (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The chairman of <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> party </ORGANIZATION> says the newly-elected delegates to the party's national convention in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> represent all elements of the party, including both sexes, minorities and elected public officials at all levels. `` This delegation is as balanced as any <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> has ever sent to a national convention,'' state chairman <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Ruvolo </PERSON> said of the slate which was finalized in a Friday night vote. The balloting was for 34 at-large delegates and 21 from the ranks of previously pledged local party and elected public officials. They will join 104 who were elected in <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>'s May 3 primary, 15 members of the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> and nine designated members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> for an overall total of 183.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>__</HEAD>
<HEAD>Unity Stressed As DFL Convention Opens</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ROCHESTER, Minn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION> Democrats are being urged to settle their differences this weekend and unite to win the l988 presidential, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> and other races. The state party, known as the Democratic-Farmer-Labor party or DFL opened their three-day state convention at the Mayo Civic Center Friday. The focus of the nearly 2,700 delegates and alternates turned almost immediately to the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> endorsement, which Attorney General <PERSON> Hubert </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Humphrey </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON> is expected to win Saturday. Peace activist <PERSON> Polly </PERSON> <PERSON> Mann </PERSON>, a co-founder and former co-director of Women Against Military Madness, also is seeking the DFL endorsement to challenge 10-year veteran Republican Sen. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Durenberger </PERSON>. `` When they're through -LRB- with the endorsement contest -RRB-, I want them to join hands and work to defeat the Republican incumbent,'' said the convention keynote speaker, retired <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge Miles Lord.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880611-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-11-88 0431EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-InventorsCongress     06-11 0350</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Inventors Congress,0361</SECOND>
<HEAD>Inventors Gather To Market Their Gadgets</HEAD>
<DATELINE>REDWOOD FALLS, Minn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Necessity may be the mother of invention but the possiblity of making a million dollars seems to help. An attorney who helped organize the 31st annual <ORGANIZATION> Minnesota </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inventors </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> says some gadget makers come with dollar signs in their eyes. `` Some are quite naive,'' said <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Braddock </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Minneapolis </LOCATION> patent attorney. `` They will come and say ` I've got this invention. It works. Where do I go to get my million dollars?' It's often that simplistic. We try to put them on the right road.'' <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Ludvigson </PERSON>, of <LOCATION> Sioux </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Falls </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> S.D. </LOCATION>, said a harrowing experience led to his invention. `` I was almost killed off by a kid on a skateboard one night, so I went home and invented the ` thrasher flasher,''' said <PERSON> Ludvigson </PERSON>, a camera repairman and participant in the three-day <ORGANIZATION> Inventors </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, which began Friday. His thrasher flasher is essentially a headlight for a skateboard. It's a low-intensity strobe light attached to the board's wheel axle. Like many of the 88 exhibitors and 108 inventors at the congress, <PERSON> Ludvigson </PERSON> is hoping someone will spot the flasher and decide to market it. People come to the <ORGANIZATION> congress </ORGANIZATION>, which has been held annually in <LOCATION> Redwood </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Falls </LOCATION> since 1958, not only to get exposure and to market their ideas, but also to find direction. Others come to get the public's reaction to their inventions, said <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> <PERSON> Amoroso </PERSON>, a business development specialist from the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Small </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Business </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>. `` They want to know, ` Is there any market for my products? I have shown it to my family, and they all think it is a good idea, but what about <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Q </PERSON>. Public? What is he going to think about it?''' <PERSON> Amoroso </PERSON> said. Some people, such as brothers <PERSON> Darrell </PERSON>, <PERSON> Vernon </PERSON> and <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Fox </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Langdon </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.D. </LOCATION>, are compulsive inventors and design products after seeing a need for it. They invented an aluminum can crusher, an electrical contraption that hangs on the rim of garbage cans and crushes cans. `` We saw that whole cans were really causing space problems,'' <PERSON> Darrell </PERSON> <PERSON> Fox </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880611-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-11-88 0521EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-WashingtonInBrief     06-11 0442</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Washington In Brief,450</SECOND>
<HEAD>Reagan Administration Proposes Tougher Stance Against Coal
Wildcatters</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration has asked <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to make it a felony to strip mine coal without a permit. Legislation proposed Friday by the <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Surface </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mining </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reclamation </ORGANIZATION> and Enforcement which calls for a maximum prison term of five years for people convicted of mining without a permit is seen as the administration's attempt to get tough with coal wildcatters. ` The civil procedures are so ponderous, it's difficult to keep up with the wildcatters,'' said office spokesman <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Cole </PERSON>. Strip mining without a permit is now a civil offense with a top penalty of $ 22,500, but the bill also would allow a judge to impose a fine of up to $ 250,000 against a convicted individual and a fine of up to $ 500,000 against a convicted organization.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>___</HEAD>
<HEAD>Teacher With AIDS Subject Of Child Molestation Probe</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> officials say a department elementary school teacher who has AIDS has been arrested on charges he received child pornography through the mail and is the subject of a broader child molestation investigation. The 34-year-old teacher was identified Friday by the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Command </ORGANIZATION> as <PERSON> Cirio </PERSON> <PERSON> Lopez </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>. <PERSON> Lopez </PERSON> who had been assigned to the department's <ORGANIZATION> Dependents </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> program in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> since September 1985 was arrested on June 4 after voluntarily traveling from <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ga. </LOCATION>, the command said in a statement `` <PERSON> Lopez </PERSON> is being charged with violation of Title 18 ... and <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. Postal regulations for the possession of two magazines containing child pornography. The materials were discovered through the <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. Postal System in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>.'' The command said it is conducting interviews with students and parents concering possible misconduct by <PERSON> Lopez </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> citizen and second-grade teacher who is `` an admitted homosexual suffering AIDS.''
</TEXT>
<HEAD>___</HEAD>
<HEAD>Agreement Reached With Trucking Companies In Midwest</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Teamsters </ORGANIZATION> union and an employer group representing some 50 small and regional trucking companies in the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> has reached agreement on a new three-year contract. The contract, announced Friday, with the <ORGANIZATION> Motor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Carrier </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Advisory </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chicago </ORGANIZATION> covers some 35,000 drivers and terminal workers and parallels an agreement signed earlier by the union and the industry's main bargaining arm, <ORGANIZATION> Trucking </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Management </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc </ORGANIZATION>. Under the terms of both contracts, drivers get a 35 cents per hour wage increase in each of three years, the first retroactive to April 1 when the old pacts expired. The basic wage rate under the old agreement was $ 14.71 an hour. `` The monetary terms are the same,'' said <PERSON> Chip </PERSON> <PERSON> Roth </PERSON>, a Teamster spokesman. `` I think you could describe the non-monetary differences as inconsequential.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880611-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-11-88 0521EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-UNESCO-Press     06-11 0496</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-UNESCO-Press,0517</SECOND>
<HEAD>UNESCO Plays Down Controversial Communications Order</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By HARRY DUNPHY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PARIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> UNESCO </ORGANIZATION> officials have backed away from a proposal to create a global communications order that some Western nations viewed as a threat to the freedom of the press. The <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> observer to <ORGANIZATION> UNESCO </ORGANIZATION> cautiously praised the recommendations, released by the group's executive board Friday. The new communications strategy played down establishing a new world information and communication order. The concept lay at the heart of a decade-old debate at the 158-nation <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Educational </ORGANIZATION>, Scientific and Cultural Organization and helped convince the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> to withdraw. The board's recommendations go to <ORGANIZATION> UNESCO </ORGANIZATION> Director General <PERSON> Federico </PERSON> <PERSON> Mayor </PERSON>, who is trying to persuade those two nations to rejoin. The report's communications section admitted that journalists had widely interpreted <ORGANIZATION> UNESCO </ORGANIZATION>'s efforts to establish a new world order as aimed at `` undermining freedom of information.'' `` This resulted in a misunderstanding that was used to sully the organization's image,'' it said. The section said <ORGANIZATION> UNESCO </ORGANIZATION> should `` explore the possibilities of a new strategy ... that will dispel the misunderstanding.'' It said the strategy should emphasize `` development of critical acumen among -LRB- media -RRB- users, the ability for individuals and communities to react to any kind of manipulation -LRB- by the media -RRB- and to become familiair with the means available to users to defend their right of reply.'' The section also said <ORGANIZATION> UNESCO </ORGANIZATION> should seek to `` ensure a free and wider and more balanced flow of information.'' In the past, Western governments and media groups have tried to replace the words `` more balanced'' with `` unrestricted.'' These governments and Western media groups expressed concern that the proposed new world communications order could lead to codes of conduct and licensing of journalists. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> observer <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> T. </PERSON> <PERSON> Miller </PERSON> said the latest recommendations, approved by consensus without a vote, contained `` scope for positive change.'' `` However, I am distressed at the tone'' in the communications section, which `` tries to set up an adversary relationship between the media and its audience.'' The board's recommendations, presented at the end of its spring meeting, are intended to guide Mayor in preparation of <ORGANIZATION> UNESCO </ORGANIZATION>'s plan of activities for the l990s At the board's opening meeting three weeks ago, Mayor, a <LOCATION> Spanish </LOCATION> scientist who took office in November, proposed that <ORGANIZATION> UNESCO </ORGANIZATION>'s 14 major programs be reduced to five. He suggested that the organization should do fewer things but do them better and with more follow-up. The board has recommended cutting programs to seven. It added one dealing with peace, human rights and elimination of discrimination, and another that covers development studies. A group of 77 Third World countries and the Soviet bloc criticized Mayor for dropping these programs from his plan for the 1990s. Along with communications, the peace and human rights proposals have provoked controversial debates in the past. Mayor will use the document prepared by the board to draft an outline of the plan for the 1990s for the fall meeting of the board.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880611-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-11-88 0427EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Cambodia-US     06-11 0226</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Cambodia-US,0232</SECOND>
<HEAD>Cambodia To Release American Prisoner</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BANGKOK, Thailand (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The pro-Vietnamese government in <LOCATION> Phnom </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Penh </LOCATION> will release an American who was captured 13 months ago after illegaly crossing into <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION>, the official <LOCATION> Cambodian </LOCATION> news agency <ORGANIZATION> SPK </ORGANIZATION> said today. The agency said Sterling <PERSON> Brian </PERSON> <PERSON> Bono </PERSON>, 35, was seized on May 2, 1987 after he crossed the <LOCATION> Thai </LOCATION> border into the western <LOCATION> Cambodian </LOCATION> province of <LOCATION> Battambang </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> SPK </ORGANIZATION> did not say when <PERSON> Bono </PERSON>, of <LOCATION> Las </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Animas </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Colo. </LOCATION>, would leave <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION>. Some reports have said that <PERSON> Bono </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> war army veteran, crossed into <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION> to look for some 80 Americans still listed as missing in action from the <LOCATION> Indochina </LOCATION> conflict. But others said <PERSON> Bono </PERSON> hoped to locate and help Vietnamese he had known during the war who he thought might have fled to the Thai-Cambodian border area. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials were aware of <PERSON> Bono </PERSON>'s capture and said they were working on his case through the <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION>. <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> does not recognize the <LOCATION> Phnom </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Penh </LOCATION> government which was set up following the late 1978 invasion of <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION> by Vietnamese forces. <PERSON> Phnom </PERSON> <PERSON> Penh </PERSON>'s Prime Minister, <PERSON> Hun </PERSON> <PERSON> Sen </PERSON>, spoke about <PERSON> Bono </PERSON> to several Western correspondents visiting <LOCATION> Phnom </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Penh </LOCATION> last year. <LOCATION> Phnom </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Penh </LOCATION> is also known to be holding a number of Thais captured along the frontier where Vietnamese and <LOCATION> Phnom </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Penh </LOCATION> troops have been fighting Cambodian guerrillas since 1979.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880611-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-11-88 0542EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-GemExpert     06-11 0332</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Gem Expert,0341</SECOND>
<HEAD>Missing Woman's Body Found Floating In Hudson</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The body of a gemologist who disappeared while carrying more than $ 500,000 worth of diamonds was tossed into the <LOCATION> Hudson </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> after she was bludgeoned to death, officials said. <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Mangiameli </PERSON>, 33, a free-lance gemologist, was last seen at her <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION> apartment building on Feb. 4, when she had an appointment to return six diamonds after a proposed sale fell through. Her naked body, bound in the fetal position around the neck, wrists and ankles, was found Thursday floating in the river near the lower end of <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION>, police said. Her body was covered by plastic bags, police said. An autopsy Friday determined she died from multiple blunt force injuries to the scalp and face that caused skull fractures, brain contusions and brain hemorrhaging, said <PERSON> Ellen </PERSON> <PERSON> Borakove </PERSON>, a spokeswoman for the medical examiner's office. `` She was n't in the water for very long,'' Ms. <PERSON> Borakove </PERSON> said. `` She was not dead for a very long period of time from the time they found her -LRB- Thursday -RRB-. It certainly is not months. Whether its weeks or days, I can not pin it down.'' She was identified through dental records, Ms. <PERSON> Borakove </PERSON> said. Two brothers who were friends of Ms. <PERSON> Mangiameli </PERSON>'s were arrested in the case April 11 and have been in custody without bail since, police said. <PERSON> Raoul </PERSON> <PERSON> Rivalta </PERSON>, 48, and his brother <PERSON> Fausto </PERSON>, 33, allegedly arranged a meeting between Ms. <PERSON> Mangiameli </PERSON> and a potential buyer that never took place. Ms. <PERSON> Mangiameli </PERSON> called the diamonds' owner on Feb. 3 to say she would return the six diamonds worth between $ 500,000 and $ 600,000 the next day. A resident of her apartment building saw her in the building's vestibule the afternoon of Feb. 4, relatives said She was not seen after that. According to the complaint, <PERSON> Fausto </PERSON> <PERSON> Rivalta </PERSON> sold a pear-shaped diamond that was among those Ms. <PERSON> Mangiameli </PERSON> had in her possession to a <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Palm </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION> pawnshop for $ 14,000 on Feb. 17.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880611-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-11-88 0542EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Yugoslavia     06-11 0586</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Yugoslavia,0605</SECOND>
<HEAD>Report: Police Feared Popular Opposition; Party Calls For Radical
Change</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BELGRADE, Yugoslavia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Yugoslavia </LOCATION>'s increasingly open press has reported that federal authorities were worried about a popular uprising if they seized control in <LOCATION> Slovenia </LOCATION>, the nation's most liberal republic. The ruling <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, meanwhile, called for radical economic changes on Friday, including freer, profit-oriented markets and more foreign investment to overcome <LOCATION> Yugoslavia </LOCATION>'s deepening economic crisis Reports have circulated for several weeks that military authorities in <LOCATION> Slovenia </LOCATION> were thinking about stepping in to quell liberal tendencies in the northernmost of <LOCATION> Yugoslavia </LOCATION>'s six republics. Federal officials and Communist leaders in the republic have denied any plans for such an action. But <ORGANIZATION> NIN </ORGANIZATION> magazine on Friday published what it said were excerpts of a transcript of a discussion of the police role after such a takeover. A police official, whom the magazine did not identify, was quoted as speaking of police ability `` to control the situation after the arrests, since it is believed that the people will come out into the streets.'' NIN also quoted <PERSON> Igor </PERSON> <PERSON> Bavcar </PERSON>, a spokesman for a group formed to fight the arrests of two journalists who first wrote of the alleged takeover, as saying the transcript means `` nobody believes that the stories about the coup have been fabricated.'' Authorities have denied any link between the journalists report on the takeover and their arrests last week by military authorities. Police have said the journalists were arrested along with a soldier after an unmarked document on combat readiness was found in their possession. <PERSON> Bavcar </PERSON> said his group would decide this weekend whether or not to call for a 15-minute general strike next Tuesday in protest at the arrests. The Slovenian daily Delo reported from <LOCATION> Ljubljana </LOCATION> that more than 7,000 people have signed a petition calling for the release of the trio. Money is pouring into a special account to help the families of those held, and more than 200 companies, Communist party cells and trade union groups have backed the petition for release, <PERSON> Delo </PERSON> said. <LOCATION> Slovenia </LOCATION>'s official lawyers' union issued a statement saying public unease over the case should be seen as popular concern over preserving gains of democratization. `` State organs can not any longer demand in advance uncritical trust from the people,'' the lawyers said, calling for strict adherence to the law in the handling of the controversial case. The party's 52-page blueprint for economic change, largely adopted at a party conference last month, advocated `` the strengthening of market mechanisms'' and recomended measures to attract `` the investment of more foreign capital'' in the Yugoslav economy. It said the party supported `` investment of private funds'' in small businesses as a means of `` restructuring the economy and overcoming high unemployment.'' `` The theses call for sweeping economic reforms to ensure the autonomy of enterprises, the full affirmation of all elements of the market and of economic laws, a single home market and an opening to the world,'' the document said. <LOCATION> Yugoslavia </LOCATION> suffers from 150 percent inflation, a $ 21 billion debt, worker unrest and heavily endebted firms. The government recently undertook a strict austerity program curbing wages and spending as part of sweeping changes to be completed before the end of the year. One of the party's most radical proposals is to base the economy, for the first time, on the profit motive, ending the practice of subsidizing and, when necessary, rescuing money-losing enterprises. The party blueprint also contained a reference to human rights, widely seen as a victory for a liberal faction in the party.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880611-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-11-88 0519EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-TardyScholar     06-11 0577</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Tardy Scholar,0592</SECOND>
<HEAD>Commencement Brings Vindication for Tardy Scholar</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JAMES LITKE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CHICAGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A man whose doctoral dissertation was rejected by a faculty committee in 1942 but hailed by historians four decades later as a pioneering work has received his Ph.D. `` Celebrity is a new status and it's hard to get used to,'' <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Bourgin </PERSON>, who gained national attention earlier this year when his dissertation was finally accepted, said Friday. `` But if all this hoopla was n't going on, I think I'd be feeling quite depressed,'' said the 77-year-old retired civil servant, who lives in <LOCATION> Chevy </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Chase </LOCATION>, Md. `` My polio is acting up, my walking ability is reduced and I'm having difficulty getting out of a chair. `` But this attention, the commencement,'' he added, `` is such great compensation.'' <PERSON> Bourgin </PERSON> was a graduate student at <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> and a disciple of the late Professor <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Merriam </PERSON>, the leading political scientist of the day and a member of then-President <PERSON> Franklin </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Roosevelt </PERSON>'s circle of advisers known as the `` Brain Trust. Under <PERSON> Merriam </PERSON>'s guidance, <PERSON> Bourgin </PERSON> re-examined the history of government planning in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. He then argued in his dissertation that the country's early leaders, <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON> <PERSON> Hamilton </PERSON> and <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Jefferson </PERSON> among them, had intended to use the powers of the federal government to develop the fledgling nation's resources through public works and other projects. The paper challenged the then-common conviction that <ORGANIZATION> Roosevelt </ORGANIZATION>'s New Deal social programs marked a departure from laissez-faire principles attributed to the founding fathers By the time his paper was rejected as not yet `` in satisfactory shape,'' <PERSON> Bourgin </PERSON> was married with a child to support. He said he could n't afford to return to campus as a full-time student to revise his manuscript, so he locked it away in a box. In the intervening years, he manufactured light fixtures, owned a chain of men's clothing stores in <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION> and became a federal civil servant, eventually rising to become regional director for the <ORGANIZATION> federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Emergency </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Planning </ORGANIZATION>, supervising a five-state region in the <LOCATION> Midwest </LOCATION>. `` But I never changed my mind on the essential idea I'd developed in my paper,'' he recalled `` I maintained my interest in history, I looked everywhere, and whenever I read, I was constantly looking to see if someone else had it. `` I was so convinced I was right, and so convinced of the importance of it that tenacity was the easy part,'' he said. <PERSON> Bourgin </PERSON>'s reward came last year, when he read historian <PERSON> Arthur </PERSON> <PERSON> Schlesinger </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>'s `` Cycles of American History,'' a chapter of which made essentially the same argument <PERSON> Bourgin </PERSON>'s paper had offered nearly a half-century earlier. He wrote to <PERSON> Schlesinger </PERSON>, who looked at the dissertation and wrote back: `` Congratulations on your path-breaking work ... I am astonished by the fate of your thesis at <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>.'' Emboldened, <PERSON> Bourgin </PERSON> set in process a motion that culminated Friday with <PERSON> Bourgin </PERSON> receiving his doctorate. `` I'm not sure how the paper was rejected the first time, but my best guess is that after professor <PERSON> Merriam </PERSON> retired, my dissertation became a kind of orphan. `` Also, I was already working at making a living while it was being considered and I think the chairman of the department at the time may not have wanted the degree cheapened by giving it to someone who would n't use it,'' <PERSON> Bourgin </PERSON> said. `` I do n't know if all that makes it any sweeter,'' he said. `` But it certainly has made the last few months of my life an interesting time.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880611-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-11-88 0543EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Soviet-Religion     06-11 0656</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Soviet-Religion,0676</SECOND>
<HEAD>Vatican Officials Meet Underground Church Leaders</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARK J. PORUBCANSKY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MOSCOW (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A 90-minute meeting with two high-level <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION> officials gave the underground Ukrainian <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> `` much hope and strength,'' one of its lay leaders said. Also Friday, the 1,000 th anniversary of <LOCATION> Russian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Christendom </LOCATION> was marked with a gala at the Bolshoi Theater attended by <PERSON> Raisa </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>, wife of Soviet leader <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> American evangelist <PERSON> Billy </PERSON> <PERSON> Graham </PERSON> and Rabbi <PERSON> Arthur </PERSON> <PERSON> Schneier </PERSON>, head of the <ORGANIZATION> Appeal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conscience </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, were among the speakers. The meeting and the appearance of the Soviet leader's wife at a religious event underscored the changing attitude of the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, which is officially atheist. The meeting of <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION> and Ukrainian clergymen at a <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> hotel, the first official one since Soviet leader <PERSON> Josef </PERSON> <PERSON> Stalin </PERSON> crushed the church more than 40 years ago, was kept quiet by both sides. `` The meeting was very warm and fruitful. It gave us much hope and strength,'' said <PERSON> Ivan </PERSON> <PERSON> Gel </PERSON>, a lay leader of the Ukrainian <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> who accompanied the church delegation to the hotel. Members of the delegation said two bishops and three priests of the Ukrainian <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> met at the hotel with two cardinals from the <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION>: Secretary of State <PERSON> Agostino </PERSON> <PERSON> Casaroli </PERSON> and <PERSON> Johannes </PERSON> <PERSON> Willebrands </PERSON>, head of the Secretariat for <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Unity </ORGANIZATION>. Gel said previous contacts were informal, at lower levels, and Friday's meeting would not have been possible without the reforms <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> is making in Soviet society. It lasted 90 minutes, three times longer than scheduled, Gel said. <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION> officials would not talk about the meeting. Members of the Ukrainian delegation canceled a news conference, saying they had promised not to discuss it further and were returning to the <LOCATION> Ukraine </LOCATION> later Friday. No information was available about whether Pope <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> II </PERSON> addressed the issue of Ukrainian Catholics in a letter to <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> brought by <PERSON> Casaroli </PERSON>, the No. 2 <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION> official. Religious groups must be registered with the government, which puts strict limits on the practice of religion. Officials have not recognized Ukrainian Catholic groups, making their religious services illegal. Officials say the <ORGANIZATION> Ukrainian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> numbers 4-5 million believers, primarily in the western <LOCATION> Ukraine </LOCATION>. It was forcibly assimilated into the Russian Orthodox Church in 1946 when <PERSON> Stalin </PERSON> consolidated his control over lands captured at the end of World War II. Gel said 11 bishops were imprisoned under <PERSON> Stalin </PERSON> and only three survived to carry on the consecration of other bishops and priests. Bishops <PERSON> Safron </PERSON> <PERSON> Kurchaba </PERSON> and <PERSON> Pavlo </PERSON> <PERSON> Vasilik </PERSON> led the <LOCATION> Ukrainian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Church </LOCATION> delegation to the meeting Friday, said Gel, who did not attend although he accompanied the group to the Sovietskaya Hotel. The Russian Orthodox Church opposes recognition of the Ukrainian church but has said it will discuss the issue with <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION> representatives in <LOCATION> Finland </LOCATION> later this month. Others at the Bolshoi said Mrs. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>, dressed in a gray suit and red blouse, sat in the front row of about 80 church and government dignitaries. <PERSON> Schneier </PERSON> said Mrs. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> blushed when he turned from the audience, faced her and said, alluding to the biblical story of creation: `` You have been a trusted and devoted helpmate to your husband. Your presence here is more than symbolic. It shows that as his helpmate you are in sympathy with his cause and in support of his pronouncements on the rights of believers.'' <PERSON> Graham </PERSON> said he was `` encouraged by reports that there is a new readiness on the part of both churches and the state to face the mistakes of the past, and to seek together to find new ways of expanding the religious rights and opportunities of believers and religious groups within the framework of your socialist society,'' according to a text of his remarks. Patriarch <PERSON> Pimen </PERSON>, head of the Russian Orthodox church, called <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> a `` tireless architect of perestroika and a herald of new political thinking,'' the official news agency <ORGANIZATION> Tass </ORGANIZATION> reported.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880611-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-11-88 0543EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-SpaceShuttle     06-11 0350</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Space Shuttle,0361</SECOND>
<HEAD>NASA Officials Cautiously Optimistic About Aug. 31 Shuttle Launch</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By HOWARD BENEDICT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Aerospace Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CAPE CANAVERAL, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The pieces are coming together and officials here are confident they soon will launch their first space shuttle mission since Challenger exploded nearly 2 -LCB- years ago. Two 126-foot-tall solid fuel booster rockets were hooked up Friday with a huge external fuel tank, and on Thursday the stack will be joined with the shuttle Discovery. The projected liftoff date is Aug. 31. But <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> officials caution the schedule is tight, with many milestones to be passed. `` The August target is optimistic, for sure, but given where we are today, we've got a shot at it,'' launch director <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Sieck </PERSON> said. `` We're getting close and there's a feeling of excitement here,'' said astronaut <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Crippen </PERSON>, who as deputy director of shuttle operations will make the decision in the closing minutes whether Discovery should be launched. <PERSON> Crippen </PERSON>, a veteran of four space shuttle flights, and <PERSON> Sieck </PERSON> spoke at a news conference. When Discovery reaches the launch pad, workers will prepare it for a critical flight readiness firing of its three main liquid fuel engines. The 20-second ignition, with Discovery bolted firmly to the pad, will test several modifications made to the powerful engines during the long period the shuttles have been grounded. It also will provide countdown experience for the launch team. Also ahead, on Tuesday and on July 26, are two more full-scale firings of test models of the solid fuel booster rockets at the <ORGANIZATION> Morton </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Thiokol </ORGANIZATION> facility in <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION>. A faulty booster joint was blamed for the explosion of Challenger and loss of its seven crew members on Jan. 28, 1986. Testing of the redesigned booster has gone so well that <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> was able to confidently assemble here the two rockets for Discovery's flight Assigned to fly Discovery on the mission will be <PERSON> Frederick </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Hauck </PERSON>, the commander; <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> O </PERSON>. <PERSON> Covey </PERSON>, the pilot; and mission specialists <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON>, <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Lounge </PERSON> and <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Hilmers </PERSON>. They are to deploy a communications satellite and conduct 11 science and technology experiments.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880611-0025 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-11-88 0552EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-VDTVeto     06-11 0277</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-VDT Veto,0284</SECOND>
<HEAD>County Executive's Veto Of VDT Law Angers Unions</HEAD>
<DATELINE>HAUPPAUGE, N.Y. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Union leaders criticized the <LOCATION> Suffolk </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> executive for his veto of a bill that would have made the county the nation's first major municipality to regulate video display terminals. `` I'm outraged at the county executive's submissiveness to the business community, whose arguments of the cost of the legislation are innocuous and untrue,'' state <ORGANIZATION> AFL-CIO </ORGANIZATION> President <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Cleary </PERSON> saud Friday. But Executive <PERSON> Patrick </PERSON> <PERSON> Halpin </PERSON> told reporters that several businesses threatened to leave the county or cancel relocation plans if he signed the legislation. `` In both cases, the consequence would be hundreds, if not thousands of jobs lost, and these are losses that I do not think <LOCATION> Suffolk </LOCATION> can afford,'' <PERSON> Halpin </PERSON> said. Under the bill, employers would be required to pay 80 percent of the cost of eye examinations, glass lenses and frames on a yearly basis, if needed. It also required 15-minute work breaks every three hours and outlined strict work station standards, including what type of chairs should be used, adjustability of the terminals and office lighting. `` This law would cost local businesses millions of dollars to implement at the same time that their competitors in other areas faced no restrictions,'' <PERSON> Halpin </PERSON> said. `` This would be an economic disadvantage to them of no small consequence.'' <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Rechler </PERSON>, chairman of the Association for a <ORGANIZATION> Better </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Long </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Island </ORGANIZATION>, a group of 40 developers, said after the veto was announced Friday: `` The economy of <LOCATION> Suffolk </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> has just breathed a sigh of relief.'' The Legislature could override <PERSON> Halpin </PERSON>'s veto with 12 votes. The measure was originally approved by 13 of the 18 legislators.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880611-0026 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-11-88 0600EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-MerryWidows     06-11 0423</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Merry Widows,0435</SECOND>
<HEAD>Kitchen Band Entertains Nursing Home Residents With Old Songs</HEAD>
<DATELINE>McHENRY, Ill. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A band of widows low on talent but high on spirit grabbed a few unconventional musical instruments _ a washboard, a soap bottle filled with beans and a teapot _ donned floral aprons, and embarked on a sentimental journey. `` You do n't have to have talent,'' said one of the Happy Tooters, <PERSON> Frances </PERSON> <PERSON> Widhalm </PERSON>, after a recent performance. `` Almost none of us does. All you have to do is like music.'' At 88, Mrs. <PERSON> Widhalm </PERSON> is the oldest of the Happy Tooters, with the youngest being 62. The 15 women, all widows, perform at nursing homes and retirement villages, choosing their material with people their own age in mind. The songs are traditional, like `` Melody of Love,'' `` Alley Cat'' and `` Peg O' My Heart.'' The orchestration, however, is anything but traditional. The Happy Tooters play kazoos, shake soap bottles filled with beans and croon into the spouts of teapots. Pianist <PERSON> Isabelle </PERSON> <PERSON> Miller </PERSON> and drummer <PERSON> Madeline </PERSON> <PERSON> Behm </PERSON> play the only `` real'' instruments, but someone occasionally chimes in on the triangle. Like any band worth its gigs, the Happy Tooters have uniforms _ blue floral aprons over white blouses with blue floral bonnets to match. `` I've never sat in the audience, so I do n't know what we sound like,'' said <PERSON> Marion </PERSON> <PERSON> Schmitt </PERSON>, 74, of <PERSON> McHenry </PERSON>. `` But we do have fun, and I think we do bring pleasure to people.'' Mrs. <PERSON> Schmitt </PERSON>, the band's organizer and conductor, said she first organized a kitchen band in November 1985, when her chapter of <PERSON> Naim </PERSON>, a Roman Catholic support group for widows and widowers, was slated to provide entertainment at a dinner in the <LOCATION> Rockford </LOCATION> diocese. The Happy Tooters made their debut March 9, 1986. It was supposed to be a one-shot deal, but the show biz bug bit. They've been touring northern <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> ever since _ weather permitting `` The ladies are getting up in age,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Schmitt </PERSON> explained. `` We try not to peform too much in July and August, when it's hot.'' Cold weather and rain can also be a problem. `` We do n't like to travel when the weather is unstable, we're such a bunch of crips,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Miller </PERSON> said `` But playing for people makes us feel better.'' Mrs. <PERSON> Schmitt </PERSON> pointed out to the elderly and infirm people who were beginning to gather in the activity room at a home before a performance. `` You see some pretty sad faces out there,'' she said. `` It makes us feel good to see them smile.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880611-0027 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-11-88 0612EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-WeatherpageWeather     06-11 0400</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Weatherpage Weather,0411</SECOND>
<HEAD>Chill Lingers Over North</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 An unseasonable cold wave lingered over much of the nation today, bringing chilly temperatures from the <LOCATION> Great </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lakes </LOCATION> region through the <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> valleys with freeze warnings posted for <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>. The freezing temperatures damaged some corn crops in St. Cloud, <LOCATION> Minn. </LOCATION>, and some farmers may have to replant, agriculture agent <PERSON> Burton </PERSON> <PERSON> Olson </PERSON> said. Freeze and frost warnings were posted for extreme western <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION> and for the northern and central mountains of <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>. Much of the nation was dry Friday night and early this morning. But showers and thunderstorms were widely scattered from western and central parts of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> through the east slopes of the <ORGANIZATION> Colorado </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rockies </ORGANIZATION> and <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION> to eastern <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION> and western <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION>. Showers and thunderstorms also were scattered across northern <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> and the southern tip through the <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Keys </LOCATION>. Today's forecast called for showers and thunderstorms along southern <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> and central <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION>; and sunny skies over the rest of the nation. High temperatures were forecast in the upper 60s and the 70s from <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> across northern <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>, from the <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION> across <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, also along the northern <ORGANIZATION> Rockies </ORGANIZATION> and the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Coast </LOCATION>; in the 90s from the northern half of the Plains, as well as from central <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> across western <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> and western <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION>; in the 90s to about 110 through the desert <LOCATION> Southwest </LOCATION>; in the 80s over the rest of the nation. Temperatures around the nation at 3 a.m. EDT ranged from 37 degrees at <LOCATION> Bradford </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION>, to 91 degrees at <LOCATION> Williston </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.D. </LOCATION>. Other reports: _ East: <ORGANIZATION> Atlanta </ORGANIZATION> 61 fair; <ORGANIZATION> Boston </ORGANIZATION> 57 fair; <ORGANIZATION> Buffalo </ORGANIZATION> 49 cloudy; <LOCATION> Charleston </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> S.C. </LOCATION> 55 fair; <ORGANIZATION> Cincinnati </ORGANIZATION> 44 fair; <ORGANIZATION> Cleveland </ORGANIZATION> 44 fair; <ORGANIZATION> Detroit </ORGANIZATION> 52 fair; <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> 79 cloudy; <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> 56 fair; <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION> 50 fair; <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION> 44 fair; <LOCATION> Portland </LOCATION>, 46 fair; <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> 56 fair. _ Central: <ORGANIZATION> Bismarck </ORGANIZATION> 75 fair; <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> 55 fair; Dallas-Fort Worth 65 fair; <ORGANIZATION> Denver </ORGANIZATION> 67 cloudy; <PERSON> Des </PERSON> <PERSON> Moines </PERSON> 58 fair; <LOCATION> Indianapolis </LOCATION> 53 fair; <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> 58 fair; Minneapolis-St. <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> 60 fair; <ORGANIZATION> Nashville </ORGANIZATION> 54 fair; <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION> 70 fair; <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Louis </LOCATION> 57 _ West: <ORGANIZATION> Albuquerque </ORGANIZATION> 62 cloudy; <ORGANIZATION> Anchorage </ORGANIZATION> 52 cloudy; <ORGANIZATION> Las </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Vegas </ORGANIZATION> 73 fair; <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> 57 fair; <ORGANIZATION> Phoenix </ORGANIZATION> 84 fair; <LOCATION> Salt </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> 62 fair; <ORGANIZATION> San </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Diego </ORGANIZATION> 60 partly cloudy; <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> 55 partly cloudy; <ORGANIZATION> Seattle </ORGANIZATION> 52 partly cloudy _ <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>: <ORGANIZATION> Montreal </ORGANIZATION> 54 partly cloudy; <ORGANIZATION> Toronto </ORGANIZATION> 48 partly cloudy
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880611-0028 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-11-88 0622EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-CigaretteSuit     06-11 0199</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Cigarette Suit,0203</SECOND>
<HEAD>Cigarette Suit Jurors Complete Fourth Day Of Deliberations</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEWARK, N.J. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A federal jury will take the weekend off before resuming deliberations in a cigarette liability lawsuit carried on by the widower of a lung-cancer victim who smoked for 40 years. The jury considering the <PERSON> Cipollone </PERSON> case ended their fourth day of deliberations about 5 p.m. Friday with no verdict. It will resume deliberations Monday. Jurors asked few questions during deliberations, which began at noon Tuesday. They are considering whether or not to award damages to <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Cipollone </PERSON> for the 1984 death of his wife, <PERSON> Rose </PERSON>, at 58. During the four-month trial, he charged that cigarette-makers <ORGANIZATION> Lorillard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Liggett </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Group </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Philip </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Morris </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> misled the public about the dangers of cigarette smoking and contributed to Mrs. <PERSON> Cipollone </PERSON>'s death. The companies contend she made an intelligent, strong-willed choice to smoke knowing the risks. They argue smoking is not a proven cancer-cause, and that her type of cancer is n't linked to cigarettes anyway. On Friday, jurors asked if the 1984 Surgeon General's report on smoking and health was in evidence and whether they could see it. It was n't, and the judge said they could n't.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880611-0029 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-11-88 0626EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a BC-Quotes     06-11 0191</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Quotes,0195</SECOND>
<HEAD>Current Quotations</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 `` There should be a plank in this platform that says no person will sleep on the streets of <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> on grates or on park benches any cold night.'' _ <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> Mayor <PERSON> Ray </PERSON> <PERSON> Flynn </PERSON>, commenting on the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> platform under discussion on <LOCATION> Mackinac </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mich </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 `` People are appalled that something like this could happen. It's becoming a common problem across the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> with a surplus of lions, who breed well in captivity.'' _ <PERSON> Patricia </PERSON> <PERSON> Mercer </PERSON>, executive director of the Society for the Prevention of Cruelty to Animals in <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION>, on a <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> man who operates a lion-hunting safari in which people shoot a lion released from a cage.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 `` You have no right, I want to be here with my people. I do n't want to be here with all the rest of you people who hate the truth You better check yourself and make sure you are not burning on the way to hell.'' _ <PERSON> Eric </PERSON> <PERSON> Parker </PERSON>, 16, who was among 60 youths taken into state custody following allegations of mental and physical abuse at a Baptist boarding home in <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880611-0030 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-11-88 0627EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Lebanon-Palestinians 1stLd-Writethru a0430 06-11 0263</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lebanon-Palestinians, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0430,0266</SECOND>
<HEAD>Arafat Loyalists Fight Syrian-Backed Guerrillas In Camps</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: LEADS with 2 grafs to UPDATE with more deaths. PICkS up 3rd
graf, `Police said ...'</NOTE>
<DATELINE>BEIRUT, Lebanon (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
