<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881117-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-17-88 2347EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Korea-USFirebombing     11-17 0377</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Korea-US Firebombing,0392</SECOND>
<HEAD>Attackers Raid U.S. Housing Area, Wound Two</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SEOUL, South Korea (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Forty youths wielding iron pipes and clubs hurled firebombs on Thursday at a housing complex for families of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> troops, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> authorities said. Two servicemen were wounded. The assailants, believed to be radical students, escaped after damaging or destroying nine military vehicles and passenger cars, the officials said. Attackers yelled `` Yankee go home!'' during the evening assault about one mile from the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> 8th Army headquarters near central <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION>, authorities said. Ten firebombs exploded and caused at least $ 15,000 in damage, said a military spokesman. Gen. <PERSON> Louis </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Menetrey </PERSON>, who commands <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> forces in <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>, issued a statement Friday calling the attackers `` cowardly criminals.'' <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials said security was increased at the housing complex. A <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> spokesman said the youths attacked the back gate of the <LOCATION> Hannam </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Village </LOCATION> complex, which houses about 2,500 military dependents. At least 15 youths got inside, he said, speaking on condition of anonymity. The spokesman said the back gate is used for road traffic and was open, with two guards on duty. He said additional help was called, but the attackers fled. An Army news release said a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military policeman was hurt when the youths hit him with iron pipes. A <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officer was injured when a pipe was thrown through the windshield of his car. The soldiers' identities were withheld. <LOCATION> Hannam </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Village </LOCATION> is leased from the <ORGANIZATION> Korean </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Housing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> for use by <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military dependents. It faces <ORGANIZATION> Dankook </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. Radical students attacked the housing area front gate twice in October with no reports of injury. In central <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION> on Thursday, riot police battled thousands of farmers chanting `` Drive out the <ORGANIZATION> Yankees </ORGANIZATION>!'' and trying to march on the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> to protest American farm imports. About 2,000 riot police blocked an estimated 7,000 farmers and other protesters. Hundreds of protesters hurled rocks and bricks at police and attacked troopers with clubs after the march was blocked a few hundred yards from the embassy. Students joined the march and threw a few firebombs at police. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has been pressuring <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> to open its markets to <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> imports, especially agricultural products, to help ease <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>'s $ 10 billion annual trade deficit with <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881117-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-17-88 2338EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-Smith-Execution 3rdLd-Writethru a0788 11-17 0551</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Smith-Execution, 3rd Ld-Writethru, a0788,0561</SECOND>
<HEAD>Smith's Fate Again Up to 8th Circuit</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: LEDES with 4 grafs to UPDATE with Supreme Court's action;
picks up 4th graf pvs, `Smith, 30...</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By KAREN BALL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>JEFFERSON CITY, Mo. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> refused late Thursday to lift a stay of execution for man who killed an inmate in a dispute over a diamond ring, marking the second time the man's execution has been blocked against his wishes In a ruling handed down shortly after 9 p.m. CST, the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> denied the state's motion to vacate a stay that had been issued to <PERSON> Gerald </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> earlier Thursday by the 8th <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Circuit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appeals </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Louis </LOCATION>. In a 7-3 ruling handed down about 5 p.m. in <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Louis </LOCATION>, the court said it needed more time to review <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>'s case, including the issue of whether he is competent to abandon his appeals. <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> had been scheduled to die at 12:01 a.m. Friday. The execution would have been the first in <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION> since 1965, the first under the state's 11-year-old reinstated capital punishment law and the first use of lethal injection, a change from the former gas chamber. <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, 30, has said he wants to die now rather than spend years on death row awaiting `` the inevitable.'' <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>'s wife, <PERSON> Lynn </PERSON>, filed a petition with the court earlier Thursday, seeking to stop the execution, contending <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> is not competent to abandon his appeals. The <ORGANIZATION> Missouri </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defenders </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> had asked the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> for a stay. <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> was sentenced to die for the 1985 stabbing death of inmate <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON>. He also had been scheduled to die Oct. 4 for the 1980 beating death of <PERSON> Karen </PERSON> <PERSON> Roberts </PERSON>, a former girlfriend, but the 8th Circuit stayed that execution, saying it needed more time to determine if <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> was competent to abandon his appeals. Authorities said <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> was killed in a dispute over a diamond ring, although <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> said he committed the murder so he could be executed. <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> has said he killed Ms. <PERSON> Roberts </PERSON> because she gave him a venereal disease and caused him to lose his fiancee. Last month, Mrs. <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> stood by her husband in his decision to abandon his appeals, but recently decided to challenge his competency and try to get the latest execution halted. Mrs. <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, a registered nurse from <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, got to know <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> through letters and married him last year in the prison. `` <PERSON> Gerald </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> is a very sick and emotionally disturbed young man who is not competent to decide whether to abandon his appeals and acquiesce in his execution,'' said Mrs. <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>'s motion for a stay. The state's response contended <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>'s competency has already been established and criticized Mrs. <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> for her `` eleventh hour'' request for a stay. In a telephone interview from the prison Wednesday, <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> said his wife had joined forces with those trying to save him because she had been `` brainwashed.'' `` Apparently they told her it would come off and she is their only chance to stop it,'' <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> said. `` They told her that with her there is a 90 percent chance of stopping it.'' <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> has vowed to start a hunger strike and threatened to commit violence against others if his execution is halted by the courts.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881117-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-17-88 2352EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Dollar-Markets 1stLd-Writethru a0793 11-17 0359</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Dollar-Markets, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0793,0364</SECOND>
<HEAD>Strong Central Bank Intervention Stabilizes Dollar</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: ADDS 1 graf to UPDATE with early Friday dollar trading in
Japan; longer version moved on financial wires.</NOTE>
<HEAD>With AM-Fed-Dollar</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By VIVIAN MARINO</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Business Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Major central banks came to the dollar's rescue Thursday in a united buying spree that stabilized the weakening currency. But analysts warned the recovery might be short-lived because of continued concerns about the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> trade and budget deficits. The coordinated worldwide buying of dollars by central banks appeared to be the heaviest since the spring, and it lent some support to the slumping stock market, which has been keeping a keen eye on dollar activity. On Wall Street, the Dow Jones average of 30 industrial stocks closed up 13.87 points at 2,052.45. But the rebound still left the market's best known measure down about 75 points over seven sessions. Bond prices slipped, pushing interest rates higher. The yield on the <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION>'s bellwether 30-year bond rose to 9.15 percent from 9.11 percent, although some analysts blamed the decline on the <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION>'s auction of long-term bonds Thursday rather than the action in the currency markets. Investors in the financial markets worry that a weak dollar could drive up interest rates and spark higher inflation, since it would raise prices of imports and some domestic commodities. Currency traders said the central-bank intervention began without much success in <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION>, as heavy buying of the dollar by the <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Japan </ORGANIZATION> did not keep the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> currency from dropping to a near 40-year low of 121.5 yen. The <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reserve </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> began selling yen for dollars in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, and the West German <ORGANIZATION> Bundesbank </ORGANIZATION> also bought up dollars to reduce the supply of the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> currency on the market, traders said. The central banks of <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Switzerland </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Austria </LOCATION> and other nations then joined in. The dollar rebounded to about 122.6 yen in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> before slipping to 122.2 in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>. The dollar gained ground against all other major currencies. On Friday morning in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, the dollar opened at 122.15 yen, and by midmorning was trading at about 122.23 yen.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881117-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-17-88 2341EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-MIARemains     11-17 0166</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-MIA Remains,0168</SECOND>
<HEAD>Remains Returned to U.S.</HEAD>
<DATELINE>FAIRFIELD, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The remains of four <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> servicemen reported missing in action in <LOCATION> Indochina </LOCATION> during the <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> War arrived in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> on Thursday. The bodies will be transferred to <ORGANIZATION> Tri </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mortuary </ORGANIZATION> at the <ORGANIZATION> Oakland </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Depot </ORGANIZATION>, where final arrangements will be made by their families, said Master Sgt. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Castillo </PERSON> at <ORGANIZATION> Travis </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Base </ORGANIZATION>, about 45 miles northeast of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION>. A brief ceremony was held to honor the men whose remains were returned to <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials by the Vietnamese government earlier this year. They earlier were cleared for entrance by federal officials in <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION>. Three of the men were identified as Army Maj. <PERSON> Kenneth </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Yonan </PERSON>, of <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>, reported lost on April 24, 1972; <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> Lt. j.g. M.D. McMican, of <LOCATION> Topenish </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wash. </LOCATION>, lost June 2, 1965; and <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> Lt. j.g. <PERSON> Gerald </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Romano </PERSON>, of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, lost June 2, 1965. One soldier's name was withheld at the request of his family.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881117-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-17-88 2356EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-Thatcher 1stLd-Writethru a0691 11-17 0619</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Thatcher, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0691,590</SECOND>
<HEAD>Mrs. Thatcher: Palestinian Declaration Offers `Signs of Hope'</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: SUBS 3rd graf pvs bgng, `Speaking to,' with 2 grafs and SUBS
12th graf pvs bgng, `Mrs. Thatcher reaffirmed,' with 4 grafs to
UPDATE with comments on Cold War</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By GEORGE GEDDA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 British Prime Minister <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> said Thursday the recent <ORGANIZATION> Palestine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> policy statement offers `` signs of hope'' that should be explored through a revived <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> peace effort. At a news conference, Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> said acceptance by the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> parliament in exile of two key <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> resolutions on the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> represents a `` modest step forward'' on which progress toward peace could be made. And in a separate interview with reporters and editors of <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Newsweek </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> magazine </ORGANIZATION>, the prime minister declared that the policies of Soviet President <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> have ended the Cold War between the East and the West. At a news conference shortly before ending her two-day visit here, Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> offered a slightly more upbeat appraisal of the declaration by the <ORGANIZATION> Palestine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> than the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration. The <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> said Wednesday `` more movement on key issues'' will be required by the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> before the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> regards it as ready to participate in the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> peace process. But Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> said the indications of <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> flexibility should be encouraged, otherwise `` you wo n't get further moves.'' She called for a `` strenuous effort,'' including heavy pressure on both <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Arabs </LOCATION>, to get peace negotiations started. On the specifics of the declaration, Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> indicated that she shares the administration's views. While offering restrained praise for the <ORGANIZATION> PNC </ORGANIZATION> stand on <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> resolutions 242 and 338, Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> said she opposes the <ORGANIZATION> PNC </ORGANIZATION> proclamation establishing an independent state and added the declaration did not go far enough in repudiating terrorism. `` Obviously there are a lot of things in it that none of us like,'' she said. The two <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> resolutions call for <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> withdrawal from occupied territories and asserts the right of all countries in the area to live within secure borders. The administration has said the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> declaration on the resolutions was `` an advance'' compared with previous statements. But it said the council declaration as a whole falls short of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> requirements for opening a dialogue with the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION>. During the hour-long interview with <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Newsweek </ORGANIZATION>, Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> said, `` We're not in a Cold War now'' but in a `` new relationship much wider than the Cold War ever was,'' according to a story in the <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION>'s Friday editions. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s policies have affected East-West relations profoundly, Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> said, adding that the previous `` minimal relationship'' with <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> that focused on arms control has expanded to include trade, culture and other major issues. `` I expect Mr. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> to do everything he can to continue his reforms,'' she said. `` We will support it.'' At the news conference, Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> reaffirmed her high regard for President-elect <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, citing his extensive experience in government as a major asset. `` You will have a president who does n't have to be briefed,'' she said. She said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has carried out his many missions to <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> as vice president `` superbly,'' including his effort to ensure <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> intermediate-range missiles were installed in allied countries on time in 1983. Before a breakfast meeting with <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> on Thursday, Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> said she had `` not the slightest shadow of a doubt'' that <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> will deal responsibly with the budget deficit. She offered similar expressions of confidence in <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> economy in network television interviews she had at her temporary residence in the <ORGANIZATION> Blair </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, across the street from the White House.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881117-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-17-88 0005EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Scarfo-Racketeering     11-17 0516</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Scarfo-Racketeering,0534</SECOND>
<HEAD>Final Arguments Made in Scarfo Racketeering Trial</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LEE LINDER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PHILADELPHIA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A prosecutor told jurors Wednesday that reputed mob boss <PERSON> Nicodemo </PERSON> `` Little Nicky'' <PERSON> Scarfo </PERSON> and 16 associates should be convicted of racketeering based on their own recorded words. Defense lawyers, in their final arguments, said the government relied on liars and hearsay to form its case. `` According to the defendants, all the witnesses lied. And the defendants tell you that the Mafia is a figment of the imagination of -LRB- informants -RRB- <PERSON> DelGiorna </PERSON> and <LOCATION> Caramandi </LOCATION>,'' Assistant <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Attorney <PERSON> Arnold </PERSON> <PERSON> Gordon </PERSON> said. `` Now that is not true. There is a mob. The evidence has proven it.'' <PERSON> Gordon </PERSON>'s statements came after the jury heard from the last of the defense lawyers, <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Simone </PERSON>, who represents <PERSON> Scarfo </PERSON>. The 59-year-old <PERSON> Scarfo </PERSON>, who authorities say heads the Mafia in the Philadelphia-southern <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> area, and his 16 associates are standing trial on federal racketeering charges, which include allegations of nine murders, extortion and loan sharking. The jurors, sequestered since the two-month trial began, are scheduled to receive instructions from <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> Franklin </PERSON> <PERSON> VanAntwerpen </PERSON> Thursday morning before beginning deliberations. <PERSON> Simone </PERSON> suggested the government was trying to prove his client guilty through newspaper stories identifying <PERSON> Scarfo </PERSON> as a mob boss, not by evidence. `` That's how they want to prove the Mafia exists and that's how they want to prove his guilt,'' <PERSON> Simone </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Simone </PERSON>, like the other defense lawyers, hammered hard at the two star government witnesses, <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> DelGiorno </PERSON> and <PERSON> Nicholas </PERSON> <PERSON> Caramandi </PERSON>. Both accepted government plea bargains and are under government protection. `` Is it possible for you to remove from your notes or remove from your minds the testimony of <LOCATION> Caramandi </LOCATION> and <PERSON> DelGiorno </PERSON> and other government witnesses?'' <PERSON> Simone </PERSON> asked. `` If you do, you will find that the government case will collapse like a house of cards.'' But <PERSON> Gordon </PERSON> noted that, besides the testimony, the government presented 15 to 20 hours of secretly recorded conversations. `` You heard <PERSON> Scarfo </PERSON> on the tape, and what he was talking about with others,'' <PERSON> Gordon </PERSON> said. `` They were talking about the Mafia. Their words. `` It is on the basis of those words that the government wants you to find these defendants guilty, not on newspaper articles.'' <PERSON> Gordon </PERSON> acknowledged that a good deal of the evidence came from the two informants. `` The defense would like you to believe that <PERSON> DelGiorno </PERSON> and <PERSON> Caramandi </PERSON> told you lies, and that there is no case, but that is not true, `` <PERSON> Gordon </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Gordon </PERSON> acknowledged that the two witnesses were criminals, but said they were government witnesses `` because that's how you prosecute mob members.'' `` -LRB- Law-abiding citizens -RRB- do n't associate with the kind of people the evidence shows these defendants are. The only people who can tell you about the mob and how it works are people inside the mob. `` People like <PERSON> Caramandi </PERSON> and DelGiorno are not found among honest citizens. They are found in the sewers of the underworld.'' On the basis of testimony from <ORGANIZATION> DelGiorno </ORGANIZATION> and <PERSON> Caramandi </PERSON> a year ago, <PERSON> Scarfo </PERSON> and former City Councilman <PERSON> Leland </PERSON> <PERSON> Beloff </PERSON> were convicted of trying to extort $ 1 million from a developer.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881117-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-17-88 0009EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-FrugalFuneral     11-17 0227</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Frugal Funeral,0235</SECOND>
<HEAD>Man Plans $180 Funeral, `No Rip Off' Epitaph</HEAD>
<DATELINE>EXETER, England (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Teddy </PERSON> <PERSON> Corbett-Winder </PERSON> has organized his own funeral to avoid bothering anyone with a mortician's bill. The 72-year-old retired businessman is ready to meet his maker for a bargain price of less than $ 180. A carpenter made a chipboard box coffin for less than $ 125, and a friend will take him to his final resting place in a station wagon. Corbett-Winder keeps dirty laundry in the coffin under his bed at his home in <LOCATION> Exeter </LOCATION>, southwest <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>, until it is needed. `` All they will have to do is roll me out of my bed and straight into the box,'' he said. He has also written his epitaph: `` <PERSON> Edmund </PERSON> <PERSON> Frederick </PERSON> <PERSON> Corbett-Winder </PERSON>, 1916 - No Rip Off.'' `` I'm deadly serious. Funerals can cost more than 1,000 pounds -LRB- $ 1,800 -RRB- and I'm not leaving any cash to the funeral directors,'' he said. `` Once I've slipped a few quid -LRB- pounds -RRB- to my mates to carry the coffin and paid the cremation fee it will be very cheap.'' He has already had a trial run for his cremation. `` It was beautiful, but a bit hard on the backside. I'll have to put in a cushion and pillow,'' he said. Corbett-Winder, a grandfather, said he will leave all his money to the <LOCATION> Exeter </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospice </LOCATION>, where he works as a volunteer.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881117-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-17-88 0009EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--FireSleeper     11-17 0093</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Fire Sleeper,0094</SECOND>
<HEAD>Fire Brigade Rouses Sleeper To Home Burning Down</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SWANSEA, Wales (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Myfsud </PERSON> was sound asleep in his bed upstairs when an ultra-polite firefighter tapped him on the shoulder and said: `` Excuse me sir, your house is burning down.'' <PERSON> Myfsud </PERSON>, 28, a builder, had slept through an explosion in his television receiver which started a fire downstairs at his home in <LOCATION> Swansea </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> south </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Wales </LOCATION>, early Wednesday. Neighbour <PERSON> Margery </PERSON> <PERSON> Davies </PERSON> said she saw the smoke and raised the alarm. <PERSON> Myfsud </PERSON> got out safely but his row house was gutted.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881117-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-17-88 0023EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-BunglingBurglar     11-17 0201</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bungling Burglar,0204</SECOND>
<HEAD>Burglar Breaks Ankle, Calls Police To Pick Him Up</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WILLISTON, N.D. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A man charged with burglarizing three grain elevators summoned police to the scene of one of his alleged crimes when he broke his ankle as he wrestled with a door, authorities said. <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> Dowell </PERSON>, 58, was listed in good condition at <LOCATION> Mercy </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION>, where he was taken after he injured himself at the <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Elevator </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, authorities said. Police arrested <PERSON> Dowell </PERSON> at the elevator after he telephoned authorities early Wednesday, identified himself as a burglar and said he had hurt his left leg, Police Capt. <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Molinari </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Dowell </PERSON> told police he had broken into two other elevators, <PERSON> Molinari </PERSON> said, and he was charged with three counts of felony burglary. <PERSON> Dowell </PERSON>, who was released from the <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION> <LOCATION> State </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Penitentiary </LOCATION> earlier this month after serving almost seven years for burglary, fell and hurt his ankle as he was trying to close a sliding door at City Elevator, <PERSON> Molinari </PERSON> said. He told police he had decided to spend the night there. <PERSON> Dowell </PERSON> crawled to the office area, where he made himself coffee and enjoyed a few lollipops before the pain prompted him to call police.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881117-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-17-88 0004EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-PilotsIndicted     11-17 0230</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Pilots Indicted,220</SECOND>
<HEAD>Eight Pilots Indicted in Transportation Department Drug Crackdown</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Eight pilots in <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION> were indicted Wednesday for allegedly failing to disclose drug and alcohol-related convictions when they applied for medical certification from the federal government, the <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> said. The eight indictments `` involve false statements made to the <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aviation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> -RRB- by pilot applicants for medical certification,'' <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Burnley </PERSON> said in a statement. The maximum penalties faced by the pilots if convicted are five years in prison and a $ 5,000 fine. The statement did not indicate whether the pilots worked for commercial air lines. <ORGANIZATION> Burnley </ORGANIZATION> said there are likely to be more indictments as part of a special national effort by the departments of transportation and justice to achieve a drug-free transportation system. `` Our inspector general is pursuing similar investigations in all 50 states, and further criminal charges are expected,'' said <LOCATION> Burnley </LOCATION>. Twenty-seven airline pilots, flight instructors and private pilots were indicted on Sept. 30 in the first such actions by the <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>. `` These indictments reflect the serious problem of drug and alcohol abuse that affects all parts of our society. ... That is why I issued this week drug testing regulations covering 4 million employees in sensitive safety and security positions in commercial aviation, railroads, mass-transit, interstate trucking and in the maritime and pipeline industries ...,'' <ORGANIZATION> Burnley </ORGANIZATION> added.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881117-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-17-88 0049EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-SouthernBaptistRdp     11-17 0607</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Southern Baptist Rdp,0621</SECOND>
<HEAD>Old Arguments Pop Up In State Southern Baptist Conventions</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Southern Baptists convening in 11 states decided Wednesday to give a little less to charity, interpret the Bible for themselves and work seriously toward uniting moderate and conservative factions in the nation's largest Protestant denomination. Southern Baptists from <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Kentucky </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> have been meeting most of this week to elect new officers and define bylaws tht govern the Southern Baptist Convention. Always present during the proceedings is a power struggle between moderate Baptists, who believe the Bible is authoritative but open to scholarly interpretation, and fundamentalists, who take a literal interpretation of the Bible and have controlled the 14.7 million-member denomination for the past decade. In <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Baptists </ORGANIZATION> voted to cut back the denomination's donation to national and international causes. Some 2,200 Baptists, gathered at 127th annual <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> State Baptist Convention in <LOCATION> Lakeland </LOCATION>, Tuesday approved giving to charity 47.65 percent, or $ 10.3 million of their $ 21.6 million budget next year, down from 50 percent. The Rev. <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Snell </PERSON>, chairman of the budget-allocations committee, said budget requests are up $ 500,000 from last year, most of it due to debt payments, salary adjustments, program increases and such expenses as insurance. <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> Baptists elected as their president the Rev. <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Billingsley </PERSON>, a 54-year-old pastor from <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> Townsend </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, a layman from <LOCATION> Niceville </LOCATION>, was elected first vice president. In <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION>, Baptists closed their three-day convention with a vote that reaffirmed Baptists' right to interpret the Bible as they see it. During Wednesday's final session, a resolution that says pastors can encourage members to `` exercise the traditional privileges and rights of believers as priests'' passed on a 791-629 vote. The moderate-backed resolution challenged a measure passed by the national convention that gave pastors more authority for running their churches and interpreting scriptures for their congregations. Convention delegates also voted on six resolutions that could affect policies at more than 3,000 affiliated churches. Among the resolutions were official statements opposing pornography, abortion and legalized gambling. The gambling resolution warned Baptists that the state legislature will soon consider establishing a lottery. The <ORGANIZATION> Alabama </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Baptist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Convention </ORGANIZATION> ended Wednesday with a new president being selected by acclamation for the first time in decades. The Rev. <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Carter </PERSON>, a conservative <LOCATION> Birmingham </LOCATION> pastor, was the only candidate nominated to succeed layman <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Tondera </PERSON>, who served the customary two years as convention president. `` I would describe my posture as bridge building or centrist,'' <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> said. `` By concentrating on that on which we agree, we can continue to defuse that on which we disagree. I put that as a priority.'' <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> Baptists agreed Wednesday to open several group homes for retarded adults in <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION>, approved a $ 25.8 million budget, selected <PERSON> Calvin </PERSON> <PERSON> Metcalf </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Knoxville </LOCATION> as the group's president and decided to support a three-year missions partnership with the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION>. The <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> Baptist Convention on Wednesday denounced criticism leveled at slain civil rights leader <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Luther </PERSON> <PERSON> King </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> by a state denomination leader earlier this year. The convention adopted a resolution condemning remarks made by <PERSON> Curtis </PERSON> <PERSON> Caine </PERSON> of <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> that praised South African apartheid and labeled King as a fraud. The convention's 1,961 delegates also voted unanimously to elect the Rev. <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Futral </PERSON>, pastor of a Jackson church, to a second one-year term as president. In <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Baptists </ORGANIZATION> said they may reconsider their funding of convention ministries. About 2,500 messengers, or delegates, from congregations across the state approved moderate-backed statements saying they would do so unless the convention provides `` more direct communication, accountability and flexibility regarding matters of conscience.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881117-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-17-88 0057EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Japan-Beaujolais     11-17 0411</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Japan-Beaujolais,0423</SECOND>
<HEAD>Japanese Plunge Into Beaujolais Nouveau</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TAKESHI NAKANISHI</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Japanese wine lovers plunged into the first batch of <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>'s 1988 <ORGANIZATION> Beaujolais </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nouveau </ORGANIZATION> early today, marking the start of what industry officials predict will be a record year in sales of the wine in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>. A fleet of more than 400 trucks loaded to the brim with cases of new Beaujolais spread out across <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION> to deliver the red burgundy to restaurants and distributors following its release by customs. Because the distribution embargo on the wine was lifted at midnight local time around the world, Tokyoites received their <ORGANIZATION> Beaujolais </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nouveau </ORGANIZATION> eight hours ahead of Parisians. Corks popped and wine glasses brimmed over at one of the first Beaujolais Nouveau parties of the year at <ORGANIZATION> Le </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Maestro </ORGANIZATION>, a <LOCATION> French </LOCATION> restaurant in <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Shigeta </PERSON> <PERSON> Saito </PERSON>, a well-known psychiatrist and one of some 30 guests at the restaurant, led the toast by announcing: `` The Beaujolais Nouveau of 1988 has arrived ... Bravo.'' The 72-year-old <PERSON> Saito </PERSON>, who says he indulges in all types of alcoholic beverages, said he came to the early-morning gathering `` just out of curiosity.'' Participants, who paid $ 40 a head, all said they were pleased with the newest batch of wine, released every fall following the grape harvest. <PERSON> Hiroshi </PERSON> <PERSON> Yamamoto </PERSON>, lawyer and organizer of the wine-tasting, said <PERSON> Beaujolais </PERSON> <PERSON> Nouveau </PERSON>, a newly fermented wine, appeals to Japanese wine drinkers because it contains less tannin than wine fermented for longer periods of time. `` And traditionally, Japanese have fun drinking and consuming the fresh food items of each season,'' he added. Industry officials are already predicting a record year in sales for the wine, which is produced in <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>'s Beaujolais region. Officials of <ORGANIZATION> Suntory </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ltd. </ORGANIZATION>, a major Japanese distiller and leading importer of Beaujolais, said overall imports of the new wine will total 153,000 cases in 1988, an increase of over 70 percent compared to last year. Suntory alone will import 23,000 cases of the 1988 Beaujolais Nouveau wine, up from 12,000 cases last year, to meet the growing thirst of Japanese wine drinkers, said <PERSON> Kiyoshi </PERSON> <PERSON> Inoue </PERSON>, a spokesman for <ORGANIZATION> Suntory </ORGANIZATION>. Japanese consumers, who already pay the world's highest food and beverage prices, will be expected to put up with hefty price tags on the new Beaujolais. <ORGANIZATION> Suntory </ORGANIZATION>'s <PERSON> Inoue </PERSON> estimated that airfreighted <PERSON> Beaujolais </PERSON> will be sell in the range of $ 14 to $ 30 a bottle, while wine arriving one month later by ship will for $ 6.50 to $ 15.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881117-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-17-88 0100EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-SpaceShuttle     11-17 0349</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Space Shuttle,0357</SECOND>
<HEAD>NASA Announces Dec. 1 Launch Date, But Little Else</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By HOWARD BENEDICT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Aerospace Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CAPE CANAVERAL, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> pronounced the space shuttle Atlantis `` ready to fly'' and set Dec. 1 as its launch date, but the space agency is n't divulging the liftoff time or length of the secret <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> mission. Rear Adm. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Truly </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION>'s associate administrator for space flight, made the announcement Wednesday following a two-day flight readiness review of the mission, which will carry five military astronauts and a spy satellite. The launch will be the second for the shuttle program since the Challenger explosion that killed seven astronauts in January 1986. Following a 32-month period of major modifications, the program resumed Sept. 29 with the successful launch of Discovery and a five-man crew. `` I am pleased to report that the space shuttle Atlantis is as ready to fly as Discovery was at this same point before its flight last September,'' Truly said. The publicity that heralded Discovery's flight will be missing for Atlantis, with <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> and the Pentagon cloaking most information in secrecy because of the military payload. The exact launch time and length of the mission will not be disclosed in advance, and once <LOCATION> Atlantis </LOCATION> is in orbit, there will be a news blackout until the landing. Defense officials said the secrecy would make it more difficult for Soviet ground and space systems to monitor the launch and the deployment of the payload. Sources said they expect a liftoff about 7 a.m. EST and report the astronauts will deploy an intelligence-gathering satellite whose assignments include helping American intelligence officials verify that the Soviets are complying with arms control treaties. The sources also reported the five crew members will conduct several experiments aimed at defining man's role as a military observer in space. The all-military crew is commanded by <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> Cmdr. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gibson </PERSON>. The pilot is Air Force Lt. Col. <PERSON> Guy </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gardner </PERSON> and the mission specialists are <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> Col. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Mullane </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> Lt. Col. <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Ross </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> Cmdr. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shepherd </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881117-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-17-88 0105EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Cincinnati-Handguns     11-17 0192</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Cincinnati-Handguns,0197</SECOND>
<HEAD>Cincinnati Approves Handgun Law</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CINCINNATI (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> on Wednesday overrode intense opposition by the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rifle </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> and enacted a law requiring prospective handgun owners to wait 15 days before picking up their weapons. The ordinance, approved 7-2, takes effect Dec. 16. Mayor <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Luken </PERSON>, a council member who proposed the ordinance, praised the council for passing the law over the <ORGANIZATION> NRA </ORGANIZATION>'s pressure The pressure included a deluge of letters and telephone calls to council members, and booing and heckling to drown out people who spoke in favor of the proposal at the council's public hearing Tuesday. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Gardiner </PERSON>, an <ORGANIZATION> NRA </ORGANIZATION> assistant general counsel in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, said <LOCATION> Cincinnati </LOCATION>'s law appears to be broader than that of some other cities in that it applies to handgun sales by individuals as well as dealers. <PERSON> Gardiner </PERSON> said that without seeing a copy of <LOCATION> Cincinnati </LOCATION>'s law, he could not say whether the <ORGANIZATION> NRA </ORGANIZATION> would try to challenge it in the courts Some other cities and states, including <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, also require waiting periods before allowing purchase of handguns. The <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> on Sept. 15 rejected a proposed seven-day waiting period.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881117-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-17-88 0111EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-NIreland-Weapons     11-17 0286</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-NIreland-Weapons,0295</SECOND>
<HEAD>Arms Could Have Been Used Against Republic, King Says</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BELFAST, Northern Ireland (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Authorities arrested 10 people and seized a rocket-powered grenade launcher, rifles, warheads and other weapons believed to belong to Protestant loyalist guerrillas. Northern Ireland Secretary <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> King </PERSON> said the huge arms cache found in British-ruled <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION> on Wednesday could have been used against targets in the <LOCATION> Irish </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Republic </LOCATION>. The Royal Ulster Constabulary, the province's police force, said it arrested 10 people after seizing the arms in a predominantly <ORGANIZATION> Protestant </ORGANIZATION> public housing project 30 miles southwest of <LOCATION> Belfast </LOCATION>. It said the weapons included a rocket-propelled grenade launcher and five warheads, rifles, hand grenades, more than 12,000 rounds of ammunition and inoperative scrap parts for a missile launcher. `` Here we have an apprehension by the police of what appear to be loyalist weapons which, no doubt, could have been used against targets in the republic,'' King told reporters at Stormont Castle, the seat of government in <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION>. `` I think it clearly indicates the importance and the effect of increased cooperation on security,'' he said. Loyalist is the term used for the province's <ORGANIZATION> Protestant </ORGANIZATION> majority, who want to remain under the British flag as part of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kingdom </LOCATION> and not merge with the overwhelmingly Roman Catholic Irish Republic. <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION> police said earlier that so far this year they recovered from <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Protestant </ORGANIZATION> guerrilla groups 438 guns, 90,000 rounds of ammunition, 9,600 pounds of explosives, 111 rockets and mortars and 200 pounds of plastic explosive. Another 8,300 pounds of explosive was recovered from defused bombs. The mainly Catholic and outlawed <ORGANIZATION> Irish </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> is fighting to end British rule in <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION> and unite it with the republic.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881117-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-17-88 0113EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FarmScene     11-17 0977</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Farm Scene,980</SECOND>
<HEAD>Exotic Vegetables Catching On In American Supermarkets</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DON KENDALL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Farm Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Bok </PERSON> choy and escarole are n't crops for every farmer, but an <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> economist says such exotic food items are catching the eye of supermarket shoppers. Increasingly, produce counters are also including fruits that are a bit off the trodden path of consumers: pomegranates, guava, kumquats, and melons named <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Clause </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Casaba </PERSON> and <PERSON> Crenshaw </PERSON>. `` Specialty fruit and vegetable displays form a fundamental part of the new up-scale image of many produce sections,'' said <PERSON> Catherine </PERSON> <PERSON> Greene </PERSON> of the department's <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>. Rising demand for specialty produce is in line with a general increase in fruit and vegetable consumption, she said. The average American consumed 427 pounds of fruits and vegetables last year, up 12 percent since 1972. That is a farm weight equivalent before trimming, processing and after-harvest losses, she said Wednesday. <PERSON> Greene </PERSON> said the per capita trend is expected to continue upward, although there could be some year-to-year variations. For example, she said, this year's drought probably will cause some decline from the 1987 average. In any case, specialty fruits and vegetables are the rage among many consumers, and there is no sign the demand will taper off soon. <PERSON> Greene </PERSON>, writing in the agency's <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Food </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Review </ORGANIZATION>, said there are a number of reasons. `` Americans have become more health conscious, eating lots of fruits and vegetables as part of a well-balanced diet,'' she said. `` Consequently, we want a huge selection of produce.'' Further, Americans travel more frequently than they used to, and many want `` foreign'' foods when they return home. `` Unusual fruits and vegetables are appearing on restaurant menus,'' <PERSON> Greene </PERSON> said. `` Also influencing our diets are recent immigrants from the <LOCATION> Caribbean </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Southeast </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION> who have brought their native foods with them.'' A recent survey by the industry's <ORGANIZATION> Food </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Marketing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> showed that the number of items sold in supermarket produce departments more than doubled to 150 between the mid-1970s and the early 1980s. Today, more than 250 items is the norm, including new packs and sizes of traditional fruits and vegetables, along with exotic and specialty produce. Another survey conducted for a trade journal, The <PERSON> Packer </PERSON>, showed the most frequently tried specialty fresh vegetables were alfalfa and bean sprouts, followed by snow peas, pearl onions, parsnips, leeks, baby vegetables, Chinese cabbage and shallots. Moreover, about a third of those surveyed also had seen or heard of less widely known specialty vegetables such as Belgian endive, bok choy, celeriac, daikon, kohlrabi, parsley root and <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION> artichoke. The most frequently tried specialty fresh fruits, in order, were pomegranates, persimmons, kumquats, quince and guavas. Additionally, at least a third of those surveyed had seen or heard of breadfuit, passion fruit, plantains, prickly pear and red bananas. But some fruits were nearly unkown: Asian pears, carambolas, cherimoyas, sapotes, radiccho and rappini. <PERSON> Greene </PERSON> said the survey showed that consumers in the western <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> are more likely to try specialty produce and fresh herbs, another group of growth items. One factor is the West's large Asian and Hispanic populations, with their interests in exotic produce. Also, it was shown that consumers in the upper income brackets eat more of the speciality fruits and vegetables. `` They may be better informed about the variety of produce available and better able to afford the premium prices that specialities sometimes command,'' <PERSON> Greene </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> says the value of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> agricultural exports jumped 26 percent to a four-year high of $ 35.2 billion in the fiscal year that ended on Sept. 30. Actual quantities of grain and other commodities totaled 147.5 million metric tons, up 14 percent from 129.2 million tons shipped in 1986-87 when the value was $ 27.9 billion. The new figures released Wednesday were up from the previous forecast issued on Aug. 25, when the value was projected at $ 34 billion and the volume at 146 million tons. Despite the sharp gains, the year's totals were still far below the record levels of $ 43.8 billion and 162.3 million tons in 1980-81 before world economic conditions, high interest rates, foreign competition and other economic factors triggered annual declines. Deputy Secretary <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Myers </PERSON> credited the 1985 farm law's lower price support mechanisms with making <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> commodities more competitive in world trade <PERSON> Myers </PERSON> said a decline in food prices last month `` proves that export increases did not occur at the expense of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> consumers, despite this summer's damaging drought.'' The <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> says higher commodity prices point to another increase in the value of exports in the fiscal year that began on Oct. 1. But it says the actual volume may decline. A forecast of 1989 farm exports is scheduled for release on Nov. 29. Wheat accounted for two-thirds of the volume increase last fiscal year, and `` significant increases'' were reported for corn, livestock feed and fodder, and vegetable oils. Overall, exports of grains and feeds accounted for more than $ 12.7 billion of the total, up 37 percent. Other categories included: oilseeds and products, $ 7.7 billion, up 19 percent; livestock products, $ 4.9 billion, up 24 percent; horticultural products, $ 3.8 billion, up 21 percent; cotton, $ 2.15 billion, up 50 percent; and tobacco, $ 1.3 billion, up 8 percent.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 This year's drought-reduced grain and soybean harvests will mean sharply higher feed costs for livestock producers in the coming year, with some items costing almost half again as much, says the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>. Drought and hot weather reduced total feed grain production by 34 percent this year to the smallest total since 1983. Prices of feed grains, mostly corn, are expected to average 25 percent to 45 percent above last year's weighted average of $ 76.70 per ton, the department's <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> said Wednesday. Soybean meal prices may average $ 235 to $ 275 per ton, compared with $ 222 in 1987-88.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881117-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-17-88 0114EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-MarielDetainees     11-17 0424</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Mariel Detainees,0434</SECOND>
<HEAD>Deportation Of At Least 12 Mariel Detainees Appears Imminent</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MIAMI (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 At least 12 Mariel prisoners have apparently exhausted their administrative appeals and could be deported within days, but plans are in the works by prisoner advocates to block any deportations, a newspaper reported Thursday. <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Leshaw </PERSON>, director of the non-profit <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> legal aid organization representing Mariel detainees, said he was informed by the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> that there would be an announcement Thursday on the prisoners. Meanwhile, prisoner advocate groups in <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> plan to ask federal judges to stop the deportations, which if carried out would mark the first time Cubans have been deported to their communist homeland since May 1985, The <ORGANIZATION> Miami </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Herald </ORGANIZATION> reported. `` There is a chance if we all speak with one united voice here and explain the merits of our case,'' said <PERSON> Rafael </PERSON> <PERSON> Penalver </PERSON>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Task </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cuban </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Citizen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organizations </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Penalver </PERSON> is a lawyer who helped negotiate the settlement to end riots by 3,800 Mariel detainees in <LOCATION> Oakdale </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> La. </LOCATION>, and at an <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> prison last November. `` We will appeal to President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>. He can block the deportations, even if the people are sitting in an airplane at the airport.'' A special three-member <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> panel was created in the aftermath of the riots to review the cases of 113 Mariel detainees in federal prison in <LOCATION> Talladega </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ala </LOCATION>. In the past two months, the panel has looked at prison records, immigration history, written statements from the prisoners and other materials, but there have been no personal appearances by the prisoners or their lawyers. Deportations to <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> were reinstated as part of a renewed immigration pact between the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> that allows up to 20,000 Cubans and 3,000 political prisoners and their families to emigrate and, in return, the <LOCATION> Cuban </LOCATION> government will take back 2,500 prisoners. The <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> contends that these prisoners are criminals the <LOCATION> Cuban </LOCATION> regime injected into a boatlift of refugees from the port of <LOCATION> Mariel </LOCATION>. Prisoners selected for deportation are being taken from a list of <LOCATION> Mariel </LOCATION> inmates who were imprisoned at the time of the 1984 immigration pact. <PERSON> Jorge </PERSON> <PERSON> Mas </PERSON> <PERSON> Canosa </PERSON>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Cuban-American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION>, acknowledges there is much division over the deporations, even in <LOCATION> Dade </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>'s Cuban exile community. He said the foundation favors letting Cubans apply for visas to immigrate to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> but opposes the deportations to <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION>. `` I can not in one hand denounce the human rights situation in <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> and then support sending them back,'' <PERSON> Mas </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881117-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-17-88 0115EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-DefenseIndictments Bjt   11-17 0671</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Defense Indictments, Bjt,670</SECOND>
<HEAD>Justice Officials Postpone Defense Fraud Indictments</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MICHAEL J. SNIFFEN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> officials have postponed initial indictments in the massive <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> purchasing fraud scandal while they debate whom to charge first. `` We expect action in the very near future but not this week and probably not next week,'' said <PERSON> Sharon </PERSON> <PERSON> Dibbley </PERSON>, spokeswoman for <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Attorney <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> Hudson </PERSON> in suburban <LOCATION> Alexandria </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, where the more than 2-year-old investigation is headquartered. Last month, <PERSON> Hudson </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> sources predicted that the first indictments would be brought by mid-November, but now the best estimates are that the grand jury will vote on charges either very late in November or in early December. A source at <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> headquarters said Wednesday, `` It's still being reviewed here, over legal issues.'' Another government source added, `` It was anticipated that something would happen tomorrow and it will not happen tomorrow.'' <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Russell </PERSON> said Assistant Attorney General <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Dennis </PERSON>, head of the criminal division, `` has never set a timetable. He's told them to take their time and go when the case is in shape.'' Prosecutors say they have evidence that consultants _ including some former high-level <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration officials and former high-ranking military men who work for the nation's largest defense contractors _ bribed <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> officials for information vital to winning contracts worth billions of dollars. Two corporations and three individuals were identified this week by government and defense sources as among the potential targets of the first charges. These sources said consultants <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Parkin </PERSON> and <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> Lackner </PERSON> had been offered plea bargains by prosecutors, but the pair had declined to plead guilty to the charges offered. Those charges included conspiracy and bribery, the sources said. The sources also said prosecutors were weighing charges against <ORGANIZATION> Teledyne </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> , </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, and <ORGANIZATION> Hazeltine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, both of which were searched in <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> raids last June. The sources also suggested that charges were being contemplated against <PERSON> Stuart </PERSON> <PERSON> Berlin </PERSON>, a procurement specialist with the <ORGANIZATION> Naval </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Systems </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Command </ORGANIZATION>. <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> and four other <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> employees have been transferred away from contract work. Other sources, however, had said earlier that no government employee would be among the first group charged. <PERSON> Parkin </PERSON> has said he paid <PERSON> Lackner </PERSON> $ 15,000 to $ 18,000 in late 1986 for information on a pending <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> contract for equipment to distinguish hostile and friendly aircraft. <PERSON> Parkin </PERSON> said he then turned the information over to <LOCATION> Hazeltine </LOCATION> on <LOCATION> Long </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION> <PERSON> Parkin </PERSON> said he concluded the information came from <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> but that it was not secret. <PERSON> Parkin </PERSON> also has said he split fees with <PERSON> Lackner </PERSON> from <ORGANIZATION> Teledyne </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Electronics </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Newbury </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Park </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, which was seeking an <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> contract. But <PERSON> Parkin </PERSON> said they did not have to do any work in that case. <PERSON> Lackner </PERSON>'s attorney, <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Dougherty </PERSON>, said his client `` never gave anybody a nickel.'' <PERSON> Berkley </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Teledyne </ORGANIZATION> spokesman, said, `` We were told this week by the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> that they have made no decision yet. We are not going to respond to unofficial statements from the government. When the government has an official statement, we will respond.'' <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Orso </PERSON>, a spokesman for <ORGANIZATION> Hazeltine </ORGANIZATION>, said, `` We are not commenting on the investigation in any form.'' <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> could not be reached for comment. Some observers have questioned whether <LOCATION> Hazeltine </LOCATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Teledyne </ORGANIZATION> should be included in the same indictment because they did not compete for the same contracts even though they employed the same consultants. One Justice source said there were legal arguments on both sides of that question, and the arguments and theories were changing regularly in the complex case. `` These things tend to change almost daily as you sift the evidence,'' this source said. `` But we do n't want to end up with 30 trials.'' <LOCATION> Hudson </LOCATION> has said charges could be brought over a period of up to a year. At the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Hendricks </PERSON>, chief of the fraud section, said, `` The department is simply interested in ensuring that any actions taken are done diligently and aggressively but with care and to insure propriety.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881117-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-17-88 0124EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Lookingto'92 Bjt   11-17 0630</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Looking to '92, Bjt,620</SECOND>
<HEAD>And You Thought the Campaigns Were Over ...</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP News Analysis</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DONALD M. ROTHBERG</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Political Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Dave </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Brien </PERSON> needed help and he got plenty of it from some big names in the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>: <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Simon </PERSON>, <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON>, <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Biden </PERSON>. They all were eager to help <PERSON> O'Brien </PERSON> in his campaign to unseat Republican Rep. <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Tauke </PERSON>. Their appearances were n't enough. <PERSON> O'Brien </PERSON> got only 36 percent of the vote on Election Day. But for Sens. <PERSON> Simon </PERSON>, <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON> and <PERSON> Biden </PERSON>, the effort was n't wasted. For them, a chance to campaign in <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>, to make a few friends in the state that holds the nation's first presidential caucuses every four years, is no waste of time. Other familiar Democratic faces who campaigned in <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> in 1988 were <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, Rep. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION>, the winner of the 1988 <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> caucuses, and former Gov. <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Babbitt </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION>. Sen. <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> bypassed <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> during the caucus campaign and later as well, but he was on the road elsewhere. With the exception of <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON>, those are all leftover names from 1988. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> and <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> are considered likely contenders for the 1992 Democratic nomination. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, the defeated 1988 Democratic nominee, was `` back at a job I love,'' being governor of <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION>. At his appearances immediately after his defeat, supporters chanted ``'92,'92,'92,'' but <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> refused to discuss the possibility of another presidential campaign. <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> Sen. <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> became something of a folk figure as the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> vice presidential candidate and presumably will receive a lot of early attention as a prospect for the top spot on the ticket in four years. But <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> will be 71 years old in 1992. Another familiar name that comes up every four years is Gov. <PERSON> Mario </PERSON> <PERSON> Cuomo </PERSON> of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>. Twice he's been mentioned and twice he's declined to run Gov. <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Clinton </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Arkansas </LOCATION> decided against running n 1988, but is certain to take another look. `` He does n't know what he'll be doing in four years,'' said spokesman <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Gauldin </PERSON>. Sen. <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> <PERSON> Nunn </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION>, a favorite of Southern conservatives, also considered a 1988 run and opted out. `` It's premature to be talking about personalities in'92, me or anybody else,'' said <PERSON> Nunn </PERSON>. `` It's much too early, premature and downright immature to be talking about 1992 politics,'' said <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, when it became clear on Election Night that <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> was going down to defeat. But while two-time presidential candidate <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> brushed off talk about 1992, he already has formed a political action committee, Keep Hope Alive, and declared his intention to be involved in municipal elections in 1989. He's certain to be involved in the high-profile battle for mayor of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> where incumbent <PERSON> Ed </PERSON> <PERSON> Koch </PERSON> will face a strong challenge fueled in part by his bitter clash with <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> during the 1988 <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> presidential primary. <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> chairman <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kirk </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> hopes the potential 1992 candidates are serious when they say it's premature to start the next presidential campaign. `` Our focus ought to be on 1990,'' said <PERSON> Kirk </PERSON>, who called that the key year for determining which party has the edge when congressional and legislative redistricting takes place after the 1990 Census. That process, occurring once every 10 years, is certain to shift more <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> seats from the Rust Belt to the <LOCATION> Sun </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Belt </LOCATION> and force a redrawing of lines that could change the political makeup of scores of <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> districts. Maybe <PERSON> Kirk </PERSON> can keep Democrats focused on redistricting. But as he is well aware, the first poll assessing the potential 1992 field is almost certain to be taken before Christmas 1988.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Rothberg </PERSON> is the chief political writer for <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881117-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-17-88 0126EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Bush     11-17 0301</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bush,300</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush's Role In Gorbachev Meeting Will Be As VP</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s role in next month's meeting between President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and Soviet leader <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> will be as vice president, and any discussions about <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s future dealings with the <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION> leader will be `` fairly brief,'' a spokesman said. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, the president-elect, will be attending the talks in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> with <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> when the Soviet leader is in town to address the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION>. `` It should not be expected that the meeting is being designed as a summit or designed with a set of objectives in mind that would be the kinds of things that we would hope for in a future meeting,'' <PERSON> Craig </PERSON> <PERSON> Fuller </PERSON>, a co-director of <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s transition team, said Wednesday. He said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> would be prepared to take stock of U.S.-Soviet developments over the past eight years. `` He will particpate in the meeting as vice president,'' <PERSON> Fuller </PERSON> said. `` We're not certain exactly what the scenario is going to be for those discussions but any discussion they have about the future I think will be fairly brief and will be designed merely to set the stage for each other's approach with regard to meetings in the months ahead,'' <PERSON> Fuller </PERSON> added. <PERSON> Fuller </PERSON> commented at a news conference where the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> team also announced that all people involved in his transition are being asked to sign a code of conduct pledging they will not leak any news about assignments in the new administration and will avoid any conflict of interest. After talks today with <LOCATION> British </LOCATION> Prime Minister <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> and a separate meeting with <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> returns to the job of assembling a Cabinet. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Teeter </PERSON>, another transition co-director, said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> would review candidates today for two or three Cabinet posts, which he did not identify.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881117-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-17-88 0130EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lottery     11-17 0049</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lottery,0051</SECOND>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the winning weekly state lottery numbers picked Wednesday:
</TEXT>
<HEAD>MASSACHUSETTS</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Wednesday Megabucks: 03; 04; 07; 21; 28; 29.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>NEW YORK</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Wednesday Lotto 54 Game: 09; 23; 33; 49; 51; 54. Supplementary 32.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>RHODE ISLAND</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Grand Lot Game: 9-5-0; 2-2-5-3; 1-9-1-1-3; 3-9-3-1-6-3.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881117-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-17-88 0132EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-SocialSecurity Bjt   11-17 0750</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Social Security, Bjt,750</SECOND>
<HEAD>Study Finds No Solution To Fix Discrepancies In Benefits</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JILL LAWRENCE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Social Security benefits to people born before 1917 are higher than <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> intended, but there's no practical way to fix the inequity, a study concludes. <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> should neither reduce benefits to those getting the unintended windfall nor raise them for everyone else, said the study released Wednesday by the non-partisan <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Social </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Insurance </ORGANIZATION>. `` I would strongly hope that this issue can be put to rest'' as a result of the report, said <PERSON> Suzanne </PERSON> <PERSON> Dilk </PERSON>, a former senior analyst with the <ORGANIZATION> Social </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> and one of four experts on the study panel. In a related development, lawmakers and lobbyists reacted angrily to a draft government proposal that would make it harder for the elderly, disabled and poor to appeal government decisions denying them welfare or Social Security benefits. The proposed rule, still under review, would require people to submit all evidence at least seven days in advance of a hearing before an administrative law judge. Current regulations permit new evidence to be introduced during or after the hearing. The benefits report focused on a category of Social Security recipients known as `` notch babies,'' _ those born between 1917 and 1921. It said their benefits in some cases are as much as $ 200 a month less than those of people born earlier. But the notch babies are receiving the level of benefits <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> intended and in fact are at an advantage compared to people born after them, the report concluded. The inequity, the report said, lies in the fact that those born before 1917 are getting higher benefits than <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> intended _ not that others are receiving too little. The notch, or discrepancy in benefits, arose when <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> adopted a new formula meant to keep rising Social Security benefits at a constant percentage of a person's average pre-retirement earnings. However, people born before 1917 were allowed to use the old, over-generous method of calculation. The result: a benefit rate that peaked in 1981 at 56 percent of average earnings, about 15 percentage points higher than what <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> had intended. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Myers </PERSON>, chairman of the study panel and formerly executive director of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> on </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Social </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reform </ORGANIZATION>, said there are probably about 1 million notch babies feeling `` substantial impact'' from the situation. He estimated it would cost up to $ 300 billion to equalize everyone's benefits _ and that would create new notches affecting those born in later years. He said it would be difficult and expensive to find the individuals who got windfalls, not to mention politically impossible to cut their benefits. `` We are not in favor of keeping a discrepancy in the law,'' said panel member <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Kelley </PERSON>, former staff director to the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ways </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Means </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>'s Social Security subcommittee. But he added: `` You find a member of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> who wants to lower benefits. ... Good luck.'' Many on Capitol Hill, meanwhile, reacted angrily Wednesday to the draft proposal making it more difficult for the elderly, disabled and poor to appeal government decisions to deny welfare or Social Security benefits. `` There they go again,'' said Rep. <PERSON> Claude </PERSON> <PERSON> Pepper </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Fla </LOCATION>., 88, the oldest member of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and its foremost champion of the elderly He challenged President-elect <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> to kill the plan and said if it goes forward, <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> will `` stop this thing in its tracks.'' The draft rules on Social Security appeals were designed to reduce a staggering load of appeals hearings. Last year, the agency received 5.5 million claims and 250,000 requests for appeals hearings. <PERSON> Chuck </PERSON> <PERSON> Kline </PERSON>, a spokesman for <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Human </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Otis </PERSON> <PERSON> Bowen </PERSON>, said the Social Security and <ORGANIZATION> Medicare </ORGANIZATION> appeals processes must become more efficient. `` The solution they are suggesting -LRB- in the <ORGANIZATION> Social </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> -RRB- may not be workable or doable, and until it's reviewed, you do n't know that,'' he said. But critics were quick to attack the draft proposals. Several charged they would violate the spirit of the 1935 Social Security Act as well as a 1971 <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> ruling supporting an informal and liberal appeals process easily accessible to the elderly, poor and disabled who often do not have lawyers. <PERSON> Horace </PERSON> <PERSON> Deets </PERSON>, executive director of the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Retired </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Persons </ORGANIZATION>, called the proposals `` misguided and unjustified.'' <PERSON> Ken </PERSON> <PERSON> Hoagland </PERSON>, a spokesman for the private <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> to Preserve Social Security and Medicare, accused the administration of `` trying to stack the deck against disability appeal claimants.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881117-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-17-88 0134EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Brazil     11-17 0629</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Brazil,0649</SECOND>
<HEAD>Surge For Leftist Mayors Indicates Displeasure With President's
Party</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BRUCE HANDLER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>RIO DE JANEIRO, Brazil (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Brazilians expressed frustration with President <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Sarney </PERSON>'s center-right government, economic chaos and corruption by giving massive support to leftists in muncipal elections around the nation. `` At least now the voters ca n't blame us for everything that goes wrong with <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION>,'' said Gov. <PERSON> Pedro </PERSON> <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Rio </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Grande </LOCATION> do Sul state, a member of <PERSON> Sarney </PERSON>'s Brazilian <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Movement </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>. Early returns from Tuesday's balloting showed that the dominant party since 1964 was taking a beating from both the right and the left, but that leftists were surging ahead for control of major cities. Final results were not expected until Sunday. Analysts said voters were dissatisfied with a record 1,000 percent annual inflation rate, the falling value of the cruzado, political corruption and nearly constant strikes. `` The voters did n't send us just a message. A message is short. This was a telex,'' said Gov. <PERSON> Wellington </PERSON> <PERSON> Moreira </PERSON> <PERSON> Franco </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Rio </LOCATION> <LOCATION> de </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Janeiro </LOCATION> state, a member of <PERSON> Sarney </PERSON>'s party. In the biggest upset, <PERSON> Luiza </PERSON> <PERSON> Erundina </PERSON>, a 53-year-old social worker and a Marxist from the <ORGANIZATION> Workers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, was expected to win as mayor of <LOCATION> Sao </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Paulo </LOCATION>, the country's largest city. With 15 percent of the city's more than 5 million votes counted, Ms. <PERSON> Erundina </PERSON> led <PERSON> Paulo </PERSON> <PERSON> Maluf </PERSON>, a wealthy industrialist and former military-backed presidential candidate, by 4 percent. Ms. <PERSON> Erundina </PERSON> told reporters she would concentrate municipal funding on public health, transportation and abandoned children, areas in which `` hardly anything ever was invested before.'' In Rio, the No. 2 city, the winner was <PERSON> Marcello </PERSON> <PERSON> Alencar </PERSON>, a 63-year-old lawyer from the leftist <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>. He is a close ally of <PERSON> Leonel </PERSON> <PERSON> Brizola </PERSON>, the expected candidate of the left in next year's presidential elections. With 28 percent of the ballots counted, <PERSON> Alencar </PERSON> had one-third more votes than his closest opponent. The projected winner in <PERSON> Belo </PERSON> <PERSON> Horizonte </PERSON>, the third-largest city, was <PERSON> Joao </PERSON> <PERSON> Pimenta </PERSON> da <PERSON> Veiga </PERSON> <PERSON> Filho </PERSON>, 41, of the left-center <ORGANIZATION> Brazilian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Social </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democracy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>. This group recently broke away from <PERSON> Sarney </PERSON>'s party The Democratic Movement, which swept mayoral elections in 1985 and captured 22 of 23 state governorships in 1986, appeared headed for mayoralty wins in just four capitals. Leftists seemed assured of victory in at least seven important state capitals. Candidates from various groups to the right of <PERSON> Sarney </PERSON>'s were headed toward wins in seven other capitals. The biggest prize for the rightists was the large northeastern city of <LOCATION> Recife </LOCATION>, where <PERSON> Joaquim </PERSON> <PERSON> Francisco </PERSON> <PERSON> Cavalcanti </PERSON>, 40, of the <ORGANIZATION> Liberal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, was far ahead. He resigned this year from <PERSON> Sarney </PERSON>'s Cabinet. Races in the remaining capitals were too close to call or the results were not yet in because of the cities' remoteness. The <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Movement </ORGANIZATION> and <PERSON> Sarney </PERSON> have controlled Brazilian politics since the nation of 144 million returned in 1985 to civilian rule after a 21-year military dictatorship. <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION> is in the throes of its worst strike by petroleum workers. The state-owned oil monopoly <ORGANIZATION> Petrobras </ORGANIZATION> said Wednesday that <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION> has nearly run out of diesel oil and cooking gas because of the six-day nationwide strike. Twenty-nine parties participated in the election for mayors and city councils of more than 4,000 cities and towns. The races were based largely on local issues, but analysts said they indicate general feelings about presidential elections scheduled for Nov. 15, 1989. It will be the first presidential election in <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION> in 29 years. The 58-year-old <PERSON> Sarney </PERSON> is a civilian, but he gained office indirectly through an electoral college system imposed by the departing military regime. He was the vice presidential candidate on a ticket headed by <PERSON> Tancredo </PERSON> <PERSON> Neves </PERSON>, a popular centrist political figure. <PERSON> Neves </PERSON> died before he could assume office, and <PERSON> Sarney </PERSON> moved into the top spot.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881117-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-17-88 0133EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-SeawayCoal     11-17 0242</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Seaway Coal,270</SECOND>
<HEAD>U.S. Coal Exports Through St. Lawrence Seaway Increase</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Problems among foreign coal producers and the lower dollar abroad contributed to a 247 percent increase in the amount of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> coal shipped through the St. <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> <PERSON> Seaway </PERSON>, officials say. The increase, to 569,000 metric tons, was recorded during the period from April to October, as compared to the same period last year. Spurring the demand for American-mined coal were the lower value of the dollar; competitive worldwide ocean freight rates; a tight supply due to a series of industrial disputes last summer in <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION>; sanctions against using South African coal; and production problems and rising production costs in <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> coal exports through the seaway in April-October of 1987 totaled 234,000 metric tons. In 1985 and 1986, the biggest coal years since 1982, coal exports just exceeded 600,000 tons each year. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Emery </PERSON>, administrator of the <ORGANIZATION> Saint </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lawrence </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Seaway </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, which operates the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> portion of the American-Canadian channel, said the majority of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> export coal through the system so far this year has been transported to <LOCATION> Denmark </LOCATION> for power production. Nationally, 1988 <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> coal exports as of Aug. 31 totaled 52.2 million metric tons, up 15 percent from the same period last year, according to the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>. The seaway begins at the mouth of the <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lawrence </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> and runs through the <LOCATION> Great </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lakes </LOCATION>, ending 2,342 miles later at <LOCATION> Duluth </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Minn </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881117-0025 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-17-88 0134EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-AgingAmerica     11-17 0658</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Aging America,660</SECOND>
<HEAD>Nation's Median Age Heading Upward</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RANDOLPH E. SCHMID</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Thirty-nine, that magic age teetering between youth and maturity, will be the most typical age for Americans early in the next century, according to <ORGANIZATION> Census </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> projections. Historically a nation of youthful orientation, the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> is now thirty-something, heading upward, the <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> reports. Combining to increase the median age of the population are the maturing of the massive post World War II Baby Boom and that generation's relatively low birth rates, which reduce the number of babies to pull down the numbers. So if present trends continue, census officials expect that half of all Americans will be over the age of 39 by the year 2010, and half younger. The agency's most recent estimate of median age was 31.7, as of 1986. Whether <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> will plateau at 39 _ as did the late comedian <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Benny </PERSON> _ remains to be seen. The median age of the country touched 30 for the first time in 1950, then slipped back as the Baby Boom produced a bouncing crop of youngsters to lower the numbers. It took until the 1980 census to hit 30 again, edged up to 31.7 as of 1986 and is expected to climb to 33 by 1990, 36.5 by 2000 and 39 by the year 2010, according to the new projections from the <ORGANIZATION> Census </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION>. Despite the aging of the population, however, the report anticipates that the so-called dependency ratio will decline. That ratio is the number of people under 18 and over 65 compared to the number of people of working age in between. The younger and older groups are most likely to `` depend'' on those working. The 1986 ratio of 62.2 dependents per 100 workers is expected to slip to 56.7 by the year 2010, with the low birth rate reducing the number of young dependents to a greater extent than aging adds to the older group. While there have been reports of increases in the total number of births in the last few years, that is because the giant Baby Boom generation is largely in its prime childbearing years. The rate of births per 1,000 remains well below that of the post-World War II period. The new census study also estimates that the nation's black population will increase to 13.7 percent by 2010. Blacks made up 11.8 percent of the population in the 1980 census. Nearly one in five Southerners will be black in 2010, 19.7 percent of the population. That will be up from 18.7 percent in 1980. In the Northeast, blacks will increase from 10.1 percent to 13.2 percent. They will go from 9.1 percent to 11.9 percent in the <LOCATION> Midwest </LOCATION> and from 5.3 percent to 6.3 percent in the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION>. The projections show the Northeast remaining the oldest section of the country, with the median age for that region increasing from 33.6 in 1986 to 40.3 in 2010. The South will be second in 2010 at a median age of 38.4, up from 31.4 in 1986. The Midwest will mature from 31.6 to 38.8 and the West will go from 31.0 to 37.4. <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> will remain the state with the highest median age and <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION> will still be the youngest state, according to the projections. <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>, with a median age of 36.0 in 1986, will age to 45.3. <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION>'s median will rise from 25.5 to 27.6, leaving it the only state with a median age below 30 years, thanks largely to a continuing high birth rate. In the 1986 estimates no state had a median over 40 but several were under 30, including _ besides <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION> _ <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION>. In 2010 not only <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> will have topped 40. Other states with median ages above that milestone will include <LOCATION> Arkansas </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Rhode </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881117-0026 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-17-88 0135EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Intelligence-Bush     11-17 0235</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Intelligence-Bush,230</SECOND>
<HEAD>Conservatives Urge More US Covert Actions</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A conservative group contends that President-elect <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> should make covert action a routine technique in the American spy arsenal. A study sponsored by the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Strategic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Information </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> says covert action _ unacknowledged financial, political or military action to influence events in foreign countries _ should be restored as a common tool of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> foreign policy. `` American intelligence, as it is presently constituted, will not be up to the challenges of the'90s,'' said <PERSON> Roy </PERSON> <PERSON> Godson </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> Georgetown </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, who edited the study. The report was released Wednesday at a news conference. The report says covert action tactics have been tainted in the eyes of the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> public by the Iran-Contra scandal. While covert actions have proliferated under the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration, they still are viewed by the public and many within the <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> as stepchildren, the study concluded. It also said <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> intelligence analysts should do more to spot the vulnerabilities of foreign governments and leaders and point out opportunities for <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> leverage and influence. The report said `` there will be major opportunities for the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> to advance its interests in the 1990s through a broad array of -LRB- covert action -RRB- techniques.'' <PERSON> Kenneth </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> deGraffenreid </PERSON>, former intelligence director at the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration's <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>, said covert action `` should be perceived as a useful, limited adjunct, and a normal one, to statecraft.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881117-0027 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-17-88 0136EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-DeficitCommission     11-17 0717</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Deficit Commission,700</SECOND>
<HEAD>Advisory Panel Told Quick Action Needed To Cut Budget Gap</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARTIN CRUTSINGER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
