<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880830-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-30-88 2341EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p AM-GeorgiaPrimary 1stLd-Writethru a0662 08-30 0319</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Georgia Primary, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0662,0326</SECOND>
<HEAD>Voters Decide Congressional Runoff</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ATLANTA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A businessman defeated a city planner Tuesday in a Republican primary runoff for the right to challenge Democratic Rep. <PERSON> George </PERSON> `` Buddy'' <PERSON> Darden </PERSON>, while a late-breaking campaign financing controversy complicated another state race. According to unofficial returns from all 207 precincts, <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Lamutt </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Cobb </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> had 6,220 votes, or 52 percent, to 5,691, or 48 percent, for <PERSON> Kevin </PERSON> <PERSON> Johns </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Roswell </LOCATION> planner. The two were the surviving candidates for the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION>'s 7th District nomination after the primary election three weeks ago. The race was thrown into a runoff when neither could claim a majority. <PERSON> Darden </PERSON> was unopposed in the Democratic congressional primary. In <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION>'s only statewide primary runoff, former state Sen. <PERSON> Bobby </PERSON> <PERSON> Rowan </PERSON> won the Democratic nomination for a seat on the utility-regulating <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> Tuesday after a bitter fight with state Rep. <PERSON> Cathey </PERSON> <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON>. According to unofficial returns from 2,290 of the 2,569 precincts, <PERSON> Rowan </PERSON> had 216,321, or 55 percent, to Ms. <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON>'s 176,175, or 45 percent While polls were still open, a transcript unsealed in federal court indicated <ORGANIZATION> Georgia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Power </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> supervisors and managers were pressured to make contributions to <PERSON> Rowan </PERSON>. Utility officials said that would violate `` a very important policy'' of the company, and <PERSON> Rowan </PERSON> called the allegations `` reckless and unfounded.'' In a mid-evening telephone interview after the contest appeared concluded, <PERSON> Rowan </PERSON> refused to say he would decline future contributions from sources with power company interests. `` If I go on the commission, we ought to talk about what we're going to do about this,'' he said `` I should n't try to stand out as an island by myself.'' Ms. <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON> said, `` I'm not going to win; the utilities are going to win. My opponent beat me to death with a money bag.'' She said <PERSON> Rowan </PERSON> distorted her legislative record in ads aired throughout the state and described the campaign as `` very nasty.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880830-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-30-88 2351EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Philippines-Politics     08-30 0258</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Philippines-Politics,0264</SECOND>
<HEAD>Military Claims Pro-Marcos Renegades Reorganizing</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MANILA, Philippines (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A military official said Tuesday that renegade soldiers loyal to ousted President <PERSON> Ferdinand </PERSON> <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> have organized a new strike force to try to topple President <PERSON> Corazon </PERSON> <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON>. Col. <PERSON> Guilleromo </PERSON> <PERSON> Ruiz </PERSON>, chief of staff of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Capital </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Region </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Command </ORGANIZATION>, told reporters in the capital that the new group called itself `` <ORGANIZATION> Marcos </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lost </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Command </ORGANIZATION>.'' <PERSON> Ruiz </PERSON> said the force was made up of troops who deserted the <ORGANIZATION> Presidential </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Command </ORGANIZATION> after <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> fled to <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION> after the 1986 civilian-military uprising toppled his administration. `` Lost Command'' is a Filipino term for military units which desert and hire out as `` private armies'' of politicians, businessmen and others. Military officials gave no estimate of the size of the group. They said the renegades were believed linked to forces loyal to renegade former Lt. Col. <PERSON> Reynaldo </PERSON> <PERSON> Cabauatan </PERSON>, who has been sought since a coup attempt in January 1987. Troops in the <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION> area went on alert Saturday to guard against coup attempts while President <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON> visited <LOCATION> Brunei </LOCATION>. She was expected to return Wednesday after a three-day visit. On Monday, troops raided suspected right-wing hideouts in the <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION> area and arrested three renegades believed linked to former Brig. Gen. <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Marie </PERSON> <PERSON> Zumel </PERSON>. The former superintendent of the <ORGANIZATION> Philippine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Military </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION> is also sought in the January 1987 coup attempt. The government said that coup attempt, which included the seizing of military and media facilities in the capital, was designed to pave the way for <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> to return from exile in <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880830-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-30-88 2355EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-Titan-Evacuation     08-30 0352</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Titan-Evacuation,0362</SECOND>
<HEAD>Fuel Leak Spurs Evacuation Of Launch Pad For Classified Titan
Flight</HEAD>
<DATELINE>VANDENBERG AIR FORCE BASE, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Leaking rocket fuel forced the evacuation of a Titan 2 launch pad during the weekend, the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> said Tuesday. The <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> declined to confirm whether the mishap Sunday delayed the classified launch of four <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> spy satellites. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Pike </PERSON>, a space policy expert at the Washington-based <ORGANIZATION> Federation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Scientists </ORGANIZATION>, said last week that a classified Titan 2 launch was expected soon. He said the one-time intercontinental ballistic missile, in its maiden flight as a space booster, was almost certain to carry into orbit a set of four <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cloud </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ocean </ORGANIZATION> Surveillance System satellites designed to eavesdrop on radio and radar transmissions by the Soviet fleet. The <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Martin </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Marietta </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> have previously said that <ORGANIZATION> Space </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Launch </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Complex </ORGANIZATION> 4 West will be used to launch refurbished Titan 2s carrying military payloads. `` We had a minor vapor escape of monomethyl hydrazine at Space Launch Complex 4 West this weekend,'' said Capt. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON>, a spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Space </ORGANIZATION> and Missile Test Organization at this military base 140 miles northwest of <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>. `` The leak was detected by our sensors and the pad was evacuated with our safety procedures,'' he added. `` The vapor dispersed harmlessly into the atmosphere. At no time was there any danger to the base or community population'' in nearby <LOCATION> Vandenberg </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Village </LOCATION> or the neighboring city of <LOCATION> Lompoc </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON> emphasized the leak was n't serious, but said he did n't know how many people were evacuated from the launch pad He also declined comment on whether a Titan 2 was being loaded with the hydrazine fuel to prepare it for a classified launch. For about 25 years, Titan 2 rockets served as ICBMs, each carrying a nine-megaton hydrogen warhead. Maintenance and safety problems spurred removal of the obsolete missiles from their silos in <LOCATION> Arkansas </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> has ordered 13 Titan 2s reconditioned as space boosters under a $ 528.9 million contract with <ORGANIZATION> Martin </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Marietta </ORGANIZATION> because it was cheaper than building new rockets.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880830-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-30-88 0029EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-BoxOffice     08-30 0486</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Box Office,0505</SECOND>
<HEAD>`Nightmare' Remains At Top</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RICHARD DE ATLEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>HOLLYWOOD (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The latest `` Nightmare on Elm Street'' movie retained first place in box office revenues last weekend, while `` Betrayed,'' about white supremacists in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, made its debut in second place. `` Nightmare on Elm Street 4: The Dream Master'' earned $ 6.9 million last weekend. `` Betrayed,'' the Costa-Gavras directed thriller, took in more than $ 5.5 million. Two other movies made debuts in the top 10, with `` Stealing Home'' coming in ninth and `` Hot To Trot'' finishing 10th. `` A Fish Called Wanda'' moved to third place from fourth last week, earning $ 3.7 million. `` Die Hard'' was fourth with $ 3.66 million, and has earned $ 52 million so far as the summer's solid action-adventure film. `` Young Guns'' dropped from last week's second place to fifth place this week with $ 3.62 million. Disney's `` Who Framed Roger Rabbit'' reached a new plateau in earnings last weekend. Its $ 2.98 million, good for sixth place, brought its total to $ 124.6 million, making it the second-highest grossing Disney movie. Last year's `` Three Men and A Baby,'' from <ORGANIZATION> Disney </ORGANIZATION>'s Touchstone division, earned $ 167.4 million. In seventh place was `` Cocktail'' with $ 2.92 million, followed by `` Married To The Mob'' with $ 2.4 million. `` Stealing Home'' was good for $ 2.3 million and ninth place, with `` Hot to Trot'' earning $ 2.2 million for 10th place. `` The Last Temptation of Christ,'' in its third week of release, was on 48 screens compared with 18 in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> last week, with ticket sales for the Universal movie at $ 561,631 for the weekend and $ 11,701 per screen. The movie, which has spurred protests from some Christians, has so far grossed $ 2.6 million. Here are the top films for the weekend as tallied by Exhibitor Relations, with distributor, weekend gross, number of theater screens, average per screen, total gross and number of weeks in release. 1. `` Nightmare On Elm Street 4: The Dream Master,'' New Line, $ 6.9 million, 1,767 screens, $ 3,955 per screen, $ 25 million, two weeks. 2. `` Betrayed,'' <ORGANIZATION> MGM-UA </ORGANIZATION>, $ 5.5 million, 1,036 screens, $ 5,342 per screen, $ 5.5 million, one week. 3. `` A Fish Called Wanda,'' <ORGANIZATION> MGM-UA </ORGANIZATION>, $ 3.7 million, 1,223 screens, $ 3,083 per screen, $ 30.7 million, seven weeks. 4. `` Die Hard,'' 20th Century <PERSON> Fox </PERSON>, $ 3.66 million, 1,432 screens, $ 2,561 per screen, $ 52 million, seven weeks. 5. `` Young Guns,'' 20th <ORGANIZATION> Century </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fox </ORGANIZATION>, $ 3.62 million, 1,371 screens, $ 2,645 per screen, $ 22.9 million, three weeks. 6. `` Who Framed <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> Rabbit </PERSON>,'' Disney, $ 2.98 million, 1,549 screens, $ 1,924 per screen, $ 124.6 million, 10 weeks. 7. `` Cocktail,'' <ORGANIZATION> Disney </ORGANIZATION>, $ 2.92 million, 1,339 screens, $ 2,185 per screen, $ 51.4 million, five weeks. 8. `` Married to the Mob,'' <ORGANIZATION> Orion </ORGANIZATION>, $ 2.4 million, 826 screens, $ 2,907 per screen, $ 7.4 million, two weeks. 9. `` Stealing Home,'' <ORGANIZATION> Warner </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bros. </ORGANIZATION>, $ 2.3 million, 984 screens, $ 2,385 per screen, $ 2.3 million, one week. 10. `` Hot To Trot,'' <ORGANIZATION> Warner </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bros. </ORGANIZATION>, $ 2.2 million, 1,056 screens, $ 2,089 per screen, $ 2.2 million, one week.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880830-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-30-88 0113EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FarmScene     08-30 0817</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Farm Scene,800</SECOND>
<HEAD>Farmers' 1989 Income Forecast Down</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DON KENDALL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Farm Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> says there is some likelihood that farmers' net cash income in 1989 will drop from this year's level, even if there are drought-busting rains and production increases. According to the department's <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>, production expenses `` may increase substantially'' in calendar 1989, judging from what has happened after previous droughts and an expected boost in plantings as a result of relaxed acreage set-aside requirements. `` As in the second half of 1988, higher feed prices will affect 1989's costs,'' the agency said in a new outlook report. `` Higher prices for feeder cattle likely will help boost livestock incomes. For crops, bigger planted acreage will boost expenditures for seed, fertilizer, chemical and fuels.'' The report in the September issue of Agricultural Outlook magazine by economists <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Kodl </PERSON> and <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> <PERSON> Bernat </PERSON> said 1988 net cash farm income is expected to be in the range of $ 55 billion to $ 60 billion, near last year's record of $ 57.1 billion. They offered no specific figure for 1989 income. <PERSON> Bernat </PERSON> said Monday that the first official projections for 1989 farm income wo n't be made until November but that `` we thought it would add something'' to the report by including some of the factors down the road. As used by the agency, net cash income in a calendar year is the difference between gross cash income _ which includes government payments in addition to farm sales receipts _ and cash expenses. The economists noted that higher prices for some commodities hit hard by drought have more than offset losses due to drought, on a national scale. The rub is that only those farmers whose crops were not hurt severely are able to benefit from the higher prices, unless they hold inventories from earlier harvests. For 1988, crop sales receipts are forecast at $ 66 billion to $ 68 billion, up from $ 59 billion in 1987 and reversing two years of decline, the report said. Livestock receipts this year may be in the range of $ 77 billion to $ 79 billion, compared with $ 77 billion in 1987. `` Consistent with recent droughts, this year's livestock receipts will probably be relatively stable,'' the report said. `` This year's smaller cattle herd appears to limit cullings, thus preventing substantial price weakening.'' The report added: `` Also contributing to lower-than-expected cullings is the fact that the five largest cattle-producing states -LRB- <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION> -RRB- have not been as hard hit by the drought as many other states.'' Crop deficiency payments to farmers are declining as a result of higher market prices, with the greatest effects likely in 1989. Also, if a large portion of the $ 3.9 billion drought emergency payments authorized recently go to farmers by the year's end, that will mean further 1989 reductions in benefits. `` Following the drought, next year's crop prices may remain higher, and crop production will increase,'' the report said. `` This would boost total cash receipts. However, it seems unlikely that revenue gains will compensate for reduced federal supports and higher operating costs.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Fed by what appears to be another bumper cotton crop in the making, the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> supply could be pushed to a 22-year high in 1988-89, according to <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> analysts. Based on Aug. 1 indications, the cotton harvest could be 14.9 million bales, up from 14.8 million bales last year. The increase would result from a larger acreage this year, despite a reduction in per-acre yields. In all, counting cotton left over from previous harvests, the total 1988-89 supply will be about 20.5 million bales, the most since the 1966-67 season, the department's <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> said Monday. Because domestic and export use is not keeping pace with production, the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> cotton stockpile when the next marketing year begins on Aug. 1, 1989, could rise to 8.9 million bales from an estimated carryover of 5.6 million bales this Aug. 1, the agency reported. Meanwhile, world cotton production in 1988-89 is expected to rise to nearly 86 million bales, up 7 percent from last season. Foreign production, at about 71 million bales, is expected to gain 5 million bales, including record crops in <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Greece </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Turkey </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION>. World cotton consumption, forecast at nearly 83 million bales, will about match last season, the report said. Cotton use is expected to increase primarily among producing countries, while falling among importers. As a result, world cotton stocks are expected to increase nearly 9 percent in 1988-89 to more than 35 million bales by the end of the season. All of the buildup will occur in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, while foreign inventories are expected to decline 2 percent. The report said <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> cotton `` has not been priced competitively in world markets for several months'' and that reduced export sales, along with large crops last year and in 1988 translate into the rise in inventories.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880830-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-30-88 0134EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Shuttle-Press     08-30 0509</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Shuttle-Press,490</SECOND>
<HEAD>Air Force Seeks Cuts in Shuttle Launch Witnesses</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By HARRY F. ROSENTHAL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> says safety concerns prompted its request that <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> cut back drastically on the number of people allowed on a close-in press site to cover next month's launch of space shuttle Discovery. In the past, there have been as many as 3,500 people on the press mound during a launch at <LOCATION> Cape </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Canaveral </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>, said <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Sheehan </PERSON>, chief spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aeronautics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Space </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>. <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> already has processed 2,600 news media applications for the Discovery launch. <PERSON> Sheehan </PERSON> declined to specify the number the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> wants to allow, but the number circulating around the <ORGANIZATION> Kennedy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Space </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> is 100 _ including <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> public affairs personnel. Those excluded would be allowed back onto the press site soon after the shuttle lifts off. As discussions with the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> continued, top <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> managers met Monday and decided not to set a specific launch date until after a detailed preparedness review on Sept. 13-14. <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> has been working toward a liftoff of the first post-Challenger mission in the last week of September. The <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION>, which has jurisdiction over safety at <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION>'s Kennedy facility, is worried about flying shrapnel should one of the solid rocket boosters explode `` They are asking us ` what are the minimum numbers you can have there and still be able to operate effectively?''' <PERSON> Sheehan </PERSON> said. He said 6,000 to 7,000 space center workers not involved with the shuttle on the pad also might be barred for some period preceding launches. The press site and <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION>'s huge vehicle assembly building are 4.2 miles from pad 34-B. Reporters have been there for every launch beginning with the Apollo program in 1967. `` They have some real basis for concern,'' <PERSON> Sheehan </PERSON> said. `` It came about because of what they learned after the Challenger -LRB- accident -RRB- and what they learned from the Atlas that had to be destroyed. `` What they learned is you ca n't predict where it's going to go. It can go down, it can go forward, it can go up.'' After the Challenger shuttle was engulfed in flames 73 seconds after liftoff on Jan. 28, 1986, killing its crew of seven, the Challenger's booster rockets careened about over the <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> for another minute before they were destroyed by a command from the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> safety officer. In March 1987, an Atlas Centaur rocket had to be destroyed 51 seconds into its flight when it started to tumble. No one on the ground was injured in either incident. Before Challenger, <PERSON> Sheehan </PERSON> said, engineers assumed the booster rockets would continue on the same path if they were released during flight, perhaps tumbling. `` The detonation of the <ORGANIZATION> SRB </ORGANIZATION> is not as clean as everyone thought it was,'' he said. `` It breaks apart at different times and has debris as large as an automobile and as small as a piece of small shrapnel. The issue concerns the spread of debris and the fragmentation of the <ORGANIZATION> SRB </ORGANIZATION> when it disintegrates.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880830-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-30-88 0108EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-BackyardStumping Bjt   08-30 0691</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Backyard Stumping, Bjt,740</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHINGTON TODAY: If It's Tuesday, This Must Be Greenfield</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN KING</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PITTSFIELD, Mass. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The man who would be president came to the shores of <LOCATION> Pontoosuc </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> with a mission, and a rather large following. The housing development here was one stop Monday for <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> on a nostalgic trip with all the trappings of a gubernatorial re-election campaign: talk of the rebound from double-digit unemployment, plans to convert an abandoned mill into a major art museum, and praise of partnership after partnership that has spurred western <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION>' sudden resurgence. It was the sixth such annual visit for <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, but this time things are a bit different: he's running for president, not governor. While <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and running mate <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> denounce <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> as soft on crime and weak on defense while questioning his patriotism, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> has spent two days in each of the past three weeks touring his home state talking about home ownership, health care, economic development and drunken driving. Those are all important issues, to be sure, but such talk has for the most part been lost in the aggressive tone of the early campaign. On Monday, for example, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> toured a <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION> defense plant and characterized <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> as opposed to every modern weapon system `` since the slingshot.'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> was here at a lakefront housing development, touting his Homeownership Opportunity Program, which made it possible for moderate-income families to buy their first homes in an area that otherwise would have been out of their price range. This at a time when <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> is being criticized for allowing his presidential campaign to lose its edge, and <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> to surge ahead in the polls. `` I am the sitting governor of this state and I've got to do my job,'' was <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' straight answer to a simple question: What was he doing here? There were complaints from <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> aides that his message was being obscured by coverage of the attacks on <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> by <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and the controversy over the Quayle selection. `` It's been a little difficult to get through,'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> said in a huge understatment. But the problems are n't all the doings of <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and the media's Quayle hunt <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> has offered few new national ideas during his regional trips at home and has focused most of his dicussion on state programs. Many of these initiatives, in fact, are models for the nation, used as examples in shaping congressional proposals ranging from the National Economic Development Act to major welfare reform. And had these trips come at another time, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> might get out of them what his campaign wants: media coverage of some of his most successful programs, several of which he touts almost daily when campaigning for the presidency. But with <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> criss-crossing the country pushing their agenda and slamming <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, his attempt to talk about public-private partnership, health care and jobs _ to bring the campaign, in <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' words, `` up where it belongs'' _ has been frustrating. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, for sure, has n't faced any questions, or protests, lately over the Route 7 interchange proposal here in <LOCATION> Pittsfield </LOCATION>. But opponents of the plan to widen the rural highway from two lanes to four at the cost of more than 20 homes turned out Monday. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> appears undaunted by the recent criticism, much of which has come from the large media contigent he has brought with him to <LOCATION> Pittsfield </LOCATION> this week, <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> last week and <LOCATION> Worcester </LOCATION> the week before. `` I am a sitting governor and I do have a responsibility to the citizens of this state,'' he told curious reporters Monday. But his post-Labor Day schedule will have him in <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> less frequently and his only remaining regional visit _ to southeastern <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> _ is scheduled for just one day. None of the criticism of the backyard stumping has been lost on <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, who was perhaps mindful of it when he delivered this promise Monday: `` The dog days of August are almost over.''
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> King </PERSON> of the The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> covered <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> as governor in <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> and is now reporting on the national presidential campaign.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880830-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-30-88 0135EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-PartyMoney     08-30 0557</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Party Money,580</SECOND>
<HEAD>Direct-Mail Falloff Causes Decline In Donations</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID GOELLER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Americans are giving less to the two major political parties, and Republicans hold a smaller fund-raising lead over Democrats than before, the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Election </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> says. The <ORGANIZATION> FEC </ORGANIZATION> said in a report released Monday that contributions to five fund-raising committees operated by each party totaled some $ 226 million during the first 18 months of the 1987-88 election cycle. That was well below the $ 267 million the 10 committees took in during the corresponding period in 1983-84 when <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> was heading for a second term as president. The $ 226 million also was about $ 1 million below the combined take for the first 18 months of the 1985-86 cycle, a non-presidential election period when contributions usually are less than in presidential years. The <ORGANIZATION> FEC </ORGANIZATION> said contributions to the five <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> committees totaled $ 166.19 million during the 18 months ending June 30, compared with $ 59.84 million raised by the five Democratic counterparts in the same period. That left the Republicans in front by $ 106.35 million, but their lead was smaller than the $ 152.7 million bulge during the corresponding period in 1985-86 and the $ 147.85 million advantage for the first three quarters of the 1983-84 election cycle. The <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Election </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> report covered the finances of the Democratic and Republican national committees; their <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> campaign committees; their national convention funds; and their state-local finance committees. The <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> saw its 1987-88 receipts fall to $ 61.58 million, the lowest point for a similar 18-month period during the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> presidency. Corresponding figures were $ 64.16 million in 1985-86, $ 75.23 million in 1983-84 and $ 65.75 million in 1981-82. <PERSON> Kathryn </PERSON> <PERSON> Murray </PERSON>, the committee's communications director, blamed the falloff on poor response to the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION>'s direct-mail solicitations in the first and second quarters of 1987. During this period, the scandals that rocked the television evangelists hurt direct-mail appeals by the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> and a variety of non-political fund-raisers, according to <PERSON> Murray </PERSON>. She said that since then, contributions have picked up, with the second quarter of this year running second only to a three-month period in 1984. The National Republican <ORGANIZATION> Senatorial </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Congressional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, which support <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> candidates in races for <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, also showed lower receipts in the first 18 months of this election cycle. The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> committee reported contributions of $ 42.3 million, down from a 1980s high of $ 65.81 million in 1985-86. The House apparatus had receipts of $ 21.32 million, nearly half the $ 41.96 it had in the first 18 months of the 1983-84 cycle. On the Democratic side, contributions to the five entities in the current cycle were only about $ 98,000 above where they were at the same period in the last presidential cycle. The <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, which relies less than its Republican counterpart on direct-mail solicitations, had receipts of $ 16.85 million, down from the $ 29.76 million taken in during 1983-84. This drop, however, was offset by increased giving to the <ORGANIZATION> Democrats </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ' </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> committees and their committees for state and local party affairs. The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> panel received $ 11.42 million, compared with a previous high of $ 7.56 million in 1985-86. The <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> panel was at $ 9.45 million, up from $ 8.74 million in 1985-86. The state-local share was $ 12.64 million, compared with a previous high of $ 10.97 million in 1983-84.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880830-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-30-88 0142EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-TreasuryBills     08-30 0196</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Treasury Bills,200</SECOND>
<HEAD>Interest Rates Mixed on Short-Term T-Bills</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Interest rates on short-term <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> securities were mixed in the latest auction, with rates on three-month bills rising to the highest level in more than three years but rates on six-month bills edging down. The <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> sold $ 7.0 billion in three-month bills Monday at an average discount rate of 7.26 percent, up from 7.18 percent last week. Another $ 7.0 billion was sold in six-month bills at an average discount rate of 7.50 percent, down from 7.51 percent last week. The rates on three-month bills were the highest Aug. 5, 1985, when they sold for 7.30 percent. Six-month bill rates were the lowest since Aug. 8, when they averaged 7.26 percent. The new discount rates understate the actual return to investors _ 7.50 percent for three-month bills with a $ 10,000 bill selling for $ 9,816.50 and 7.90 percent for six-month bills selling for $ 9,620.80. In a separate report, the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reserve </ORGANIZATION> said the average yield for one-year <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> bills, the most popular index for making changes in adjustable rate home mortgages, rose to 8.28 percent last week after averaging 8.27 percent the week before.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880830-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-30-88 0159EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Wildfires-T-Shirts     08-30 0264</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Wildfires-T-Shirts,0274</SECOND>
<HEAD>Yellowstone T-Shirts Give Firefighters, Tourists Something to
Remember</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Wildfires-Commander, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KURT J. REPANSHEK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WEST YELLOWSTONE, Mont. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A moose, bear and ranger dash around the flames in Yellowstone National Park. `` Would the last one out of the park please put the fire out!'' So says one of the T-shirts <PERSON> Sheila </PERSON> <PERSON> Hanna </PERSON> sells to tourists looking in the Wild West Mercantile for a memento of <ORGANIZATION> Yellowstone </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Park </ORGANIZATION>'s unprecedented 1988 fire season. The `` fire shirts,'' as <PERSON> Hanna </PERSON> calls them, are among the few good things to come out of <ORGANIZATION> Yellowstone </ORGANIZATION>'s wildfires, which have blackened more than 450,000 of the park's 2.2 million acres during the past two months. One T-shirt's design carries a map of the park with the various fires pinpointed in fire-engine red. Another portrays a <ORGANIZATION> Yellowstone </ORGANIZATION> entrance sign with a sketch of Old Faithful geyser, whose upper reaches have been transformed from steam into flame. `` We'd been asked if we had anything before we had any,'' <PERSON> Hanna </PERSON> said Sunday. `` It's worked out pretty well,'' Up the street from <PERSON> Hanna </PERSON>'s store, <PERSON> Merle </PERSON> <PERSON> Adams </PERSON>' Savage Shop also has found a steady demand for fire shirts. One he offers portrays a bear lounging at the mouth of a cave, bone _ human, presumably _ in paw, saying, `` Send more firefighters, the last ones were delicious!'' `` Everybody always thought that the park's fires would deter them -LRB- tourists -RRB-,'' said <PERSON> Hanna </PERSON>, pressing a `` Wildfires 1988'' logo onto a cap. `` But I think it brings more people. A national disaster. Everybody's been coming to see Yellowstone National Park on fire.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880830-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-30-88 0047EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-WeatherpageWeather 1stLd-Writethru a0709 08-30 0524</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Weatherpage Weather, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0709,0528</SECOND>
<HEAD>Chris' Remants Trigger Flood Watches</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Inserts one graf after 1st to UPDATE with New York storm.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 People in four states were alerted to the possibility of flash flooding Monday after heavy rains and gusty winds hit the <LOCATION> Northeast </LOCATION> in the wake of Tropical Storm <PERSON> Chris </PERSON>. A storm in metropolitan <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> uprooted trees, cut power to nearly 30,000 customers in five counties and caused train delays, according to electric companies. A large oak tree fell on a car, killing a woman in suburban <LOCATION> Mamaroneck </LOCATION>, police said. A low pressure center crossing the middle <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Coast </LOCATION> region and remnants of <PERSON> Chris </PERSON> helped showers and thunderstorms develop along a slow-moving cold front in the northeastern states. Strong winds were reported near the center of the low pressure system. Wind gusts to 50 mph in the <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION>, area caused some property damage late Monday morning. In the afternoon, wind gusts to 55 mph were reported at <LOCATION> Baltimore </LOCATION> and up to 48 mph at <LOCATION> Wilmington </LOCATION>, Del. Up to 5 inches of rain fell in north-central <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> and up to 4 -LCB- inches at <LOCATION> Lyndonville </LOCATION>, Vt. Flood watches were in effect Monday night in southern <LOCATION> Vermont </LOCATION>, western <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> Susquehanna </LOCATION> region of eastern <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> and in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> state in the <LOCATION> Catskills </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> Mohawk </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION>, the Adirondacks and the entire <LOCATION> Hudson </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION>. Rain fell from northern <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION> and from the lower Great Lakes to <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> Monday afternoon. Showers and thunderstorms were scattered from the southern <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Coast </LOCATION> to the western Gulf Coast, with a few showers over the upper <LOCATION> Great </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lakes </LOCATION>, the southern <LOCATION> Plains </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Northwest </LOCATION>. Temperatures warmed into the 90s across parts of <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> and southern <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> by early afternoon. Readings were in the 60s and upper 50s in the northern <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Coast </LOCATION> region, the upper <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION>, the Great Lakes region, the upper <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION>, the southern high Plains and the southern <LOCATION> Rockies </LOCATION>. Both the high and low temperatures in the nation at 3 p.m. EDT were in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, with 54 degrees at <LOCATION> Arcata </LOCATION> and 100 degrees at <LOCATION> Lemoore </LOCATION>. The nation's low Monday morning was 29 degrees at <LOCATION> Jackson </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wyo </LOCATION>. The forecast for Tuesday called for showers and thunderstorms over the <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Coast </LOCATION> states, the central <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Coast </LOCATION> states, southern <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, the southern Rockies and the southern Plateau region. Showers and thunderstorms were expected to be most numerous from northern <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION> to southern <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, along the <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION> coast and from eastern <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> to southern <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>. A few showers were expected in the upper <LOCATION> Great </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lakes </LOCATION> region. Sunny skies were expected for the rest of the nation. High temperatures were forecast in the 70s and upper 60s from the middle and northern <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Coast </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION>. Highs were predicted in the 80s elsewhere east of the <LOCATION> Rockies </LOCATION>, with lower 90s in the northern high Plains and over <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>. Highs in the 80s and lower 90s were expected in the Western states, with 100 degrees in the deserts of southern <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> and southwestern <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION> and afternoon highs in the 70s along the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Coast </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880830-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-30-88 0212EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     08-30 0976</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,1021</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names In The News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LEEDS, England (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Pop singer <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> was given an ovation by 90,000 people who showed up at a park in this northern <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> industrial city for a concert on his 30th birthday. The crowd sang `` Happy birthday'' Monday night and <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> replied simply, `` Thank you.'' No fanfare, no gifts and no birthday cake, in keeping with remnants of <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s earlier <PERSON> Jehovah </PERSON>'s Witnesses religious beliefs, tour spokesman <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> said. Police described the event as `` very successful'' from their point of view, with only 96 arrests, most for drunkenness, damage and drug offenses. All 90,000 tickets for the concert were sold months ago and the most serious injury reported was a broken leg suffered by a man as ticketless fans tried to enter the arena. <ORGANIZATION> Leeds </ORGANIZATION> was the latest stop on <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s 43-date European concert tour.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> MacMurray </PERSON> will be surrounded by the women of his life at a small gathering to celebrate his 80th birthday today. On hand will be his wife of 34 years, former actress <PERSON> June </PERSON> <PERSON> Haver </PERSON>, the couple's twin 32-year-old daughters, <PERSON> Kate </PERSON> and <PERSON> Laurie </PERSON>, and his two dogs, also females. `` He's the father of ` My Three Sons' but he's surrounded by females,'' his wife said Monday during a telephone interview. <PERSON> MacMurray </PERSON>, who is recovering from a stroke, was asleep and could n't come to the phone, she said <PERSON> MacMurray </PERSON> has been encouraged by an outpouring of get-well cards, letters and flowers, she said. `` If life begins at 40, he's only 40,'' she said. `` He's very happy to be 80 years old. Many of his friends are older, you know. He looks at <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Burns </PERSON> -LRB- 92 -RRB- and <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Hope </PERSON> -LRB- 85 -RRB- and he says, ` Gee, I feel like a kid.'''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>PHOENIX (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Jessica </PERSON> <PERSON> Hahn </PERSON>, the church secretary whose night with TV evangelist <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON> led to his downfall, launched her radio career here to mixed reviews. <PERSON> Jay </PERSON> <PERSON> Stevens </PERSON>, KOY-FM's program director, said listener response to Ms. <PERSON> Hahn </PERSON>'s first day Monday was all positive. But <PERSON> Bud </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilkinson </PERSON>, radio-television critic for The <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Republic </LOCATION>, writing for today's editions, said that `` as an air talent, <PERSON> Hahn </PERSON> is n't a sleeper, a wit awaiting harvest, but rather a bust.'' The station said Ms. <PERSON> Hahn </PERSON>, 29, was signed to a 30-day contract with options for renewal. Ms. <PERSON> Hahn </PERSON> became an overnight celebrity in 1987 when revelations about her sexual liaison with <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON> led to his giving up his <ORGANIZATION> PTL </ORGANIZATION> empire. She later sold her story to <ORGANIZATION> Playboy </ORGANIZATION>, posed nude for the publication and moved into the <ORGANIZATION> Playboy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mansion </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>DENVER (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Comedian <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Paulsen </PERSON> and his agent, <PERSON> Linda </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Chaney </PERSON>, were secretly married during the Democratic National Convention in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>, his spokeswoman said. <PERSON> Paulsen </PERSON>, 61, and <PERSON> Chaney </PERSON>, 35, exchanged vows in a July 20 civil ceremony at <LOCATION> Fulton </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Courthouse </LOCATION>, spokeswoman <PERSON> Marianne </PERSON> <PERSON> Jasin </PERSON> said Monday. The <ORGANIZATION> Paulsens </ORGANIZATION>, in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> for the convention, wanted to keep the ceremony a secret at the time, but `` about a month later, they thought they should release the news,'' <PERSON> Jasin </PERSON> said. The couple met five years ago at a comedy club here. Three years later, she took over his bookings. In September, <PERSON> Paulsen </PERSON>, the perennial presidential candidate, is scheduled to begin work on the <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> television show `` The <ORGANIZATION> Smothers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Brothers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Comedy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hour </ORGANIZATION>,'' <PERSON> Jasin </PERSON> said. The marriage is the second for <PERSON> Paulsen </PERSON> and the first for his new wife. <PERSON> Paulsen </PERSON> has three grown children.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEWTON, Mass. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Garret </PERSON> <PERSON> FitzGerald </PERSON>, former prime minister of <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION>, will lecture at <ORGANIZATION> Boston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> during a two-week visiting professorship this fall. <PERSON> FitzGerald </PERSON> will conduct a seminar on Anglo-Irish relations from 1922 to the present as part of the university's concentration in Irish studies, the college said Monday. <PERSON> FitzGerald </PERSON>, who led two coalition governments during his tenure as prime minister, was defeated in <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION>'s general election in 1987 by current Prime Minister <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Haughey </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>Eds: Versions of following items moved on sports wires.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>WEST BRIDGEWATER, Mass. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Irving </PERSON> <PERSON> Fryar </PERSON>, the often troubled New England Patriots wide receiver, got a break when police pulled him over for speeding. Police clocked <PERSON> Fryar </PERSON> at 55 mph in a 45 mph zone early Monday. <PERSON> Fryar </PERSON>, 26, could have been arrested for driving without a valid license but instead received a citation for speeding and driving with a suspended license, said Police Chief <PERSON> Erving </PERSON> <PERSON> Lothrop </PERSON>. <PERSON> Fryar </PERSON>'s license was suspended for failure to pay a $ 20 fine for a minor driving offense, officials said. In February, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> police charged <PERSON> Fryar </PERSON> with unlawful possession of a gun, shotgun and hollow-point bullets after stopping him for speeding. The weapons charges later were dropped. <PERSON> Fryar </PERSON> missed the <ORGANIZATION> Patriots </ORGANIZATION>' 1985 AFC championship game with the <ORGANIZATION> Miami </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dolphins </ORGANIZATION> after receiving a deep knife wound in his hand during an argument with his wife. Two weeks later, <PERSON> Fryar </PERSON> was one of six Patriots named as being treated for drug abuse during the 1985 season.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>MIDDLETOWN, Conn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Former major-league baseball player <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Ellis </PERSON> must forfeit his 12-foot boat as part of a special probation he received on lobster-poaching charges. <PERSON> Ellis </PERSON>, who played for the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Yankees </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Cleveland </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Indians </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rangers </ORGANIZATION> in a 13-year career that ended in 1981, did n't have to enter a plea Monday under the special program for first-time offenders The charges, which could have drawn three years imprisonment and an $ 8,800 fine, will be stricken from records if he successfully completes probation. <PERSON> Ellis </PERSON> and his brother-in-law were arrested July 28 by state agents on <LOCATION> Long </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sound </LOCATION> near <LOCATION> Old </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Saybrook </LOCATION>. Under an agreement with prosecutors, <PERSON> Ellis </PERSON>, a partner in a <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> real estate firm, also will pay $ 1,500 to a state program designed to fight poachers. `` Certainly I think that the disposition of the case is satisfactory to everybody involved,'' <PERSON> Ellis </PERSON>, 39, said after the hearing in <ORGANIZATION> Middletown </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Superior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880830-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-30-88 0217EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lites     08-30 0534</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lites,0557</SECOND>
<HEAD>On The Light Side</HEAD>
<DATELINE>OKLAHOMA CITY (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The business of the <ORGANIZATION> Oklahoma </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Legislature </ORGANIZATION> has gotten in the way of Rep. <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON>' honeymoon again. <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON> and his wife, former state Rep. <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> <PERSON> Virtue </PERSON>, had to put off their June honeymoon because of delays in adjournment of the Legislature. They got married and re-scheduled the honeymoon to start Monday. But Gov. <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> Bellmon </PERSON> called the <ORGANIZATION> Legislature </ORGANIZATION> back into special session Monday to solve problems with prison overcrowding. <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON>, the Democrat who is chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appropriations </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Budget </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, says the honeymoon plans are on hold again. `` I'm beginning to think we may have to wait for our 25th anniversary,'' he said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>EAST LANSING, Mich. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A pair of entrepreneurs turned rejection into a profitable business venture by creating a fraternity that anybody can join, even women, and everybody is president. `` Fraternities are elitist organizations,'' said <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Southwick </PERSON>, cofounder of Sigma Phi Nothing. `` We feel that everyone should be special.'' <PERSON> Southwick </PERSON>, 24, his 21-year-old partner, <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Toth </PERSON>, launched <ORGANIZATION> Sigma </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Phi </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nothing </ORGANIZATION> after an unhappy rush week at one of <ORGANIZATION> Michigan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>'s fraternity houses. `` I got in and <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> did n't and that kind of upset us both. So I decided not to join,'' <PERSON> Southwick </PERSON> said. Later, they figured, the rejection signified nothing, sparking the Sigma Phi Nothing idea. So the two invented their own fraternity, created a logo, and held a `` Do n't rush, relax'' party. They brought 48 Sigma Phi Nothing T-shirts, which quickly were sold at $ 10 a shirt. As their story spread, they sold more than 300 shirts in a few weeks. Then a marketing company expressed interest in selling the fraternity idea nationwide. The two have spent the summer developing plans for selling the T-shirts at Big Ten schools this fall. So far, the fledgling company has expanded its inventory to include sweatshirts, corduroy caps and bumper stickers. And the T-shirt price has risen to $ 11. The two budding businessmen, meanwhile, are taking some time off from <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION> State to pursue their fraternity.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>INDIANAPOLIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A current Beach Boys hit extols `` <LOCATION> Kokomo </LOCATION>'' as a tropical paradise, which makes sense only after you learn the group had never heard of the land-locked <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION> city. Beach Boys fans looking for `` bodies in the sand'' and a `` tropical drink melting in your hand'' wo n't find it in the real-life <LOCATION> Kokomo </LOCATION>, an auto industry town about 50 miles north of <LOCATION> Indianapolis </LOCATION>. The Beach Boys _ <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Love </PERSON>, <PERSON> Carl </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON>, <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> Jardine </PERSON> and <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnston </PERSON> _ performed at the <ORGANIZATION> Indiana </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fair </ORGANIZATION> on Friday night. There, they learned <LOCATION> Kokomo </LOCATION> does exist somewhere else besides in their song. `` <LOCATION> Kokomo </LOCATION>'' is one cut on the soundtrack to the <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Cruise </PERSON> movie `` Cocktail.'' The soundtrack went gold last Tuesday, having sold half a million copies. The `` Kokomo'' single, released about eight weeks ago, is climbing the adult-contemporary chart, reaching No. 11 this week. The Beach Boys said they thought they were singing of a make-believe place. `` It was just a made-up ... it was a nice-sounding name,'' <PERSON> Love </PERSON> said. `` The writer is <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Phillips </PERSON> -LRB- of Mamas and Papas fame -RRB-. He started it and it would n't stop; it was out of control.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880830-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-30-88 0218EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Mexico-Politics 1stLd-Writethru a0729 08-30 0460</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Mexico-Politics, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0729,0467</SECOND>
<HEAD>Electoral College Approves Congressional Seats</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: LEADS with 2 grafs with Electoral College postponing decision
on remaining lawmakers until Tuesday night. Picks up 3rd pvs, `The
Electoral ...'
^By CHRIS ANGELO</NOTE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MEXICO CITY (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Electoral </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> on Monday ended a 23-hour session by approving the last of 300 congressmen elected directly to the Chamber of Deputies during balloting in July that the opposition says was fraudulent. The body then postponed until Tuesday night its certification of the elections of 200 other deputies assigned to the different parties according to a proportional representation formula. The <ORGANIZATION> Electoral </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION>, made up of the newly elected members of the <ORGANIZATION> Chamber </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Deputies </ORGANIZATION>, began its marathon session at 1 p.m. Sunday and ended it shortly after noon Monday. Protests from opposition parties, accusing the governing <ORGANIZATION> Institutional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Revolutionary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, known as the <ORGANIZATION> PRI </ORGANIZATION>, of fraud in the July 6 elections, delayed the certification process. The delay raised the small possibility there would not be a quorum for the opening session of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> on Thursday and threatened President <PERSON> Miguel </PERSON> de la <LOCATION> Madrid </LOCATION>'s state of the nation speech that day. Under the constitution, the president must attend the opening session and by tradition that is when he delivers the state of the nation address. If the <ORGANIZATION> PRI </ORGANIZATION> does not have the 251 seats for a majority in the 500-member Chamber of Deputies an opposition boycott could cancel the session. The Electoral College began the certification process, seat by seat, on Aug. 15 and in the results announed Monday the <ORGANIZATION> PRI </ORGANIZATION> won 235 of the 300 seats. The conservative <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Action </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> had 36 and leftist parties backing presidential candidate <PERSON> Cuauhtemoc </PERSON> <PERSON> Cardenas </PERSON> received 29. An earlier official vote count by the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Election </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> gave the <ORGANIZATION> PRI </ORGANIZATION> 247 seats in the 500 member chamber and opposition parties 227 with 26 in dispute. The <ORGANIZATION> PRI </ORGANIZATION> has dominated Mexican politics since 1929 and this year for the first time it will not have the two-thirds majority required to amend the constitution. Opposition parties claim the <ORGANIZATION> Election </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> has not released results from about 25,000 polling places. They say those would show that <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Salinas </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Gortari </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> PRI </ORGANIZATION> presidential candidate, did not win the 50.36 percent of the vote awarded him in official results. <PERSON> Cardenas </PERSON> received 31.12 percent of the vote in the official results and <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Clouthier </PERSON>, the candidate of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Action </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, 17.07 percent. In early September the <ORGANIZATION> Electoral </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> the </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chamber </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Deputies </ORGANIZATION> is to confirm <PERSON> Salinas </PERSON> as president-elect. The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Electoral </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> has finished certifying all its members. Parties backing <PERSON> Cardenas </PERSON> won four of the 64 seats, marking the first time the <ORGANIZATION> PRI </ORGANIZATION> had lost any seats in the upper house.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880830-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-30-88 0314EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-PLO-Mission     08-30 0545</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-PLO-Mission,530</SECOND>
<HEAD>U.S. Gives Up Effort To Expel PLO From U.N. Offices</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration is abandoning efforts to get the <ORGANIZATION> Palestine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> kicked out of offices at the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, while continuing to fight any attempt to reopen a <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> office in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> says. The <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration, following what one source described as a bitter internal fight over the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> issue, decided not to appeal a judge's ruling that allowed the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> to maintain its <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> office. A year-old law had ordered the administration to close <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> facilities in both <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, but <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> Edmund </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Palmieri </PERSON> on June 29 struck down the provision regarding the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> office, saying obligations to the international body took precedence. Monday was the deadline for appealing <PERSON> Palmieri </PERSON>'s order. The <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> said the decision not to fight <PERSON> Palmieri </PERSON>'s order `` was based on a determination that, on balance, the interests of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> are best served by not appealing. The department said its `` normal policy'' was to appeal adverse district court decisions of this kind, but `` it was decided, in light of foreign policy considerations, including the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> role as host to the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> organization, not to appeal in this instance.'' The department said, however, it would continue to oppose any effort to reopen the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION>'s <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> office. The <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> had opposed <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> efforts to launch an appeal, according to <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION> officials who spoke on condition they not be identified. The Anti-Terrorism Act of 1987 required closure of the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> and <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> offices on ground that the organization sponsors terrorism The administration had opposed enactment of the anti-terrorism measure, saying it could possibly violate international obligations. But once the act became law, the administration moved to enforce it. The <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> office, which has no <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> affiliation, was shut down, but <PERSON> Palmieri </PERSON> said the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> office must remain open because of the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> obligations under the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> Headquarters Agreement. The <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION>'s representative in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Hassan </PERSON> <PERSON> Abdul </PERSON> <PERSON> Rahman </PERSON>, praised the administration's decision, saying it `` is the only sensible thing to do because otherwise they would have pursued the misguided policy of confrontation with the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> and of acquiescence with the pro-Israel lobby in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>.'' <PERSON> Abdul </PERSON> <PERSON> Rahman </PERSON>, whose <ORGANIZATION> Palestine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Information </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> was shut down by the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> last year, now heads the <ORGANIZATION> Palestine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Affairs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> which operates out of the <ORGANIZATION> Arab </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> League </ORGANIZATION> offices. Republican Sens. <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Helms </PERSON> of <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> and <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Roth </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Delaware </LOCATION> had urged the administration to proceed with an appeal. `` At issue is the question of who determines the sovereign powers of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> _ the <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and the president through the constitutional process, or the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> and a single District Court judge in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Helms </PERSON> wrote in a letter to White House chief of staff <PERSON> Kenneth </PERSON> <PERSON> Duberstein </PERSON>. <PERSON> Roth </PERSON> and <PERSON> Helms </PERSON> both said the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION>'s ability to control access to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> would be hampered by allowing the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> office to remain open. <PERSON> Roth </PERSON> added there was `` clear and irrefutable evidence'' that the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> sponsored terrorism. <PERSON> Roth </PERSON>, in a letter to Attorney General <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON> last week, said he intended `` to proceed further in this matter'' once <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> returns after the August recess.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880830-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-30-88 0220EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Burma-Chaos     08-30 0654</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Burma-Chaos,0678</SECOND>
<HEAD>Analysts: Authorities May be Sowing Chaos to Retake Control</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DENIS D. GRAY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BANGKOK, Thailand (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Burma </LOCATION>'s besieged government and military may be deliberately pushing the country toward anarchy in an attempt to reassert control after 26 years of authoritarian rule, diplomats and other analysts say. Remaining silent since Aug. 19, the government has withdrawn troops and police from the streets while looting and other crimes reportedly go unchecked. Civilian administration has ceased to function in many areas. There have been increasing reports and some witness accounts of military agents seeking to provoke tensions. The state media has reported nine almost simultaneous prison uprisings in widely different areas of the country and the escape or release of nearly 9,000 inmates. `` My impression is it is strongly possible that this chaos is being planned by state authorities to give them good reasons to intervene eventually,'' said a Japanese diplomat in <LOCATION> Rangoon </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> Burmese </LOCATION> capital. However, others, also speaking on condition of anonymity, caution that with virtually no access to the current leadership analysts can at best make educated guesses on its intentions. One Western diplomat watching developments from <LOCATION> Bangkok </LOCATION> said the drift towards chaos may simply reflect confusion within the leadership coupled with an `` arrogance, an unwillingess to accept that they have to give up.'' `` There's an obvious vacuum with students and others trying to find some leadership. The obvious people to step into the vacuum are the military, conspiratorially or not,'' an <LOCATION> Asian </LOCATION> diplomat in <LOCATION> Bangkok </LOCATION> said. The leadership withdrew into itself following the announcement Aug. 19 _ after months of bloody anti-government rioting in which hundreds were killed _ that civilian lawyer <PERSON> Maung </PERSON> <PERSON> Maung </PERSON> had replaced the widely hated <PERSON> Sein </PERSON> <PERSON> Lwin </PERSON> as president and head of the sole political party. <PERSON> Maung </PERSON> <PERSON> Maung </PERSON>'s promise of a referendum on Sept. 12 that would pave the way for democracy did not quiet the protests that have erupted throughout <LOCATION> Burma </LOCATION> in the past month. Unsatisfied opposition leaders demanded an interim government and the end of one-party rule. A number of Burmese and some outsider observers believed that <PERSON> Ne </PERSON> <PERSON> Win </PERSON>, who formally retired in late July after wielding almost absolute power for 26 years, was still pulling strings behind the scenes along with loyal military officers. Leaders have urged that demonstrations remain peaceful so the government can not take advantage of the turmoil. `` The public must be united and well disciplined ... people must be alert to prevent machinations of destructive elements to create anarchy in the country,'' a former defense minister, Tin Oo, told an anti-government rally last week. In <LOCATION> Rangoon </LOCATION> and other areas, `` democracy centers'' and block committees have replaced judicial and civil authorities to maintain law and order. Whether such makeshift measures will stop the growing lawlessness, widespread strikes, soaring commodity prices and food shortages remains a crucial question. One Swedish journalist and <LOCATION> Burma </LOCATION> expert, <PERSON> Bertil </PERSON> <PERSON> Lintner </PERSON>, notes that <PERSON> Ne </PERSON> <PERSON> Win </PERSON> and his military followers used the pretext of domestic turmoil and threats to national security to seize power from a democratic government in 1962. `` The government ca n't control the situation so they are letting things get worse. They hope the people will beg them to come back. It's vicious,'' <PERSON> Lintner </PERSON> said, quoting a <LOCATION> Burmese </LOCATION> proverb that translates: `` If you ca n't eat the beef yourself, throw sand on it.'' One Bangkok-based diplomat said the students and other anti-government forces might react dramatically to keep up their hitherto remarkable momentum. `` The students have been the engine of change and used a lot of imagination. But now they have to take a new initiative,'' he said. `` There appears to be a paralysis in the government. A hiatus has set in and nobody knows what to do next,'' the diplomat said. Referring to Ne Win, he added: `` In every dictator there is an element of contempt for the people. He ca n't accept that the people no longer want him.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880830-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-30-88 0320EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-CleanAir Bjt   08-30 0665</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Clean Air, Bjt,0686</SECOND>
<HEAD>Ban On New Industry In L.A. Smog Basin Largely Symbolic</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RIC LEYVA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A federally ordered building ban on major new <LOCATION> Southern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> polluters is largely symbolic because the region has no plans for heavy industries, fuel refineries or power generating plants, officials say. The <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> on Monday announced plans to ban construction of industry emitting more than 100 tons of carbon monoxide or ozone pollutants a year as a congressional moratorium on such sanctions expires. The ban could be extended to more than a dozen other <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> locations, including <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION> and suburban <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>. The <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Basin </LOCATION> comes under the sanctions slated to take effect at midnight because the air pollution control plan submitted to the agency was rejected. The order came as no surprise to <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Lents </PERSON>, executive officer of the <ORGANIZATION> South </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Quality </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Management </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION>, who said it would do nothing to reduce smog in the nation's largest and most populous urban area. A lawsuit by environmentalists resulted in a January federal court order requiring the <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> to reject the <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> plan because it failed to bring regional air quality into compliance with a 10-year deadline set by the 1977 Clean Air Act, <PERSON> Lents </PERSON> said. `` We've known for some time that if <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> did n't act, the construction ban would go into effect,'' said <PERSON> Lents </PERSON>, who oversees smog eradication efforts in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Orange </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bernardino </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Riverside </LOCATION> counties. But he said the <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> ban only affects heavy sources of pollution such as oil refineries, power plants or automotive factories. No such plants are planned for the region, <PERSON> Lents </PERSON> said. `` Based on the permit applications we've received this year and last, the ban will have absolutely no effect on smog abatement in the short run,'' <PERSON> Lents </PERSON> said, adding that it will take at least 20 years to clear <LOCATION> Southern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> smog to acceptable levels. `` There will be some psychological impact, certainly,'' <PERSON> Lents </PERSON> said. He said he hoped the <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> move would spur <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to revise the Clean Air Act and allow cities more time to clear smog. `` A complete solution calls for federal action,'' he said. `` <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> needs something to motivate them, but I'm afraid this wo n't be enough.'' Mayor <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON> hailed the ban as a signal that the federal government cares about reducing air pollution, even though the effects may be insignificant. `` While it will not have a major impact on the <LOCATION> Southern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> economy,'' <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON> said, `` the construction ban on major stationary pollution sources re-emphasizes the difficult air quality challenge facing cities and counties of this area.'' The <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION>'s announcement followed a weekend `` Air Pollution Summit'' at City Hall organized by the <ORGANIZATION> Coalition </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Clean </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> and <LOCATION> Campaign </LOCATION> <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, which were brought together by Assemblyman <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Hayden </PERSON>. Among other proposals, speakers called for tight controls on urban growth. `` <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> has intolerable levels of air pollution,'' <PERSON> Hayden </PERSON> said. `` I'm told current smog levels will expose everybody in the basin to toxic pollution 200 to 300 percent above acceptable health standards.'' <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> was one of about 100 metropolitan areas that the <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> said missed December's deadline to contain smog at acceptable levels. Because of its weather and terrain, <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> has by far the nation's highest ozone concentrations. <PERSON> Lents </PERSON> said his agency will present a draft of a new 20-year smog reduction plan that would go to the <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> for approval. Before the end of the year, the <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> expects to adopt a policy requiring areas not meeting pollution standards to demonstrate steady progress, with a goal of an average 3 percent reduction in pollution concentrations annually. When it adopts that policy, the agency will decide whether to impose construction bans at <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Reno </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Nev. </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Bakersfield </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Sacramento </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Fresno </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Louis </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ill. </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION> suburbs of <LOCATION> Louisville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ky. </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Cleveland </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION>. Decisions on similar construction bans are pending for <LOCATION> Ventura </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, and for the <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> suburbs of <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880830-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-30-88 0222EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i BC-Japan-Stocks     08-30 0027</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Japan-Stocks,0027</SECOND>
<HEAD>Stocks Climb In Tokyo</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Nikkei Stock Average closed at 27,511.65 points, up 132.55 points, on the <ORGANIZATION> Tokyo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Stock </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Exchange </ORGANIZATION> Tuesday.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880830-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-30-88 0326EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Wildfires-Commander Bjt   08-30 0620</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Wildfires-Commander, Bjt,0642</SECOND>
<HEAD>After 30 Years, Fire Boss Still Gets Excited About Fighting Fires</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KURT J. REPANSHEK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>YELLOWSTONE NATIONAL PARK, Wyo. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Thirty years of firefighting have n't steeled fire boss <PERSON> Dave </PERSON> `` Ponce'' Poncin against the worst fear a commander harbors while calling the shots against a fire. `` I think the biggest fear is killing someone, injuring people,'' <PERSON> Poncin </PERSON> said during a break from his command of the 85,000-acre North Fork fire that is eating through <ORGANIZATION> Yellowstone </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Park </ORGANIZATION>'s forests. He especially dreads aircraft accidents. `` When a helicopter goes down, there are usually fatalities. When there are n't, you count your blessings.'' But in eight years as a fire boss, the soft-spoken man who seems to have a minute for everyone has never realized his greatest fear. He knows, too, that he's been lucky. <PERSON> Poncin </PERSON> called a helicopter crash earlier this month in the <ORGANIZATION> Bighorn </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION>, in which one firefighter died and three were injured, a `` harbinger, or an alert,'' for his squad of tactical firefighters. `` It's not unexpected,'' he added. `` It just seems like there's more potential for accidents,'' <PERSON> Poncin </PERSON> said, especially considering the long weeks of firefighting; the beating the helicopters take; and the stress that the crews and the machines endure. Relaxing in a lawn chair at his Madison Junction fire base, the 51-year-old <PERSON> Poncin </PERSON> looked back on his 30 years with the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> and did n't mention a single regret. He also said he's learned how to live with, but not forget, his fears `` It accumulates with you, and when you think back over the years, you think of the bad things,'' he said. As a boy growing up in <LOCATION> Cedar </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rapids </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>, he looked up to his uncle in <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION> and longed for the day when he could head west and join the <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Poncin </PERSON> got his chance out of high school, when he worked as a smoke jumper, parachuting into strategic hot spots, in northern <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION> to pay his way through college. Now based in <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Nez </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Perce </LOCATION> <LOCATION> National </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Forest </LOCATION>, where he is an assistant to the forest supervisor, <PERSON> Poncin </PERSON> spends summers as the leader of 10 people who make up one of the nation's few forest fire overhead teams, who coordinate the firefighting of major forest fires. From the beginning of May until the end of October he and his team live on two-hour standby, always knowing that wherever they are, they can immediately be summoned to a fire. But <PERSON> Poncin </PERSON> would n't want it any other way. `` Firefighting is a lot like circuses,'' he said. `` It gets in your blood. Part of it is the people -LRB- you work with -RRB-. Part of it is the challenge of chasing and catching a big fire.'' In <LOCATION> Yellowstone </LOCATION> during this unusually dry summer, <PERSON> Poncin </PERSON> has mostly been chasing. He spent 14 days as commanding the forces for the `` Snake Complex,'' a collection of three tricky fires that by Monday had charred 92,000 acres in <LOCATION> Yellowstone </LOCATION>. Less than a week later, he was sent back to <LOCATION> Yellowstone </LOCATION>, this time to oversee the North Fork fire, which twice threatened the Old Faithful geyser complex, burned across the <LOCATION> Madison </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> and through <PERSON> Norris </PERSON>. Married 28 years, <PERSON> Poncin </PERSON>'s wife and two sons have grown accustomed to his being away from home summers. And his wife is quick to tell young women to steer their affections clear of firefighters, he said. `` I think she's gotten used to it,'' <PERSON> Poncin </PERSON> added, chuckling. `` It's hard on a wife and family. But it's a commitment they make.'' He realizes, too, that his family may not have to make that commitment for much longer. `` I hear the engines of a retirement plane warming up on the runway,'' <PERSON> Poncin </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880830-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-30-88 0334EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Shuttle-Satellite     08-30 0266</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Shuttle-Satellite,0275</SECOND>
<HEAD>Workers Load Satellite On Discovery</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CAPE CANAVERAL, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> engineers say they can begin final testing of space shuttle Discovery's payload now that a $ 100 million spacecraft-tracking satellite has been loaded into the cargo bay. The tests are scheduled for the first two weeks of September and are intended to ensure the payload, nearly identical to one destroyed in the 1986 Challenger explosion, was installed properly, said <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Diller </PERSON>, a spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aeronautics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Space </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>. One test will involve the launch control center in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> and one will involve a ground-based tracking station at <LOCATION> White </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sands </LOCATION>, N.M. The Tracking and Data Relay Satellite, designed to help ground controllers monitor shuttles and their payloads, is the principal cargo for the 26th space shuttle mission, scheduled for launch in late September or early October. Loading the satellite took 10 hours Monday and was completed with no significant problems, <PERSON> Diller </PERSON> said. Deployment of the satellite is set for the first day of the four-day Discovery mission. Payload engineers and technicians, wary of the potential of lightning from a tropical weather system that moved up the coast, had been working feverishly during the weekend to prepare for the satellite-loading. <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> officials in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, meanwhile, decided not to announce a date for the resumption of space shuttle flights until after a review Sept. 13-14, said spokesman <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Kast </PERSON>. <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> had scheduled _ and postponed _ the launch five dates previously, beginning with July 15, 1987. The <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> manned space program has been grounded since the January 1986 Challenger explosion that killed seven astronauts.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880830-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-30-88 0246EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Seals     08-30 0440</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Seals,0452</SECOND>
<HEAD>Canine Virus Believed To Be Seal Killer</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PAUL VERSCHUUR</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PIETERBUREN, Netherlands (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A virus common in dogs has killed more than 11,000 seals in <LOCATION> Western </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>'s coastal waters this summer and humans can do little to stop the spread of the disease, a Dutch biologist says. Up to 80 percent of the seals in the <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sea </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Kattegat </LOCATION> waters between <LOCATION> Denmark </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Sweden </LOCATION> might die, <PERSON> Ab </PERSON> <PERSON> Osterhaus </PERSON> told a news conference Monday. `` Canine distemper virus, or a closely related virus, is the primary cause of the seal deaths,'' said <PERSON> Osterhaus </PERSON> in this northern Dutch village, which has <LOCATION> Western </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>'s largest seal nursery. The virus causes infections of the respiratory and central nervous systems and the digestive tracts. <PERSON> Osterhaus </PERSON> said no specific cure exists for seals with the virus. Distemper may have spread to seals when one was bitten by a dog, said <PERSON> Osterhaus </PERSON>, who works for the <ORGANIZATION> Dutch </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protection </ORGANIZATION>. Specialists in <LOCATION> Western </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> who have been investigating the seal deaths have speculated that pollution has played a role in the killer epidemic. <PERSON> Osterhaus </PERSON> said research is still being conducted to determine if the massive pollution of Western European waters could have accelerated the epidemic by weakening seals' immune systems. `` We know that certain substances we find in the seas today ... can affect the immune system,'' he said. `` Pollution may have triggered the thing but it was not the cause as such.'' <PERSON> Osterhaus </PERSON> said antibodies to canine distemper virus were found in all of the dead seals he examined: `` The development of these antibodies coincided clearly with the surfacing of symptoms'' of the disease. A similar report was made at a news conference Monday in <LOCATION> Stockholm </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Sweden </LOCATION>, by patholigist <PERSON> Anders </PERSON> <PERSON> Bergman </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> Stockholm </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>'s veterinary school. He said he began suspecting in June that the canine distemper virus was linked to the seal deaths. <PERSON> Bengt </PERSON> <PERSON> Klingeborn </PERSON>, a virologist at the veterinary school, said he believed the 25 percent of Western European seals that have survived so far will live through the epidemic because they have developed antibodies. <PERSON> Osterhaus </PERSON> noted that there had been an outbreak of the canine distemper virus among dogs in <LOCATION> Greenland </LOCATION> shortly before the epidemic broke out among seals early this year. Each summer, thousands of seals migrate from <LOCATION> Greenland </LOCATION> to Western European waters. <PERSON> Osterhaus </PERSON> said his team had developed an experimental vaccine against the canine distemper virus but added `` it will not be possible to carry out preventive vaccinations in the wild.'' <LOCATION> Sweden </LOCATION> has reported 3,400 dead seals, <LOCATION> Denmark </LOCATION> nearly 3,000, <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> 3,900, <LOCATION> Norway </LOCATION> 600 and the <LOCATION> Netherlands </LOCATION> 175.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880830-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-30-88 0337EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-AncientTomb     08-30 0514</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Ancient Tomb,0529</SECOND>
<HEAD>4,000-Year-Old Funeral Boat Gently Moved into Elaborate Museum
Tomb Scene</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PAUL A. DRISCOLL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CHICAGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Nearly 4,000 years after it was built, the funeral boat of one of <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION>'s most powerful pharaohs takes another journey this week. The delicate, 32-foot long, wooden craft was gently lifted off the floor of the <ORGANIZATION> Field </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Museum </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Natural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> History </ORGANIZATION> on Monday and rotated 180 degrees. Expert riggers who performed the tricky maneuver kept their hands off, fearing sweat or body oils would harm the ancient wood. Today, the boat used in the funeral of King Sen-wosret III in about 1850 B.C. will be moved inch by inch a few yards to its new setting in the museum _ a $ 2.2 million permanent exhibit. When the exhibit opens in November, it will allow visitors to walk through the eerie world of tombs, mummies, shrines to cat goddesses and other treasures from ancient <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION>. The museum said the exhibit would give visitors the only opportunity outside <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION> to enter and explore a life-size tomb complex. King Sen-wosret's boat _ a graceful, crescent-shaped canoe-like craft _ is but one of more than a thousand artifacts and treasures from the museum's collection used to recreate the burial scenes. Visitors enter the tomb chambers of the 5th Dynasty pharaoh, King Unis, dating to 2400 B.C. and excavated from <LOCATION> Saqqara </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION>, in 1908. Beneath a false door, a 35-foot burial shaft takes visitors into the dark and eerie burial chamber. The sarcophagus is empty. When it was excavated, the pharaoh's mummy was gone, stolen by robbers or destroyed by time. Leaving the burial chamber, the visitor passes through a roughly hewn tomb robbers' tunnel and into another scene depicting a variety of Egyptian burial rites. `` This could well be the most fascinating part of the exhibit,'' said its developer, <PERSON> Janet </PERSON> <PERSON> Kamien </PERSON>. `` It gives them -LRB- visitors -RRB- a chance to explore the age-old mysteries of mummies and life after death.'' Next month, the museum staff will move 23 mummies into the exhibit, along with the accouterments their souls were to take with them to the afterworld. Sen-wosret's boat will be displayed nearby. No one actually knows if the boat was used to transport the king's body across the <LOCATION> Nile </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> to the burial site, said <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Yurco </PERSON>, a scholar on ancient <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION> at the <ORGANIZATION> Oriental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> and a consultant on the museum project. The boat was one of six found at the burial compound in 1893-94 by <PERSON> Jacques </PERSON> <PERSON> DeMorgan </PERSON>, a Welsh Egyptologist. Two badly deteriorated ones were left at the site. Two of the four DeMorgan saved are at the Egyptian Museum in <LOCATION> Cairo </LOCATION> and the other is at the <ORGANIZATION> Carnegie </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Museum </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Natural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> History </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION>. Sen-wosret is remembered for military campaigns that extended <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION>'s boundary into the Nubian region of <LOCATION> Ethiopia </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Sudan </LOCATION>, as well as securing control of the <LOCATION> Nile </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> to the south, he said. He also centralized the Egyptian government, setting the pattern for several hundred years. Sen-wosret is believed to have died when he was about 50, said <PERSON> Yurco </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880830-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-30-88 0403EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-CantoneseHoods     08-30 0363</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Cantonese Hoods,0374</SECOND>
<HEAD>Report: Young Toughs Abound In Canton</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN POMFRET</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Gangs of high school students are roving the industrial city of <LOCATION> Canton </LOCATION>, committing an increasing number of violent crimes, an official newspaper reported today. The Legal Daily -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> Fazhi </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ribao </ORGANIZATION> -RRB- said students have murdered, raped, robbed and are `` imitating feudal and underworld practices by forming illegal gangs.'' In another story, the paper called on the police to protect railway passengers from bands of teen-agers who raid trains and steal food and luggage. `` Let's deal with these little railroad guerrilla bands,'' the paper said. Although the report on <LOCATION> Canton </LOCATION> did not say how many crimes had been committed by the young hoodlums, it did say that 769 students were convicted of violent crimes last year, a 78.4 percent increase over 1986. The paper said the students took to a life of crime mainly because they did n't have sufficient political education. `` Some teachers these days are more willing to give three classes in math and literature than one class in political studies,'' the paper quoted one school principal as saying. The paper also said pornographic and violence-oriented literature and videocassettes were to blame for encouraging students to break the law. In addition, it said an increasing number of students are leaving school early to work. The paper said the dropouts exert a bad influence on their friends still in school. <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> is in the midst of economic reforms that are transforming the social stucture of the nation. Violent crime, especially robbery, and corruption have risen dramatically in the past few years. <LOCATION> Canton </LOCATION>, because it is in the forefront of the reforms, is changing most rapidly. In the report on the `` railroad guerrillas,'' the paper related an incident that occurred on June 19 as a train entered a station in <LOCATION> Hunan </LOCATION> province. `` Several dozen youngster ran to the train and began walking by the windows, occasionally looking in,'' the report said. `` Just as the train began moving, these children shoved their hands in the windows and grabbed food, beer bottles, cans, luggage and then fled with the goods.'' Said the report: `` All the victims could do was curse.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880830-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-30-88 0315EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Japan-Markets     08-30 0189</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Japan-Markets,0194</SECOND>
<HEAD>Stocks, Dollar Rise On Tokyo Exchange</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Share prices rose moderately on the <ORGANIZATION> Tokyo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Stock </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Exchange </ORGANIZATION> Tuesday, while the dollar inched up against the Japanese yen. The Nikkei Stock Average of 225 selected issues, a 299.81-point loser Monday, rebounded to close Tuesday's trading at 27,511.65. The market's main barometer erased marginal early losses and added 132.55 points or 0.48 percent. The dollar, which opened at 134.57 yen, closed at 134.39, up 0.19 yen from Monday's close of 134.20 yen. It ranged between 134.30 and 134.60 yen. Stock market participants were continuing to stay on the sidelines amid lackluster trading, according to an analyst with a major securities firm in <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION>. `` Because investors were still in a wait-and-see mood, trading was thin,'' he said on condition of anonymity. `` Any notable change is unlikely before the scheduled <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> report on employment figures Friday.'' He said investors were also acting cautiously ahead of the <ORGANIZATION> Tokyo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Stock </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Exchange </ORGANIZATION>'s plans to begin a new system of forward transactions. Press reports have said the new system will begin Sept. 3 and offer investors opportunities to earn profit with less risk.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880830-0025 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-30-88 0438EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-PoliticalBriefs 1stLd-Writethru a0502 08-30 0422</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Political Briefs, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0502,330</SECOND>
<NOTE>Eds: SUBS lead of 3rd item, to fix grammar, changes `says' to
`say'; Note item covers the same subject as the WASHINGTON TODAY
column for Monday PMs, which was slugged PM-Bush-Iran-Contra.</NOTE>
<HEAD>___</HEAD>
<HEAD>Cuomo Sees Dukakis Regaining Spotlight</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ALBANY, N.Y. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
