<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880403-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-03-88 2257EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Pope-Excerpts     04-03 0800</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Pope-Excerpts,0816</SECOND>
<HEAD>Excerpts from Pope's Easter Message</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-World Easter</HEAD>
<DATELINE>VATICAN CITY (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The following are excerpts from the official <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION> translation in English of Pope <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> II </PERSON>'s Easter Sunday message, `` Urbi et Orbi'' -LRB- To the City and World -RRB-, given in Italian: Queen of heaven rejoice! Behold, precisely today on this first day after the Sabbath the women went to the tomb, where the body of your son had been laid, having been taken down from the cross, and they found the stone rolled away, and the tomb empty. From within the tomb they heard a voice: `` Do not be amazed; you seek <PERSON> Jesus </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Nazareth </LOCATION>, who was crucified. He has risen, he is not here.'' Rejoice, queen of heaven! Rejoice, mother of Chirst! `` But go, tell his disciples and <PERSON> Peter </PERSON>.'' Then <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> of </PERSON> <PERSON> Magdala </PERSON> ran to tell the Apostles: `` They have taken the Lord out of the tomb, and we do not know where they haven laid him.'' <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> and <PERSON> John </PERSON> went at once to the place, and they found that it was as the women had said. He is not here. He is not here, in the place where they laid him, in the tomb. He is not here _ he has risen. Rejoice, queen of heaven! Rejoice, queen of heaven. ... What the tongues of the first witnesses now proclaim had first been foretold by himself. `` Destroy this temple, and in three days I will raise it up.. he spoke of the temple of his body.'' His scourged, tortured crucified body; his head wounded by the thorns; his side pierced by the lance. He is not here. ... Rejoice, queen of heaven! Rejoice, <PERSON> Mary </PERSON>, rejoice, mother! You bore his body in your virginal womb, you bore within you the God-man. And then you brought him forth on the night of <LOCATION> Bethlehem </LOCATION>, you bore him in your arms as a child. You bore him into the temple on the day of his presentation. Your eyes _ more than the eyes of anyone else _ saw the incarnate word. Your ears heard him, from his very first words. Your hands touched the word of life. Rejoice, queen of heaven! `` He whom you bore has risen.'' You bore him, even more than in your arms, in your heart. Particularly during those last hours, when you had to stand beneath the cross, at the feet of the divine condemned one. Your heart was pierced by the sword of sorrow, in accordance with the words of the aged <PERSON> Simeon </PERSON>. And you shared the sorrow as you associated yourself, with your maternal soul, in the sacrifice of your son. O mother! You consented to the immolation of the victim whom you had borne. You lovingly consented _ with that love which is planted in your heart. With that love which is stronger than death and stronger than sin, in the whole history of man on earth. And then, when he had breathed his last, and they had taken him down from the cross, he rested once more in your arms, as he has rested so many times before as a child ... And then, they laid him in the tomb. They took him from your maternal arms and gave him back to the earth; they closed the tomb with a stone ... And behold, now the stone has been rolled away, the tomb is empty. Christ whom you bore is risen, <PERSON> Hallelujah </PERSON>! Rejoice, queen of heaven! This is the day of the church's Easter joy we all share in your glory, O mother ... Everyone, the whole church of your son, the whole church of the incarnate word. Christ whom you bore is risen! Pray for us! Your who were present in the deepest possible way in the mystery of Christ. Behold, the whole church today looks to you, O <PERSON> Mary </PERSON>. Even though we do not see you among the people about whom the accounts of Easter tell, we all look to you. We look to your heart. Could any narrative record the moment of the resurrection of the son in the heart of his mother? Yet we fix our gaze on you. The whole church shares in your Easter joy the whole church knows that on this day that the Lord has made you `` go before'' in a singular way along this path of pilgrimage of faith in paschal mystery. Pray for us! During this year which has been dedicated in a particular way to you, during this Marian year, be present in a special way in the church, be present along all the paths of the people of God, paths upon which shines the light of Christ. Let this light never leave anyone, this light of the new life which is he himself, the risen one!
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880403-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-03-88 2257EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-KingAnniversary 1stLd-Writethru a0728 04-03 0612</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-King Anniversary, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0728,0621</SECOND>
<HEAD>Observances Remember King On 20th Anniversary Of His Killing</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: LEADS with 9 grafs to UPDATE with King service, quote from
King speech; Picks up 3rd graf, `On Monday ...'; ADDS 2 grafs with
Portland march; Note `promise land' in 4th graf quote is cq.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 The legacy of the Rev. <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Luther </PERSON> <PERSON> King </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, assassinated 20 years ago Monday, was remembered around the country Sunday by blacks and whites continuing the fight for racial equality and social justice that <PERSON> King </PERSON> began. `` Twenty years later, everything has changed and nothing has changed,'' <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Lowery </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Leadership </ORGANIZATION> conference, a civil rights organization formed by <PERSON> King </PERSON>, said Sunday night at a memorial service in <LOCATION> Memphis </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Tenn. </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s poor are as bad off as ever, speakers told the 500 people attending the service at the <ORGANIZATION> Mason </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Temple </ORGANIZATION> where King gave his `` Mountain Top'' speech on the eve of his murder at the <PERSON> Lorraine </PERSON> <PERSON> Motel </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Memphis </LOCATION> `` I've been to the mountain top ... I've looked over, and I've seen the promise land,'' <PERSON> King </PERSON> said in the speech `` I may not get there with you, but I want you to know tonight, that we as a people will get to the promised land.'' <PERSON> Benjamin </PERSON> <PERSON> Hooks </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> the </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Advancement </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Colored </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION>, said the address was one of the most emotional he had heard King deliver. `` It was a tremendous experience,'' <PERSON> Hooks </PERSON> said before speaking to about 500 people attending the <LOCATION> Memphis </LOCATION> service. Hooks urged the audience to renew its commitment to King's `` poor people's campaign,'' which was under way at the time of his death `` So Dr. <PERSON> King </PERSON>, we have n't made it yet ... but we are determined from this day, we are going to march forward, and ai n't nobody going to turn us around,'' he said. On Monday in <LOCATION> Memphis </LOCATION>, a memorial sponsored by the city is to begin with a ceremony at the <PERSON> Lorraine </PERSON>, followed by the beginning of a <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Leadership </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conference </ORGANIZATION> march through <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION>. That march is to conclude April 30 in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>. A simple wreath-laying ceremony will be held Monday afternoon at King's tomb in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> at the Martin Luther King Jr.. Center for Nonviolent Social Change King's widow, <PERSON> Coretta </PERSON> <PERSON> Scott </PERSON> <PERSON> King </PERSON>, has long favored an approach focusing on her late husband's life, not his death. Last year, she came out in opposition to plans to make the <PERSON> Lorraine </PERSON> <PERSON> Motel </PERSON> a museum, and said she did not want such a project to bear his name. Also in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> SCLC </ORGANIZATION> planned to hold its ninth annual `` Drum Major For Justice'' awards dinner Monday night. The event takes its title from a phrase King used to describe how he wished to be remembered. This year's honorees include <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Rep. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Espy </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION>, singer <PERSON> Dionne </PERSON> <PERSON> Warwick </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Redskins </ORGANIZATION> quarterback <PERSON> Doug </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>. <PERSON> Sharissa </PERSON> <PERSON> Fox </PERSON>, 17 and a senior at <ORGANIZATION> Greensboro </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dudley </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> High </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>, worries that her generation may not hear King's story often and powerfully enough `` Black people have made progress since King's assassination, but I do n't think we have gone as far as he would have liked,'' she said. `` His message was to help other people as much as we can. But my generation is so hooked on themselves, they do n't have time.'' In <LOCATION> Portland </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ore. </LOCATION>, nearly 100 people on Saturday joined in a 1.5-mile walk to mark King's assassination on April 4, 1968. `` When people gather together there is hope,'' said <PERSON> Ron </PERSON> <PERSON> Herndon </PERSON>, co-director of <LOCATION> Portland </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Black </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION>. `` The message is there still are those who will stand up against racism.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880403-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-03-88 2259EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-ChurchShooting 4thLd-Writethru a0792 04-03 0653</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Church Shooting, 4th Ld - Writethru, a0792,0664</SECOND>
<HEAD>Three Killed, Three Wounded In Shooting Outside Funeral</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: INSERTS 1 graf after 4th graf, `Michael Leslie...', to UPDATE
with mabn held without bail; picks up 5th graf, `Sheriff's
Capt...'. SUBS 11-12th grafs, bgng `Hatchett said...' with 4 grafs
to add further detail from sheriff's spokesman. Picks up 13th graf,
`The three ...'</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By PAUL NOWELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>EDNEYVILLE, N.C. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A man apparently angry over a land dispute involving his former in-laws opened fire on mourners gathering for an Easter Sunday funeral, killing three and wounding three others including his ex-wife, authorities said. The shooting occurred in the parking lot of the <ORGANIZATION> Mountain </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Home </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Baptist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION>, where family and friends gathered for a funeral service for <ORGANIZATION> Effie </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Collins </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION>, 79. The service had been scheduled to begin at 3 p.m., officials said, and the shooting took place shortly before that. `` It was just a really horrible experience, nothing I could ever have imagined,'' said <PERSON> Lester </PERSON> <PERSON> Justice </PERSON>, a nephew of Mrs. Justice. Like most of the mourners, Justice was already inside the small, brick rural church when the shooting began but could hear the gunfire. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Leslie </PERSON> <PERSON> Rainey </PERSON>, 41, was charged with three counts of first-degree murder and three counts of assault with a deadly weapon with intent to kill, according to a release from the Henderson County Sheriff's <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Rainey </PERSON> was being held without bond Sunday evening in the <LOCATION> Henderson </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jail </LOCATION>, awaiting an initial court appearance set for Monday morning. Sheriff's Capt. <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Hatchett </PERSON> said the dead were the parents of <PERSON> Rainey </PERSON>'s ex-wife, along with a 24-year-old man whose relationship to the family was not immediately determined. The three, <PERSON> Wilford </PERSON> <PERSON> Owensby </PERSON>, 61, of <PERSON> Fletcher </PERSON>; his wife, <PERSON> Ponnelle </PERSON>, 60; and <PERSON> Scott </PERSON> <PERSON> Bowles </PERSON>, 24, were all pronounced dead at the scene, the sheriff's department said. Mrs. <PERSON> Owensby </PERSON> was Mrs. Justice's daughter The suspect's former wife, <PERSON> Andrea </PERSON> <PERSON> Rainey </PERSON>, 40, of <LOCATION> Kennesaw </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ga. </LOCATION>, was taken to <LOCATION> Margaret </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Pardee </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Hendersonville </LOCATION> where she was listed in good condition with bullet wounds in the neck, said hospital spokeswoman <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Ann </PERSON> <PERSON> Morris </PERSON>. Mrs. <PERSON> Rainey </PERSON>'s sister, <PERSON> Sheila </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnston </PERSON>, 30, of <PERSON> Fletcher </PERSON>, and her daughter, <PERSON> Wendy </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnston </PERSON>, 11, were both listed in critical but stable condition at <ORGANIZATION> Memorial </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mission </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Asheville </LOCATION>, said nursing supervisor <PERSON> Evelyn </PERSON> <PERSON> Woody </PERSON>. Mrs. <PERSON> Johnston </PERSON> was wounded in the chest, while her daughter was wounded in the leg, the hospital said. <PERSON> Rainey </PERSON> apparently confronted his former wife and her relatives in the parking lot, <PERSON> Hatchett </PERSON> said. `` There seems to be some sort of domestic thing, over conflict over some land,'' he said. The suspect owned land near the church which is adjacent to property belonging to Mrs. <PERSON> Rainey </PERSON>'s family, he said. Witnesses said the suspect walked into the church to view the body of Mrs. Justice, and then walked outside. Mourners in the church then heard gunshots. `` I understand they were having visitation when he came to the church. He apparently had weapons in a vehicle outside the church. He went outside and got them out of the trunk and then started shooting,'' <PERSON> Hatchett </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Hatchett </PERSON> said <PERSON> Rainey </PERSON> left the shooting scene on foot after dropping the weapons in the parking lot. He was arrested without incident a short distance away. Two weapons were found in the parking lot, a handgun and a shotgun, <PERSON> Hatchett </PERSON> said. Witnesses said Mrs. <PERSON> Rainey </PERSON> drove herself and her wounded sister and niece away from the church after the shooting, and her <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> sedan was riddled with bullet holes. The three were in the car when the shooting broke out, <PERSON> Hatchett </PERSON> said. The three reached the <LOCATION> Hendersonville </LOCATION> city limits, a few miles away, before authorities transferred them from the blood-stained car to ambulances. The funeral was canceled. Police were still interviewing witnesses at the church Sunday evening. <LOCATION> Edneyville </LOCATION> is an unincorporated town in a rural area in the western part of the state, about 20 miles southeast of <LOCATION> Asheville </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880403-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-03-88 0007EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Drive-ByShootings 3rdLd-Writethru a0644 04-03 0695</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Drive-By Shootings, 3rd Ld - Writethru, a0644,0711</SECOND>
<HEAD>Police Chief Vows To Deploy 1,000 Officers In Gang Area</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDS: LEADS with 3 grafs to UPDATE with two gang members wounded in
Saturday violence. Pickup 2nd graf pvs, `County Supervisor...'</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By BARBARA METZLER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Police Chief <PERSON> Daryl </PERSON> <PERSON> Gates </PERSON> vowed Saturday to deploy 1,000 officers on gang-ridden south-central streets to keep Easter churchgoers safe after a drive-by shooting in which one man died and 12 others were wounded. Gang violence erupted later in the day when two gang members were wounded by gunfire after a confrontation between rival groups in a downtown parking lot, said police Lt. <PERSON> Orley </PERSON> <PERSON> Barton </PERSON>. The victims, both 21, were taken to <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> County-USC Medical Center. A spokeswoman said one was in fair condition with a gunshot wound in the foot and the second, who was hit in the buttocks, was listed as serious. County Supervisor <PERSON> Kenneth </PERSON> <PERSON> Hahn </PERSON> sent a telegram to Gov. <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Deukmejian </PERSON> urging him to declare a state of emergency in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> and send in two companies of military police from the <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> National Guard. `` The people of <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> are increasingly living in a state of fear. No one is safe,'' he wrote. `` The governor is very concerned about the escalation of gang violence in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>,'' said <PERSON> Deukmejian </PERSON>'s press secretary, <PERSON> Kevin </PERSON> <PERSON> Brett </PERSON>. However, he would declare a state of emergency only after the city and county governments proclaim that such an emergency exists and that it exceeds the capabilities of local law enforcement officials, <PERSON> Brett </PERSON> said. No one had been arrested in Friday's shooting, but <PERSON> Gates </PERSON> said police were investigating leads on two men seen shooting from a passing car. One of those wounded was a 4-year-old boy. The shootings came in the midst of a police crackdown on escalating gang violence, which only a day earlier prompted one <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> supervisor to call for help from the <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> National Guard. `` If we were angry before, we are exceedingly angry now,'' <PERSON> Gates </PERSON> said at a news conference where he called gang members `` rotten little cowards ... who shoot down 4-year-old kids.'' Plans were under way to put 1,000 officers on south-central streets where 200 officers usually patrol, <PERSON> Gates </PERSON> said, adding that 300 officers would be out Saturday night. `` We have all this shooting going on on the holy weekend. People in south-central <LOCATION> L.A. </LOCATION> want to go to church tomorrow and we're going to make sure they're safe,'' <PERSON> Gates </PERSON> said. He also called for night sessions at all courts in order to speed up trials and put criminals behind bars, special courts to handle gang and narcotic cases, and a south-central justice center. Lt. <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Massey </PERSON> said Friday's shots were fired on turf claimed by five or six gangs, and that the shootings probably were intended as some type of retaliation. Police believe a semi-automatic weapon was used. <PERSON> Rodney </PERSON> <PERSON> Bragg </PERSON>, 16, said he saw men in a Cadillac stop and talk to a group of people. `` All of a sudden they just opened up,'' he said. `` There were about 20 shots, I guess. Maybe more than that. You could hear them hitting the trees and the houses _ everything.'' The car sped off and then returned `` for another look'' before fleeing, <PERSON> Bragg </PERSON> said. At least 25 rounds were fired, <PERSON> Gates </PERSON> said. Cmdr. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Booth </PERSON> said 13 people were hit. Only 11 were accounted for at local hospitals. Authorities said two people may have sought medical attention on their own. Seven anti-gang police sweeps through the city in the past month, including one through the southside Thursday night, have resulted in 874 arrests and seizures of weapons, drugs, cash and cars. On Thursday, county Supervisor <PERSON> Kenneth </PERSON> <PERSON> Hahn </PERSON> asked Gov. <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Deukmejian </PERSON> to call in the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> to help quell gang violence. <PERSON> Hahn </PERSON> cited 387 gang-related deaths within the county last year and said the gang-related death rate in the first three months of 1988 exceeds the rate for the same period last year. However, since the sweeps, the tally of gang-related homicides apparently has decreased, from 25 in March 1987 to 14 in March 1988, police said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880403-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-03-88 0057EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Britain-Waldheim     04-03 0230</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Britain-Waldheim,0235</SECOND>
<HEAD>Wartime British Pilot Captured By German Army Says Waldheim Saved
His Life</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A former British fighter pilot was reported Sunday as saying Austrian President <PERSON> Kurt </PERSON> <PERSON> Waldheim </PERSON> saved his life and those of other Allied prisoners during World War II by preventing them falling into the hands of Nazi executioners. The Sunday Times said the pilot, <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Ogilvie </PERSON>, is the `` first and possibly the only British ex-serviceman to speak in defense of <PERSON> Waldheim </PERSON>,'' who denies accusations of involvement in war crimes when he was serving with the German army. <PERSON> Ogilvie </PERSON>, now 66, said he was in danger of being shot when he was found armed and in civilian clothes on the British-occupied Greek island of Leros in November 1943, the day after German paratroops invaded. He said he was taken to an airfield outside <LOCATION> Athens </LOCATION> where he met <PERSON> Waldheim </PERSON>, who introduced himself by name and ensured that <PERSON> Ogilvie </PERSON> and others were sent to a prisoner-of-war camp instead of the Nazi SS, who shot prisoners. <PERSON> Ogilvie </PERSON> said <PERSON> Waldheim </PERSON> took the prisoners' identity discs and gave them substitutes which had been taken from the bodies of Allied servicemen killed in action. The discs enabled the prisoners to prove they were not commandos or spies. <PERSON> Ogilvie </PERSON> said he mentioned <PERSON> Waldheim </PERSON>'s help to <ORGANIZATION> Royal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Officers </ORGANIZATION> who debriefed him after his release from a prison camp in May 1945.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880403-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-03-88 0128EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Japan-Bridge     04-03 0238</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Japan-Bridge,0245</SECOND>
<HEAD>Thousands Fete Completion Of Seto Ohashi Bridge</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhotos OKA1,2,TOK1</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserColor OKA3</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Thousands of cyclists, joggers and sightseers turned out Saturday and Sunday to cross <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s majestic <LOCATION> Seto </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ohashi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bridge </LOCATION>, which straddles five small islands over an expanse of 7.6 miles in the <LOCATION> Seto </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Inland </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sea </LOCATION>. Police bands performed and hundreds of balloons were set off as <PERSON> Seto </PERSON> bridge authorities feted to mark the completion of the first physical linkup between the main island of <LOCATION> Honshu </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Shikoku </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION>, located on the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> side of southeastern <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>. About 100,000 pedestrians, selected by lottery from around the country, formed a human link between <ORGANIZATION> Shikoku </ORGANIZATION> and <LOCATION> Honshu </LOCATION> on the bridge at noon Sunday. On Saturday, 3,000 people crossed the <PERSON> Ohashi </PERSON> -LRB- literally <LOCATION> Great </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bridge </LOCATION> -RRB- on bicycles, while an estimated 7,000-8 ,000 joggers joined in later the same day The bridge, which cost $ 8.7 billion and took 10 years to build, will open to both rail and vehicle traffic after the official opening April 10. Transportation officials acknowledge that while the railway portion of the bridge is not expected to recoup its construction costs, toll charges for the highway section of the bridge should help to keep operation costs near or above deficit levels. The Seto <LOCATION> Ohashi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bridge </LOCATION>, consisting of six suspension bridges in the style of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Golden </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gate </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bridge </LOCATION>, will be formally connected to that Californian symbol in a sister bridge ceremony scheduled for Tuesday.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880403-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-03-88 0356EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i BC-Greece-Quakes     04-03 0216</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Greece-Quakes,0223</SECOND>
<HEAD>Three Moderate Quakes Shake Athens</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ATHENS, Greece (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Three moderate overnight quakes shook the <LOCATION> Greek </LOCATION> capital, frightening some residents out of their homes but causing no damage or injuries, officials said Sunday. A spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> Athens </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Seismological </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> said the first temblor measured 4.2 on the <PERSON> Richter </PERSON> scale at 11:06 p.m. Saturday. It had its epicenter 12 miles east of <LOCATION> Athens </LOCATION>, just outside the seaside resort town of <LOCATION> Loutsa </LOCATION>. The second quake struck in the same area at 00:58 a.m. Sunday and registered 4.6 on the <PERSON> Richter </PERSON> scale. The third tremor, hitting 4.4 on the <PERSON> Richter </PERSON> scale, took place at 06:35 a.m. Sunday and had its its epicenter 47 miles west-northwest of <LOCATION> Athens </LOCATION>. `` We had some minor panic and some people ran out of their homes and into the streets, but we had no damage,'' said a police spokesman in <LOCATION> Loutsa </LOCATION>. The earthquakes, felt all over the capital, did not cause much panic, <LOCATION> Athens </LOCATION> police said. `` We had alot of people call in to see what happened but we had no reports of serious panic,'' an <LOCATION> Athens </LOCATION> police spokesman said. The Richter scale is a gauge of the energy released by an earthquake, as measured by the ground motion recorded on a seismograph. A magnitude 4 quake can cause moderate damage.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880403-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-03-88 0458EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i BC-Soviet-NuclearTest     04-03 0195</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Soviet-Nuclear Test,0202</SECOND>
<HEAD>Soviets Set Off Third Nuclear Test in Kazakhstan</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MOSCOW (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> set off an underground nuclear test explosion early Sunday in the republic of <LOCATION> Kazakhstan </LOCATION>, the official <ORGANIZATION> Tass </ORGANIZATION> news agency reported. The blast, the third nuclear test announced by the Soviets this year, was `` carried out with a view to upgrading military technology,'' <ORGANIZATION> Tass </ORGANIZATION> said. The explosion had a yield of 20 to 150 kilotons, <ORGANIZATION> Tass </ORGANIZATION> said. The <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> atom bomb dropped on <LOCATION> Hiroshima </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, on Aug. 6, 1945, had a yield of 20 kilotons, or the equivalent of 20,000 tons of TNT. The device was exploded at the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>'s main nuclear testing range in <LOCATION> Semipalatinsk </LOCATION>, in the Central Asian republic of <LOCATION> Kazakhstan </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Tass </ORGANIZATION> provided no further information on the blast. In January, an American scientific delegation visited the <LOCATION> Semipalatinsk </LOCATION> range to gather information that may be used in verifying U.S.-Soviet compliance with a future test ban. An exchange of visits to <LOCATION> Semipalatinsk </LOCATION> and to the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> nuclear testing site in <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION> is planned this month. The Soviet government has been pressing for a pact prohibiting nuclear testing, but <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and Soviet officials disagree on enforcement procedures.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880403-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-03-88 0604EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i BC-Israel     04-03 0576</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Israel,0591</SECOND>
<HEAD>Army: Arab Electrocuted While Hanging Palestinian Flag To Utility
Pole</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KARIN LAUB</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>JERUSALEM (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The army said an Arab youth was electrocuted Sunday when he tried to attach a <LOCATION> Palestinian </LOCATION> flag to a utility pole. Hospital officials said a second <PERSON> Arab </PERSON> died of gunshot wounds suffered last week in a clash with <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> soldiers. The fatalities came hours before the scheduled arrival of Secretary of State <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> for a third round of talks with Israeli leaders on his <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> peace initiative and while hundreds of Christians celebrated Easter in <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION>. The deaths also occurred a day after <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> soldiers shot and killed six <PERSON> Arab </PERSON> protesters in the occupied <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strip </LOCATION>, the highest one-day death toll in four months of unrest. The <ORGANIZATION> Jerusalem </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> newspaper quoted military sources as saying the army has adopted a new policy of entering even remote Arab villages to break up protests instead of ignoring demonstrators as long as they did not endanger lives or interfere with traffic on the main roads. `` The confrontations -LRB- over the weekend -RRB- were a result of our initiative,'' Defense Minister <PERSON> Yitzhak </PERSON> <PERSON> Rabin </PERSON> told <ORGANIZATION> Israel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> radio </ORGANIZATION>. In <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION>, about 1,000 pilgrims from around the world attended Easter Sunday services in the Church of the Holy Sepulcher where most Christians believe <PERSON> Jesus </PERSON> was buried and rose from the dead. Church officials said the number of worshipers dropped by half from last year, apparently because many pilgrims were scared away by the violence in the occupied territories. In the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> town of <LOCATION> Tulkarem </LOCATION>, 40 miles northwest of <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION>, an army official said a 20-year-old Arab youth died early Sunday after being electrocuted when he tried to attach a red, white, black and green Palestinian flag, outlawed by <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>, to a utility pole. After receiving the shock, the youth fell from the pole and hit his head, said the official who, in keeping with army regulations, spoke on condition of anonymity. The youth was pronounced dead at <LOCATION> Tulkarem </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Arab </PERSON> journalists identified the victim as 15-year-old <PERSON> Mahmoud </PERSON> <PERSON> Abdul </PERSON> <PERSON> Rahim </PERSON> <PERSON> Jarad </PERSON> and said he was shot to death by <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> soldiers. Officials at <LOCATION> Tulkarem </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION> could not immediately be reached for comment on the cause of death. At <LOCATION> Ramallah </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION>, 10 miles north of <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION>, a 40-year-old <PERSON> Arab </PERSON> died Sunday of wounds he suffered Wednesday in a clash with <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> soldiers. During the clash, <PERSON> Ali </PERSON> <PERSON> Diab </PERSON> <PERSON> Abu </PERSON> <PERSON> Ali </PERSON> of the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> village <LOCATION> Yatta </LOCATION>, was shot in the neck and paralyzed, said a doctor who spoke on condition of anonymity. His death brought to 134 the number of Arabs killed in four months of anti-Israeli protests, according to <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> figures. The youth from <LOCATION> Tulkarem </LOCATION> was not included in the count because of conflicting reports on the circumstances of his death. One Israeli soldier has died in the violence. <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> is scheduled to meet Monday with <PERSON> Rabin </PERSON>, Prime Minister <PERSON> Yitzhak </PERSON> <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON> and Foreign Minister <PERSON> Shimon </PERSON> <PERSON> Peres </PERSON>. <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> radio quoted sources in <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION> as saying <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> planned to present to <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> leaders an invitation to an international peace conference which is to launch direct bilateral negotiations between the parties to the conflict. <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON> opposes key elements of the <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> plan, especially a proposed international conference. The <ORGANIZATION> Jerusalem </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> quoted a <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON> aide as saying `` if <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> does n't present any new ideas in his talks with <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON> ..., the prime minister will not budge.'' <PERSON> Peres </PERSON> supports the <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> plan.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880403-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-03-88 0644EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i BC-Pope-Easter     04-03 0579</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Pope-Easter,0596</SECOND>
<HEAD>Appeals for Peace and Justice; Wishes Happy Easter in 52 Languages</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By STEPHEN R. WILSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>VATICAN CITY (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Pope <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> II </PERSON> celebrated Easter Sunday Mass in <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Peter </LOCATION><LOCATION> 's </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Basilica </LOCATION>, then appealed for world peace and offered Easter greetings in 52 languages to thousands of worshipers in rain-drenched <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Peter </LOCATION>'s Square. Among the thousands of people who packed <LOCATION> Christendom </LOCATION>'s biggest church for the Mass was <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Secretary of State <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON>, who was to leave later in the day for <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> on a new <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> peace mission. The Mass, usually held on the flower-decked travertine steps of <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Peter </LOCATION>'s, was moved inside the church because of rain. But the pope later spoke from the church's central balcony as more than 100,000 people stood in the square below. In his traditional Easter message `` Urbi and Orbi'' -LRB- to the city of <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION> and the world -RRB- following the Mass, the pope asked the <PERSON> Virgin </PERSON> <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> to pray for peace, justice, human rights and religious freedom. Departing from his written text and speaking emotionally in a strong, hoarse voice, the pontiff said, `` Pray for peace in the world, for justice, pray for the rights of man, especially for religious freedom, for every man, for every Christian and non-Christian, pray for us.'' `` Pray for the solidarity of all peoples of the world, the first world, second, third and fourth, all the world,'' he said. `` In yours and our Easter joy, we carry again this weight of humanity, this weight of so many human hearts, our brothers, our sisters, and we repeat: pray for us.'' In a private audience on Saturday, <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> had received the <PERSON> pope </PERSON>'s blessing for his voyage. <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON>'s wife, <PERSON> Helena </PERSON>, a Roman Catholic, was one of those taking Communion from the pope. Winter weather descended on <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION> this weekend, with a cold, steady rain drenching the capital Sunday morning. It was decided at the last moment to move the service inside the basilica, where the pope celebrated Mass from an altar under the `` Baldacchino,'' the immense Baroque canopy designed by <PERSON> Bernini </PERSON>. The Italian news agency <ORGANIZATION> ANSA </ORGANIZATION> estimated that 150,000 Romans, pilgrims and tourists _ most of them huddling under umbrellas _ stood outside in the square and its side streets and listened to the service broadcast on loud speakers by <ORGANIZATION> Radio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Vatican </ORGANIZATION>. The crowd broke into loud cheers and chants of `` Viva il Papa'' -LRB- long live the pope -RRB- when <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON>, keeping with tradition, appeared on the central balcony at noon to deliver his Easter message and blessing. The message was directed to the <PERSON> Virgin </PERSON> <PERSON> Mary </PERSON>, for whom the pope has a special devotion and dedicated the current Marian Year. `` Christ whom you bore is risen, Alleluia,'' said the pope, wearing a white robe trimmed in gold and a tall, gold miter, or bishop's hat. `` Queen of heaven, rejoice. This is the day of the church's Easter joy. We all share in your glory, oh mother.'' `` Behold the whole church today tooks to you, oh <PERSON> Mary </PERSON>. Even though we do not see you among the people about whom the accounts of Easter tell, we all look to you ... `` During this year, which has been dedicated in a particular way to you, during this <PERSON> Marian </PERSON> <PERSON> Year </PERSON>, be present in a special way in the church..'' Then, following his improvised plea for world peace, the polyglot pope wished the world a happy Easter in 52 languages The longest greeting was in his native Polish.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880403-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-03-88 0840EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i BC-Iran-Iraq     04-03 0240</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Iran-Iraq,0247</SECOND>
<HEAD>Iraq Renews War of Cities</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NICOSIA, Cyprus (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> said its warplanes raided two oil refineries deep inside <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> on Sunday, but <ORGANIZATION> Iran </ORGANIZATION> said the bombs landed in residential areas and killed at least five civilians and wounded 50 more. The attacks signaled the rekindling of the `` war of the cities'' after a break of 2 -LCB- days. Hundreds of civilians have been killed or wounded in more than a month of missile and warplane raids on major population centers. The official <ORGANIZATION> Iraqi </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> quoted a military communique as saying the strikes on the refineries near the cities of <LOCATION> Isfahan </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Tabriz </LOCATION> were carried out at 2:40 p.m.. That was about six hours after Turkish Prime Minister <PERSON> Turgut </PERSON> <PERSON> Ozal </PERSON> left the <LOCATION> Iraqi </LOCATION> capital <LOCATION> Baghdad </LOCATION> had ceased its attacks on Iranian cities during his visit and announced it would not resume attacks for six hours after he left. <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Islamic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> said the warplanes bombed residential quarters in <LOCATION> Tabriz </LOCATION>, in northeastern <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>, and the central city of <LOCATION> Isfahan </LOCATION>. At least five civilians were killed and 50 wounded, said the news agency report. The Iranian and <LOCATION> Iraqi </LOCATION> dispatches were monitored in <LOCATION> Cyprus </LOCATION>. The Iranian agency claimed that anti-aircraft batteries shot down one of the warplanes at <LOCATION> Isfahan </LOCATION> `` seconds after the attack'' on the city. It did not say where the plane fell nor disclose the fate of the pilot. <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> had no comment on the claim.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880403-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-03-88 1032EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Soviet-PartyCleanup     04-03 0250</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Soviet-Party Cleanup,0257</SECOND>
<HEAD>Party Expels Officials For Gross Misconduct, Embezzlement</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MOSCOW (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Two <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> factory managers were expelled from the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> for embezzlement, on-the-job drinking parties and paying $ 1.6 million to two hockey players who masqueraded as machine operators, a Soviet newspaper said Sunday. The report in Pravda, the official paper of the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, was taken to be a message to party members at all state industries. Pravda also reported that party's <ORGANIZATION> Control </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> had disciplined two officials of the state <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aviation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Machine-Building </ORGANIZATION> involved in the errant enterprise. The report said the managers of the Salyut air transport machine-building enterprise engaged in embezzlement but it did not give a total figure for the losses suffered by the factory. Still, the newspaper gave several examples of excesses that cost in the tens of thousands of dollars, indicating the violations were broad. Factory director Y.V. <PERSON> Pugin </PERSON> and party committee chairman <PERSON> A.G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Samarkin </PERSON> were expelled, and other senior party officials at the plant and the ministry were reprimanded, the newspaper said. Under Soviet leader <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s reforms aimed at improving economic performance, party members have come under close scrutiny. Only about 8 percent of Soviet adults gain entrance into the all-powerful party, and the <ORGANIZATION> Control </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> is charged with ensuring that Communists set an appropriate example for other workers. Stories about the abuse of authority and inattention to the cause of poor performance have become common as the party carries out internal reviews of its personnel.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880403-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-03-88 1032EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-BRF-NewZealand-Climbers     04-03 0125</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF-New Zealand-Climbers,0128</SECOND>
<HEAD>Two Climbers Die On Mountain, One Survives</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CHRISTCHURCH, New Zealand (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Two <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Zealand </LOCATION> climbers died and a third was injured after they plunged 500 feet down a mountainside while roped together, police said Sunday. The two women and a man fell off <LOCATION> Mount </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Cook </LOCATION> as they were approaching the top of the <LOCATION> Copeland </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Pass </LOCATION>, police spokesman <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Apes </PERSON> said. Two alpine guides witnessed the accident from the Copeland shelter, he said. One radioed for help while the other went to the scene, where the man died. One of the women suffered head injuries and was flown by helicopter to <LOCATION> Timaru </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION> where she died on Saturday night. The other woman was admitted to hospital with moderate injuries, Apes said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880403-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-03-88 1032EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-BRF--France-Explosion     04-03 0092</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--France-Explosion,0095</SECOND>
<HEAD>One Dead In Apartment House Explosion</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PARIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An explosion apparently caused by a gas leak ripped through an apartment building in suburban Ville d'Avray on Sunday, killing an 18-year-old woman and injuring 14 people, the fire department said. The woman was crushed to death by a falling chuck of concrete. One of the 14 injured was reported in serious condition. The explosion occurred at about 3 a.m. and devastated the second, third and fourth floors of the nine-story building. The other residents of the building were evacuated.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880403-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-03-88 1034EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-BRF--France-Accident     04-03 0135</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--France-Accident,0139</SECOND>
<HEAD>Two Die In Bus-Truck Crash</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 SALON-DE-PROVENCE, <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> -RRB- _ A <LOCATION> Spanish </LOCATION> bus carrying 53 people Sunday slammed into a small truck that stopped on a highway because of a flat tire. Police said the drivers of both vehicles were killed. The truck's driver had stopped in the right line to repair the flat tire and one of its four occupants tried to alert traffic, police said. The Spanish bus, traveling in the same direction, hit the truck from behind and killed its driver, 32-year-old <PERSON> Bouhid </PERSON> <PERSON> Abdellati </PERSON>. The driver of the bus, <PERSON> Eduardo </PERSON> <PERSON> Asensio </PERSON> <PERSON> Arribas </PERSON>, 61, also was killed. The three other occupants of the truck suffered no injuries. Twenty-six passengers on the bus were slightly injured and taken to local hospitals. They were identified as teen-agers from a religious school in <LOCATION> Saragosa </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880403-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-03-88 1035EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p AM-JacksoninAspen Bjt   04-03 0757</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Jackson in Aspen, Bjt,740</SECOND>
<HEAD>Candidate of the Downtrodden Gets Support from the Already
Uplifted</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By WILLIAM M. WELCH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ASPEN, Colo. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, accustomed to bringing an uplifting message to the downtrodden, found a warm reception among the already uplifted at this chic ski playground. Looking to win delegates in Mondays' <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION> Democratic caucuses, <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> dropped in on the sunny, snowy resort high in the <LOCATION> Rocky </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mountains </LOCATION> on Saturday afternoon. It was a visit that took the black civil rights leader and presidential candidate a long way from his usual audiences _ like the Hispanics who surged to touch him in <LOCATION> Pueblo </LOCATION>, and the striking meatpackers in <LOCATION> Greeley </LOCATION> who cheered wildly to his denunciation of the rich and powerful earlier in the day. `` I was surprised he came here,'' said <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Scheerer </PERSON>, a tanned and blond frequent visitor from <LOCATION> Minneapolis </LOCATION> who strained to get <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> in the sights of her video camera as he arrived. `` I guess it's because the mayor invited him.'' <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> was greeted by the town's white, bearded mayor, <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Stirling </PERSON>, a local real estate man who sported a <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> bumper sticker across his white cowboy hat. Later, wearing a blue pin-stripe suit and bow tie, he danced and sang along with a recorded campaign song after introducing the candidate. `` People have said, ` Why Aspen?' It's too glitzy, too lily white, too middle class,'' the mayor said, his last remark drawing laughter. `` Well, we vote here too.'' Arriving after a day of skiing was <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Hayden </PERSON>, the <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> legislator and husband of actress <PERSON> Jane </PERSON> <PERSON> Fonda </PERSON>. He was n't endorsing <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, he said, but he had nice things to say about him. The gathering spilled out the door from the ornate room in the old <PERSON> Jerome </PERSON> <PERSON> Hotel </PERSON>, a recently restored three-story brick building that looks like it came straight out of the Old West _ but updated for the ski crowd. To get to <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s speech, people walked past guests frolicking in the hotel's outdoor hot tub and through a bar with a giant chandelier made of antlers. Some who turned out were supporters, and some just seemed curious. Many wore bright ski suits. One man dressed in cowboy shirt and hat, face red from skiing, said on his way in: `` We're here for both _ <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> and the fashion show.'' He said there really was a fashion show in town, but he might have been talking about the affluent, all-white crowd's wardrobe Others claimed to be real supporters. At the <LOCATION> Pitkin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION>, where the idle private jets of <LOCATION> Aspen </LOCATION>'s visitors wait in rows, <PERSON> Andrea </PERSON> <PERSON> Hanson </PERSON> was among the handful of greeters. `` I just think he's the best thing going,'' said <PERSON> Hanson </PERSON>, clad in a black leather miniskirt. She described herself as an author of children's books. Posters printed by local supporters invited people to see <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>. Included was a notice that the reception beforehand was `` for substantial contributors only -LRB- $ 100 to $ 1,000 -RRB-.'' <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> spoke passionately, as usual, of the poor, but at the same time responded to his monied audience. The poor work, he said, and are all around, even in <LOCATION> Aspen </LOCATION>. `` They changed the sheets in the hotel you slept in last night,'' he said. `` The upper class can not remain upper if there is not a middle class,'' he told the substantial contributors. One man put a tough question to <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>: did he back raising taxes as high as 60 percent on upper incomes like his own? It would discourage the creation of jobs, he said. `` To tax you 60 percent would be as absurd as a tax cut,'' responded <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, who hours earlier had denounced President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> for `` reverse Robin Hood'' _ taking from the poor for the rich. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> suggested the tax rates before President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s 1981 tax cut were reasonable. With the larger crowd, <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> did n't miss an opportunity to ask for contributions to his campaign. `` Give like you live _ high,'' <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> led in responsive chants as he does with other audiences _ evoking such shouts as `` vote'' and `` <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON>.'' When they did n't get it right, he interrupted: `` Let's stop and do it right, do it with rhythm and soul. A few feet to the side, <PERSON> Hayden </PERSON> was talking politics and speculating on a <PERSON> Mario </PERSON> <PERSON> Cuomo-Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> ticket. `` Something very powerful is happening,'' <PERSON> Hayden </PERSON> said. `` I do n't know if he can win in November, but nobody else is having an effect like this. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> seemed to enjoy his visit, too. The chanting done, <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> grinned and waved. `` Okay, <LOCATION> Aspen </LOCATION>,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880403-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-03-88 1035EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-SouthAfrica-Mines     04-03 0165</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-South Africa-Mines,0168</SECOND>
<HEAD>Military Exhibit Teaches Public How Land Mines Work</HEAD>
<DATELINE>JOHANNESBURG, South Africa (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A military exhibit at a popular South African festival includes a detailed demonstration on how to plant and detect land mines. The South African <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> exhibit is part of the Grand Rand Show, a three-week festival that began Wednesday on the outskirts of <LOCATION> Johannesburg </LOCATION>. The large military display includes a section with a South African soldier explaining how land mines work and how the military detects them. Visitors are allowed to handle the mine detector and wear the headset that gives off a beeping noise when a dummy mine is detected. If someone steps on the dummy mine, it gives off a harmless puff of green smoke. The soldier at the exhibit also explains the proper way to plant and disguise a land mine. Guerrillas of the <ORGANIZATION> African </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> often employ land mines as part of their bombing and sabotage campaign to overthrow the white-led government.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880403-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-03-88 1037EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-People     04-03 0833</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-People,0870</SECOND>
<HEAD>People in the News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY44</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WOODSIDE, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Boldly going where few have gone before, actor <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Shatner </PERSON> touched hands and talked with <PERSON> Koko </PERSON> the gorilla. <PERSON> Shatner </PERSON>, also known as Capt. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> T. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kirk </PERSON> of `` Star Trek'' fame, spent half an hour with the celebrated 16-year-old lowland gorilla at the Gorilla Foundation Saturday. <PERSON> Koko </PERSON> lives at the nonprofit organization's center and has been taught to understand 2,000 words of spoken English and use a vocabulary of 600 signs. `` <PERSON> Koko </PERSON> and I talked,'' <PERSON> Shatner </PERSON> said. `` We touched hands and we touched minds. Feeling her powerful hand on the back of my neck was unlike any other experience I've known.'' <PERSON> Koko </PERSON> also touched <PERSON> Shatner </PERSON> on the face, making what Dr. <PERSON> Francine </PERSON> `` Penny'' <PERSON> Patterson </PERSON>, <PERSON> Koko </PERSON>'s trainer and the foundation president, interpreted as romantic overtures. <PERSON> Koko </PERSON> has communicated to foundation officials that she `` want gorilla baby.'' The foundation has made arrangements to have her artificially inseminated. <PERSON> Shatner </PERSON> was promoting a new program under which Californians can donate money to help endangered species through a checkoff on their state tax forms.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>Embargoed by source until 6:01 EDT Sunday</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY5</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Prince <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> and Princess <PERSON> Diana </PERSON> have `` ordinary'' marital quarrels, but <PERSON> Diana </PERSON> still loves her husband and is happy as a member of the royal family, her father, <PERSON> Earl </PERSON> <PERSON> Spencer </PERSON>, was quoted as saying Sunday. In an interview with Woman's Own magazine, the earl was also quoted as saying <PERSON> Diana </PERSON>, who has two sons, <PERSON> William </PERSON>, 5, and <PERSON> Harry </PERSON>, 3, wants a larger family _ perhaps five children. `` <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> and <PERSON> Diana </PERSON> have their rows, what couple does n't. But they are nothing out of the ordinary'' the 64-year-old aristocrat was quoted as saying. `` What makes it so different for them is that they're on show all the time. They might have had a disagreement, then they have to step out in front of the cameras and pretend that everything is going well and that's not easy.'' <PERSON> Spencer </PERSON> was questioned about press reports that the marriage of <PERSON> Charles </PERSON>, 39, and <PERSON> Diana </PERSON>, 26, now in its seventh year, was in deep trouble. <PERSON> Spencer </PERSON> said dismissed reports his daughter is bored and frustrated with her role. `` She's the fairy tale princess because she does a wonderful job.'' <PERSON> Spencer </PERSON> was quoted as saying. `` She's very genuine, she's very beautiful and she's still very much in love with <PERSON> Charles </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NASHVILLE, Tenn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actor-director <PERSON> Spike </PERSON> <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> did n't shy from a heated debate with <ORGANIZATION> Fisk </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> students about his latest film, `` School Daze.'' <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> appeared at this black school Thursday to promote the movie, which focuses on a black college and students' attitudes about fraternities. `` The fraternity members were upset about how fraternities were portrayed in the film. We had 90 minutes of heated dialogue. It was very healthy and just the kind of thing I like to see happen,'' he said. <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> said the movie is about the need for `` more unity among black people.'' `` The viewers from the black underclass will see in the film what they have seen in real life _ being looked down upon and shunned by the middle class,'' said <PERSON> Lee </PERSON>, who is black. His first movie, the surprise hit `` She's Got ta Have It,'' was made for $ 175,000 and has reaped about $ 8 million.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>PALM SPRINGS, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Restaurateur and mayoral candidate <PERSON> Sonny </PERSON> <PERSON> Bono </PERSON> says he regrets his outburst at a televised candidates' forum but refuses to apologize The forum had been under way for more than an hour Thursday night when <PERSON> Bono </PERSON> arrived and said he could n't participate because his pregnant wife was ill. <PERSON> Bono </PERSON>, the former husband and singing partner of <PERSON> Cher </PERSON>, demanded to know why moderator <PERSON> Ed </PERSON> <PERSON> Kibbey </PERSON> had not explained <PERSON> Bono </PERSON>'s absence <PERSON> Kibbey </PERSON> said neither he nor the forum's sponsor, the <ORGANIZATION> Palm </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Springs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Jaycees </ORGANIZATION>, were told why <PERSON> Bono </PERSON> was absent. He asked the candidate to join the forum, but <PERSON> Bono </PERSON> declined and said he would return to his wife. At one point, <PERSON> Bono </PERSON> told <PERSON> Kibbey </PERSON>, `` If anything happens to her, you're going to have to answer to me.'' The interruption prompted booing and shouts, and a walkout of 20 <PERSON> Bono </PERSON> supporters. `` I regret getting that upset, but it's almost like being handcuffed. I could n't get my explanation out,'' <PERSON> Bono </PERSON> told a news conference Friday. His wife, <PERSON> Mary </PERSON>, was admitted to hospital Wednesday with the flu and returned home Friday.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>MALIBU, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Sylvester </PERSON> <PERSON> Stallone </PERSON>, straddling his glistening <ORGANIZATION> Harley-Davidson </ORGANIZATION> motorcycle, has been thrilling coastal crowds near his home with frequent stops in beach parking lots to chat with youngsters. `` He enjoys intermingling with kids. He enjoys the camaraderie of it,'' <PERSON> Stallone </PERSON> publicist <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Bloch </PERSON> said Saturday. Last weekend, <PERSON> Stallone </PERSON> and seven biker buddies, including actor <PERSON> Ray </PERSON> <PERSON> Sharkey </PERSON>, pulled off <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Coast </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Highway </LOCATION> and into the parking lot at <LOCATION> Zuma </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION> for a half-hour chat with beachgoers. <PERSON> Stallone </PERSON>, who lives in <LOCATION> Malibu </LOCATION>, has owned the <PERSON> Harley </PERSON> chopper for seven years and rides the bike at least twice during the week and on weekends, <PERSON> Bloch </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880403-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-03-88 1037EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Jordan-PLO     04-03 0088</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Jordan-PLO,0091</SECOND>
<HEAD>Pro-Soviet Palestinian Leader Arrested by Jordan</HEAD>
<DATELINE>DAMASCUS, Syria (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Taysir </PERSON> <PERSON> al-Zibri </PERSON>, a member of the political bureau of the pro-Soviet <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION> for the Liberation of <LOCATION> Palestine </LOCATION> and of the <ORGANIZATION> Palestine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>, was arrested in <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION>, the front said Sunday. The announcement said <PERSON> Jordan </PERSON> gave no reason for <PERSON> al-Zibri </PERSON>'s arrest Tuesday night The front, led by <PERSON> Nayef </PERSON> <PERSON> Hawatmeh </PERSON>, is one of the Palestinian guerrilla groups included in the <ORGANIZATION> Palestine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> run by <PERSON> Yasser </PERSON> <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON>. The <ORGANIZATION> Palestine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> is the Palestinian parliament-in-exile.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880403-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-03-88 1037EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Obit-Milano     04-03 0191</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Obit-Milano,0200</SECOND>
<HEAD>Paolo Milano, Literary Critic, Dead at 84</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ROME (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Paolo </PERSON> <PERSON> Milano </PERSON>, a professor and prominent literary critic, has died after a long illness. He was 84. <PERSON> Milano </PERSON>, who died of Parkinson's disease Saturday in <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION>, was described by the city's daily <ORGANIZATION> La </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Repubblica </ORGANIZATION> on Sunday as `` one of the most cosmopolitan voices of Italian culture.'' Born in <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION> in 1904, Milano, a Jew, fled the Italian fascist regime in the late 1930s. After a brief period in <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION>, he settled in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> in 1940. He lived there for 15 years teaching comparative literature at <ORGANIZATION> Queens </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> and at the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Social </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION>. He edited `` The Portable Dante,'' published in 1947, and wrote `` <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> James </PERSON> _ The Voluntary Exile,'' which came out in 1948. He also contributed articles to such publications as Politics, the Partisan Review and The Nation. From 1957 to 1986, <ORGANIZATION> Milan </ORGANIZATION> worked in <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION> as literary critic of the Italian weekly magazine <PERSON> L'Espresso </PERSON>. His funeral was scheduled for Tuesday in the Jewish Cemetery of <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION>. Survivors are his wife, <PERSON> Rachel </PERSON>, of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>; a son <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON>, of <LOCATION> Scarsdale </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION>; and three grandchildren.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880403-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-03-88 1038EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Greece-Earthquakes     04-03 0290</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Greece-Earthquakes,0300</SECOND>
<HEAD>Three Earthquakes Near Athens, Another On Corfu</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ATHENS, Greece (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Three moderate earthquakes shook Athenians awake Saturday and Sunday while another strong temblor rocked the western resort island of <LOCATION> Corfu </LOCATION>. None of the quakes caused injuries or damage, authorities said. A spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> Athens </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Seismological </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> said a strong quake measuring 5.0 on the <PERSON> Richter </PERSON> scale occurred at 11:56 a.m. Sunday. Its epicenter was 212 miles northwest of <LOCATION> Athens </LOCATION> in the seabed off the island of <LOCATION> Corfu </LOCATION>. The popular resort island has about 2,000 mostly British tourists visiting over the Easter holiday, local police said. Three other quakes registering 4.2, 4.6 and 4.4 on the <PERSON> Richter </PERSON> scale rumbled through the Greek capital between 11 p.m. Saturday and 7 a.m. Sunday. `` The four quakes are not geologically connected, we rule out the chance of a disastrous quake coming from any of the areas ... so people should n't panic,'' Professor <PERSON> Yiannis </PERSON> <PERSON> Dracopoulos </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Greece </LOCATION>'s senior seismologist, told state-run television. The <LOCATION> Athens </LOCATION> region has 3.5 million residents, a third of <LOCATION> Greece </LOCATION>'s population The first two quakes had their epicenters 12.5 miles east of <LOCATION> Athens </LOCATION> in the seabed off the coastal town of <LOCATION> Loutsa </LOCATION>, while the third had its epicenter 47 miles northwest of the capital. An <LOCATION> Athens </LOCATION> police spokesman said the three quakes were felt throughout the capital, but did n't cause any injuries or damage. `` We had a lot of people calling in to find out what was happening but nobody panicked,'' said a police spokesman who requested anonymity. The Richter scale is a gauge of the energy released by an earthquake, as measured by the ground motion recorded on a seismograph. A magnitude 4 quake can cause moderate damage while a force 5 temblor can cause considerable damage.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880403-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-03-88 1045EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Israel-Easter Bjt   04-03 0700</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Israel-Easter, Bjt,0720</SECOND>
<HEAD>Under Guard, Pilgrims Gather For Dawn Services</HEAD>
<NOTE>With LaserPhoto</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By MASHA HAMILTON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>JERUSALEM (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Under police and army guard, pilgrims from around the world gathered at dawn for Easter Sunday services in the church marking the site where most Christians believe <PERSON> Jesus </PERSON> rose from the dead. About 1,000 worshipers _ half as many as last year _ attended services in the 12th century Church of the Holy Sepulcher, church officials said. Many pilgrims were scared away by four months of almost daily violence in the Israeli-occupied territories that have left more than 130 Palestinians and one Israeli soldier dead. The Greek Orthodox Church canceled three pre-Easter processions scheduled for the weekend. Security was low-key Sunday at the Crusader-built church, where about half a dozen uniformed police stood guard in the courtyard and at the entrance. But dozens of soldiers were stationed throughout the walled <LOCATION> Old </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, some on rooftops and others patrolling the narrow cobblestone streets. An Arab attacker stabbed an Israeli policeman in the <LOCATION> Old </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> on Friday. `` Before we came, our friends were worried and said they would pray for us,'' said 71-year-old <PERSON> Arnold </PERSON> <PERSON> Rosenbrock </PERSON>, a Lutheran from <LOCATION> Kankakee </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ill. </LOCATION> `` We've been fine, but someone was killed in <LOCATION> Bethlehem </LOCATION> yesterday -LRB- Saturday -RRB- a few hours before we visited,'' he added. `` There were boulders in the street, and it was tense.'' `` We were frightened before we came, but now that we are here, we feel it is safe,'' said <PERSON> Philip </PERSON> <PERSON> Jiamachello </PERSON>, 31, of <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, who attended the services with his wife and young son. `` For me, this was a very moving experience.'' Tourism ministry officials said they had no figures for the month of March, but acknowledged a 13 percent drop in tourism for the first week of the month as compared with a year ago. Officials also expressed concern about possible cancellations in April and May. Clouds of incense and organ music filled the church during the Latin service held in front of the marble-enclosed tomb marking the site where <PERSON> Jesus </PERSON> is believed to have been resurrected. The Roman Catholic patriarch of <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION>, Monsignor <PERSON> Michel </PERSON> <PERSON> Sabbah </PERSON>, the first Palestinian to hold the post, presided over the service. Last week, he called on worshipers to make special Easter prayers for those caught up in the <LOCATION> Arab-Israeli </LOCATION> conflict. At the church entrance, visiting pilgrims kissed and pressed their foreheads to the rose-colored marble stone where followers are believed to have washed <PERSON> Jesus </PERSON>' body before his burial. Several worshipers dropped handkerchiefs to soak up some of the holy water that dampens the stone. Others walked upstairs to the candle-lit table marking the site where <PERSON> Jesus </PERSON>' cross is believed to have been buried. `` One feels very humble walking on the same soil where <PERSON> Christ </PERSON> walked,'' said <PERSON> Gale </PERSON> <PERSON> Crisher </PERSON>, 48, of <LOCATION> Long </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION> `` My children could n't believe I was coming to <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> now, but I felt have very comfortable here.'' While the Roman Catholics were celebrating Easter, Orthodox denominations were marking their Palm Sunday, walking along the Via <LOCATION> Dolorosa </LOCATION>, or Way of Sorrow, where <PERSON> Jesus </PERSON>, wearing a crown of thorns, was forced to carry the cross on which he died. Orthodox Christians celebrate Easter this coming Sunday. In the midst of the <ORGANIZATION> Easter </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>, about two dozen chanting Coptic priests and choir boys in long dark robes entered the church carrying palm leaves, some formed in the shape of a cross. Easter also fell on the third day of the Jewish holiday of Passover, commemorating the deliverance of the ancient Hebrews from slavery in <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION>. Palestinian shopkeepers opened stores around the church from morning until noon, the times permitted by the <ORGANIZATION> Palestine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> has ordered afternoon strikes in <LOCATION> Arab </LOCATION> <LOCATION> east </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION> to protest the <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> occupation. But even merchants who remained open complained there was little business. `` I sold about $ 1,000 worth of items a day last year during Holy Week. This year, I'm lucky if it is $ 100,'' said <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Mannix </PERSON>, a Jerusalem-born Palestinian and owner of a shop selling olive-wood crosses and icons. `` Last Easter my store was filled to the doorway and people were crowded on the streets outside,'' the 32-year-old <PERSON> Mannix </PERSON> added. `` This year, there is no one.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880403-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-03-88 1051EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Libya-Gadhafi Bjt   04-03 0759</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Libya-Gadhafi, Bjt,0785</SECOND>
<HEAD>Two Years After U.S. Bombing, Gadhafi Permits Some Reform</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By FRANCES D'EMILIO</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>TRIPOLI, Libya (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Two years after a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> bombing raid shocked the nation, Libyans are breathing a bit easier. <PERSON> Moammar </PERSON> <PERSON> Gadhafi </PERSON>, their leader and the target of the attack, is permitting some long-awaited, though small steps to fix the economy. He is also calling for greater personal liberty. `` And it's true, right, that <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> ca n't become president again?'' asked a Libyan military man, confident that life is looking up for his countrymen. For the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> president, Col. <PERSON> Gadhafi </PERSON> was the `` mad dog of the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION>'' and a sponsor of terrorism, including 1985 attacks on airports in <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION>. To <PERSON> Gadhafi </PERSON>, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> was the `` Israeli dog'' in the `` black house,'' the villain behind the April 15, 1986, bombing, which Libyans say killed the colonel's baby daughter and 36 other people. The good-guy, bad-guy rhetoric drew attention from an economy badly needing direction, especially after falling oil prices flattened <LOCATION> Libya </LOCATION>'s plump cushion of petroleum income. The global theater also overshadowed the growing demands of Libyan consumers. Now <PERSON> Gadhafi </PERSON> seems bent on ensuring his popularity by improving life for his more than 3.5 million countrymen in the North African nation. Of course, motives are often difficult to judge in the case of the mercurial colonel who came to power in a 1969 coup and who is now simply called `` the leader'' by Libyans. Some observers think the 45-year-old <PERSON> Gadhafi </PERSON> may have decided to reform his virulent anti-Americanism, which sometimes made him an easy target of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> outrage. Others think <PERSON> Gadhafi </PERSON> may also have been affected by an <ORGANIZATION> Amnesty </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> appeal in July to end an alleged policy of assassinating opposition figures. While slogans denouncing purported American aggression are still plastered on buildings, one diplomat says that there has been a quiet exchange of messages between the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Libyan </LOCATION> governments indicating a desire, if not to improve relations, at least to keep channels open. There are several signs <PERSON> Gadhafi </PERSON> may also have decided to push for a more liberal economy. A <LOCATION> Tripoli </LOCATION> newspaper last month reported that small businesses are now permitted to import items, such as automobile parts, previously allowed only for government-franchise holders, and sell them at a profit. Diplomats were apparently told to improve distribution of consumer goods, and more private businesses were allowed to operate. Insisting repeatedly that Libyans must produce for themselves, <PERSON> Gadhafi </PERSON> has tried to reduce dependence on imports, especially after <LOCATION> Libya </LOCATION>'s oil revenues dropped dramatically from a 1980 peak of $ 22 billion. By 1986, lower oil prices saw annual revenue plummet to less than $ 6 billion. Prospects for slightly higher oil prices this year could put income at about $ 6.5 billion. On <LOCATION> Tripoli </LOCATION>'s shopping streets, business seems to have grown over the past year. Freshly slaughtered fat chickens hang from doorways enticing customers. Women _ some shrouded head-to-toe in white cotton, others in form-fitting, olive green military pants and jackets _ examine satin-striped fabric, while men try out imported calculators. It seems every other store window has cheap leather shoes, vinyl pocketbooks and suitcases. A diplomat reports that in the past year the government, which likes to boast of an extensive health care system, is allowing Libyans to buy Western currency and go abroad, ostensibly for medical treatment. One thing that has n't changed in <LOCATION> Libya </LOCATION>, though, is the ground rule of anonymity which covers conversations with diplomats, businessmen and the few Libyans willing to give their reading on what's happening. <PERSON> Gadhafi </PERSON> has been focusing as well on personal liberties. One afternoon last month, the masterful user of the media rode a bulldozer to knock down the gate of a <LOCATION> Tripoli </LOCATION> prison. To the cheers of one of the largest rallies in the capital in years, according to a diplomat, <PERSON> Gadhafi </PERSON> declared that the released inmates included some who had plotted to kill him. A week later, <PERSON> Gadhafi </PERSON> called for abolishing the death penalty in a nation where hangings have been broadcast on state television. On March 28, <PERSON> Gafhafi </PERSON> announced that all arrests should be backed by a court order. `` This is a very good thing,'' said a smiling Libyan, relaxing in a lounge a few hours after the speech. `` Now members of the Revolutionary Committees just come up and take people away without warning.'' The committees are <PERSON> Gadhafi </PERSON>'s watchdogs of revolutionary ideology. <PERSON> Gadhafi </PERSON> also announced he is withdrawing troops from eastern <LOCATION> Libya </LOCATION> as a goodwill gesture toward its eastern neighbor, <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION>, with which it has been feuding for 15 years.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880403-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-03-88 1054EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Philippines-Communists Bjt   04-03 0840</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Philippines-Communists, Bjt,0866</SECOND>
<HEAD>Arrests Seen As Setback But Movement Far From Crushed</HEAD>
<HEAD>AP News Analysis</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MIGUEL C. SUAREZ</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MANILA, Philippines (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Communist rebels suffered a major setback with the recent arrest of their top leaders, but military officials and analysts say the insurgents are far from beaten. Through their 19-year rebellion, the guerrillas have demonstrated remarkable resilience. Despite harsh crackdowns, their influence has spread from the countryside to urban centers, attacks have stepped up and captured leaders have been replaced immediately. President <PERSON> Corazon </PERSON> <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON>, who has vowed to crush the insurgency before her term expires in 1992, hailed last Tuesday's arrests of the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> commander and the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>'s No. 2 man as the beginning of the end. `` It clearly demonstrates that we have turned the tide and are winning the war against the Communist insurgency,'' she said in a statement. But military officials and others say the president may have spoken too soon, although they acknowledge that the arrests were a big blow to the 25,000-strong guerrilla army. `` It will disturb some of their programs,'' Brig. Gen. <PERSON> Rodolfo </PERSON> <PERSON> Biazon </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION> area commander, said of the arrests. `` But to say that this means the defeat of the Communist movement may not entirely be correct because we are fighting an idea, and the idea is still there.'' <PERSON> Francisco </PERSON> <PERSON> Tatad </PERSON>, a columnist and former information minister under ousted President <PERSON> Ferdinand </PERSON> <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON>, noted the insurgents not only survived but expanded after the capture of party founder <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Maria </PERSON> <PERSON> Sison </PERSON> and former rebel commander <PERSON> Bernabe </PERSON> <PERSON> Buscayno </PERSON> in the mid-1970s. <PERSON> Tatad </PERSON> said the rebels now enjoy broad support among workers, students, the clergy and other groups in society and that the government must improve its services `` to make the very idea of insurgency obsolete.'' Still, the arrests of rebel commander <PERSON> Romulo </PERSON> <PERSON> Kintanar </PERSON>, Secretary-General <PERSON> Rafael </PERSON> <PERSON> Baylosis </PERSON> and four other rebels marked a dramatic success for the government. They came as the military was on alert for rebel attacks marking last Tuesday's 19th anniversary of the rebel force. Instead it was the military which struck, raiding Communist hideouts in the capital. The arrest of <PERSON> Kintanar </PERSON>, 37, is especially significant. <PERSON> Kintanar </PERSON>, a master guerrilla strategist, was widely believed to have organized assassination squads known as `` Sparrow Units,'' which brought the guerrilla conflict from the countryside to the cities. Police say up to 4,000 Sparrows are deployed in metropolitan <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION>, where they have killed more than 150 police, soldiers and government officials since January 1987. Veteran journalist <PERSON> Max </PERSON> <PERSON> Soliven </PERSON> wrote in the Philippine Star that for the first time in years, the rebels are `` now sweating it out.'' But he warned against complacency. The rebels `` are so desperate at this juncture that they may unleash a series of furious attacks and ambushes, just to create the impression that the movement remains strong,'' <PERSON> Soliven </PERSON> wrote. Sen. <PERSON> Rene </PERSON> <PERSON> Saguisag </PERSON>, Mrs. <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON>'s former spokesman, agreed it was too early to say whether the arrests have dealt a fatal blow to the insurgency. <PERSON> Saguisag </PERSON> said one factor favoring the government is Mrs. <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON>'s continued popularity. Another, he said, was the ongoing attempt to hammer out a land reform act. He said since Mrs. <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON> took over from <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> on Feb. 25, 1986, she has introduced broad social and economic reforms. <PERSON> Saguisag </PERSON> acknowledged that substantial disaffection remains but `` it is nowhere like the disenchantment with <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON>, which was across the board.'' Even more than a debacle for the rebels, the arrests are seen as a morale booster for the underpaid, ill-equipped Armed Forces of the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION>. Since Mrs. <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON> took office when a military-civilian uprising deposed <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON>, the 160,000-member armed forces has been wracked by divisions that resulted in at least half a dozen coup attempts. <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Fidel </PERSON> <PERSON> V. </PERSON> <PERSON> Ramos </PERSON> says those days are over. He said the arrests show the military is now a united, effective force. <PERSON> Ramos </PERSON> spoke before the escape Saturday of former Lt. Col. <PERSON> Gregorio </PERSON> `` Gringo'' <PERSON> Honasan </PERSON>, leader of a failed coup attempt in August. Many Filipinos saw the escape as a blow to the prestige and unity of the armed forces. The significance of Tuesday's arrests may well depend on the accuracy of intelligence reports of a bitter power struggle within rebel ranks. According to military officials, the infighting is between those favoring violent struggle and others who want the movement to expand politically among the rural population. Brig. Gen. <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON> <PERSON> Aguirre </PERSON>, the capital's chief law enforcer, predicted that Tuesday's arrests will deepen divisions among the rebels because each faction will blame the other for the setback. Much also depends on how much foreign assistance flows to the rebels. Military officials say the funds come from leftist groups in <LOCATION> Western </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Zealand </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Armitage </PERSON>, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> assistant defense secretary, told a <ORGANIZATION> congressional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> committee </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> this week that the Soviets were sending money. Soviet diplomats here deny the charge.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Miguel </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Suarez </PERSON> is <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION> news editor for <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> and has been reporting on events in the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION> since 1970.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880403-0025 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-03-88 1059EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Panama-Noriega Bjt   04-03 0851</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Panama-Noriega, Bjt,0873</SECOND>
<HEAD>Options Limited For Noriega, Opponents</HEAD>
<HEAD>AP News Analysis</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By REID G. MILLER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PANAMA CITY, Panama (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Gen. <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>, the indicted strongman of <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>, may be running out of time and options in his stubborn quest to remain in power. The man President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> once called a `` tin-horn dictator'' so far has relied on brute force, threats and intimidation to maintain his grip on the nation. But despite another harsh crackdown on his opposition last week, many diplomatic and other observers feel <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> can count his remaining days on his fingers and toes. `` He really does n't have anywhere to turn,'' said one Western diplomat late last week. `` He is almost totally without meaningful support, either within the country or abroad.'' Still, <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> has withstood four weeks of mounting economic pressure with such mulish defiance that another foreign diplomat, also speaking on condition of anonymity, was led to comment: `` This guy's proving to be harder to get rid of than fleas on a dog. The problem is becoming one of whether you have to kill the dog before the fleas will leave.'' Even <PERSON> Elliott </PERSON> <PERSON> Abrams </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> official masterminding the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> effort to oust <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>, acknowledged last week that he and others in the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration had misjudged the general's staying power <PERSON> Abrams </PERSON>, the assistant secretary of state for <LOCATION> Latin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> affairs, said the miscalculation was based in part on the successful use of economic pressure to remove presidents <PERSON> Ferdinand </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> from the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Jean-Claude </PERSON> <PERSON> Duvalier </PERSON> from <LOCATION> Haiti </LOCATION>. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has cut off all economic and military aid to <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>, withheld about $ 6.5 million a month in user fees from the <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Canal </LOCATION>, helped tie up more than $ 50 million in government funds on deposit in <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> banks and eliminated some trade preferences. <PERSON> Abrams </PERSON> suggested the time had come to consider even harsher economic sanctions, up to a total trade embargo. That's a bridge the administration so far has been unwilling to cross for fear of so badly damaging the country that a post-Noriega government would be unable to pick up the pieces. `` We now realize that it is easier to remove civilian dictators than military ones,'' <PERSON> Abrams </PERSON> said. `` In analogous circumstances, <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> and <PERSON> Duvalier </PERSON> were gone already.'' Some foreign diplomats in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> do n't see the situation here as analogous to the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Haiti </LOCATION>, regardless of any possible differences between civilian and military dictators. `` In the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION>, you had a <PERSON> Cory </PERSON> <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON>, who provided a rallying point,'' said one, referring to <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION> President <PERSON> Corazon </PERSON> <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON>. `` There's nobody like that here. There also are n't many people here who appear willing to risk their lives in the struggle In the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Haiti </LOCATION> we saw desperate people acting desperately.'' The diplomats and two private economists, all of whom spoke on condition of anonymity, agreed there is little chance of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military intervention, despite <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s decision late last week to send an additional 1,300 soldiers to <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> to help the 10,500 already here guard the <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Canal </LOCATION> and protect American civilians. Indeed, only a day before <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> announced his decision to send the new troops, the <LOCATION> Panamanian </LOCATION> government issued a communique saying it had no intention of provking an excuse for <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military action. The diplomats and economists also agreed unanimously that <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>'s days are numbered by a rapidly souring economy that already has the general trapped in a fiscal maze with no outlet. <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> went bankrupt last year, unable to make interest payments to any of the lenders to whom it owes $ 4.8 billion, one of the highest per capita debts in the world. Then, early this year, <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> was indicted by two federal grand juries in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> that accused him of selling out his country to <LOCATION> Colombian </LOCATION> drug traffickers in exchange for millions of dollars in bribes. After some weeks of apparent soul searching, <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s president, <PERSON> Eric </PERSON> <PERSON> Arturo </PERSON> <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON>, called for <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>'s dismissal, only to have the effort backfire with his own ouster in a thinly disguised coup orchestrated by the general. Three weeks ago, <PERSON> Abrams </PERSON>' chief deputy, <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Walker </PERSON>, and a <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> legal officer came to <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> and offered <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> a deal: Accept offered asylum in <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> will not pursue you. The general refused. <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON>'s ouster triggered a run on banks that forced their closure. The government, short of cash, could not pay its employees. Some disgruntled officers tried but failed to overthrow <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>. And his civilian opposition heaped coals on the fire with a two-week general strike that began to crumble only late last week. Even with the anticipated reopening of most industries and businesses this week, the government and its people are so short of money and so unlikely to get a big cash infusion that there is no hope of a return to `` normalcy'' anytime soon. `` What we're seeing here is a revolution in slow motion,'' said one diplomat. `` It may be taking longer than anyone expected, but it's happening.''
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Reid </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Miller </PERSON> has been covering <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> from <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jose </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Costa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rica </LOCATION>, since January 1984.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880403-0026 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-03-88 1101EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-CatBurglar     04-03 0553</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Cat Burglar,0569</SECOND>
<HEAD>Failed Stakeout Of I-75 Cat Burglar Results In Probation For
Officers</HEAD>
<DATELINE>GAINESVILLE, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Police patiently watched a stolen motorcycle for 17 days, 24 hours a day, in hopes of catching a burglar linked to nearly 200 break-ins, until one officer took a two-minute restroom break and the bike disappeared. Two <LOCATION> Alachua </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> sheriff's investigators involved in the failed surveillance were placed on six months of probation. The so-called Interstate 75 cat burglar, a cocky thief who police believe has occasionally helped himself to a snack while his victims slept soundly, has been linked to more than 180 break-ins in seven <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> counties along I-75. He remains at large. <LOCATION> Alachua </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> investigators had their best shot at catching him in January, when a motorcycle stolen in <LOCATION> Citrus </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> during one of the cat burglar's sprees was found at a <LOCATION> Gainesville </LOCATION> apartment complex, the <LOCATION> Gainesville </LOCATION> Sun reported Saturday. Teams of officers kept watch over the motorcycle from a motor home 125 yards away to see if the burglar would return to use it. But Sgt. <PERSON> William </PERSON> `` Bear'' <PERSON> Bryan </PERSON> and Investigator <PERSON> Tony </PERSON> <PERSON> Canchola </PERSON> said Friday that a combination of incredible luck on the burglar's part and a poor line of sight from their vantage point combined to doom the surveillance The $ 2,000 motorcycle was discovered parked at the apartment complex on Jan. 9. One resident remembered seeing a man drive away on it on the same day the cat burglar struck a <LOCATION> Gainesville </LOCATION> neighborhood, and it was later returned to the complex. <PERSON> Bryan </PERSON> and <PERSON> Canchola </PERSON> said the discovery of the motorcycle was the only real break in the I-75 cat burglar cases, which have frustrated authorities since November. So two deputies at a time kept vigil, with the aid of a television camera and night-vision scope. <PERSON> Bryan </PERSON> and <PERSON> Canchola </PERSON> even took the precaution of disabling the motorcycle's engine so it could n't be started. On Jan. 16, <PERSON> Canchola </PERSON> was watching the TV monitor while <PERSON> Bryan </PERSON> sat in the back of the motor home repairing other surveillance equipment, they said Friday. <PERSON> Canchola </PERSON> saw no one near the motorcycle, so he went to the bathroom for about two minutes. By the time both men got back to the monitor, the motorcycle was gone. `` We were so shocked that we were laughing,'' <PERSON> Canchola </PERSON> said. `` We thought somebody had moved the motorcycle and was playing a joke on us.'' Interviews with witnesses later revealed the cat burglar had snatched the motorcycle in a matter of seconds. The suspect drove up in a small pickup truck and parked just out of the investigators' line of sight. Then, without trying to start the disabled motorcycle, he wheeled it to his truck and lifted it in the back. The cat burglar did not hit <LOCATION> Gainesville </LOCATION> that night, when law-enforcement agencies were at full alert. The motorcycle was later found abandoned in <LOCATION> Port </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orange </LOCATION>, south of <LOCATION> Daytona </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Alachua </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> sheriff's spokesman <PERSON> Spencer </PERSON> <PERSON> Mann </PERSON> said that city had several night burglaries at that time, but they have not been positively linked to the I-75 cat burglar. <PERSON> Canchola </PERSON> and <PERSON> Bryan </PERSON> wound up on probation and said Friday they still feel bad about losing their best chance at collaring the burglar. `` If we'd have caught him, we'd have been heroes,'' <PERSON> Bryan </PERSON> said. Instead, `` we just got burned this time,'' <PERSON> Canchola </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880403-0027 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-03-88 1103EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w AM-US-Lebanon-Drugs Bjt   04-03 0881</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-US-Lebanon-Drugs, Bjt,900</SECOND>
<HEAD>Lebanon Reportedly Becomes Big Heroin Center</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOAN MOWER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
