<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880510-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-10-88 2324EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p BC-PP-Dem-Pres-All     05-10 0128</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-PP-Dem-Pres-All,400</SECOND>
<HEAD>05-10-88 23:18</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the latest, unofficial results in the Democratic presidential primaries on Tuesday.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>NEBRASKA</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 1,327 of 1,870 precincts reporting - 71 percent <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, 65,682 - 64 percent <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, 25,736 - 25 percent Uncommitted, 2,868 - 3 percent <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON>, 3,000 - 3 percent <PERSON> Gore </PERSON>, 1,582 - 2 percent <PERSON> Hart </PERSON>, 2,410 - 2 percent <PERSON> LaRouche </PERSON>, 273 - 0 percent <PERSON> Simon </PERSON>, 1,269 - 1 percent
</TEXT>
<HEAD>WEST VIRGINIA</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 666 of 2,151 precincts reporting - 31 percent <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, 67,722 - 79 percent <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, 12,041 - 14 percent <ORGANIZATION> Duke </ORGANIZATION>, 405 - 0 percent <PERSON> Dennerll </PERSON>, 478 - 1 percent <PERSON> Gore </PERSON>, 3,058 - 4 percent <PERSON> LaRouche </PERSON>, 433 - 1 percent <ORGANIZATION> McDonald </ORGANIZATION>, 1,012 - 1 percent <PERSON> Simon </PERSON>, 675 - 1 percent <PERSON> Traficant </PERSON>, 281 - 0 percent
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880510-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-10-88 2324EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p BC-PP-GOP-Pres-All     05-10 0078</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-PP-GOP-Pres-All,400</SECOND>
<HEAD>05-10-88 23:18</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the latest, unofficial results in the Republican presidential primaries on Tuesday.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>NEBRASKA</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 1,322 of 1,870 precincts reporting - 71 percent <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, 78,047 - 72 percent <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON>, 5,494 - 5 percent <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>, 24,871 - 23 percent
</TEXT>
<HEAD>WEST VIRGINIA</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 664 of 2,151 precincts reporting - 31 percent <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, 28,194 - 89 percent <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON>, 2,690 - 9 percent <PERSON> Conley </PERSON>, 258 - 1 percent <PERSON> Stassen </PERSON>, 446 - 1 percent
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880510-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-10-88 2324EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p BC-PP-GOP-Deleg-All     05-10 0071</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-PP-GOP-Deleg-All,400</SECOND>
<HEAD>05-10-88 23:19</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the latest, unofficial results in the Republican presidential primaries and caucuses on Tuesday.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>NEBRASKA</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 44 percent of precincts reporting <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, 6 <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON>, 0 Uncommitted, 2 <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>, 1 <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON>, 0 Total - 9
</TEXT>
<HEAD>WEST VIRGINIA</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 3 percent of precincts reporting <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, 23 <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON>, 0 Uncommitted, 3 <ORGANIZATION> Conley </ORGANIZATION>, 0 <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>, 2 <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON>, 0 <PERSON> Stassen </PERSON>, 0 Total - 28
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880510-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-10-88 2328EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>b p AM-NebraskaPrimary 3rdLd a0880 05-10 0123</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Nebraska Primary, 3rd Ld, a0880,0124</SECOND>
<HEAD>URGENT</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Karnes wins</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By ED HOWARD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>OMAHA, Neb. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Sen. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Karnes </PERSON>, appointed to office 14 months ago, won the <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> nomination for a full term Tuesday, beating back a fierce primary challenge from Rep. <PERSON> Hal </PERSON> <PERSON> Daub </PERSON>. <PERSON> Karnes </PERSON>, at 39 the nation's youngest senator, will face another tough fight in November against popular former Gov. <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Kerrey </PERSON>, who easily won the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> nomination. <PERSON> Daub </PERSON>, 47, had represented the <LOCATION> Omaha </LOCATION> area in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> for eight years, but gave up his seat to challenge <PERSON> Karnes </PERSON>. With 68 percent of the vote counted, <PERSON> Karnes </PERSON> had 60,828 votes or 54.2 percent and <PERSON> Daub </PERSON> had 51,400 votes or 45.8 percent.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>The popular: 4th pvs</HEAD>
<TEXT>

</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880510-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-10-88 2335EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p AM-StatePrimariesRdp 6thLd a0871 05-10 0327</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-State Primaries Rdp, 6th Ld, a0871,0331</SECOND>
<HEAD>URGENT</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Karnes wins, Moore holding to leads, later figures</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By MIKE SILVERMAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION> Sen. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Karnes </PERSON> won a bitter Republican primary battle Tuesday against Rep. <PERSON> Hal </PERSON> <PERSON> Daub </PERSON>, while <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> Gov. Arch <PERSON> Moore </PERSON> held a small but steady lead over a millionaire businessman as he sought the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> nomination for a record fourth term. In <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION>'s Democratic primary for <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>, popular ex-Gov. <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Kerrey </PERSON> crushed a little-known opponent, while <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Majority Leader <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON> easily captured <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> nomination for a sixth term. With 67 percent of the <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION> vote reporting, <PERSON> Karnes </PERSON>, who was appointed to office 14 months ago, had 57,500 votes or 53.2 percent, and <PERSON> Daub </PERSON>, who served four terms in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, had 50,643 votes or 46.8 percent. On the Democratic side, <PERSON> Kerrey </PERSON> had 50,200 votes or 91.3 percent and <PERSON> Ken </PERSON> <PERSON> Michaelis </PERSON>, a disbarred lawyer, had 4,806 votes or 8.7 percent. In <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>, with 36 percent of the vote in, <PERSON> Moore </PERSON>, seeking a record fourth term, had 22,919 votes or 52.3 percent and <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Raese </PERSON>, who accused the incumbent of failing to deal with <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>'s financial problems, had 20,877 votes or 47.7 percent. In the race for the Democratic gubernatorial nomination, insurance executive <PERSON> Gaston </PERSON> <PERSON> Caperton </PERSON> was far ahead of former <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Delegates </ORGANIZATION> Speaker Clyde See and five other candidates. <PERSON> Caperton </PERSON> had 13,984 votes or 39.4 percent and See had 10,092 votes or 28.4 percent. The 71-year-old <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON> was piling up 27,801 votes or 81.9 percent, while moving company owner <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Myers </PERSON> had 6,158 votes or 18.1 percent. The <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> primary was won by state Sen. <PERSON> Jay </PERSON> <PERSON> Wolfe </PERSON>, who had 7,197 votes or 68.2 percent. Welfare recipient <PERSON> Bernie </PERSON> <PERSON> Lumbert </PERSON> had 3,351 votes or 31.8 percent. <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION>'s GOP <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> race proved a divisive campaign with <PERSON> Daub </PERSON> on the attack as <PERSON> Karnes </PERSON>, the nation's youngest senator at 39, made his first bid for elective office.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>Karnes was: pickup at dash</HEAD>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880510-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-10-88 0145EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-StarWars     05-10 0729</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Star Wars,0750</SECOND>
<HEAD>Peace Workers Take Aim At SDI Through Town Meetings</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By CAROLYN LUMSDEN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SPRINGFIELD, Mass. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Activists in the western <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> towns where the nuclear freeze movement was born are attacking `` Star Wars'' with the tactic they used so well eight years ago: town meetings. So far, residents of 13 communities have voted to order their town clerks to notify President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> of their displeasure with the satellite-based missile-killing system also known as the Strategic Defense Initiative. The anti-SDI article failed in two other towns and was tabled in a third, but activists said Monday they were heartened by the results thus far. Fifteen to 20 towns are expected to debate the question in May and June. `` <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Einstein </PERSON> said nuclear technology should be discussed on the village square,'' said <PERSON> Frances </PERSON> <PERSON> Crowe </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Friends </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Northampton </ORGANIZATION>, who is helping to organize the drive against SDI. `` These town meetings are really the most democratic way of letting the people discuss and decide about nuclear issues,'' said <PERSON> Crowe </PERSON>. She and others in the Coalition to <ORGANIZATION> Stop </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Star </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wars </ORGANIZATION>, a group of 35 area activists, hope to use the town meeting votes to get an anti-SDI question on the statewide referendum in November. In western Massachachusetts, where Democrats outnumber Republicans by better than 3-1, towns have never been shy about their opinions on global matters. The nuclear freeze movement began on the floors of town meetings in western <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> in the spring of 1980. It spread to the ballot box that fall, when voters in the four westernmost counties instructed their state senators to favor a resolution asking the president to propose a mutual nuclear weapons moratorium to the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. In 1983, the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Representatives </ORGANIZATION> passed a freeze resolution by a 2-1 margin. Anti-war activists have since turned to the town meetings, a 350-year-old institution, to tell the president their thoughts on such matters as nuclear test ban treaties. Anti-war sentiment runs deep in towns such as <LOCATION> Amherst </LOCATION>, where residents have voted in town meetings against hostilities involving <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> forces since the War of 1812. To get a question on a town meeting warrant, a resident need only collect 10 signatures on a petition. The Coalition to Stop Star Wars went town to town to find sponsors for anti-SDI articles, and held seminars explaining SDI's cost to each community. The 1,502 residents of <LOCATION> Ashfield </LOCATION>, for example, unwittingly contributed an estimated $ 24,990 to `` Star Wars'' in fiscal 1988, said <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Holroyde </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Traprock </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Peace </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Deerfield </LOCATION>, a non-profit, privately funded group. Since the SDI research project began in 1983, he said, <LOCATION> Ashfield </LOCATION> has contributed $ 91,000. Voters at <LOCATION> Ashfield </LOCATION>'s town meeting approved the anti-SDI article in a voice vote. `` For people who have to fight hard to pay for schools and police and fire departments, it puts the whole thing into perspective,'' said Dr. <PERSON> Ira </PERSON> <PERSON> Helfand </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Northampton </LOCATION>, a member of the national board of directors of Physicians for Social Responsibility. However, some of that money comes back. The <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Massachusetts </ORGANIZATION>, whose main campus is in <LOCATION> Amherst </LOCATION>, was the 20th-largest SDI contractor in the nation, according to `` Star Wars: The Economic Fallout,'' by the New York-based Council on Economic Priorities. The book said that that in fiscal 1985 and 1986, the university received $ 1.24 million in SDI contracts. The SDI issue has sparked much heated discussions in town meetings, but rarely have voters questioned why the matter is before them, <PERSON> Holroyde </PERSON> said. `` What we are talking here about is programs we are paying for,'' he said. Only Whately voters rejected the resolution as an inappropriate topic for their town meeting in a 35-28 vote, <PERSON> Holroyde </PERSON> said. At the <LOCATION> Whatley </LOCATION> meeting, resident <PERSON> Kenneth </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Daniels </PERSON> questioned the arguments of SDI critics. `` You're criticizing the government,'' he told them. `` To me it sounds like propaganda.'' Besides <LOCATION> Ashfield </LOCATION>, the articles were approved by voice vote in the <LOCATION> Franklin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> towns of <PERSON> Conway </PERSON> and <LOCATION> Shelburne </LOCATION> and were denied by voice vote in <LOCATION> Northfield </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Franklin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> voters approved the articles by ballot, hand vote and lineups in <LOCATION> Colrain </LOCATION>, 56-50; <PERSON> Heath </PERSON>, 42-13; <PERSON> Leverett </PERSON> 59-4; <LOCATION> Shutesbury </LOCATION>, 42-4; and <PERSON> Wendell </PERSON> 96-35. In <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, the articles passed on voice votes in <LOCATION> Cummington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Huntington </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Pelham </LOCATION>. In <LOCATION> Berkshire </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, the articles passed in <LOCATION> Monterey </LOCATION>, 48-16, and by voice vote in <LOCATION> Windsor </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880510-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-10-88 0147EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-StressDisorder     05-10 0626</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Stress Disorder,0646</SECOND>
<HEAD>New Stress Makes Stress-Disorder Patients Less Sensitive To Pain</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By MALCOLM RITTER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Science Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MONTREAL (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> veterans with post-traumatic stress disorder were less sensitive to pain after seeing scenes from a war movie, according to a study which gives a glimpse into the complex biology of the disorder. The finding may also be a step toward new treatments, scientists said. `` This may well be getting at some basic core biological aspect of PTSD,'' said <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> Pitman </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Veterans </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Manchester </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.H. </LOCATION> <PERSON> Pitman </PERSON> and colleague <PERSON> Scott </PERSON> <PERSON> Orr </PERSON> did the work with <PERSON> Bessel </PERSON> <PERSON> van </PERSON> <PERSON> der </PERSON> <PERSON> Kolk </PERSON> and <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Greenberg </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Pitman </PERSON> was interviewed before speaking Monday at the annual meeting of the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Psychiatric </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>. Post-traumatic stress disorder is estimated to affect hundreds of thousands of people who have survived battle, airplane crashes, earthquakes and other extreme stresses. Often appearing several months or years after the event, the disorder causes sudden memories of the event that can be so vivid that the person thinks he is going through it again. Powerful nightmares, onslaughts of emotions that appear to have no cause, and avoidance of close relationships can also appear. The condition is treated with psychotherapy, and some drugs appear to help. Researchers hope that by understanding biological underpinnings of the disorder they can find more effective medications. Animals exposed to extreme stress, such as inescapable electric shocks, typically lose sensitivity to pain, <PERSON> Pitman </PERSON> said, because their bodies release natural painkillers called endorphins. When animals are given a substance called naloxone that blocks the action of endorphins, sensitivity to pain returns to normal, he said. The same phenomenon has been reported in humans exposed to electric shocks, he said. The new work involved eight <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> veterans with the disorder and eight combat veterans who did not develop the condition. Researchers applied heat to their forearms and asked them to rank the intensity of the pain on a scale of 1 to 100. The experiment was done at several temperatures and the ratings were averaged. The veterans' pain sensitivity was measured before and after they watched 15 minutes of an ambush scene from the <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> movie `` Platoon.'' The experiment was done twice. One time the veterans received the endorphin-blocking substance naloxone, and the other time a placebo. Neither the veterans nor the researchers knew which was being administered at the time. Six of the eight veterans with the disorder showed a decrease in pain sensitivity after viewing the ambush scene and getting the placebo. The decrease averaged about 30 percent. Naloxone prevented the decrease in sensitivity, showing it was due to endorphins, <PERSON> Pitman </PERSON> said. Even with the placebo, no change in pain sensitivity appeared in seven of the eight other veterans. <PERSON> Pitman </PERSON> said he doubts the endorphins themselves cause symptoms of the disorder, but that their appearance in response to the movie reflects a learned response caused by the severe stress of the original combat experience. The finding is new evidence that the disorder `` does indeed have a complex and unique biological basis,'' said <PERSON> Matthew </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Friedman </PERSON>, professor of psychiatry and pharmacology at <ORGANIZATION> Dartmouth </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> and chief of the psychiatry service at the <ORGANIZATION> Veterans </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> White </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Junction </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Vt </LOCATION>. It supports the theory that the disorder is associated with biological alterations in the brain's endorphin system, affecting the brain's emotion and arousal centers, he said. In another study reported Monday, researchers found that nine post-traumatic stress disorder patients tended to have a different hormone profile from that of seven depression patients. Scientists at the <ORGANIZATION> Yale </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medicine </ORGANIZATION> found the difference by studying each patient's levels of cortisol, epinephrine, growth hormone, norepinephrin, testosterone and thyroxin.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880510-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-10-88 0137EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-CapitolHillRapist     05-10 0294</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Capitol Hill Rapist,0301</SECOND>
<HEAD>Jury Convicts Man In Capitol Hill Rape Cases</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DEBBIE NEWBY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>DENVER (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A jury Monday convicted a man accused of being <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Capitol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION> rapist of 14 counts in connection with assaults on six women. The seven-woman, five-man jury convicted <PERSON> Quintin </PERSON> <PERSON> Wortham </PERSON>, 27, of five counts of rape, one count of attempted rape, six burglary counts and two counts of theft. District Judge <PERSON> Lynne </PERSON> <PERSON> Hufnagel </PERSON> set sentencing for Friday. <PERSON> Wortham </PERSON> could be sentenced to a maximum of 350 years. <PERSON> Wortham </PERSON>, who acted as his own attorney throughout the trial, his second, was charged with five rapes and one attempted rape in <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Capitol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION> neighborhood in 1985 and 1986. His first trial ended in a mistrial because of his behavior while acting as his own counsel. District Attorney Norm Early said, `` The jury saw that justice was done. It was a very swift verdict.'' <PERSON> Wortham </PERSON>, who took more than two hours during closing arguments on Friday trying to convince the jury of his innocence, showed no emotion as the verdicts were read Monday. <PERSON> Wortham </PERSON> had claimed the victims misidentified him. One woman who testified against <PERSON> Wortham </PERSON> in both trials told reporters following the verdict it had been difficult to look him in the face. `` I did n't do it often; but when I was called on, it reaffirmed my conviction he was the man.'' <PERSON> Hufnagel </PERSON> disallowed results of a new DNA test that prosecutors say proved that <PERSON> Wortham </PERSON> raped a woman in 1985. The judge said admission of the scientific evidence would not be fair to <PERSON> Wortham </PERSON> and could result in a reversal of a conviction. <PERSON> Hufnagel </PERSON> said no appeals court had yet approved DNA testing and only five states, not including <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION>, accept it.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880510-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-10-88 0137EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w AM-US-China-Trade 1stLd-Writethru a0763 05-10 0554</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-US-China-Trade, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0763,510</SECOND>
<HEAD>Verity Calls on China to End Protectionist Measures</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDs: INSERTS 1 graf after 2nd graf pvs and 2 grafs after 9th graf
pvs bgng, `A policy,' to UPDATE with Tian comments</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By GENE KRAMER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Commerce Secretary <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Verity </PERSON> urged a high-level <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> delegation Monday to end protectionist measures that have forced some <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> companies `` to question the wisdom of pursuing business in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>.'' <ORGANIZATION> Verity </ORGANIZATION> made his comments as he greeted Chinese Vice Premier <PERSON> Tian </PERSON> <PERSON> Jiyun </PERSON> at the start of the sixth meeting of the two governments' joint commission on commerce and trade <PERSON> Tian </PERSON> said <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> is `` unswervingly pursuing the policy of reform and opening to the outside world,'' as part of its program `` to build a socialist political system with a high degree of democracy ... a system that it is effective and full of vitality.'' During the day, Vice President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> hosted <PERSON> Tian </PERSON> at a dinner at <ORGANIZATION> Blair </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, the restored <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> official guest quarters. The vice premier was scheduled to meet President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> on Tuesday. <ORGANIZATION> Verity </ORGANIZATION> told the <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> delegation that the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> is making progress in reducing trade deficits and asserted that `` the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has recovered from the shock of a wave of imports that swept the country ...'' <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, meanwhile, over the past year has overcome challenges to its economic reforms and reaffirmed its commitment to reform, <ORGANIZATION> Verity </ORGANIZATION> said. However, he noted, <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> at the same time has expanded import controls and raised tariffs. In the past two years, he said, <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> has restored some confidence in the climate for joint ventures with foreign firms, but still, `` high cost and uncertainty of doing business ... are forcing some -LRB- <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> -RRB- companies to question the wisdom of pursuing business in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>.'' <ORGANIZATION> Verity </ORGANIZATION> said <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s recently announced first-stage foreign trade reform is a major step in promoting competition, but he complained that `` trade restrictions appear to have increased ... a significant number of new import barriers have appeared ...'' `` A policy which stresses exports while heavily protecting the domestic market will also lead to increase friction in the bilateral trade relationship'' between <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, he added. Tian, in a speech released by the <ORGANIZATION> Chinese </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION>, said <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> industries should recognize that there is `` fierce competition'' to sell to <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, and that he hopes they will become more competitive by improving quality, technical features and terms of trade. He called for `` eventual removal of all undue restrictions'' on selling <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> high-technology products to <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, and urged the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> not to impose any new controls against import of Chinese textiles, his country's major export. <ORGANIZATION> Verity </ORGANIZATION> said the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> would work with <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> to smooth its entry into <ORGANIZATION> GATT </ORGANIZATION>, the General Agreement on Tariffs and Trade, on terms that would bolster <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>'s efforts to promote open market conditions and competitiveness. The secretary also said the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> would continue to expand transfer of high technology in its <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> trade. A basic objective of the three-day commission meeting was to increase that trade, which last year reached a $ 10.4 billion total in both directions. <ORGANIZATION> Verity </ORGANIZATION> indicated the session would air measures to improve the business environment for <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> firms trading with <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> in such areas as patent and copyright protection, contract and dispute procedures and profitability.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880510-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-10-88 2357EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p BC-PP-GOP-Pres-All     05-10 0078</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-PP-GOP-Pres-All,400</SECOND>
<HEAD>05-10-88 23:50</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the latest, unofficial results in the Republican presidential primaries on Tuesday.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>NEBRASKA</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 1,490 of 1,870 precincts reporting - 80 percent <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, 95,154 - 72 percent <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON>, 6,784 - 5 percent <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>, 30,565 - 23 percent
</TEXT>
<HEAD>WEST VIRGINIA</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 854 of 2,151 precincts reporting - 40 percent <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, 36,731 - 89 percent <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON>, 3,596 - 9 percent <PERSON> Conley </PERSON>, 336 - 1 percent <PERSON> Stassen </PERSON>, 609 - 1 percent
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880510-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-10-88 2358EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p BC-PP-Dem-Deleg-All     05-10 0085</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-PP-Dem-Deleg-All,400</SECOND>
<HEAD>05-10-88 23:50</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the latest, unofficial results in the Democratic presidential primaries and caucuses on Tuesday.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>NEBRASKA</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 79 percent of precincts reporting <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, 18 <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, 7 Uncommitted, 0 <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON>, 0 <PERSON> Gore </PERSON>, 0 <PERSON> Hart </PERSON>, 0 <PERSON> LaRouche </PERSON>, 0 <PERSON> Simon </PERSON>, 0 Total - 25
</TEXT>
<HEAD>WEST VIRGINIA</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 9 percent of precincts reporting <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, 36 <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, 0 <ORGANIZATION> Byrd </ORGANIZATION>, 0 Uncommitted, 1 <PERSON> Babbitt </PERSON>, 0 <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON>, 0 <PERSON> Gore </PERSON>, 0 <PERSON> Hart </PERSON>, 0 <PERSON> LaRouche </PERSON>, 0 <PERSON> Simon </PERSON>, 0 <ORGANIZATION> Traficant </ORGANIZATION>, 0 Total - 37
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880510-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-10-88 2358EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p AM-ExitPolls     05-10 0533</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Exit Polls,500</SECOND>
<HEAD>Dukakis Scores Well With Reagan Democrats in Nebraska, West
Virginia</HEAD>
<HEAD>With AM-Primaries Rdp</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GARY LANGER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> showed strength among <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> Democrats in the <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> presidential primaries Tuesday, a good sign for him in November should he win the Democratic nomination. Nearly a quarter of the Democrats voting said they backed President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> in 1984, but about three-quarters of them said this year they would support <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> over <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, an <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> exit poll found. `` <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> could bring home the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> <PERSON> Democrats </PERSON>,'' said <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> poll analyst <PERSON> Doug </PERSON> <PERSON> Muzzio </PERSON>. He noted that the finding has been consistent since <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> started asking the question in its <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION> exit poll March 29. The <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> poll Tuesday said <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> scored one of his best showings of the primary season with white voters in <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION>, winning 24 percent of the white vote. He did better only in <LOCATION> Vermont </LOCATION>, where he won 32 percent in an <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> poll. Still, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> won all white subgroups in <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION> and won overwhelming majorities of voters of all groups other than blacks in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Muzzio </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> even made some inroads into the small black vote, winning 32 percent of the black vote in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> and 11 percent in <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION>. Blacks made up 4 percent of the total in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> and 5 percent in <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION>, and the margin of sampling error is high for such a small group in a poll. Among all voters, the error margin was 5 points in the surveys. As in other recent contests, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> appeared acceptable to voters across the spectrum of political ideologies in his party, <PERSON> Muzzio </PERSON> said. A majority of liberals, a majority of moderates and a plurality of conservatives said his views were `` just right'' as opposed to too liberal or too conservative. `` In a sense, ideologically <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> is a Rorschach test,'' <PERSON> Muzzio </PERSON> said. `` Voters of different ideologies look at <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> and are seeing what they want to see. In a sense he's all ideologies to all voters.'' Still, <PERSON> Muzzio </PERSON> noted that a sizeable share of voters _ about 30 percent _ said they did not know enough about <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' ideological stand to answer the question on ideology. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, who appealed to distressed farmers in <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION> for their votes, ran somewhat more competitively there than in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>. About a quarter of the voters said the poor and elderly were a key issue to them, and <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> won that group, 52 percent to 44 percent for <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>. Another quarter said an ability to bring changes was key, and <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> won them 50 to 42, <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> said. The key issue to the most voters in both states was job protection, and <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> won a majority of that group. Most significant for the fall, <PERSON> Muzzio </PERSON> suggested, was <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' support from <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> Democrats In <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>, 23 percent of the primary voters told <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> they backed <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> in 1984, and 73 percent of them said they would vote for <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> over <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. In <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION>, 22 percent of the total said they voted for <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> in 1984, and 78 percent said they would take <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> over <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880510-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-10-88 2359EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p BC-PP-GOP-Deleg-All     05-10 0071</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-PP-GOP-Deleg-All,400</SECOND>
<HEAD>05-10-88 23:51</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the latest, unofficial results in the Republican presidential primaries and caucuses on Tuesday.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>NEBRASKA</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 52 percent of precincts reporting <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, 6 <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON>, 0 Uncommitted, 2 <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>, 1 <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON>, 0 Total - 9
</TEXT>
<HEAD>WEST VIRGINIA</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 5 percent of precincts reporting <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, 23 <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON>, 0 Uncommitted, 3 <ORGANIZATION> Conley </ORGANIZATION>, 0 <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>, 2 <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON>, 0 <PERSON> Stassen </PERSON>, 0 Total - 28
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880510-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-10-88 0018EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Israel-Settlers Bjt   05-10 0861</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Israel-Settlers, Bjt,0883</SECOND>
<HEAD>Settlers Strive For Normalcy Despite Unrest in West Bank</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By NICOLAS B. TATRO</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>GUSH ETZION, Occupied West Bank (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The leftfielder wore a .38 - caliber pistol on his hip, and the sandlot baseball game was held on the obstacle course of an army But the Jewish settlers, most American emigrants, intently pursued the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> pastime on a sunny afternoon in May and saw little strange in the setting. In fact, they viewed their ball game as a symbol of the normalcy of life in the occupied <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION>. `` This could be anywhere in the <LOCATION> U.S.A. </LOCATION> on a summer afternoon,'' <PERSON> Mordechai </PERSON> <PERSON> Goodman </PERSON>, 46, said, surveying the field where about 30 Israelis aged 5 to 50 had gathered to watch and play. <PERSON> Goodman </PERSON>, who wore a <ORGANIZATION> Houston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Astros </ORGANIZATION> T-shirt, quit a job as a men's wear salesman in <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION> two years ago to move to the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> settlement of <LOCATION> Efrat </LOCATION> nearby, where he opened a pizzeria. `` I guess you could say this is a sign of how normal life is here,'' he said, tossing a softball to his 4-year-old son, <PERSON> Shimon </PERSON>. Maybe so, but <PERSON> Ephraim </PERSON> <PERSON> Ben-Zeev </PERSON>, a physician who had jogged over to the field from <LOCATION> Efrat </LOCATION> to watch his teen-age son play, carried a .357 Magnum on one hip. He said the gun was insurance against being ambushed by Palestinian youths. `` I wear it in case there is a sudden shower of stones. Thank heavens I have n't had to use it yet,'' said <PERSON> Ben-Zeev </PERSON>, who was listening to rock music on a radio-cassette player. He stood along the foul line that led past a large piece of board used to train soldiers to scale walls. The flames of an explosion were painted on the wood in fading red and orange. Settlers maintain that media concentration on five months of <LOCATION> Palestinian </LOCATION> riots has given a distorted picture of the actual situation in the occupied <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strip </LOCATION>. They say daily life continues largely unaffected for the 65,000 Jewish residents of the occupied territories. While there is no evidence that settlers are leaving their homes in the occupied lands, government and settlement officials agree that the unrest has affected potential residents. <PERSON> Yossi </PERSON> <PERSON> Margalit </PERSON>, a housing ministry official, said the impact has been greater on the `` commuter settlers'' who live just outside <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s 1967 borders and are lured primarily by the chance to live in a house with a yard instead of in an cramped urban apartment. `` There has been some decline in purchases of homes in towns'' near the Israeli border, <PERSON> Margalit </PERSON> said. `` But deeper into the territory, where the idealists live, there has n't been a change.'' He estimated that housing sales have declined by a few percentage points, but stressed there has been no mass departures from the area. `` Some perhaps have left the -LRB- large settlements -RRB- for personal reasons, but -LRB- the Palestinian uprising -RRB- has n't been the dominant factor,'' he said. Even before the riots began Dec. 8, the settlement building program had slowed. Since 1984, the government has approved six settlements but people are living in only four. Government spending on settlements, which totaled $ 2 billion between 1968 and 1986, has declined from a 1982-83 peak of $ 250 million a year to $ 150 million at the end of 1986, according to <ORGANIZATION> Meron </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Benvenisti </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> West </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Data </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Project </ORGANIZATION>. The studies by the independent center are funded by the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> and Rockefeller foundations. In <LOCATION> Efrat </LOCATION>, eight miles south of <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION>, town manager <PERSON> Yossi </PERSON> <PERSON> Beck </PERSON> said the settlement's bulletin board had notices from prospective buyers seeking houses. But he said many of the 300 families who have moved in the hilltop community since 1983 have begun to wonder what will happen as a result of the unrest. `` If it continues, there is no doubt it will affect the idea of people moving here,'' said <PERSON> Beck </PERSON>, an immigrant from <LOCATION> Holland </LOCATION>. `` My feeling is that after it calms down the interest in people moving here will resume.'' <PERSON> Shlomo </PERSON> <PERSON> Riskin </PERSON>, chief rabbi of <LOCATION> Efrat </LOCATION> and a driving force behind its founding in 1983, said he was pressing ahead with plans to expand the settlement with 450 more houses and a religious education center. `` This was just stones,'' <PERSON> Riskin </PERSON> said, pointing to <LOCATION> Grape </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION> on which is built a cluster of villas with red tile roofs. Rows of houses under construction are going up on nearby <LOCATION> Pomegranate </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION> and more units are planned for <PERSON> Date </PERSON> <PERSON> Hill </PERSON>, he said. For <PERSON> Riskin </PERSON>, the attachment to this land is rooted in modern and ancient history and this lure is felt by residents, most of whom are Orthodox Jews. `` The young shepherd boy <PERSON> David </PERSON> raised his flocks here in <LOCATION> Efrat </LOCATION>, and the book of <PERSON> Ruth </PERSON> takes place here in the city of <LOCATION> Efrat </LOCATION>,'' said <PERSON> Riskin </PERSON>, who emigrated from <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. At the same time, he maintains there is a national consensus to stay in Gush Etzion, the bloc of settlements that includes <LOCATION> Efrat </LOCATION>. This stems from the killing of 200 Jewish settlers there in the 1948 war of independence. The unrest, he said, had strengthened settlers' commitment. `` If anything, it has drawn us more closely together,'' <PERSON> Riskin </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880510-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-10-88 0209EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FarmScene     05-10 1019</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Farm Scene,1000</SECOND>
<HEAD>Dairy Group Protests Further Cuts In Milk Price Supports</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DON KENDALL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Farm Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Dairy farmers are being asked to join a lobbying effort by the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Milk </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Producers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federation </ORGANIZATION> to head off a further cut in federal milk price supports scheduled by the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> next year. The 72-year-old federation, which represents most of the nation's dairy cooperatives, wants <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Lyng </PERSON> to use authority in the 1985 farm law to cancel the next reduction in milk supports on Jan. 1, 1989, in favor of an alternate plan to cut production. `` Enough is enough,'' federation president <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Camerlo </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Canon </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Colo. </LOCATION>, said Monday. `` Dairy farmers are tired of suffering continual price reductions after having done more to address federal policy concerns than any segment of <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. agriculture.'' <PERSON> Camerlo </PERSON> said <PERSON> Lyng </PERSON> has the authority to set up a new whole-herd buyout or a diversion program, both of which have been used in recent years to trim <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> milk production. However, <PERSON> Lyng </PERSON> has been steadfast against reviving the buyout and diversion programs as an alternative to the reduction in price supports. Camerlo and other federation officials told a news conference at the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Club </ORGANIZATION> that the 50-cent reduction scheduled for next Jan. 1 would put the milk support level at $ 10.10 per 100 pounds of milk, the lowest since 1979. `` Dairy farmers will have to live at 1979 income levels with 1989 costs,'' he said. Milk price supports have been lowered progressively from a record high of $ 13.10 per 100 pounds since 1983 to help discourage surplus production. A diversion plan to pay farmers for cutting back production, and a whole-herd buyout, or Dairy Termination Program, also were used. The 18-month whole-herd buyout program began April 1, 1986, and continued through October 1987. More than 1.22 million dairy cows, heifers and calves were sent to market by thousands of producers who agreed to quit dairying for at least five years. About 38 percent of the buyout program's cost of $ 1.8 billion was paid by dairy farmers themselves who were charged assessments on milk they sold. Similar arrangements helped hold down costs on the earlier diversion plan. <PERSON> Camerlo </PERSON> said the 50-cent reduction next Jan. 1 would come as milk production costs, including feed, are on the upswing. The two-way crunch would add up next year to a 37 percent slide in dairy farm income from 1987 levels. Dairy farmers have contributed $ 2.9 billion in assessments since 1983 to reduce the costs of their programs by 50 percent, overall, <PERSON> Camerlo </PERSON> said. Federation leaders have met frequently with <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> officials, including <PERSON> Lyng </PERSON>, in an attempt to persuade them to abandon the path of lower milk supports. `` The secretary has been consistent, as has his staff, that they will cut the price,'' <PERSON> Camerlo </PERSON> said. `` They do not intend to utilize the authority that they have in the'85 act to implement a whole-herd or Dairy Termination Program.'' <PERSON> Camerlo </PERSON> said <PERSON> Lyng </PERSON> stated that policy at the federation's annual meeting in December 1986 and has not budged. `` Another 50-cent cut in the dairy price support level on Jan. 1, 1989, is simply unsound policy,'' he said. `` It will increase, not reduce federal dairy program costs. And it will be as costly _ and perhaps more costly _ to the government than another limited, dairy termination program.'' The previous DTP in 1986-87 was designed to reduce milk production by 12 billion pounds. <PERSON> Camerlo </PERSON> said a limited DTP could be set up to cut production by 4 billion or 5 billion pounds, which would serve as a stopgap measure until new legislation is worked out. According to <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> figures, milk production in calendar 1987 declined about 1 percent to 142.5 billion pounds from a record of 143.8 billion pounds in 1986. But production is rising again and is expected to gain 1 percent to 3 percent in 1988 to another record level.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Visitors to national forests may soon find it easier to enjoy the scenery, says the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>. Officially, stretches of road selected will be called <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Scenic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Byways </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> chief <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Dale </PERSON> <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> said Monday. `` Scenic driving is the single most popular form of outdoor recreation on the national forests,'' <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> said. `` Many of the 105,000 miles of roads we have designed and maintained for passenger car travel pass through some of <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s most spectacular scenery.'' Designated byways will have interpretive signs, some overlook and parking areas, and other facilities such as rest stops and short-loop walking trails, he said. `` There are 156 national forests across the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and we want to showcase their beauty with these byways,'' <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> said. The agency will seek partnerships with groups and organizations to identify suitable roads and to assist in placing signs, developing interpretive materials and constructing facilities, he said. Some examples of scenic roads that <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> said could be included in the program: _ <LOCATION> Talimena </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Scenic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Drive </LOCATION> in the <ORGANIZATION> Ouachita </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Arkansas </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION>, which follows the top of Winding Stair Mountain _ <LOCATION> Mount </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hood </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Scenic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Loop </LOCATION> in the <ORGANIZATION> Mount </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hood </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION>, which runs from <LOCATION> Portland </LOCATION>, around <LOCATION> Mount </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hood </LOCATION>, and into the <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gorge </LOCATION> _ <LOCATION> Carson </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Pass </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Forest </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Highway </LOCATION> in the <ORGANIZATION> Eldorado </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, which covers 25 miles in the <LOCATION> Sierra </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION> mountains _ <LOCATION> Kancamagus </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Scenic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Road </LOCATION> in the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mountain </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION>, which covers 32 miles with overlooks that view the Presidential Range
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Farmers idled about 59.9 million acres of cropland under 1987 acreage reduction programs, an area larger than all of <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION> combined, according to new <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> figures. The preliminary report for compliance in the 1987 programs said Monday the acreage represented about 87 percent of the base acreage for wheat, feed grains, cotton and rice. In 1986, by comparison, farmers idled 44.6 million acres, or 82 percent of their total base for those crops. Wheat farmers idled 23.8 million acres last year, followed by corn, 23 million acres; sorghum, 4 million; barley, 2.9 million; oats, 800,000; cotton, 3.8 million; and rice, 1.6 million.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880510-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-10-88 0314EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Mondale-Veep     05-10 0458</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Mondale-Veep,460</SECOND>
<HEAD>Mondale Urges Dukakis To Use Different Strategy Than His For
Picking Veep</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DONALD M. ROTHBERG</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Political Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Mondale </PERSON> says the interviews he held four years ago with prospective running mates proved a `` damaged strategy'' and he thinks <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> ought to find a different way of selecting the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> vice presidential nominee this year. Four years ago, <PERSON> Mondale </PERSON> interviewed a succession of candidates before he chose <PERSON> Geraldine </PERSON> <PERSON> Ferraro </PERSON>, then a congresswoman from <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, as the first woman on a major party's national ticket. One by one, the vice presidential hopefuls visited <PERSON> Mondale </PERSON> at his home in <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION>. In retrospect, `` I do n't think it built confidence,'' <PERSON> Mondale </PERSON> said of the process. The 1984 Democratic presidential nominee's comments came in a telephone interview from his <LOCATION> Minneapolis </LOCATION> law office on Monday `` I do n't think the way that process played out reassured Americans,'' he said. `` It's a damaged strategy even though it was not a bad idea.'' He suggested that <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> `` pursue a different way of looking at vice presidential candidates.'' Asked if he thought <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, who now appears likely to lock up the Democratic presidential nomination before the July convention, should choose a Southerner for his running mate, <PERSON> Mondale </PERSON> said, `` I would n't say he has to. But what I ca n't figure out is how you get the numbers if you do n't run strong in the South.'' <PERSON> Mondale </PERSON> was optimistic about the Democrats' chances of winning a presidential election for only the second time in the last six. `` We've got a shot at this deal,'' he said. Republican Vice President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> `` is a troubled candidate,'' he said. `` I think he gets off in an uncertain way. I think there are going to be vulnerabilities on both sides. But <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> looks strong as a person and I do n't think <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> does.'' <PERSON> Mondale </PERSON> said there is a need to `` constantly reassure Americans that you possess that special presidential strength of character and independence and resolve to serve the public interest.'' In recent campaign appearances, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> often has seemed to be campaigning against <PERSON> Jimmy </PERSON> <PERSON> Carter </PERSON>, under whom <PERSON> Mondale </PERSON> served as vice president. `` I believe that's a sign of weakness,'' said <PERSON> Mondale </PERSON>. `` Here's a guy who ought to be filling in the blanks where people are worried about him, which is character and vision and direction and presidential status `` Instead, he's out there hacking around against a president who's been out of office for eight years.'' <PERSON> Mondale </PERSON> also suggested that <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> avoid following his example of declaring that if elected president he would raise taxes to reduce the federal deficit. `` I think it's too bad ... that we ca n't talk about our real problems,'' he said, but `` I think the verdict is in on that.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880510-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-10-88 0249EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-DukakisEnemies Bjt   05-10 0643</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Dukakis Enemies, Bjt,650</SECOND>
<HEAD>As Dukakis' Star Rises, His Enemies Hone Their Attacks</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN KING</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BOSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 As Democratic front-runner <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> prepares for a likely fall campaign, Vice President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> is n't the only one going after him. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> has the likes of <PERSON> Dorothea </PERSON> <PERSON> Thomas-Vitrac </PERSON> to contend with too. <PERSON> Thomas-Vitrac </PERSON>'s dispute with the <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> governor is strictly a local affair. But she _ like other political enemies of <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> _ intends to do what she can to disrupt the governor's presidential bid in order to make her point As <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> comes under increasing scrutiny, that task becomes easier and easier. <PERSON> Thomas-Vitrac </PERSON> is a member of the board of selectmen in the tiny western <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> town of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Braintree </LOCATION>, where <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> has proposed building a 500-bed prison. She has led the fight against it. When <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> went to <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> late last year to tell struggling farmers he was concerned about their plight, <PERSON> Thomas-Vitrac </PERSON> went too. `` He would n't acknowledge me, but I was blocking the only entrance to the pigpen,'' <PERSON> Thomas-Vitrac </PERSON> said. `` I think I made my point.'' Former <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> King </PERSON>, a former <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> governor who has switched parties, is making his point too. The <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> campaign is bankrolling King's travel around the country criticizing <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>. King turned <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> out of office in 1978; <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> defeated King in 1982. King made a speech Monday, attacking <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' image as a competent manager. `` I do n't think it's based on facts,'' he said. `` I think it sharply contrasts what he has done.'' A Dukakis presidency, <PERSON> King </PERSON> said, would bring `` an ever expanding, more costly government, more regulation, more taxes.'' Another vocal <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> opponent is <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON>, the director of the anti-tax group <ORGANIZATION> Citizens </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Limited </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Taxation </ORGANIZATION>. The group has successfully battled <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' efforts in the last five years to create additional exemptions to a voter-passed property tax cap. When <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> takes credit on the presidential campaign trail for cutting taxes back home in <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> fumes. `` He was dragged kicking and screaming into those tax cuts,'' said <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON>. `` The reputation is a fabricated myth.'' When <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> heads to <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> later this week to campaign, he likely will be reminded of a policy in <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> that effectively bans homosexuals from becoming foster parents by encouraging placements of foster children in `` traditional'' families. The Washington-based National Gay and <ORGANIZATION> Lesbian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Task </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> since last year has organized protests of <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> events, and activists and newspapers in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>'s gay community have criticized the policy. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> is a supporter of a gay rights bill languishing before the state legislature, but the foster parent policy has tended to overshadow that. `` He's responsible for a very discriminatory social policy,'' said task force spokeswoman <PERSON> Sue </PERSON> <PERSON> Hyde </PERSON>. <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> politics are dominated by Democrats, but not all of them shower praise on <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>. `` I've always felt that he's spent too much,'' said Rep. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Flood </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Canton </LOCATION>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Taxation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>. `` We've spent all this money and we have n't addressed our major problems, overcrowded prisons, unfunded pension liability and the need for more money to clean up hazardous waste. Flood was quick to add: `` Of course <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has a lot of baggage of his own.'' <PERSON> Charlie </PERSON> <PERSON> Manning </PERSON>, meanwhile, is relishing his job these days. As the top spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> Massachusetts </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Manning </PERSON> gets a lot of attention when he talks about <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>. <PERSON> Manning </PERSON> said he has been fielding an `` incredible'' number of telephone calls from out-of-state reporters in recent weeks. Not only does <PERSON> Manning </PERSON> take every opportunity to rap the governor _ he calls the thought of a <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> presidency `` scary'' _ he's always willing to steer journalists toward other critics of <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> In fact, he has a new card in his desktop Rolodex _ just for numbers of <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> enemies. `` I made it just for moments like these,'' he said with obvious glee.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880510-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-10-88 0315EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Dukakis     05-10 0388</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Dukakis,370</SECOND>
<HEAD>Dukakis Prods Bush On Noriega</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN KING</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BOSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> held one in a series of meetings with congressional leaders and renewed his demand that <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> detail his knowledge of alleged drug trafficking by Panamanian strongman <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> did not campaign this week for today's primaries in <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>. He took the weekend off and spent Monday at the <ORGANIZATION> Statehouse </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> paid visits to both <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> last week, however. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> has said he is still focusing on <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> and the remaining primaries, but his comments about <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and the meeting with <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> Sen. <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON> were signs he is looking increasingly toward the fall campaign. `` I think that the American people deserve an overall explanation about who in this administration was doing business with him -LRB- <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> -RRB- and why,'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> said Monday. `` I can tell you one thing: If I'm the president we wo n't be doing business with drug-running Panamanian dictators,'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> said as he left his Statehouse office. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> spokesman <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Teeley </PERSON> said Monday that the vice president was aware before <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>'s indictment on drug charges in February of speculation that the <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> government was involved in drug trafficking. But <PERSON> Teeley </PERSON> said the information was not substantive. <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON> told reporters that his meeting with <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> centered on U.S.-Soviet relations. He said the topic of the No. 2 spot on the Democratic ticket did not come up during the meeting, adding he was not interested and would be a poor choice anyway. `` That's not in the cards,'' <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON> said as he left <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' office `` <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> do n't go well together.'' <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON> said he did not think <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' lack of foreign policy experience would hurt him in his expected general election campaign against <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, although the vice president has already raised the issue. `` Experience is no substitute for ability and he's got real ability,'' <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON> said he expected <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> to defeat <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION>'s primary June 7, the same day as the <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> primary. The <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> governor said he and <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON> `` had a good discussion.'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> plans to travel to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION>, on Thursday for meetings with congressional leaders including <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Speaker <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Majority Leader <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON> of <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880510-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-10-88 0315EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--Hungary-Censor     05-10 0159</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Hungary-Censor,0165</SECOND>
<HEAD>Police Seize 1,500 Copies Of Newsletter In Hungary</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BUDAPEST, Hungary (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Security police raided the headquarters of an underground dissident publishing operation and seized 1,500 copies of a newsletter critical of Communist Party policies, an activist said. <PERSON> Gabor </PERSON> <PERSON> Demszky </PERSON>, an underground book publisher and editor of the newsletter known as The Message, said police on Monday seized the publication and printing equipment in a house near <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Balaton </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Demszky </PERSON> said the publication contained articles from several groups and was timed to coincide with the May 20 <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> conference. `` They are trying to make an example of us,'' <PERSON> Demszky </PERSON> told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> in a <LOCATION> Budapest </LOCATION> apartment, `` but they wo n't succeed in stopping us.'' A growing number of independent non-Communist and activist groups have been calling for more openness and representation in Hungarian society. <PERSON> Demszky </PERSON> said the latest issue of the newsletter contained articles and commentaries on the policies of <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> leader <PERSON> Janos </PERSON> <PERSON> Kadar </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880510-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-10-88 0315EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-CookieMisfortune     05-10 0181</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Cookie Misfortune,170</SECOND>
<HEAD>Senator Says Girl Scouts' Cookie Crunch Resolved</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A shipment of 402 boxes of Girl Scout cookies will finally reach sailors aboard the USS Midway after being blocked once by Japanese officials and returned to <LOCATION> Corpus </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Christi </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>. `` That's good news for our sailors and for the Brownies from Troop 807,'' Sen. <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Texas </LOCATION>, said Monday while announcing that the dispute with <PERSON> Japanee </PERSON> customs officials had been resolved. <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> said the cookies should be on their way sometime today now that Japanese officials have relented. Japanese customs officials initially blocked the shipment of cookies from the Brownie troop in <LOCATION> Corpus </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Christi </LOCATION> and assessed a $ 2,000 duty fee, which <ORGANIZATION> Brownie </ORGANIZATION> officials said was too steep for the children. The cookies were shipped April 26, then spent four days in a <LOCATION> Japanese </LOCATION> customs warehouse before being returned to the airport in <LOCATION> Corpus </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Christi </LOCATION>. Thirty-five servicemen aboard the aircraft carrier had ordered cookies from the Brownies, who had sent the men Christmas cards and a Valentine's Day box of candy. The Midway's home port is <LOCATION> Atsugi </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880510-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-10-88 0022EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p BC-PP-Dem-Deleg-All-SAMPLE     05-10 0725</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-PP-Dem-Deleg-All-SAMPLE,400</SECOND>
<HEAD>05-09-88 13:34</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the latest, unofficial results in the Democratic presidential primaries and caucuses on Tuesday.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>NEBRASKA</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 100 percent of precincts reporting <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, 0 <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, 0 Uncommitted, 0 <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON>, 0 <PERSON> Gore </PERSON>, 0 <PERSON> Hart </PERSON>, 0 <PERSON> LaRouche </PERSON>, 0 <PERSON> Simon </PERSON>, 0 Total - 0
</TEXT>
<HEAD>WEST VIRGINIA</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 100 percent of precincts reporting <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, 0 <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, 0 <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON>, 0 Uncommitted, 0 <PERSON> Babbitt </PERSON>, 0 <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON>, 0 <PERSON> Gore </PERSON>, 0 <PERSON> Hart </PERSON>, 0 <PERSON> LaRouche </PERSON>, 0 <PERSON> Simon </PERSON>, 0 <ORGANIZATION> Traficant </ORGANIZATION>, 0 Total - 0
</TEXT>
<HEAD>BC-PP-Dem-Deleg-Sum-SAMPLE,100</HEAD>
<HEAD>05-09-88 13:34</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the delegates won by each candidate in the Democratic presidential primaries on Tuesday.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, 0 <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, 0 Uncommitted, 0 <PERSON> Babbitt </PERSON>, 0 <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON>, 0 <PERSON> Gore </PERSON>, 0 <PERSON> Hart </PERSON>, 0 <PERSON> Simon </PERSON>, 0 Other, 0 Total - 0
</TEXT>
<HEAD>BC-PP-GOP-Deleg-All-SAMPLE,400</HEAD>
<HEAD>05-09-88 13:34</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the latest, unofficial results in the Republican presidential primaries and caucuses on Tuesday.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>NEBRASKA</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 100 percent of precincts reporting <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, 0 <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON>, 0 Uncommitted, 0 <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>, 0 <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON>, 0 Total - 0
</TEXT>
<HEAD>WEST VIRGINIA</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 100 percent of precincts reporting <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, 0 <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON>, 0 Uncommitted, 0 <ORGANIZATION> Conley </ORGANIZATION>, 0 <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>, 0 <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON>, 0 <PERSON> Stassen </PERSON>, 0 Total - 0
</TEXT>
<HEAD>BC-PP-GOP-Deleg-Sum-SAMPLE,100</HEAD>
<HEAD>05-09-88 13:35</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the delegates won by each candidate in the Republican presidential primaries on Tuesday.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, 0 <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON>, 0 Uncommitted, 0 <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>, 0 <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON>, 0 Other, 0 Total - 0
</TEXT>
<HEAD>BC-PP-Dem-Pres-All-SAMPLE,400</HEAD>
<HEAD>05-09-88 13:34</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the latest, unofficial results in the Democratic presidential primaries on Tuesday.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>NEBRASKA</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 0 of 1,870 precincts reporting - 0 percent <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, 0 - 0 percent <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, 0 - 0 percent Uncommitted, 0 - 0 percent <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON>, 0 - 0 percent <PERSON> Gore </PERSON>, 0 - 0 percent <PERSON> Hart </PERSON>, 0 - 0 percent <PERSON> LaRouche </PERSON>, 0 - 0 percent <PERSON> Simon </PERSON>, 0 - 0 percent
</TEXT>
<HEAD>WEST VIRGINIA</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 0 of 2,151 precincts reporting - 0 percent <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, 0 - 0 percent <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, 0 - 0 percent <PERSON> Duke </PERSON>, 0 - 0 percent <PERSON> Dennerll </PERSON>, 0 - 0 percent <PERSON> Gore </PERSON>, 0 - 0 percent <PERSON> LaRouche </PERSON>, 0 - 0 percent <ORGANIZATION> McDonald </ORGANIZATION>, 0 - 0 percent <PERSON> Simon </PERSON>, 0 - 0 percent <PERSON> Traficant </PERSON>, 0 - 0 percent
</TEXT>
<HEAD>BC-PP-GOP-Pres-All-SAMPLE,400</HEAD>
<HEAD>05-09-88 13:34</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the latest, unofficial results in the Republican presidential primaries on Tuesday.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>NEBRASKA</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 0 of 1,870 precincts reporting - 0 percent <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, 0 - 0 percent <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON>, 0 - 0 percent <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>, 0 - 0 percent
</TEXT>
<HEAD>WEST VIRGINIA</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 0 of 2,151 precincts reporting - 0 percent <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, 0 - 0 percent <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON>, 0 - 0 percent <PERSON> Conley </PERSON>, 0 - 0 percent <PERSON> Stassen </PERSON>, 0 - 0 percent
</TEXT>
<HEAD>BC-NE-Dem-Senate-Sum-SAMPLE,79</HEAD>
<HEAD>05-09-88 13:38</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the latest, unofficial results in the Democratic primary for the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 0 of 1,870 precincts reporting - 0 percent <ORGANIZATION> Kerrey </ORGANIZATION> 0 - 0 percent <PERSON> Michaelis </PERSON> 0 - 0 percent
</TEXT>
<HEAD>BC-NE-GOP-Senate-Sum-SAMPLE,79</HEAD>
<HEAD>05-09-88 13:38</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the latest, unofficial results in the Republican primary for the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 0 of 1,870 precincts reporting - 0 percent <ORGANIZATION> Daub </ORGANIZATION> 0 - 0 percent <PERSON> Karnes </PERSON>, -LRB- i -RRB- 0 - 0 percent
</TEXT>
<HEAD>BC-WV-Dem-Senate-Sum-SAMPLE,79</HEAD>
<HEAD>05-09-88 14:00</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the latest, unofficial results in the Democratic primary for the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 0 of 2,151 precincts reporting - 0 percent <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON>, -LRB- i -RRB- 0 - 0 percent <ORGANIZATION> Myers </ORGANIZATION> 0 - 0 percent
</TEXT>
<HEAD>BC-WV-GOP-Senate-Sum-SAMPLE,79</HEAD>
<HEAD>05-09-88 14:00</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the latest, unofficial results in the Republican primary for the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 0 of 2,151 precincts reporting - 0 percent <ORGANIZATION> Lumbert </ORGANIZATION> 0 - 0 percent <ORGANIZATION> Wolfe </ORGANIZATION> 0 - 0 percent
</TEXT>
<HEAD>BC-WV-Dem-Gov-Sum-SAMPLE,79</HEAD>
<HEAD>05-09-88 13:38</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the latest, unofficial results in the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Gubernatorial </ORGANIZATION> primary in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 0 of 2,151 precincts reporting - 0 percent <ORGANIZATION> Caperton </ORGANIZATION> 0 - 0 percent <ORGANIZATION> Douglass </ORGANIZATION> 0 - 0 percent <ORGANIZATION> Harless </ORGANIZATION> 0 - 0 percent <ORGANIZATION> Nuchims </ORGANIZATION> 0 - 0 percent <PERSON> Palumbo </PERSON> 0 - 0 percent See 0 - 0 percent <PERSON> Tonkovich </PERSON> 0 - 0 percent
</TEXT>
<HEAD>BC-WV-GOP-Gov-Sum-SAMPLE,79</HEAD>
<HEAD>05-09-88 13:38</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the latest, unofficial results in the <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Gubernatorial </ORGANIZATION> primary in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 0 of 2,151 precincts reporting - 0 percent <PERSON> Moore </PERSON>, Jr. -LRB- i -RRB- 0 - 0 percent <ORGANIZATION> Raese </ORGANIZATION> 0 - 0 percent
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880510-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-10-88 0247EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Bush-Ignorance Bjt   05-10 0810</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bush-Ignorance, Bjt,810</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush's Defense On Two Fronts: Lack Of Knowledge</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP News Analysis</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TOM RAUM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s defense on his two biggest campaign liabilities, the Iran-Contra affair and alleged drug dealing by <LOCATION> Panamanian </LOCATION> leader <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>, is the same: a plea of ignorance. On both counts, the Republican presidential candidate sounds alike: _ Although he once headed the <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Intelligence </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> and a presidential task force on drugs, he says he did n't know <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> was involved in alleged drug trafficking until this past February, when a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> indictment was handed down in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> _ Even though a member of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>, he says he had no hint that <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> arms were being sold to <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> in an effort to free hostages, or that proceeds were funnelled illegally to the Contras in <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> The vice president's continued denial of advance knowledge in both instances has hung over his campaign like a two-edged sword. Either he knew more than he's admitting, in which case he's not telling the truth; or the candidate who claims vast experience in foreign policy was kept in the dark on two matters of crucial international importance. Either way, it's a no-win political situation for <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. The vice president has stock ways of dealing with the twin issues. Of Iran-Contra, he says he fully expects Democrats to exploit it as a major campaign issue, but claims that's only because they have little else to talk about. And the political fallout so far has been minimal, he claims. `` It's been tried. It was used against me in the -LRB- GOP -RRB- primaries,'' he told reporters during a campaign stop last week in <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION>. `` It does n't show up _ unless they -LRB- Democrats -RRB- have got data that I have n't seen _ as a great vulnerability. `` I certainly ca n't say it's a plus,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> conceded. `` But, fortunately neither of them -LRB- Democratic candidates <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> -RRB- has any experience at all in international affairs. So I can offset the criticism by talking about the rest of the world. That's what I've tried to do.'' On <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> maintains he lacked clear knowledge that the Panamanian general was involved in alleged drug dealings before the indictment three months ago. Campaign spokesman <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Teeley </PERSON> said Monday that <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was aware of rumors of such activity but viewed them as unsubstantiated. `` We heard all sorts of accusations about the government in the <LOCATION> Bahamas </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Bolivia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Peru </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Teeley </PERSON> said. `` But the question is, when do you get concrete evidence that something of this nature is indeed true?'' As recently as last Thursday in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> reiterated his denial of any advance knowledge of <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>'s alleged drug dealings. Asked whether he ever had been told of reports of ties between <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> and drugs, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said, `` Not that I was ever aware of.'' Seeking to deflect criticism, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> says the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration sought to bring <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> to justice `` once we found out he had gone bad.'' He also has made an anti-drug theme a major thrust of his race, calling for a Western Hempishere drug `` summit'' and for an international anti-drug force under the auspices of the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION>. And he has challenged <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> to show they're as serious as he is by joining him in supporting the death penalty for `` drug kingpins. Thus far, the Democrats have not gone for the bait. Democratic front-runner <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> accuses the Reagan-Bush administration of `` dealing with drug-running Panamanian dictators.'' And <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> asserts: `` The reason Mr. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has not led the charge to fight drugs is because he knew of the administration's dealings with the drug dealers.'' The question of exactly when <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> learned of <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>'s alleged role in drug-dealing was first raised in the Republican primaries by Sen. <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has been hit with the question by reporters at nearly every campaign stop since. The accusations go to the core of <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s campaign, since he trumpets repeatedly his experience in international affairs _ with a resume that includes serving as <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> director, ambassador to the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION>, envoy to the People's Republic of <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> and heading the <ORGANIZATION> South </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Florida </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Task </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION>, a federal drug-interdiction effort in the early 1980s. Sen. <PERSON> Christopher </PERSON> <PERSON> Dodd </PERSON>, D-Conn., chairman of a <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> subcommittee on Latin American affairs, has said he would be surprised if <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> did n't have advance knowledge of <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>'s alleged drug trafficking, given his extensive `` If he did n't know, that's almost as disturbing,'' <PERSON> Dodd </PERSON> says. But <PERSON> Teeley </PERSON> said Monday: `` The Democrats have nothing to attack <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> on. They ca n't attack him on unemployment, inflation, interest rates; they're all down. Personal income is up. Real wages are up. Taxes are down. There is a new arms-control treaty. So they are going to be looking for issues like this -LRB- <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> and Iran-Contras -RRB- to attack him on.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880510-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-10-88 0319EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Wedtech-Meese     05-10 0272</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Wedtech-Meese,270</SECOND>
<HEAD>Chairman Challenges Meese Aide on Report Criticizing AG</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Assistant Attorney General <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Bradford </PERSON> <PERSON> Reynolds </PERSON> has been challenged to back up his criticism of a bipartisan report saying Attorney General <PERSON> Edwin </PERSON> <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON> violated White House ethics policy. Sen. <PERSON> Carl </PERSON> <PERSON> Levin </PERSON>, D-Mich., urged <PERSON> Reynolds </PERSON> in a letter Monday to `` kindly inform us'' of any incorrect information in the 244-page report issued by his subcommittee The report accuses <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> of violating White House ethics policy by helping the scandal-plagued <ORGANIZATION> Wedtech </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> obtain a $ 32 million no-bid Army contract while he was counselor to the president. Reynolds on Sunday called the report `` sleaze,'' and said the policy went into effect after `` the <ORGANIZATION> Wedtech </ORGANIZATION> thing was referred over to the attorney general.'' However, the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> report noted that memos sent to <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> from his longtime friend <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Wallach </PERSON> seeking help for <ORGANIZATION> Wedtech </ORGANIZATION> came to then-White House counselor <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> in 1982 as well as in 1981. The White House policy barring contact by White House staff with procurement officers about a contract in which a friend has a financial interest took effect in October 1981. In addition to asking <PERSON> Reynolds </PERSON> to back up his criticism of the report, <PERSON> Levin </PERSON> pointed out that it was the work of four Republicans as well as five Democrats. <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> <PERSON> Eastland </PERSON> said <PERSON> Reynolds </PERSON> `` will respond in due course'' to <PERSON> Levin </PERSON>'s letter. <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> has acknowledged intervening on behalf of <ORGANIZATION> Wedtech </ORGANIZATION>, a <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bronx </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION>, defense contractor, in connection with the $ 32 million Army contract. <ORGANIZATION> Wedtech </ORGANIZATION> subsequently won the no-bid contract. <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> says he merely wanted to assure that <ORGANIZATION> Wedtech </ORGANIZATION> got a fair hearing.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880510-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-10-88 0040EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-StormsRdp 1stLd-Writethru a0745 05-10 0750</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Storms Rdp, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0745,0767</SECOND>
<HEAD>High Wind Damages Kentucky Town, Leaves One Dead; Hail Storms in
Midwest</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: LEADS with 16 grafs to UPDATE with storm damage in Kentuck,
one dead, Ohio weather, picking up 8th graf ``Quarter-sized...''</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Powerful winds ripped through the center of a <LOCATION> Kentucky </LOCATION> town Monday, causing widespread damage and killing one person, while hail storms battered homes and cars in a four-state area southeast of <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION>. A day earlier, as many as 82 tornadoes swept through the <LOCATION> Midwest </LOCATION>. In <LOCATION> Middlesboro </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ky. </LOCATION>, wind gusts blew roofs of downtown buildings, shattered windows and leveled the top floor of a furniture building, officials said. `` It's not just a few shingles, it's entire roofs,'' said Lt. <PERSON> Woody </PERSON> <PERSON> White </PERSON> of the <LOCATION> Middlesboro </LOCATION> Fire Department. `` The buildings we can see -LRB- from fire department building -RRB-, the roofs are gone.'' One person was killed and there were numerous injuries, said Sgt. <PERSON> Jimmy </PERSON> <PERSON> England </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Middlesboro </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>. ` Oh Lord. When I was on the floor, I just saw my life, I just thought I was gone,'' said <PERSON> Lemodee </PERSON> <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON>, 20, who is six weeks pregnant. `` Well I've got a bunch of cuts and bruises, but you know, thank God I'm alive. I just thank God I did n't lose it.'' Mayor <PERSON> Troy </PERSON> <PERSON> Welch </PERSON> declared an emergency and was trying to reach the governor's office to ask for help from the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION>. Weather officials said they could not immediately determine if a tornado had struck. The city of 11,000 is in southeast <LOCATION> Kentucky </LOCATION>, bordering on <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>. A low-pressure system over the upper <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION> and north of the <LOCATION> Great </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lakes </LOCATION> produced the tornadoes and threatened to stir up more twisters or thunderstorms Monday in southeast lower <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, southeast <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION> and north-central <LOCATION> Kentucky </LOCATION>, forecasters said. `` It was unusual to have so many reports of tornadoes in one day as occurred yesterday,'' <PERSON> Lyle </PERSON> <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON>, a meteorologist at the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Weather </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mo. </LOCATION>, said Monday. The weather service received 82 reports of tornadoes Sunday in <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Arkansas </LOCATION>, but some may be downgraded after further investigation, he said. Few injuries were reported, but an <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION> man was killed Sunday when high winds collapsed a building under construction, <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> Coroner <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> said. At the outset of the violent weather Saturday, a 29-year-old woman and her 2-year-old daughter died after a tornado struck a mobile home in <LOCATION> Gretna </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Neb </LOCATION>. Wind clocked at 81 mph broke up a car show Sunday near <LOCATION> Rockford </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ill. </LOCATION>, by tossing tents, debris, and portable toilets. `` One outhouse flew right past me and then I got hit by another one as I was running away,'' said <PERSON> Dwight </PERSON> <PERSON> Dunlop </PERSON>, 21. Thunderstorms packing winds of up to 70 mph rolled across <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> on Monday, dropping hail, knocking down trees and power lines, and blowing over airplanes at the <LOCATION> Burke </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lakefront </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Cleveland </LOCATION>. There were reports of tornadoes in western <LOCATION> Cuyahoga </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> in northeast <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> and in <LOCATION> Butler </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> in southwest <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, but the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Weather </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> said they could not be confirmed. Quarter-sized hail fell Monday in east-central <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION>, and hail and heavy rain halted traffic on Interstate 70 near <LOCATION> Greensburg </LOCATION>, authorities said. The weather service warned residents in part of <LOCATION> Rush </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> to seek shelter in reinforced buildings because of hail driven by 40 mph winds. High winds knocked down trees Monday afternoon near <LOCATION> Alpena </LOCATION> in northeast <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION>. Pea - and marble-sized hail was reported across much of the state's <LOCATION> Lower </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Peninsula </LOCATION> About 2,300 homes and businesses in the Grand Rapids area and an additional 2,000 in the <LOCATION> Lansing </LOCATION> area were left without electrical service Monday from storms that first reached the state late Sunday, <ORGANIZATION> Consumers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Power </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Knopick </PERSON> said. At least 160 reports of thunderstorms with wind gusts over 50 mph, some with baseball-sized hail, occurred Sunday from <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION>. Several thousand homes lost electricity for several hours Sunday in <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>, and in the <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> area, winds gusting up to 55 mph blacked out 40,000 customers, utilities reported. An air traffic controller at <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>'s Midway Airport complained of a duststorm as strong winds swept through the city. Midway and O'Hare airport officials said some flights were delayed. In north-central <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION>, two people were hospitalized with injuries Sunday after high winds with rain and hail struck their mobile homes in Marathon County. A woman was injured Sunday night when a mobile home was blown over in <LOCATION> Wabash </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, in northern <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION>, police said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880510-0025 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-10-88 0319EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-TortoiseBreeding     05-10 0243</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Tortoise Breeding,0248</SECOND>
<HEAD>Rare Tortoises Breeding, Growing In Stress-Free Captivity</HEAD>
<DATELINE>FORT LAUDERDALE, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Aldabra tortoises rarely breed in captivity, but three have been born at <LOCATION> Ocean </LOCATION> <LOCATION> World </LOCATION> in the last two months because of its stress-free environment, a breeder says. <PERSON> Zoomer </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, born March 31, has almost doubled his 40-gram weight and now weighs 78 grams. His brother, the month-old Hatchback, has increased in weight from 31 grams to nearly 67 grams. <PERSON> Caylith </PERSON>, born last week, weighs 40 grams. The hatching is a rare event in captivity, said <PERSON> Ed </PERSON> <PERSON> Chapman </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> breeder of rare reptiles. The marine park's success can be attributed to a soothing environment where the tortoises do n't have to worry about goats eating them or about being served up as a delicacy, as in their native <LOCATION> Seychelles </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Islands </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Chapman </PERSON> said recently. `` Stress is an important thing with reptiles,'' he said. `` It affects their growth, and it affects their fertility. If wild tortoises are disturbed, they will still lay eggs, but the eggs wo n't be fertile.'' In the wild, tortoises take about 25 to 30 years to reach their adult weight of 500 pounds, <PERSON> Chapman </PERSON> said. `` We're hoping that by feeding them lots of good vegetable protein, such as cactus, they'll reach their full size in about 15 years,'' he said. `` If we can get them to mature and reproduce faster than they do in the wild, then we will have learned something valuable for tortoise breeders.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880510-0026 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-10-88 0322EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-DrunkenDriving     05-10 0437</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Drunken Driving,440</SECOND>
<HEAD>Koop Says Drunken Driving Is Mainly Local Concern</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto WX7</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ALAN FRAM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Surgeon General <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Everett </PERSON> <PERSON> Koop </PERSON> says that despite the wishes of almost the entire <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>, state and local governments are in a better position than the federal government to handle the nation's drunken drivers. <PERSON> Koop </PERSON> attended a news conference Monday at which several lawmakers handed the surgeon general a letter signed by 99 senators asking that he declare drunken driving a `` national crisis.'' <PERSON> Koop </PERSON> acknowledged that intoxicated drivers are `` the direct cause of far too many tragedies in our homes and neighborhoods.'' But he said he believed there was little the federal government can do. `` We can talk about things that can be done about it, but unless we have on every level of state and municipal government a tougher policy with those people who are guilty of drunk driving, then we are never going to succeed,'' <PERSON> Koop </PERSON> said. `` And the people who can bring that about are the grass-roots people in this country,'' he said. In their letter, the senators wrote that about 24,000 people are killed and 43,000 seriously injured in alcohol-related automobile accidents each year. `` We urge you to focus national attention on this slaughter on our highways by declaring drunk driving to be a ` national crisis,''' the letter said. Such a declaration would have no legal force, but would focus publicity on the problem. The letter was signed at the news conference by 12-year-old <PERSON> Charlene </PERSON> <PERSON> Boyette </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Hopkins </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> S.C. </LOCATION>, whose father was killed in an accident involving a drunken driver in 1986. <PERSON> Koop </PERSON> said that on June 15, a member of his staff will begin developing a plan his office can use to support efforts by citizens groups to reduce drunken driving. He declined to say what the initiative would be. When pressed by reporters on whether he would declare the `` national crisis'' requesed by the senators, <PERSON> Koop </PERSON> said, `` I do n't think it takes a surgeon general to declare a crisis when everybody knows there is a crisis. He also said he felt `` a little bit put upon by people not in the government to assume responsibilities that are not mine and that I do n't believe I can usurp.'' Sens. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Warner </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Va </LOCATION>., and <PERSON> Claiborne </PERSON> <PERSON> Pell </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-R.I. </LOCATION>, who wrote the letter to <PERSON> Koop </PERSON>, both said at the news conference that they were satisfied with what the surgeon general said he would do The only senator who did not sign the letter to <PERSON> Koop </PERSON> is <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Biden </PERSON>, D-Del., who is recuperating from surgery on an artery that leads to his brain
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880510-0027 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-10-88 0204EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-PostEditor     05-10 0235</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Post Editor,0242</SECOND>
<HEAD>Post To Get New Editor</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Jane </PERSON> <PERSON> Amsterdam </PERSON>, founding editor of <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION>, inc. magazine, will be named editor of the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION>, a spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> said Monday. <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Rubenstein </PERSON>, the spokesman, said the <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> will make an announcement Tuesday naming Ms. <LOCATION> Amsterdam </LOCATION>, 36, to the position. She will start work in about a month, he said. She will replace <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Devine </PERSON>, who is expected to leave by the end of the year, <PERSON> Rubenstein </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Devine </PERSON> stayed on after <PERSON> Rupert </PERSON> <PERSON> Murdoch </PERSON> sold the paper in March to <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kalikow </PERSON>, the real-estate developer, who made <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> O </PERSON>. Price publisher. Ms. <LOCATION> Amsterdam </LOCATION> was an editor in the Style section and the investigative unit of <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION>, and executive editor at <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION>, American Lawyer and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> magazines. She is generally credited with making a success of <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION>, inc., which was founded in 1984 as an upscale city magazine that treated top business executives as celebrities. She resigned in March 1987 after a disagreement over editorial autonomy with the owner of the magazine, <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Herbert </PERSON> <PERSON> Lipson </PERSON>. In January, she joined <PERSON> Knopf </PERSON> as a senior editor. According to the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Newspaper </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Editors </ORGANIZATION>, Ms. <LOCATION> Amsterdam </LOCATION> would become the sixth woman currently holding the position of top editor at a newspaper with a circulation of more than 100,000. The Post is the nation's oldest continually published daily newspaper.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880510-0028 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-10-88 0324EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-OtherBooks     05-10 0571</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Other Books,560</SECOND>
<HEAD>Regan Follows Critical Path of Others Who Have Left</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Regan's Reagan Bjt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
