<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880731-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-31-88 2338EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-RatermanMemorial     07-31 0211</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Raterman Memorial,0216</SECOND>
<HEAD>Slain Teen-ager Remembered In Service</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SEASIDE, Ore. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A 15-year-old girl whose disappearance in mid-June led to a search by hundreds of volunteers, was remembered at her memorial service Sunday as a precious child. Mourners filled the main hall of the Seaside Civic and Convention Center for services honoring slaying victim <PERSON> Dorene </PERSON> <PERSON> Raterman </PERSON> of <PERSON> Gearhart </PERSON>. In a prayer to God, the Rev. <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Walker </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> Seaside </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Baptist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> said, `` We need to hear from you. We need to feel your great arm of love and strength right now.'' `` You're the only one who can make sense right now out of this loss and hurt,'' he said. The teen-ager vanished June 15 after leaving her parents a note saying she was taking a bicycle ride to a beach half a mile from her home. Her remains were found July 25 in a brushy area about 16 miles east of <LOCATION> Astoria </LOCATION>, on the state's northwest coast. <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON> <PERSON> Mullins </PERSON>, 20, was charged with murder and kidnapping, and <ORGANIZATION> Tiac </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> C. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Eastman </ORGANIZATION>, 25, was charged with hindering prosecution. <PERSON> Walker </PERSON> told the memorial gathering of more than 1,000 people that <PERSON> Doreen </PERSON> was a `` precious child.'' `` Happy, friendly, loving, a joy to her parents, a blessing from God. She was Daddy's little girl.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880731-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-31-88 2350EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Britain-Rain     07-31 0238</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Britain-Rain,0246</SECOND>
<HEAD>For The Brits, The Wettest July In More Than 50 Years</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 While the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> suffered through record drought and heat, <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> slogged through its wettest July in 52 years. Soaked by downpours and chilled in sub-normal temperatures, tourists spent vacations in raincoats. Homeowners struggled to keep up with the backyard jungle growth. And rain forced the postponement of the men's tennis finals at <LOCATION> Wimbledon </LOCATION> and the last day of the British Open golf championship. <LOCATION> Scotland </LOCATION> had the worst of the downpours. Average rainfall there was the heaviest since modern records began, well over a century ago in 1869, the nation's <ORGANIZATION> Meteorological </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> said Sunday. Fort <PERSON> William </PERSON> in the Highlands had 12 inches. <LOCATION> Glasgow </LOCATION> was only half as wet, with 6 inches. <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Wales </LOCATION> had the wettest July since 1936, the office said. The mercury rose to its highest _ 77 degress _ at <LOCATION> Margate </LOCATION> at a time of year when temperatures in the 80s are not uncommon. Highest overall rainfall totals for <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> were in the central lowlands of <LOCATION> Scotland </LOCATION>, which had between 2 -LCB- and 3 times the normal July rainfall. In <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Manchester </ORGANIZATION> had 5 -LCB- inches of rain, <ORGANIZATION> Birmingham </ORGANIZATION> 4 inches, and <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> 2 -LCB- inches. In the center of the capital it had on Sunday rained, at least a bit, every day since July 18. Nationwide, average temperatures for the month were below normal everywhere, the weather department said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880731-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-31-88 2358EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-JordanHospitalized 3rdLd-Writethru a0768nge 07-31 0705</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Jordan Hospitalized, 3rd Ld-Writethru, a0768,0719</SECOND>
<HEAD>Former Lawmaker Remains Hospitalized But `Vastly Improved'</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: INSERTS 2 grafs after 3rd graf to UPDATE with condition
Sunday night; picks up 4th graf pvs `Ms. Jordan ...' CORRECTS by
deleting ``Last week'' from 13th graf pvs about Democratic
convention.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By MICHAEL HOLMES</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>AUSTIN, Texas (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Former <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Rep. <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Jordan </PERSON> was `` vastly improved'' and giving the thumbs-up sign to her hospital nurse Sunday following a near-drowning in her swimming pool. `` She's in good spirits now because she knows she's going to get well,'' said Dr. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Deaton </PERSON>, a lung specialist treating Ms. <PERSON> Jordan </PERSON>. `` She's emotional about that and a little bit teary-eyed some of the time, knowing what she's been through and how close she came to a real catastrophic event. But she still also has her jovial personality. She was joking a little bit this morning,'' <PERSON> Deaton </PERSON> said. `` She is vastly improved.'' Ms. <PERSON> Jordan </PERSON>'s condition was upgraded from critical to serious but stable, and she continued to improve Sunday night. `` She started her liquid diet tonight. She is breathing on her own. She is receiving supplemental oxygen, though,'' hospital spokeswoman <PERSON> Kari </PERSON> <PERSON> Larsen </PERSON> said. Ms. <PERSON> Jordan </PERSON>, 52, who gained national attention during the <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> impeachment hearings, was flown by emergency helicopter to <LOCATION> Brackenridge </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION> on Saturday after she was found floating face-down in her pool. <PERSON> Deaton </PERSON> said she came within `` four to five minutes, 10 minutes at most'' of suffering severe brain damage and possibly death. Ms. <PERSON> Jordan </PERSON> apparently lost consciousness while in the pool. <PERSON> Deaton </PERSON> and Dr. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Little </PERSON>, a neurologist, said it is n't known what caused her to lose consciousness, but that the lack of oxygen then caused cardiac arrest. Ms. <PERSON> Jordan </PERSON> had been in critical condition in the hospital's intensive care unit, but <PERSON> Deaton </PERSON> said Sunday afternoon that `` she's upgraded She's certainly stable, in a much less serious condition.'' Ms. <PERSON> Jordan </PERSON> was breathing without the aid of a mechanical ventilator, responding to questions and trying to make sure a Monday dental appointment was canceled. `` She obviously has pretty good mental recall if that's her biggest concern,'' <PERSON> Deaton </PERSON> said. `` Right now, I think things look very good that she'll get totally back to normal,'' <PERSON> Little </PERSON> said. `` She's very close to normal right now. I think she will continue to improve. As best as I can tell right now, she probably will regain full mental functions.'' The doctors said Ms. <PERSON> Jordan </PERSON>, who has used a wheelchair for several years, suffers from multiple sclerosis but her condition should n't have had an effect on the incident. `` She has muscle weakness and it would be difficult for her to rescue herself from the swimming pool if she had any warning of any event. ... I doubt, though, based on the suddenness of the event, that she had any warning,'' <PERSON> Deaton </PERSON> said. Little said possible causes for her losing consciousness were a sudden heartbeat irregularity or a seizure. But hospital tests showed `` her cardiac status has been very stable. She's had no evidence of seizure activity,'' he said. Ms. <PERSON> Jordan </PERSON> delivered a nominating speech for vice presidential candidate Sen. <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> at the Democratic National Convention in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> telephoned a message to Ms. <PERSON> Jordan </PERSON> on Sunday, said hospital spokeswoman <PERSON> Carolyn </PERSON> <PERSON> Hinckley </PERSON> <PERSON> Boyle </PERSON>. Visitors to the hospital have included <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> Treasurer <PERSON> Ann </PERSON> <PERSON> Richards </PERSON>, who delivered the keynote address at the convention; <PERSON> Walt </PERSON> <PERSON> Rostow </PERSON>, a former aide to President <PERSON> Lyndon </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>; <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION> women's basketball Coach <PERSON> Jody </PERSON> <PERSON> Conradt </PERSON>; plus Ms. <PERSON> Jordan </PERSON>'s two sisters and live-in companion, <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> <PERSON> Earl </PERSON>, who found Ms. <PERSON> Jordan </PERSON> in the pool. Ms. <PERSON> Jordan </PERSON> is a fan of the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ' </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lady </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Longhorns </ORGANIZATION>, and nurse <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Tucker </PERSON> said the basketball team's former star, <PERSON> Fran </PERSON> <PERSON> Harris </PERSON>, visited before leaving for the Olympic trials. `` When I remember seeing Ms. <PERSON> Jordan </PERSON> on TV, I frequently remember the thumbs-up sign that things are OK. She's probably given me that about 20 times today,'' Ms. <PERSON> Tucker </PERSON> said Ms. <PERSON> Jordan </PERSON> in 1966 became the first black state senator in <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> history. In 1972, she was the first Southern black elected to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> since Reconstruction, serving until 1978, when she left politics after three terms in the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> to teach at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880731-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-31-88 0529EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a BC-JordanHospitalized     07-31 0423</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Jordan Hospitalized,0434</SECOND>
<HEAD>Former Congresswoman Remains In Critical Condition</HEAD>
<DATELINE>AUSTIN, Texas (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Former <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Rep. <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Jordan </PERSON> remained in critical condition early Sunday after she was found floating unconscious in her swimming pool, authorities said. `` She's been awake off and on through the night, but she goes right to sleep,'' said <PERSON> Sheryln </PERSON> <PERSON> Gembol </PERSON>, a nursing supervisor at <LOCATION> Brackenridge </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION>. `` We're trying to let her rest. `` They're going to be running some more tests throughout the day today. They know it was not a heart attack or a stroke, but as far as what made her unconscious in the pool, they're not sure,'' she added. Ms. <PERSON> Jordan </PERSON>, who rose to fame during the Watergate impeachment hearings, was found in the pool about noon Saturday by a woman who lives with her. Ms. <PERSON> Jordan </PERSON>, 52, was taken to the hospital by helicopter. Paramedics `` said she had a pulse, was trying to breathe and they were able to help her breathe en route to hospital,'' said hospital spokeswoman <PERSON> Carolyn </PERSON> <PERSON> Boyle </PERSON>. At a briefing late Saturday, a doctor said Ms. <PERSON> Jordan </PERSON> was being treated for fluid in her lungs but showed no signs of heart or brain dysfunction. `` She has full recovery of her intellectual functions. Her vital signs are much better,'' Dr. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Deaton </PERSON> said. Though she remained in critical condition, `` the capital ` c' is not so big as when she got here.'' `` She has to heal her own lungs, which she will hopefully do,'' added <PERSON> Deaton </PERSON>, a lung specialist. He said Ms. <PERSON> Jordan </PERSON> apparently lost consciousness while swimming alone in the pool, for unknown reasons. A lack of oxygen then caused the cardiac arrest, he said. Ms. <PERSON> Jordan </PERSON> has had medical problems for several years and has used a wheelchair to get to her job on the faculty of the <ORGANIZATION> Lyndon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> B. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Johnson </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Affairs </ORGANIZATION> at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION>. Ms. <PERSON> Jordan </PERSON> has refused to discuss the illness, calling it `` a mobility problem'' and denying it was <PERSON> Lou </PERSON> <PERSON> Gehrig </PERSON>'s disease or bone cancer. <PERSON> Deaton </PERSON> described it as a progressive loss of `` nerve function in her lower extremities'' similar to multiple sclerosis. In 1966, Ms. <PERSON> Jordan </PERSON> became the first black state senator in <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>. In 1972, she was the first Southern black elected to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> since Reconstruction. She gained a national reputation during the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Judiciary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>'s 1974 hearings that ended with a vote to press impeachment charges against President <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON>. She stirred television audiences when she declared, `` My faith in the Constitution is whole, it is complete, it is total.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880731-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-31-88 0957EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i BC-Iran-PersianGulf     07-31 0359</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Iran-Persian Gulf,0371</SECOND>
<HEAD>Official: Iran to Stop Attacks on Shipping During Cease-Fire Talks</HEAD>
<DATELINE>DOHA, Qatar (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A senior Iranian envoy indicated that <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> would stop attacking commercial ships in the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> while his country and <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> try to negotiate a cease-fire in their 8-year-old war. The envoy, Deputy Foreign Minister <PERSON> Ali </PERSON> <PERSON> Ahmed </PERSON> <PERSON> Besharati </PERSON>, also said he expected <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> protection of Kuwaiti tankers to end soon, and that <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> is ready to use its influence for the release of foreign hostages held in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Besharati </PERSON> is on a tour of the Arab Persian Gulf nations to assure them of <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION>'s intention to abide by a <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> resolution calling for a cease-fire. He spoke to reporters in <LOCATION> Abu </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dhabi </LOCATION> on Saturday before continuing to <LOCATION> Qatar </LOCATION>. `` We will try to do our best not to violate anything ... so that resolution 598 will become a reality,'' <PERSON> Besharati </PERSON> said when asked if <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> would continue to attack neutral shipping in the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Besharati </PERSON> said now that cease-fire talks are being held at the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION>, he expected `` the <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> flag to come down from the Kuwaiti tankers soon.'' He also said he believed the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> would stop providing naval escort for Kuwaiti tankers in the gulf. The tankers have been flying the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> flag for one year to qualify for protection against Iranian attacks. Iranian and <LOCATION> Iraqi </LOCATION> representatives are holding separate talks with <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> Secretary-General <PERSON> Javier </PERSON> <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Cuellar </PERSON> in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> to arrange a cease-fire. Asked about <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> hostages in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Besharati </PERSON> said: `` So far, no Western country has negotiated the hostage issue with us. If they did so, we promise to use all our influence to release them.'' Eighteen foreigners, including nine Americans, are being held hostage by pro-Iranian extremists in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>. The longest held is <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON>, 40, chief <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> correspondent for <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>, who was kidnapped March 16, 1985. <PERSON> Hashemi </PERSON> <PERSON> Rafsanjani </PERSON>, speaker of <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION> and commander-in-chief, said last week that his country would be prepared to use its influence in efforts to free the hostages if President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> released Iranian assets frozen since 1979. The White House rejected the offer.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880731-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-31-88 1007EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i BC-Malaysia-PierCollapse 1stLd-Writethru a0676 07-31 0217</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Malaysia-Pier Collapse, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0676,0217</SECOND>
<HEAD>Pier Collapse Kills At Least 30 People</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Lead with 3 grafs to UPDATE with higher casualty figures.
Pickup 4th graf pvs, ``Fireman and...''</NOTE>
<DATELINE>KUALA LUMPUR, Malaysia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A pier holding thousands of people collapsed in northwestern <LOCATION> Malaysia </LOCATION> on Sunday, killing at least 30 people and injuring 400, official <ORGANIZATION> Radio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Television </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Malaysia </ORGANIZATION> reported. In an earlier report, the national news agency <ORGANIZATION> Bernama </ORGANIZATION> said at least 21 people died and more than 150 were injured. It was not immediately possible to reconcile the conflicting casualty figures. The people on the pier were waiting for a ferry to take them to nearby <LOCATION> Penang </LOCATION> island in the Strait of <LOCATION> Malacca </LOCATION> when the pier collapsed in <LOCATION> Butterworth </LOCATION>, 190 miles northwest of <LOCATION> Kuala </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lumpur </LOCATION>, the news agency said. Firemen and <ORGANIZATION> Penang </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Port </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> workers were clearing the debris and searching for more bodies, <ORGANIZATION> Bernama </ORGANIZATION> said. A stream of cars, motorcycles, taxis and vans carried the injured to the district hospital in <LOCATION> Butterworth </LOCATION> and private clinics in the area, the news agency said. It said people with broken hands and legs and or bleeding profusely from the head were lying along the corridors of the hospital. In <LOCATION> Kuala </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lumpur </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Malaysia </LOCATION>'s capital, Transport Minister <PERSON> Ling </PERSON> <PERSON> Liong </PERSON> <PERSON> Sik </PERSON> said an inquiry would be held into the incident.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880731-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-31-88 1108EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-BRF--Birdwatchers     07-31 0156</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Birdwatchers,0163</SECOND>
<HEAD>Royal Air Force Rescues 22 Stranded Birdwatchers</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PWLLHELI, Wales (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Royal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> rescued 22 birdwatchers who ran out of food after bad weather stranded them on a small island, officials said. Two air force helicopters picked up the group Saturday afternoon and took them to the coastal town of <LOCATION> Pwllheli </LOCATION>, according to a <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> spokesman. The birdwatchers had been stranded on Bardsey, a tiny island two miles off the northern coast of <LOCATION> Wales </LOCATION>, according to an <ORGANIZATION> LBC </ORGANIZATION> radio report. The <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> spokesman said the birdwatchers had planned to leave the island a week ago. `` Because of the sea state, the high winds, they had n't been able to get a boat across either to get them off or to supply them with food,'' <ORGANIZATION> Royal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> Lt. <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Murkin </PERSON> told the radio station. `` They'd run out of food so they were rather desperate to get back,'' <PERSON> Murkin </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880731-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-31-88 1108EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Japan-Quakes     07-31 0132</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Japan-Quakes,0139</SECOND>
<HEAD>Series Of Quakes Shake Japanese Coastline</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A series of undersea earthquakes Sunday shook the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> coastline of the <LOCATION> Izu </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Peninsula </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Meteorological </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> said. Officials reported no damage or injuries from the quakes, which measured up to 5.4 on the <PERSON> Richter </PERSON> scale. A total of 73 quakes shook <LOCATION> Izu </LOCATION> since Tuesday, with at least 64 recorded on Sunday morning, according to the agency. The strongest one, which occurred Sunday at 8:40 a.m. near the <LOCATION> Izu </LOCATION> coastal town of <LOCATION> Ajiro </LOCATION>, was felt in <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION> 60 miles to the southwest. In 1978, an earthquake measuring 7 on <PERSON> Richter </PERSON> scale shook the Isu area and killed 27 people. The Richter scale measures the magnitude of a quake at its epicenter, according to ground motion as recorded on seismographs.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880731-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-31-88 1109EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Italy-Bombs     07-31 0276</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Italy-Bombs,0284</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bombs Explode In Street, Power Plant; One Injured</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BOLZANO, Italy (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Three bombs exploded Sunday in the northern province of <LOCATION> Alto </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Adige </LOCATION>, injuring one person and damaging about 30 cars, police said. Authorities blamed the blasts on German-speaking extremists seeking autonomy for the province. Thirteen bombs attributed to the extremists have gone off since March, but none have caused deaths or serious injuries. Police said one bomb exploded in a garbage bin in the city of <LOCATION> Bolzano </LOCATION> at about 4:30 a.m., injuring a 65-year-old man who was cut by flying glass. Windows and cars were also damaged, they said. At about the same time, two bombs exploded at a hydroelectric plant in <LOCATION> Ponte </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gardena </LOCATION>, about 10 miles north of <LOCATION> Bolzano </LOCATION>. One of the plant's three power transformers was heavily damaged by one explosion and a resulting fire, police said. State-owned RAI television said about $ 750,000 in damage was done to the plant owned by <PERSON> Selm </PERSON>, a subsidiary of the chemical company <ORGANIZATION> Montedison </ORGANIZATION>. A second bomb exploded in a field about 100 yards from the houses of eight Italian-speaking plant workers, but caused no serious damage. On the plant's gates, investigators found an envelope on which was scrawled in German `` <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tyrol </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Combat </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Group </ORGANIZATION>,'' a name left at other bomb sites. German inhabitants refer to the province as <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Tyrol </LOCATION>. The Alto Adige province was stripped from <LOCATION> Austria </LOCATION> after World War I. The 300,000 ethnic German-speakers are a majority and have demanded priority in government jobs and more control over local broadcasting. Extremists want an independent Tyrolian state. After a terrorism campaign in the 1960s, the Italian government made the province officially bilingual.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880731-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-31-88 1109EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Poland-Labor     07-31 0234</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Poland-Labor,0242</SECOND>
<HEAD>Miners Press Management To Respect Labor Laws</HEAD>
<HEAD>With AM-Poland-Shipyard, Bjt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WARSAW, Poland (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An independent mining commission threatened to call a strike at a copper mine in southwestern <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> if management does not improve safety conditions by Aug. 15, an opposition spokesman said Sunday. `` Working conditions there are disastrous,'' said <PERSON> Marek </PERSON> <PERSON> Jakubiec </PERSON>, a member of Solidarity's <ORGANIZATION> Law </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Observance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Jakubiec </PERSON> said that men are working in noxious conditions and are entitled to special bonuses, but he said the company wo n't pay them more because it would bankrupt the mine. The mine is in the town of <LOCATION> Rudna </LOCATION>. The commission was created July 20 to force management to adhere to promises made May 3 during a strike at the mine. <PERSON> Jakubiec </PERSON> said a recent study showed that temperatures in the mine reach 97 degrees, while official industry rules say work should not proceed at temperatures exceeding 82 degrees. The mine has 6,000 workers. Meanwhile, in the port city of <LOCATION> Gdansk </LOCATION>, church and opposition sources said several hundred people gathered in front of <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Brygida </ORGANIZATION>'s church and marched to the nearby train station in support of the banned Solidarity trade union federation. `` There is no freedom without Solidarity,'' and `` We want <PERSON> Lech </PERSON>,'' they shouted, referring to Solidarity leader <PERSON> Lech </PERSON> <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON>. Police watched but did not intervene, and the crowd dispersed quietly at the railway station. There were no immediate reports of arrests.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880731-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-31-88 1109EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-BRF--BusCrash     07-31 0074</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Bus Crash,0075</SECOND>
<HEAD>At Least Eight Killed In Bus Accident</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TARRAGONA, Spain (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A passenger bus overturned in northeastern <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION> Sunday, killing at least eight people, police said. The bus overturned near <LOCATION> Vendrell </LOCATION>, a town about 30 miles east of this northeastern city, police said. They said they did not know how many passengers were on board, but they included several children. The cause of the accident was not determined, police said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880731-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-31-88 1109EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-BRF--Bangladesh-Capsize     07-31 0087</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Bangladesh-Capsize,0091</SECOND>
<HEAD>Eight Die When Boat Capsizes</HEAD>
<DATELINE>DHAKA, Bangladesh (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A small ferry capsized in rough weather on the <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Padma </LOCATION> near <LOCATION> Dhaka </LOCATION>, killing eight people, police said Sunday. The boat, which was overburdened with 40 passengers, sank in a storm Friday night, police said. Eight bodies were recovered, and the other passengers and crew were believed to have arrived safely to shore, police said. They said the boat was carrying traders from the market in the town of <LOCATION> Manikganj </LOCATION> to villages along the river.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880731-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-31-88 1109EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Economy-Stats     07-31 0117</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Economy-Stats,0126</SECOND>
<HEAD>List of Week's Economic Statistics</HEAD>
<HEAD>With AM-Inflation Fears, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the economic numbers announced last week: GNP: Increased at an annual rate of 3.1 percent in the second quarter. INFLATION: A 4.7 percent annual rate in the second quarter. CONSUMER SPENDING: Rose 1.0 percent to $ 3.21 trillion in June. PERSONAL INCOME: Rose 0.7 percent, or $ 27.9 billion, to $ 4.04 trillion in June. PERSONAL SAVINGS RATE: Fell 0.1 percent to 4.3 percent in June. IMPORT PRICES: Rose 2.7 percent in the second quarter. WAGE INCREASES: Averaged 2.2 percent a year during the first half of 1988. FACTORY ORDERS: Up 8.8 percent, or $ 10.14 billion, to $ 125.23 billion in June.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880731-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-31-88 1110EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Soviet-CreditCards     07-31 0270</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Soviet-Credit Cards,0277</SECOND>
<HEAD>Soviet Official First Holder of VISA Card Issued in USSR</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SAN FRANCISCO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The first VISA and <ORGANIZATION> MasterCard </ORGANIZATION> credit cards ever issued by <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> banks have gone to the head of the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Olympic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> and a <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> banking executive. The first VISA card, called `` SovCard,'' was issued Friday to <PERSON> Yuri </PERSON> <PERSON> Titov </PERSON> by <ORGANIZATION> VAO </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Intourist </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>, which is responsible in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> for foreign travel, said <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Brigham </PERSON>, a spokesman for <ORGANIZATION> Visa </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Titov </PERSON> said in a prepared statement released by VISA that he has declared VISA the `` official credit card'' of the 1988 Soviet Olympic Team. An Intourist spokesman predicted that SovCards soon will be avilable to the general Soviet population. On Saturday, <ORGANIZATION> MasterCard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> issued a Eurocard-MasterCard in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> to <PERSON> Yu </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Moskovsky </PERSON>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> USSR </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Affairs </ORGANIZATION>, known as <ORGANIZATION> Vnesheconombank </ORGANIZATION>, said <ORGANIZATION> MasterCard </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> <PERSON> Pulchin </PERSON> in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>. A 75-second MasterCard commercial is scheduled to air Monday during the popular Soviet news program Vremya, <PERSON> Pulchin </PERSON> said. The so-called `` Gold Card'' eventually will be widely available in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, he said. The credit limits of the cards and other policies governing their use were not immediately available. The government agency Intourist joined Visa as a card-issuing member in January. It issued the card through <PERSON> Sberegatelnybank </PERSON>, a Soviet bank with sole responsibility for consumer banking, <ORGANIZATION> Brigham </ORGANIZATION> said. <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> Misko </PERSON>, director of Intourist's credit card program, said in the statement, that he is working with <ORGANIZATION> Okobank </ORGANIZATION>, the Finnish cooperative bank, to `` establish the systems necessary for our Visa card to be accepted worldwide.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880731-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-31-88 1110EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-BRF--Contest-Kittens     07-31 0184</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Contest-Kittens,0189</SECOND>
<HEAD>Contest Involving Kittens Draws Protests From Humane Society</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SELMA, Ala. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Complaints from the humane society prompted a radio station to change the rules in a scavenger hunt in which contestants were to bring in kittens as a tie-breaker for the $ 1,000 prize. Participants deadlocked at the end of the regular contest would have received one point for every kitten they took to a shopping mall. <PERSON> Rhonda </PERSON> <PERSON> Poe </PERSON>, who operates the <ORGANIZATION> Selma </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Humane </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION>, said she was concerned for the safety of any kitten being used in the contest. `` We've been getting calls all day from people who want kittens, but we're afraid they only want them to win some money and will get rid of them when the contest is over,'' she said. <PERSON> Ed </PERSON> <PERSON> Davies </PERSON>, operations manager at WTUN-FM, said using kittens as a tie-breaker `` seemed like a cute idea.'' But the station decided against it `` after being told they might not be treated properly.'' Instead of collecting kittens, <PERSON> Davies </PERSON> said the names of two contestants with the same number of points were drawn Saturday to decide the winner.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880731-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-31-88 1110EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Robber'sEar     07-31 0202</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Robber's Ear,0206</SECOND>
<HEAD>Would-Be Robber Has Ear Bitten Off In Robbery Attempt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>OLATHE, Kan. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 One of two men accused of trying to rob a couple in their apartment had his ear bitten off in a struggle that followed the foiled robbery, police said. Two men on Saturday knocked on the door of the apartment shared by <PERSON> Columbus </PERSON> <PERSON> Neal </PERSON> and <PERSON> Nikki </PERSON> <PERSON> Hernandez </PERSON>, forced their way in and demanded money, said Lt. <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Galbrecht </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Olathe </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>. One intruder was armed with a knife and the other with a shotgun, <PERSON> Galbrecht </PERSON> said. While the would-be robbers were inside, <PERSON> Neal </PERSON>'s brother, <PERSON> Kendall </PERSON> <PERSON> Neal </PERSON>, and another friend arrived at the apartment to visit. When the two guests heard a commotion inside the apartment, they burst in and attacked the intruders, <PERSON> Galbrecht </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Columbus </PERSON> <PERSON> Neal </PERSON> joined the struggle and bit off the right ear of one of the intruders before the men fled, <PERSON> Galbrecht </PERSON> said. The 34-year-old man was arrested when he went to an <LOCATION> Olathe </LOCATION> hospital to seek treatment. <PERSON> Galbrecht </PERSON> said a police officer took the severed ear to the hospital, where it was sewn back on. A 25-year-old suspect also was arrested near the apartment complex about the same time.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880731-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-31-88 1111EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-WheelchairProtest     07-31 0224</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Wheelchair Protest,0230</SECOND>
<HEAD>Activists Demonstrate Outside Theater Screening `Monkey Shines'</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A dozen wheelchair users demonstrated outside a <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION> theater screening a new horror film, `` Monkey Shines,'' which the activists claim portrays the disabled as bitter, evil murderers. `` We're tired of the wheelchair school of horror in <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION>,'' said <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Bolte </PERSON>, founder of ADAPT-Cal, a disabled rights group that organized the protest Saturday. `` It was filled with inaccuracies and out-and-out lies about handicapped people,'' said <PERSON> Bolte </PERSON>, 57, a quadriplegic who was afflicted with polio as a child and has been in a wheelchair for the last 12 years. `` Monkey Shines,'' an <ORGANIZATION> Orion </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pictures </ORGANIZATION> production which opened Friday, is about a quadriplegic who uses a monkey trained to help severely disabled people to murder his ex-girlfriend, his doctor, his mother, his best friend and his nurse. `` The central insult is that it's another picture showing disabled people as `` bitter, angry cripples and murderers,'' <PERSON> Bolte </PERSON> said. Twelve protestors in wheelchairs carried signs and demonstrated for three hours in front of the <ORGANIZATION> Hollywood </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pacific </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Theater </ORGANIZATION>, trying to persuade moviegoers to boycott the film. One of the hand-made signs read: `` What next Orion: Attack of the killer seeing-eye dogs!'' `` I really did n't pay attention to them,'' said <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Fernandez </PERSON>, assistant manager of the theater. `` They talked to some patrons but they did n't disturb them.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880731-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-31-88 1112EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Economy-Glance     07-31 0505</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Economy-Glance,0546</SECOND>
<HEAD>Summary of Week's Economic Indicators</HEAD>
<HEAD>With AM-Inflation Fears, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 The economic news last week was mostly positive. But the word on inflation was worrying to many. Here is a brief recap:
</TEXT>
<HEAD>GNP</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 In the second quarter, the gross national product expanded at a 3.1 percent annual pace, down slightly from a revised 3.4 percent in the first three months of the year.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>INFLATION</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Inflation, as measured by a price index tied to the GNP, climbed at a 4.7 percent annual pace in the second quarter, the biggest advance since 1982. The index rose at a 3.5 percent rate in the first quarter.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>CONSUMER SPENDING</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Consumer spending in June rose a seasonally adjusted 1.0 percent to $ 3.21 trillion, following a 0.6 percent increase in May. It was the biggest increase since spending shot up 1.3 percent last August.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>PERSONAL INCOME AND SAVINGS</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Americans' personal income jumped 0.7 percent in June, the best showing in three months. The $ 27.9 billion increase to $ 4.04 trillion followed a 0.5 percent rise in May. The personal savings rate fell to 4.3 percent, compared with 4.4 percent in May. The average savings rate for the first half of 1988, 4.1 percent, is up substantially from 3.2 percent in 1987.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>IMPORT PRICES</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Import prices rose 2.7 percent in the April-June quarter, the biggest increase in more than a year. The climb followed a 1.2 percent increase in the January-March period and was the steepest since the 4.1 percent jump in the first three months of 1987.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>WAGE INCREASES</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Major collective bargaining settlements in private industry during the first six months of this year provided for wage increases averaging 2.2 percent a year. This was a slight decline from the 2.9 percent average wage increases in the contracts when they were negotiated two to three years ago.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>FACTORY ORDERS</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Factory orders for durable goods advanced 8.8 percent in June, their fastest pace in 30 months. Orders totaled $ 125.23 billion, $ 10.14 billion higher than the May total. The June increase, which followed a 1.9 percent decline in May, was the biggest advance since an 8.9 percent jump in December 1985.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>FOREIGN INVESTMENT</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Foreign investment in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has jumped by more than 215 percent since 1980, while American investment abroad increased by only one-fifth that rate, said a study by the <ORGANIZATION> Congressional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Leadership </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION>. The study said the pace is expected to accelerate, with foreign buyouts in 1988 expected to make up as much as 20 percent of all <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> acquisitions, up from 5 percent in 1987. But the report said foreign investments still account for only 5 percent to 6 percent of total <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> assets.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>STOCK MARKET</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 The Dow Jones average of 30 industrials climbed 67.74 points during the week, finishing with a 46.40-point rise Friday. Analysts attributed the advance to fresh strength in the dollar and favorable reaction to indications by Chairman <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Greenspan </PERSON> that the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reserve </ORGANIZATION> has not changed credit policy recently.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880731-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-31-88 1116EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-CarterSpot     07-31 0241</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Carter Spot,0247</SECOND>
<HEAD>TV Station Inadvertantly Runs Part Of Old Carter Ad</HEAD>
<DATELINE>AKRON, Ohio (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Dozens of puzzled television viewers called a newspaper after seeing 15 seconds of a commercial spot from <PERSON> Jimmy </PERSON> <PERSON> Carter </PERSON>'s 1976 presidential campaign during the `` Wheel of Fortune.'' `` It was there as plain as the nose on your face,'' said <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Estep </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Akron </LOCATION>. `` <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> was standing in front of his house in <LOCATION> Plains </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ga. </LOCATION>, and there was a 1976 copyright -LRB- on the tape -RRB-.'' The Carter spot aired at 7:20 p.m. Wednesday over station <ORGANIZATION> WEWS </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Cleveland </LOCATION> during a broadcast of the popular game show, a secretary at the station said Friday. The <ORGANIZATION> Akron </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Beacon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Journal </ORGANIZATION> reported that dozens of viewers called the newspaper saying they had seen the ad. <PERSON> Dorothy </PERSON> <PERSON> Fay </PERSON> of <PERSON> Stow </PERSON> said she and her daughter, <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Banks </PERSON>, had just returned from grocery shopping when they saw the spot. `` My daughter had bought a couple of lottery tickets, so we turned on the TV to catch the lottery numbers and there it -LRB- the Carter commercial -RRB- was. My daughter said, ` What's going on here? Is he going to run again?''' A secretary for WEWS Programming Director <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Stark </PERSON>, whom the <ORGANIZATION> Beacon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Journal </ORGANIZATION> did not identify, told the newspaper that another commercial had been taped over the Carter commercial. `` It -LRB- the Carter commercial -RRB- was supposed to have been erased,'' she said. But the final 15-second segment of the <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> spot was accidentally left intact.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880731-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-31-88 1118EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-India-Disease     07-31 0157</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-India-Disease,0163</SECOND>
<HEAD>11 More People Die In Cholera Epidemic</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW DELHI, India (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Eleven more people died Sunday from diseases blamed on flooding in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Delhi </LOCATION>, health authorities said. The deaths brought to 212 the number of residents killed by cholera and gastroenteritis in the Indian capital since the beginning of July, when heavy monsoon rains hit <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Delhi </LOCATION>. Officials blamed the diseases on flood waters that have washed through sewage and uncollected garbage and infiltrated drinking water. Hospitals admitted at least 231 people suffering from the diseases Sunday, including 38 people with cholera, raising to 624 the number of reported cholera cases in this city of 8 million, health officials said. More than 16,000 patients have sought treatment for the two diseases in July, according to official figures. The areas hardest-hit by the epidemic are slums, where garbage has not been collected for months because of a dispute over which municipal agencies are responsible.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880731-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-31-88 1122EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-France-Explosion     07-31 0301</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-France-Explosion,0311</SECOND>
<HEAD>Explosion Destroys Offices of Leftist Monthly</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PARIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An explosion and fire apparently caused by a bomb Sunday destroyed the offices of the left-leaning monthly <ORGANIZATION> Globe </ORGANIZATION>, and a firefighter was injured, police said. The exact cause of the blast in the central Opera district of the capital was not expected to be revealed until Monday, but employees of the magazine and the French TV station TF1 said it was a bomb. No one claimed responsibility for the blast. <PERSON> Georges-Marc </PERSON> <PERSON> Benamou </PERSON>, director of the magazine, said that `` for the past 2 -LCB- years, we've received threats from racist organizations.'' Police said the explosion occurred at 3:30 a.m. in the second-floor offices of the Globe. No one was in the offices at the time. About 30 people were evacuated as the fire began spreading to apartments in the seven-story building, and a firefighter was injured, police said. The firefighter's condition was not immediately known. `` The door was forced open, a bomb was place in the newsroom, the doors and windows were blown out,'' an unidentified <ORGANIZATION> Globe </ORGANIZATION> employee was quoted as saying by Agence France-Presse, the French news agency. `` All the archives, the new layout, were destroyed.'' In a telegram to <ORGANIZATION> Globe </ORGANIZATION> employees, Culture and Communications Minister <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Lang </PERSON> called the blast an `` act of barbarism and hate.'' `` Liberty of expression ... will be firmly protected by the government,'' the telegram said. The slick Parisian magazine, which started publication in November 1985, says it is geared to 20 - to 40-year-olds who like both `` glamour'' and politics It is known for its pro-Israeli sympathies. During presidential elections in May, the magazine contributed to the spectacular rise in popularity of Socialist President <PERSON> Francois </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitterrand </PERSON> with a glowing issue devoted to the chief of state. <PERSON> Mitterrand </PERSON> was re-elected to a seven-year term May 8.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880731-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-31-88 1156EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p AM-People-Clinton     07-31 0296</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-People-Clinton,0306</SECOND>
<HEAD>From Doghouse To White House?</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LITTLE ROCK, Ark. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Arkansas </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Clinton </PERSON> has gone from the media doghouse to media darling in one short week. And all it took was a smile, a few self-deprecating jokes and a song. <PERSON> Clinton </PERSON>, panned for a Democratic convention speech that seemed like the last word in boredom when he nominated <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> for president, has apparently made a comeback with his appearance Thursday with <PERSON> Johnny </PERSON> <PERSON> Carson </PERSON> on `` The Tonight Show.'' <ORGANIZATION> Cable </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Network </ORGANIZATION> on Friday cited the governor for the `` fastest turnaround ever'' on its weekly `` Winners and Losers.'' <PERSON> Clinton </PERSON>, considered a rising political star, had been the big loser the previous week for his July 20 speech. `` <PERSON> Clinton </PERSON> proved that being a good sport is the first step to political rehabilitation,'' said <PERSON> Frederick </PERSON> <PERSON> Allen </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> CNN </ORGANIZATION> political analyst. <PERSON> Clinton </PERSON> traded quips with <PERSON> Carson </PERSON> and confided that his 35-minute nomination speech, which was interrupted by chants and less polite suggestions that he stop, was actually designed to make <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> look good. He also took a turn on the saxophone, doing a passable rendition of `` Summertime'' with <PERSON> Doc </PERSON> <PERSON> Severinson </PERSON> and the NBC Orchestra. `` People who watch television love this kind of comeback story. He was so boyish and charming. I'm sure he won a lot of hearts,'' said <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Shales </PERSON>, syndicated television critic for <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION>. E.J. <PERSON> Dionne </PERSON>, national political writer for <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION>, said, `` It may well be that <PERSON> Clinton </PERSON> had a bigger audience on <PERSON> Johnny </PERSON> <PERSON> Carson </PERSON> than he had at the convention.'' Not everybody was watching, though. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> missed the broadcast, but <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Gearan </PERSON>, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' press secretary, said he did get favorable reports. `` It came as no surprise to him that Gov. <PERSON> Clinton </PERSON> went out of the ballpark,'' <PERSON> Gearan </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880731-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-31-88 1200EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-People     07-31 0824</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-People,0856</SECOND>
<HEAD>People in the News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY44</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PORTLAND, Ore. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Trust a Knievel to want to jump just a little farther. <PERSON> Robbie </PERSON> <PERSON> Knievel </PERSON>, son of stunt legend <PERSON> Evel </PERSON> <PERSON> Knievel </PERSON>, sailed over 22 cars on his motorcycle, let go of the handlebars for a blink and landed more than halfway down a 100-foot ramp. By his own estimate, it was about a 26-car sail. `` My gap here was about 140 feet,'' <PERSON> Knievel </PERSON> said after the jump Saturday at <ORGANIZATION> Portland </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Raceway </ORGANIZATION>. `` I might have gone about 170 feet. Actually, I wanted to clear the whole ramp.'' Knievel teased the crowd with three practice passes at the takeoff ramp, climbed it once slowly for a last look, then retreated. After a pause for effect, he gunned his dirt bike for the takeoff. <PERSON> Knievel </PERSON> guessed that he was going about 75 mph when he hit the ramp. `` Usually you know about halfway across whether you're going to make it or not, and about then I knew I was going to be all right,'' he said. `` But I thought I was getting back too far, and I did n't want to flip over. That's why I only let go for a little bit.'' <PERSON> Evel </PERSON> <PERSON> Knievel </PERSON>, who suffered a total of 35 broken bones during his daredevil career, said he had never cleared more than 21 cars during his career. He says his son is a far better jumper than he ever was. `` It felt really good,'' <PERSON> Robbie </PERSON> <PERSON> Knievel </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WARWICK, R.I. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Willie </PERSON> <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON>, picketed by police because of a benefit concert he gave for a man convicted of killing two <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> agents, has agreed to give a benefit for both American Indian and police causes. The country music star's concert Friday was picketed by more than 400 <LOCATION> Rhode </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> police and their supporters, but there were no picket lines at Saturday's show after <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON> made his announcement. Police had charged that <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON> supports `` cop killers'' because of a benefit last year for <PERSON> Leonard </PERSON> <PERSON> Peltier </PERSON>, an Indian serving two life sentences for killing two <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> agents in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION> in 1975. `` For many years, there's been hard feelings'' between Indians and police, <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON> said. `` If this is the first way to ease hard feelings, then I'm happy to be a part of it.'' `` By this agreement, he's sending a message to every law enforcement officer,'' <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Patterson </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> Providence </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fraternal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Order </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Poice </ORGANIZATION>, said Saturday. The joint benefit will be held Aug. 23 in <LOCATION> Springfield </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mass. </LOCATION>, with proceeds going to the American Indian Relief Fund and the National Police Memorial Fund.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>RICHMOND, Va. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The only sign marking the office at the <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. Courthouse here is a room number scratched in black pen above a door frame. Inside, there are no plaques, no citations, no personal photographs of a man once described as a more powerful influence on the law than President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> or Chief Justice <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Rehnquist </PERSON>. `` Very few people find me over here, which I regard as a plus,'' says <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Powell </PERSON>, who retired from the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> one year ago. <PERSON> Powell </PERSON> was often seen during the 1980s as the justice who kept the court from drifting too far left or right. But he takes a modest view of his role. `` If I got into a footnote, I'd be surprised,'' <PERSON> Powell </PERSON> said. Although he cited age and declining health when he retired, he's maintaining a full schedule `` His idea of retirement is to stop working at 4 o'clock on Saturday afternoon,'' said <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Merhige </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> district judge and longtime friend. Since he `` retired,'' <PERSON> Powell </PERSON> has sat with appellate court panels, taught at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Virginia </ORGANIZATION> and delivered commencement addresses at <ORGANIZATION> George </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mason </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> and <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Lee </PERSON>. <PERSON> Powell </PERSON>, 80, said he has had no regrets about retirement. He and his wife, <PERSON> Josephine </PERSON>, have four children and seven grandchildren. `` When you reach my ancient age, family is far more important than any of the less personal things that happen to one over a long lifetime,'' he said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>MIAMI (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Comedian <PERSON> Jackie </PERSON> <PERSON> Mason </PERSON> has asked a state appellate court to throw out a ruling that he is the father of a 2 -LCB- - year-old girl from north <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> Attorney <PERSON> Gerald </PERSON> <PERSON> Mager </PERSON> questioned the validity of the blood test on which the paternity ruling was based, telling the <ORGANIZATION> 3rd </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appeal </ORGANIZATION> on Friday that the test could not prove positively that he was the father. A judge decided in April that <PERSON> Mason </PERSON>, star of `` Caddyshack II,'' is the father of <PERSON> Ginger </PERSON> <PERSON> Reiter </PERSON>'s daughter. The judge said the child `` looks like'' <PERSON> Mason </PERSON> and said other evidence and testimony made it evident that he is the father. A blood test showed <PERSON> Mason </PERSON>'s probability of being the father was 99.94 percent, according to court records. The judge ordered <PERSON> Mason </PERSON> to pay child support of $ 1,500-a-month. The appeals court gave no indication when it would rule.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880731-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-31-88 1205EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-India-LordRama     07-31 0257</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-India-Lord Rama,0262</SECOND>
<HEAD>Lord Rama Returning to Television</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW DELHI, India (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>'s most popular television program, the serialization of a Hindu epic that was canceled despite protests and strikes by viewers, will return to the air, the government said Sunday. The announcement was made on government television just after what was to have been the 78th and final episode of the serial `` Ramayana.'' No date for broadcasting further programs was given in the announcement. The show's producer, <PERSON> Ramanand </PERSON> <PERSON> Sagar </PERSON>, told <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Trust </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> India </ORGANIZATION> that it would take until at least November to tape more episodes. About 100 million of <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>'s 800 million people watched the half-hour show each Sunday, many on communal sets in small villages. The 2,600-year-old epic tells the story of the warrior-king <PERSON> Rama </PERSON>, an incarnation of a major Hindu god, <PERSON> Vishnu </PERSON>. In Sunday's program, he returned to be crowned king after 14 years in exile However, the traditional story goes on to tell of the banishment of <PERSON> Rama </PERSON>'s wife, <PERSON> Sita </PERSON>, the birth of her twins <PERSON> Luv </PERSON> and Kush, and her being swallowed up by <LOCATION> Earth </LOCATION> as the youngsters are reunited with <PERSON> Rama </PERSON>. The program was orignally scheduled to run for 52 weeks, but it was extended to 78 weeks because of protests from people who did not want it to end. In Hindu-dominated <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>, garbage collectors went on strike in three cities to demand the show go on to tell the rest of the epic. One union filed suit, claiming <PERSON> Rama </PERSON> was not properly characterized in the shorter version.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880731-0025 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-31-88 1226EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w AM-InflationFears Bjt   07-31 0807</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Inflation Fears, Bjt,770</SECOND>
<HEAD>Some Economists Believe High Inflation Poised for Return</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserGraphic NY11</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARTIN CRUTSINGER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 New government statistics have revived the debate over whether the evil inflation monster, which terrorized <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> during the 1970s, is starting to awaken after having slept for most of this decade. The <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration, mindful of how voters' perceptions will affect the presidential race, insists there are no signs that inflation is becoming a problem. But many private economists disagree. These economists contend that the 68-month economic expansion, now the second longest of the post-World War II period, has used up all of the economy's slack capacity. Tight labor markets and high factory operating rates are beginning to be translated into accelerating wage demands and higher prices, they believe. Proponents of this theory received more ammunition last week with two new government reports, one on wage increases and the other on overall economic growth and inflation. The wage report showed that compensation for American workers, wages and fringe benefits such as health insurance and pensions, was rising this year at the highest rate since the summer of 1985. Wages and benefits, which represent about two-thirds of all business costs, climbed by 4.5 percent in the 12-month period ending in June, compared with an increase of just 3 percent in the prior 12 months. In a second report, the government said an inflation index tied to the gross national product shot up at an annual rate of 4.7 percent from April through June, the fastest pace in almost six years. The big jump in prices was blamed on higher consumer costs for food, clothing and energy. To the administration, these reports were not cause for concern. <PERSON> Beryl </PERSON> <PERSON> Sprinkel </PERSON>, the president's chief economic adviser, blamed the inflation spurt on temporary factors, including the drought and higher import costs because of the weaker dollar. He insisted that there was no evidence that the economy was being overtaken by a new wage-price spiral. `` We remain convinced that inflation will continue under restraint,'' he told reporters during a briefing. Some private economists agree, contending that inflationary pressures from the drought and tight labor markets are being offset by weakness in oil prices and a rebound in the dollar, which reduces the costs of imports. They note that the consumer price index, after registering big jumps in the early spring, calmed down in May and June only 0.3 percent. During the first six months of the year, consumer prices rose 4.4 percent, identical to the inflation rate for all of 1987. `` I do n't think we are seeing signs of higher inflation ahead,'' said <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Evans </PERSON>, head of a <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> consulting firm. `` The rise in energy and clothing prices in the spring has since been reversed.'' But this view is disputed by other private analysts, who argue that inflation has once again become a threat for the first time since the early 1980s, when the fight to reduce double-digit inflation rates led to the steep 1981-82 recession. `` The pickup in inflation is worrisome and is likely to continue through the end of the year, raising the possibility of a slowdown in growth in 1989,'' said <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Jasinowski </PERSON>, chief economist of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Manufacturers </ORGANIZATION>. Other analysts raise the possibility of an outright recession beginning next year. The <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reserve </ORGANIZATION> since March has been taking a series of steps to push interest rates higher in an effort to ease inflationary pressures by dampening demand. While this is the classic recipe for starting a recession, <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reserve </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Greenspan </PERSON> has maintained that a downturn can be avoided if the central bank acts quickly at the first sign of inflation, when the amount of credit restraint needed is still small. But <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Wyss </PERSON>, an economist with <ORGANIZATION> Data </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Resources </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, said the <ORGANIZATION> Fed </ORGANIZATION> may have already waited too long. `` The pattern is that the <ORGANIZATION> Fed </ORGANIZATION> always waits too long to act, then it clamps down too hard and causes a recession,'' he said. <PERSON> Wyss </PERSON> said the <ORGANIZATION> Fed </ORGANIZATION> has been hesitant about moving too quickly because this is a presidential election year and big interest-rate boosts would not be viewed favorably by the administration in its efforts to keep the White House in Republican hands. As a result, <PERSON> Wyss </PERSON> predicted that consumer prices would rise at around 5.5 percent annual rate next year, which would be the fastest inflation clip since an 8.9 percent rise in 1981. <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Sinai </PERSON>, chief economist of the <ORGANIZATION> Boston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, said one of the problems is that demand pressures are outstripping the country's ability to produce the goods and services `` We are starting to see a situation where we have too many dollars chasing too few goods,'' he said. `` Once the economy runs out of slack, we often get a credit crunch, which ultimately leads to a recession.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880731-0026 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-31-88 1236EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-AIDS-Shuttle Bjt   07-31 0407</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-AIDS-Shuttle, Bjt,0419</SECOND>
<HEAD>Researchers Preparing AIDS Experiment That May Fly On Shuttle</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LAURA TOLLEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SPACE CENTER, Houston (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Astronauts on the first post-Challenger shuttle flight may grow crystals of a protein taken from the AIDS virus in an experiment researchers hope will lead to drugs to fight the fatal disease. The protein, reverse transcriptase, is an enzyme the AIDS virus uses to replicate its genetic material in order to reproduce and spread through the body, said Dr. <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Bugg </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Alabama-Birmingham </ORGANIZATION> researcher. `` AIDS would never infect human cells without using this enzyme,'' said <PERSON> Bugg </PERSON>, coordinator for <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> of protein experiments that are to be conducted aboard Discovery. The shuttle is scheduled to fly later this year. Researchers want to grow the crystals of reverse transcriptase to decipher its structure. Crystals grown in space are not distorted by gravity while they form. Scientists hope to learn how the AIDS virus takes over the genetic machinery inside a cell and use that knowledge to develop a drug to conquer AIDS. Dr. <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Krenitsky </PERSON> at <ORGANIZATION> Burroughs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wellcome </ORGANIZATION> in Research Triangle Park, <LOCATION> N.C. </LOCATION>, developed the experiment. <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> is making sure it meets safety guidelines. `` We want to make sure there is no danger of infection to the crew with just this protein,'' <PERSON> Bugg </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Ball </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> spokesman in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, said the review would take several weeks. <PERSON> Krenitsky </PERSON> predicted that if the shuttle is launched in September and the experiment works well, researchers could have a model of the protein's structure by the end of the year. But he cautioned it could take 10 years to make a new AIDS drug. `` It's still very much an experimental program, but one that we feel is full of promise,'' he said. Discovery is in the middle of a simulated countdown leading up to a crucial test-firing of its main engines to test modifications. The countdown was interrupted Friday because of problems with ground fueling equipment, and the firing was postponed from Monday until Thursday. <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> officials so far have found no evidence to suggest the experiment could infect any of the astronauts with AIDS. <PERSON> Krenitsky </PERSON> said Thursday that it even if the protein somehow got into an astronaut's bloodstream it would not infect him. `` First of all, you only have one of 20 to 30 proteins the virus needs to be a viable organism,'' <PERSON> Krenitsky </PERSON> said. `` It's such a small piece, it's not workable.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880731-0027 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-31-88 1258EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p AM-ChildCare Bjt   07-31 0909</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Child Care, Bjt,870</SECOND>
<HEAD>Child Care Moving to Center Stage in Political Debate</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JILL LAWRENCE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Behind the arguments about various child-care proposals, the real winners are working mothers whose problems are getting unprecedented attention on the presidential campaign trail and on <LOCATION> Capitol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION>. Although there's no certainty that <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> will enact such legislation this year, given the little time left on the election-year legislative calendar, both Democrat <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> and Republican <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> have latched onto the issue. Passage of legislation more comprehensive than the current patchwork of federal child-care policies, therefore, seems inevitable. <PERSON> Helen </PERSON> <PERSON> Blank </PERSON>, director of child care at the Children's Defense Fund, says she could n't be more pleased. `` The landscape is changing, both demographically and politically,'' she said. `` Families need child care. They've waited a long time to turn any attention to this issue. Clearly both candidates have an interest ... and both candidates understand -LRB- the need for -RRB- new, significant resources.'' In fact, both <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> visited day-care centers last week. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, the Democratic presidential nominee, and <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, his certain Republican opponent, favor rival child-care approaches, so the issue is sure to remain in public view as the general election campaign unfolds. The day-care visits seemed tacit recognition by the two men of a new American social norm documented recently by the <ORGANIZATION> Census </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION>: More than half of new mothers go back to work before their children are a year old. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> is proposing a $ 2.2 billion program of tax credits for working parents, while <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> is backing a $ 2.5 billion child-care bill in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. The obvious concern displayed by <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, plus the surprisingly high dollar commitment in <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s proposal, are fueling optimism that a comprehensive child-care bill may be enacted this year. `` Apparently we're not arguing money anymore,'' an ebullient Sen. <PERSON> Christopher </PERSON> <PERSON> Dodd </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Conn </LOCATION>., said after <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> made his proposal `` We're all agreed we've got to do something about child care. We're all agreed that it's going to cost a lot of money,'' <PERSON> Dodd </PERSON> said. The Connecticut Democrat is chief sponsor of the $ 2.5 billion Act for <ORGANIZATION> Better </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Child </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Care </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> has endorsed the Democratic initiative in principle. The legislation won <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> committee approval last week and is tentatively scheduled for action this week in the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Education </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>. The bill reserves 75 percent of its money to help low - and middle-income parents pay for day care at homes and centers that meet minimum federal safety and staffing standards States could use the rest of the money for capital improvements, day-care staff training and salaries and administrative costs. The approach differs substantially from the one that <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has proposed. The vice president's day-care program would be built around a tax credit of up to $ 1,000 for low-income families for each child under 4 _ even if one parent in the family was staying home to take care of the child. The largest existing government program is the dependent-care tax credit for dual-earner families who pay for child care. It costs the Department of the <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> about $ 4 billion a year in lost revenue. According to <PERSON> Blank </PERSON>, other government child-care programs include a $ 2.7 billion social services block grant to states, of which less than 20 percent is used for day care, and a $ 600 million food program that helps day-care homes and centers provide nutritious meals. Welfare parents in job training programs or jobs that do n't pay enough for them to leave the rolls are also entitled to some help with child-care expenses. The <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> bill, endorsed in general terms by President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, would depart from current policy by giving tax breaks to families with a spouse at home _ families not eligible for the existing dependent care tax credit. At least four Republican-sponsored bills pending in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> take the same approach. Conservatives support it as a way to eliminate what they see as tax discrimination against mothers who decide to stay home with their children. But Citizens for <ORGANIZATION> Tax </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION>, a labor-backed tax study group, said the bills are unfair and unlikely to help those most in need, since low-income families can least afford to have one parent stay at home. Backers of the Democratic initiative say a universal tax break for families with preschool children is no substitute for their bill. They argue that a $ 1,000 tax credit would pay for only a third of the cost of one child's annual day care, and after the fact. They say a simple tax credit does not address the uneven quality of day care. Conservatives criticize the Democrats' bill on two major points _ its cost and the federal day-care standards it sets. But <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s plan and a recent House GOP initiative with a $ 1.3 billion price tag may blunt the controversy over spending That leaves federal standards for child-care as the primary sticking point. Sen. <PERSON> Strom </PERSON> <PERSON> Thurmond </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-S.C. </LOCATION>, summing up the conservative view during committee discussion of the Democratic bill, said, `` It has not been established in my mind that state and local governments ... need to be guided by the superior wisdom from <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>.'' <PERSON> Dodd </PERSON> and Children's Defense Fund officials say national standards are critical. `` This is a linchpin'' of <PERSON> Dodd </PERSON>'s bill, <PERSON> Blank </PERSON> said. `` Clearly this is not a regional issue,'' she said. `` Infants have the same needs no matter what state they're located in. A child care-giver with no training has no training no matter where she resides.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880731-0028 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-31-88 1314EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Italy-Mafia     07-31 0580</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Italy-Mafia,0598</SECOND>
<HEAD>Resignation of Mafia Investigator Causes Crisis In Confidence</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By STEPHEN R. WILSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ROME (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The resignation of <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>'s top investigator of the Mafia has shaken public confidence in the government's battle with the mob and prompted fears about a new wave of corruption in <LOCATION> Sicily </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Giovanni </PERSON> <PERSON> Falcone </PERSON> and eight other investigating magistrates, who played a prominent role in <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>'s largest Mafia trial, resigned Saturday. The so-called maxi-trial ended in December with convictions of 338 Mafiosi, including 19 reputed members of the <ORGANIZATION> Cosa </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nostra </ORGANIZATION>'s leadership commission. The nine magistrates of the `` anti-Mafia pool'' in <LOCATION> Sicily </LOCATION> submitted their resignations to the <ORGANIZATION> Superior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Magistrates </ORGANIZATION>, which oversees Italian judges, and asked to be transferred to other posts. <PERSON> Falcone </PERSON> gave several reasons for the action, including what he called obstruction of Mafia investigations on the island of <LOCATION> Sicily </LOCATION>. In a letter to the council, <PERSON> Falcone </PERSON> cited `` ommissions and inertia'' in the fight against organized crime. `` That which I feared could happen unfortunately happened. The investigations into the Mafia have been obstructed and -LRB- the anti-Mafia pool -RRB- ... is now stalled.'' <PERSON> Falcone </PERSON> also said in the letter that he wanted to leave his job so he could testify freely before a <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION> inquiry into Mafia investigations. The Council of Magistrates has been holding an inquiry into statements by the prosecutor of the Sicilian city of <LOCATION> Marsala </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Paolo </PERSON> <PERSON> Borsellino </PERSON>, that state and local officials curbed the power of the anti-Mafia group. <PERSON> Palermo </PERSON>'s mayor said <PERSON> Falcone </PERSON>'s resignation could mark a return to the days when Sicilian authorities and politicians conspired with the mob. `` We have weeded out corrupt politicians, or those who were in some way accomplices of the Mafia,'' the mayor, <PERSON> Leoluca </PERSON> <PERSON> Orlando </PERSON>, said in an interview with the state-run <ORGANIZATION> RAI </ORGANIZATION> television Saturday night. `` Today,'' he said, `` we are worried that there can be a return to the past, a return to the years in which magistrates, policemen and politicians were in collusion with the Mafia. I would n't want to return to the past.'' Ten days ago, <PERSON> Borsellino </PERSON> caused a national uproar when he charged that authorities had gone soft on the Mafia since the `` maxi-trial'' and that state and local officials had curbed the power of the magistrates. The charges prompted President <PERSON> Francesco </PERSON> <PERSON> Cossiga </PERSON> to dispatch national police officials to <LOCATION> Palermo </LOCATION> to examine the situation. He also ordered the inquiry by the national judges' council in <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION>. In his letter to the council, <PERSON> Falcone </PERSON> also said his methods `` differ radically'' with those of his new superior, <PERSON> Antonino </PERSON> <PERSON> Meli </PERSON>. <PERSON> Meli </PERSON> was appointed overseeing magistrate in February despite objections by <PERSON> Falcone </PERSON> that he had no experience in Mafia probes. <PERSON> Falcone </PERSON> said his resignation should be seen as `` the profound unease of one who must perform a delicate job in unfavorable conditions and the desire to express freely my thoughts without any conditions.'' The anti-Mafia pool was put together in 1983, after an investigator was killed in <LOCATION> Palermo </LOCATION>. The team worked under heavy security and devoted attention to fighting the Mafia. The magistrates were the first to take advantage of new laws to examine bank accounts of anyone suspected of Mafia association. The information was used successfully in trials of suspected Mafia drug traffickers. <PERSON> Falcone </PERSON> won the cooperation of <PERSON> Tomasso </PERSON> <PERSON> Buscetta </PERSON>, a Mafia leader who broke the mob's code of silence to describe its command structure in the 1987 trial. <PERSON> Falcone </PERSON> has become a national symbol of <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>'s war on organized crime and is considered its top investigator of the Mafia.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880731-0029 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-31-88 1334EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Cyprus-Shooting     07-31 0231</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Cyprus-Shooting,0237</SECOND>
<HEAD>Greek Cypriot Soldier Shot By Turkish Troops</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NICOSIA, Cyprus (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Turkish troops shot and seriously wounded a Greek Cypriot soldier Sunday in the fortified buffer zone that divides this capital city, officials said. Greek soldiers said Sgt. <PERSON> Evagoras </PERSON> <PERSON> Evagorou </PERSON>, 19, was shot in the back while crossing the 25-yard-wide zone in a quarter of the old city to talk to a Turkish guard on the other side. The men, who spoke on condition of anonymity, said <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> troops who patrol the strip rushed Evagorou to the hospital. <LOCATION> Cyprus </LOCATION> state radio said <PERSON> Evagorou </PERSON> was in critical condition after surgery for removal of a kidney and part of the spleen. This was the first serious shooting incident in the buffer zone since another Greek Cypriot soldier was shot and killed by Turkish troops two years ago. The strip, patrolled by Turkish and <LOCATION> Greek </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Cypriot </LOCATION> troops, has divided <LOCATION> Cyprus </LOCATION> in two since 1974, when <LOCATION> Turkey </LOCATION> seized the northern part of the island. A spokesman for the Foreign Ministry of the <LOCATION> Turkish </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Republic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Cyprus </LOCATION> said in a statement that a Turkish soldier warned <PERSON> Evagorou </PERSON> several times that he was dangerously close to the Turkish position. The statement said the Turkish guard shouted `` stop'' three times in <LOCATION> Greek </LOCATION> and then fired once into the air, in accordance with military regulations, before shooting and wounding Evagorou from about four yards away.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880731-0030 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-31-88 1339EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-EagleExports Bjt   07-31 0604</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Eagle Exports, Bjt,0622</SECOND>
<HEAD>Biologists Scale Huge Trees To Capture Baby Eagles For Export</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By SUE CROSS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ABOARD THE MV SURFBIRD, Alaska (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> eagle No. 3 looked glum. In just two hours, the baby bald eagle had been plucked from its nest in a tall spruce, lowered to the ground in a sack, put in a portable dog pen and ferried on a bouncing skiff to a <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. Fish and <ORGANIZATION> Wildlife </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> vessel. The bird was to become one of more than 300 bald eagles captured in <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> and relocated in other states in an effort to replenish the threatened national symbol. Bald eagles, an endangered species in every other state because of lead poisoning, pollution and other man-made dangers, are abundant in southeast <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>, numbering about 12,000 at biologists' last count _ about the number in all the other states combined The region has become the stocking ground for eagle-recovery programs in five states. `` The demand for birds is getting so great the supply ca n't meet the demand, and <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>'s been a great bonanza for us,'' said <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Tennessee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wildlife </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Resources </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION>, which hopes to release 60 bald eagles by 1990. Including 46 exported this year, <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> has contributed 264 bald eagles for relocation in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION>, said <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Jacobson </PERSON> of the <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. Fish and <ORGANIZATION> Wildlife </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Juneau </LOCATION>. From 1980 to 1987, 400 eagles from <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> and elsewhere were relocated in more than a dozen states, authorities say. Sightings of birds and nests make biologists confident the program is succeeding, though they wo n't have statistical proof for a few years. An eagle expedition begins with time-consuming helicopter surveys. Fish and Wildlife workers fly over some 200 miles of coastline each spring, plotting nests. Though eagle nests often span 8 feet or more, the sticks, grass and other matter they're made of camouflage them in the rain forest Come July, biologists from other states fly in and board two 65-foot military surplus vessels run by the Fish and <ORGANIZATION> Wildlife </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>. The capture area is a half-day's cruise away in the middle of the <ORGANIZATION> Tongass </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION>. Once there, <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> conservationist <PERSON> Kevin </PERSON> <PERSON> Schutt </PERSON> and fellow tree-scaler <PERSON> Dave </PERSON> <PERSON> Evans </PERSON> climb to the nests. While they ascend, the adult birds fly in agitated circles or perch in trees nearby, keening and trilling, and shy away from the climber and his assistants. The young birds do n't resist. `` Eagles, they're pretty docile,'' said <PERSON> Schutt </PERSON>. `` I do n't think they've -LRB- climbers -RRB- ever been struck on this project. It would be kind of unnerving to be 80 feet up a tree and struck by a bird that's 12 to 14 pounds,'' said Fish and Wildlife's <PERSON> Phil </PERSON> <PERSON> Schempf </PERSON> Though the young eagles appear nearly full-size when they're captured at 6 to 7 weeks of age, their feathers are soft and their bodies unprepared for flight They usually begin flying at 10 to 12 weeks. They do n't gain the characteristic white head and tail feathers until they are 3 or 4 years old, and their immature plummage varies from dark brown to mottled brown and white. Caretakers band their legs for identification and dust them with flea powder to kill feather lice. Once powdered, measured and recorded, the eagles ride out the trip in relative comfort, dining twice daily on diced halibut and snapper. They quickly adapt a tidy-nest instinct in their cages, ejecting their refuse through the doors onto the deck and hapless deckhands. Once the capture quota is met, the eagles are taken to <LOCATION> Juneau </LOCATION> and the next stage of their travel aboard commercial airliners.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880731-0031 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-31-88 1401EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w AM-ForeignOwnership     07-31 0566</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Foreign Ownership,550</SECOND>
<HEAD>Lawmaker Pushing for Foreign Investment Disclosure</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JENNIFER DIXON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Foreign investment in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> is expected to accelerate dramatically this year, but the true scope of overseas ownership remains hidden, a congressional critic complains. `` We need to know if foreign ownership is concentrating itself in key areas of our economy _ energy, steel, banking _ whether foreign ownership is gaining control of key sectors of the American economy,'' says Rep. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Bryant </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Texas </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Bryant </PERSON> came into the spotlight last year as sponsor of a provision of the 1,000-page trade bill approved by the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>. It would have forced a major increase in the amount of disclosure required of foreign investors. Lawmakers eventually dropped <PERSON> Bryant </PERSON>'s heavily debated plan in an unsuccessful effort to win President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s approval. And it is not part of the revised version of the trade bill now under debate. But <PERSON> Bryant </PERSON> is still pushing legislation to require foreign owners to register their major <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> assets with the <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, including business, industrial, real estate and farm holdings. The <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration opposes his bill because `` they do n't want to look like the folks that gave away the store,'' the <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION> Democrat said Prospects for getting the bill to the president's desk this year are not especially bright, but <PERSON> Bryant </PERSON> vows not to give up. To bolster his case, he cites a private study released last week showing foreign ownership in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> more than tripled since 1980. The <ORGANIZATION> Congressional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Leadership </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> said foreign investors own about 33 percent of prime commercial real estate in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION>, 46 percent in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>, and 39 percent in <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION>. It said they own 10 percent of the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> manufacturing base, hold a majority interest in concrete and consumer electronics industries, and a significant portion in machine tools, chemicals and auto parts. Nearly 3 million Americans are employed full or part-time as a result of foreign investment, the study said. It acknowledged, however, that foreign investments still account for no more than 5 percent to 6 percent of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> assets. <PERSON> Bryant </PERSON> said it is `` foolhardy'' to believe foreign investors will avoid the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> if they must register their holdings because `` every other country collects careful data'' without scaring off business. <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> <PERSON> LeaMond </PERSON>, president of the institute, said: `` In our innermost circle of trading partners, we are the only nation that swings the door open unconditionally to virtually every investment.'' Treasury Secretary <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON> and former <ORGANIZATION> Cabinet </ORGANIZATION> official <PERSON> Elliot </PERSON> <PERSON> Richardson </PERSON> claim <PERSON> Bryant </PERSON>'s bill is anti-competitive. <PERSON> Richardson </PERSON> testified before the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> that it would discourage foreign investment and result in higher <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> interest rates and an economic slowdown. <PERSON> Richardson </PERSON> called the reporting requirements burdensome. He said sufficient data already have been collected by 16 federal agencies and that investors would have to reveal business secrets. In its study, the institute said an `` unprecedented transfer of <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> assets to foreign control is under way.'' Since 1980, foreign direct investment in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> expanded by more than 215 percent, while American investment abroad jumped by one-fifth that rate, the study said. Foreign buy-outs are expected to make up as much as 20 percent of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> acquisitions this year, up from 5 percent in 1987, said the study, which based its findings on the latest available data from the <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> and other sources.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880731-0032 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-31-88 1421EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p AM-Blanton Bjt   07-31 0511</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Blanton, Bjt,0532</SECOND>
<HEAD>Ex-Governor, Ex-Con Counting on Voter Sympathy in Congressional
Race</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By WOODY BAIRD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>JACKSON, Tenn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Ray </PERSON> <PERSON> Blanton </PERSON>, former congressman, ex-governor and one-time inmate at a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> penitentiary, is hoping for a big sympathy vote as he bids for political resurrection in Thursday's Democratic primary for <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Blanton </PERSON>, who left the governor's office in 1979 in a swirl of controversy over the sale of pardons and state liquor licenses, said he expects voters to see that he was a victim of political persecution. `` They know I was railroaded and falsely accused,'' he said. <PERSON> Blanton </PERSON> faces three primary opponents in <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION>'s 8th District, a largely rural area that borders the <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> and runs from just north of <LOCATION> Memphis </LOCATION> to the <LOCATION> Kentucky </LOCATION> state line. The favorite, state Rep. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Tanner </PERSON>, has the support of <PERSON> Ed </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>, the district's popular outgoing congressman, and has raised more than $ 450,000 to <PERSON> Blanton </PERSON>'s $ 25,000. `` I've got a million dollars worth of name recognition which I have earned over the years,'' <PERSON> Blanton </PERSON> said. `` I have n't gone out begging and have n't held any arm-twisting fund-raisers.'' <PERSON> Blanton </PERSON> won some of that recognition when he was unceremoniously dumped from the governor's office before his term expired in January 1979. Fellow Democrats swore in Republican <PERSON> Lamar </PERSON> <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON> three days early after <PERSON> Blanton </PERSON> abruptly pardoned three former felons and commuted the sentences of 49 inmates, most of them armed robbers and murderers. The pardon scandal, in which two of <PERSON> Blanton </PERSON>'s aides were convicted of taking bribes to free prisoners, became the subject of the movie `` Marie,'' starring <PERSON> Sissy </PERSON> <PERSON> Spacek </PERSON>. <PERSON> Blanton </PERSON> was never charged in that scandal, but he was convicted in federal court in 1981 of taking part in a scheme to sell state liquor licenses. The conviction was on charges of conspiracy, extortion and mail fraud. The fraud conviction was overturned after his release from prison because of a <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> ruling on the definition of the offense. A state court restored his citizenship rights last year. <PERSON> Blanton </PERSON>, who represented the state's 7th District in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> from 1967 to 1972 and was <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION>'s chief executive from 1975 to 1979, is running on a platform of government experience and fair play. `` There's a large silent vote that we still feel will come down on my side,'' he said. <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>, who has represented the district without serious opposition since 1969, said he has known <PERSON> Tanner </PERSON> all his life and has followed his 12-year career in the Legislature. `` I might have retired two years ago but he was n't ready,'' <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> said from his office in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. The other Democrats in the race are <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> Mayor <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Conger </PERSON> and <PERSON> Ivy </PERSON> <PERSON> Scarborough </PERSON>, a <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> lawyer. The race has produced few fireworks or sharp differences on issues. The candidates promised to help create jobs, protect the family farm, improve education and oppose drug dealers. None has seriously attacked <PERSON> Blanton </PERSON> in public for his prison record, but <PERSON> Tanner </PERSON> has been criticized as too well financed and tied to the district's political establishment. Three Republicans are running in the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> primary.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880731-0033 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-31-88 1431EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-SAfrica-CryFreedom     07-31 0448</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-SAfrica-Cry Freedom,0458</SECOND>
<HEAD>Newspapers Attack Government Ban On Film</HEAD>
<DATELINE>JOHANNESBURG, South Africa (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Newspapers on Sunday condemned the government's ban on `` Cry Freedom'' and said the anti-apartheid film could help South Africans confront and address their deep racial divisions. The movie tells the story of black South African activist <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Biko </PERSON>, who died in police detention in 1977, and white journalist <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Woods </PERSON>, who befriended him. The film was approved by government censors Friday morning and immediately began playing in 30 theaters nationwide. However, police seized the film seven hours later, saying it was contributing to the `` revolutionary climate'' in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>. `` South Africans have been reminded anew that the government wants to decide for them what they should see, think, feel,'' the independent Sunday Star said in an editorial. `` The central point about ` Cry Freedom' is ... whether South Africans are mature enough to confront a substantially accurate and thoroughly discomfiting piece of recent history,'' the <ORGANIZATION> Star </ORGANIZATION> said. `` We think they are.'' During the film's brief run, three bombs exploded at theaters where the movie was shown and there were several bomb threats. There were no injuries. On Saturday, a bomb blast at a shopping area in a white suburb outside <LOCATION> Johannesburg </LOCATION> killed one woman and injured 56. Police cited the theater attacks as proof that the controversial film was a threat to public safety. Never before has a film shown in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> contained such emotional and violent scenes related to the government's apartheid policies. By law and custom, apartheid establishes a racially segregated society in which the nation's 26 million blacks have no voice in national affairs. The country's 5 million whites control the economy and maintain separate residential areas, schools and health services. The banning `` is an act of a desperate government whose thoughts are clouded with fear and uncertainty,'' said the black-oriented City Press. `` We are dealing with certain government officials who do not have the slightest idea of the basic tenets of freedom of thought and expression.'' The independent Sunday Times, the country's largest Sunday newspaper, said the government was more worried about the film's `` considerable truth'' than its alleged anti-South <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> propaganda `` The challenge of ` Cry Freedom' for whites is to commit themselves to redressing those wrongs -LRB- of racial discrimination -RRB-,'' the Sunday Times said. `` The test for black South Africans is to rise above the bitterness ... and take up the task of constructive participation in building a better <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>,'' it added. The Sunday Times and The Sunday Star both ran front-page stories suggesting that international distributors of movies and television programs could face increased pressure to pull out of <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> following the ban on `` Cry Freedom.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880731-0034 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-31-88 1440EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Brites     07-31 0458</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Brites,0474</SECOND>
