<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880625-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-25-88 0048EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-GM-Johnson     06-25 0164</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-GM-Johnson,0170</SECOND>
<HEAD>GM Executive To Return To Chicago Law Firm, Sources Say</HEAD>
<DATELINE>DETROIT (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Elmer </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>, executive vice president and a director of <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Motors </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, plans to leave the automaker and return to a <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> law firm, the <ORGANIZATION> Detroit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Free </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> reported in Saturday's editions. The official announcement is expected to come when <ORGANIZATION> GM </ORGANIZATION>'s board of directors meets Monday, according to <ORGANIZATION> GM </ORGANIZATION> executives who spoke to the newspaper on the condition of anonymity. <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>, 56, decided to leave his job because his often-controversial ideas to change the nation's top automaker have been ignored, the executives said. <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> was on vacation and could n't be reached and <ORGANIZATION> GM </ORGANIZATION> declined official comment, the newspaper said. <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Vittum </PERSON>, a partner in the <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> law firm of <ORGANIZATION> Kirkland </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> Ellis </PERSON>, would n't confirm that <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> was returning to the firm. <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> has remained a partner in the firm since joining <ORGANIZATION> GM </ORGANIZATION> in 1983. He sits on its management committee, for which he receives $ 30,000 annually, <PERSON> Vittum </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880625-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-25-88 0053EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Sheriff'sCrack     06-25 0283</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Sheriff's Crack,0290</SECOND>
<HEAD>Sheriff's Department Makes Its Own Crack</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BARTOW, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Polk </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sheriff </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> is making its own crack these days, having decided it is a safer and more efficient way to supply its undercover agents for sales to drug buyers. While most law enforcement agencies use crack confiscated during investigations for undercover operations, <LOCATION> Polk </LOCATION> officials decided they needed more than the `` very limited supply'' of crack they had on hand, a department report said. In addition, there were worries about impurities sometimes found in confiscated crack. Turning powder cocaine into crack cocaine requires a powdery base substance as well as the drug. Some dealers have been known to use Drano or other toxic chemicals as the base, sheriff's Lt. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Madden </PERSON> said recently. `` After reviewing all our options and checking with other agencies in the state that are taking an aggressive approach to crack, we felt the safest and most reliable way to handle these reverses would be use crack that was produced in a clean, controlled environment,'' the report said. <LOCATION> Polk </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> deputies posing as drug dealers have routinely set up shop in known drug neighborhoods and sold crack to drug buyers in cars. Deputies have made more than 600 reverse-sting arrests since the campaign began in earnest last fall. The Sheriff's Office crack was made at the department by a supervisor in the drug unit who had gone over the fairly simple cooking procedure with technicians from the <ORGANIZATION> Florida </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Law </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Enforcement </ORGANIZATION>. Baking powder was used as a base substance. The cooking session produced 11 ounces, enough to make several thousand pieces of crack in the size commonly sold on the street, officials said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880625-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-25-88 0054EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-PierWedding     06-25 0224</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Pier Wedding,0229</SECOND>
<HEAD>Couples Can Take The Wedding Plunge Next To Lake Michigan</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CHICAGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Looking for a unique setting to exchange vows? How about an old pier, complete with dramatic view of the city, a gentle lake breeze, and a couple of fishermen and joggers thrown in for charm? The city's <ORGANIZATION> Marriage </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> offers the service at <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pier </ORGANIZATION> on <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION> as an alternative to the mundane civil ceremony at City Hall. The $ 10 price wo n't hurt the wallet much and the view is almost guaranteed to take the wedding party's breath away. `` A judge from <ORGANIZATION> Circuit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> marries the couples. ... It's like getting married at the City Hall only you get married at lovely <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pier </ORGANIZATION>,'' said <PERSON> Susan </PERSON> <PERSON> Wayman </PERSON>, who coordinates the weddings for the Department of Cultural Affairs. `` You can be as elaborate as you want, within reason,'' Ms. <PERSON> Wayman </PERSON> said Friday. `` I've seen six bridesmaids and flower girls'' at one wedding, she said. `` I've seen couples arrive by horse and carriage ... and a lot of people walk out just casually dressed. It runs the gamut.'' The pier, which once was bustling with Great Lakes' shippers, is frequented by athletes and anglers, so couples who marry there should be prepared for `` fishermen sitting right next to them ... and joggers jogging right by,'' Ms. <PERSON> Wayman </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880625-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-25-88 0055EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-BurnCamp     06-25 0632</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Burn Camp,0651</SECOND>
<HEAD>Scarred Youngsters Get Week To Forget Their Burns</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Saturday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By ROB WELLS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WONDER VALLEY, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 From a distance, there's no telling sign that the noisy children and teen-agers romping around a summer camp share the deep emotional and physical scars that accompany disfiguring burns. `` We try to give them a whole week to be free of their burn,'' said <PERSON> Shirley </PERSON> <PERSON> Turner </PERSON>, who heads the special camp. It's called <LOCATION> Wonder </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ranch </LOCATION>, this secluded spot nestled in the <LOCATION> Sierra </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mountains </LOCATION> 200 miles southeast of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION>. This week 77 young burn survivors from <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> state frolicked in a swimming pool, rode ponies or cast a fishing line into a trout pond. `` If my mom would n't have taken me, I would have walked here,'' declared <PERSON> David </PERSON>, an 11-year-old enjoying the camp sponsored by the <ORGANIZATION> Alisa </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ann </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ruch </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Burn </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION>. `` The counselors are real cool. They treat you really nice.'' Mrs. <PERSON> Turner </PERSON>, the foundation's executive director, described the camp as therapy to help fortify a burn victim's self-esteem. Most important, it lets them simply be kids free from a society too often repelled by the disfigurement of burns. There is one strict rule: No one can ask the children about their accident. `` That's why camp is so good for them _ they do n't have to deal with the accident,'' said Mrs. <PERSON> Turner </PERSON>. `` We do n't want them reliving that.'' The children splashing in the pool on a hot summer morning played as if they never had endured painful skin grafts, worn an uncomfortable pressure garment to reduce swelling or been cruelly teased by peers. As <PERSON> Corky </PERSON> and <PERSON> Cecily </PERSON> splashed around, <PERSON> Corky </PERSON> stretched her scarred arm around <PERSON> Cecily </PERSON>'s back, proclaiming with a wide smile: `` We're friends. Mrs. <PERSON> Turner </PERSON>'s husband, <PERSON> Jim </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> firefighter and foundation member, said there's little reluctance among these summer campers to test new experiences. `` They've been through so much pain, they'll try anything,'' <PERSON> Turner </PERSON> said. The camp is rewarding for the volunteer counselors, mostly firefighters and their spouses. `` If you come up here for a week, you get enough hugs and kisses to last a year,'' said <PERSON> Nan </PERSON> <PERSON> Ziegler </PERSON>, a nurse from <LOCATION> Long </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION>. `` I love them. They are just little kids. They can forget what they look like,'' said <PERSON> Christen </PERSON> <PERSON> Powell </PERSON>, a lifeguard from <LOCATION> Clovis </LOCATION>. `` I'm going to miss these kids.'' Mrs. <PERSON> Turner </PERSON> said such a loving and accepting environment is n't typical for burn survivors Society is wary of burn victims, she said. Some gawk at a survivor's blistered and grafted skin, while others treat them like pariahs. She told of an incident of a restaurant owner asking a family to leave because the sight of their child, a burn victim, made his patrons uncomfortable. These experiences, along with the fact that many burn victims remain physically scarred for life, add up to a `` devastating'' psychological effect on the victims and their families, Mrs. <PERSON> Turner </PERSON> said. Easing such trauma is one of the foundation's goals. `` Now that -LRB- doctors -RRB- have solved the major medical problems and are able to keep them alive, they are now concentrating on the quality of life,'' she said. She estimated that 4,000 children are seriously burned in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> each year. All expenses for the children at the camp are paid by the foundation's fund-raising efforts and volunteer labor. Mrs. <PERSON> Turner </PERSON> estimated that the week in <LOCATION> Wonder </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION>, which ends with a trip to <LOCATION> Disneyland </LOCATION>, cost the group about $ 100,000. Judging by the the children's grins, it appeared to be money well spent. `` Today and this week they are just kids,'' said Mrs. <PERSON> Turner </PERSON>. She said she hopes the camp will help make them `` strong enough inside to take and handle the pressures their peers and adults give them.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880625-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-25-88 0056EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-APArts:Daley     06-25 0749</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AP Arts: Daley,0766</SECOND>
<HEAD>Books And Authors: Police Inspiration</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Saturday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By HELEN MILES</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>RIDGEFIELD, Conn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Author <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Daley </PERSON> knows that the quick grip of fear and split-second decisions that can make or break a cop's career are not just the stuff of police fiction. A former deputy commissioner of the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Daley </PERSON> has grabbed the attention of readers on subjects ranging from treasure diving in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> to bullfighting in <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION>, but is best known for his insider's tales of street crime and police bureaucracy. During an interview at the converted cottage on his <LOCATION> Ridgefield </LOCATION> estate where he does his writing, the best-selling author of `` Year of a Dragon,'' `` Hands of a Stranger'' and `` Prince of the City,'' explained how fact and fantasy merge in his latest novel, `` Man With a Gun'' -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> Simon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; Schuster, $ 19.95 -RRB-. `` Most of the incidents happened to me one way or the other, but they did n't happen just that way,'' <PERSON> Daley </PERSON> said. `` All of them have been extracted from the way they actually happened and moved together to make a story.'' The story of `` Man With a Gun'' is loosely based on events surrounding the <LOCATION> Harlem </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mosque </LOCATION> murder of 1972, when a police officer was killed during a confrontation between black Muslims and authorities. The book deals with the power and politics behind the police handling of a situation where every decision has long-term consequences. `` In moments of terror you do what it seems like you have to do and no one is responsible for that,'' <PERSON> Daley </PERSON> said. `` I made some mistakes which did n't seem like mistakes at the time,'' he said of his involvement in the Mosque riots. <PERSON> Daley </PERSON> and the central character in `` Man With a Gun,'' <PERSON> Phillip </PERSON> <PERSON> Keefe </PERSON>, are alike in many ways. <PERSON> Keefe </PERSON> is a deputy police commissioner and, like <PERSON> Daley </PERSON>, resigns after the incident. <PERSON> Keefe </PERSON> is a former journalist. <PERSON> Daley </PERSON> worked for five years as a foreign correspondent for <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Keefe </PERSON> drives a <ORGANIZATION> Porsche </ORGANIZATION>; so does <PERSON> Daley </PERSON>. However, <PERSON> Keefe </PERSON> is not <PERSON> Daley </PERSON>, the author insists. `` I have no ghosts to exorcise.'' For one thing, <PERSON> Keefe </PERSON> is not a successful author. <PERSON> Daley </PERSON> has 20 books to his credit. Five novels have been made into films, and <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Newman </PERSON> is slated to play the lead role in `` Man With a Gun.'' In his novels, the 57-year-old <PERSON> Daley </PERSON> aims to provide more than a mirror image of life. Literature should provide `` new insights into your own life, into everybody's life, a new understanding of what we are all up against,'' he said. Novels about the police, however, tend to be grouped together as thrillers, said <PERSON> Daley </PERSON>, who considers thrillers to be books with `` preposterous characters doing preposterous acts all the time.'' `` Thriller means discardable, thriller means light entertainment, thriller means not important,'' he said. `` The word denigrates what I am trying to do. I think I am writing something else and keep getting accused of writing thrillers.'' As an undergraduate studying literature at <ORGANIZATION> Fordham </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Daley </PERSON> said he wanted to be the greatest writer that ever lived. He has since lowered his goal to writing books that will stand the test of time. Translations of <PERSON> Daley </PERSON>'s books cram his closets. `` I ca n't throw them away because they are books and books are icons.'' Samples of his photographic work decorate his walls. <PERSON> Daley </PERSON> bought a camera when <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> offered to pay him $ 15 extra for every photograph used in the newspaper. His photographs have since been exhibited at the <ORGANIZATION> Baltimore </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Museum </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Art </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> Gallery of Modern Art. But he prefers writing. `` To me literature is the greatest of the arts because it takes you further outside yourself than any other,'' he said, adding there's also a practical side to his work. `` I do n't want to be poor. I would n't give up the things we have in order to be a renowned writer that no one ever reads.'' He keeps apartments in <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, as well as his <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION> home where he lives with his wife. Currently working on a `` part personal memoir, part history of <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Daley </PERSON> said he considers the time spent writing the book as a rest period from the pressures of producing what is expected of him. `` I have to write something that's going to sell,'' he said. `` -LRB- You -RRB- get trapped in whatever it is that you are doing that's successful.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880625-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-25-88 0057EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--Door-To-DoorThief     06-25 0138</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Door-To-Door Thief,0140</SECOND>
<HEAD>Alleged Thief Stops By House, Steals $70,000 Painting</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MEXICO CITY (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An art thief who apparently knew a man wanted to sell a $ 70,000 painting by <PERSON> Diego </PERSON> <PERSON> Rivera </PERSON>, went to the victim's residence, asked a maid for the painting and walked away with the canvas, police said A <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> judiciary police report said the theft occurred last Monday, but the victim, <PERSON> Gonzalo </PERSON> <PERSON> Faustino </PERSON> <PERSON> Gonzalez </PERSON>, did n't find out about it until Friday. When questioned by police, the maid claimed that a black-haired man with a beard and dark eyeglasses rang the bell of <PERSON> Gonzalez </PERSON>'s home when he was away The man said he had come to pick up the painting that <PERSON> Gonazlez </PERSON> wanted to sell, the report said. The maid, <PERSON> Aurelia </PERSON> <PERSON> Delgado </PERSON>, said she gave the painting to the man, the report said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880625-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-25-88 0058EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-France-Colorization     06-25 0224</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-France-Colorization,0232</SECOND>
<HEAD>Judge Prohibits Broadcast Of Colorized Version Of Huston Film</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PARIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A <LOCATION> French </LOCATION> judge has prohibited a private television station from broadcasting a colorized version of `` Asphalt Jungle,'' a classic <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Huston </PERSON> film. The ruling Friday was the first of its kind in <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>. Lawyers for the station, <ORGANIZATION> La </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cinq </ORGANIZATION> -LRB- Channel 5 -RRB-, said they would appeal. The colorized version of the 1950 film had been scheduled to run Sunday night. Judge <PERSON> Huguette </PERSON> <PERSON> Le </PERSON> <PERSON> Foyer </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Costil </PERSON> said the ruling affected all of <PERSON> Huston </PERSON>'s films. She noted that <PERSON> Huston </PERSON>, who died in August, opposed colorization and it was her duty to respect his will. The French <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Film </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Directors </ORGANIZATION>, which representives of <PERSON> Huston </PERSON>'s estate in <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>, had requested the injunction. `` We hope the first blow to the ` colorizers' will put a definitive stop to the surge of profiteering against creativity,'' the group said in a news release. <PERSON> Huston </PERSON> was so vehemently opposed to the tinting of his films that he attended a news conference denouncing the process not long before his death. A spokeswoman for <ORGANIZATION> La </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cinq </ORGANIZATION> said the station had aired colorized films previously, but none in which the authors had expressed their disapproval. French laws protecting the control by artists of their works are among the strongest in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> but it has no specific legislation dealing with colorization.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880625-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-25-88 0058EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Europe-ArmsScandals     06-25 0812</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Europe-Arms Scandals,0837</SECOND>
<HEAD>Europe Has Its Arms Scandals, But Of A Different Kind
^Eds: Also in Saturday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ARTHUR MAX</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>STOCKHOLM, Sweden (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> has its arms scandals, but the kind that has shaken <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> is unlikely because procurement programs are run differently and governments generally avoid direct competition among contractors. In <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, a 2-year-old investigation has focused on allegations that private consultants bribed government employees to obtain <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> secrets that could help their clients win huge contracts. Proportion alone is a significant factor in the relative opportunity for corruption. Nothing in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> even approaches the colossus of the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> defense budget, $ 290 billion for 1988. <LOCATION> Sweden </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Norway </LOCATION> _ respective recent budgets of about $ 4 billion and $ 2.8 billion _ have had scandals recently, but they involved bribery and illegal exports. Both Scandinavian are considering measures to control their arms traders. Even <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> spend only one-tenth the amount of money on defense that goes through the Pentagon funnel every year. The giant <ORGANIZATION> British </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Marconi </ORGANIZATION> communications group currently is the object of a year-long fraud investigation, but defense scandals in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> seldom are publicized. The Marconi case is based on suspicions that the company made excessive profits and did not pay royalties it owed the government. <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION> had a major bribery scandal a decade ago in which a former defense minister and an air force chief were convicted of accepting payoffs from <ORGANIZATION> Lockheed </ORGANIZATION>, the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> aircraft manufacturer. In <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Franz </PERSON> <PERSON> Josef </PERSON> <PERSON> Strauss </PERSON> was accused of taking millions from from <ORGANIZATION> Lockheed </ORGANIZATION> when he was defense minister in 1961, but the case was dropped. `` The Europeans deal with these things differently. They do n't want to know about them,'' said <PERSON> Aaron </PERSON> <PERSON> Karp </PERSON>, an American who tracks worldwide weapons sales for <ORGANIZATION> SIPRI </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Stockholm </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Peace </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> `` All over <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> the procurement networks are much smaller than in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>.'' he said. `` There are real old-boy networks here. ... The Europeans are very hesitant to prosecute people on the team.'' <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Greenwood </PERSON> said <LOCATION> European </LOCATION> governments seldom use middlemen on contracts and most weapons come from `` preferred sources'' that coordinate development programs with defense ministries. <PERSON> Greenwood </PERSON>, a professor at <ORGANIZATION> Aberdeen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Scotland </LOCATION>, said in an interview that <LOCATION> European </LOCATION> governments and companies have `` almost a symbiotic relationship'' and few secrets from each other. Lack of competition sometimes bloats prices. <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>'s Guardian newspaper said recently <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Accounts </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> has complained to the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> for years about `` unsatisfactory administration'' and a `` disturbing failure'' to control costs. <PERSON> Karp </PERSON> said corruption is hard to pin down in European procurements, but some armaments in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> are three or four times the price of comparable <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> weapons systems. `` Europeans expect to pay more and they accept that. It's the price they pay to keep their independence from the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>,'' he said. According to <PERSON> Greenwood </PERSON>, `` The key difference with the Americans is that in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> until recently you did n't have consultants, the ` Beltway Bandits,' or people who are hungry for contracts.'' <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> controls 15 percent of the national arms production and the government has a share in companies that handle about half the rest, a ministry spokesman said. Supervision of arms sales in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> is handled by government agencies, sometimes by parliaments. <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION> has no oversight process, said a spokesman for the prime minister's office. When corruption occurs in the European arms trade, it usually involves export sales, especially to Third World countries. <ORGANIZATION> Bofors </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> AB </ORGANIZATION>, the privately owned Swedish munitions company, is accused of paying $ 50 million in bribes and commissions to get a $ 2.4 billion artillery contract from <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>. Some of the money allegedly found its way to Prime Minister <PERSON> Rajiv </PERSON> <PERSON> Gandhi </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, spawning charges in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Delhi </LOCATION> of government corruption. For deals in many parts of the world, bribery payments are incorporated in to the prices of weapons, two sources said privately. One, a retired Swedish salesman of defense equipment, said of <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>: `` It was taken for granted that you ca n't secure an arms deal without bribes.'' <ORGANIZATION> Bofors </ORGANIZATION>, the largest arms maker in <LOCATION> Sweden </LOCATION>, also is accused of circumventing rules against selling weapons to nations that are at war or located in volatile regions. The rules are meant to safeguard Swedish neutrality. Four former <ORGANIZATION> Bofors </ORGANIZATION> executives were indicted this week on charges of smuggling anti-aircraft missile systems to <LOCATION> Dubai </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Bahrain </LOCATION> in the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION>, where <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> are at war. None was accused of profiting personally. Prime Minister <PERSON> Ingvar </PERSON> <PERSON> Carlsson </PERSON> threatened to halt all arms exports unless the companies follow the regulations. <PERSON> Kongsberg </PERSON> <PERSON> Vapenfabrikk </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Norway </LOCATION>'s largest defense contractor, admitted violating Western export controls by selling equipment to the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> that would enable it to built quieter submarines. The deal, revealed last year, led to a public apology from Prime Minister <PERSON> Gro </PERSON> <PERSON> Harlem </PERSON> <PERSON> Brundtland </PERSON> to President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880625-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-25-88 0106EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-China-Flood     06-25 0214</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-China-Flood,0223</SECOND>
<HEAD>Floods Kill 62 In East China</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Floods and landslides caused by more than a week of heavy rains have killed 62 people in two provinces in eastern <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, official reports said today. Six of the victims were children killed when a waterlogged school building collapsed in <LOCATION> Zhejiang </LOCATION> province's <LOCATION> Longquan </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, the official <ORGANIZATION> China </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> reported. Heavy rains also fell this week in <LOCATION> Jiangxi </LOCATION> province on <LOCATION> Zhejiang </LOCATION>'s western border, causing a landslide that killed at least 17 people, the paper said. Reports today did not specify where or how the other 39 people died. The <ORGANIZATION> Xinhua </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> said 212,420 acres of farmland have been flooded and nearly 6,400 homes destroyed in <LOCATION> Zhejiang </LOCATION> since the rains began June 15. The rains in <LOCATION> Jiangxi </LOCATION> have flooded 568,000 acres of farmland and forced 14,000 people to flee their homes, the <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> Daily said. The report said four to 12 inches of rain fell on various parts of <LOCATION> Zhejiang </LOCATION> during a 10-day period ending Friday. <LOCATION> Zhejiang </LOCATION> normally receives about four inches of rain during the entire month of June. In <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, the rainy season generally lasts until mid-July and more storms are forecast. Heavy storms last month in the same area of <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> killed at least 131 people and heavily damaged crops.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880625-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-25-88 0108EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Soviet-History     06-25 0790</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Soviet-History,0814</SECOND>
<HEAD>Under Glasnost, School History Exams Give Way To `Discussion'</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Saturday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By JOHN-THOR DAHLBURG</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MOSCOW (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Before glasnost, School No. 734 would have looked like this: 17-year-olds lined up in the hall in the summer heat, nervously awaiting a grilling on Soviet politics and history by a panel of teachers. That's what lanky, blond-haired <PERSON> Dmitri </PERSON> <PERSON> Predkov </PERSON> and his classmates at the school in eastern <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> had been expecting Friday. But last month, the head of Soviet education, <PERSON> Gennady </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Yagodin </PERSON>, suddenly ordered the tests canceled. The reason: The final exams would have made students in the final year of school parrot material in textbooks now contradicted by the revelations of <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s drive for more openness in history and other areas. Instead, <PERSON> Dmitri </PERSON> and his 24 classmates, like 10th graders nationwide, were called into school for a three-hour ungraded `` discussion'' to gauge their knowledge of the past and awareness of problems facing the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> today. `` We want to be sure that the children can take part in discussions and are able to to voice their opinion anywhere,'' said their teacher, <PERSON> Vera </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Zorich </PERSON>, 53. Despite that wish, most of the teen-age Muscovites who gathered at 9 a.m. Friday around four tables in a geography classroom said nothing during the ensuing `` discussion,'' despite repeated prompting from teachers. Some, however, aired views at odds with official ideology, and that presumably would have gotten them into trouble only a few years ago. One even joked about the Russian Revolution. <PERSON> Predkov </PERSON> stood up to say that <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s program for `` perestroika,'' or economic and social restructuring, was not a natural consequence of the growth of Soviet socialism, and that people who say otherwise do so `` only because <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> is the head of our party.'' `` We do n't have any rights. They're just words on paper,'' declared the son of a building engineer. Glasnost, <PERSON> Dmitri </PERSON> added, may allow more candor about history, but it does n't mean Soviet citizens are getting more information about current political problems. Another 17-year-old, wearing a thin black tie, said Soviets of all schools of thought, even `` fascists,'' should have the legal right to form their own political parties to challenge the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> that <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> heads. <PERSON> Gennady </PERSON> <PERSON> Kaztman </PERSON>, whose father works as a printer, made his classmates and teachers roar with laughter by telling this bittersweet joke about the legacy of the 1917 Russian Revolution: When the <ORGANIZATION> Bolsheviks </ORGANIZATION> seized power, <PERSON> Gennady </PERSON> said, a <LOCATION> Russian </LOCATION> countess whose grandfather had been a 19th-century revolutionary summoned her maid to see what the shouting in the streets was about. `` Why, Madame, it's the revolution,'' the maid replied. `` Oh yes, grandfather dreamed of that. Tell me, what do they want?'' the countess asked. `` Why, they want a society where there are no more rich people.'' `` Strange,'' the countess replied. `` Grandfather wanted a society where there were no more poor people.'' `` Four years ago, maybe even a year ago, they would not have dared speak like that,'' a beaming Mrs. <PERSON> Zorich </PERSON> told a visiting reporter at the end of the meeting. In recent months, Soviet educators and official media have heaped scorn on the country's history textbooks, which have been outpaced by criticism in the glasnost-revitalized media about the crimes of dictator <PERSON> Josef </PERSON> <PERSON> V. </PERSON> <PERSON> Stalin </PERSON> and corruption and stagnation under <PERSON> Leonid </PERSON> <PERSON> I. </PERSON> <PERSON> Brezhnev </PERSON>. `` Frankly, the books are of the ` hooray' type,'' said <PERSON> Tatyana </PERSON> <PERSON> Cherkashena </PERSON>, head of teaching methods in the <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> neighborhood where School No. 734 is located. `` In our country, they say, everything is wonderful _ ` hooray.' Those who perished in the repressions, those who were imprisoned, are not even mentioned.'' A recent competition was held to select a new generation of Soviet textbooks, but it is uncertain whether they will be ready for the next school year in September. In the meantime, many Soviet teachers have been using articles published in the press as the basis for their history lessons. In years past, 10th grade students taking their final exams were given a slip of paper that bore two questions on history and civics. After a half-hour or more to prepare, they were called before a panel of teachers to speak and answer questions. In May, the principal of School 734, <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON> <PERSON> N. </PERSON> <PERSON> Tubelsky </PERSON>, was informed by the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> on </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Education </ORGANIZATION> that the customary year-end history exams for senior school pupils had been canceled. `` We were n't told about how to structure the discussions, so we decided to use the regular form of our history class, which the students would feel comfortable with,'' <PERSON> Tubelsky </PERSON> said. `` We need to change out textbooks,'' he added. `` They are based on a Stalinist conception that sees every event, every historical figure, through the dogma of class warfare.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880625-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-25-88 0109EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-BRF--CollegeMerger     06-25 0147</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--College Merger,0151</SECOND>
<HEAD>Atlanta University, Clark College to Merge</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ATLANTA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The trustees of <ORGANIZATION> Atlanta </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Clark </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> voted Friday to merge the schools into a new entity, <ORGANIZATION> Clark </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Atlanta </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Atlanta </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> is the financially troubled graduate school of the <ORGANIZATION> Atlanta </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>, a consortium of <PERSON> Clark </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Morehouse </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Morris </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Brown </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Spelman </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Morehouse </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medicine </ORGANIZATION> and the Interdenominational Theological Center. The merger of <PERSON> Clark </PERSON>, an undergraduate school, with the graduate school alters a nearly 60-year-old agreement among the seven historically <PERSON> black </PERSON> colleges to jointly finance maintenance, management and some academic programs. The new school will become the largest member of the consortium in terms of students and budget, with its annual budget placed at $ 30 million and 2,000 undergraduates and 1,000 graduate students. <PERSON> Clark </PERSON> president <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Cole </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, will be chief executive officer of the new institution.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880625-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-25-88 0111EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-UN-Disarmamant     06-25 0834</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-UN-Disarmamant,0859</SECOND>
<HEAD>Monks, Hiroshima Victims Among Those Rallying For Peace At U.N.</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Saturday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By VICTORIA GRAHAM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>UNITED NATIONS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 These days, this <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> enclave is a magnet for peace marchers, <ORGANIZATION> Buddhist </ORGANIZATION> monks, <LOCATION> Nigerian </LOCATION> `` drummers of passion,'' victims of <LOCATION> Hiroshima </LOCATION>, poets and blues singers of the nuclear age. All have converged on the Third Special Session on Disarmament, a monthlong gathering ending this week. They have camped on the sidewalks and exploded 1,000 balloons to symbolize nuclear tests. They have gathered at a corner coffee shop to discuss radioactive military landfills, the evils of transnational corporations, and the future of the Siberian crane. They range from a 12-year-old <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> girl who invented a peace game to <PERSON> Mother </PERSON> <PERSON> Teresa </PERSON>, the 77-year-old Nobel laureate. But all the spinning of prayer wheels, scattering of flower petals, chanting of mantras, and meditation on brotherhood have not harmonized discordant views on disarmament. The 159 <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> members are trying to devise a realistic agenda for peace, and delegates hope they'll be able to adopt a final document by concensus, without divisive voting that usually pits the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> against most of the developing world and socialist countries. The superpower backdrop is positive: the <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> summit, the Soviet pullout from <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>, and the treaty on elimination of intermediate-range nuclear weapons. But differences over such issues as nuclear and conventional disarmament and a nuclear test ban treaty are enormous. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has made clear it will not reaffirm what it calls a sweeping and unrealistic <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> disarmament document adopted 10 years ago. Last year, the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> voted alone on most disarmament issues in the <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION>, ranging from a demand for a comprehensive nuclear test ban to prohibiting the military uses of outer space. It refused to participate in a conference on the relationship between disarmament and development. Third World nations have been clamoring for a disarmament fund of military savings in the industrialized world to be diverted toward economic and social development in poor countries. Western diplomats say that the developing world should do its part by halting its regional wars and curbing its massive spending on conventional arms _ spending that deprives people of food, health care and education. The American positions have not changed in the current disarmament session. The <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> administration and Western allies emphasize the importance of bilateral negotiations with the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> in nuclear and other fields and do not want bilateral talks subject to multilateral pressures. `` We are hearing a lot of cant,'' said one Western diplomat. `` The <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and the Soviets are doing just fine. What we need is a realistic approach that will leave nations free to pursue their bilateral actions without multilateral interference.'' At this session, the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> is a major player and is seen, far more than the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, as a team player in the world body. The <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> has been calling for a larger and more powerful role for the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> in multilateral arms negotiations, disarmament verification and monitoring, expanded peacekeeping operations and crisis management. It has called for a new <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> naval peacekeeping force and <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> space agency. But the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, more than $ 400 million in arrears in <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> dues, does n't want to see expanded <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> operations infringe on traditional areas of national prerogative. <PERSON> Eduard </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shevardnadze </PERSON>, the Soviet foreign minister, unfurled a sweeping blueprint of disarmament proposals and in a grand gesture, invited the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> secretary-general, <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> and nonaligned leaders to attend the first Soviet destruction of intermediate-range nuclear missiles. `` The first and perhaps the hardest thing to do,'' <PERSON> Shevardnadze </PERSON> said, `` is to abandon the myth of nuclear weapons as the guarantor of peace ... We are convinced that ensuring security by non-nuclear means is possible.'' The speech initially was praised by <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. Ambassador <PERSON> Vernon </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Walters </PERSON> as constructive and deserving of study. But <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials have not responded to specific proposals, such as a permanent moratorium on nuclear testing, slashing conventional armies in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> by 500,000 soldiers each, and announcement of port calls by warships with or without nuclear arms. Secretary of State <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> outlined the standard <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> positions. He emphasized the dangers of proliferation in nuclear, conventional, ballistic, chemical and other weapons and cited the dangers of the Iran-Iraq war and the rivalry between <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>. He did not mention the Soviet proposals. British Foreign Secretary Sir <PERSON> Geoffrey </PERSON> <PERSON> Howe </PERSON> sounded the theme of nuclear deterrence _ considered anathema to most <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> delegates. `` It may be that one day we shall find a better way to prevent war than through nuclear deterrence,'' he told the <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION>. `` But to suggest that between East and West such an alternative is within reach is to deny reality.'' Meanwhile, 12-year-old <PERSON> Michelle </PERSON> <PERSON> Robyn </PERSON> <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Fresno </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, was promoting her game, `` Give Peace a Chance,'' and saying her dream was to play it with Soviet leader <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>. She said she still was waiting for a White House response.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880625-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-25-88 0112EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-AsbestosComplaint     06-25 0251</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Asbestos Complaint,0258</SECOND>
<HEAD>Suburban School First In Nation To Be Cited Under Asbestos Removal
Rules</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LINDSEY TANNER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CHICAGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Unaccredited workers botched asbestos removal at a high school and exposed students to cancer-causing fibers, the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> charged Friday in its first enforcement of new regulations. The agency, which proposed a $ 5,000 fine, said 6,400 square feet of asbestos-containing floor tiles were improperly removed in February from a hallway at <ORGANIZATION> Thornton </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Township </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> High </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> in suburban <PERSON> Harvey </PERSON>. Workers who were not accredited by the <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> `` had sanded, chipped and cut the tiles, releasing clouds of dust containing asbestos,'' the agency said in a statement. The district overseeing the school in southwest suburban <PERSON> Harvey </PERSON> failed to `` post signs and restrict the affected area to only those persons necessary to do tile removal and cleanup,'' the <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> said. School officials have until July 11 to respond to the complaint. They can either seek an informal hearing with <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> officials in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> or request a hearing before a federal administrative law judge, <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON> said. The school was closed Friday afternoon and officials could not be reached for comment. Ms. <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON> said school officials did not know the tiles contained asbestos when the removal began, but suspected they might and ordered tests. The <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> called the complaint its first enforcement action nationwide under last year's Asbestos Hazard Emergency Response Act, which specifies procedures for removing asbestos in public and private elementary and secondary schools.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880625-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-25-88 0113EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-RecordSession     06-25 0710</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Record Session,0735</SECOND>
<HEAD>Arizona's `Walking Wounded' Surpass Record In Legislative Session</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Saturday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By LARRY LOPEZ</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PHOENIX, Ariz. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Two years of turmoil has taken a physical toll of <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION>'s lawmakers, who had to deal with the governor's time-consuming impeachment trial and face raising taxes $ 200 million just months before re-election bids Their current session set a record Friday as the longest in state history and they're far from finished with their business. `` I do n't think there's a member here who's not among the walking wounded,'' said House Minority Leader <PERSON> Art </PERSON> <PERSON> Hamilton </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Phoenix </LOCATION> Democrat. `` I'm just exhausted,'' said <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Majority Leader <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Usdane </PERSON>, a Republican from <LOCATION> Scottsdale </LOCATION>. `` It does n't feel good,'' said House Speaker <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Lane </PERSON>. Friday was the 166th day of the session, but taxes, budgets, and about 50 other pieces of legislation are still not settled. And the lawmakers are operating on reduced pay, increased fatigue and, in some cases, worse health. In theory, legislative sessions are supposed to end by the Saturday of the week in which the 100th day falls. But the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> impeachment and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> trial of Gov. <PERSON> Evan </PERSON> <PERSON> Mecham </PERSON> took weeks out of each chamber's schedule this year. And the trauma started last year, when <PERSON> Mecham </PERSON> faced off against a largely inexperienced set of legislative leaders. The stage was set in 1986, when then-Gov. <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Babbitt </PERSON> decided to run for president, <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Majority Leader <PERSON> Burton </PERSON> <PERSON> Barr </PERSON> decided to run for governor, Speaker <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Sossaman </PERSON> ran for <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> President <PERSON> Stan </PERSON> <PERSON> Turley </PERSON> and Minority Leader <PERSON> Alfredo </PERSON> <PERSON> Gutierrez </PERSON> retired. <PERSON> Mecham </PERSON> beat <PERSON> Barr </PERSON> in a rough Republican primary election and clashed repeatedly with the Republican-controlled legislature, until this year when the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> ousted him on April 4. Now, <PERSON> Mecham </PERSON> loyalists are vowing revenge at the polls and Democrats are drooling at the prospect of increased numbers in both chambers. Many Republican incumbents simply are n't running for re-election, and others, such as <PERSON> Lane </PERSON>, face uphill election fights _ if they find the time to gather signatures on their nominating petitions before the June 30 deadline. Among the casualties: _ <PERSON> Hal </PERSON> <PERSON> Runyan </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>'s majority whip, suffered a stroke while undergoing an operation and is confined to a wheelchair. He comes in only for key votes and will not seek re-election. _ <PERSON> Greg </PERSON> <PERSON> Lunn </PERSON>, touted as one of the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION>'s rising young stars, aggravated a pre-ulcerous condition and has decided to run for county supervisor instead of re-election. _ <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Ratliff </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> majority leader, suffered a heart attack and is retiring. _ Sterling Ridge, a <LOCATION> Glendale </LOCATION> Republican, also is retiring, citing health reasons. <PERSON> Hamilton </PERSON>, in his 16th year as a representative, said it was a very stressful session. `` It is the cumulative effect of the <PERSON> Mecham </PERSON> administration and the kind of meanness that was there _ all of this madness.'' <PERSON> Hamilton </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Democratic leader <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Stephens </PERSON> say <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> leaders bear some of the blame for allowing the session to continue drifting along. `` We've been putting things off and putting things off and putting things off,'' said <PERSON> Stephens </PERSON>, who estimated that 75 bills were languishing without debate while lawmakers cool their heels. `` To paraphrase <PERSON> Winston </PERSON> <PERSON> Churchill </PERSON>, ` Never have so many worked for so long for so little,''' <PERSON> Hamilton </PERSON> said Thursday after <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Finance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Jeff </PERSON> <PERSON> Hill </PERSON> staged his second walkout of the week, spiking a tentative tax agreement. Other than <PERSON> Mecham </PERSON>'s impeachment, lawmakers faced three major issues this year: air quality, indigent health care, and a state budget of about $ 3 billion. An air-quality bill is on the governor's desk, but there's no agreement on indigent health or budgets. Lawmakers draw salaries of $ 15,000 a year and extended their regular expense pay for 30 days beyond the normal 120-day limit, but since then they have been operating on reduced pay of $ 10 a day for Phoenix-area lawmakers and $ 20 a day for those from outside <LOCATION> Maricopa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>. Some grouchiness is a standard feature at every end-of-session crunch as lawmakers confront issues they avoided at first. But between the <PERSON> Mecham </PERSON> trial's unheeled scars and the prospect of election fights ahead, lawmakers, lobbyists and others say things seem worse than usual. `` It just is n't as much fun,'' said <PERSON> Lunn </PERSON>. The previous record, 165 days, was set in 1976.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880625-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-25-88 0117EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--Soviet-Lake     06-25 0152</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Soviet-Lake,0156</SECOND>
<HEAD>Kazkahstan Stops Irrigation Plans, Citing Danger To Lake</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MOSCOW (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Authorities in the Soviet republic of <LOCATION> Kazakhstan </LOCATION> have bowed to public pressure and decided to halt two controversial irrigation projects that would have damaged a vast inland lake, <ORGANIZATION> TASS </ORGANIZATION> reported. The official news agency said Friday that the projects were halted because studies showed they would cause the water level of <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Balkhash </LOCATION> to drop sharply. The lake, located in <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION>, covers 320 square miles. <ORGANIZATION> TASS </ORGANIZATION> said the decision was preceded by a campaign of letters and articles in <LOCATION> Kazakhstan </LOCATION>'s state-run media against the scheme. The lake in eastern <LOCATION> Kazakhstan </LOCATION> helps modify the dry, scorching climate of the area, home to about 2.5 million people, <ORGANIZATION> TASS </ORGANIZATION> said. Since <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> came to power in 1985, Soviet authorities have stopped a number of controversial large-scale projects that scientists say would have done irreversible damage to the environment.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880625-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-25-88 0136EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Paraguay-Drugs     06-25 0238</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Paraguay-Drugs,0244</SECOND>
<HEAD>DEA Agents, Paraguayan Police Break Up Drug Network</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ASUNCION, Paraguay (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> drug agents and Paraguayan police captured three alleged drug smugglers and seized 590 pounds of cocaine shortly before the drugs were supposed to go to <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, a newspaper reported. In an attempt to break what <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Drug </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Enforcement </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> agents called the `` <LOCATION> Asuncion </LOCATION> Connection,'' police arrested a Bolivian and two Colombians last Saturday. The trio allegedly were couriers for the notorious <LOCATION> Medellin </LOCATION> drug cartel of <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION>, the daily independent Hoy reported Friday. <PERSON> Hoy </PERSON> said 222 packages of 97 percent pure cocaine, worth about $ 100 million, were found jammed in nine suitcases at <LOCATION> Asuncion </LOCATION>'s airport hours before a regularly scheduled commercial flight to <LOCATION> Madrid </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION> It was the largest drug bust in <LOCATION> Paraguay </LOCATION> since 1982, when 92 pounds of cocaine were found at a ranch, 217 miles northeast of <LOCATION> Asuncion </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Drug </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Enforcement </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> agents have been working with <LOCATION> Paraguayan </LOCATION> police since December when they re-opened an office in the capital to counter the growing drug trade in this landlocked <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> nation Investigators say private aircraft registered in bordering <LOCATION> Bolivia </LOCATION> were used to drop the cocaine at a ranch in the remote Chaco region of western <LOCATION> Paraguay </LOCATION>. From there, the cocaine was flown to <LOCATION> Asuncion </LOCATION> in other small planes, the newspaper said. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials say the <PERSON> Medillin </PERSON> cartel sends to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> about 80 percent of the cocaine consumed in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880625-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-25-88 0134EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-MysteriousStones Bjt   06-25 0657</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Mysterious Stones, Bjt,0672</SECOND>
<HEAD>Stone Circles In Western Maryland Puzzle Residents, Archaelogists</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto BA1</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DEB RIECHMANN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>FLINTSTONE, Md. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 They could have been cremation pits, cock-fighting rings, animal pens, Civil War foxholes or secret hiding places for moonshine equipment. Maybe they were prehistoric Indian burial sites, charcoal pits or foundations for native American abodes. Or maybe, some say, the stone circles dotting the western slope of Polish Mountain encircled apple trees in the early 1900s. For more than a decade, 150 to 200 circles of sandstone rock have puzzled area residents and archaelogists. Virtually hidden by brush and poison ivy, the gray-colored rocks of various shapes and sizes are neatly arranged in circles. No one knows their purpose, or who put them there. `` Everybody that goes up there has some kind of weird theory,'' said <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Mash </PERSON>, manager of <LOCATION> Green </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ridge </LOCATION> <LOCATION> State </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Forest </LOCATION>, where the circles are found. `` One guy even mentioned that they could have been sweat lodges _ like a Turkish bath. `` The Indians would have these rituals when they would go into manhood,'' he said. `` They would go in these buildings with hot rocks and put water on them _ something like a sauna.'' But 150 to 200 saunas on one hillside in western <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION>? <PERSON> Mash </PERSON> said rangers noticed the stone rings in the early 1970s. In 1975, <PERSON> Mash </PERSON> contacted State Archaeologist <PERSON> Tyler </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bastian </PERSON>, who visited the site and put the circles on a list of archaeological areas in <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION>. But it was not until last year that some archaelogists and volunteers excavated one of the circles. `` They did the dig and found zip, except for the rattlesnakes,'' <PERSON> Mash </PERSON> said. Hoping to uncover clues, another group conducted a dig this spring. `` In a nutshell, we did n't discover anything. They still remain a mystery,'' said <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> McVeigh </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, a member of the <ORGANIZATION> Western </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Maryland </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Archaeological </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION>. `` We dug out in the center of them. We did n't go down very far before we got to bedrock. We found no artifacts. We found nothing to indicate prehistoric use.'' No future digs are planned, and two local archaeologists who took an interest in the circles, <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Wall </PERSON> and <PERSON> Connie </PERSON> <PERSON> Huddleston </PERSON>, both have moved from <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION>. Neither could be reached for comment recently. Meanwhile, the state forest has put the circles on its historic preservation list to ensure the five-acre tract remains untouched, <PERSON> Mash </PERSON> said. The site could be eligible for the National Register of Historic Places if additional information could be found to document the age of the rings, their use and significance. <PERSON> Mash </PERSON> has dismissed the moonshine theory because there is no nearby water source needed to make moonshine. He said he did not think they were cock-fighting rings because only one pit is needed to hold a fight. And the rings are too close together to have been foxholes during the Civil War, he said. `` The site has no strategic value,'' <PERSON> Mash </PERSON> said. `` -LRB- And -RRB- the guy in the middle foxhole is going to be shooting his own pals before he can get his bullet out to hit the bad guys.'' Until someone conjures up a more believable theory, <PERSON> Mash </PERSON> said he puts the most stock in the orchard theory _ that someone placed the stones around apple trees that once grew in the area. There were 1 million apple trees in <LOCATION> Green </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ridge </LOCATION> by 1914, he said. `` It is possible that they hired immigrants who could not understand directions given in English and some of them were told to clear the rocks away to plant the apple trees,'' he suggested. `` They were new in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> and wanted to do a nice, neat job, so they put these rocks in nice neat little circles and left a space in the middle for the tree. And they might have worked on these for a couple of days, or a week until somebody stopped them. That could be a theory ...''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880625-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-25-88 0136EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--Soviet-Floods     06-25 0123</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Soviet-Floods,0128</SECOND>
<HEAD>Floods Damage Crops, Homes, Roads In Western Ukraine</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MOSCOW (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Torrential rains have caused flooding that has ruined crops, roads, homes and bridges in the western <LOCATION> Ukraine </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> TASS </ORGANIZATION> said. A report said Friday that rainfall over the past 20 days in the western <LOCATION> Ukraine </LOCATION> had exceeded the average precipitation for two months. The rivers <LOCATION> Pripyat </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Stokhod </PERSON> have burst their banks, flooding 573,040 acres planted with crops and more than 296,400 acres of pasture for cattle, <ORGANIZATION> TASS </ORGANIZATION> said. Roads, bridges, dykes and buildings have also been damaged, it added. It said special food supplies and youth brigades had been sent to affected areas to help alleviate the situation and repair the damage. There were no reports of any casualties.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880625-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-25-88 0616EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--PuppySkinning     06-25 0159</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Puppy Skinning,0163</SECOND>
<HEAD>Cambodian Immigrants Jailed In Death and Skinning of Puppy</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Contents may be offensive to some readers</NOTE>
<DATELINE>LONG BEACH, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Two Cambodian immigrants were jailed after police discovered a partially skinned puppy with its throat slit lying in a pool of blood on the men's kitchen floor, officials said. Neighbors who heard the puppy's whining as it was allegedly being beaten to death called officers Thursday night to an apartment in a predominantly <LOCATION> Cambodian </LOCATION> neighborhood, said police Sgt. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Bauer </PERSON>. <PERSON> Caea </PERSON> <PERSON> Sokheng </PERSON> and <PERSON> Ou </PERSON> <PERSON> Seng </PERSON> <PERSON> K </PERSON>, both 32, were arrested and booked for investigation of felony cruelty to animals, <PERSON> Bauer </PERSON> said. `` Well, our guys found the dead dog in the kitchen so you can draw your own conclusions,'' the sergeant said. Investigators estimated the dead puppy was 4 months old. Another puppy of similar age was rescued unharmed from the apartment, <PERSON> Bauer </PERSON> said. Both men denied ownership of the dead dog, he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880625-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-25-88 0022EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a PM-Names     06-25 0835</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0874</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in the News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Pop singer <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> will undergo surgery next week to remove a cyst from his vocal cords, forcing him to cancel the rest of his scheduled performances in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, a spokesman says. The operation will be performed Wednesday at an undisclosed <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> hospital, publicist <PERSON> Phil </PERSON> <PERSON> Lobel </PERSON> said Friday. `` It will be four weeks before <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> can sing again,'' <PERSON> Lobel </PERSON> said. Exploratory surgery this week found the cyst, he said. `` While I am very sad that I will have to disappoint my fans,'' <PERSON> Michael </PERSON>, 25, said in a statement, `` I am at least relieved that at long last the real reason for my problems has been discovered.'' Throat problems forced <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> to drop 20 shows in <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION> at the beginning of his tour in March, and he had feared he would lose his voice. The remainder of <PERSON> Michael </PERSON>'s European tour was canceled, but the <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> leg of his world `` Faith Tour'' will proceed as planned beginning Aug. 6 at the <ORGANIZATION> Capitol </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> D.C </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>FULTON, Mo. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> reminisced about his acting days in a telegram to this central Missouri town, saying a scene in the movie `` Kings Row'' was the finest he ever did. The 1941 movie was based on a book of the same name about growing up in <LOCATION> Fulton </LOCATION>, which is holding its Kingdom Days celebration this weekend. In the scene, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, waking up after a leg has been amputated, screams, `` Where's the rest of me?'' `` We did this scene without rehearsal and you know or will soon see the results,'' he said in the telegram Friday. `` I do n't believe I ever did quite as well again in a single shot. The movie is to be screened during Kingdom Days, held to celebrate the Civil War heritage of <LOCATION> Callaway </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Cummings </PERSON>, who starred with <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> in the movie, is scheduled to appear and clothes worn in the movie will be displayed.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NASHVILLE, Tenn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 When entertainer <PERSON> Roy </PERSON> <PERSON> Clark </PERSON> takes his down-home brand of music to the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> this fall, he'll be broadening his guitar-picking repertoire to include Russian folksongs. `` It will be a country version of a balalaika orchestra,'' <PERSON> Clark </PERSON> told a news conference Thursday. <PERSON> Clark </PERSON> plans 12 November performances as part of `` The Friendship Tour,'' a venture partly underwritten by the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Information </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> and the Soviet concert agency Gosconcert. To raise additional funds, $ 2 postcards are being sold through a nationwide radio network. <PERSON> Clark </PERSON> said he plans to present the giant collection of postcards to Soviet leader <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> as a goodwill gesture. `` There was no other way to say ` I represent the American people' unless they were involved,'' the musician said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 `` Dirty Dancing'' star <PERSON> Patrick </PERSON> <PERSON> Swayze </PERSON> says his next dance film will be his last, and will co-star his wife, <PERSON> Lisa </PERSON> <PERSON> Niemi </PERSON>. `` I've had so much knee surgery; I think I have only one major dance film left in me. <PERSON> Lisa </PERSON> and I will do it together,'' <PERSON> Swayze </PERSON> said in an interview published in <ORGANIZATION> Vogue </ORGANIZATION> magazine's July issue. <PERSON> Swayze </PERSON> says he and his wife are more than just a marriage. `` When I move with <PERSON> Lisa </PERSON>, something electric happens,'' he said. They have been married 11 years, and met at his mother's dancing school in <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION>. `` <PERSON> Lisa </PERSON> and I are in this together. She's as much the reason for my success as ` Dirty Dancing.' This is a partnership. I just got noticed first,'' he said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NORTH PLATTE, Neb. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Boxleitner </PERSON>, who says he'd pay to act in westerns, was named the annual Buffalo Bill Award winner for his commitment to family entertainment. Friday's award was part of the Nebraskaland Days celebration here. It is named for <PERSON> Buffalo </PERSON> <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Cody </PERSON>, the world's first rodeo producer who took his Wild West Show from North Platte on tours around the world. Previous recipients include western novelist <PERSON> Louis </PERSON> <PERSON> L'Amour </PERSON> and actors <PERSON> Gene </PERSON> <PERSON> Autrey </PERSON> and <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> Fonda </PERSON>. Working in westerns is challenging, said <PERSON> Boxleitner </PERSON>, 38, who starred in the TV series `` Scarecrow and Mrs. King'' and in two `` Gambler'' movies with <PERSON> Kenny </PERSON> <PERSON> Rogers </PERSON>. `` It's not <PERSON> Shakespeare </PERSON>, but you have to learn the tools of the trade,'' he said. `` I do n't think a pay check enters into it. I'd pay them.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actor <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> Matthau </PERSON>'s wife, <PERSON> Carol </PERSON>, says she is writing a book about <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION> called `` The Wrong Color Green.'' `` All the cliches about this never-never land are true, yet nobody has written successfully about it,'' she said in the July-August issue of <PERSON> Lear </PERSON>'s magazine. `` There is no ` they' who destroy you here. ... You are your own villain.'' Mrs. <PERSON> Matthau </PERSON>, an actress who was twice married to playwright <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Saroyan </PERSON> before her 28-year union with the actor, says she never told her husband when she finally decided to make her dream of being a writer come true. `` I never said a word about it to him. -LRB- I -RRB- just started writing,'' she said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880625-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-25-88 0138EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lottery     06-25 0025</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lottery,0024</SECOND>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the winning weekly state lottery numbers picked Friday:
</TEXT>
<HEAD>CONNECTICUT</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Lotto: 01; 09; 14; 16; 19; 20.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880625-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-25-88 0138EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-LotteryRdp     06-25 0083</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lottery Rdp,0088</SECOND>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the winning weekly state lottery numbers picked so far this week:
</TEXT>
<HEAD>CONNECTICUT</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Lotto: 01; 09; 14; 16; 19; 20.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>DELAWARE</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Play 4: 6-7-1-6.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>MASSACHUSETTS</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Wednesday Megabucks: 05; 09; 23; 28; 32; 35.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>NEW JERSEY</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Pick 6 Lotto: 08; 09; 12; 18; 23; 38. Bonus: 31438.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>NEW YORK</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Wednesday Lotto 54 Game: 06; 23; 26; 34; 43; 44. Supplementary 05.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>PENNSYLVANIA</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Big 4 Lottery: 4-3-8-2.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>RHODE ISLAND</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Grand Lot Game: 7-7-6; 8-3-4-9; 7-8-5-9-3; 6-6-4-1-0-2.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880625-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-25-88 0144EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Drought-BOTScene     06-25 0758</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Drought-BOT Scene,0776</SECOND>
<HEAD>Drought Quickens Pace At Bustling Board Of Trade</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Saturday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By DAVID DISHNEAU</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CHICAGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 High atop the <ORGANIZATION> Chicago </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Trade </ORGANIZATION> building a statue of <LOCATION> Ceres </LOCATION>, the Roman goddess of grain, stared unflinchingly into the searing, cloudless sky. If anybody was praying to her for rain, she had n't heard them. Besides, the whispered plea of an <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> corn farmer would n't stand a chance against the din from the floor of the world's oldest and largest grain exchange, where bushels of grain are traded in millions and blessings are counted in dollars The <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Trade </ORGANIZATION>'s grain floor, abandoned by many traders when prices and trading activity slumped in the mid-1980s, is filled these days with people looking to profit from the Midwestern drought. As the drought withers crops across the Farm Belt, it ignites big rallies on commodity exchanges, where contracts for future delivery of grain grow more precious by the day. `` This is the only place I could think of where I can make a lot of money in a fairly short period of time,'' said <PERSON> Brad </PERSON> <PERSON> Whitacre </PERSON>, 21, an entry-level employee of a large investment firm who dreams of owning his own seat on the exchange. <PERSON> Whitacre </PERSON>'s job is to stand just outside the apparent chaos of the jam-packed corn futures pit and report to his boss on the moves of the market's major players. He has put his college education on hold for this opportunity, which was created by the dramatic rise in trading activity accompanying the drought-driven jump in prices. `` If you start out working at a corporation it takes years to work your way up to the top,'' <PERSON> Whitacre </PERSON> said. `` But you come down here, after a couple of years you buy a seat, and you can be making a lot of money.'' How much? `` Your imagination's the only limit.'' <PERSON> Whitacre </PERSON> is n't the only one lured to the Board of Trade by one of the biggest grain rallies in the exchange's 140-year history. The population of the grain trading floor has swelled more than 40 percent to nearly 2,000 in just the past two months, according to exchange figures. About half of those people are traders. Their job is to face each other on the steps of circular pits and use a combination of hand signals and shouted bids to strike deals for deliveries of grain and soybeans in 5,000-bushel lots. Big trading companies such as <ORGANIZATION> Refco </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> and C & amp; D Commodities frequently trade thousands of contracts, totaling millions of bushels, during a session. Perhaps a third of the traders are independents, called `` locals'' or `` scalpers,'' who trade for their own accounts and drift from pit to pit in search of action. When grain trading slowed after the volatile, dry-weather period of late 1983 and early 1984, many locals moved to the exchange's financial-futures room to bet on the performance of stocks and bonds. Because of its boisterous nature, trading in the pits is usually perceived as a young person's game. But among the recent returnees to the grain room are a good number of silver-haired veterans, some of whom say their experience gives them an edge. `` I can tell what's going on standing here with a blindfold on,'' said 74-year-old <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> McGuire </PERSON>, a former <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Trade </ORGANIZATION> chairman, as he surveyed the scene from the sidelines while waiting for the right moment to strike. `` I can tell whether the markets are going up or down by the sound.'' Although this is the fifth significant dry-weather boom the grain markets have seen since the record-setting rally of 1973, the timing and severity of this drought makes it unique, traders said. `` Nobody here has ever really traded -LRB- on -RRB- the fear of a real potential disaster,'' said one trader who asked not to be identified. `` That's what makes this market different from any other time in history.'' Independent traders resent the perception that they seek to profit from the nation's misfortune, a view that inspired a recent <ORGANIZATION> Chicago </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tribune </ORGANIZATION> editorial cartoon depicting commodity traders as vultures descending on a drought-stricken farmer. `` When the traders start to make a little money, some people begrudge it to us but they do n't realize we've had a severely depressed business here the last four years,'' said <PERSON> Bernard </PERSON> <PERSON> Dorman </PERSON>, an independent grain trader who also runs a small trading company. `` We feel very badly that the farmers are hurt but we ca n't do anything about that,'' <PERSON> Dorman </PERSON> said. `` We just follow the market, we do n't make the market.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880625-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-25-88 0144EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FordAmbulances     06-25 0333</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Ford Ambulances,330</SECOND>
<HEAD>Ambulance Association Asks Probe of Ford Recall</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TIM BOVEE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Ambulance operators say <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Motor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> may have done an inadequate job of repairing up to 14,500 fire-prone ambulances, and they are calling for an investigation by federal transportation officials. <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> counters that its recall work on the ambulances has been more than adequate and that some ambulance operators have been slow to bring in the vehicles for repairs. The <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ambulance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, a Washington-based organization representing private ambulance operators, said Friday in a letter to the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Highway </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Traffic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> that it had received reports of long delays, unavailable parts, shoddy work and added bills for fixing the ambulances. `` It would appear that a significant number of ambulances are still not fully retrofitted,'' the association wrote. <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> recalled about 14,500 of the vehicles, converted to ambulances by other companies from the 1983-1987 <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Econoline </ORGANIZATION> E-350 models, after reports of fuel-system problems that caused fires. The recall came in two phases, one in July 1987 for rerouting of the fuel line and a second in August 1987 for installation of further safety precautions. More than 20 fires were reported and were blamed on overpressurization of fuel tanks and lines caused by muffler heat. `` We feel -LRB- the recall -RRB- is certainly more than adequate,'' said <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Parris </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> spokesman in <LOCATION> Dearborn </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mich. </LOCATION> `` We're concerned with it. We do n't take it lightly at all. We do n't drag our feet. ... We've made every effort to try to get these people in here to get this recall taken care of.'' He said some 700 Ford dealers had parts available for the recall work. `` If these people will bring these vehicles in, they can have it done,'' <PERSON> Parris </PERSON> said. Eighty percent of the recalled ambulances were brought in for the first phase of work, but only 65 percent have undergone the second phase, <PERSON> Parris </PERSON> said. <ORGANIZATION> NHTSA </ORGANIZATION> has 120 days to respond to the ambulance association's petition
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880625-0025 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-25-88 0144EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Candidates-Schedules     06-25 0194</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Candidates-Schedules,200</SECOND>
<HEAD>Presidential Candidates' Schedules</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are tentative schedules for the presidential candidates for the week beginning June 26. The information was provided by the candidates. Sunday, June 26: Democrats: <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> Nantucket </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mass </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> Puerto </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rico </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> Republican: <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> Columbus </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> Monday, June 27: Democrats: <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> Nantucket </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jackson </LOCATION> _ <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.J. </LOCATION> Republican: <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION> Tuesday, June 28: Democrats: <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jackson </LOCATION> _ <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> Republican: <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> overnight -RRB- Wednesday, June 29: Democrats: <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> Midwestern </LOCATION> swing <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION>; <ORGANIZATION> Chicago </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION>: <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION> Thursday, June 30: Democrats: <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> Midwestern </LOCATION> swing <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> _ open Republican: <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION> Friday, July 1: Democrats: <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> _ open <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> _ open Republican: <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> Kennebunkport </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION> Saturday, July 2: Democrats: <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> _ open <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> _ open Republican: <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> Kennebunkport </LOCATION> Sunday, July 3: Democrats: <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> _ open <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> _ open Republican: <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> Kennebunkport </LOCATION>
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880625-0026 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-25-88 0148EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-DefenseProbe-Glance     06-25 0419</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Defense Probe-Glance,400</SECOND>
<HEAD>Latest Developments In Defense Probe</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Defense Probe Bjt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are highlights of the latest developments in the investigation into allegations of fraud and bribes paid by defense contractors and consultants to procurement officials in the Defense Department:
</TEXT>
<HEAD>INVESTIGATORS REPORTEDLY HAVE VIDEOTAPES OF BRIBES</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Federal investigators have videotapes of defense consultants allegedly bribing <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> officials for inside information, <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> reported. The <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> officials on the tapes are Deputy Assistant Secretary of the Air Force <PERSON> Victor </PERSON> <PERSON> Cohen </PERSON> and Deputy Assistant Secretary of the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Gaines </PERSON>, and the consultants on the tapes include <PERSON> Melvyn </PERSON> <PERSON> Paisley </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> reported. Attorneys for <PERSON> Paisley </PERSON> and <PERSON> Gaines </PERSON> refused comment on the content of the report while <PERSON> Cohen </PERSON>'s attorney was not immediately available for comment.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>COMMITTEE CONSIDERS A BAN ON PAYMENTS</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Finance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> briefly considered a proposal that would have allowed the government to suspend payments to defense contractors under investigation in the case. The panel took no action.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>CONSULTANT'S FIRM PAID WIFE OF EX-NAVY OFFICIAL UP TO $50,000</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> VAMO </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, a <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> firm incorporated by <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Galvin </PERSON>, a consultant to defense contractors, paid up to $ 50,000 in 1986 to <PERSON> Vicki </PERSON> <PERSON> Paisley </PERSON>, the wife of the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>'s then-procurement chief, <PERSON> Melvyn </PERSON> <PERSON> Paisley </PERSON>. Federal investigators have searched the offices of both <PERSON> Galvin </PERSON> and <PERSON> Paisley </PERSON>, who left government service in 1987 to become a defense consultant.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>SENATOR SAYS RE-NEGOTIATIONS MAY BE NEEDED</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 In a television interview, Sen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Warner </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Va </LOCATION>., a former <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> secretary, said that if a substantial number of contracts turn out to have been tainted, they will have to be renegotiated `` And that's a tough, tough problem, because those contracts are producing essential goods to our national defense today,'' <ORGANIZATION> Warner </ORGANIZATION> said.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>MEESE COMMENTS</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Attorney General <PERSON> Edwin </PERSON> <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>, asked about the probe's status, said he did not know `` whether it will expand at all,'' adding: `` It's at the normal stage of an investigation ... where you're collecting information, you're analyzing information and then you're determining what the next steps might be.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>COMPANY WANTS TO SEE AFFIDAVIT</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 An attorney for <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Technologies </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> said he has asked <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Pratt </PERSON> to allow the company to examine a government affidavit supporting a search warrant that the judge had issued. The warrant enabled <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> agents to search the <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> office of <PERSON> Eugene </PERSON> <PERSON> Tallia </PERSON>, a vice president for <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> operations of the company's <ORGANIZATION> Pratt </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <LOCATION> Whitney </LOCATION> engine manufacturing unit. Company lawyers said they wanted to determine whether the search was proper.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880625-0027 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-25-88 0154EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Salvador-Relief     06-25 0290</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Salvador-Relief,0298</SECOND>
<HEAD>Church Charges Army Prevented Delivery Of Supplies To Refugees</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SAN SALVADOR, El Salvador (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Representatives from eight <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> churches say <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>'s army stopped them from delivering food, medicine and fertilizer to resettled refugees in northern <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>. Eight representatives of <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Area </LOCATION> churches and synagogues told a news conference Friday that the <ORGANIZATION> 4th </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Brigade </ORGANIZATION> blocked their three-truck convoy on June 16. The convoy, which was carrying about $ 7,000 worth of supplies, was stopped in <LOCATION> Chalatenango </LOCATION>, the capital of the northern province of the same name. The supplies, which were bound for the towns of <LOCATION> Guarjila </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ranchos </LOCATION>, were left in a convent in the town while efforts to deliver them continued, the church workers said. Leftist guerrillas battling the U.S.-backed government of President <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Napoleon </PERSON> <PERSON> Duarte </PERSON> maintain a strong military and political presence in much of <LOCATION> Chalatenango </LOCATION> province. <PERSON> Dean </PERSON> <PERSON> McFalls </PERSON>, a member of the church group and a student at the <ORGANIZATION> Pacific </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Religion </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Berkeley </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, said the delegation had obtained permission to deliver the supplies from military officials in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION> before leaving for the region. <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ranchos </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Guarjila </LOCATION> were evacuated in the early 1980s because of heavy fighting in the civil war. The towns were resettled last fall under the auspices of the non-governmental <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> for Repopulation. They now have a combined population of about 1,800. Over the past year the armed forces have allowed some relief shipments to reach their destinations but have held up others. Military authorities have expressed concern the supplies might end up in rebel hands. People who answered the phone at 4th Brigade headquarters and the army's public relations office said no one was immediately available for comment on the blocked convoy.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880625-0028 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-25-88 0604EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-PentagonSpending     06-25 0330</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Pentagon Spending,330</SECOND>
<HEAD>Pentagon Relaxes Some Spending Limits After Cost-Cutting Freeze</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> plans to resume offering contracts for research and consulting work next month but other restrictions on military spending will remain in effect in order to hold down costs. Deputy Defense Secretary <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Taft </PERSON> <PERSON> IV </PERSON> on Friday announced plans to relax a freeze on outside contracting for supplies and services starting July 1. The freeze had been imposed in May to limit spending in fiscal 1988, which ends on Sept. 30. <PERSON> Taft </PERSON> said Friday he would begin allowing some new contracts to be awarded for research, development and evaluation work and for consultant services on July 1. But all other restrictions remain in effect, including a ban on purchases of office supplies, an end to overtime pay and limits on civilian hiring, <PERSON> Taft </PERSON> said. Active-duty personnel and civilian employees also can forget collecting their Oct. 1 paychecks a day early just because Oct. 1 falls on a Saturday, <PERSON> Taft </PERSON> declared. The Pentagon does n't want any extra outlays before the current fiscal year ends, he wrote in a memo to <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> offices. The <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION>'s No. 2 executive said he still wanted some controls on the research and consultant contracts, however, specifying that `` total obligations during any month of the fourth quarter may not exceed 75 percent of the average monthly obligations incurred to date.'' The ban on new purchases of office supplies and other equipment will continue to cover everything from magazine and newspaper subscriptions to TV sets, library materials, recreation equipment, lawnmowers and furniture, tools, paint, lumber, air conditioners and fork lifts, he said. Also still prohibited is any spending on new leases for cars, office space or computer equipment. The spending restrictions originally were promulgated by <PERSON> Taft </PERSON> to comply with a deficit-reduction compromise reached last November by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration. That compromise was crafted to control government outlays _ the amount of money actually paid out during the fiscal year.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880625-0029 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-25-88 0155EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-HazardousMail     06-25 0381</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Hazardous Mail,350</SECOND>
<HEAD>Dangerous Biological Agents To Be Banned From Mail</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Postal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> is proposing new rules to ban germs and dangerous toxins from the mail just as the military reportedly was planning to increase shipments of such materials. The regulations were announced Friday, but must go through a formal rule-making process before they take effect. The <ORGANIZATION> Postal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> said it took the action because of concern `` that some customers are planning increased use of the mails for sending disease germs or hazardous toxins -LRB- etiologic agents -RRB-.'' <PERSON> Jeremy </PERSON> <PERSON> Rifkin </PERSON>, an activist who heads the <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> on </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Trends </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, hailed the decision as a step toward avoiding a potential catastrophe. He had petitioned the <ORGANIZATION> Postal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> to ban such shipments. <PERSON> Rifkin </PERSON> said he plans to push the <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> to investigate shipments of dangerous products by private carriers. Various products, including biological warfare toxins, have been mailed in the past under strict packaging and labeling rules, and postal officials say no problems have occurred. But following reports that the Army planed to expand research facilities in <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> Attorney General <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Van </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Kamp </PERSON> complained that the need for increased shipments of dangerous biological products could create a hazard. Army officials have told a <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> subcommittee that they actually ship very few parcels containing biological items, and those almost always by private, commercial carrier. The packages have been tested and are literally able to survive an aircraft or highway crash, said <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Dashiell </PERSON>, director of environmental and life sciences at the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>. While attention has focused on shipments of germs and toxins by the military, the federal <ORGANIZATION> Centers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Disease </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Control </ORGANIZATION> and other medical establishments also make such shipments, officials report. `` Our experience to date seems to support the opinion, expressed by medical experts, that there is little risk associated with handling properly packaged etiologic agents,'' Postmaster General <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON> <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> said in a letter to <PERSON> Rifkin </PERSON>. The planned new rules would cover dangerous items, but would not affect the mailing of blood samples and other such materials being sent to laboratories for routine medical testing, the <ORGANIZATION> Postal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> said. Postal regulations already prohibit the mailing of a variety of items, including strike-anywhere matches, explosives, fuses, many poisons, most flammable liquids and certain chemicals.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880625-0030 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-25-88 0156EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Politics-Quotes 220   06-25 0218</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Politics-Quotes, 220</SECOND>
<HEAD>Quotes From The Presidential Campaign Trail</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
