<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881017-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-17-88 2333EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-Storm-O'Hare     10-17 0384</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Storm-O'Hare,0395</SECOND>
<HEAD>Powerful Storm Rips Central Illinois, Snarls Air Traffic</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CHICAGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A fast-moving storm raked central and northern <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> with hail and high winds on Monday, delaying hundreds of flights at <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> airports, and forcing the evacuation of two schools and a factory near <LOCATION> Peoria </LOCATION>. The storm forced delays of 225 jetliners flying into and out of <LOCATION> O'Hare </LOCATION> <LOCATION> International </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION>, the nation's busiest, said <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Handschiegel </PERSON>, a spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aviation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>. `` The average delay was an hour and 15 minutes and the maximum was three hours,'' he said. Flights also were delayed at Midway airport as a tornado watch was issued for the <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> area Monday afternoon. A water spout was reported on <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION> about 2 p.m., weather service officials said, but it caused no damage. The storm, caused by a collision between a warm front from the south and a cold front from the north, was headed east, weather officials said. <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> was expecting mostly sunny skies Tuesday, with highs in the 50s and 60s. Five people were reported struck by lightning in the <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> area, and one, an electrician, remained hospitalized in stable condition Monday night. In <LOCATION> Peoria </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, the storm unleashed wind gusts up to 63 mph and golf-ball-sized hail, causing extensive damage to buildings, homes and several schools Monday morning. `` We got no warning, no sirens, no nothing,'' said <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Collier </PERSON>, school superintendent at <LOCATION> Dunlap </LOCATION>, about six miles northwest of <LOCATION> Peoria </LOCATION>. `` It was a freak storm that blew up out of nowhere. I was sitting here at my window and I saw it get dark. `` Within about 15 seconds it was really blowing and there was a tremendous electrical storm. Car windows were popping out and exploding, glass was breaking and trees and power lines went down.'' Youngsters at the five <PERSON> Dunlap </PERSON> school buildings were unscathed, although the 500 high school students were ushered outside and classes canceled when officials smelled smoke and feared a fire. Officials found roof damage but no fire. The <ORGANIZATION> Mossville </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Grade </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION>, about 15 miles east of <LOCATION> Dunlap </LOCATION>, also was closed because of roof damage. Assembly lines were shut down for about 30 minutes and employees were evacuated from shops at <ORGANIZATION> Caterpillar </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>'s <LOCATION> Mossville </LOCATION> engine plant in a complex that employs about 5,000 people, said <PERSON> Gil </PERSON> <PERSON> Nolde </PERSON>, company spokesman.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881017-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-17-88 2343EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--FerrySinking     10-17 0134</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Ferry Sinking,0136</SECOND>
<HEAD>17 Drown In Ferry Sinking</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MANILA, Philippines (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 At least 17 people drowned when a small ferry boat sank off <LOCATION> Luzon </LOCATION> island on the same day that 55 people were killed in a similar sinking in the central <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION>, the Philippine Constabulary reported today. A belated report said five other people were missing from the <LOCATION> Lady </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Aurea </LOCATION>, a motorized outrigger which capsized as it was buffeted by big waves Friday off <LOCATION> Aurora </LOCATION> province, 120 miles northeast of <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION>. It said 11 others were rescued. The report gave no other details. At least 55 people drowned and 77 others were rescued when an overloaded ferry boat sank during a squall Friday as it was sailing from <LOCATION> Samar </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Leyte </LOCATION> island in the central <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> reported last Saturday.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881017-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-17-88 2343EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Italy-Kappler 1stLd-Writethru a0647 10-17 0274</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Italy-Kappler, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0647,0280</SECOND>
<HEAD>Italy Asks Widow of Nazi Criminal to Stay Away</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Adds 4 grafs on senators asking about government action,
possible legal penalties</NOTE>
<DATELINE>ROME (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>'s justice minister on Monday urged the widow of a Nazi war criminal not to come to <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION> to promote a book on how she helped her husband escape from a <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION> military prison in 1977. <PERSON> Giuliano </PERSON> <PERSON> Vassalli </PERSON> said that such a visit solely for publicity `` is the cause of legitimate concern'' by relatives of those killed in a massacre for which <PERSON> Herbert </PERSON> <PERSON> Kappler </PERSON> was judged responsibile. <PERSON> Kappler </PERSON>, an SS colonel in <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION> during World War II, was sentenced to life in prison for his role in the massacre of 335 Italians in 1944. He escaped in August 1977, reportedly concealed in a large suitcase wheeled out of the prison by his wife. <PERSON> Kappler </PERSON> died of cancer a year later in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>. His widow, <PERSON> Annelise </PERSON>, said last week she would come to <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION> Saturday to present her book `` I Will Bring You Home.'' A <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> spokesman said <PERSON> Vassalli </PERSON> issued a statement in response to a letter he received from Mrs. <PERSON> Kappler </PERSON> in which she stated why she planned to come to <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION> and asked his opinion. Three senators representing <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>'s largest political parties, the <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democrats </ORGANIZATION>, Communists and Socialists, asked the government Monday to declare what measures it would take to keep Mrs. <PERSON> Kappler </PERSON> out of the country. But the government did not say immediately if it might take legal action. Law provides a prison term of up to 10 years for aiding the escape of a convict sentenced to life.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881017-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-17-88 2346EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Italy-Crash Bjt   10-17 0626</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Italy-Crash, Bjt,0642</SECOND>
<HEAD>Jet Tried For Seldom-Used, Less Equipped Runway, Union Says</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARY BETH SHERIDAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ROME (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Uganda </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> jet that crashed near <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION>'s main airport killing 31 people was aiming for a seldom-used runway that lacks sophisticated landing equipment, an Italian union official said The choice of the runway meant that the pilot had to calculate how to land the Boeing 707 at the fog-shrouded airport, instead of having electronic equipment guide him, said <PERSON> Andrea </PERSON> <PERSON> Gariup </PERSON>, president of the main Italian pilots' union. The red, yellow and white jet plowed through three houses and a rental-car parking lot before coming to rest in a field and bursting into flames early Monday. Thirty-one people were killed, including six of the seven crew members; 21 were injured. Most of those on board Flight QU775 were Ugandans traveling from <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Uganda </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Entebbe </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION> via <PERSON> Leonardo </PERSON> da Vinci Airport. Two Nigerians were listed among the injured, while the <ORGANIZATION> British </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION> said seven or eight passengers were Britons. The airport said it did not yet have a complete list of passenger identities. <PERSON> Gariup </PERSON> said the pilot apparently chose runway `` 34 Left'' because visibility was slightly better there than on two other runways he had previously approached. However, the strip lacked the Instrument Landing System installed at other runways to provide information to pilots about their altitude, said <PERSON> Gariup </PERSON>, head of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commercial </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airline </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pilots </ORGANIZATION>. The pilot therefore had to target his descent using information from the control tower and his view of the runway, <PERSON> Gariup </PERSON> said. The pilot `` had to calculate every minute, based on the distance to the airport, how he had to approach,'' <PERSON> Gariup </PERSON> said in a telephone interview Monday night with The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>. `` With the other system, the instruments would tell him if he was too low.'' `` Perhaps he miscalculated or perhaps he saw something else that he thought was the runway.'' There was no answer at the airport director's office or the press office Monday evening, but an air traffic controller in the flight tower confirmed that the runway was not frequently used and lacked the landing equipment other strips had. He spoke on condition of anonymity. Government and airport authorities emphasized that they had not yet established the cause of the crash. The Italian government announced Monday evening that a nine-man commission would investigate, in addition to a judicial board. The commander of the <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION> province's fire department, <PERSON> Guido </PERSON> <PERSON> Chiucini </PERSON>, who helped coordinate the rescue, speculated in a telephone interview that there was a `` misunderstanding'' between the control tower and the pilot since the plane approached at such a low altitude. However, the air traffic controllers' union denied there had been any misunderstanding. Other officials noted there had not yet been an examination of the `` black box,'' which records flight information data, or the recordings of the pilot's conversations with the tower. Among those who survived were a British dairy farmer and his 26-year-old wife who leaped from the burning aircraft clutching their 8-month-old son. `` We jumped out of a hole in the fuselage behind us,'' <PERSON> Geoffrey </PERSON> <PERSON> Gait </PERSON>, 31, told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> in an interview at Sant ` <ORGANIZATION> Eugenio </ORGANIZATION> `` <PERSON> Ruth </PERSON> jumped backward, holding -LRB- baby <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> -RRB- to her chest, and then fell about six feet to the ground. I picked them up. We walked about 200 yards and then some Ugandans came out.'' The Gaits, who suffered minor burns, were on their way to the African nation to work with a charity project that provides farmers with cows. Chunks of the aircraft and passengers' clothing covered a wide swath in the plane's wake. Long after the crash, hundreds of sheets of blue-lined paper stamped `` <ORGANIZATION> Uganda </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Examination </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION>'' still blanketed the ground.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881017-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-17-88 2347EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Israel-ArabVote Bjt   10-17 0736</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Israel-Arab Vote, Bjt,0754</SECOND>
<HEAD>Peres Gets Cool Reception Among Crucial Arab Voters</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KARIN LAUB</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SHFARAM, Israel (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Shimon </PERSON> <PERSON> Peres </PERSON> kissed a girl with flowers and shook hands with robe-clad notables, but once the organized hoopla was over, the reception in this <PERSON> Arab </PERSON> town for the <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> leader turned frosty. Polls show the left-of-center <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> might lose half its Arab support, partly because <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION>'s No. 2 man, <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> Minister <PERSON> Yitzhak </PERSON> <PERSON> Rabin </PERSON>, is held responsible for the harsh crackdown on the Palestinian uprising in the occupied <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strip </LOCATION>. Labor and the right-wing <ORGANIZATION> Likud </ORGANIZATION> bloc headed by Prime Minister <PERSON> Yitzhak </PERSON> <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON> are running neck-to-neck and a drop in Arab support for Labor could hand the Nov. 1 election to <ORGANIZATION> Likud </ORGANIZATION>. `` Are you going to vote for us?'' a shirt-sleaved <PERSON> Peres </PERSON>, surrounded by a dozen security men, asked a resident Monday during a walking tour of <PERSON> Shfaram </PERSON>, a northern Israeli town of 26,000. The man did not answer, and instead told <PERSON> Peres </PERSON> the town needed better roads. Responded Peres: `` If we get enough votes, we'll get the <ORGANIZATION> Finance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION>, and then we can do it.'' In an attempt at conviviality, <PERSON> Peres </PERSON> greeted a woman with the Arabic phrase `` sabah ilher,'' but after being told he had said `` good morning'' instead of the intended `` good evening,'' <PERSON> Peres </PERSON> stuck to Hebrew. Most Shfaram residents stayed indoors or watched from their balconies as <PERSON> Peres </PERSON> and a few dozen party activists walked through the town which in 1984 gave half its votes to the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>. During a reception at the home of local <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> leader <PERSON> Khalil </PERSON> <PERSON> Mishal </PERSON>, <PERSON> Peres </PERSON> was handed flowers by <PERSON> Mishal </PERSON>'s daughter who wore a Hebrew sticker reading `` I'm also for Labor.'' <PERSON> Mishal </PERSON> had invited about 150 Arab notables who shook hands with <PERSON> Peres </PERSON> and provided the backdrop for brief welcoming speeches. At a later rally, <PERSON> Peres </PERSON> urged Israeli Arabs not to `` waste'' their votes on the communists or the Progressive List for Peace. Both are pro-PLO and unacceptable to Labor as coalition partners. `` If this time, there is no peace, it will be the fault of the Israeli Arabs. If you waste your votes, nothing is going to happen,'' <PERSON> Peres </PERSON> told about 500 people who listened in silence and applauded briefly and politely at the end. About 330,000 of <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s 800,000 <PERSON> Arab </PERSON> citizens are eligible to vote this year, and could control 14 seats in the 120-member Parliament. In 1984, one in four Arabs voted Labor, giving the party the three seats that provided its 44-41 advantage over <ORGANIZATION> Likud </ORGANIZATION>. But this year, support for Labor is slipping, mainly because of growing Israeli Arab identification with the 10-month-old uprising that has claimed at least 299 Palestinian and six <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> lives. Analysts say Labor could lose 1.5 seats in the Arab sector. `` Many people do n't want to vote for Labor because of what <PERSON> Rabin </PERSON> is doing in the occupied territories,'' said a 37-year-old carpenter in the Arab town of <LOCATION> Nazareth </LOCATION> near <LOCATION> Shfaram </LOCATION>. The man, who said he supported Labor in 1984, spoke on condition of anonymity. Asked whether <PERSON> Rabin </PERSON> was a liability for Labor's <PERSON> Arab </PERSON> campaign, <PERSON> Peres </PERSON> was evasive. `` I think they -LRB- Arab voters -RRB- must understand the situation as it is, and I hope they will change their minds,'' he told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> in Shfaram. But <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> activists in <LOCATION> Shfaram </LOCATION> were optimistic that the revolt against <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> occupation would boost their chances. `` We'll get more votes because of the uprising,'' said local party leader <PERSON> Sagir </PERSON> <PERSON> Moussa </PERSON>, 39, as he and other activists handed out leaflets saying `` Yes to a Palestinian state'' and `` Long live the uprising.'' His party might gain one seat this year, bringing its total to five, according to recent polls Labor has conducted among Arab voters. The polls were cited by the <ORGANIZATION> Jerusalem </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> newsaper. According to the polls, the Progressive List for Peace would maintain its strength with two seats, while <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> would win 1.5 seats. Six other parties, including the <ORGANIZATION> Likud </ORGANIZATION>, would share the remaining four seats, an unidentified Labor official told the newspaper Monday. A 26-year-old <PERSON> Shfaram </PERSON> resident, who would only give his first name, <PERSON> Ahmed </PERSON>, said he was not convinced by <PERSON> Peres </PERSON>' speech. He also criticized <PERSON> Peres </PERSON> for promising true equality, better schools and more jobs for Israeli Arabs if Labor is elected. `` Every four years they discover that we exist,'' said <PERSON> Ahmed </PERSON>, a hairdresser. `` They make promises, but nothing changes.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881017-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-17-88 2354EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p AM-Bush 3rdLd-Writethru a0812 10-17 0864</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Bush, 3rd Ld-Writethru, a0812,880</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush Criticizes Dukakis on Military</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: To UPDATE with report on advertising expenditures,
anti-Dukakis ad, INSERT two grafs after 11th pvs, Bush was...</NOTE>
<HEAD>With AM-Political Rdp Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TOM RAUM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LITTLETON, Colo. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> on Monday accused Democrat <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> of a `` total lack of understanding of our military'' and called the Nov. 8 election a referendum on military policy. The vice president used a <ORGANIZATION> Martin-Marietta </ORGANIZATION> defense plant, where `` Star Wars'' research is being conducted, to launch his latest attack on <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>. `` I will not leave <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> defenseless against ballistic missiles,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> told about 2,500 company employees in the cavernous assembly plant where Titan IV rockets are built. The vice president made the comments before flying to <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>, where he addressed a Jewish group at the Holocaust Memorial in <LOCATION> Skokie </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ill. </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> told his audience that `` the relationship between <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has never been better, never been stronger. At the <ORGANIZATION> Martin-Marietta </ORGANIZATION> plant, in the foothills of the <LOCATION> Rocky </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mountains </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> ridiculed <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> for opposing continued ballistic missile flight testing. `` We need to modernize. We need to test. And we ca n't defend <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> with blueprints,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said. And he scoffed at the Democrat's position on the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration's Strategic Defense Initiative, or `` Star Wars,'' program. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> has been highly critical of the proposed system _ designed to destroy incoming <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> missiles in space _ but has also said during the campaign that he might support some continued research. Noting that <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> had once called the program a fantasy, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> asked: `` Why spend a dime, if you think it's a fantasy?'' Attacking <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> for his opposition to new missile systems and for his emphasis on stronger conventional forces has been a main <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> campaign theme. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was planning to introduce that theme in an ad using footage of <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> riding around in a tank during a campaign visit to <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION>, said campaign spokeswoman <PERSON> Sheila </PERSON> <PERSON> Tate </PERSON>. Although Ms. <PERSON> Tate </PERSON> had no information on a <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> report Tuesay that the campaign was tentatively planning to spend more than $ 15 million of its $ 30 million-plus advertising in three states, she said three new ads were being aired Tuesday, and a new ad was being shot then. The three states are <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> said. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> declared on Monday that with the next century approaching, `` it is all that more important for us to understand the role that our defense has played in securing the peace, the role our military forces must continue to play if <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s future is also to be secure. `` And this election is a referendum about that role.'' At <LOCATION> Skokie </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> stood in a violent thunderstorm at an outdoor rally for the dedication, where he said: `` I am committed to the survival of <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> has survived, will survive, has flourished, will flourish.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> talked about the importance of maintaining the `` strategic relationship'' with <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> and joked: `` I wish that the Lord had given us a little bit of a different weather condition. He works in strange and mysterious ways.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> did not mention the controversial effort by the American <ORGANIZATION> Nazi </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> to hold a march in <LOCATION> Skokie </LOCATION> in 1978 in which the <ORGANIZATION> Nazis </ORGANIZATION> were represented by the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Civil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberties </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> Nazis </ORGANIZATION> decided at the last minute to hold their march in neighboring <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has frequently criticized <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> for his membership in the <ORGANIZATION> ACLU </ORGANIZATION>. Aides said the visit should be viewed reinforcement of <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s criticism With polls showing the vice president pulling ahead of <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> _ including an <ORGANIZATION> NBC-Wall </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Street </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Journal </ORGANIZATION> poll Monday showing <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> ahead 55-38 _ Republican strategists say <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> will focus on a few proven-effective themes such as defense in the remaining three weeks before the election. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> donned a bright blue work jacket as he toured the <ORGANIZATION> Martin-Marietta </ORGANIZATION> plant, accompanied by <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Schlesinger </PERSON>, who has served in Cabinet jobs in both Democratic and Republican administrations. The vice president was shown a simulator for a laser weapon system to be based on an orbiting space station called `` Rapid Retargeting, Precision Pointing,'' or by its facetious code name, `` R2P2.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was told by <ORGANIZATION> Martin-Marietta </ORGANIZATION> vice president <PERSON> Morris </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Thorson </PERSON> that the device was so accurate that it could hit a basketball on top of the Empire State Building in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> from <PERSON> Pike </PERSON>'s Peak in <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Schlesinger </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> defense </ORGANIZATION> secretary and <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> director for President <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> and energy secretary for President <PERSON> Carter </PERSON>, told the plant employees that `` the presidency is no place for on-the-job training.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said that the <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> governor's refusal to back new nuclear systems and his willingness to cut two aircraft carriers `` indicates his total lack of understanding of our military.'' `` Governor, it's time to stop running down our defenses,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said. Meanwhile, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said he favors a `` possible mix'' for a new generation of mobile intercontinental ballistic missiles between the Midgetman missile and a rail-based MX missile system _ but not full deployment of both. <PERSON> Dennis </PERSON> <PERSON> Ross </PERSON>, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s foreign policy adviser, said going ahead with both weapons systems would cost some $ 60 billion, and that <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> wanted to keep the costs of the program to about half that.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881017-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-17-88 0107EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Teacher-Slur     10-17 0811</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Teacher-Slur,0831</SECOND>
<HEAD>Lesson In Tolerance: Black Students Forgive White Librarian's Slur</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Note contents of 6th graf.</NOTE>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By SCOTT CHARTON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>GOULD, Ark. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A racial slur uttered in frustration nearly ended <PERSON> Lois </PERSON> <PERSON> Bostic </PERSON>'s 27-year career in education. Then her black students stepped in, taught their elders a lesson in tolerance, and saved Mrs. <PERSON> Bostic </PERSON>'s job. `` We were ready to forgive and go on,'' said senior <PERSON> Angela </PERSON> <PERSON> Matthews </PERSON>, 17, one of six students who initiated, typed and distributed petitions in support of the white librarian. `` Anybody ought to get a second chance.'' After the slur was reported last month, parents in this farming town 80 miles southeast of <LOCATION> Little </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rock </LOCATION> circulated petitions calling for Mrs. <PERSON> Bostic </PERSON>'s ouster, and she told school officials she would quit. The board promptly endorsed her decision. But then, high school students mounted their own petition drive, the school board rescinded its resolution, and Mrs. <PERSON> Bostic </PERSON> is here to stay. Mrs. <PERSON> Bostic </PERSON>, who is in her first year here teaching both elementary and high school students, said her troubles began Sept. 27 as she taught her seventh class of the day on using the library at <ORGANIZATION> Gould </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Elementary </ORGANIZATION>. As she recalls it, the 20 sixth-graders in the class were n't paying attention and were growing increasingly rowdy In an effort to settle them down, she told the students, all of them black: `` I think you're trying to make me think you're a bunch of poor, dumb niggers, and I do n't think that.'' Mrs. <PERSON> Bostic </PERSON>, 50, said she immediately realized the inappropriateness of the word. `` I opened my mouth and put my foot in it,'' she said in an interview. `` In our part of the country, we call each other hicks and hillbillies and that's OK. But if somebody from <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> moves in and they refer to us as hillbillies, we get angry. And I realized that it was wrong. `` I was at my rope's end. I was just trying to get these kids to behave. I was n't even conscious that I was using a word that would offend them,'' she said. Children told their parents about the remarks, and parents went to the school board in this town of 1,670 people, about 60 percent of them black. On Oct. 3, a petition calling for Mrs. <PERSON> Bostic </PERSON>'s dismissal was presented to the board. Many of the 91 parents who circulated and signed it say they remembered routine discrimination and hateful use of the word in their youth. The parents' petition alleged other insulting racial remarks had been made by Mrs. <PERSON> Bostic </PERSON>. She denied that and said her only use of the slur was before the sixth-graders. It was, she told the board, `` a dumb, stupid mistake.'' Mrs. <PERSON> Bostic </PERSON> recalls that she did n't encounter many blacks while growing up in southern <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION>. `` That word I used is not part of my vocabulary. My mother would have slapped me across the mouth if I'd said that when I was growing up,'' she said. Overhearing the word in conversations between black students, usually in a humorous context, Mrs. <PERSON> Bostic </PERSON> concluded she could relate to them better if she used it. `` I had no prejudices. I was going to be one of them and went so far as using a word I should not have used, that I did n't realize would offend them,'' she said. Repentant and tearful, the librarian announced she would quit by the end of that week. The school board endorsed her exit, saying she had lost effectiveness. Mrs. <PERSON> Bostic </PERSON> was preparing to move out of town with her retiree husband, her career ended, less than three months after she moved to <LOCATION> Arkansas </LOCATION>. On the day before her self-imposed departure deadline, she learned that pupils were circulating petitions asking the board to reconsider. They bore signatures from 124 of the town's 147 high school students, only two of whom are white. Surprised, board members reopened their discussion and reversed the request for Mrs. <PERSON> Bostic </PERSON>'s resignation. `` It's their school. They're the ones that have to be with her every day,'' said school board president <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Minor </PERSON>, who is black. `` We figured this: Why would this woman move to this town with more blacks than whites if she's a bigot? She just made a bad mistake and we decided she deserved a second chance,'' said senior class president <PERSON> Roy </PERSON> <PERSON> Rainey </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>, 17. Mrs. <PERSON> Bostic </PERSON> said <PERSON> Rainey </PERSON>, a lanky basketball center, `` is my hero right now. He came to my defense. It was my miracle.'' Home economics teacher <PERSON> Doris </PERSON> <PERSON> Rucker </PERSON>, one of five blacks on the 13-person high school faculty, praised the students. `` I'm so proud of them. They showed us the way,'' she said. `` I'm encouraged about the future of our little town,'' said Mayor <PERSON> Dave </PERSON> <PERSON> Rochelle </PERSON>, who is white. `` This petition indicates we have 124 young citizens who are good people.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881017-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-17-88 0239EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--MaleNOWPresident     10-17 0174</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Male NOW President,0178</SECOND>
<HEAD>Man Elected President of NOW Chapter</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOUISVILLE, Ky. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <LOCATION> Kentucky </LOCATION> chapter of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Women </ORGANIZATION> has elected <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Newlin </PERSON> its president, making him the second man in the nation to lead a NOW chapter. <PERSON> Newlin </PERSON>, who was elected Saturday and lives in nearby <LOCATION> Henryville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ind. </LOCATION>, said he joined NOW because `` their cause covers just about everybody else's causes _ equal rights for everyone, man, woman and child.'' He said he was the only man among 19 women when he attended his first NOW meeting, in 1985. Although the members included him in its work immediately, he said, `` they thought I was a spy. I felt I had to earn my stripes. Within two months, I had brought in 10 new members.'' Former <LOCATION> Kentucky </LOCATION> NOW President <PERSON> Jean </PERSON> <PERSON> Varble </PERSON> said there may be `` a few members who may not be comfortable with the idea'' of a male president, but `` We ca n't cut off half the population.'' Only the chapter in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION>, has had a male president.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881017-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-17-88 0017EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-SoCalFires     10-17 0391</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-SoCal Fires,0401</SECOND>
<HEAD>Fires Burn in Sequoia National Park, Angeles National Forest</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MICHAEL FLEEMAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Wildfires Sunday threatened centuries-old giant sequoia trees in the state's mid-section and crackled toward homes along the mountain ridges surrounding <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>. The fires erupted during another <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> fall heat wave with temperatures nudging 100 degrees in many areas and <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ana </LOCATION> winds, dried and heated by inland deserts, reaching 30 mph. More than 3,500 acres were blackened in the fires, several of them man-caused, authorities said. A wind-pushed 2,000-acre blaze in the Angeles National Forest endangered homes in the path of the flames 30 miles north of <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>. The fire's huge brown smoke plume, rising 7,000 feet skyward, could be seen 50 miles away at <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> <LOCATION> International </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION>. Mountain residents of the northeast <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Fernando </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION> were put on alert but no evacuations were ordered. About 200 firefighters were battling the blaze and hundreds more were on the way late in the afternoon. `` This one is giving us real problems,'' said <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Bundick </PERSON>. `` It's going in about three different directions faster than we can corral it.'' About 160 miles northwest, firefighters battling a 600-acre fire in Sequoia National Park were optimistic a buffer zone cleared in a previous controlled burn would save the magnificent trees in the 3-square-mile <ORGANIZATION> Giant </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION>, said park spokesman <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Tweed </PERSON>. The ancient trees are considered the largest living things on <LOCATION> Earth </LOCATION>. `` These are certainly one of the biological wonders of the world,'' Tweed said. `` The fire will inevitably reach the edge of the <ORGANIZATION> Giant </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION>. We think that because of the steps taken, we can prevent it from going into the forest.'' About 100 campers fled the flames, which started at 8 a.m. in <LOCATION> Potwisha </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Camp </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ground </LOCATION> about 30 miles northeast of <LOCATION> Visalia </LOCATION>. A careless camper or angler was the suspected cause of the blaze, <ORGANIZATION> Tweed </ORGANIZATION> said. Another fire 85 miles southeast of <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Riverside </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> charred 800 acres near <LOCATION> Hemet </LOCATION>, but firefighters were gaining the upper hand and containment was anticipated by dawn Monday, said <PERSON> Joanne </PERSON> <PERSON> Evans </PERSON>, a spokeswoman for the <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forestry </ORGANIZATION>. Two smaller fires erupted in the mountainous eastern portion of the Angeles National Forest. One, started by children playing with matches and a cigarette lighter, destroyed a house.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881017-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-17-88 0239EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--PoliceChase     10-17 0137</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Police Chase,0140</SECOND>
<HEAD>Man Leads Pursuing Police To Jail</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A man driving a stolen car led police in four cruisers and two helicopters on a chase he ended at the jail parking lot, authorities said. The end of early Sunday's chase came after the driver put the car into reverse and rammed a police car near the downtown jail, said police Lt. <PERSON> Carl </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilhite </PERSON>. `` He mentioned the fact he had been booked by <ORGANIZATION> LAPD </ORGANIZATION> officer before and he knew where to go,'' <PERSON> Wilhite </PERSON> said. `` It was convenient of him, huh?'' <PERSON> Frankie </PERSON> <PERSON> Hill </PERSON>, 32, of <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> was booked for assault with a deadly weapon on a police officer and held on $ 8,000 bail, <PERSON> Wilhite </PERSON> said. The 15-minute chase began when officers noticed the car <PERSON> Hill </PERSON> was driving had been stolen, <PERSON> Wilhite </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881017-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-17-88 0240EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--NorthwesternGift     10-17 0160</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Northwestern Gift,0164</SECOND>
<HEAD>Patient Repays Doctors For Gift Of Life With $17 Million Donation</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CHICAGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Reuben </PERSON> <PERSON> Feinberg </PERSON> says he has a good reason for giving $ 17 million to doctors at <ORGANIZATION> Northwestern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> _ they saved his life. <PERSON> Feinberg </PERSON>'s gift, the third largest ever received by the university, was announced Saturday, one year after his heart surgery at Northwestern Memorial Hospital. `` I never had thought about giving money to a hospital before then,'' said <PERSON> Feinberg </PERSON>, 70, president and director of the <ORGANIZATION> Jefferson </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>. `` I was thinking more about a building or something,'' he said. `` But bricks do n't accomplish much. People can.'' <PERSON> Feinberg </PERSON>, whose father, <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON>, died of heart disease, is donating the money to establish a cardiovascular research center at the medical school. University president <PERSON> Arnold </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Weber </PERSON> said the planned <ORGANIZATION> Feinberg </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cardiovascular </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> `` has the promise to become the finest center of excellence in cardiovascular research and education in the nation.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881017-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-17-88 0115EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-HarvardOrYale     10-17 0886</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Harvard Or Yale,880</SECOND>
<HEAD>Presidential Campaign Elevates Elite Rivalry _ Harvard Vs. Yale</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Political Rdp Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BRENT LAYMON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW HAVEN, Conn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> class of 1940, could n't resist some good-natured teasing when <ORGANIZATION> Yale </ORGANIZATION> awarded him an honorary doctorate in 1962. `` As General <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Gaulle </PERSON> occasionally acknowledged <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> to be the daughter of <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, so I am pleased to come to <ORGANIZATION> Yale </ORGANIZATION>, the daughter of <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION>,'' <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> told graduates assembled in the courtyard of <ORGANIZATION> Yale </ORGANIZATION>'s Old Campus on that sunny June day. `` It might be said now that I have the best of both worlds _ a <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> education and a <ORGANIZATION> Yale </ORGANIZATION> degree,'' <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> said. This year's presidential campaign has elevated what is perhaps the oldest, most intense and most snobbish rivalry in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> to a new height. For the spoils of this contest will go either to a <ORGANIZATION> Yale </ORGANIZATION> man or a <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> man _ only the second time in 200 years that graduates of the two schools have vied for the presidency of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. And the only other time it happened, in 1912, the <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> man, <PERSON> Theodore </PERSON> <PERSON> Roosevelt </PERSON>, and the <ORGANIZATION> Yale </ORGANIZATION> man, <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> <PERSON> Taft </PERSON>, both lost to a <ORGANIZATION> Princeton </ORGANIZATION> man, <PERSON> Woodrow </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON>. While <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> was a master at exploiting his <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> education for political advantage, Republican <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Yale </ORGANIZATION> class of 1948, has tried to turn Democrat <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' Harvard connections into a campaign liability. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, scion of a wealthy <LOCATION> Greenwich </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Conn. </LOCATION>, family, accuses the <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> governor, the son of <LOCATION> Greek </LOCATION> immigrants, of having a `` Harvard boutique'' mentality tainted by `` liberalism and elitism.'' Campaigning Saturday in <LOCATION> Modesto </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said, `` I do n't want somebody from <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> telling me what I can do and what I ca n't do. Asked about that statement at a news conference Sunday, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said he did not want to take on the institution itself, asking `` How can I, a nice guy from <ORGANIZATION> Yale </ORGANIZATION>, feel that way about <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION>? Now come on. `` I'm talking about a handful of people that have served in -LRB- recent -RRB- Democratic administrations that come out of the same liberal philisophy. And they know who they are,'' he said. `` There's an elite inside the elite there.'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, in turn, has tried to stay out of the Harvard-Yale debate, saying his 1960 <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> law degree and teaching stint at <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Kennedy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Government </ORGANIZATION> do n't make him a <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> man at all. `` I'm a <ORGANIZATION> Swarthmore </ORGANIZATION> guy,'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> says, referring to the liberal arts college in <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> where he received his undergraduate degree. But <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> line held little sting given his own Ivy League connections. And it probably was lost on most Americans, who view both <ORGANIZATION> Yale </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> as elite Eastern universities for the wealthy. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> campaign aides could n't hold their tongues when outgoing Education Secretary <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON>, himself a <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Law </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> graduate, asserted on national television in September that the <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> crowd `` with which <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> runs ... think they're smarter'' than most Americans `` <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON> spent seven or eight years getting an education in <LOCATION> Massachussetts </LOCATION> and these comments are a clear indication that it did n't do him a bit of good,'' shot back <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Gearan </PERSON>, press secretary at <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> headquarters. <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Yale </ORGANIZATION> have eyed each other with haughty disdain for nearly 300 years, since <ORGANIZATION> Yale </ORGANIZATION> was founded in 1701 by a group of clergy worried about religious backsliding at the more liberal <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION>, the oldest college in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>. Harvard was founded in 1636, just 16 years after the Pilgrims landed at <LOCATION> Plymouth </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rock </LOCATION>. `` We have been natural rivals almost from the beginning,'' <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Pierson </PERSON>, the Larned professor emeritus of history at <ORGANIZATION> Yale </ORGANIZATION>, said recently. `` We were the only two with the exception of <PERSON> William </PERSON> and <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> that you could go to. After that, we both grew in the favor of the Lord.'' The Harvard-Yale annual crew race is the oldest intercollegiate sports rivalry in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, dating from 1852. The schools refer to their annual football contest as `` The Game,'' as if all others hardly matter. Other Harvard-Yale presidential campaigns have been averted only by quirks of history. The 1824 election would have pitted <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> graduate <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Quincy </PERSON> <PERSON> Adams </PERSON> against <ORGANIZATION> Yale </ORGANIZATION> graduate <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Calhoun </PERSON>, but <PERSON> Calhoun </PERSON> dropped out and threw his support to <PERSON> Adams </PERSON>, who defeated <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, who did n't have a college degree. The 1876 contest between <PERSON> Rutherford </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Hayes </PERSON>, a graduate of <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Law </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION>, against <PERSON> Samuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Tilden </PERSON> would have been a Harvard-Yale matchup, except <PERSON> Tilden </PERSON> dropped out of <ORGANIZATION> Yale </ORGANIZATION> after one year and graduated from <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. Although this is only the second head-to-head match, <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Yale </ORGANIZATION> both boast presidents among their graduates. While <ORGANIZATION> Yale </ORGANIZATION> holds the edge in their football series, 56-40, and <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> holds the edge in crew races, 72-51, <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> holds a substantial lead in the presidential sweepstakes: six <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> graduates have held the office _ <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Adams </PERSON>, <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Quincy </PERSON> <PERSON> Adams </PERSON>, <PERSON> Hayes </PERSON>, <PERSON> Theodore </PERSON> <PERSON> Roosevelt </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Franklin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Roosevelt </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> _ compared to just two from <ORGANIZATION> Yale </ORGANIZATION> _ <PERSON> Taft </PERSON> and <PERSON> Gerald </PERSON> <PERSON> Ford </PERSON>, a 1941 graduate of <ORGANIZATION> Yale </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Law </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Raymond </PERSON> <PERSON> Wolfinger </PERSON>, a political scientist at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION> at <LOCATION> Berkeley </LOCATION>, says most Americans do n't give a hoot about the Harvard-Yale rivalry. `` In terms of the mass public, the difference between <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Yale </ORGANIZATION> is nonsense,'' said <PERSON> Wolfinger </PERSON>, who earned his doctorate at <ORGANIZATION> Yale </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881017-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-17-88 0119EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-RhodeIslandSenate     10-17 0532</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Rhode Island Senate,520</SECOND>
<HEAD>Few Issues Distinguishing Licht, Chafee In Race For Senate</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KAREN SCHWARTZ</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PROVIDENCE, R.I. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Republican Sen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Chafee </PERSON> admits some people may find it ironic that <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Licht </PERSON> is challenging him in his run for a third <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> term. The Democratic Licht, <LOCATION> Rhode </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION>'s lieutenant governor, was 20 years old when his uncle, <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Licht </PERSON>, defeated <PERSON> Chafee </PERSON> in his 1968 bid for a third term as governor. And Licht, who has n't lost an election in his 13 years as a politician, said he has no intention of starting now. But <PERSON> Chafee </PERSON>, 64, who narrowly won a second <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> term in 1982 against former Attorney General <PERSON> Julius </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Michaelson </PERSON> with 51 percent of the vote, said he feels confident as the Nov. 8 election approaches. `` You can never be totally sure as a candidate, but you can tell some things and certainly I think the people appreciate what I've done for them over the years,'' <PERSON> Chafee </PERSON> said recently <PERSON> Chafee </PERSON>, the first <LOCATION> Rhode </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> Republican to be elected to the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>, is considered a moderate, and there are few substantial issues separating the two men. Earlier this year, <PERSON> Chafee </PERSON> announced support for a national parental leave bill, a measure backed by Licht in the <ORGANIZATION> Rhode </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Island </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION>. Both of the candidates also support open space preservation. <PERSON> Chafee </PERSON>, who has been endorsed by four major national environmental organizations, said he would work to initiate a $ 10 billion federal open space program if re-elected. Licht sponsored several bills last year that led to the state's $ 65 million open-space bond issue <PERSON> Chafee </PERSON> has charged that the idea was first his. As the election draws near, the candidates have turned to attacks and the resulting barrage of television commercials has pushed their campaign spending to nearly $ 2.5 million each. <PERSON> Chafee </PERSON> ran a television ad asserting that when <PERSON> Licht </PERSON> represented the <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Side </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Providence </LOCATION> in the state <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> from 1975 to 1984, `` He missed one out of every three votes.'' `` Did he not care? Was he afraid to take a stand?'' the ad asks. `` Or was he too busy doing something else?'' Licht in turn ran two ads that said he has had a 90 percent attendance record in the past six years. He said he missed a number of votes in the early 1980s because of his father's fatal illness and his own role in a lawsuit that overturned a controversial 1982 redistricting plan. Another Licht ad attacked <PERSON> Chafee </PERSON> for his voting record on issues concerning senior citizens _ a familiar Democratic tactic nationwide. `` <PERSON> Chafee </PERSON> voted 12 times to cut Social Security and five times to cut Medicare,'' said <PERSON> Licht </PERSON>, who has been endorsed by the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Senior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Citizens </ORGANIZATION>. Polls continue to show <PERSON> Chafee </PERSON> in the lead, although <ORGANIZATION> Licht </ORGANIZATION> has narrowed the gap slightly. A poll taken in September gave <PERSON> Chafee </PERSON> a lead of 30 percentage points over the Democrat with 59 percent of the vote. A poll taken in early October, with the same 5 percentage point margin of error, showed <PERSON> Chafee </PERSON> with 54 percent of the vote, while <PERSON> Licht </PERSON> was the choice of 33 percent of the 400 people surveyed.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881017-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-17-88 0123EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-TrumanFever Bjt   10-17 0799</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Truman Fever, Bjt,800</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHINGTON TODAY: Time Running Out, Democrats Dream of a Truman
Upset</HEAD>
<BYLINE>An AP News Analysis</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>By JONATHAN WOLMAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 In the modern age of presidential politics, the Democrats have a lot of experience being given up for dead. Generally, it's been a realistic enough presentiment, but <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> will surely look for inspiration to several remarkable party heroes. <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> Truman </PERSON> and <PERSON> Hubert </PERSON> <PERSON> Humphrey </PERSON> are the Mr. Octobers of their era. It was probably <PERSON> Truman </PERSON> foe <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Dewey </PERSON> whom <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> front-runner <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was thinking about when he vowed over the weekend to `` go the extra mile'' this month, and added, `` I'm not going to mess up.'' <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> was using <PERSON> Truman </PERSON> and <PERSON> Kirk </PERSON> <PERSON> Gibson </PERSON> as his weekend role models. `` Our party has a proud tradition of closing from behind,'' said <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' indefatigable running mate. He told a farmer's market in <LOCATION> St </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Louis </LOCATION>, `` I ca n't help but remember <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> Truman </PERSON> out there when the press had written him off.'' <PERSON> Humphrey </PERSON> came up short, of course, but his 1968 October comeback was still extraordinary, following as it did a divisive primary campaign and a calamitous convention. He sought to succeed an unpopular president _ <PERSON> Lyndon </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> _ for whom the word albatross comes to mind. But come back he did. After finally staking out some independence from <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>, <PERSON> Humphrey </PERSON> put together a high-energy campaign in October and ended with 42.7 percent of the vote, nearly scaring <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> out of his wits. -LRB- <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> ended with 43.4 percent. <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Wallace </PERSON> had 13.5 percent -RRB-. Though a sitting president in 1948, <PERSON> Truman </PERSON> did n't win nomination until well after midnight, at which time convention managers released a flock of doves to celebrate. The doves, stifled by the heat, promptly dropped dead on the convention floor, prompting one party stalwart to reflect, `` Dead pigeons, just like <PERSON> Truman </PERSON>.'' Except the year did n't end with <PERSON> Truman </PERSON> dead. Unpopular and far behind in the polls, <PERSON> Truman </PERSON> invented the whistlestop, making an average of 10 speeches a day from the back of a train and sparing the Republicans no ridicule in that blunt, partisan `` Give ` Em Hell'' manner of his. <PERSON> Dewey </PERSON> was no <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>; he stayed above the fray. On election day, <PERSON> Truman </PERSON> stood expectations on their head, winning 49.5 percent of the vote to <PERSON> Dewey </PERSON>'s 45 percent. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> enjoys the same mid-October expectations as <PERSON> Truman </PERSON>, which is to say few outside his immediate family really believe he'll win. But there are differences between the two men, and one is half-tempted to look over at the cerebral and aloof <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> and say, `` Governor, you're no <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> Truman </PERSON>.'' <PERSON> Truman </PERSON> never had to say, `` I think I'm a reasonably likable guy,'' and if you asked him to name his heroes in American life, can you imagine <PERSON> Truman </PERSON> responding _ as did <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> last Thursday night _ `` Some of them are in public life, in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, some of my fellow governors ... are real heroes to me.'' His fellow governors! <PERSON> Truman </PERSON>, like <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, was not a commanding figure. Lots of people looked down upon him, figuratively and literally. `` At first the critics referred to my -LRB- campaign -RRB- tour as a ` one-man circus,' and called it less efficient and less dignified than the campaign being put on by the Republicans,'' <PERSON> Truman </PERSON> said in his memoirs, describing his comeback this way: `` I simply told the people in my own language that they had better wake up to the fact that it was their fight. If they did not get out and help me win this fight, I emphasized, the Republicans would soon be giving the farmers and the workers the little end of the stick again.'' The <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> command huddled in <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> and emerged to tell <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> they would, a la Truman, concentrate on economic themes in the last-ditch drive for a miracle. They mapped out an effort to concentrate on 18 states with 272 electoral votes. That does n't leave any margin for error. It takes 270 electoral votes to win the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, and common sense says you ca n't win every state you contest _ unless you're <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and you're going to win them all anyway By Sunday, <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> had merged his Truman reminisces with a World Series theme, buoyed by the fact that the underdogs from <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> had won a first-game victory with the gimpy <PERSON> Gibson </PERSON>'s two-out homer in ninth `` We're going to be like the <ORGANIZATION> Dodgers </ORGANIZATION> last night,'' he said. `` It looked like they were down and out and all of a sudden they hit a home run and won it. And I think we can do that in the next 24 days.'' Of course this is <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> talking, not <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 EDITOR'S NOTE: <PERSON> Jonathan </PERSON> <PERSON> Wolman </PERSON> is <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION>'s assistant bureau chief in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881017-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-17-88 0123EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Quayle'sMetamorphosis Bjt   10-17 0861</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Quayle's Metamorphosis, Bjt,850</SECOND>
<HEAD>`New' Quayle Is More Accessible But Still Relegated To Safe GOP
Turf</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP News Analysis</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By EILEEN PUTMAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 When <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>'s campaign plane was late taking off one night last week, a reporter suggested a reason for the delay. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>, he said, was up in the cockpit giving an interview to the pilot. `` It's the only person he has n't talked to yet,'' the reporter said. When the `` new,'' accessible <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> emerged last week, the contrast with the `` old,'' aloof <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> seemed dramatic to those who had studied him since he became the Republican vice presidential nominee. The old <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> was a wooden, programmed speaker who avoided the media at every turn. The new <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> has a conversational speaking style and is relentlessly available, engaging protesters and showing up everywhere there is a camera, microphone or notepad. Like a schoolboy given a reprieve from a final exam, <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> now seems relaxed, cheerful, confident and, as he put it, `` a lot happier.'' The <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION> senator's public break with the rigid control of his campaign by <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> handlers and declaration that `` I am my own handler'' raised skeptical eyebrows among his press entourage. The change still seems one more of style than substance. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> is still relegated to campaigning mostly in safe Republican areas or small towns in swing states of his native <LOCATION> Midwest </LOCATION>. And he continues to echo positions already propounded by the campaign. But after a week of scrutiny, even the most dedicated skeptics were forced to observe that <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> did indeed seem to be a changed candidate. Those who have known <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> for years say his new style typifies him before he was lifted from relative obscurity to the intense spotlight of a national political campaign. He is quick to challenge protesters who disrupt his speeches, telling them `` You do n't know my record.'' And his speeches are often delivered from notecards rather than prepared texts. Often, they are followed by a chatty question-and-answer session with the audience. With close media scrutiny and the fallout from damaging questions about his military service, academic record and personal life _ it simply took <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> time to decide that it was best to just be himself, aides argue. It is a theory <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> echoes. `` I was just trying to feel my way through this national campaign and what the ground rules were and the expectations are and how best I can serve <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, and it's just taken me a while,'' he said. `` Now I know and now I'm off on my own.'' <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> tackled his new role with relish. In fact, his enthusiasm for his self-styled job of `` Dr. Spin'' _ the man who interprets campaign developments for the press _ was such that a sign was posted at the entrance of the press section of the plane reading: `` Spin Free Zone.'' But <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> came back anyway, again and again. hose <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> strategists would be wringing their hands, <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> told reporters one night as he perched on a the arm of a seat in the aircraft, `` if they knew I was back here now.'' <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> says the moment he knew he had to break away came two days after his debate with Democrat <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>, when he learned of the anonymous sniping from <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> staffers who viewed him as a liability to the ticket. Angry, <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> telephoned <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> campaign chairman <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>. Then he went public, saying he would take more control of his campaign. Aides denied that the whole episode was <PERSON> Baker </PERSON>'s latest ploy to prop up a weak candidate. What appeared more likely was that <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> and company had turned <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>'s dissatisfaction into a positive development. Campaign officials in fact seemed delighted at the media attention drawn by <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>'s metamorphosis into an `` in-charge'' candidate. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> says that if the strategists `` did n't like what I was doing, I suppose they could find a way to try to stop me.'' `` But ... I think what is happening is that they trust my judgment and my judgment from a political point of view is good,'' he said. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> denies suggestions of a rift between the two camps. `` We're all together. We're all pulling together for <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>.'' The new strategy may be risky. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>'s campaign to date has been noteworthy for those few moments when he did strike out on his own to depart from a prepared text and ended up committing gaffes, such as the time he told reporters, `` I did n't live in this century.'' But <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> seems philosophical about the dangers. `` You're in a critical position no matter how you conduct yourself and I made a decision on the way I'm going to conduct myself ... and it's going to be entirely different than I did the first weeks of the campaign,'' he said. `` In some respects you can say that it's a higher wire that we're walking on, but it will help <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and I am convinced of that,'' he said. `` That's my judgment and I'm very comfortable with it.''
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Eileen </PERSON> <PERSON> Putman </PERSON> is an <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> writer covering <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>'s campaign.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881017-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-17-88 0126EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Dukakis-Budgets Bjt   10-17 0917</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Dukakis-Budgets, Bjt,910</SECOND>
<HEAD>Dukakis Record of Budget-Balancing In Massachusetts</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DUNCAN MANSFIELD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BOSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Democratic presidential candidate <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> has been variously described as draconian and innovative in his fiscal policies as governor of <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION>, but the record suggests he met the bottom line in balancing nine state budgets through good times and bad. Criticism lingers about how <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> turned a $ 360 million revenue shortfall into a $ 67 million surplus in the fiscal year that ended June 30. And doubts remain about whether the current $ 11.6 billion budget _ <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' 10th as governor _ will be in balance when fiscal 1989 ends next June. But even as those concerns leave the lips mostly of a small <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> minority in the <ORGANIZATION> Legislature </ORGANIZATION> and find their way onto the national scene in the rhetoric of <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' presidential opponent, Vice President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, non-partisan experts continue to show confidence in the <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> economy and the governor's management of state finances `` There are n't many financial analysts that listen too closely to politicians; we've been -LRB- deceived -RRB- too many times by them,'' said bond analyst <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON> <PERSON> Naylor </PERSON>, senior vice president with the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> firm of <ORGANIZATION> Rodman </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <ORGANIZATION> Renshaw </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc </ORGANIZATION>. In a report this past week, the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> bond rating service, <ORGANIZATION> Standard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; Poor's, said it `` expects the state to continue to achieve sound financial results.'' Earlier this year, S & amp; P gave <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> its second-highest bond rating, AA-plus, marking the state's first upgrading since 1984. Another major bond rating agency, <ORGANIZATION> Moody </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Investors </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>, said last month when the commonwealth went to market with $ 250 million in long-term bonds that the state's `` budgets for both fiscal 1988 and fiscal 1989 have been balanced.'' <ORGANIZATION> Moody </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION>, which also upgraded <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION>' rating to its second-highest level this year _ the first such increase since 1975 _ noted that the state has `` little financial leeway'' in balancing fiscal 1989. But it said, `` Indicators suggest that the underlying economy continues to be among the strongest in the country.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, most recently in his Thursday night debate with <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, picked up on one small component of <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' package for balancing the fiscal 1988 budget. He accused <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> of raiding the state's pension fund reserves of $ 27 million <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> denied it. In fact, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> tapped $ 27 million in pension funds he determined to be surplus after meeting immediate state obligations to the system of about $ 560 million in fiscal 1988. More than half the $ 27 million went to a teachers' pension account and the rest to pay a general fund shortfall. State <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> executive director <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON> <PERSON> Tennant </PERSON> urged the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> back into session last week, contending the fiscal 1989 budget is as much as $ 1 billion out of balance. <PERSON> Tennant </PERSON> based his assumption on the slow rate of new revenue generated in the first fiscal quarter. Revenues for the period were up only 1.2 percent over a year ago, while the state needs a 8.3 percent annual rate to balance the budget. But the first quarter results were affected by a $ 68 million payout in corporate abatements stemming from a tax break the Legislature has now closed. The <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> administration contends revenues will rebound this year through a variety of new specialized tax increases, such as levying the sales tax on cigarettes; increased tax auditing practices and ending certain tax breaks. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Manley </PERSON>, president of the non-partisan <ORGANIZATION> Massachusetts </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Taxpayers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Alliance </ORGANIZATION>, is not so confident. The foundation estimates a shortfall of $ 180 million to $ 220 million. However, <PERSON> Manley </PERSON> said that is manageable if the administration demonstrates the same discipline it showed in fiscal 1988. The budget problems the state faced in the past fiscal year resulted mainly from unexpected changes in taxpayer behavior due to federal tax law changes, particularly affecting capital gains. As a result, final revenue growth for the year was 2.1 percent compared to a budget expectation of 6.6 percent. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> was able to balance the books on fiscal 1988 principally through the largest planned reduction in spending ever attempted in <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION>. Some $ 233 million was systematically trimmed, primarily by delaying the start of new programs. The policy caused disappointment among advocates but little reduction in existing services. The administration also shifted about $ 185 million in construction projects scheduled to be paid from general funds to long-term bonds. In the fiscal 1989 budget, which <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> proposed in January before all of the problems surfaced in fiscal 1988, he cut about $ 200 million in new and expanded programs while the Legislature was still debating the bill and vetoed or delayed spending over $ 200 million more when he signed it into law. He also won passage of several new revenue sources: the $ 33.7 million cigarette sales tax; $ 75 million from income tax updating; $ 180 million from new tax enforcement; and $ 40 million from corporate tax changes. In 1975, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> inherited a deficit that slowly grew to $ 560 million out of a budget of $ 3.8 billion. It forced him to slash spending for general relief and state employee pay raises and finally to sign an income surtax, the biggest broad-based tax in the state's history. The actions contributed to his defeat four years later and gave <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> the basis to label him a tax-raiser. Re-entering the governor's office in 1983, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> inherited another deficit projected to reach $ 300 million. This time, <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> legislators urged him to go for another big tax increase, but instead he pushed for smaller spending cutbacks and a major crackdown on uncollected taxes. The year ended with a $ 41 million surplus.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881017-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-17-88 0125EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-China-VD     10-17 0260</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-China-VD,0267</SECOND>
<HEAD>Beijing Opens First Venereal Disease Treatment Center</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> has opened its first venereal disease treatment center to handle the rapid rise in VD cases, the official <ORGANIZATION> China </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> said today. The report said the capital will grant $ 13,500 to the <ORGANIZATION> Western </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Venereal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Disease </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Prevention </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Treatment </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> and plans to set up other district centers to combat the growing health problem. It said 427 <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> residents last year were diagnosed as having gonorrhea, syphilis and other types of VD. VD is said to be most serious in southern <LOCATION> Guangdong </LOCATION> province, one of <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s most open areas bordering <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION>. The province recorded 5,600 cases last year, triple the previous year. Venereal disease was a scourge of 20th century, pre-revolutionary <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, especially in the cities, where prostitution and opium trafficking ran rampant. After the communist takeover in 1949, Chinese doctors launched a campaign to cure venereal disease _ placing prostitutes in re-education camps and treating victims. By the 1960s, <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> claimed to have virtually wiped out the diseases. But the problem returned in the 1980s with the nation's opening to the outside world Lack of education about the diseases, and lax enforcement of the ban on prostitution, are also blamed for the spread of VD. The daily said the <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> center opened with an exhibition of pictures and videos focusing on the symptoms, means of infection and harm caused by VD, and on sex and family life. About 100 people, mostly in their 20s and 30s, visited the exhibition during its first two days.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881017-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-17-88 0131EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Reagan'sLastCampaign     10-17 0653</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Reagan's Last Campaign,640</SECOND>
<HEAD>President Relishes Key Campaign Role</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Political Rdp Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MERRILL HARTSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, with little left on his agenda but to keep the White House in Republican hands, is relishing his high-profile role in <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s campaign. As he attends to the business of signing legislation passed by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> in its waning days, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> is continuing to stump for <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> in key battleground states. He'll take his `` peace-and-prosperity'' message into the heart of <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> this Wednesday, and will increase the campaign pace after <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> adjourns, possibly this week. `` I think the president's thriving. He's enjoying himself. He thinks he's making a difference,'' White House chief of staff <PERSON> Kenneth </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Duberstein </PERSON> said recently. By all accounts, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s role in <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s bid for the White House has gone through an evolution in recent weeks. The president has stepped up his appeal to the so-called `` <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> Democrats'' in <LOCATION> Midwestern </LOCATION> and Northeastern states, whereas it was once thought he would play a smaller role. `` I was of the impression that they -LRB- the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> campaign -RRB- were going to say, ` Go carry <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>,''' said Democratic consultant <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Keefe </PERSON>. Some inside both the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> campaign and the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> had said early on that <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s campaign activities would likely be focused on <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, his home state, and on southern and <LOCATION> Sun </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Belt </LOCATION> <LOCATION> states </LOCATION>, where <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> has been immensely popular, even during his hard times. One Republican strategist, discussing the changing campaign route on grounds of anonymity, said it was decided that <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> should focus on the key battleground states where there are large numbers of ethnics, conservative Democrats and independents. And so <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> has spent recent weeks in such places as <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION>. `` Some of the places where the president is strongest have just solidified for <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> ... much faster than we expected,'' said this Republican. `` So the question became, do you want to go to a state where you're 20 points up. ... It obviously makes more sense to look at the other states that are close.'' `` I think the role is just right,'' said <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> consultant <PERSON> Eddie </PERSON> <PERSON> Mahe </PERSON>. `` You're sending your biggest guns into the biggest battles, and there's no surrogate bigger than <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>.'' <PERSON> Keefe </PERSON>, the Democrat, acknowledged that the strategy of having <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> follow <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> into states the vice president has visited recently has been helpful to the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> cause. `` They have had a marvelous campaign where they have integrated the message themes very well,'' he said. Besides making campaign appearances for his vice president _ <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> will likely put on a full-court press in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, for example _ the president has used the trappings of his office to <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s benefit. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> frequently works a pro-Bush pitch into his official chores, such as bill-signings, whenever he can connect the vice president to the situation at hand, and throws pro-Bush statements into his weekly radio addresses. Perhaps <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s all-out campaign for <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> can be traced to conversations that both the president and <PERSON> Duberstein </PERSON> had with former President <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON>. <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> is known to believe that the lukewarm support given him by President <PERSON> Dwight </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Eisenhower </PERSON> in 1960 contributed to his loss to Democrat <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>. In an interview, <PERSON> Duberstein </PERSON> said that `` <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> and I spoke several months ago, and I asked him to give his historical perspective _ what <PERSON> Eisenhower </PERSON> did and did n't do for him,'' and <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> entertained <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> for a private White House dinner. The chief of staff said in an interview that because of these and other factors, `` I think it's fair to say that <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> has campaigned for his vice president in an unprecedented manner.'' <PERSON> Keefe </PERSON> agreed with that. `` What they have is an extremely commanding voice that can get himself heard any time he wants to, day or night, and it's just awfully handy to have someone who can do that,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881017-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-17-88 0134EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FarmScene     10-17 0821</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Farm Scene,820</SECOND>
<HEAD>Voracious Ducks Damaging Fish Farms</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DON KENDALL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Farm Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Fish farmers do n't believe their crops are for the birds, but try telling that to a hungry duck, blackbird or heron. `` Birds are a costly problem where fish are cultured,'' says researcher <PERSON> Vickie </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> in a new <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> report. `` Waterfowl frequently blamed for heavy losses of fish at aquacultural facilities include diving ducks, herons, egrets, terns, gulls, kingfishers, blackbirds, ospreys and anhingas.'' These birds _ the diving ducks include grebes, cormorants and mergansers _ were described as `` voracious fish eaters'' that not only cause property loss and damage but can transmit diseases to fish stock. `` Due to fecal contamination and the fact that some of the fish they consumed are diseased, predatory birds may transmit diseases from pond to pond,'' she said. Moreover, when fish farmers attempt to guard against the airborne marauders, they can be frustrated because a majority of the birds are legally categorized as migratory and are protected under federal and state laws. <PERSON> Martin </PERSON>, a student at <ORGANIZATION> Fort </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Valley </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ga. </LOCATION>, worked as an intern for the department's <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> the last two summers. Although there are no figures documenting bird predation by fish species and location, she said losses to birds have been reported on baitfish, catfish, shellfish, tropical fish and trout, and are greatest in the largest aquaculture states: <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Arkansas </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION>. `` Baitfish, particularly minnows, are lost to blackbirds in the winter, cormorants in the fall and winter, and herons in the summer,'' <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> said. `` In the Northeast, herons prey on baitfish in the fall, while trout are harassed by grackles, kingfishers, herons, ospreys and occasionally owls during the spring, late summer and early fall.'' She added that diving ducks are the main bird threats to shellfish, although swans occasionally are problems. `` Catfish in the Southeast are preyed upon most by anhingas -LRB- locally called water turkeys -RRB- and kingfishers during the spring and summer months,'' <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> said. `` Herons and cormorants cause problems year-round. Crawfish and shrimp are prone to predation by purple grackles, herons, egrets, ibises, gulls, diving ducks and kingfishers.'' Fish ponds can be protected somewhat by barriers such as perimeter fencing, netting, overhead wires and other devices, including fireworks, exploders and similar items used to frighten birds. Some chemicals, such as Avitrol, a registered `` frightening agent'' for use on herring gulls and blackbirds, have also been effective, she said. But state and federal permits are required to use this chemical on gulls, because they are legally protected. After ingesting the chemical, the gull `` will behave erratically and emit distress calls,'' which frighten away the other birds, she said. Some migratory game birds may be shot during the hunting season, and other permits are available for some species. Local state and federal wildlife authorities should be contacted. Still, <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> said, some fish farmers believe `` birds are uncontrollable and that all frightening tactics are futile, no matter what method of control of prevention is used.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> has decided to renew an advisory panel in hopes of out-thinking or out-maneuvering some of the `` depredating animals'' that cause losses to farmers. Deputy Secretary <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Myers </PERSON> said losses to farmers from blackbirds, rodent and coyotes _ which were named as examples _ are estimated at more than $ 300 million a year and `` often represent the difference between profit and loss'' for many producers. In recently announcing the renewal of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Animal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Damage </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Control </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Advisory </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Myers </PERSON> said the panel serves as a public forum so that ranchers, farmers and wildlife interests can have a voice in <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> policies on animal control. Members of the committee include scientists, farmers, trade association representatives, university and government people. The chairman is Assistant Secretary <PERSON> Kenneth </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gilles </PERSON>, who oversees <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> marketing and inspection services.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Researchers say Southern poultry farmers could save an estimated $ 7 million a year by using softer, lower-power lights in their broiler houses. High summer heat makes chickens go off their feed, so producers keep broiler houses lighted during the summer nights so the birds will eat during the cooler hours, says <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Deaton </PERSON> of the department's <ORGANIZATION> Agricultural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Deaton </PERSON> said farmers traditionally use 75 - or 100-watt bulbs because they want to simulate actual daylight `` But our tests show that broiler chickens more than two weeks old eat normally and gain just as much weight under 25-watt bulbs,'' he said in a report released here by the agency. <PERSON> Deaton </PERSON>, who works at the department's <ORGANIZATION> South </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Poultry </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Laboratory </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> said the annual savings `` could amount to $ 7 million across the South, or about $ 1,000 for a typical producer who raises about 160,000 chickens during the summer.'' The tests also showed that chickens under the dimmer lights `` waste less feed energy in fighting, running around and chirping,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881017-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-17-88 0135EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-CivilRights-Martin     10-17 0656</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Civil Rights-Martin,650</SECOND>
<HEAD>Congresswoman Calls House Civil Rights Compliance Long Overdue</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID FOX</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Few were as surprised as Rep. <PERSON> Lynn </PERSON> <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> when her six-year fight to extend civil rights protection to <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> employees finally paid off. `` Six years we'd been fighting for this! Sometimes, you'd feel like you were banging your head against the wall,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> said. `` So I really did n't expect it to happen the way it did.'' To the <ORGANIZATION> Illinois </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION>'s surprise, members agreed overwhelmingly this month to end what she calls `` the ultimate irony,'' their self-enacted exemption from the Civil Rights Act of 1964. `` To impose a law, as we did, and then totally exempt oneself is a kind of hypocrisy that should not have continued this long,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> said. `` The <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> recognized this, finally. It's about time.'' The chamber approved a compromise offered by Rep. <PERSON> Leon </PERSON> <PERSON> Panetta </PERSON>, D-Calif., banning discrimination on the basis of race, age, sex, religion, handicap or national origin in the hiring and employment of <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> committee and staff employees The measure taking effect Nov. 3 also establishes an Office of Fair Employment Practices to hear discrimination complaints, mediate disputes and penalize <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> members who violate the law. Mrs. <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> blamed the lack of progress _ until this year _ on resistance from `` a handful of old dons who run this place like they had their own little fiefdoms and do n't want it to change.'' `` That's probably true,'' <PERSON> Panetta </PERSON> said Friday. `` There are older members on both sides of the aisle who resisted ethics reform, too, when it happened a few years ago. On the other hand, they've been around long enough to know changes are inevitable. This one was.'' The <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> lawmaker began her campaign for the civil rights legislation in 1982, when a study she requested found inequities between the salaries paid to male and female employees on <LOCATION> Capitol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION>. Although she complained about the disparity to colleagues, Mrs. <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> said a follow-up survey in 1984 showed little change. She introduced a bill in January 1985 to require <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and the federal judiciary to comply with the Civil Rights Act. The bill died in subcommittee. Last May, after a third study found a continuing gap between pay for men and that received by women and minorities, she submitted the bill again. This time, it bore the names of more than 100 co-sponsors. The action finally approved Oct. 4 on a 408-12 vote amends <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> rules to prohibit discrimination by members. The exemption to the civil rights law still applies to the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> and the judiciary. However, lawmakers agreed under the compromise to consider Mrs. <PERSON> Martin </PERSON>'s proposal again in June with an eye to creating a statute that would cover all congressional and judicial employees. Although 12 members voted against the measure, aides said the votes did not necessarily mean they disagreed with its intent. `` The boss went in planning to vote for it,'' said <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> VanHoose </PERSON>, the administrative assistant to Rep. <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Hopkins </PERSON>, R-Ky. `` His opposition was purely symbolic `` He is completely in sympathy with <PERSON> Lynn </PERSON> <PERSON> Martin </PERSON>. He just did n't think the compromise went far enough, because <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>' record is n't too impressive when it comes to regulating itself. <PERSON> Tish </PERSON> <PERSON> Brink </PERSON>, a spokeswoman for Rep. <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> DeLay </PERSON>, said the <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> Republican `` objected because he opposes regulation generally.'' Meanwhile, Mrs. <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> said she has started getting `` some fallout'' from members who voted for the change but have reservations about it. For example, an aide said one complained that eliminating the Civil Rights Act exemption would force him to fire some female employees because he had more women on his staff than men. That concern is unfounded, Mrs. <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> said. `` I'm sure there is a down side to this somewhere,'' she added. `` I'll get the blame for any problem, there's no question about that. But occasionally, you do the right thing. This one, I've got no regrets on.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881017-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-17-88 0137EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-CongressRdp Bjt   10-17 0655</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Congress Rdp, Bjt,650</SECOND>
<HEAD>Drug, Tax Bills Major Items Left for 100th Congress</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDS: Senate meets at 10 a.m. EDT; may be led</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By LEE GOULD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The 100th <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> plans to adjourn this week once it clears its desk of unfinished business including a campaign-year attack in the war on drugs. The fate of dozens of bills lies in the balance as the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> begin what both sides agree will be the last week of the two-year <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. The biggest of the bills is a massive anti-drug package passed by the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> last Friday. The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> bill is n't as tough on drug users as one passed earlier by the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and negotiators from both bodies will be meeting to try to resolve the differences. If they agree on a single package, a final vote will be needed in the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> before it can go to President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> for enactment into law. House and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> negotiators were bogged down on another major legislative package _ so-called technical corrections to a 1986 tax bill. In addition to making technical corrections to that bill, the proposal included selected new tax reductions, the tax increases to pay for them, and a `` bill of rights'' for taxpayers facing enforcement or collection action from the <ORGANIZATION> Internal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Revenue </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>. Differences in the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> versions of the bill were so sharp that negotiations broke down Friday and an aide to <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> negotiators said `` whether the conference gets back together at all again is very much up in the air.'' On the other end of the priority list were bills ranging from legislation designed to assist individual people, nominations of federal judges, water projects affecting specific cities and states and a plan to end the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>' trusteeship over the western <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> island nation of <LOCATION> Palau </LOCATION>. Yet another bill that could make it under the wire would elevate the Veterans Administration to Cabinet-level status. The fate of each of them was up in the air as members, already in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> for a week or two longer than they had hoped, strive toward an adjournment that will let them go home and campaign for re-election. <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Majority Leader <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON>, D-W. <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, told senators on Friday that `` I certainly would hope we would n't have to stay beyond But nobody can predict that.'' The House returns from a long weekend on Tuesday with a scheduled vote on legislation that would require full disclosure of credit card information to consumers. The bill, passed by the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> last week, requires that banks, department stores and other companies that offer credit cards tell consumers about annual fees, interest rates, late fees and other information. Currently, only a few states have laws requiring public disclosure of such information before consumers receive the cards. Rep. <PERSON> Fernand </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> St </PERSON> <PERSON> Germain </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-R.I. </LOCATION>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Banking </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, called the measure `` one of the most important and strongest credit disclosure acts that we have been able to move through the <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> since the first truth-in-lending statute was passed 20 years ago.'' Also pending is legislation providing first-ever restrictions on lobbying by former members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, part of a general tightening of federal rules against influence peddling by top government officials. The legislation has passed both houses of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> in different versions and a compromise will have to be worked out before it can win final approval and be sent to <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>. The bill covers not only lobbying, but any communication done for pay to influence government decisions, including writing letters, filing motions or granting requests. It would prevent members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and senior staff members, for one year after leaving office, from contacting the legislative house in which they served. The restrictions also would apply to lobbying for pay by anyone from the president and vice president on down through the top several thousand executive-branch policy makers.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881017-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-17-88 0138EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-SpiesforBush Bjt   10-17 0775</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Spies for Bush, Bjt,750</SECOND>
<HEAD>Spies Make No Secret of Support for Bush</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOAN MOWER</BYLINE>
