<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880917-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-17-88 0217EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-GayRodeo     09-17 0434</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Gay Rodeo,0446</SECOND>
<HEAD>Contract Battle Waged Over Controversial National Event</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LAURA MYERS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>RENO, Nev. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Organizers of a rodeo for homosexuals on Friday accused officials of the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nevada-Reno </ORGANIZATION> officials of bowing to public pressure and using a contract dispute to cancel the contest. In August, the university's <ORGANIZATION> Lawlor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Events </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> canceled the contract to rent out its stadium Oct. 21-23 for the international championship gay rodeo, in which top riders from regional gay rodeos compete. `` I think it is just an excuse on the part of <LOCATION> Lawlor </LOCATION> to prevent these types of events from coming to the facility,'' attorney <PERSON> Rod </PERSON> <PERSON> Sumpter </PERSON> told a <ORGANIZATION> Washoe </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> judge. <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Klasic </PERSON>, general counsel for the university and <PERSON> Lawlor </PERSON>, denied the charge, telling the judge, `` It has always been a contract action. This is not a civil rights action.'' On Sept. 1, the <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Gay </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rodeo </ORGANIZATION> and the Silver State Gay Rodeo associations sued <ORGANIZATION> UNR </ORGANIZATION>, which oversees the events center on its campus. The associations are seeking an injuction from Judge <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Forman </PERSON> to force <PERSON> Lawlor </PERSON> to rent its stadium for the gay rodeo, which has been advertised for several months throughout the world. <PERSON> Forman </PERSON> said he would rule on the injuction Monday. <PERSON> Klasic </PERSON> told the court the contract was canceled by <PERSON> Lawlor </PERSON> after Aug. 15 when the gay organization failed to come up with $ 9,000 in pre-payments to cover expenses for security, parking, cleanup and other operation costs. He said <PERSON> Lawlor </PERSON> became concerned about the organization's ability to pay expenses so a prepayment schedule was orally agreed to in June. <PERSON> Les </PERSON> <PERSON> Krambeal </PERSON>, president of the international association, said he only agreed to the demands because he feared <PERSON> Lawlor </PERSON> otherwise would cancel the event. His organization paid $ 2,263 in prepayments before running out of money. During initial contract talks in October 1987 and when the document was signed in February 1988, <PERSON> Krambeal </PERSON> said he was told expenses would not be due until Oct. 23. <PERSON> Sumpter </PERSON> said the written contract did not call for any prepayments. Instead, it only required that $ 7,300 be paid up front to rent out the stadium, which was done, he said. <PERSON> Sumpter </PERSON> said <PERSON> Lawlor </PERSON> used the financial concern as a way to cause the association to violate its contract because of negative complaints from area residents who protested similar events held in the late 1970s and early 1980s. The prepayment plan was decided only after news leaked that a gay rodeo was returning to <PERSON> Reno </PERSON> and two local business groups told <PERSON> Lawlor </PERSON> officials that previous gay rodeo organizations did n't pay all their bills, he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880917-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-17-88 0246EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Colombia-Rebels     09-17 0444</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Colombia-Rebels,0458</SECOND>
<HEAD>Guerrillas free five imprisoned comrades, kill hostage</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TOM WELLS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BOGOTA, Colombia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Left-wing guerrillas firing automatic weapons burst into a federal court building in the town of <LOCATION> Buga </LOCATION> Friday and freed five of their comrades being held for trial, police reported. They said a judge's administrative assistant was taken hostage by the gunmen and his body was found with a bullet in the head beside a highway near the town 160 miles southwest of <LOCATION> Bogota </LOCATION>. Two of the guerrillas freed by the attackers were captured after an hour-long pursuit, the police said. They did not report any other casualties or give further details. In other developments, leftist rebels freed 22 government soldiers and policemen captured in a raid last month and also released two Colombian geologists seized in another attack, the government and military announced. The soldiers and policemen freed Friday had been taken prisoner Aug. 23 by guerrillas of the <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Colombian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Revolutionary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Armed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forces </ORGANIZATION> during a joint attack on the northwestern town of <LOCATION> Saiza </LOCATION>. A statement from the office of President <PERSON> Virgilio </PERSON> <PERSON> Barcos </PERSON> said a one-day cease-fire had been arranged so the captives could be released in the <LOCATION> Uraba </LOCATION> region, about 300 miles northwest of <LOCATION> Bogota </LOCATION>. Two of the government troopers had been wounded in the rocket and mortar attack on the police station in <LOCATION> Saiza </LOCATION>, Gen. <PERSON> Jesus </PERSON> <PERSON> Arias </PERSON> said in an interview with the radio station <ORGANIZATION> RCN </ORGANIZATION>. He did not list their conditions or elaborate. The two geologists released Thursday were among five who worked with coal companies and were kidnapped Aug. 20 by rebels of another guerrilla group, the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>, or ELN. Rebels freed the two geologists in an arranged meeting with a group of reporters in the city of <LOCATION> Bucaramanga </LOCATION>, 200 miles northeast of <LOCATION> Bogota </LOCATION>. An <ORGANIZATION> ELN </ORGANIZATION> communique said the three other geologists would be released soon, but declared the guerrillas would launch an offensive against foreign coal-mining companies. <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION> and the <LOCATION> Colombian </LOCATION> state company <ORGANIZATION> Carbacol </ORGANIZATION> are partners in a $ 3 billion surface mine near <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Caribbean </LOCATION> coast. <ORGANIZATION> ELN </ORGANIZATION> guerrillas have attacked oil pipelines and oil installations operated by <ORGANIZATION> Occidental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Petroleum </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Shell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Oil </ORGANIZATION> and the <LOCATION> Colombian </LOCATION> state company <ORGANIZATION> Ecopetrol </ORGANIZATION> 46 times this year, according to the government. It placed the damage at $ 300 million. A <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> communique released Friday said 1,174 people have been killed this year in guerrilla attacks and battles between rebels and security forces. It listed the slain as 499 guerrillas, 378 civilians and 297 policemen and soldiers. The ministry has reported 2,037 people were killed last year in fighting involving rebels, government forces and civilians caught in the violence.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880917-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-17-88 0640EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-MondoArrest     09-17 0308</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Mondo Arrest,0317</SECOND>
<HEAD>Cult Film Performer Arrested for Mice-Biting Act</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Note contents</NOTE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An underground performer who allegedly bites the heads off two mice in the cult film `` <LOCATION> Mondo </LOCATION> <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>'' has been arrested on animal cruelty charges, an <ORGANIZATION> ASPCA </ORGANIZATION> spokesman said. <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Coleman </PERSON>, 32, a <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION> performance artist, was taken into custody by <ORGANIZATION> ASPCA </ORGANIZATION> agents at his <LOCATION> Greenwich </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Village </LOCATION> apartment Friday, said <PERSON> Jeffrey </PERSON> <PERSON> Hon </PERSON>, spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION> for the Prevention of Cruelty to Animals. <PERSON> Coleman </PERSON> was booked at a police station on charges under the state Agriculture and Markets Law; if convicted, he could face up to one year in prison and a $ 1,000 fine per mouse, <PERSON> Hon </PERSON> said. `` While this one act may seem fairly insignificant, the whole issue of animals in entertainment is not,'' said <PERSON> Hon </PERSON>. `` We're letting people from underground acts to <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION> producers know they ca n't get away with animal cruelty. <PERSON> Coleman </PERSON> was still being processed by police and could not immediately be reached for comment. `` <LOCATION> Mondo </LOCATION> <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>,'' a cult favorite which plays in weekend midnight shows at a <LOCATION> Greenwich </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Village </LOCATION> theater, features an assortment of bizarre acts from the downtown <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION> scene. Although the film was released earlier this summer, <PERSON> Coleman </PERSON> was not arrested because <ORGANIZATION> ASPCA </ORGANIZATION> investigators hoped to catch him in the act during one of his live performances, <PERSON> Hon </PERSON> said. Authorities have an eyewitness to <PERSON> Coleman </PERSON>'s performance and decided to arrest him after receiving a tip that he was leaving for <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, he said. In his scene, <PERSON> Coleman </PERSON> allegedly bites the heads off two mice and spits them into the audience. According to <PERSON> Hon </PERSON>, the scene has outraged animal rights activists, including television game show host <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Barker </PERSON>. `` <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Barker </PERSON> has been very keen for us to arrest this guy <PERSON> Coleman </PERSON> so legislators can see exactly what's going on,'' said <PERSON> Hon </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880917-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-17-88 0641EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-People-Rivers     09-17 0229</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-People-Rivers,0235</SECOND>
<HEAD>Rivers Negotiates for Talk Show Job</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Comedian <PERSON> Joan </PERSON> <PERSON> Rivers </PERSON> is currently in negotation with with <ORGANIZATION> Tribune </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Entertainment </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> about hosting a daytime television talk show, according to industry newspaper reports. The former host of <ORGANIZATION> Fox </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Broadcasting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>'s `` The Late Show'' and guest host of <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` The Tonight Show Starring <PERSON> Johnny </PERSON> <PERSON> Carson </PERSON>'' is said to be working out a deal for a 26-week cycle beginning in the fall of 1989 that would serve as a counterpart to <ORGANIZATION> Tribune </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Geraldo. Neither Miss Rivers nor <ORGANIZATION> Tribune </ORGANIZATION> could be reached for comment in calls made after business hours. Although a contract has not been signed, it was only a matter of `` crossing the T's and dotting the I's,'' according to Friday's editions of The Hollywood Reporter The talk show would be carried by the six Tribune-owned television stations, including <ORGANIZATION> KTLA </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> WPIX </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> and WGN in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>, The <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Variety </ORGANIZATION> reported in its Friday editions. Miss Rivers is currently appearing on <LOCATION> Broadway </LOCATION> in <PERSON> Neil </PERSON> <PERSON> Simon </PERSON>'s `` Broadway Bound. She also stars as the permanent `` center square'' on television's `` Hollywood Squares.'' Miss Rivers vacated the guest host spot on the <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> talk show in 1986 to take the starring role in `` The Late Show,'' which debuted Oct. 9, 1986. The show got lower ratings than expected, and she left the program in May 1987.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880917-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-17-88 0255EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-US-Soviet Bjt   09-17 0681</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-US-Soviet, Bjt,680</SECOND>
<HEAD>Administration Cool To Soviet Offer On Bases</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MERRILL HARTSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration is reacting coolly to new Soviet proposals aimed at removing <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> objections to a large radar facility in <LOCATION> Siberia </LOCATION>. White House spokesman <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said Friday the administration continues to insist that the <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION> dismantle the huge installation at <LOCATION> Krasnoyarsk </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials say the facility violates the Anti-Ballistic Missile treaty. There is little administration interest in a Soviet offer to allow <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials to inspect the facility or a separate proposal to convert it into an international space center, <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> indicated. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials took a mostly cautious stance in response to several initiatives that Soviet General Secretary <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> announced Friday in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> _ steps that <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> said would improve world security. Among <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s proposals was an offer to dismantle a large Soviet naval base at <LOCATION> Cam </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ranh </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> in exchange for <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> willingness to close military installations in the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION>. President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> told reporters he had not had time to study the <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> proposal fully, saying, `` I look forward to doing that because we certainly want to do anything we can to help bring about a better relationship between our two countries.'' But in a reference to the pitfalls of card-playing, he said, `` As I have frequently said to him -LRB- <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> -RRB-, ` Trust everybody, but cut the cards.''' <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> voiced skepticism earlier, saying, `` We're somewhat pessimistic.'' `` It just does n't seem to make sense on the face of it,'' the spokesman said when asked about <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s base-closing proposal. `` But, on the other hand,'' he said, `` we want to give a full analysis to the speech to that proposal, and the context of what was said. ... I do n't want to elaborate. We'll wait for a more detailed analysis.'' <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> also proposed creation of an international center on the peaceful use of outer space at the Siberian radar station, according to the Soviet news agency <ORGANIZATION> Tass </ORGANIZATION>. It appeared he was proposing the elimination or conversion of the <LOCATION> Krasnoyarsk </LOCATION> radar installation, which the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government claims violates the 1972 ABM treaty. <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said `` there was some mention'' of allowing <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> inspectors into <LOCATION> Krasnoyarsk </LOCATION> during a recent superpower review of the ABM treaty in <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION>, and he said, `` We essentially reject that idea.'' `` Our demand has always been that <LOCATION> Krasnoyarsk </LOCATION> be dismantled as a violation of the ABM treaty and we still believe that to be the case,'' he said. `` To allow inspections or personnel to view their equipment and so forth, or to turn it into a space station or a drive-in movie theater, or anything else, simply does not respond to the need to dismantle what is a violation of the treaty,'' the spokesman said. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> maintains that the <LOCATION> Krasnoyarsk </LOCATION> facility violates provisions of the ABM treaty prohibiting the deployment of large radar stations capable of giving early missile attack warnings unless such facilities are stationed on the periphery of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> or Soviet territory. The Soviets have argued that the facility's function is to follow objects in outer space. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> got some support from <LOCATION> Capitol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION> as the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> voted 81-0 to support the administration's contention that the giant Soviet radar system violates the treaty. `` These violations are a threat to the security of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>,'' said Sen. <PERSON> Malcolm </PERSON> <PERSON> Wallop </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Wyo </LOCATION>., author of the resolution The non-binding resolution said the radar station question should be settled before there are any new U.S.-Soviet agreements on limiting strategic, or long-range, atomic weapons. The two sides are now negotiating toward a 50 percent reduction in such arms. The resolution also urged <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> to develop `` appropriate, proportionate response options'' to the Soviet radar station. <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> told reporters at the daily <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> news briefing that the administration was not yet prepared to declare <LOCATION> Krasnoyarsk </LOCATION> a `` material breach'' of the treaty _ a step that effectively would serve notice of American withdrawal from the ABM pact. `` I frankly think it's unlikely that there would be any change in our present position'' against a breakout from the treaty, he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880917-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-17-88 0634EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-SpaceShuttle Bjt   09-17 0521</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Space Shuttle, Bjt,0533</SECOND>
<HEAD>NASA Sets Shuttle Launch Date As Threat Of Hurricane Eases</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By HARRY F. ROSENTHAL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The much-delayed launch of the shuttle Discovery for the first manned space mission since the 1986 Challenger disaster has been set by <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> for Sept. 29. A three hour launch `` window'' from the <ORGANIZATION> Kennedy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Space </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> opens at 9:59 a.m. EDT. `` I'm delighted to have reached this point,'' said <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Truly </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aeronautics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Space </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> flight chief, in making the announcement Friday. `` My hat is off to all members of the shuttle team whose tireless efforts have brought us here to the brink of <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s return to manned space.'' The date was set after Truly decided that Hurricane <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON> would not disrupt operations at the <ORGANIZATION> Johnson </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Space </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION>, home of <ORGANIZATION> Mission </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Control </ORGANIZATION> for shuttle flights. `` No threat to <ORGANIZATION> JSC </ORGANIZATION> facilities is projected if <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON> continues on its current path,'' the announcement said. The first flight in 32 months will be a four-day, one hour mission to deploy a huge <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> communications satellite. Discovery is to land at <ORGANIZATION> Edwards </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> base in the <LOCATION> Mojave </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Desert </LOCATION> on Oct. 3, if the launch goes as scheduled. <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> Capt. <PERSON> Frederick </PERSON> <PERSON> Hauck </PERSON> will command the five-man flight, all of whom have been on previous missions. The crewmen are <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> Col. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> O </PERSON>. <PERSON> Covey </PERSON>, the pilot, and mission specialists <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON>, <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Lounge </PERSON> and Marine Lt. Col. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Hilmers </PERSON>. The shuttle was cleared for flight Wednesday after a two-day review of the shuttle's systems and the readiness of launch and flight control teams at the launch site. The $ 100 million Tracking and Data Relay Satellite that the astronauts will carry into orbit is a twin of one lost in the Challenger explosion Jan. 28, 1986. It is needed to complete a communications system that eventually will replace all ground-to-air links with the space shuttle and a number of satellites. They will also conduct 11 science and technology experiments and check out hundreds of design changes made to the shuttle. <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> had hoped to return to manned space flight sooner with the 26th shuttle mission, designated as STS-26. But five announced launch dates had to be scrubbed because of technical problems involved in the $ 1.2 billion redesign. There were 56 major changes and more than 400 lesser ones; the orbiter alone received 210 fixes. The most extensive changes were made to solid fuel rockets that provide more than 70 percent of the power to propel the shuttle into orbit. The Challenger explosion, which claimed the lives of seven astronauts including schoolteacher <PERSON> Christa </PERSON> <PERSON> McAuliffe </PERSON>, was caused by a leak in one booster that allowed a plume of flame to reach the fuel tank. <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> grounded the shuttles following the explosion. One major change implemented is an escape system designed for use if the shuttle has to ditch in the ocean. It has been installed in Discovery and will be put into the two other shuttles remaining in the fleet. A replacement for Challenger is being built and should be ready for flight in 1990.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880917-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-17-88 0643EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-BRF--FoodPoisoning     09-17 0136</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Food Poisoning,0139</SECOND>
<HEAD>More Than 220 Students Treated For Apparent Food Poisoning</HEAD>
<DATELINE>GRAND FORKS, N.D. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A sudden rash of illness affecting hundreds of <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> North </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dakota </ORGANIZATION> students who ate at a school cafeteria has been blamed on food poisoning, university officials said. More than 220 students had been treated with antibiotics at the school's student health services as of Friday, university spokesman <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> said. Two diabetic students were hospitalized as a precaution, <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> said. All of the students apparently had eaten recently at the Wilkerson Hall cafeteria, school officials said. The cafeteria serves a university complex of five residence halls, which house about 1,500 students. Dr. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Swenson </PERSON>, director of student health services, said food poisoning was the most likely cause of the illnesses, which included stomach cramps, diarrhea and vomiting.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880917-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-17-88 0015EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w PM-US-Vietnam     09-17 0499</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-US-Vietnam,500</SECOND>
<HEAD>US, Vietnam To Search for MIA's</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GEORGE GEDDA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A joint U.S.-Vietnamese team soon will begin an on-site investigation into the fate of missing <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> servicemen, focussing on seven cases in which there is evidence the victims were alive when they disappeared. <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Redman </PERSON> said Friday the seven are part of the 70 `` most compelling cases'' which <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials raised with Vietnamese authorities last year. Other officials said that although the 70 were presumed to be alive when they became separated from their units, all have long since been presumed dead because there is no evidence to prove otherwise. This is the first time the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> have agreed on a joint investigation involving more than one site. Officials from the two countries participated in the excavation of a crash site in search of missing servicemen in November 1985. Lt. Col. <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Harvey </PERSON>, commander of the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Joint Casualty Resolution Center, said in a telephone interview Friday from <LOCATION> Honolulu </LOCATION>, `` We're going to do joint investigations of incidents, not just crash sites, but places where people were last thought to be but we do n't know exactly what happened to them. `` I think it's a very significant development,'' he said. `` We think this will be the first of many such joint activities.'' The inspections will be concentrated in an area north of <LOCATION> Hanoi </LOCATION>. On Friday, <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Republican Leader <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Michel </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> urged the families of missing servicemen to ignore the rumors that will be inevitable during the pending search. `` We have to continue to press for an accounting of each and every one, even though the prospects of finding anyone alive diminish with the passing of time,'' <PERSON> Michel </PERSON> told a crowd of several hundred at a National POW-MIA Recognition Day ceremony on the steps of the Capitol. All told, more than 1,700 Americans remain unaccounted for in <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> since <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military involvement in the country ended 15 years ago. There is no firm evidence that any are alive although officials routinely check out reports of live sightings. The two countries reached agreement on an on-site inspection procedure during a meeting in <LOCATION> Hanoi </LOCATION> that ended Wednesday, <PERSON> Redman </PERSON> said. The investigation will involve interviews with villagers and other activities. A 90-day period, beginning Sept. 1, was set aside for carrying out the investigations, <PERSON> Redman </PERSON> said, with each one limited to 10 days. After suspending cooperation with the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> on the MIA issue in August, <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> recently agreed to resume discussions on the issue. The suspension was precipitated by <LOCATION> Hanoi </LOCATION>'s unhappiness with the administration's policy of keeping <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> isolated diplomatically and economically until that country withdraws its troops from <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> is one of the few countries with which the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> does not have diplomatic relations. While restoring cooperation on the MIA question, <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> has not lifted a ban on discussions about a program to permit thousands of former political prisoners to emigrate to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880917-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-17-88 0335EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-LotteryRdp     09-17 0083</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lottery Rdp,0088</SECOND>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the winning weekly state lottery numbers picked so far this week:
</TEXT>
<HEAD>CONNECTICUT</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Lotto: 01; 05; 06; 17; 21; 28.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>DELAWARE</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Play 4: 3-9-9-0.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>MASSACHUSETTS</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Wednesday Megabucks: 01; 03; 07; 23 28 31.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>NEW JERSEY</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Pick 6 Lotto: 01; 04; 19; 27; 40; 41. Bonus: 40531.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>NEW YORK</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Wednesday Lotto 54 Game: 09; 22; 24; 32; 37; 49. Supplementary 31.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>PENNSYLVANIA</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Big 4 Lottery: 7-0-6-8.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>RHODE ISLAND</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Grand Lot Game: 1-4-9; 9-5-2-9; 4-5-4-4-0; 7-4-6-9-3-0.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880917-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-17-88 0335EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lottery     09-17 0025</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lottery,0026</SECOND>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the winning weekly state lottery numbers picked Friday:
</TEXT>
<HEAD>CONNECTICUT</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Lotto: 01; 05; 06; 17; 21; 28.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880917-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-17-88 0245EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-PersianGulf-Navy Bjt   09-17 0585</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Persian Gulf-Navy, Bjt,0601</SECOND>
<HEAD>US Considers Changing Convoy Procedures In Persian Gulf</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By NORMAN BLACK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Military Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration has approved in principle its first change in <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> convoy procedures as a result of the Iran-Iraq cease-fire, defense officials say. Assuming the changes are finalized, U.S.-flag tankers in the waterway will be kept within a `` defensive zone'' by American warships and always under surveillance, but wo n't be accompanied every step of the way as is now the case, the sources said. `` The best way to describe it is in basketball terms, by saying you're going from a man-to-man defense to a zone defense,'' said one official. The change will allow only a slight reduction in the number of warships deployed to the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> _ probably one fewer ship _ but will increase the flexibility of the task force commander and allow the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>'s ships to operate at a lesser alert level, the officials added. The sources, who agreed to discuss the matter only if not identified, said the change in procedure had been tentatively approved by the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, but would not be ordered until allies with warships in the region and certain <LOCATION> Mideast </LOCATION> countries were consulted. The <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> declined to discuss details of the plan on Friday but acknowledged in a statement: `` The administration is considering additional steps which ... -LRB- could be described as -RRB- modest modifications of our present method of providing protection to U.S.-flagged shipping in the gulf. `` The modifications currently under consideration do not involve any significant reduction in force levels. We are continuing to consult with our friends and allies.'' The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has 26 <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> ships assigned to its Joint Task Force <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION>, including 17 inside the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> itself. As of Friday, the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> had conducted 85 convoy operations since the summer of 1987, when the escorts began. With the exception of the departure of one cruiser, the <ORGANIZATION> USS </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Vincennes </ORGANIZATION>, the naval force has not changed in size despite last month's end to hostilities between <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Carlucci </PERSON> has said repeatedly the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> will not reduce its military presence in the region until it is absolutely convinced the cease-fire will hold and that <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> merchant ships are n't threatened. According to the sources, <PERSON> Carlucci </PERSON> has approved the idea of `` providing flexibility'' to the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> on convoys. `` You keep your warships nearby, always close enough to act, but drop the continuous, side-by-side presence,'' explained one source. `` The <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> vessels deploy in what amounts to a picket line up and down the gulf, ready to pick up a merchant as it moves within a particular range,'' said another. The sources said the plan called for the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> to directly escort merchants through the narrow <LOCATION> Strait </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hormuz </LOCATION>, the sole entrance to the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION>, but to use the picket-line approach for the remainder of the trip. `` This is the first important response to the cease-fire,'' said one source. `` If this works out OK, then we can consider additional steps.'' The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> mounted its escort operations in 1987 after President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> approved a request by <LOCATION> Kuwait </LOCATION> to reflag 11 of its tankers under the American flag. <LOCATION> Kuwait </LOCATION>, a key ally of <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> in the 8-year-old war, had seen its ships become a special target of Iranian forces and wanted to obtain <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military protection. For more than 40 years before the escorts, the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>'s normal <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> presence consisted of four to six ships.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880917-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-17-88 0255EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FAA-Flaps Bjt   09-17 0465</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-FAA-Flaps, Bjt,450</SECOND>
<HEAD>Airlines Ordered To Check Takeoff Warning Alarms On All Boeing 727
Jets</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By H. JOSEF HEBERT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Airlines have been ordered by the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aviation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> to check takeoff warning alarms on all <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> 727 jetliners because of questions raised in the investigation of a <ORGANIZATION> Delta </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lines </ORGANIZATION> crash last month. <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> officials said Friday the directive to the airlines for a one-time check of the estimated 1,200 727 jets in domestic operation was `` purely precautionary.'' There is no evidence that the alarm, which warns of a false flap setting, malfunctioned in the <ORGANIZATION> Delta </ORGANIZATION> plane that crashed Aug. 31 at the <LOCATION> Dallas-Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Worth </LOCATION> airport, killing 14 of the 108 people aboard, the officials said. <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON> <PERSON> Broderick </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION>'s associate administrator for regulation and certification, said checking the alarms on all <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> 727s was `` not anything other than our own effort to gather data.'' `` It should n't be read that we have any indication that the flaps were involved in the -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> Delta </ORGANIZATION> -RRB- accident,'' he said. In <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman <PERSON> Liz </PERSON> <PERSON> Reese </PERSON> said the company was unaware of the <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> order. She added that the order is not an unusual action. <PERSON> Broderick </PERSON> said the action was taken because there have been `` a lot of questions asked'' in connection with the crash and the positioning of the flaps during the takeoff. Investigators have uncovered conflicting evidence as to whether the flaps were positioned properly prior to the <ORGANIZATION> Delta </ORGANIZATION> crash. The federal investigation has not yet determined the cause of the accident. <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> investigators have said that among the areas being examined is whether the flight crew extended the flap setting as required. If the flaps were not extended for takeoff as required, an alarm should have sounded in the Delta's cockpit, but no such alarm could be heard on the cockpit voice recorder tape. An aircraft's wing flaps help the plane gain lift and should have been extended 15 degrees when the Delta jet took off. The lever that controls the flaps in the <ORGANIZATION> Delta </ORGANIZATION> jet was found in a `` retracted'' position and the flaps on the wing also were found retracted. However, the co-pilot was heard on the cockpit voice recorder tape to acknowledge that the flaps had been set at the 15 degree position. One theory being examined is that the flap setting might have been called out, but not set properly. Another theory has been that a crew member might have extended the flaps properly prior to takeoff, but at the last second retracted them in a desperate attempt to reduce drag and keep the plane aloft. The <ORGANIZATION> NTSB </ORGANIZATION> announced Thursday that an inspection of the three engines of the <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> 727 found no mechanical failure that could be blamed for the accident.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880917-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-17-88 0301EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Lehman-DefenseProbe     09-17 0512</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lehman-Defense Probe,500</SECOND>
<HEAD>Lehman Says His Changes Didn't Weaken Procurement System</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TIM AHERN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Former <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Lehman </PERSON> says the changes during his controversial tenure did n't lead to the current <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> investigation of bribery in <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> contracts. `` I am very proud of the achievements made in rebuilding the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> during my tenure. I do not believe the changes that led to that success made the system, by its nature, more susceptible to waste, fraud and abuse,'' he said Friday. <PERSON> Lehman </PERSON>'s appearance before the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Armed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> was his first major public comment since the ongoing investigation became public three months ago. The investigation concerns allegations of bribes from consultants, many of them former <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> employees, to current <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> employees to obtain inside information about contracts. Those details could be crucial to winning multimillion dollar contracts. No charges have yet been filed. A key figure of the investigation is <PERSON> Melvyn </PERSON> <PERSON> Paisley </PERSON>, the former assistant <ORGANIZATION> navy </ORGANIZATION> secretary for research and engineering and a close associate of <LOCATION> Lehman </LOCATION> during their <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> tenure. <PERSON> Paisley </PERSON> resigned and became a high-priced consultant shortly after <PERSON> Lehman </PERSON> quit to take a Wall Street job in April 1987. <PERSON> Lehman </PERSON> was a controversial figure during his six-year tenure, often clashing with lawmakers and other critics of <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s naval build-up. That buildup was the key component of <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s program of large increases in the Pentagon budget. <PERSON> Lehman </PERSON> did n't talk about specifics of the investigation and committee members did n't seek those details because they did n't want to harm the probe But he noted the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> has more consultants than the other services, chiefly because the service has fewer officers. Some <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> tasks are performed by consultants that in the <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> would be done by officers, he said. `` Consultants are essential, but we do have too many,'' he added. `` The <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> could substantially reduce its reliance on consultants.'' `` I was never comfortable with the dependence on consultants,'' <PERSON> Lehman </PERSON> said, adding that his efforts to reduce that dependence were thwarted by unidentified bureaucrats. <PERSON> Lehman </PERSON> did endorse a pair of reforms proposed after the investigation became public. One would require consultants to register and the other would direct them to disclose all their contracts to prevent conflicts of interest. <PERSON> Lehman </PERSON> strongly defended his running of the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>, disputing critics who have said the changes he ordered may have fostered a climate which led to the investigation. Those changes include more centralized management and elimination of some layers of bureaucracy. `` With regard to strong centralized policy-making and decentralized execution, I see no way that either principle increases the opportunity for waste, fraud and abuse,'' he said. Overall, said <PERSON> Lehman </PERSON>, the Pentagon should be reorganized to give much more authority for daily decisions to lower-level personnel, rather than top officials. He opposed the creation of a single purchasing `` czar,'' a change proposed by some lawmakers. He proposed that the secretary of defense simply make policy, and turn all other major decisions over to the three services. The staff also should be reduced by half, he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880917-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-17-88 0636EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-HouseMailings     09-17 0321</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-House Mailings,320</SECOND>
<HEAD>House Panel Suggests New Limits On Free Mailings For Congress</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BARRY MASSEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Election-year mass mailings by lawmakers have risen dramatically and prompted leaders of a <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> committee to call for new restrictions on how much mail can be sent at taxpayer expense. Four members of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, including its Democratic chairman and senior <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> member, said in a letter Friday that increased numbers of taxpayer-paid mailings this year have caused a backlog in their processing and delivery. That could cause some of the mail to arrive at voters' homes during the height of the campaign season in late October, they said. Critics contend that some mailings, particularly newsletters, are little more than government-paid campaign literature intended to promote the re-election of officeholders. Under House rules, members can not send a mass mailing less than 60 days before the date of a primary or general election in which their name appears on the ballot. Mailings must be delivered to the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> folding room by that deadline for processing. The lawmakers said that after the cutoff period this month, there were 58 million pieces of mail awaiting processing by the <ORGANIZATION> Publications </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Distribution </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>. There were 35.4 million pieces of mail ready for processing at the same point in 1986, 36.7 million in 1984 and 33.3 million in 1982. A temporary second shift of workers was added to the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> folding room earlier this year at a cost of nearly $ 500,000, and their employment has been extended through mid-October to help handle the larger volume of mail, the lawmakers said. `` It is essential that additional limitations be considered to prevent this situation from repeating itself to the detriment of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and its members,'' the lawmakers said in their letter. Generally, members are limited to six mass mailings for their districts during a year, but that does not include town meeting notices.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880917-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-17-88 0637EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Homeless-Housing     09-17 0438</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Homeless-Housing,440</SECOND>
<HEAD>Court Decision Expected Soon On House Auctioning</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A federal judge is expected to decide soon whether the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration has considered the needs of the homeless before auctioning off about 47,000 foreclosed homes that are owned by the government. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> <PERSON> Gasch </PERSON> declined Friday to decide several challenges by the homeless to the federal government's policies, but said he would make his decision as soon as possible after taking the arguments under advisement <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Bradford </PERSON>, an attorney for homeless advocates, reminded <PERSON> Gasch </PERSON> that two temporary restraining orders barring the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Housing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Urban </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION> from selling houses in the greater <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> area and in <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION> expired Friday. <PERSON> Gasch </PERSON> replied, `` I would hope they would maintain the status quo.'' Government attorneys told <PERSON> Gasch </PERSON> they would have to consult with their clients, but <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> general counsel <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dorsey </PERSON> said later through a spokesman that the housing agency would follow the terms of the restraining order through the end of business next Wednesday. The coalition of advocates for the homeless argued the <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> has violated the law by selling its stock of foreclosed single-family homes to the highest bidder without determining whether they could be beneficial to the homeless and low-income people. <PERSON> Bradford </PERSON> told <PERSON> Gasch </PERSON> that <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> receives 70,000 houses each year _ about 7,000 a month _ but the agency `` can not proceed as if it is simply in the real estate business. They must consider the homeless.'' In a related case, the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coalition </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> the </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Homeless </ORGANIZATION> also argued that the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration has defied a congressional mandate to release underused federal property as housing for the nation's homeless. Ms. <PERSON> Maria </PERSON> <PERSON> Foscarinis </PERSON>, a coalition attorney, said `` there are thousands of properties underutilized which could be used for the homeless.'' She said that of the 12 facilities that have been officially identified as underutilized, only two have been made available to the homeless. `` It's unconscionable - as well as illegal - that federal buildings stand vacant while homeless men, women and children sleep on the streets,'' she said. The suits want the court to order the government agencies to survey their property, determine which is underutilized or no longer needed and make those properties available for the homeless. Government attorney <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Irwin </PERSON> argued that the 1987 homeless act does not apply to single family dwellings `` They want to shut down a program that has been going on for 50 years,'' he said. `` They want to tie up the program.'' <PERSON> Arthur </PERSON> <PERSON> Goldberg </PERSON>, another government lawyer, said all the agencies have complied with the requirements of the provisions of the homeless act.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880917-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-17-88 0302EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-MinumumWage     09-17 0489</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Minumum Wage,480</SECOND>
<HEAD>Republicans Pushing `Training' Wage As Alternative To Kennedy Plan</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MATT YANCEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Labor Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Republicans are planning to whittle away at Democratic-proposed increases in the $ 3.35 minimum wage for the first time in eight years through a subminimum `` training'' wage _ but not until next week. With many senators taking Friday off to campaign for re-election in their home states, Sen. <PERSON> Orrin </PERSON> <PERSON> Hatch </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Utah </LOCATION>, was unwilling to risk a vote on a Democratic measure aimed at killing his proposal for a 80 percent subminimum wage. Under the <PERSON> Hatch </PERSON> proposal, employers could pay the `` training'' wage during the first 90 days a worker is on their payroll. Sen. <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, D-Mass., the chief author of the mininum wage bill, was ready to vote Friday on his proposal to double the number of student exemptions that employers can now use to pay part-time workers 15 percent below the wage floor _ or $ 2.85 an hour presently <PERSON> Hatch </PERSON> called <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>'s proposal a `` mock training wage,'' saying it would would not give employers any incentive to `` open the door to those who have nothing, who are undereducated and unskilled.'' He said his subminimum training wage advocated by the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration, Vice President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s running mate, Sen. <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>, R-Ind., could `` create hundreds of thousands of new jobs. With presidential and congressional elections just eight weeks away, President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and other Republicans have softened their opposition to any increase, but have not said how large it should be. In June, <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> offered before the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> a proposed raise to $ 4 an hour over two years but coupled it with a subminimum training wage. The measure was never voted on. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, campaigning in <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, said Friday that a lower training wage, the administration's euphemism for a subminimum rate that it has advocated since 1981, must accompany any increase for him to support it. <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> called the Republican proposals a <ORGANIZATION> Trojan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Horse </ORGANIZATION>, saying <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>'s proposal for a $ 4 minimum wage amounts to a 10 percent cut in buying power after taking inflation into account from when <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> took office. `` And from that miserly floor, he proposes a further cut for all new hires,'' <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> said. `` Can this be what <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> means when he talks about a kinder, gentler <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>?'' <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>'s bill would raise the minimum wage 40 cents an hour in each of the next three years _ to $ 3.75 in 1989; $ 4.50 in 1990 and $ 4.55 in 1991 _ directly benefitting about 15 million workers now paid less than $ 4.50 an hour. Majority Leader <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON>, D-W. <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, said he hoped to get a vote on <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>'s and <PERSON> Hatch </PERSON>'s different subminimum proposals next Tuesday and a vote on final passage by the end of next House Speaker <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Texas </LOCATION>, said the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> will take up and `` likely pass'' it as soon as the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> acts.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880917-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-17-88 0304EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Rowan-Shooting     09-17 0355</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Rowan-Shooting,300</SECOND>
<HEAD>Judge Refuses to Drop Weapons Charges Against Columnist</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RICHARD KEIL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Syndicated columnist <PERSON> Carl </PERSON> <PERSON> T. </PERSON> <PERSON> Rowan </PERSON> received a setback when a judge refused to dismiss weapons charges against him, ruling that <PERSON> Rowan </PERSON> was not authorized to own a handgun he used to wound a teenager trespassing in his backyard. District of <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Superior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Judge </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Arthur </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> L. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Burnett </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sr. </ORGANIZATION> on Friday also directed that <PERSON> Rowan </PERSON>'s case be heard before a jury in a trial scheduled for Sept. 22. The columnist, an outspoken opponent of ownership and use of handguns, faces one count each of possession of an unregistered weapon and ammunition for the gun. If convicted of both misdemeanor charges, he would face a maximum penalty of two years in jail and a $ 2,000 fine. <PERSON> Rowan </PERSON>, 63, had argued in a pre-trial hearing that the charges should be dismissed because the weapon used in the June 14 shooting had been given to him by his son, <PERSON> Carl </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, a former <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> agent, who had been told it was not necessary to register the weapon because he was a law enforcement officer. Although <PERSON> Rowan </PERSON> concentrated on whether his son was misled by city officials in his efforts to register the weapon, <PERSON> Burnett </PERSON> gave greater weight to the question of whether the elder <PERSON> Rowan </PERSON> was authorized to possess the gun. The city's far-reaching 1976 handgun ordinance makes clear that `` a valid holder of a registration certificate for a firearm could not lend or give it to another person ... whether that person be a relative or a friend, and whether the purpose was for protection or some other worthy objective,'' <PERSON> Burnett </PERSON> concluded. <PERSON> Burnett </PERSON> also rejected <PERSON> Rowan </PERSON>'s claim of exemption from the gun control law on the grounds that he uses his home as a business, not just a residence. <PERSON> Benjamin </PERSON> <PERSON> N. </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, 19, of suburban <LOCATION> Chevy </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Chase </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Md. </LOCATION>, was wounded in the wrist when <PERSON> Rowan </PERSON> caught him and three others taking a swim in his backyard pool. <PERSON> Rowan </PERSON> says he shot <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> when the teen-ager lunged at him, but <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> said he was shot while trying to flee.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880917-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-17-88 0637EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FBI-CISPES     09-17 0429</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-FBI-CISPES,410</SECOND>
<HEAD>Sessions Acknowledges Contacts With Salvadoran National Guard</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> Director <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Sessions </PERSON> has acknowledged contact between between a bureau intelligence source and the <ORGANIZATION> Salvadoran </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION>. But in comments to a <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> subcommittee Friday, Sessions said it will be impossible to determine whether the source gave the Guard sensitive information from <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> files. Critics of the Salvadoran government claim links between the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> and right-wing death squad killings in the Central American country. Salvadoran political leaders reject the allegations. Sessions told the subcommittee hearing on the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION>'s investigation of the <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> in Solidarity with the <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> El </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Salvador </ORGANIZATION> that there were `` communications'' between former bureau intelligence source <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Varelli </PERSON> and the Guard `` I do not know specifically what he gave to the <ORGANIZATION> El </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Salvador </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION>,'' Sessions said. `` We have no way of establishing that.'' He said it was possible <PERSON> Varelli </PERSON> passed along sensitive information. It was disclosed last year that <PERSON> Varelli </PERSON>, who is suing the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> for back pay, had given congressional investigators a list of 13 Salvadorans facing deportation from the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. He told <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> in February 1987 that he had gotten the list from <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> Agent <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Flanagan </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION>, and he passed it along to the <ORGANIZATION> Salvadoran </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Flanagan </PERSON> subsequently resigned from the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION>. Rep. <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON>, D-Calif., suggested <PERSON> Varelli </PERSON> may have had access to other such lists as well `` It is quite possible,'' Sessions responded in testimony before the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> subcommittee on civil and constitutional rights, which <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON> chairs. Sessions noted that the bureau took action to ensure that the 13 Salvadorans `` were in fact informed'' their names had turned up on the list. The <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> early in 1987 rejected a suggestion by <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON>, based on information from <LOCATION> Varelli </LOCATION>, that the bureau was trading information with the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> <PERSON> Revell </PERSON>, executive assistant director of the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION>, said at the time that such a suggestion `` is not true.'' Based on information supplied by <PERSON> Varelli </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> launched a terrorism probe of <ORGANIZATION> CISPES </ORGANIZATION> in March 1983. Sessions disciplined half a dozen bureau personnel Wednesday for negligence in the investigation. He said the bureau failed initially to check out <PERSON> Varelli </PERSON>'s unreliable background and that the bureau broadened the probe unnecessarily in October 1983 to cover rank-and-file <ORGANIZATION> CISPES </ORGANIZATION> members who had nothing to do with international terrorism. The <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> closed the probe in June 1985 after failing to establish any substantial link between <ORGANIZATION> CISPES </ORGANIZATION> and international terrorism. Sessions said the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> in the <ORGANIZATION> CISPES </ORGANIZATION> probe committed no illegal acts and no violations of constitutional rights.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880917-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-17-88 0304EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Bush     09-17 0580</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bush,570</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush Says Dukakis Cannot Conceal Liberalism, Softness on Defense</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Political Rdp Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RITA BEAMISH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>FINDLAY, Ohio (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Vice President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> is steeping himself in the symbols and rhetoric of patriotism while stepping up accusations that <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> is an out-of-touch liberal who acts like a chameleon on the campaign trail. In campaign appearances on Friday, the Republican presidential candidate ridiculed <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' campaign trip this week to plants and other facilities run by defense contractors. In one appearance, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> rode in an M-1 tank. `` I ca n't say he's not trying, the opponent from <LOCATION> Masachusetts </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> told a rally in Findlay, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, honoring the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> flag. `` He drove a tank this week but after he drove it, the tank kept veering left.'' In a news conference earlier Friday, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> accused the Democratic <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> governor of being a `` made over'' candidate who is trying to hide a liberal record from American voters. After opposing the MX missile, the Midgetman, and the B-1 Bomber, `` Now suddenly he rides around in a tank, jumps out of the tank, takes off the helmet and comes on with different positions,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> charged. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> has since modified his opposition on the B-1. `` The tank did not fit,'' he said. `` It's time to take another message to <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> ... You can not fool the Soviet leadership by knocking <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s defense for 10 years and then riding around in a tank for 10 minutes ... You ca n't fool the American people.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> made the comments in <LOCATION> Columbus </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, after a tour of the <LOCATION> Buckeye </LOCATION> Steel plant where his grandfather, <PERSON> Samuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Prescott </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, was president in the early part of the centry. Later, the visual setting was all red-white-and-blue as <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> spoke against a colorful backdrop of flags on his visit to Findlay in northwest <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>. His appearance in the city, which was formally designated <LOCATION> Flag </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> USA </LOCATION>, in 1974, was to help kick off the town's three-day festival honoring the flag He said the Findlay townspeople got <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to designate their city <LOCATION> Flag </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> in 1974 because `` the time had come to stand up for the <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> flag and the values it represented and that is good old-fashioned patriotism.'' A crowd of a few thousand crowded the town intersection where <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> spoke from the steps of the stately old <ORGANIZATION> Elks </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Club </ORGANIZATION> building. Of the flag he said, `` It is the symbol of these <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> and to the liberty for which it stands one nation under god, with freedom and justice for all.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has made a campaign target of <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' gubernatorial veto of a <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> measure to require teachers to lead their students in the pledge of allegiance to the flag. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> also said <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> is trying to hide his liberalism. `` He refuses to repeat the positions that he took in wrapping up that <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> primary,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said. `` He ran way out on the left and now he's trying to move over, and I'd say make the American people forget the positions that he ran on and the positions that he's lived on since he's been the liberal governor of the state of <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION>.'' Later <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> continued to emphasize his own pro-defense themes when he helped unveil a monument to the Airmen who died in <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> at the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Museum </ORGANIZATION> at <ORGANIZATION> Wright-Patterson </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Base </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Dayton </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has planned a quiet weekend, with only one public event, attending a naturalization ceremony today for a group of immigrants.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880917-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-17-88 0638EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Quayle     09-17 0481</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Quayle,490</SECOND>
<HEAD>Quayle Rallies Farm Crowds With `Endive' Chant, One-Liners</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Political Rdp Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By EILEEN PUTMAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Republican vice presidential candidate <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> has a new campaign battle cry: `` endive!'' <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> got a lot of mileage in farm states Friday out of the leafy vegetable and some pithy one-liners as he accused Democrat <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> of being `` out of touch'' with the nation's heartland `` We need people who will listen to agriculture, not talk down to it,'' <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> said in speeches in <LOCATION> Omaha </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Neb. </LOCATION>, and in <LOCATION> Des </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Moines </LOCATION>. `` I reviewed the farm program of the governor of <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION>. His idea of farm production is growing flowers in <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Yard </ORGANIZATION>.'' In his five-day campaign swing through the <LOCATION> Midwest </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Plains </LOCATION> states, <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> increasingly turned to ridicule and hyperbole to make his points. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> is spending the weekend at home in <LOCATION> McLean </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va </LOCATION>. He attends a picnic today at the <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> home of Sen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Warner </PERSON>, the ranking Republican on the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Armed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, on which <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> also serves. On Friday, <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> ridiculed <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, the Democratic presidential nominee, for suggestions that livestock and grain farmers consider growing Belgian endive. `` During the primary season last winter, our opponent responded that one of the answers to helping farmers was for them to grow different crops,'' <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> said. `` He suggested blueberries and Belgian endive to pull farmers out of their economic doldrums.'' Republicans have been making hay of <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' endive remark, which he made in <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>, since the Republican National Convention. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> said the `` entire national market'' for Belgian endive is worth less than $ 10 million per year. `` So if you start growing these little things, do n't count on paying off the farm debt,'' <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> said. He got laughs from the crowds when he held up a head of endive to show them `` just how the man from <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> thinks he can rebuild the farm economy.'' In <LOCATION> Des </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Moines </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> joined in after the audience started chanting: `` endive! endive!'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, he said, does n't understand the `` heartland of <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'' and is `` out of touch with the people across <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>.'' He said <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> also had switched `` back and forth'' so much on defense issues in recent days that `` I decided to sum it up this way: His farm policy is the Belgian endive and his defense policy is the Belgian waffle.'' <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> said a <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration would open more markets abroad for <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> agricultural products, support development of alternative fuels such as ethanol, which is made from grain, and focus more on rural economic development. `` We'll get that capital gains tax down to 15 percent and that will help small businesses which means more jobs here in the heartland,'' <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> said. `` I can also assure you that with us, you get folks who are experienced in lowering interest rates, lowering inflation, creating jobs, increasing productivity and keeping the peace,''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880917-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-17-88 0305EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Dukakis     09-17 0531</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Dukakis,540</SECOND>
<HEAD>Dukakis Says Stepped-Up Drug Enforcement Would Pay For Itself</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Political Rdp Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By WILLIAM M. WELCH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SAN DIEGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrat <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> laid part of the blame for <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION>'s growing drug problem on <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> as he pledged more agents and prosecutors in a stepped up fight against drug kingpins. `` <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was supposed to be in charge of that war, and we all know what happened,'' the Democratic presidential nominee told students at <ORGANIZATION> Roosevelt </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> High </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> in the Latino section of <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> on Friday. `` You know, if you do n't show up at school, you fail, and if you do n't show up at your job as chief officer of the war on drugs, you fail, the <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> people lose, and the drug lords take over,'' he said. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, trying to reverse a slide in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> polls, was campaigning for a second day in the state today. He was meeting with campaign workers in <LOCATION> Anaheim </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Orange </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, a conservative Republican area where the campaign hopes to cut into <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s expected support. From there, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> was flying back to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> to meet with members of the <ORGANIZATION> Congressional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Black </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Caucus </ORGANIZATION> at a dinner <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> was expected to attend. The <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> governor planned to resume campaigning Monday with stops in <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, possibly to visit hurricane-damaged areas, while devoting much of the rest of his week to preparations for meeting his Republican rival in their first debate. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> made drugs the focus of his <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> foray, and he suggested the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration had slighted <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> in favor of <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> in allocating anti-drug resources. `` Today you have less than half the number of <ORGANIZATION> DEA </ORGANIZATION> -LRB- Drug Enforcement Admininstration -RRB- agents they have in <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> told rookies at the <ORGANIZATION> Los </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Angeles </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION>. `` That's going to change.'' <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, the largest state with 47 electoral votes, is considered a crucial battleground along with <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> for the <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> campaign _ while <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> remains virtually out of reach and has been the object of little personal campaigning by the candidate. However, his running mate, Sen. <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, visited <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> on Friday and today. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> pledged to double the 2,800 <ORGANIZATION> DEA </ORGANIZATION> agents nationally over five years, beginning with 600 next year, and to add 800 new federal prosecutors in an effort to speed up handling of drug cases. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> promised to send the first 100 drug agents to <LOCATION> Southern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, where he said cocaine seizures have risen 3,500 percent during the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> years and there have been `` massive increases'' in drug-related deaths. Campaign aides said the prosecutors would cost $ 40 million and the new drug agents would cost $ 50 million the first year. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> asserted that the agents would pay for themselves, however, through seizure and forefeiture of assets. `` It's really a no-cost step,'' he told police officers in <LOCATION> Chula </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vista </LOCATION>, just south of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Diego </LOCATION>. Outside the <LOCATION> Chula </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vista </LOCATION> police station, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> was greeted by demonstrators needling him for his prison furlough policy, which was changed in the face of public opposition. Several demonstrators wore mock prisoner's stripes. They chanted, `` Let me out, I'll kill again.'' One carried a sign saying `` Hey <PERSON> Mike </PERSON>, thanks for the weekend.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880917-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-17-88 0305EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Bentsen     09-17 0491</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bentsen,480</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bentsen Defends Dukakis In South</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Political Rdp</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By STEVEN KOMAROW</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PANAMA CITY, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Democratic vice presidential candidate <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> stood in a downtown ballroom, on courthouse steps and at a shuffleboard court _ in three different cities _ to deliver the same message. `` I'm looking for old friends who wandered away in recent years,'' he said. `` I'm talking to the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> Democrats. I'm urging them to come home, and they're responding.'' <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>, the <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> senator who <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> picked as running mate to help woo the <LOCATION> South </LOCATION>, spoke Friday morning in a <LOCATION> Memphis </LOCATION> hotel and in the afternoon at the <LOCATION> Pitt </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.C. </LOCATION>, courthouse in <LOCATION> Greenville </LOCATION>. There, he spiced his stump speech with a rebuke of Vice President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s attempts to denigrate <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' performance as <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> governor. `` Under <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> unemployment is the lowest rate of any major industrial state in this union,'' he said. `` Wages are growing twice as fast as the national average, personal income growing faster than any other state, and he submitted ten balanced budgets in a row. `` When <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> speaks out against <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>. We should all remember that when it came to speaking out against arms to <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>, when it came to speaking out against cozy deals with Gen. -LRB- <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> -RRB- <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>, when it came to speaking out against economic policies that have almost tripled the national debt, <PERSON> Geoge </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> did n't speak, he just voted present. `` I'll tell you, when it comes to strong leadership, <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has got himself a bad case of laryngitis.'' By evening, <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> was in <LOCATION> Palm </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>, in a trailer park's shuffleboard area next to a <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cutter </ORGANIZATION>, where he tailored his speech with an attack on the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration and <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> for failure in the fight against drug imports `` They asked him to lead'' the fight against drugs, he said. `` And he blew it badly.'' <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> was joined by Sen. <PERSON> Lawton </PERSON> <PERSON> Chiles </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Fla </LOCATION>., an old friend from <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> who also accompanied him to <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> The <LOCATION> Palm </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION> stop also included a ritzy, closed-door fund-raiser at the home of a prominent attorney. About $ 50,000 was raised for <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> re-election campaign. Under an unusual <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> law, <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> is running both for the vice presidency and a fourth term in the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>. The vice presidential campaign, which had been bogged down by scheduling difficulties the day before, appeared to be picking up the pace. `` We've had a helluva good day,'' <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> told reporters on his campaign plane. <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> was returning to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> this afternoon and heading back on Monday to his home state of <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> to resume campaigning. <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> expressed relief that Hurricane <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON> appeared to be going ashore in a sparsely-populated area of <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>. In addition to his general concerns about <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Bentson </PERSON>'s father has a ranch in the <LOCATION> Rio </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Grande </LOCATION> <LOCATION> valley </LOCATION> near <LOCATION> Brownsville </LOCATION>, which apparently was being spared major damage.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880917-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-17-88 0307EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-PoliticalRdp Bjt   09-17 0730</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Political Rdp, Bjt,720</SECOND>
<HEAD>Campaign Shifts Focus From Law Enforcement, Patriotism To Debate</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Top prospects uncertain</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT GREENE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> pledged in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> to fight the nation's drug problem with more spending and more hiring, while <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> questioned his rival's sincerity on defense issues as both candidates planned for the first presidential debate of the campaign. In a speech Friday at the <ORGANIZATION> Los </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Angeles </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION>, the Democratic presidential nominee told recruits he would double the number of <ORGANIZATION> Drug </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Enforcement </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> agents over the next five years, paying for the increase with cash and other assets seized in drug busts. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> also pledged to hire 800 more federal prosecutors. `` We're going to send a message to drug kingpins,'' he said. `` As far as <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> is concerned, there's nowhere you can run, there's nowhere you can sail, there's nowhere you can hide. There will be no safe haven for dope peddlers and drug profits anywhere on this Earth.'' But <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, in a later appearance, mistakenly said that <ORGANIZATION> DEA </ORGANIZATION> agents at one point had to hold a bake sale to raise stakeout money. Aides explained that the book that was the source of that anecdote said the bake sale was held to raise money for drug education. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, the Republican nominee, spent much of the day in <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, where he derided what he called <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' shifting positions on defense. `` You can not fool the Soviet leadership by knocking <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s defense for 10 years and then riding around in a tank for 10 minutes,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said Friday in <LOCATION> Columbus </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, making light of <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' well-filmed visit to a tank design facility `` You ca n't fool the American people. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s running mate, Sen. <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION>, combined that criticism with a jab at <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' farm policy by referring to his statement that cash grain and livestock farmers should consider alternative crops such as Belgian endive and blueberries. Contending that <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> is out of touch with <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> told an audience in <LOCATION> Omaha </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Neb </LOCATION>.: `` I decided to sum it up this way: His farm policy is the Belgian endive and his defense policy is the Belgian waffle.'' <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> was finishing a five-day swing of <LOCATION> Midwest </LOCATION> and Plains states. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>'s Democratic counterpart, Sen. <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>, took special aim during an appearance in <LOCATION> Greenville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.C. </LOCATION>, at <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s claim Thursday that <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> mismanaged <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION>' fiscal affairs `` When <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> speaks out against <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>,'' he said, `` we should all remember that when it came to speaking out against arms to <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>, when it came to speaking out against cozy deals with Gen. <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>, when it came to speaking out against economic policies that have almost tripled the national debt, <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> did n't speak, he just voted present.'' Both <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> ran into some turbulence while campaigning. Outside the <LOCATION> Chula </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vista </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, police station, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> was greeted by demonstrators needling him for his prison furlough policy, which was changed in the face of public opposition. Several demonstrators wore mock prisoner's stripes. They chanted, `` Let me out, I'll kill again.'' One carried a sign saying `` Hey <PERSON> Mike </PERSON>, thanks for the weekend.'' In Findlay, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, where the annual flag celebration was held Friday, some residents complained <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> had turned it into a political photo opportunity. `` What was intended to be a non-partisan promotion of fun and patriotism has turned into a partisan use of the flag for private gain by a candidate,'' said local businessman <PERSON> Neil </PERSON> <PERSON> Scott </PERSON>. The vice president returned to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, where <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> also was headed to meet with members of the <ORGANIZATION> Congressional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Black </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Caucus </ORGANIZATION> at a dinner that <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> was also expected to attend. Both men have set aside large parts of next week to prepare for their first debate of the fall presidential campaign, a 90-minute nationally televised session a week from Sunday in <LOCATION> Winston-Salem </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.C </LOCATION>. In <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, members of the <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> campaign, the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> and <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rainbow </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coalition </ORGANIZATION> stressed unity during a news conference in which they announced a stepped-up registration and get-out-the-vote effort aimed at minority voters. <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Warren </PERSON>, the general election coordinator for the <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> campaign, said the drive targets 42 cities in 14 states. The <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> will `` take the lead'' in the campaign, which will try to register 2 million new voters and win a minimum 70 percent black voter participation in the Nov. 8 election.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880917-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-17-88 0639EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Deaver     09-17 0610</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Deaver,600</SECOND>
<HEAD>Conflicting Testimony On Whether Alcoholism Hurt Deaver's Memory</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JAMES ROWLEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The judge who will sentence <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> K. </PERSON> <PERSON> Deaver </PERSON> for perjury is pondering sharply conflicting testimony about whether alcoholism impaired the former presidential aide's memory when he gave sworn testimony. Dr. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Flynn </PERSON>, <PERSON> Deaver </PERSON>'s doctor during two hospital visits for alcoholism in 1985 and 1986, said the former <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> aide likely suffered memory impairment from tranquilizers he took for alcohol withdrawal. But <PERSON> Ralph </PERSON> <PERSON> Tarter </PERSON>, an alcoholism expert testifying for the prosecution, said `` motivational reasons rather than neurological reasons'' best explained <PERSON> Deaver </PERSON>'s failures of recollection under oath. Attorneys for <PERSON> Deaver </PERSON> offered two days of medical testimony to show that alcoholism should be considered a mitigating factor when the former presidential aide is sentenced for lying when his lobbying was investigated for possible ethics-law violations. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Penfield </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> is scheduled to sentence <PERSON> Deaver </PERSON> on Sept. 23. The former deputy White House chief of staff faces a possible five-year sentence and a $ 6,800 fine for each of three perjury counts. <PERSON> Deaver </PERSON> was found guilty last year of lying when he said he could n't recall contacting former <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration colleagues on behalf of major corporations who paid him six-figure fees for his services. <PERSON> Flynn </PERSON>, head of the alcoholism and drug abuse clinic at <ORGANIZATION> Georgetown </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION>, testified that <PERSON> Deaver </PERSON> `` definitely'' suffered memory and judgment impairments during two hospital stays for detoxification. But on cross-examination, <PERSON> Flynn </PERSON> admitted to independent counsel <PERSON> Whitney </PERSON> <PERSON> North </PERSON> <PERSON> Seymour </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> that he never tested <PERSON> Deaver </PERSON> for memory loss during the hospital stays and meant to say that `` people in that situation have impaired memory and judgment.'' <PERSON> Flynn </PERSON> also provided another piece of circumstantial evidence that <PERSON> Deaver </PERSON> telephoned then-Secretary <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> on behalf of <ORGANIZATION> Trans </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Word </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Deaver </PERSON> was talking on the phone at 5 p.m. June 3, 1985 when he first entered the former presidential aide's room at the hospital, <PERSON> Flynn </PERSON> said. A log kept by Mrs. <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>'s secretary that was produced at the trial showed <PERSON> Deaver </PERSON> had called the Cabinet official at precisely that hour. Among other things, <PERSON> Deaver </PERSON> was convicted of lying when he told a federal grand jury on June 20, 1986 that `` I do n't recall any government contact I made on behalf of <ORGANIZATION> TWA </ORGANIZATION>.'' The defense is trying to show that <PERSON> Deaver </PERSON> honestly could n't recall the telephone contact because he was drugged and suffering from alcoholic withdrawal But <PERSON> Flynn </PERSON>, who testified that <PERSON> Deaver </PERSON> later took heavy doses of the tranquilizer Valium to counteract alcohol withdrawal, said the former <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> aide was neither drunk nor sedated by a dose of <LOCATION> Librium </LOCATION> he took 30 minutes earlier. The defense countered with Dr. <PERSON> Dolores </PERSON> <PERSON> Morgan </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> physician who treats alcoholics. She said medical records showed that by 1985 when <PERSON> Deaver </PERSON> had resigned from President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s staff his alcoholism had reached an advanced stage. Kidney failure that kept <PERSON> Deaver </PERSON> from attending <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s second inaugural in January 1985 was `` a classic example'' of the medical complications of alcoholism, she said. It was misdiagnosed as an allergic reaction to blood-pressure medicine because <PERSON> Deaver </PERSON> did n't tell doctors he was drinking heavily <PERSON> Morgan </PERSON> said <PERSON> Deaver </PERSON> probably understated his problem when he told <PERSON> Flynn </PERSON> and other doctors six months later that he had only recently started drinking more than a fifth of Scotch whisky a day. On appeal, the defense is expected to repeat arguments that improper trial rulings by the judge put <PERSON> Deaver </PERSON> at a strategic disadvantage that prevented him from testifying. The defense, confronted with these rulings from the bench, chose to rest its case without calling <PERSON> Deaver </PERSON> or any of the medical experts who were prepared to testify.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880917-0025 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-17-88 0641EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-SeabrookLicense     09-17 0525</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Seabrook License,520</SECOND>
<HEAD>Seabrook Finances Now Lone Obstacle To Low-Power License</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CHRISTOPHER CALLAHAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Nuclear </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Regulatory </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> says the idled <LOCATION> Seabrook </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.H. </LOCATION>, reactor will not get a low-power operating license until regulators are convinced the plant's owners are financially stable. But <PERSON> Seabrook </PERSON> officials, buoyed by a commission vote Friday that removed the only other regulatory obstacle to gaining the license, said they will begin immediately preparing the reactor for low-power testing in anticipation of a license. The <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION> voted 4-0 for a rules `` clarification'' that will allow nuclear plants to receive low-power permits without an emergency siren system in place to alert neighbors within 10 miles of the reactors of an atomic emergency. Commission regulations say financial qualification should not be a consideration for a low-power license, but <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Lando </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Zech </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> said there are extenuating circumstances in the <PERSON> Seabrook </PERSON> case. For the first time, he said, <PERSON> Seabrook </PERSON>'s finances would be a factor in consideration of a low-power license. `` It's a serious issue,'' <PERSON> Zech </PERSON> told reporters after the hearing. `` We'll be watching closely to see the financial qualification situation at <LOCATION> Seabrook </LOCATION>.'' <PERSON> Zech </PERSON>'s concerns focused on <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Company </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hampshire </ORGANIZATION>, a partial <ORGANIZATION> Seabrook </ORGANIZATION> owner which filed for bankruptcy reorganization last January. `` In my judgment, bankruptcy is a special case,'' the chairman said. `` ... We should be satisfied that bankruptcy will not prevent safe, low-power operation.'' <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> communities within <PERSON> Seabrook </PERSON>'s 10-mile zone fought successfully to have the emergency sirens removed. State officials led by Gov. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, the Democratic presidential nominee, believe those coastal towns, with their narrow roads and bulging summer populations, would not be able to evacuate quickly. The new rule takes effect in 30 days. <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>, president of the reactor's owner, <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hampshire </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Yankee </ORGANIZATION>, hailed the commission vote as `` another major step forward for <PERSON> Seabrook </PERSON>.'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> blasted the ruling, saying it `` defies logic and brings new meaning to the word irresponsible.'' He derided the commission as the `` Not <ORGANIZATION> Responsible </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION>'' and said it `` is experiencing a meltdown in its thinking process.'' The lone regulatory obstacle remaining for <PERSON> Seabrook </PERSON>'s low-power license is a petition filed by plant opponents charging that the reactor's owners are financially unfit to operate the plant. That question was tentatively scheduled for a vote following the siren issue, but was postponed. The idle $ 5.6 billion reactor is losing $ 50 million each month in maintenance and finance costs. <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Malsch </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION> deputy general counsel, said he hoped the commission would have the issue resolved within a month. <PERSON> Seabrook </PERSON> officials said they were optimistic of a favorable ruling. `` We feel we have proved to the commission that we are financially qualified,'' said <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Sher </PERSON>, spokesman for <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hampshire </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Yankee </ORGANIZATION>. If the <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION> rules that the <LOCATION> Seabrook </LOCATION> owners are financially fit, the plant would be eligible for a low-power license, which allows it to run tests at 5 percent power. The owners need the 5 percent permit before securing a full-power commercial license, while opponents say low-power testing would contaminate the reactor with radioactive fuel and make a future conversion to a gas-fired plant much more expensive.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880917-0026 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-17-88 0644EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-DefenseContracting     09-17 0311</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Defense Contracting,310</SECOND>
<HEAD>`Truth-in-Contracting' Rules Loosened By Pentagon</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
