<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880904-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-04-88 2330EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-TropicalWeather 1stLd-Writethru a0767 09-04 0324</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Tropical Weather, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0767,0327</SECOND>
<HEAD>Tropical Storm Ernesto Fizzles En Route To Azores</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDS: Changes overline and LEADS with 5 grafs to update with storm
fizzling, latest advisory; picks up 6th graf pvs, `The storm...'</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By BRIAN MURPHY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MIAMI (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The fifth tropical storm of the <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> hurricane season lost its strength as it raced towards <LOCATION> Portugal </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Azores </LOCATION> island chain, and its remnants were absorbed by a large north <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> storm system Sunday. Tropical Storm Ernesto, located roughly 400 miles north of the <LOCATION> Azores </LOCATION> near latitude 45.0 north at longitude 28.0 west, could no longer be identified late Sunday, according to a 10:30 p.m. advisory from the National Hurricane Center. Earlier in the evening, the storm had top sustained winds of 40 mph and was racing northeastward toward the <LOCATION> Azores </LOCATION> at about 50 mph. The <ORGANIZATION> Civil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> on the islands monitored the storm but chose to not warn residents Sunday evening, said <ORGANIZATION> Azores </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Regional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Government </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Baiao </PERSON>. Meteorologist <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON> of the Hurricane Center said <PERSON> Ernesto </PERSON> probably would lose strength when it moved over colder water. `` The storm draws its strength from the warm, moist tropical water,'' he said. `` Even a few degrees can affect the storm.'' Tropical storms have wind of at least 39 mph rotating around a warm core of low pressure. If sustained wind reaches 74 mph, the system is upgraded to a hurricane. If wind drops below 39 mph, it is downgraded to a tropical depression. On Saturday, storm warnings for the Gulf coast from <LOCATION> Cameron </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> La. </LOCATION>, to <LOCATION> Apalachicola </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>, were canceled after a tropical depression dissipated several hours after forming off the <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> coast. The first hurricane of the season, <PERSON> Debby </PERSON>, swirled to life Friday but was downgraded to a tropical storm hours later after moving inland at <LOCATION> Tuxpan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, about 165 miles northeast of <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. The <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> hurricane season runs from June 1 to Nov. 30.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880904-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-04-88 2340EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-People-Tyson 1stLd-Writethru a0848 09-04 0473</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-People-Tyson, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0848,0480</SECOND>
<HEAD>Heavyweight Champion Injured in Auto Accident</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Inserts one graf after 5th graf, ``Doctors there'' to UPDATE
with statement from doctor in NYC about Tyson having ``minor trauma
to the head and the chest wall.''</NOTE>
<DATELINE>CATSKILL, N.Y. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Heavyweight champion <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Tyson </PERSON> suffered what doctors called a slight head injury in an automobile accident Sunday near his training camp. <PERSON> Tyson </PERSON>'s car apparently skidded on a wet road about 11:20 a.m., said a spokesman for the boxer, <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Klores </PERSON>. <PERSON> Tyson </PERSON>'s car was the only vehicle involved and the accident was not reported to authorities, said <PERSON> Klores </PERSON>, who gave no other details. A state police trooper said the accident was not under investigation. If the injuries and damage were only to <PERSON> Tyson </PERSON> and his property, then he has 10 days to report the accident to the state <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Motor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Vehicles </ORGANIZATION>, the trooper said. <PERSON> Tyson </PERSON>, who was recuperating from a broken bone in his right hand suffered in a street fight two weeks ago with heavyweight <PERSON> Mitch </PERSON> <PERSON> Green </PERSON>, was taken to a <LOCATION> Catskill </LOCATION> hospital and then transferred to <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Green </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in nearby <LOCATION> Hudson </LOCATION>, where he was listed in stable condition early Sunday evening. Doctors there decided <PERSON> Tyson </PERSON> should have additional neurological tests, and <PERSON> Tyson </PERSON> was transferred Sunday night to a <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> hospital associated with <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>'s medical school, said <PERSON> Anne </PERSON> <PERSON> Grebert </PERSON>, a spokeswoman at the hospital in <LOCATION> Hudson </LOCATION>. Dr. <PERSON> Carolyn </PERSON> <PERSON> Britton </PERSON>, assistant professor of nuerology at <ORGANIZATION> Columbia-Presbyterian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> said late Sunday, `` He suffered minor trauma to the head and the chest wall. Currently he's in the hospital for observation and to undergo diagnostic tests. His condition is quite stable. He's neurologically normal. He arrived in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> shortly after 9 p.m. His wife, actress <PERSON> Robin </PERSON> <PERSON> Givens </PERSON>, was in the back of the ambulance with <PERSON> Tyson </PERSON> and tried to put a sheet over the windows to keep camera crews from photographing her husband. A few moments later, <PERSON> Tyson </PERSON> was wheeled into the hospital on a stretcher with a sheet over his body and a towel over his face. As cameramen pressed forward, <PERSON> Givens </PERSON> pushed them back, shouting, `` Give him a break.'' <PERSON> Tyson </PERSON>, whose championship bout against British champ <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Bruno </PERSON> was recently postponed until Oct. 22 because of the hand injury, was scheduled to accompany his wife to the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> on Wednesday. <PERSON> Green </PERSON>, who lost to the undefeated <PERSON> Tyson </PERSON> on May 20, 1986, in a 10-round decision, had the bridge of his nose split by <PERSON> Tyson </PERSON> in the early-morning incident outside an all-night clothing boutique. <PERSON> Tyson </PERSON> claimed <PERSON> Green </PERSON> was harassing him about their meeting in the ring. <PERSON> Tyson </PERSON> said he reacted to Green by instinct. In his last fight in the ring on June 27, <PERSON> Tyson </PERSON> knocked out previously unbeaten <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Spinks </PERSON> in 91 seconds, earning $ 22 million.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880904-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-04-88 2345EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Mexico-Storms 1stLd-Writethru   09-04 0301</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Mexico-Storms, 1st Ld-Writethru,a0854,0308</SECOND>
<HEAD>50,000 Homeless, 10 Killed By Tropical Storms</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: UPDATES throughout with additional deaths, details of
mudslides; no pickup</NOTE>
<DATELINE>MEXICO CITY (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Emergency crews worked Sunday to find shelter for 50,000 people left homeless after two tropical storms whipped through coastal areas of both eastern and western <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, killing at least 10 people, authorities said. Rain from the storms continued to drench parts of the country and many areas were without power or communications. Mud and rock loosened from hillsides by the days of rain blocked numerous roads, officials in several states said. `` There is a lot of damage and at least eight neighborhoods are badly hurt,'' <PERSON> Javier </PERSON> <PERSON> del </PERSON> <PERSON> Porte </PERSON>, a public works official, said by telephone from <LOCATION> Tapachula </LOCATION> in the southernmost state of <LOCATION> Chiapas </LOCATION> on the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> coast. Authorities said 30,000 were forced to flee their homes after Hurricane Debby, subsequently downgraded to tropical storm status, hit the Gulf of <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> coast on Friday. Most of the evacutions were in state of <LOCATION> Veracruz </LOCATION>, state government spokesman <PERSON> Raul </PERSON> <PERSON> Torres </PERSON> said. Three people died when mudslides crushed two houses in <LOCATION> Papantla </LOCATION>, 16 miles from the <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, and three storm-related deaths were reported in <LOCATION> Poza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rica </LOCATION>, he The towns, on the coast about 150 miles northeast of <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, were in the region that bore the brunt of the storm. Four others perished and 16 were injured when a mudslide crushed three houses in the mountain community of <LOCATION> Ixtlahuaco </LOCATION>, about 100 miles northeast of <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, said <PERSON> Florencio </PERSON> <PERSON> Gutierrez </PERSON> <PERSON> Hernandez </PERSON> of the State Public Security office. About 20,000 people were evacuated Saturday in <LOCATION> Chiapas </LOCATION> to avoid the brunt of tropical storm <PERSON> Kristy </PERSON>, according to the government news agency <ORGANIZATION> Notimex </ORGANIZATION> said. <PERSON> Debby </PERSON> was the first hurricane of the 1988 Atlantic hurricane season and the fourth named storm.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880904-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-04-88 2353EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Pakistan-Islam     09-04 0679</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Pakistan-Islam,0699</SECOND>
<HEAD>Zia's Death Could Slow Development Of Koranic Law</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAN BIERS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ISLAMABAD, Pakistan (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The death of President <PERSON> Mohammad </PERSON> <PERSON> Zia </PERSON> <PERSON> ul-Haq </PERSON> could slow the spread of Islamic law in <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>, a cause he fervently advanced during 11 years as this Moslem country's leader. <PERSON> Zia </PERSON>, an army general who died Aug. 17 in a plane crash, had made the `` Islamization'' of Pakistani society a pillar of his policy. But he faced opposition from some politicians, members of the middle class and others. With his death, the fate of a further expansion of Islamic law in <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> is in doubt. Islamic law is interpreted with different stringency from one Islamic nation to another. <PERSON> Zia </PERSON>'s Islamic laws included a ban on the consumption of alcohol, the provision of flogging and stoning as punishment for such crimes as drinking and adultery, and a 2.5 percent tax on the rich to help the poor. <PERSON> Zia </PERSON> failed, however, to codify into Pakistani law <ORGANIZATION> Islam </ORGANIZATION>'s opposition to collecting interest payments on loans Punishment by flogging was rare, despite its presence in the legal code, and there were no stonings. <PERSON> Zia </PERSON> was the most enthusiastic of all of <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>'s recent rulers in applying Islamic law, said Professor <PERSON> Mahmood </PERSON> <PERSON> Ahmad </PERSON> <PERSON> Ghazi </PERSON>, a leading scholar at the <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Islamic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Islamabad </LOCATION> and the man who led prayers at <PERSON> Zia </PERSON>'s funeral. If `` someone not as enthusiastic as Zia'' takes over, <PERSON> Ghazi </PERSON> said, the pace of Islamization will be slow in this 98 percent Moslem nation. <PERSON> Ghulam </PERSON> <PERSON> Ishaq </PERSON> <PERSON> Khan </PERSON>, the new president of <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>, and his caretaker <ORGANIZATION> Cabinet </ORGANIZATION> met a week after <PERSON> Zia </PERSON>'s death and pledged to continue Islamization. But nationwide elections are scheduled for Nov. 16, and that could strongly affect government policy. Opposition leader <PERSON> Benazir </PERSON> <PERSON> Bhutto </PERSON>, who could become prime minister if her party wins the elections, has spoken out strongly against <PERSON> Zia </PERSON>'s brand of Islamization, saying no one should impose personal religious views on the country. `` There are some parties that are enthusiastic, and there are some parties that are lukewarm,'' <PERSON> Ghazi </PERSON> said. In May, <PERSON> Zia </PERSON> dissolved parliament, citing corruption, laxity and lawmakers' failure to promote Islamic law over a three-year period as justification for his move. He then issued a presidential order in June that decreed the legal code of Islam to be the supreme law of <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> and expanded court powers to review laws for conformity with the Koran, the Moslem holy book. Ms. <PERSON> Bhutto </PERSON> was quoted at time as saying that `` Islam, like in the past, is again being used to perpetuate oppressive rule.'' <PERSON> Zia </PERSON> said the decree would not affect the rights of non-Moslems, or the country's business contracts with other nations. The order expires later this year unless reaffirmed by the government. Defining the relationship between Islam and the country's legal system has been a central question since 1947, when <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> was created as a home for Moslems on the Indian subcontinent. Many Islamic principles were enshrined in law before <PERSON> Zia </PERSON> came to power. But he sought to expand these dramatically, giving courts constitutional power to determine whether laws conformed to the Koran and the traditions of the Prophet <PERSON> Mohammed </PERSON>. Laws dealing with the constitution itself, judicial procedure and fiscal and personal matters were excluded from the review at first, but some of these exemptions were removed by <PERSON> Zia </PERSON>'s June decree. Although special courts now review laws for compliance with Islamic tradition, final appeals still go to civil high courts rather than to the legal bodies of religious scholars that exist in some other Moslem states. Many groups _ including much of the middle class and many lawyers and educated women _ have opposed Islamization, believing the country should not turn its back on educational and legal traditions from the West that have been in place since the British colonial era. <PERSON> Zia </PERSON>'s policy also was coolly received by Moslems with different interpretations of Islamic law. For example, the jurisprudence of the <ORGANIZATION> Shiite </ORGANIZATION> sect, which constitutes about 5 percent of the country's 107 million people, differs significantly from that of the majority Sunnis
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880904-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-04-88 2355EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-AnotherLook:MassacreSurvivor Bjt   09-04 0869</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Another Look: Massacre Survivor, Bjt,0891</SECOND>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto YAK1, Sept. 1</HEAD>
<HEAD>Last Survivor Of Last U.S. Indian Massacre Looks Back</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By NICHOLAS K. GERANIOS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>YAKIMA, Wash. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The last survivor of what many historians regard as the last massacre of Indians in <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> history thinks returning to the site after more than seven decades may finally bring the scope of the tragedy home to her. `` It would be strange because I feel like I stand off from all of it,'' said <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Jo </PERSON> <PERSON> Estepp </PERSON>, who was an 18-month-old child when taken from her dead mother's back after the ambush in <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION> in 1911. `` It's in the distance, you know.'' Though she is now making plans for the visit with friends, she lived most of her 78 or so years with only an outline of her past. Many details were finally supplied a few years ago by the author of a book about her grandfather, an Indian named <PERSON> Shoshone </PERSON> <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> who refused to live on a reservation. The ambush, by a white posse, left <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> and seven other Indians dead in the snow near <LOCATION> Winnemucca </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Nev. </LOCATION>, on Feb. 26, 1911, 21 years after the last major <LOCATION> Indian </LOCATION> massacre, at Wounded Knee, S.D. According to researchers, <PERSON> Shoshone </PERSON> <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> refused to settle on the Fort Hall Indian Reservation in <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION> and instead roamed the mountains near Twin Falls with his sons, daughters and grandchildren. The Indians lived off the land and worked for farmers, living in peace. But in 1910 one of <PERSON> Mike </PERSON>'s sons was killed by a white horse thief, and the family retaliated by killing the killer. Not trusting white justice, <PERSON> Shoshone </PERSON> <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> took his family and fled into <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION>. The 12 Indians survived a brutal winter by stealing cattle for food. When four ranchers discovered the loss, the Indians killed them and took their horses. Posses from <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> pursued the Indians for 300 miles until Feb. 26, when they caught the ragged band sleeping and slaughtered four men, two women and two boys during a brief battle. One posse member was killed. The four surviving children were put in the <PERSON> Reno </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Nev. </LOCATION>, jail because there was no place else to put them. In his 1973 book about <PERSON> Shoshone </PERSON> <PERSON> Mike </PERSON>, titled `` The Last Free Man,'' author <PERSON> Dayton </PERSON> <PERSON> Hyde </PERSON> noted the four surviving children, but he was unable to find out what happened to them. A friend of Ms. <PERSON> Estep </PERSON> contacted <PERSON> Hyde </PERSON> after reading his book, and <PERSON> Hyde </PERSON> traveled to her home in <LOCATION> Yakima </LOCATION>. There is still much Ms. <PERSON> Estep </PERSON> does n't know about the time before she was lifted from that blood-soaked cradleboard after falling face-down in the snow. The identity of her father is unclear, as is her age and whether she was born a Shoshone or a Bannock Indian. Still, she said, `` They know my mother was one of Shoshone <PERSON> Mike </PERSON>'s daughters. Her name was Snake.'' The massacre in <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION> appears to have been the last of its kind in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, said <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Bergon </PERSON>, a professor of Native American cultures at <ORGANIZATION> Vassar </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Poughkeepsie </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION>, whose novel, `` Shoshone <PERSON> Mike </PERSON>,'' was recently published by <PERSON> Viking </PERSON>. <PERSON> Hyde </PERSON> agrees. Many massacres of whites and Indians occurred in the 19th century. `` What makes this significant is it occurred in 1911, when there were automobiles, airplanes and movies,'' <PERSON> Bergon </PERSON> said. `` The fact that it did occur in the 20th century makes the whole thing surreal.'' After the massacre, the federal government ordered <PERSON> Evan </PERSON> <PERSON> Estep </PERSON>, then the superintendent of the <ORGANIZATION> Fort </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hall </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Indian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reservation </ORGANIZATION>, to pick up the children. Ms. <PERSON> Estep </PERSON>'s memories begin with the train trip north in November 1911. `` I remember when we went to the dining car I would n't eat the food,'' she said. The exception was raisins in the raisin bread, which tided her over. They may have reminded her of food her family ate, but she is n't sure. The other three children died of illnesses within a year. The toddler survived tuberculosis and was adopted by <PERSON> Estep </PERSON> and his wife, <PERSON> Rita </PERSON>, who were childless. They guessed she was about 18 months old when she was found. She moved with the family to reservations in <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, finally settling at <LOCATION> Toppenish </LOCATION> on the <ORGANIZATION> Yakima </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Indian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reservation </ORGANIZATION> in 1924. Although her adoptive parents told her about the massacre, she never asked for details and they never talked much about <PERSON> Shoshone </PERSON> <PERSON> Mike </PERSON>, she said. She was treated as a white person and noted, `` Most of my friends are non-Indians.'' The family moved to <LOCATION> Yakima </LOCATION> in 1930, after <PERSON> Estep </PERSON> retired. Ms. <PERSON> Estep </PERSON> still lives in the house purchased by her adoptive parents, who died in the 1950s. She graduated from <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> with a music degree and spent 40 years teaching school before retiring in 1974. She never married. Her only tangible link with her Indian past is a single black-and-white photograph of the four surviving children taken in front of the Reno jail. It shows the children she had thought were siblings until <PERSON> Hyde </PERSON> identified them: an aunt, <PERSON> Hattie </PERSON>, age about 4; an uncle, <LOCATION> Cleveland </LOCATION>, about 7; and another aunt, <PERSON> Heney </PERSON>, who appears to be about 18. And, of course, the haunting photo shows herself, wearing a white hat and crying.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880904-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-04-88 2358EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-HurricaneUleki     09-04 0307</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Hurricane Uleki,0316</SECOND>
<HEAD>Forecasters Say Hurricane Winds No Longer Pose Threat to Hawaii</HEAD>
<DATELINE>HONOLULU (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A tropical storm watch for the Hawaiian islands was discontinued but high surf advisories were in effect as Hurricane Uleki moved away from the state, the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Weather </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> said. At 2 p.m. Sunday, or 8 p.m. EDT, the hurricane was 385 miles southwest of <LOCATION> Honolulu </LOCATION> and 350 miles southwest of <LOCATION> Lihue </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Kauai </LOCATION>, moving to the west at 12 mph with maximum sustained winds of 80 mph and gusts to 100 mph, meteorologist <PERSON> Clarence </PERSON> <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Uleki </PERSON>'s westward movement lessened the threat of damaging winds for <LOCATION> Oahu </LOCATION>, where <LOCATION> Honolulu </LOCATION> is located, <LOCATION> Kauai </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Niihau </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> said. However, a high surf advisory remained in effect for all southern coasts that were pounded by large waves from the storm. Rescuers assisted 19 people Saturday in 5 - to 6-foot waves off <LOCATION> Waikiki </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION> and nearby <LOCATION> Ala </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Moana </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION>, according to lifeguard Capt <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Howe </PERSON>. A body was discovered Sunday off <LOCATION> Maunalua </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION> eight miles east of <LOCATION> Honolulu </LOCATION>, but it was not immediately known if the death was related to the storm, police said. <PERSON> Uleki </PERSON> was expected to continue moving westward, and gradually weaken to the point where it could be downgraded from hurricane status this afternoon, <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> said. When the storm took an unexpected turn toward the islands Friday, winds near the center gusted to 150 mph. Uleki is Hawaiian for <PERSON> Ulysses </PERSON>. The weather service in <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION> said the <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> region has its own list of Hawaiian names for storms in the region. Next will be <PERSON> Wila </PERSON>, followed by <LOCATION> Aka </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Ekeka </PERSON> and <PERSON> Hale </PERSON>. So few storms originate in the region that the list is used over and over, and does not start the year with a name beginning with the letter A as in the <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> or other regions of the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880904-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-04-88 0003EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-SeattleBlackout 3rdLd-Writethru a0676 09-04 0817</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Seattle Blackout, 3rd Ld - Writethru, a0676,0838</SECOND>
<HEAD>Electricity Finally Restored To Parts Of Downtown Seattle</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: LEADS with 6 grafs to UPDATE with power restored to parts of
downtown Seattle; picks up 6th graf pvs, ``We're keeping ...'</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By STEVE BAKER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SEATTLE (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Utility crews finally restored service Saturday night to parts of a 50-block downtown section that had been without electricity since the middle of the week. But <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION> City Light officials asked customers not to turn on their air conditioning immediately, out of fear of a surge of demand on one of the hottest days of the year. The temperature in <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION> hit 92 degrees, a record for the date, the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Weather </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> said. About half of the blacked-out area's customers got electricity back when four cables feeding power to the area were reactivated about 6:45 p.m. PDT, power company spokesman <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Aguirre </PERSON> said. All the customers were expected to be back on line when two other feeder cables are repaired and in place Sunday or Monday, <PERSON> Aguirre </PERSON> said. Restrictions on power use also were expected to end then, he said. An initial attempt to energize the cables was unsuccessful when one of them refused to take power and tripped a circuit breaker. The reason for the problem was not immediately known, <PERSON> Aguirre </PERSON> said. Earlier in the day, the outage had officials worried about fires and the effect of the heat on the elderly. `` We're keeping an eye on the heat situation, and we're on alert to evacuate people'' from housing for the elderly, said <PERSON> Hope </PERSON> <PERSON> Tuttle </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Seattle-King </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman. The high temperature Friday at <LOCATION> Seattle-Tacoma </LOCATION> <LOCATION> International </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION> was a September record of 98, one degree below the all-time record for that recording station, and a similar reading was forecast Saturday. Since power was lost in a transformer fire Wednesday, the <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION> had been serving three meals a day to 150 to 250 elderly residents. Volunteers had to take some meals up 13 flights of stairs in buildings where elevators were inoperative. Street lights, but almost no traffic signals, came on for the first time Friday night when temporary overhead wiring was hooked into the lighting system. Repair crews hoped to begin restoring power late Saturday in a complex process that would `` likely extend into Monday,'' said City Light spokesman <PERSON> Scott </PERSON> <PERSON> Forslund </PERSON>. Thirty buildings with the largest loads in the area and more than 90 others with emergency generators would remain off the system when power is restored, <PERSON> Forslund </PERSON> said. When the switch is thrown, <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Light </ORGANIZATION> engineers plan to wait two to four hours to assure that the system is stabilized before restoring service to the remaining buildings. The area typically accounts for roughly 3 percent of the city's 1,000-megawatt load. If too much equipment is turned on when the switch is thrown, the sudden added load would cause an abrupt voltage dip, or sag, said <PERSON> Hugh </PERSON> <PERSON> McIntosh </PERSON>, chief spokesman for City Light. `` It would be like halftime during a ball game when everyone flushes all the toilets and the water pressure drops,'' he said. A severe sag could trip current-monitoring equipment and trigger another blackout. <PERSON> Roy </PERSON> <PERSON> Davis </PERSON>, spokesman for the Fire Department, estimated 90 percent of the affected businesses were closed. An office of Great Northwest Federal Savings and Loan remained open, but with reduced operations. Customers' identifications were checked before they were let into the building, two at a time, to withdraw money for the weekend. `` This is banking the way it used to be,'' said <PERSON> Dianne </PERSON> <PERSON> Backus </PERSON>, division manager. `` We're taking down every transaction by hand and every couple of hours run to one of our branches and enter everything into the computer.'' Fire alarm systems were checked regularly, as were residential hotels where officials feared guests might use candles or gas camping stoves. `` Frankly, this situation is new to us, and we're a little nervous,'' said <PERSON> Davis </PERSON>. `` We've got several cars patrolling just to look for fires.'' No injuries were reported during the blackout, and heavy police patrols were credited with preventing break-ins. By Friday many hotel guests had wearied of the novelty of being issued complimentary flashlights and complained of 15-story climbs up stairways. `` I began to notice a little soreness in my calves yesterday,'' said <PERSON> Janet </PERSON> <PERSON> Hardin </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Eaton </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, a guest at the 40-story Westin Hotel's south tower, which had one of three elevators in service. <PERSON> Westin </PERSON> officials tried to accommodate most guests in the hotel's 47-story north tower, which had air conditioning It was another matter entirely for <PERSON> Viola </PERSON> <PERSON> Davis </PERSON>, 83, pausing on the ninth-floor landing in the <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, two floors from where she lives. `` I stop ... every floor ... and rest,'' she panted. `` Have to or I ca n't make it. Takes me half an hour to get up. `` It's horrible, but some of my neighbors have n't been out of their apartments all week.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880904-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-04-88 0013EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Obit-Watts     09-04 0324</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Obit-Watts,0331</SECOND>
<HEAD>Artistic Leader of Fluxus Movement Dies</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BANGOR, Pa. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Watts </PERSON>, a leader of the Fluxus Group known for creating public art events in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> during the 1960s, died Friday. He was 65. <PERSON> Watts </PERSON> died at his farm in <LOCATION> Martins </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Creek </LOCATION> after a long bout with lung cancer, according to a longtime friend and former student, <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Miller </PERSON>. <PERSON> Watts </PERSON> was planning a solo exhibition of his recent work at the time of his death, <PERSON> Miller </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Watts </PERSON>' mixed media works appeared in museums and galleries in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>. In 1946, <PERSON> Watts </PERSON> painted in the tradition of abstract expressionism, but 12 years later, he stopped painting and began working with a variety of media, including sculpture, film, video and performance work. In the early 1960s, he was one of the artistic leaders of the <ORGANIZATION> Fluxus </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Group </ORGANIZATION>, a collection of avant-garde artists whose works often consisted of creating public events, including melting a block of ice on a street corner. It was described by its founder, the late <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Maciunas </PERSON>, as `` a fusion of <PERSON> Spike </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>, vaudeville, gags, children's games and <PERSON> Duchamp </PERSON>.'' Art historian <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Moore </PERSON> of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> said the Fluxus Group was an important influence on the popularity of anti-establishment forms in art of all types. The Fluxists, in turn, were heavily influenced by the Dadaists and musician-composer <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Cage </PERSON>. At the time of his death, <PERSON> Watts </PERSON> also was developing silk-screened works and porkchop tables with art dealer <PERSON> Francesco </PERSON> <PERSON> Conz </PERSON>, of <LOCATION> Verona </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Miller </PERSON> said. In addition, <PERSON> Watts </PERSON> was working with `` flux-med,'' silk-screened images dealing with medical procedures, and had produced a portfolio of notes and sketches from his work in 1964-66. He was an art professor at <ORGANIZATION> Rutgers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> from 1953-84, and was the school's resident artist in film and mixed media from 1964-82. <PERSON> Watts </PERSON> also taught at the <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Applied </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Arts </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sciences </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Brooklyn </LOCATION> from 1951-52.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880904-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-04-88 0032EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p AM-Bush-Threat     09-04 0199</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Bush-Threat,0204</SECOND>
<HEAD>Police Say Man Arrested At Airport Made Threats Against Bush</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SPRINGFIELD, Mo. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Police arrested a man who allegedly tried to carry a gun onto an airplane and made threats against Vice President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, authorities said Saturday. The man, from <LOCATION> Springfield </LOCATION>, was being held in a psychiatric institution and was undergoing evaluation after his arrest Friday, police said. The man had not been formally charged, but was being held on suspicion of unlawful use of a weapon. He allegedly tried to carry a .45 - caliber semiautomatic pistol through a metal detector at the <LOCATION> Springfield </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Regional </LOCATION> Police said the man made threats against <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> as he was being arrested. The <ORGANIZATION> Springfield </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News-Leader </ORGANIZATION> reported in its Sunday editions that the man was traveling to <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>, where <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has scheduled campaign appearances on Monday. The plane he attempted to board was bound for <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION>, and he planned to take a connecting flight to <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>, the newspaper reported. Police would not comment further about the case and referred questions to the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> referred questions to the <ORGANIZATION> Secret </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>, where a duty officer said he could not provide details because local police handled the investigation.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880904-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-04-88 0130EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-IntellectualCruise 1stLd-Writethru a0566 09-04 0332</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Intellectual Cruise, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0566,0335</SECOND>
<HEAD>Cruise Stranded In Arctic Ice May Not Need Help</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Leads with 4 grafs to UPDATE with ship canceling call for
help. Edits to trim and to conform.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By SUSAN GALLAGHER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ANCHORAGE, Alaska (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A cruise ship that became stuck in arctic ice late last week during an educational journey for intellectuals canceled a call for help from an icebreaker on Saturday, the <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> said. The Society Explorer, with 149 passengers and crew members, reported it was in no danger because of the ice and had moved close to Canadian waters, said <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> spokesman in <LOCATION> Juneau </LOCATION>. The ship notified Canadian maritime officials on Wednesday it was trapped. `` It looks like they're free of the ice, they're moving and they have said they no longer need assistance,'' <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> said. A 399-foot <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> icebreaker had been en route Saturday to assist the ship as well an oil-research support ship stranded in ice. The research vessel, which had called for assistance Friday, continued to await help Saturday. The <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> had said the 236-foot ocean liner was caught in <LOCATION> Beaufort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sea </LOCATION> ice 50 miles northeast of Point Barrow, or about 400 miles above the <LOCATION> Arctic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Circle </LOCATION>. The liner, bound for the <ORGANIZATION> Northwest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Passage </ORGANIZATION>, is operated by Society Expeditions Cruises of <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION>, which specializes in journeys to unconventional destinations, including <LOCATION> Antarctica </LOCATION>, and emphasizes libraries and lectures. Some of the passengers aboard the Society Explorer have been using the time to float in rafts routinely used for picture-taking trips and other activities. `` Our entertainment on board is mostly intellectual entertainment, not gambling and dancing,'' <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Cox </PERSON>, planning director for the cruise operator, said late last week. He said the ship is `` absolutely safe'' and well-stocked with items on its continental menu. The cruise operator said it expects the Society Explorer to arrive on time at its destination off the southern coast of <LOCATION> Newfoundland </LOCATION> at the end of September.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880904-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-04-88 0144EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-TankerOverturns     09-04 0256</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Tanker Overturns,0264</SECOND>
<HEAD>Chemical Spill Causes Evacuation of 500; 300 from Nursing Home</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CHARLESTON, S.C. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 About 500 people, including more than 300 from a nursing home, were evacuated Saturday after a tank truck carrying a hazardous chemical tipped over, releasing the chemical which formed a noxious cloud, officials said. No serious injuries were reported, but two men near the truck were taken to a hospital, complaining of burning eyes and chests after inhaling the chemical, phosphorus trichloride. The tanker tipped over about 6 p.m. Saturday when it sank into the rain-soaked ground of an unpaved parking lot near <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Highway 78. Further details about the incident were unavailable, officials said. The cloud hung over the city's north end, authorities said. The men were in good condition, said Trident Regional Medical Center nursing supervisor <PERSON> Jan </PERSON> <PERSON> Pfennig </PERSON>. The evacuation included 15 to 20 workers of Presbyterian Home of <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> and its 320 residents, some of whom were removed in stretchers. Evacuees were taken to <ORGANIZATION> Summerville </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Elementary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> South </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Carolina </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Wildlife </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Resources </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coastal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>, about six miles away. Authorities said they did n't know how much of the chemical had leaked out. Phosphorus trichloride is a clear, colorless, fuming liquid used chiefly in organic synthesis as a chlorinating agent. When it comes in contact with moisture, it forms a compound similar to an acid, according to Dr. <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Metts </PERSON>, director of the <ORGANIZATION> Palmetto </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Poison </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION>. It can irritate the eyes and the mucous membranes of the respiratory system, <PERSON> Metts </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880904-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-04-88 0229EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-TropicalWeather 1stLd-Writethru a0657 09-04 0278</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Tropical Weather, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0657,0280</SECOND>
<HEAD>Tropical Depression Fizzles In Gulf; Tropical Storm Brews In
Atlantic</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Changes overline and UPDATES throughout with tropical
depression dissipating, tropical storm warnings discontinued. No
pickup.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By SANDRA WALEWSKI</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MIAMI (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A newly formed tropical depression dissipated several hours after it sprang from an area of disturbed weather off the <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> coast as a tropical storm churned in the <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION>, forecasters said Saturday. An <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> aircraft was unable to identify any center of circulation with the depression and all warnings along the Gulf coast were discontinued. Meantime, a depression in the <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> some 800 miles northeast of <LOCATION> Bermuda </LOCATION> became Tropical Storm Ernesto, according to a 6 p.m. EDT advisory issued by the National Hurricane Center. The storm was moving north-northeast. Tropical storm warnings issued at 5 p.m. CDT Saturday from <LOCATION> Cameron </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> La. </LOCATION>, to <LOCATION> Apalachicola </LOCATION> were discontinued by late evening, according to an advisory from the National Hurricane Center. The <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> storm was moving at 30 mph, and mainly posed a concern at sea, hurricane specialist <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Case </PERSON> said. Gradual strengthening was expected over the next 24 hours. `` It appears it is going to get some help with the colder air temperatures north of it ... and just become a big storm in the <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION>,'' he said. Depressions are upgraded to tropical storms when their maximum sustained winds reach 39 mph. Hurricanes pack winds of at least 74 mph. The first hurricane of the season, <PERSON> Debby </PERSON>, was downgraded Friday to a tropical storm after moving inland at <LOCATION> Tuxpan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, about 165 miles northeast of <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. The hurricane season runs June 1 to Nov. 30.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880904-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-04-88 0354EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a BC-PlaneCrash 1stLd-Writethru a0697 09-04 0219</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Plane Crash, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0697,0219</SECOND>
<HEAD>Four Dead in Grand Canyon Crash</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: UPDATES throughout with new details of crash; where victims
were from. No pickup.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>GRAND CANYON, Ariz. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Four men died Saturday night when their single-engine plane crashed while taking off from <LOCATION> Grand </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Canyon </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION>, officials said. The Cessna 172 stalled shortly after takeoff and the aircraft spun out of control, crashing about 100 yards north of the runway, said <PERSON> Ron </PERSON> <PERSON> Warren </PERSON>, a spokesman for <ORGANIZATION> Grand </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Canyon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION>, which is based at the airport. There were no survivors. The plane had to abort its first takeoff attempt because it had taken on too much fuel, said <PERSON> Chuck </PERSON> <PERSON> Daehler </PERSON>, who is with Grand Canyon Helicopters. The initial attempt was at 6:20 p.m, <PERSON> Warren </PERSON> said. The pilot radioed the control tower that there was too much fuel on board and then returned to the airport, he said. `` They tried to spend the night, but everything in town was full,'' <PERSON> Warren </PERSON> said. The plane then made a second attempt after draining the excess fuel but the plane crashed just after 9 p.m., <PERSON> Daehler </PERSON> said. The airport runway is about 10 miles south of the canyon's south rim. The victims were all men in their mid-20s from <LOCATION> Rustin </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> La. </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Warren </PERSON> said. Their identities were not immediately available.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880904-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-04-88 0454EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i BC-Bangladesh-Floods     09-04 0337</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Bangladesh-Floods,0349</SECOND>
<HEAD>20 Million People Marooned, 40 More Die In Floods</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By HASAN SAEED</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>DHAKA, Bangladesh (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Monsoon floods have marooned an estimated 20 million people across <LOCATION> Bangladesh </LOCATION>, officials said Sunday. Forty more people died in the deluge, bringing the death toll to 882, a newspaper reported. `` Shortage of medicine, cooked food and drinking water is causing untold miseries to millions of marooned people,'' said an official at the Relief Ministry in <LOCATION> Dhaka </LOCATION>. Rains battered <LOCATION> Dhaka </LOCATION> on Sunday, where an estimated 500,000 people have taken shelter from adjoining low-lying areas. Their presence and uncertainities over the floods caused prices of goods to rise in the city. Prices for rice, a staple, have risen 40 percent. The capital remained cut off for the third day Sunday as more areas of the runways at the international airport were submerged. Relief officials were unable to reach many interior areas where people were feared trapped with meager or no food and potable water, officials from four areas told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> by telephone. The officials spoke on condition of anonymity. They estimated that 20 million people were marooned in 50 of the country's 64 districts that were battered by the floods. The government issued new appeals for boats, helicopters and 3 million tons of food to combat the deluge. The Sangbad newspaper said 40 people died across the country on Saturday, taking the total death toll in the current monsson floods that began in June to at least 882. The government toll, considered understated, stood at 300. In <LOCATION> Dhaka </LOCATION>, several gas stations closed their pumps and hung `` No Gas'' signs. `` Unless to get fresh supplies the pumps will remain closed,'' said one station owner, <PERSON> Giasuddin </PERSON> <PERSON> Ahmed </PERSON>. Annual floods are common in <LOCATION> Bangladesh </LOCATION>, one of the poorest countries in the world. At least 1,500 people died in floods last year. In 1985, more than 10,000 people were killed when cyclones and tidal waves hit low islands in the <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bengal </LOCATION>, about 130 miles south of <LOCATION> Dhaka </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880904-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-04-88 0456EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a BC-Hostage 1stLd-Writethru a0702 09-04 0326</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Hostage, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0702,0332</SECOND>
<HEAD>Ex-Policeman Releases Hostage After 15-Hour Ordeal</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: UPDATES overline to reflect hostage released.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By LAURIE DODGE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ST. LOUIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An ex-policeman convicted of participating in a pension fund scandal ended a 15-hour hostage ordeal by releasing the man who had exposed the scam, police said. <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Daniele </PERSON>, 39, remained on the 15th floor of the office building where he had held <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Frank </PERSON>, vice president of the city police board, said police spokeswoman <PERSON> Linda </PERSON> <PERSON> Hancock </PERSON>. <PERSON> Daniele </PERSON>, who was armed with an unidentified weapon, had held no other hostages. He let <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> go about 1:30 a.m. Sunday. <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> apparently was unharmed, police said. A hostage-response team and dozens of officers who had surrounded the building continued to negotiate with <PERSON> Daniele </PERSON> through the early morning hours, <PERSON> Hancock </PERSON> said. `` Right now they're still talking with him about the possibility of his coming out and ending the whole thing,'' she said. `` We're just talking,'' said Lt. Col. <PERSON> Calzona </PERSON> <PERSON> Hall </PERSON> at an earlier briefing as the ordeal passed the 12-hour mark. `` He's been very cooperative.'' The incident began at 10:30 a.m. <PERSON> Hancock </PERSON> said <PERSON> Daniele </PERSON> earlier had demanded to make a statement over <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Louis </LOCATION> radio station KMOX-AM. Besides an eight-year term, <PERSON> Daniele </PERSON> was ordered to make restitution of $ 200,000. <PERSON> Frank </PERSON>, a lawyer and a member of the appointed civilian board that administers the <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, exposed the kickback scandal that cost police and fire pension funds an estimated $ 333,000. The scam was carried out by paying a brokerage artificially high commissions on stock transactions that were made with pension funds, prosecutors said. Participants in the scheme were then given back part of the money. <PERSON> Daniele </PERSON>, who headed the police pension fund, was the only one of six men indicted in the scam to stand trial. He was convicted of charges that included extortion, conspiracy and mail fraud, and could have received as much as 32 years in prison.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880904-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-04-88 0725EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i BC-Britain-Warship 1stLd-Writethru   09-04 0372</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Britain-Warship, 1st Ld-Writethru,a0699,0381</SECOND>
<HEAD>PRECEDE London</HEAD>
<HEAD>11 Injured After British Destroyer, Container Ship Collide</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: UPDATES throughout with destroyer sailing to port,
destination of container ship, details. No pickup</NOTE>
<DATELINE>MUSCAT, Oman (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A British container ship and a British destroyer accompanying it toward the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> collided, poking a hole in the warship and injuring 11 of its crewmen, officials said. British naval sources in <LOCATION> Oman </LOCATION> said the accident occurred Saturday night when the <ORGANIZATION> HMS </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Southampton </ORGANIZATION> and the British-registered Tor Bay were 15 miles off the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arab </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Emirates </LOCATION> port of Fujairah on the Gulf of <LOCATION> Oman </LOCATION>. The sources, speaking on condition of anonoymity, said the <ORGANIZATION> Southampton </ORGANIZATION> sailed on to Fujairah after a brief stop to assess its damage. During that stop, the 4,000-ton ship appeared `` badly holed'' and was `` seriously flooding,'' they said. But the sources said the situation was under control. The 34,477-ton Tor Bay, which was on its way from <LOCATION> Singapore </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Dubai </LOCATION>, in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arab </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Emirates </LOCATION>, escaped with only minor damage to its bow and continued its voyage after the accident. Its owners, P and O of <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>, said it would be repaired at <LOCATION> Dubai </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> said 11 crewmen were injured _ three of them with broken bones, one suffering shock and the other seven with minor cuts and bruises. On arrival at <LOCATION> Fujairah </LOCATION>, the sailors with broken bones were moved to the local government hospital. One witness at the port said the <LOCATION> Southampton </LOCATION> was `` damaged extensively. ... -LRB- there's -RRB- a big gash on its port side, bigger than the size of a car.'' The <ORGANIZATION> Southampton </ORGANIZATION> has a 253-man crew. It came to the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> region to join the <ORGANIZATION> Royal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> patrolling units last month. The sources said they could not tell how the collision occurred, especially that warships usually sail at least one mile away from the vessels they are escorting in the gulf. The <ORGANIZATION> Southampton </ORGANIZATION> is one of two <ORGANIZATION> Royal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> destroyers and a frigate that accompany merchant ships into and out of the gulf because of the 8-year-old Iraq-Iran conflict. There also are three British mine sweepers and three support vessels, including the <LOCATION> Olna </LOCATION> and Diligence, the sources added. A cease-fire began in the Iraq-Iran war Aug. 20.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880904-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-04-88 1106EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-NorthernIreland     09-04 0225</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Northern Ireland,0229</SECOND>
<HEAD>Soldiers Attacked As They Defuse 300-Pound Bomb In Northern
Ireland</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BELFAST, Northern Ireland (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Young men on Sunday hurled gasoline and acid bombs at British soldiers as they tried to defuse a 300-pound bomb, but police drove off the assailants and the job was completed safely. Two men were detained for questioning, and a police officer received medical treatment after ammonia was thrown into his eyes, said a spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> Royal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ulster </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Constabulary </ORGANIZATION>, the province's police force The confrontation occurred in the mainly Roman Catholic <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lodge </LOCATION> area of north <LOCATION> Belfast </LOCATION>, where authorities found the bomb in a parked, stolen car along with several other detonators and timing devices. Sixty homes in the area were evacuated until the bomb was defused about 6 a.m. Police fired plastic bullets at the young men who attempted to disrupt the work of the bomb disposal experts by throwing `` petrol bombs, acids bombs and other assorted missiles,'' said the spokesman, who spoke on condition of anonymity. No one immediately claimed responsibility for planting the bomb, but the police spokesman said there was `` a rather strong possibility'' it was the work of the outlawed <ORGANIZATION> Irish </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> IRA </ORGANIZATION> is fighting a guerrilla war to end British rule in <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION> and unite the mostly Protestant province with the mainly <LOCATION> Catholic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Republic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880904-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-04-88 1110EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-BRF--Philippines-Captives     09-04 0171</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Philippines-Captives,0176</SECOND>
<HEAD>Rebels Release Seven Captives In Philippines</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ZAMBOANGA, Philippines (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Moslem rebels Sunday released seven civilians, including the wife and daughter of an American, who were abducted a week ago in <LOCATION> Basilan </LOCATION> province near this southern city, the military reported. The captives were freed at dawn in <LOCATION> Sampinit </LOCATION> village and brought to the house of <LOCATION> Basilan </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Gerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Salapuddin </PERSON>, who negotiated with local Moslem rebel leader <PERSON> Rashid </PERSON> <PERSON> Kasim </PERSON> for their release, a military report said. It was not immediately known if any of the victims paid the $ 50,000 ransom the kidnappers had demanded for each of them. Among those released were <PERSON> Myrna </PERSON> <PERSON> Cawley </PERSON>, wife of <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> physician <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Cawley </PERSON>, and their daughter <PERSON> Catherine </PERSON>. The seven were among 11 civilians abducted by the rebels in an ambush of three vehicles in <LOCATION> Lamitan </LOCATION> on Aug. 27. The rebels allowed 39 other people in the vehicles to go free. Four of the kidnap victims were released Tuesday after their relatives paid the rebels an undisclosed sum of money, the military said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880904-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-04-88 1110EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-BRF--Nigeria-Crocodiles     09-04 0094</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Nigeria-Crocodiles,0097</SECOND>
<HEAD>Floods Send Crocodiles Into Villages, Three People Killed</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LAGOS, Nigeria (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Crocodiles killed three people after being swept into villages on water from the flooded <LOCATION> Benue </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Nigeria </LOCATION> radio said Sunday. The government radio also said 500 people were left homeless because of the flooding caused by heavy rains in the country's center The radio said the villagers died in <LOCATION> Plateau </LOCATION> state, but did not say when they were attacked by the crocodiles. The local government said rescue workers had been sent to the villages to help in salvage work.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880904-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-04-88 1112EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-BRF--Korea-Soviet     09-04 0159</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Korea-Soviet,0164</SECOND>
<HEAD>Soviet Boat Visits South Korean For First Time Since 1945</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SEOUL, South Korea (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 For the first time since <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> was divided in 1945, a Soviet vessel docked Sunday at a South Korean port. A Soviet tourist ship, the 12,798-ton <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> Sholokhov </PERSON>, arrived at the western port city of <LOCATION> Inchon </LOCATION>, 25 miles west of <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION>. The ship went to <LOCATION> Inchon </LOCATION> after stopping at the southern port of <LOCATION> Pusan </LOCATION> on Saturday. In <LOCATION> Pusan </LOCATION>, the venue for yachting competition in the Olympics, the ship dropped off a 27-member Soviet yachting delegation and 56 tourists. The Soviet vessel will remain in <LOCATION> Inchon </LOCATION> until the end of the Games, held from Sept. 17 to Oct. 2. The last visit of a Soviet vessel occurred in 1945, when <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and Soviet troops facilitated the surrender of <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, which colonized the peninsula for 36 years. <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION> has no diplomatic relations with <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>, which backed <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> during the 1950-1953 Korean War.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880904-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-04-88 1112EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-BRF--Pakistan-Bomb     09-04 0094</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Pakistan-Bomb,0097</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bomb Explodes At Karachi Rail Station, 12 Hurt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>KARACHI, Pakistan (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A bomb hidden in a shipment of washing machines exploded at <LOCATION> Karachi </LOCATION>'s main railway station Sunday, slightly injuring 12 people and damaging a platform at the station, police said. The blast ripped open the roof of the platform where the shipment of washing machines had been unloaded, but did not interrupt rail traffic. Police said the two-pound explosive device was put inside cargo that arrived at the station from the northern city of <LOCATION> Gujranwala </LOCATION>. No one immediately claimed responsibility.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880904-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-04-88 1113EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-BRF--SriLanka-Blast     09-04 0146</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Sri Lanka-Blast,0151</SECOND>
<HEAD>Tamil Rebels Kill 12 Government Soldiers</HEAD>
<DATELINE>COLOMBO, Sri Lanka (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Suspected Tamil rebels Sunday blew up a military vehicle in northern <LOCATION> Sri </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lanka </LOCATION>, killing nine government soldiers and injuring three, military officials said. The attack near <LOCATION> Vavuniya </LOCATION> followed an ambush by the rebels in the north eastern <LOCATION> Trincomalee </LOCATION> on Saturday in which three Sri Lankan soldiers were killed. The military officials, speaking on condition of anonymity, said the rebels used remote-controlled explosives to blow up the military vehicle at <LOCATION> Cheddikulan </LOCATION>, 15 miles south west of <LOCATION> Vavunia </LOCATION>. Nine soldiers died immediately and three were critically injured. Sri Lankan Tamils, 18 percent of the nation's 16 million people, want an independent homeland in the north and east. The Tamils, who are Hindus, accuse the majority <PERSON> Sinhalese </PERSON>, who are Buddhists, of discrimination. At least 8,500 people have died in the 5-year-old Tamil separatist war.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880904-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-04-88 1114EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-FreighterChase     09-04 0423</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Freighter Chase,0434</SECOND>
<HEAD>Freighter Surrenders In Britain After Outrunning French
Authorities</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A cargo ship suspected of carrying drugs surrendered to <LOCATION> British </LOCATION> customs officials after it was chased across the English Channel by <LOCATION> French </LOCATION> authorities who fired warning shots when it refused to stop. A <LOCATION> British </LOCATION> customs spokesman identified the vessel as the Honduras-registered <LOCATION> Salton </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sea </LOCATION> and said it failed to stop for a routine check by <LOCATION> French </LOCATION> customs officials off <LOCATION> Boulogne </LOCATION> on the northeast French coast late Saturday. `` The French fired two shots across her bows and she then did a bunk -LRB- steamed away -RRB- into British waters,'' said the spokesman, speaking on condition of anonymity. After a chase 40 miles across the English Channel, the freighter surrendered to the unarmed British coast guard cutter Swift and was escorted into <ORGANIZATION> Ramsgate </ORGANIZATION> on the southeast coast of <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>. Customs officers, specially trained dogs and divers were searching the vessel Sunday. British news reports said the ship was thought to be carrying illegal drugs, but the Customs and <ORGANIZATION> Excise </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> would not comment. <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Davies </PERSON>, an assistant collector for the Customs and <ORGANIZATION> Excise </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, said no further information would be disclosed about the ship until it was fully searched, a job that was not expected to be completed Sunday. `` It is a pretty big ship and it is going to take a lot of rummaging,'' <PERSON> Davies </PERSON> said. `` It is a long hard job and we will be at it for some while.'' <ORGANIZATION> Kent </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Constabulary </ORGANIZATION> in <ORGANIZATION> Ramsgate </ORGANIZATION> said two men were taken off the ship and held in the town's police cells before being transferred Sunday to the police station in nearby <LOCATION> Dover </LOCATION>. About 30 British customs officers, some carrying bolt cutters and electronic equipment, boarded the ship, accompanied by two dogs trained to sniff for illegal drugs. Two divers disappeared under the ship, anchored 50 yards from the outer harbor wall. The British cutter and the French clipper Vent D'Avac, which fired the warning shots, were docked nearby. The spokesman said he did not know the freighter's destination, but he said it had come from <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>. The <LOCATION> Salton </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sea </LOCATION> is not listed in <ORGANIZATION> Lloyd </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> Register of Ships. But Press Association, the domestic British news agency, said the vague outline of `` <LOCATION> Salton </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Seahorse </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Virgo </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> La </LOCATION>.'' could be seen on the ship. A ship called the <LOCATION> Salton </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Seahorse </LOCATION> is listed in <ORGANIZATION> Lloyd </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> as being owned by <ORGANIZATION> Seahorse </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fleet </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Morgan </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> La </LOCATION>. That ship, built in 1973 by the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION>, is a 170-foot-long supply ship.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880904-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-04-88 1115EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Iraq     09-04 0452</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Iraq,0467</SECOND>
<HEAD>Iraq Marks Eighth Anniversary Of War With Iran</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN RICE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BAGHDAD, Iraq (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> used song and poetry to mark the eighth anniversary of the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> war on Sunday, a date chosen to underscore its claim that <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> started the conflict. The week-long celebration of `` <PERSON> Saddam </PERSON>'s Qadissiyeh'' _ an <LOCATION> Iraqi </LOCATION> term for the war _ marks the anniversary of Iranian shelling of <LOCATION> Iraqi </LOCATION> territory that <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> claims began the fighting on Sept. 4. <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> dates the war's beginning 18 days later, when Iraqi troops invaded <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> cease-fire resolution accepted by both sides calls for an independent body to determine who began the war. The armed forces newspaper <PERSON> Al-Qadissiyeh </PERSON> said in an editorial that the anniversary `` has become an immortal event in our history so that coming generations will not forget the Persians' -LRB- Iranians' -RRB- aggression and evil intentions against Arabs and Islam. Banners strung in the streets by the ruling <ORGANIZATION> Baath </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> and poems read over state television heaped praise on President <PERSON> Saddam </PERSON> <PERSON> Hussein </PERSON>. `` Through the great leader and the great people, victory and peace have been achieved,'' read one banner. `` Oh <PERSON> Saddam </PERSON>, thou art the voice of history,'' a poet pronounced on television. `` Thou art the only hero at a time when there is no one else to confront -LRB- the foe -RRB-. `` Thou hast brought back to <LOCATION> Baghdad </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Babylon </PERSON> their glory.'' Official newspapers hammered at the themes of <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>'s stand at the U.N.-sponsored peace talks with <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION>, and accused <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> of violating the cease-fire that took effect Aug. 20. They also blasted <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'s insistence on returning to a southern border line established by the 1975 <LOCATION> Algiers </LOCATION> agreement _ the middle of the Shatt <PERSON> Al-Arab </PERSON> waterway. <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> has renounced the pact, saying it wants all of the waterway. <PERSON> Saad </PERSON> <PERSON> al-Bazaz </PERSON>, director-general of the official <ORGANIZATION> Iraqi </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION>, wrote in the <ORGANIZATION> Baath </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> daily <ORGANIZATION> Al-Thawra </ORGANIZATION> that before the war, `` <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> violated two important elements of the 1975 <LOCATION> Algiers </LOCATION> agreement and chose only one to its benefit.'' He said <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> refused to return land along the central border as the treaty demanded and failed to respect `` the principle of non-interference in internal affairs.'' Iranian support for Iraqi Kurdish rebels before the war had aggravated tensions between the neighboring states. <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> dates the war to Sept. 4, 1980, when <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> shelled Iraqi towns on the central border after months of escalating propaganda claims by both sides. <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> also accuses <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> of attacking ships in the Shatt <PERSON> Al-Arab </PERSON> before Sept. 22, when <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> invaded <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>. The term `` <PERSON> Saddam </PERSON>'s Qadissiyeh'' recalls a 7th century victory by Arab Islamic troops over the Persians in <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> that opened the way for <ORGANIZATION> Islam </ORGANIZATION>'s expansion to the east.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880904-0025 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-04-88 1116EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-RedOnion     09-04 0286</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Red Onion,0294</SECOND>
<HEAD>Restaurant Chain Settles Discrimination Suits</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SANTA ANA, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A southern <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> chain of restaurants will pay $ 15,000 each to 23 people who sued, alleging were denied service because of race or ethnicity. Friday's settlement is the third involving the <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Onion </ORGANIZATION> chain of Mexican food restaurants, based in the <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> suburb of <PERSON> Carson </PERSON>. It was accused of using dress codes and other excuses to bar minorities from their dining rooms. <PERSON> Russell </PERSON> <PERSON> Kerr </PERSON>, who represented black, Hispanic and <PERSON> Arab </PERSON> plaintiffs, said four more people were expected to accept the settlements this week. In depositions, <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Onion </ORGANIZATION> employees said board president <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Newman </PERSON> used the code name `` Norwegians'' for minorities and would say: `` The room is too dark. There's too many Norwegians in here,'' <PERSON> Kerr </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Newman </PERSON> denied the allegations, and <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Onion </ORGANIZATION> attorney <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kurlander </PERSON> said that he was unaware of any corporate policy of discrimination but that he could not speak for each of the chain's 14 restaurants `` I'm not interested in the money, but I'm interested in the principle,'' said <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> Lujan </PERSON>, 30, who claimed he was denied entry to the <ORGANIZATION> Santa </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ana </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Onion </ORGANIZATION> in 1986. `` <LOCATION> Orange </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> is such a conservative, white type of county. There was an opportunity to set a precedent here in <LOCATION> Orange </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> of how things must change.'' In November, six Iranians who sued in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> received a $ 240,000 settlement and an apology. In addition, at least 22 people who complained of discrimination in 1986 accepted $ 500 payments and agreed to forego legal action. The first complaints in 1986 prompted the state to suspend liquor licenses for six months at <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Onions </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ana </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Fullerton </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Riverside </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880904-0026 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-04-88 1118EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-SovietCorruption Bjt   09-04 0770</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Soviet Corruption, Bjt,0789</SECOND>
<HEAD>Leonid Brezhnev's Son-in-Law, Facing Possible Death Sentence, On
Trial</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN-THOR DAHLBURG</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MOSCOW (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The trial of <PERSON> Leonid </PERSON> <PERSON> Brezhnev </PERSON>'s son-in-law, accused of taking $ 1.1 million in bribes, is expected to lay bare the widespread corruption of the <PERSON> Brezhnev </PERSON> era. Court begins Monday for <PERSON> Yuri </PERSON> <PERSON> Churbanov </PERSON>, a former first deputy interior minister who once moved in the top levels of <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION> society. If found guilty of bribe-taking and abuse of office, he and eight co-defendants could be executed by firing squad. Their trial, and the extraordinary publicity given its investigatory phase, are in line with <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> chief <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s drive to break with the cronyism, corruption and nepotism now seen as endemic under <PERSON> Brezhnev </PERSON>. <PERSON> Brezhnev </PERSON> ruled the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> from 1964 until his death in 1982. The court case, to be heard by the Military Collegium of the <ORGANIZATION> Soviet </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>, may also have a political aim _ to signal the <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION> Old Guard who flourished under <PERSON> Brezhnev </PERSON> that their time has passed and that continued resistance to Gorbachev-era reforms must cease. <PERSON> Churbanov </PERSON>, who married <PERSON> Brezhnev </PERSON>'s daughter <PERSON> Galina </PERSON> in 1971 after divorcing his first wife in 1964, is a central figure in an embezzlement and bribery scheme authorities say centered on the Central Asian republic of <LOCATION> Uzbekistan </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> newspaper Pravda said that beginning in the 1970s, cotton harvests in <LOCATION> Uzbekistan </LOCATION> were padded by almost 1 million tons annually, and <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> was made to pay for the non-existent crop by corrupt officials all the way up to longtime <LOCATION> Uzbek </LOCATION> party boss <PERSON> Sharaf </PERSON> <PERSON> Rashidov </PERSON>, who died in 1983. `` Today it has been proven that the cotton barons stole more than 4 billion rubles -LRB- $ 6.34 billion -RRB- from the state, half of which they stuffed into their own pockets,'' Pravda said this year in a sensational expose on the fraud, whose scale is without Soviet precedent. <PERSON> Churbanov </PERSON>, 51, who held the rank of colonel general in the Moscow-based ministry responsible for police and law enforcement nationwide, was a power-hungry epicure who helped shield the racket, Soviet press accounts say. `` The son-in-law became the ` first violin' at the end of the 70s,'' Pravda said last week. `` Having such a ` friend' was not only an advantage for <PERSON> Rashidov </PERSON> and his group _ it was vitally important.'' <PERSON> Churbanov </PERSON>, who worked as a mechanic before taking a low-level <ORGANIZATION> Interior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> job in 1961, is accused of accepting bribes totaling 651,888 rubles, the equivalent of $ 1.1 million. That sum, stupendous by Soviet standards, is equivalent to 270 years' pay for the average Soviet factory worker. The weekly <ORGANIZATION> Moscow </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> cited this encounter between <PERSON> Churbanov </PERSON>, then deputy interior minister, and <PERSON> Abduvakhid </PERSON> <PERSON> Karimov </PERSON>, then <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> boss in <LOCATION> Uzbekistan </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Bukhara </LOCATION> region: `` When an earthquake struck the town of <LOCATION> Gazli </LOCATION> ... <PERSON> Churbanov </PERSON> came to inspect relief efforts. ` There are n't any cigarettes in the stores,' he berated <PERSON> Karimov </PERSON> on the street. At his dacha that evening, <PERSON> Karimov </PERSON> gave <PERSON> Churbanov </PERSON> 10,000 rubles -LRB- $ 15,800 -RRB- in exchange for the latter's promise ` not to report shortcomings to his superiors.''' <PERSON> Karimov </PERSON> was sentenced to death for bribery by the <ORGANIZATION> Soviet </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> in June 1987 after an anti-corruption drive in <LOCATION> Uzbekistan </LOCATION> that led to the replacement of two-thirds of all party-appointed officials. Officials announced <PERSON> Churbanov </PERSON>'s arrest in February 1987. He was fired from his top-level <ORGANIZATION> Interior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> job in 1984, but reportedly was employed as deputy chief of political administration for the ministry's uniformed security troops until September 1986. Along with <PERSON> Churbanov </PERSON>, currently in <ORGANIZATION> KGB </ORGANIZATION> custody, eight former <LOCATION> Uzbekistan </LOCATION> officials will go on trial: Interior Minister <PERSON> Khaidar </PERSON> <PERSON> Yakhyaev </PERSON>, two of his deputies and five regional police chiefs. The evidence against the nine men fills 110 volumes, and five volumes were needed to spell out the indictment. A total of 501 witnesses are mentioned in the indictment. <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Gennady </PERSON> <PERSON> Gerasimov </PERSON> told reporters last week the trial is expected to last up to two months. <PERSON> Churbanov </PERSON> may be given the death penalty if convicted, <PERSON> Gerasimov </PERSON> said, because he is charged with serious economic crimes. <PERSON> Churbanov </PERSON>'s attorney, <PERSON> Andrei </PERSON> <PERSON> Makarov </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>, said in an interview published last week that his client is being made a scapegoat for the ills of the <PERSON> Brezhnev </PERSON> era. <PERSON> Makarov </PERSON> told the <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> News: `` The impression is that <PERSON> Churbanov </PERSON> is being blamed for everything negative that we used to have, or that <PERSON> Brezhnev </PERSON> is being tried under the name of <PERSON> Churbanov </PERSON>.'' Pravda, however, called <PERSON> Churbanov </PERSON> `` an example of the ` stagnation period,' when a person reached high position not because of his merits but due to his family connections.'' It added: `` Glasnost and democracy will help to avoid Churbanovism and anything similar to it.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880904-0027 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-04-88 1118EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Sudan     09-04 0421</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Sudan,0433</SECOND>
<HEAD>Death Toll from Starvation Hits 8,000 In Sudan</HEAD>
<DATELINE>KHARTOUM, Sudan (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Fighting and seasonal flooding are blocking Western relief efforts in southern <LOCATION> Sudan </LOCATION>, where local reports indicate 8,000 people have starved to death in recent weeks, authorities say. Southerners arriving from <LOCATION> Wau </LOCATION>, 660 miles south of <LOCATION> Khartoum </LOCATION>, said Saturday that thousands of people trekking north toward the <LOCATION> Kordofan </LOCATION> region have been marooned by floods for days. Many died, they said. `` Dozens of people have fallen dead on the roads leading to <PERSON> Meriam </PERSON> camp due to hunger,'' one new arrival told The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Meriam </PERSON> is 500 miles south of <LOCATION> Khartoum </LOCATION>. The Rev. <PERSON> Aengus </PERSON> <PERSON> Finucane </PERSON>, director of the Irish aid agency CONCERN, said last month that about 40 people were dying there daily. <PERSON> Bakheet </PERSON> <PERSON> Hussein </PERSON>, another recent arrival, said he knew that thousands of people `` trying to flee the town of <LOCATION> Wau </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Babanusa </LOCATION> have perished before reaching there.'' <LOCATION> Babanusa </LOCATION> is 250 miles north of <LOCATION> Wau </LOCATION>. A government official said last week that at least 4,000 people died in <LOCATION> Aweil </LOCATION>, a way station between <LOCATION> Wau </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Babanusa </PERSON> that has been under siege by rebel forces for almost a year. Reports from the south reaching the Council of the <LOCATION> South </LOCATION>, a government body, said the death toll in <LOCATION> Aweil </LOCATION> alone rose to 8,000 in recent days and that starvation and disease threatened thousands in other southern towns. Outside confirmation of the reports was virtually impossible. Even without the chaos caused by August's floods, travel in the south by journalists and most outsiders has been restricted for years because of the civil war. The rebel <ORGANIZATION> Sudan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> took up arms against the government in 1983 and claims control over 90 percent of the southern countryside and towns. Fierce fighting between the government and rebels has forced southerners to leave crops and cattle for the safety of towns. Faced with dwindling food and medical supplies in these towns, southerners often try to make their way farther north, usually on foot. Another report reaching the <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> the </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> South </ORGANIZATION> said the situation in <LOCATION> Aweil </LOCATION> `` is dramatically deteriorating.'' It said floods washed away roads and bridges connecting the town with the outside, blocking whatever relief supplies might get through. The report said food supplies, especially southern <LOCATION> Sudan </LOCATION>'s staple sorghum, are low in <LOCATION> Wau </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Juba </LOCATION>, the south's main city 750 miles south of <LOCATION> Khartoum </LOCATION> The report said floods caused by heavy rains and fighting in the area was obstructing Western relief organizations' efforts to bring food and medicine to these areas.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880904-0028 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-04-88 1119EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Non-Aligned     09-04 0374</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Non-Aligned,0390</SECOND>
<HEAD>Delegates Gather For Non-Aligned Meeting Amid Security Fears</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ED BLANCHE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NICOSIA, Cyprus (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Fears of a terrorist attack prompted strict security measures Sunday as senior government officials from 95 countries began gathering for the <ORGANIZATION> Non-Aligned </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Movement </ORGANIZATION>'s foreign ministers conference. The five-day conference opens Monday with preparatory meetings. President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Vassilou </PERSON> formally begins the three-day foreign ministers' session Wednesday. <ORGANIZATION> Palestine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> chairman <PERSON> Yasser </PERSON> <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON> is expected to attend the conference in his current campaign to muster support for a plan to proclaim a provisional government for an independent Palestinian state. The conference will map out the 101-member <ORGANIZATION> Non-Aligned </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Movement </ORGANIZATION>'s role over the next decade and decide its next chairman. <LOCATION> Zimbabwe </LOCATION> is the current chairman. Conservative members are backing <LOCATION> Indonesia </LOCATION>, while more radical states support <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>, the only other official candidate. Some speculated that <LOCATION> Cyprus </LOCATION> could step in as a compromise candidate to break any deadlock that develops. A special anti-terrorist squad and about 1,500 police officers have been mobilized to guard the newly built conference center on <LOCATION> Nicosia </LOCATION>'s southern outskirts and the 14 hotels where the delegates will stay. Police in the Greek-controlled sector of the war-divided east <LOCATION> Mediterranean </LOCATION> island have carried out mock terrorist attacks over the last few days to test security. Mobile patrols have been stepped up between <LOCATION> Larnaca </LOCATION> airport, on the coast south of the capital, and the port city of <LOCATION> Limassol </LOCATION>. Police units have combed the ravines and hills bordering the highway. Armored vehicles have been deployed around the beachside airport. <LOCATION> Cyprus </LOCATION> government spokesman <PERSON> Akis </PERSON> <PERSON> Fantis </PERSON> said peace moves in the Iran-Iraq war, <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> Algeria-Morocco </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sahara </LOCATION> dispute, the Soviet withdrawal from <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> and U.S.-Soviet relations were `` of tremendous importance'' to the movement. Fighting between <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>, both members of the movement, halted Aug. 20 when a U.N.-sponsored cease-fire took effect. With the recent rapprochement between <LOCATION> Greece </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Turkey </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Greek </LOCATION> and Turkish Cypriots are trying to reconcile their differences as well. <LOCATION> Cyprus </LOCATION> has been divided since the Turkish Army invaded in July 1974 and seized the northern third of the island. <PERSON> Vassiliou </PERSON>, the <LOCATION> Greek </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Cypriot </LOCATION> leader, and <PERSON> Rauf </PERSON> <PERSON> Denktash </PERSON>, leader of the Turkish Cypriot minority, broke a four-year deadlock when they met in <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> under <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> auspices Aug. 24.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880904-0029 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-04-88 1120EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-DeformedPerformer     09-04 0377</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Deformed Performer,0389</SECOND>
<HEAD>Quadriplegic Performer Due Back In Court</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ATLANTIC CITY, N.J. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A quadriplegic who earns thousands of dollars in donations on the Boardwalk by using her tongue to play a portable keyboard again faces charges of breaking the city's anti-begging laws <PERSON> Celestine </PERSON> <PERSON> Tate </PERSON> faces 12 charges of playing without a permit. She was issued summonses in 1986 for the same reason, but after a trial, a lawsuit and a lot of publicity, the city allowed Ms. <PERSON> Tate </PERSON> to play for money on the <LOCATION> Boardwalk </LOCATION>. The city, in backing down, assigned her a spot on the <LOCATION> Boardwalk </LOCATION> and required a permit. But prosecutors said she has not obtained the permit and has been playing in front of <ORGANIZATION> Bally </ORGANIZATION>'s Park Place casino hotel two blocks away for most of the summer. Ms. <PERSON> Tate </PERSON> argues that her <ORGANIZATION> Bally </ORGANIZATION>'s spot is shaded and that she was misled into thinking she would receive a merchant's license. City officials have instead offered her standard one-day Boardwalk permits, which require a $ 1 million insurance bond. She said such a bond would cost her $ 500 a day. City Prosecutor <PERSON> Steven </PERSON> <PERSON> Smoger </PERSON> said the city `` made a great dispensation'' in allowing Ms. <PERSON> Tate </PERSON> to play for money on the <LOCATION> Boardwalk </LOCATION>. No other person, handicapped or otherwise, has been given that opportunity, he said. Birth defects left Ms. <PERSON> Tate </PERSON>'s arms and legs undeveloped. She supports herself and her children, ages 10 and 12, with the money she earns on the <LOCATION> Boardwalk </LOCATION>. She said she averages $ 2,000 a week, enough to send her children to private school. Police have also issued summonses to her brother and two paid attendants. The crackdown on Ms. <PERSON> Tate </PERSON>'s business was prompted by several citizen complaints, <PERSON> Smoger </PERSON> said, declining to elaborate. The prosecutor was unsympathetic to Ms. <PERSON> Tate </PERSON>'s insurance problems. `` If that's the price, so be it,'' he said. `` She earns more than enough to cover that. I think she should absorb the cost and pay it. `` She's a cunning, clever businesswoman,'' he said. `` I think she is overexaggerating to a great degree.'' Ms. <PERSON> Tate </PERSON> has requested a trial and time to obtain a lawyer. Meanwhile, she said, she will continue to entertain <PERSON> Boardwalk </PERSON> tourists with renditions of songs such as `` We Shall Overcome,'' `` Amazing Grace'' and `` Born Free.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880904-0030 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-04-88 1127EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p AM-CampaignKickoff Bjt   09-04 0973</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Campaign Kickoff, Bjt,960</SECOND>
<HEAD>Presidential Game Well Under Way at Labor Day Kickoff</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By WILLIAM M. WELCH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> make campaign-launching Labor Day appearances Monday in a race for the presidency that has ignored the ceremonial starting point and is already a close and caustic contest. `` It kicked off earlier than any presidential campaign I've ever seen,'' said <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Greer </PERSON>, a consultant to Democratic candidates. `` The intensity this early is really astounding.'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, the Democratic nominee who has seen a huge midsummer's lead evaporate, campaigns through the industrial <ORGANIZATION> Northeast </ORGANIZATION> and <LOCATION> Midwest </LOCATION> hungering for the elusive intangibles of momentum and initiative that he once commanded <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, the vice president and <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> nominee, enters the final nine weeks of his race for the White House appearing in control of their long-distance debate, at least for now, and enjoying a resurrection in the polls. He was campaigning on the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Coast </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> communications director <PERSON> Leslie </PERSON> <PERSON> Dach </PERSON> said Labor Day is `` when the season really starts'' and represents the point where the <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> governor steps up his pace from three days of campaign travel to five each week. But the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> campaign was making no effort to cloak its candidate in the traditions of Labor Day. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> passed up a chance for a visual send-off before the Statue of Liberty, where <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> began his fall campaign in 1980, and a symbolic appearance with his running mate. `` Labor Day as an opening day has been overtaken by events,'' said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> spokesman <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Goodin </PERSON>. Those events include a blistering round of attacks on <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> leveled by <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> immediately after the Democrats spent four July days ridiculing the vice president at their <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> convention. And, they include the debate over <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s controversial running mate, <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>, whose selection at a minimum forced a vacationing electorate to notice this presidential race. Both campaigns have revealed their themes, too. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> is focusing on the economy, and middle class unease about the economic future, as well as questioning the judgment and fitness of the Republican ticket. `` Most Americans do n't feel they're sharing in <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s prosperity,'' said <PERSON> Dach </PERSON>, the <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> spokesman `` We're going to run on the economic issues. Those are the issues that are going to decide this election. What <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> is trying to do is deflect the debate off the issues that people really care about.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has concentrated on raising doubts about <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> and his record as governor, while suggesting gentle change from the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration in such areas as protecting the environment. Now <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> plans to focus on jobs and the economy. Still to come are what may be the main events: televised debates, where an error can wreck a candidacy; and the wars of television advertising, which are certain to be hard fought. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s TV ads will begin airing soon, campaign manager <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Atwater </PERSON> said. Media adviser <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> Ailes </PERSON> is not tipping his hand on the content, but campaign sources said among them may be one featuring <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION> victims terrorized by convicted murderer <PERSON> Willie </PERSON> <PERSON> Horton </PERSON>, who escaped while on a furlough from the <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> prison system. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has made a major campaign issue of the furlough program that allowed passes for first-degree murderers, and which <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> reluctantly agreed to amend in the face of public outcry. Confident of his debating style honed as a public television show host, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> is eager to confront <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. The <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> campaign, however, has attempted to minimize the debates. It has agreed to two debates, plus a third between the running mates, and is insisting on scheduling them in late September and early October _ when the Olympics and World Series may keep some viewers away. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> responded strongly to <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> during their summer jousting, even at one point evoking the imagery of rotting fish heads in describing President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and his vice president. But his campaign clearly is frustrated by the appearance that he is reacting and on the defensive, unable to direct the debate. There was implicit admission that all is not well in <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' announcement Friday of the return of his former campaign manager <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Sasso </PERSON>, who resigned in controversy a year earlier And <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> on occasion has seemed tentative and reluctant in their long-distance debates, some believe. `` I'm not sure the Democrats have given back as good as we got,'' said <PERSON> Greer </PERSON>. `` I think we were lulled by that large lead.'' Where he once led by double-digit margins, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> was shown in a dead heat with <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> according to most recent polls, including an <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News-Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> poll last week. It had <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> up by 1 percentage point, 43-42, statistically insignificant. `` I do n't think anyone in the campaign, from top to bottom, anticipated the race tightening up to our advantage this quick,'' said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> manager <PERSON> Atwater </PERSON>. `` Our key is not to get confident, not to get cocky about it.'' Some Republicans believe <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> still trails a bit, however. `` I would say we're still realistically 5-6-7 points down,'' said <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> consultant <PERSON> Eddie </PERSON> <PERSON> Mahe </PERSON>, who is doing work for the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> campaign on the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Coast </LOCATION>. He bases that on the difference, in some polls, of respondents who say they are deeply committed to a candidate. The battle is largely for those wavering or swing voters. They are often described as <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> Democrats, self-identified independents or Democrats who turned away from the party in 1980 and 1984. But what is striking is that the race is breathtakingly close all across the nation _ including the big battleground states like <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>. Even <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>'s home state of <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> is even or nearly so in a recent poll. `` When <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> was ahead, he was ahead everywhere. When <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> took the lead, it was everywhere. When it evens out now, it's kind of even everywhere,'' said <PERSON> Greer </PERSON>. `` It's amazing.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880904-0031 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-04-88 1131EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Brazil-Constitution     09-04 0184</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Brazil-Constitution,0190</SECOND>
<HEAD>Brazil Postpones New Constitution to Prepare Celebration</HEAD>
<HEAD>RETRANSMITTING to fix cycle designator</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BRASILIA, Brazil (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
