<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880814-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-14-88 2336EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-Heat-Utilities     08-14 0379</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Heat-Utilities,0389</SECOND>
<HEAD>Utilities Warn of Possible Blackouts Monday</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN DIAMOND</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BOSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 New <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> power officials warned on Sunday night that blackouts may occur throughout the six-state region Monday unless businesses and homeowners conserve electricity amid the heat wave. A shutdown this weekend of the <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Yankee </LOCATION> nuclear power plant and one of four power generators on <LOCATION> Salem </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Harbor </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> has worsened the already difficult power situation for most of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>, officials said. The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Weather </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> reported that 18 cities in the northeastern quarter of the nation reported record high temperatures for the date Sunday, and forecast that <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> would have 90s, with 80s in the northern portions, on Monday. <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> had an ironic record low temperature of 78 late Sunday afternoon when an ocean breeze cooled the area. But as soon as the winds shifted, the temperature shot up 14 degrees in 10 minutes, the weather service said. Monday `` is definitely a very tight day,'' said <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Sheperdson </PERSON>, a spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> England </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Power </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pool </ORGANIZATION>, which coordinates power supplies for utilities throughout <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>. `` If we do n't get a considerable contribution by our customers, as we did a number of days last week, we may not be able to provide uninterrupted service,'' <PERSON> Sheperdson </PERSON> said. <ORGANIZATION> Boston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Edison </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Monahan </PERSON> called the situation `` tremendously tight'' and said the numbers simply do n't add up for power supply to continue without periodic, controlled blackouts Monday. The <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> region controlled by the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> England </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Power </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pool </ORGANIZATION> set a record for summertime power demand last Thursday at 19,608 megawatts. The pool is expecting demand to exceed 19,900 megawatts Monday. `` That's 300 megawatts more, plus you're missing <ORGANIZATION> Maine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Yankee </ORGANIZATION>, which is 860 megawatts,'' <PERSON> Monahan </PERSON> said. <ORGANIZATION> Maine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Yankee </ORGANIZATION> shut down over the weekend because of a transformer problem, according to <PERSON> Monahan </PERSON>. The pool is predicting the plant will be out of service until Wednesday at the earliest. In <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, meanwhile, <ORGANIZATION> Consolidated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Edison </ORGANIZATION> reported a record for Sunday electricity demand: 7,645 megawatts between 9 p.m. and 10 p.m., breaking the record of 6,770 megawatts, set last Sunday. Spokesman <PERSON> Marty </PERSON> <PERSON> Gitten </PERSON> said peak demand often occurs at that hour as people return home from weekend activities and turn on air conditioners and lights.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880814-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-14-88 2355EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Ireland-Abortion Bjt   08-14 0856</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Ireland-Abortion, Bjt,0884</SECOND>
<HEAD>Anti-Abortion Group Tries to Muzzle Students</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By EDITH M. LEDERER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>DUBLIN, Ireland (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 In the heart of this Roman Catholic city, one of the latest bits of wall graffiti says `` Abortion Now,'' but someone has blackened the telephone number. The graffiti in St. <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON>'s <PERSON> Green </PERSON> is emblematic of an ongoing clash _ but not over legalizing abortion. That's already banned in the <LOCATION> Irish </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Republic </LOCATION>. The struggle is over a woman's right to receive information on obtaining a legal abortion elsewhere. This country, with its 95 percent <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> population, enshrined an abortion ban into its constitution in 1983. Approved by a 2-1 margin in a national referendum, the amendment says a fetus and mother have an equal right to life, which must be defended by the state. Three months ago, the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>, ruling on action brought by the country's main anti-abortion group, declared that the amendment made it illegal for pregnancy counseling centers to provide women with any information to help them get a legal abortion. However, university students across the republic have vowed to continue publishing the names and telephone numbers of clinics in <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>, where abortion is legal. `` Access to information is a civil liberty, and prevention of such access is a form of censorship which we should not tolerate,'' said <PERSON> Tadhg </PERSON> <PERSON> Daly </PERSON>, president of the 120,000-member Union of Students in <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION>. The Society for the Protection of the Unborn Child, the plaintiff in the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> ruling, had sued two pregnancy counseling centers for telling women how to get abortions in <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>. Now it has now targeted <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dublin </ORGANIZATION>, with 10,000 students the country's largest university. On July 1, the anti-abortion society's lawyers wrote to four student leaders threatening legal acton unless they removed the addresses of English abortion clinics from a manual given to students at the start of each academic year. The school's student union president, <PERSON> Diarmuid </PERSON> <PERSON> Coogan </PERSON>, replied that students had voted to include the abortion information and said it will remain in the manual. `` All options should be available to women without pressure to opt for one or the other,'' said <PERSON> Coogan </PERSON>. `` Does the Society for the Protection of the Unborn Child intend to put us in jail for implementing the democratically decided mandate of our students?'' <PERSON> Coogan </PERSON> asked. All 40 colleges in the country back <PERSON> Coogan </PERSON> and four, including <LOCATION> Dublin </LOCATION>'s prestigious <ORGANIZATION> Trinity </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION>, say they will publish the same abortion information this fall. The national students' body has promised legal assistance to fight attempts to stop publication. <PERSON> Maire </PERSON> <PERSON> Vernon </PERSON>, spokeswoman for the Society for the Protection of the Unborn Child, said the group will wait to see if the information is in this year's student manuals before deciding on legal action. `` The right to life is written into the constitution, and it overrides the right to information,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Vernon </PERSON> said. `` The right to life is paramount. You do n't have an untrammeled right to information, especially if it is going to take the life of a child.'' <PERSON> Coogan </PERSON> retorted that the society wants `` to make abortion not exist.'' `` But thousands of <LOCATION> Irish </LOCATION> women go over to <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> every year for abortions,'' he said. `` If women are going to have abortions, they should have that information.'' According to British government figures, 3,673 women living in the <LOCATION> Irish </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Republic </LOCATION> received abortions in <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> in 1987, down from 3,918 in 1986. Mrs. <PERSON> Vernon </PERSON> said this was the lowest number since 1983, the year of the referendum. `` That means a lot of girls are n't even considering abortion but are going ahead and having the baby,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Vernon </PERSON> said. `` Hopefully, it will continue to drop. But <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> is only 60 miles off our coast, and we'll have to keep working away.'' <PERSON> Pauline </PERSON> <PERSON> Ryder </PERSON>, clinic administrator of The <LOCATION> Dublin </LOCATION> Well Woman Center, said the drop more likely stems in part from fewer <LOCATION> Irish </LOCATION> women giving <LOCATION> Irish </LOCATION> addresses when they have British abortions because of the controversy. The Well Woman clinic is one of two centers barred by the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> from providing information on how to get abortions after the suits by the anti-abortion society. The other center closed, and Ms. <PERSON> Ryder </PERSON> said Well Woman might be forced to do the same because it has been ordered to pay the anti-abortion society's $ 60,000 legal costs. While launching a fund-raising campaign, the center last month resumed pregnancy counseling, limiting its discussion of abortion to the operation, methods, care and cost, but not giving the addresses of the English clinics. The center plans to appeal the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> ruling to the <ORGANIZATION> European </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Human </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rights </ORGANIZATION> by Sept. 16 on grounds it violates the right `` to seek, receive and impart information and ideas through any media,'' which is guaranteed in the Universal Declaration of Human Rights. However, it's not clear a <ORGANIZATION> European </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> ruling in favor of the center would change national policy. Although legalizing abortion is not an issue, a survey released last month by the <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Social </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> found 58 percent of the population favored abortion if pregnancy seriously endangers a woman's life or health or results from rape or incest.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880814-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-14-88 0007EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-TrappersConvention 1stLd-Writethru a0575</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Trappers Convention, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0575,0554</SECOND>
<HEAD>Trappers Offer Grab Bag of Unusual Gear</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: INSERTS 4 grafs after 3rd graf pvs to UPDATE with Saturday
quotes from protesters. picks up 4th graf pvs, ``The trappers ... </NOTE>
<BYLINE>By BILL VOGRIN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PEORIA, Ill. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 About 15,000 animal trappers swapped tips and admired everything from raccoon fur to alligator heads at a national convention, while demonstrators Saturday marched with signs reading, `` Every Fur Coat Hurts.'' Some of the 200 animal rights activists marching outside the <ORGANIZATION> Peoria </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Civic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> also carried signs with a picture of a mink, reading `` This animal needs her mother. Is she on your back?'' The activists say the trappers' use of steel leg-hold traps are responsible for millions of painful animal deaths each year. `` Strong men protect and defend the innocent. Cowards trap,'' said <PERSON> Kay </PERSON> <PERSON> Sievers </PERSON>, who represented Trans-species Unlimited. `` It's time to ban this trap,'' Ms. <PERSON> Sievers </PERSON> said during a rally in front of the Civic Center. `` You know why this is a great day? It's a great day because we've got ourselves a winnable issue,'' said <PERSON> Victoria </PERSON> <PERSON> Moran </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mo </LOCATION>. The protesters collected signatures to use in their effort to lobby <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to ban leg-hold traps. The trappers, meeting this weekend for the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Trappers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>'s 29th annual convention, say they are misunderstood animal lovers and blame animal rights activists for tarnishing their image. `` We love animals,'' said <PERSON> Ray </PERSON> <PERSON> Petrunich </PERSON>, 50, of <LOCATION> Taylor </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION>, owner of <ORGANIZATION> Trappers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Specialty </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Products </ORGANIZATION>, a mail-order trapper supply company. `` We have a great deal of respect for animals. We're helping keep their numbers down and prevent overpopulation There's no logic to any of their claims. On Friday, about 400 exhibitors displayed assorted animal skins and the latest gizmos for catching wild critters. The parking lot outside resembled a giant tailgate party featuring such delicacies as <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION> red peppers, <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION> coyote and <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> alligator steaks. `` We cater gator,'' is the call from <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Braxton </PERSON>'s booth. He looks like a cross between <PERSON> Grizzly </PERSON> <PERSON> Adams </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> Crocodile </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dundee </ORGANIZATION> as he picks up the head of a 650-pound alligator he caught in his native <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Braxton </PERSON> and his partner are licensed alligator control agents in <LOCATION> Westville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>, and are hired to capture the reptiles when they pose a danger to humans. He uses their meat in his Gator Caterers business and sells gator heads _ skeletons or preserved with skin and eyes _ at prices ranging from $ 95 to $ 200. Inside the civic center exhibition hall, steel traps are available by the thousands and wire snares are common. A small dirt pond was built in one corner of the arena. An old-time trapper demonstrated the best way to conceal a small leg-old trap and fielded questions from hundreds of conventioneers on topics such as how to lure a beaver into a submerged trap. Others advertised their merchandise with videotaped in-the-field demonstrations. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Naatz </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Evansville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wis. </LOCATION>, came to the convention to sell Glaciers' Edge fox urine, at $ 12 a gallon, which he said is essential for succesful trapping. `` You spread it around your trap to kill human odors,'' said <PERSON> Naatz </PERSON>, who raises 200 foxes. `` It makes other animals think there's been a fox nearby and is a good bait.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880814-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-14-88 0020EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-LastTemptation     08-14 0557</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Last Temptation,0574</SECOND>
<HEAD>Moviegoers Outnumber Protesters at Showings of Controversial Film</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LAUREN BLAU</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Concerns about violence and vandalism dissipated Saturday as the opening of the controversial film `` The Last Temptation of Christ'' passed with little trouble and more moviegoers than protesters. The movie, which opened Friday in nine major cities in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>, has been denounced by <ORGANIZATION> Protestant </ORGANIZATION> evangelists and conservative Catholics. Protesters contend that the portrayal of <PERSON> Jesus </PERSON> in the fictional movie as a man with self-doubt and a temptation to give up his call as a savior to live as a mortal is blasphemous. Security guards and police were searching purses and guarding movie screens. There were reports of minor vandalism at the Century Plaza Cinemas in the <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>, and one arrest each in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION>, and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. Police in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> said demonstrators have kept themselves under control. `` We're handling it as a very, very low profile situation,'' Sgt. <PERSON> Rick </PERSON> <PERSON> Walker </PERSON> said Saturday. `` We have one supervisor keeping a very casual eye on it.'' Police officers had patrolled Friday in the theater complex, which showed the film to near capacity crowds on two of its screens. Some movie patrons said the protesters were trying to infringe on freedom of speech and religious tolerance, while others wondered what all the fuss was about. The 800-seat Cinerama theater in <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION> had near capacity crowds Friday night as about 300 people demonstrated outside the theater. In <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION>, the 900-seat Northpoint Theater sold out on Friday 30 minutes after the doors opened for the first show amid 100 protesters and a small band of counterprotesters. Moviegoers in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> <LOCATION> D.C </LOCATION> outnumbered demonstrators six to one when the film opened at the Avalon Theater. People lined up around the block as 75 demonstrators marched in a circle jeering at those buying tickets. Officials reported that one person was arrested for crossing a police line. The Cooper Theater in the <LOCATION> Minneapolis </LOCATION> suburb of <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Louis </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Park </LOCATION> was more than 75 percent full for its Friday evening showing of the film as about 300 demonstrators held a peaceful prayer vigil outside. The film's showing in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> was accompanied by protests from Roman Catholics, Greek Orthodox, fundamentalists, <ORGANIZATION> Muslims </ORGANIZATION>, atheists and one neo-Nazi. A total of 600 people turned out to demonstrate at the <LOCATION> Biograph </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Theater </LOCATION> _ where gangster <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Dillinger </PERSON> was gunned down more than a half-century ago. All four shows at the 800-seat theater were sold out Friday. In <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, four shows sold out at the Ziegfeld Theater, which holds 1,144 people. Demonstrators, who sang, chanted and recited the Lord's Prayer, numbered about 100 people at midday but the crowd grew to between 500 and 1,000 by evening. One man who opposed the demonstrators was arrested for disorderly conduct after getting into a scuffle. The movie also is playing in <LOCATION> Toronto </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Montreal </LOCATION>. A Universal spokesman said a decision has not yet been made whether to add other cities next week. Movie chains refusing to book the film include the <LOCATION> Newton </LOCATION>, Mass.-based General Cinema Theaters, the nation's fourth-largest movie chain with 1,338 screens in 318 locations. Director <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Scorsese </PERSON> has defended his film, pointing out it is a work of fiction and is not based on the <ORGANIZATION> Gospels </ORGANIZATION>, and was not made with blasphemous intent.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880814-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-14-88 0036EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w AM-IranianAirliner 150   08-14 0176</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Iranian Airliner, 150</SECOND>
<HEAD>Report Faults One Officer In Vincennes Incident</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> officials have recommended disciplinary action against only one officer of the USS Vincennes in the downing of an Iranian airliner July 3, the <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> reported in Sunday's editions. The recommendation of the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> board resulted from statements following the panel's review of a report scheduled to be presented to <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Carlucci </PERSON> this week. The report places most of the blame on the Aegis cruiser's operations officer for his role in misinterpreting information which resulted in the ship mistakenly shooting down the Airbus killing all 299 aboard, the newspaper said The report, currently being reviewed by Marine Gen. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Crowe </PERSON>, <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Joint </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chiefs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Staff </ORGANIZATION>, recommends a letter of reprimand to the officer to be included in his official file. The officer's name had not been released. Earlier versions of the document, compiled by an investigative team headed by Rear Adm. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> N. </PERSON> <PERSON> Fogarty </PERSON>, said human error was a major factor in the accident.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880814-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-14-88 0046EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Philippines-Rebels 1stLd-Writethru a0582 08-14 0334</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Philippines-Rebels, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0582,0342</SECOND>
<HEAD>PRECEDE: Dipolog</HEAD>
<HEAD>Rebels Free Kidnapped Soldiers; Six People Killed In Rebel Attack</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: New throughout to UPDATE with release of five military
officers. No pickup. ADDS byline</NOTE>
<HEAD>With AM-Philippines-Politics, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MIGUEL C. SUAREZ</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MAMALA, Philippines (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Communist guerrillas released five military officers in this sleepy village southeast of <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION> on Sunday after two months of captivity. About 50 communist guerrillas attacked another southern town two days earlier, killing six people, the military said. <PERSON> Gregorio </PERSON> <PERSON> Rosal </PERSON>, spokesman of the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> rebel unit operating in <LOCATION> Mamala </LOCATION>, ceremonially unlocked the chains from the prisoner's wrists at about 9:30 a.m. -LRB- 9:30 p.m. EDT Saturday -RRB- before about 170 journalists. The rebels kidnapped army Lts. <PERSON> Abraham </PERSON> <PERSON> Casis </PERSON>, <PERSON> Oscar </PERSON> <PERSON> Singson </PERSON>, <PERSON> Clarito </PERSON> <PERSON> Santos </PERSON>, <PERSON> Rommel </PERSON> <LOCATION> Salamanca </LOCATION> and constabulary Sgt. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Jacob </PERSON> on June 1 after raiding a poultry farm in <LOCATION> Quezon </LOCATION> province which includes <LOCATION> Mamala </LOCATION>, 70 miles southeast of <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION>. The five soldiers were released to Public Works and Highways Secretary <PERSON> Juanito </PERSON> <PERSON> Ferrer </PERSON>, provincial officials and Roman Catholic Bishop <PERSON> Julio </PERSON> <PERSON> Labayen </PERSON> after two weeks of negotiations which included a temporary cease-fire that will end noon Tuesday. The rebels initially demanded the release of five alleged communists in jail who are reportedly suffering from various illnesses, but settled for their treatment in exchange for the soldiers' freedom. Provincial officials also agreed to create a human rights task force that will monitor alleged military abuses and compensate victims, and make recruitment for vigilante groups voluntary in compliance with the rebels' other demands. In another southern village, about 50 communist guerrillas disguised as soldiers killed six people, the military said Saturday. Col. <PERSON> Cesar </PERSON> <PERSON> Fortuno </PERSON>, provincial army chief, told reporters the insurgents attacked Friday in the mountain village of <LOCATION> Tuburan </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Zamboanag </LOCATION> <LOCATION> del </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Norte </LOCATION> province, about 10 miles southeast of <LOCATION> Dipolog </LOCATION> and 460 miles south of <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION>. He said the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> raided the village of 200 people two days after some residents enlisted with a group of anti-communist forces in the area.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880814-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-14-88 0056EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Deaths 1stLd-Writethru a0622 08-14 0775</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Deaths, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0622,0801</SECOND>
<NOTE>Eds: ADDS Williams, Udall, Gibson obits; AMs separates moved as
a0666 on Williams, a0665 on Udall, as a0541 on Zumwalt, a0612 on
Passman</NOTE>
<BYLINE>Edward Bennett Williams</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>, a famous criminal lawyer and sports entrepreneur who thrived on victory and agonized on defeat, died Saturday after a decade-long battle with cancer. He was 68. <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>, owner of the <ORGANIZATION> Baltimore </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Orioles </ORGANIZATION> and former president and part owner of the <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Redskins </ORGANIZATION>, defended such figures as <PERSON> Jimmy </PERSON> <PERSON> Hoffa </PERSON>, <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Connally </PERSON>, <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Costello </PERSON>, <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Helms </PERSON>, <PERSON> Adam </PERSON> <PERSON> Clayton </PERSON> <PERSON> Powell </PERSON> and <PERSON> Bobby </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON>. <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>' customers also represented the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> _ he served two years as the party's treasurer _ and <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Motor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, and <ORGANIZATION> Gulf </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; Western. Born May 31, 1920, <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> won a scholarship at Holy Cross. He joined the <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> in World War II, but was medically discharged after the crash of a training plane and enrolled at <ORGANIZATION> Georgetown </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Law </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION>. `` I try to be guided by the ethics I was taught by the Jesuits,'' <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> once said. `` A trial is like a war.'' By his own account, <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> personally lost only one `` major'' case, the 1967 fraud and income tax evasion trial of <LOCATION> Baker </LOCATION>, an aide to <PERSON> Lyndon </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>. <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> went home with him, <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> said, and burst into tears.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>Elmo Zumwalt</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>FAYETTEVILLE, N.C. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Elmo </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Zumwalt </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>, son of the admiral who ordered the spraying of Agent Orange in <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> and who was exposed to the defoliant himself, died at his home Saturday from cancer. He was 42. <PERSON> Zumwalt </PERSON>, who served in <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> from June 1969 to August 1970 commanding a patrol boat, said he never blamed his father for his disease. The two co-wrote a book titled `` My Father, My Son,'' which was made into a television movie. Agent Orange contains highly toxic dioxin. Veterans had contended that exposure to it causes cancer and other illnesses. They said it caused miscarriages by wives of servicemen and birth defects in their children. <PERSON> Zumwalt </PERSON>'s son, <PERSON> Elmo </PERSON> <PERSON> Russell </PERSON> <PERSON> Zumwalt </PERSON> <PERSON> IV </PERSON>, suffers from a congenital dysfunction that confuses his physical senses. The elder <PERSON> Zumwalt </PERSON> said he ordered Agent Orange sprayed over the <ORGANIZATION> Mekong </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Delta </ORGANIZATION> to kill concealing vegetation. He commanded naval forces in <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> from 1968-1970, then served as Chief of Naval Operations until retiring in 1974.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>Otto Passman</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MONROE, La. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Otto </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Passman </PERSON>, whose 30 years in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> ended in an influence-peddling scandal involving Korean businessman <PERSON> Tongsun </PERSON> <PERSON> Park </PERSON>, died of a heart attack Saturday. He was 88. <PERSON> Passman </PERSON>, a successful businessman, was first elected to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> from northeastern <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION> in 1946. A conservative Democrat, he chaired the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Appropriations subcommittee on foreign operations from 1954 to 1976, the year he lost a bid for a 16th term. A <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> report said <PERSON> Passman </PERSON> was the largest beneficiary of cash payments from Park, who was accused of buying influence in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. The Times said <PERSON> Passman </PERSON> got $ 190,000 from Park. After leaving office, <PERSON> Passman </PERSON> was indicted on a variety of federal charges in 1978 but was acquitted.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>Ella Udall</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>McLEAN, Va. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Ella </PERSON> <PERSON> Royston </PERSON> <PERSON> Udall </PERSON>, 59, wife of Rep. <PERSON> Morris </PERSON> <PERSON> Udall </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Ariz </LOCATION>., was found dead in her garage Saturday from carbon monoxide poisoning A native of <LOCATION> Loudoun </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, Mrs. <PERSON> Udall </PERSON> had served as a staff assistant on a subcommittee of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Civil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> before her Dec. 1, 1968 marriage to the <LOCATION> Arizonia </LOCATION> congressman. Mrs. <PERSON> Udall </PERSON>, who frequently said she considered being a congressman's wife a full-time career, is survived by her son, <PERSON> Vincent </PERSON> <PERSON> Fabrizio </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, from a previous marriage, and <PERSON> Udall </PERSON>'s six children.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>James Gibson</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>HENDERSON, Nev. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 State Sen. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Gibson </PERSON>, a leading political figure and president of the rocket fuel plant demolished in earthquake-like blasts on May 4, died Saturday at his home following a bout with cancer. He was 63. <PERSON> Gibson </PERSON>, a Democrat, had served in the state legislature for more than 28 years. He had been diagnosed with cancer in November. <PERSON> Gibson </PERSON> and his brother, <PERSON> Fred </PERSON>, were officers in the <ORGANIZATION> Pacific </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Engineering </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Production </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, which ammonium perchlorate makes an oxidizer for solid rocket fuel used in the Space Shuttle and other advanced rocket boosters. The plant was flattened by a series of devastating explosions that killed two people and injured 326 others. The force blew out windows for miles around, and shook buildings in nearby <LOCATION> Las </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vegas </LOCATION>. A 1947 graudate of the <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Naval </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Gibson </PERSON> was a veteran of World War II and the Korean War. He held a master's degree in civil engineering from <ORGANIZATION> Rensselaer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Polytechnic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Troy </LOCATION>, N.Y.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880814-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-14-88 0059EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Obit-Gibson     08-14 0249</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Obit-Gibson,0259</SECOND>
<HEAD>Nevada State Senator Jim Gibson Dead at 63</HEAD>
<DATELINE>HENDERSON, Nev. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 State Sen. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Gibson </PERSON>, president of the rocket fuel plant demolished in earthquake-like blasts on May 4, died Saturday at his home following a bout with cancer. He was 63. <PERSON> Gibson </PERSON> and his brother, <PERSON> Fred </PERSON>, were officers in the <ORGANIZATION> Pacific </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Engineering </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Production </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, which makes an oxidizer for solid rocket fuel used in the space shuttle and other advanced rocket boosters. The plant was flattened by a series of devastating explosions that killed two people and injured 326 others. The force blew out windows for miles around, and shook buildings in nearby <LOCATION> Las </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vegas </LOCATION>. Plant officials came under fire from union leaders who cited numerous safety violations. Company officials have pledged to rebuild the factory in a less-populated area. <PERSON> Gibson </PERSON>, a Democrat who was completing his fifth term as senator, served in the state legislature for more than 28 years. He served in both the Assembly and the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>, where he had been both majority and minority leader. `` A legislative giant has been taken from us,'' Gov. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Bryan </PERSON> said Saturday night. `` No man enjoyed greater respect from his legislative colleagues for more than a quarter of a century. He was a commanding legislative presence.'' <PERSON> Gibson </PERSON>'s cancer was diagnosed in November. A 1947 graduate of the <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Naval </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Gibson </PERSON> was a veteran of World War II and the Korean War. <PERSON> Gibson </PERSON> is survived by his wife, <PERSON> Audrey </PERSON>, two sons and four daughters.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880814-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-14-88 0117EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-HoboRoyalty     08-14 0124</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Hobo Royalty,0126</SECOND>
<HEAD>`Fishbones' Is New Hobo King, `Would-Be-Hobo' Is Queen</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BRITT, Iowa (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Irving </PERSON> `` Fishbones'' <PERSON> Stevens </PERSON>, 79, a <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION> resident who says he's been hopping trains since the 1930s, was crowned king of the hobos at the annual International Hobo Festival. <PERSON> Lynne </PERSON> `` Would-Be-Hobo'' Vermace of <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> was selected queen. A large crowd elected the pair Saturday by its applause at the festivities along local railroad tracks. They will hold the titles until next year's gathering. Fishbones, said he has been to six conventions, but that this was the first time he sought the crown. He said he had published a collection of poems and stories on his days on the rails and earned his title after reciting a nostalgic ballad.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880814-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-14-88 0131EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-BRF-DetroitNewspapers     08-14 0142</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF-Detroit Newspapers,0144</SECOND>
<HEAD>Detroit Newspapers Raise Prices 5 Cents</HEAD>
<DATELINE>DETROIT (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The price of <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION>'s two daily newspapers, whose separate business and circulation departments are in the process of becoming one, will each go up 5 cents, the <ORGANIZATION> Detroit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Free </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> announced Sunday. The newsstand price of the Free Press will increase to 25 cents from 20 cents, and <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Detroit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> will increase to 20 cents from 15 cents in six counties near <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION> and to 25 from 20 cents elsewhere. The increases go into effect Friday. Increases had been expected after the decision by Attorney General <PERSON> Edwin </PERSON> <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON> earlier this week to approve a joint operating agreement between the two papers. The price of the combined weekend editions will be 25 cents on Saturdays and $ 1 on Sunday. The first weekend of combined editions is Aug. 20-21.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880814-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-14-88 0202EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-BRF-PlaneCrash     08-14 0155</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF-Plane Crash,0160</SECOND>
<HEAD>Plane Lands Between Ohio Interstates</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MONTGOMERY, Ohio (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A single-engine plane made an emergency landing between two freeways in the <LOCATION> Cincinnati </LOCATION> area injuring the pilot and his passenger and snarling traffic for hours. The plane clipped a guardrail, flipped and landed on its top in a grassy area Saturday night after encountering engine trouble, <ORGANIZATION> Sycamore-Montgomery </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Life </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Squad </ORGANIZATION> Chief <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Buehler </PERSON> said. `` He was looking for a dark area to land in so he would n't have to land on the interstate, instead he landed in a ravine between them,'' <PERSON> Buehler </PERSON> said. Pilot <PERSON> Harvey </PERSON> <PERSON> Reis </PERSON>, 52, and passenger <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Beck </PERSON>, 37, were taken to <LOCATION> Bethseda </LOCATION> <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Beck </PERSON> was in good condition, but <PERSON> Reis </PERSON> was still being evaluated early Sunday morning, spokeswoman <PERSON> Joyce </PERSON> <PERSON> Miller </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Buehler </PERSON> said there were no other injuries. He said traffic was very heavy at the time of the accident and it remained snarled for about three hours.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880814-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-14-88 0217EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Israel 1stLd-Writethru a0567 08-14 0600</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Israel, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0567,0614</SECOND>
<HEAD>Israeli Troops Kill Two, Wound Nine</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Leads with 9 grafs to UPDATE with additional fatality. Pickup
9th graf pvs ``A clash...''</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By DAN IZENBERG</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>JERUSALEM (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Israeli troops fatally shot two Palestinians and wounded nine Saturday in stone-throwing incidents in the occupied <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strip </LOCATION>, the army and hospital officials said. The latest confrontation was Saturday night in a refugee camp near the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> town of <LOCATION> Jenin </LOCATION>, where 18-year-old <PERSON> Yussef </PERSON> <PERSON> Mohammed </PERSON> <PERSON> Damaj </PERSON> died of a gunshot wound to the chest, the <ORGANIZATION> Haaretz </ORGANIZATION> daily said. Soldiers opened fire as youths hurled rocks at the troops in a clash that lasted several hours, the newspaper said. The army confirmed that a dead Palestinian was brought to a nearby hospital after a clash at the camp, but a spokesman said soldiers were investigating the cause of death. <PERSON> Damaj </PERSON>'s death raised to 242 the number of Palestinians killed since the uprising in Israeli-occupied territories began Dec. 8. Four Israelis have also died. Another Palestinian, 52-year-old <PERSON> Mohammed </PERSON> <PERSON> Eid </PERSON> <PERSON> Abu </PERSON> <PERSON> Rizak </PERSON>, was shot and killed earlier Saturday in the <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> town of <LOCATION> Rafah </LOCATION> on the Egyptian border, where Arabs hurled stones at troops during a protest, hospital officials said. The <LOCATION> Rafah </LOCATION> demonstration was to protest the deaths of two Arab workers in a fire last week at a construction site near <LOCATION> Tel </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Aviv </LOCATION>, hospital officials said. Police have said the fire appeared to be the work of arsonists but have refused to elaborate. The army confirmed the death in <LOCATION> Rafah </LOCATION> Saturday, saying troops opened fire with live ammunition after trying to quell stone-throwing protests by shooting tear gas and rubber bullets. Officials at Nasser hospital said a 15-year-old girl was among the wounded. A clash also broke out at <LOCATION> Nasser </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION> when protesters gathered outside and began stoning troops, who responded with gunfire. Five Palestinians were shot in the legs, hospital officials said. The army said it had no reports of casualties. The army slapped curfews on four neighborhoods of <LOCATION> Rafah </LOCATION>, located at the southern tip of the seaside <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strip </LOCATION> on the Egyptian border. Soldiers also opened fire at protesters in the <LOCATION> Tulkarm </LOCATION> refugee camp in the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION>, wounding an 18-year-old in the leg, an official at <LOCATION> Al </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ittihad </LOCATION> hospital in <LOCATION> Nablus </LOCATION> said. The army said it was investigating the report. In <LOCATION> Hebron </LOCATION>, 15 masked youths smashed every window in the three-story town hall, <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> television reported. The attack was a seen as a protest against Palestinians cooperating with the military government, the television said. In <LOCATION> Beitin </LOCATION>, an Arab alleged to have collaborated with Israeli authoriies started firing at an outlawed Palestinian flag hanging from a telephone pole, officials at the <ORGANIZATION> Rafidiyeh </ORGANIZATION> and Ittihad hospitals said. When villagers rushed at the man, he turned his fire on them, wounding three, the officials said. An Arab reporter identified the alleged collaborator as <PERSON> Sadek </PERSON> <PERSON> Bele </PERSON> from the village of <LOCATION> Funduq </LOCATION>, near <LOCATION> Nablus </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> radio said he was a land dealer who was stoned by local villagers when he came to <PERSON> Beitin </PERSON>. The man fled after opening fire, the radio said. The army had no comment on the incident and police spokesman <PERSON> Yosef </PERSON> <PERSON> Fares </PERSON> said he was not authorized to discuss it. In another development, three <PERSON> Arab </PERSON> garbage collectors were severely beaten by Jewish assailants while they worked in the <LOCATION> Tel </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Aviv </LOCATION> suburb of <PERSON> Givat </PERSON> <PERSON> Shmuel </PERSON>, the Israeli-owned <ORGANIZATION> Itim </ORGANIZATION> news agency reported. The assailants also attacked the Arabs' Jewish employer who rushed to the aid of his workers and smashed the windows of his truck, <ORGANIZATION> Itim </ORGANIZATION> said, adding that the attack was unprovoked.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880814-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-14-88 0338EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i BC-Philippines-Massacre     08-14 0159</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Philippines-Massacre,0164</SECOND>
<HEAD>14 People Hacked To Death In Central Philippines</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MANILA, Philippines (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Machete-wielding men hacked to death 14 villagers, including three children, outside the central Philippine city of <LOCATION> Tacloban </LOCATION> over a personal grudge, police said Sunday. Maj. <PERSON> Gabriel </PERSON> <PERSON> Bardillon </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Tacloban </LOCATION> police chief, said only five children survived the attack which occured shortly after midnight Saturday in the mountainous village of <LOCATION> Cabalawan </LOCATION>, some 360 miles southeast of <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION>. He told The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> in a telephone interview from <LOCATION> Tacloban </LOCATION> that six assailants, some of them wearing masks, attacked two families that lived in three shanties along an isolated and abandoned golf course in <LOCATION> Cabalawan </LOCATION>. Maj. <PERSON> Bardillon </PERSON> said the killers' motive was apparently revenge, adding that one of the survivors identified three of the killers as enemies of some of the victims. He refused to elaborate. Police are still scouring the forests around the village for the attackers who fled after the massacre, the police officer said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880814-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-14-88 0512EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i BC-SouthKorea-Protests     08-14 0279</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-South Korea-Protests,0288</SECOND>
<BYLINE>Students Clash With Police, Citizens Protest
^By PAUL SHIN
^Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SEOUL, South Korea (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Radical students demanding unification with <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> battled riot police with firebombs and rocks Sunday. Angry residents demonstrated to demand an end to the violence. Protesters staged several attacks with firebombs to try and push back thousands of police surrounding <ORGANIZATION> Yonsei </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> in the west of <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION>. Troopers in green combat fatigues and black, visored helmets fired volleys of tear gas and hurled rocks to drive students back in the third day of clashes at the school. `` Advance nation unification'' and `` <ORGANIZATION> Yankees </ORGANIZATION> go home,'' students chanted. Students tried to stage a number of demonstrations in downtown <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION>, but the handfuls of protesters who showed up were dispersed quickly by hundreds of riot police. Angry residents and shopkeepers staged several counter-protests to demand students stop violent demonstrations. Some onlookers and passersby heckled student demonstrations. Some 3,000 students were at <LOCATION> Yonsei </LOCATION> to prepare for a march Monday to the border truce village of <LOCATION> Panmunjom </LOCATION> for talks with North Korean student delegates on reuniting the divided <LOCATION> Korean </LOCATION> peninsula. The government banned the march and the students have virtually no chance of getting past the heavy police cordon blocking them. A similar attempt to march to the border June 10 was blocked by riot police and turnouts at the latest protests have been smaller. About 42,000 <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> troops are in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> under a treaty and students contend <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> backs military rule in the country. The peninsula has been divided since 1945 at the end of World War II. <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> invaded the south in 1950 to start the Korean War.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880814-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-14-88 0648EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i BC-Germany-TrainCrash     08-14 0141</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Germany-Train Crash,0146</SECOND>
<HEAD>Train Collision Injures More Than 100 People</HEAD>
<DATELINE>AUGSBURG, West Germany (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Four train cars filled with passengers rammed into a train at the <LOCATION> Augsburg </LOCATION> rail station early Sunday, injuring more than 100 people, police and radio reports said. The accident occurred after the passenger cars were decoupled from a locomotive and accidentally rammed into the train they were to link up with, said <LOCATION> Augsburg </LOCATION> police. <LOCATION> Augsburg </LOCATION> police spokesman <PERSON> Dieter </PERSON> <PERSON> Kuehle </PERSON> said 25 people were treated at local hospitals. Three people were still in a hospital but their injuries were not life-threatening, <PERSON> Kuehle </PERSON> said. German radio stations reported that more than 100 people were injured. <PERSON> Kuehle </PERSON> said the accident was under investigation. There was no immediate word on the extent of damage to the passenger cars or to the train they were to link up with.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880814-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-14-88 1131EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-BRF--LostMoney     08-14 0160</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Lost Money,0164</SECOND>
<HEAD>Four Claim $10,000 Left At Airport</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PITTSBURGH (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A <ORGANIZATION> USAir </ORGANIZATION> baggage handler who found $ 10,000 in a bag at <ORGANIZATION> Greater </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pittsburgh </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airport </ORGANIZATION> may end up with the loot if the owner is n't found, police say. At least four people staked a claim for the cash, which was found Aug. 5, they have been unable to convince police they are the rightful owner. `` They've been people who honestly believed the money could be theirs,'' said <LOCATION> Allegheny </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> Police Sgt. <PERSON> Diane </PERSON> <PERSON> Pilkington </PERSON>. `` But they were grasping at straws.'' The claimants reported either losing large sums of money or having cash stolen recently. Police ask those who try to claim the money to describe the bills in terms of denominations and, if possible, serial numbers. They also ask them to pinpoint where the cash was lost and how it was packaged. It was unclear when police would call off their search for the owner of the money.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880814-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-14-88 1132EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-GamblingMemories     08-14 0656</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Gambling Memories,0674</SECOND>
<HEAD>In Recent Past, When Gambling Was Illegal ... But Was Taxed Anyway</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By SCOTT CHARTON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>HOT SPRINGS, Ark. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Not very long ago, this resort spa's illegal gambling was hotter than its much-touted healing spring water, so much so that local government winked and even reaped tax revenue rather than stop it Throngs of tourists and townspeople took chances, in violation of state law, on at least 350 slot machines, card games, bingo and bookmaking. Police looked the other way, except to collect the municipal `` amusement'' tax, until 1967, when a state crackdown during the administration of the late Gov. <PERSON> Winthrop </PERSON> <PERSON> Rockefeller </PERSON> scrapped tons of betting devices. `` It was probably the only illegal tax in this country collected by a city,'' recalls state Sen. <PERSON> Eugene </PERSON> `` Bud'' <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>, who was <LOCATION> Garland </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> sheriff in 1967 but was n't invited to join state agents who raided the casinos. `` They built a city auditorium, where the <ORGANIZATION> Miss </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Arkansas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pageant </ORGANIZATION> is held _ a beautiful place _ and a city hall, and the main firehouse downtown, all on an illegal tax,'' he says. Dusty tax records show the city levied $ 10 monthly for each slot machine. The Baxter Hotel, <PERSON> Butler </PERSON>'s Barbecue, <ORGANIZATION> Harlem </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chicken </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Shack </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Eatmore </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cafe </ORGANIZATION> had one slot each. More adventurous were the J.D. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> Fish Market, <ORGANIZATION> VFW </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Club </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Hot </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Springs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Country </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Club </ORGANIZATION>, with two slots apiece. The best bet at Coy's <ORGANIZATION> Steak </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> these days might be the fork-tender prime cuts, but in 1967 diners waiting for a table could play eight slot machines. Tax rates ran $ 100 a month for bingo and cards, $ 500 for large casinos _ those with more than five gaming tables _ and $ 300 for small casinos. The casinos included places like the <ORGANIZATION> Ohio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Club </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Club </ORGANIZATION> and The Vapors. Tax rates were raised in 1964, but the <ORGANIZATION> Elks </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Club </ORGANIZATION> refused to pay the difference. Records show club officials sent payments on their five slots at the old rate until the state raids in early fall 1967. `` The cornerstone of public morality is respect for the law,'' <ORGANIZATION> Rockefeller </ORGANIZATION> declared that year in hiring former <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> agent <PERSON> Lynn </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> to be state police chief. <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> says he told <ORGANIZATION> Rockefeller </ORGANIZATION> he wanted to concentrate on law enforcement, not politics, and specifically on closing casinos. He says <PERSON> Rockefeller </PERSON> `` slapped his knee and said ` That's exactly what I want.''' Early on Aug. 17, 1967, <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> and about two dozen officers converged on the downtown <ORGANIZATION> Bridge </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Street </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Club </ORGANIZATION>. It was after normal business hours and the door was locked. The owner was summoned, according to newspaper accounts. When he did n't show after an hour, <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> broke a glass panel in the door with a tire iron, in front of photographers, and troopers knocked in the door Two days later, the <ORGANIZATION> Arkansas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Gazette </ORGANIZATION> editorialized: `` <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> has given the state the most convincing demonstration yet of how the state can break the back of the notorious <LOCATION> Hot </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Springs </LOCATION> gambling operation, which has been a scandal of historic, but nonetheless disgraceful dimension ... he was following his responsibility to the law where local enforcement had defaulted.'' <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> cried foul. `` I'm really incensed,'' the sheriff told reporters. He complained about the lack of notice to local lawmen, `` especially those who have to be elected and must answer to the people.'' <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> responded 21 years later: `` The <ORGANIZATION> Bridge </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Street </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Club </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Ohio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Club </ORGANIZATION> and all of the other clubs could be found by tourists who went to <LOCATION> Hot </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Springs </LOCATION>. They could have been found by a blind man. And if the sheriff did n't know they were there, then I was afraid to take him with me on a raid.'' <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> attributes the friction to politics. `` You had a brand-new Republican governor, and you had a brand-new Democratic sheriff,'' he says. Proposals to legalize casino gambling fell twice to voter rejection, in 1964 and in 1984, and once to <ORGANIZATION> Rockefeller </ORGANIZATION>'s veto, in 1967.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880814-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-14-88 1133EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM_BabyParts Bjt   08-14 0813</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM_Baby Parts, Bjt,820</SECOND>
<HEAD>Infant Slaughter-Organ Transplant Rumors Frustrate Officials</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RUTH SINAI</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials are frustrated by persistent reports _ some blamed on <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> disinformation _ that <LOCATION> Latin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> children are being butchered for organ transplants in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. The reports have been crisscrossing the globe for the past 20 months, confounding <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials who have been trying to locate their genesis, track their progress and provide credible denials. The latest report surfaced last week in <LOCATION> Paraguay </LOCATION>, after police raided a house and found seven infants and several pregnant women who apparently planned to give their babies up for adoption. A juvenile judge, <PERSON> Angel </PERSON> <PERSON> Campos </PERSON>, said that while he had no proof, he believed some of the babies might be dismembered in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> for their organs, which could then be sold for hundreds of dollars. The story, circulated by a respected news agency, has been making the rounds of the world press this week despite adamant denials from the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Embassy in <LOCATION> Asuncion </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Information </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> has concluded that all the reports are based on unsubstantiated rumors which began in <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION>. Its yearlong investigation _ aided by the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Human </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> and other agencies _ has failed to find any proof of the charges. `` The original misinformation would not have spread so far and wide if it had not been for the way it was cynically used and embellished with deliberate distortions in a disinformation campaign by several communist countries, with the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> taking the lead,'' according to a report on Soviet disinformation prepared by <ORGANIZATION> USIA </ORGANIZATION> for <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Network </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organ </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sharing </ORGANIZATION>, which oversees organ transplants in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, has also denied the charges. `` It's very frustrating when you do n't know who's spreading such rumors,'' said <PERSON> Kelle </PERSON> <PERSON> Straw </PERSON>, a spokeswoman for the non-profit organization, which receives some of its funds from the government. Ms. <PERSON> Straw </PERSON> said the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Network </ORGANIZATION> had never found any leads to follow in its own investigation of the reports. `` And anyway, it's ridiculous,'' she said. `` Children do n't make good donors; their organs are n't fully developed.'' In its report to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Information </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> cited dozens of other such reports which have surfaced in places as diverse as <LOCATION> Bangladesh </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Morocco </LOCATION>, some in <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> newspapers and others in independent publications. `` The rumor is gruesome enough so that it would feed on itself without any help,'' said <PERSON> Todd </PERSON> <PERSON> Leventhal </PERSON>, an agency official who prepared the report and has been monitoring the `` baby parts'' case as it is known in the government. `` But because the Soviets are involved, we're seeing more of these reports and with more of an anti-American slant,'' he added. <LOCATION> Latin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, where thousands of babies are adopted by foreigners every year, is a fertile ground for breeding such rumors. In its report to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> USIA </ORGANIZATION> concluded it is sometimes hard to tell which of the baby parts allegations are `` due to misinformation and which is due to disinformation.'' But <PERSON> Leventhal </PERSON> said disinformation experts in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> can tell whether the Soviets are behind a certain report according to the newspapers carrying such a story and the slant that it takes. In some cases, the Soviet role is quite obvious, he said. On July 25, 1987, the official Soviet newspaper <ORGANIZATION> Izvestia </ORGANIZATION> reported that an international <ORGANIZATION> Mafia </ORGANIZATION> brings up disabled children in <LOCATION> Guatemala </LOCATION> and sends them to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. `` There, the butcher medics cut out their hearts, kidneys and eyes,'' the <ORGANIZATION> Izvestia </ORGANIZATION> report said. The newspaper cited officials of the Geneva-based <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> for Children, <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION>, as the source of its information. The organization accused Izvestia of turning out `` a veritable masterpiece: an astute mix of quotes taken out of context, journalistic comment, established fact and unfounded allegations.'' The course of the baby parts story constitutes a fascinating study in the life of a rumor. The <ORGANIZATION> USIA </ORGANIZATION> has traced the original report to <PERSON> Leonardo </PERSON> <PERSON> Villeda </PERSON> <PERSON> Bermudez </PERSON>, formerly <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION>' top social welfare official. <PERSON> Bermudez </PERSON> was quoted as saying in January 1987 that he was told by some social workers several years previously about people seeking to adopt disabled children so they could sell them `` for parts'' in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. His comments were circulated worldwide by a respected news agency, lending them sufficient credibility and exposure so that they have been cited repeatedly since then despite his retraction the day after his remarks were reported. In his retraction, <PERSON> Bermudez </PERSON> said `` he confused a simple rumor'' with facts. Other Honduran officials denied there was any proof of such practices. But more than a year later, his comments were still circulating, and were quoted _ among other places _ in the Venezuelan newspaper <ORGANIZATION> El </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nacional </ORGANIZATION>. `` It just wo n't die. Just when we think we've managed to get rid of it, it pops up again,'' said <PERSON> Leventhal </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880814-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-14-88 1136EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-SouthernTacky Bjt   08-14 0617</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Southern Tacky, Bjt,0637</SECOND>
<HEAD>Professor Collects Tacky Items Of The South</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KATHY EYRE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>OXFORD, Miss. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 From tiny vials of `` <PERSON> Elvis </PERSON> <PERSON> Presley </PERSON>'s sweat'' to plans to bury <PERSON> Hank </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>' in the toe of a huge cowboy boot, some Southerners ai n't been whittling Dixie's icons from slabs of good taste, a trained observer says The greater the fame of the heroes, the more apt you are to find tacky items and stories twisting up around their memory like tendrils of the kudzu vine, said <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON>, a professor of history and Southern studies at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mississippi </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON>, a native Texan, has become a self-appointed keeper of what he calls the `` Southern Tacky Collection.'' Many people would say his campus office is cluttered with junk, but he views it as a display of `` material artifacts'' dating to 1950. `` This is sort of the wall of Southern culture. All sorts of posters with post cards, pictures, images of the South. Post cards often portray these icons of the <LOCATION> South </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> said, motioning to hundreds of cards papering his office wall and sitting in stacks on his desk. `` This one is my all-time favorite. ... It has a small vial of <PERSON> Elvis </PERSON>' sweat. ` The King lives. His perspiration will be your inspiration,' it says. `` Here's Presley's Cadillac. This is a real icon. There's all kinds of stories about Presley driving around in his Cadillac. He gave Cadillacs as gifts.'' Though prized, nothing in <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON>'s collection is priceless. Rather, they are generally cheap. `` These are not necessarily things that stand out for uniqueness but things that are representative,'' he said. `` They are such simple items; they're not the kind of things anybody saves.'' Every region has its mass-produced tacky items, but <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> contends some pieces are `` uniquely Southern.'' `` A lot of the things I collect are symbols,'' he said. `` A cotton bale for example. In <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> if you go to <PERSON> Stuckey </PERSON>'s or various stores they sell little cotton bales as souvenirs as a symbol of the South. That's marketing a symbol of the South.'' Other miscellaneous tacky stuff in the collection ranges from pop-up cardboard antebellum homes to a stuffed armadillo and plastic cows that moo when their heads are twisted. A big category in his collection is fans, primarily stamped with images of a happy family or pastoral theme. <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> said funeral homes most often produced and gave away the fans, which were used extensively before air-conditioning. Another favorite item is an inexpensive clock with wooden extensions on the sides. Photographs, apparently torn from magazines, of <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Luther </PERSON> <PERSON> King </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> and his wife, Coretta, and President <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> and Sen. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> are glued on each side. `` It looks almost like an icon in a Catholic church in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> or something, with wooden panels and then the Saints,'' <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> said. His collection also includes advertisements and wrappers from Southern sweets like <ORGANIZATION> Goo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Goo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Clusters </ORGANIZATION> and Moon Pies. Another facet of his work examines Southern `` yard art'' like plastic pink flamingos. `` Exactly when and how it developed, I'm still trying to find out But you do n't find this in places other than the South,'' he said. <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> also collects tacky tales of the modern South. His favorite is a proposal by some members of the <LOCATION> Montgomery </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ala. </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>, shortly after the death of country singer <PERSON> Hank </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> in 1953, to construct a monument to him in the shape of a cowboy boot. `` It was going to be a huge, towering monument with his body buried in the toe part,'' <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> chuckled. `` It was a pretty wild idea all right. The <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Montgomery </LOCATION> actually debated it.'' The idea eventually was tossed out.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880814-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-14-88 1138EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Philippines     08-14 0404</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Philippines,0425</SECOND>
<HEAD>Communists Release Officers, 14 Villagers Hacked To Death</HEAD>
<BYLINE>With AM-Marcos, Bjt
^By MIGUEL C. SUAREZ</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MAMALA, Philippines (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Communist guerrillas released four army officers and an enlisted man in this coconut farming village Sunday after holding them hostage in the mountains for more than two months. In another development, machete-wielding assailants hacked to death 14 villagers, including three children, near the central city of <LOCATION> Tacloban </LOCATION>, police said. <PERSON> Gregorio </PERSON> <PERSON> Rosal </PERSON>, spokesman for the communist <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>, unlocked the chains from the five prisoners' wrists in front of 170 journalists, relatives and officials waiting near a coconut grove. On June 1, the rebels captured Lts. <PERSON> Abraham </PERSON> <PERSON> Casis </PERSON>, <PERSON> Oscar </PERSON> <PERSON> Singson </PERSON>, <PERSON> Clarito </PERSON> <PERSON> Santos </PERSON> and <LOCATION> Rommel </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salamanca </LOCATION> and constabulatory Sgt. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Jacob </PERSON> in this village about 70 miles southeast of <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Quezon </LOCATION> province. The five men, dressed in civilian clothes, were driving toward <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION> when they were abducted by rebels they thought were government troops, according to Col. <PERSON> Hernani </PERSON> <PERSON> Figueroa </PERSON>, a military spokesman. Rebels often wear uniforms similar to army fatigues. The military and the rebels agreed to a temporary cease-fire that ends at noon Tuesday. Provincial officials in <LOCATION> Quezon </LOCATION> assured the rebels they will not force people to join government paramilitary units. Authorities also agreed to create a committee to investigate alleged human rights abuses by government soldiers and to pay damages to victims. Twelve suspected communists, including a 71-year-old woman, were arrested in a raid in <LOCATION> Kilawis </LOCATION> village on the outskirts of <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION>, according to Sgt. <PERSON> Romeo </PERSON> <PERSON> Artajos </PERSON>. Firearms and documents were seized along with the suspects, who were accused of recruiting members for the communist insurgency, <PERSON> Artajos </PERSON> said. The official <ORGANIZATION> Philippine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> said the military on the central island of <LOCATION> Negros </LOCATION> detained five suspected rebels in connection with the slaying of an Australian businessmen in the province on Monday. The police chief in <LOCATION> Tacloban </LOCATION>, Maj. <PERSON> Gabriel </PERSON> <PERSON> Bardillon </PERSON>, said six assailants, some wearing masks, attacked members of two families living in shanties along an abandoned golf course in the village of <LOCATION> Cabalawan </LOCATION>, about 350 miles southeast of <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION>. Maj. <PERSON> Bardillon </PERSON> said only five children survived the massacre shortly after midnight Saturday and that police were searching for the attackers in the forests around the village. He said the motive for the attack apparently was revenge over a personal grudge and that one of the survivors identified three of the killers as enemies of some of the victims.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880814-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-14-88 1139EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-BRF--Bees-Collision     08-14 0126</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Bees-Collision,0128</SECOND>
<HEAD>15 Killed In Bus-Truck Crash In Turkey</HEAD>
<DATELINE>DENIZLI, Turkey (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A bus collided head-on with a truck carrying beehives, and 15 people were reported killed and 24 injured. A news agency said bees escaping from the damaged truck hampered the rescue effort. The accident occurred near <LOCATION> Gurlek </LOCATION> village when the bus rammed the back of one truck, then collided head-on with the truck loaded with bees, the semi-official <ORGANIZATION> Anatolia </ORGANIZATION> news agency said. It said 10 people died at the scene and that five at <LOCATION> Denizli </LOCATION> state hospital. Of the 24 injured people, 13 were hurt seriously, the agency said. The bees coming out of the shattered hives slowed the rescue operation, and the <LOCATION> Denizli-Afyon </LOCATION> highway was closed to traffic for 2 -LCB- hours.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880814-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-14-88 1139EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-BRF-ChildSwapping     08-14 0190</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF-Child Swapping,0194</SECOND>
<HEAD>Family Tries To Give Away Daughter To Compensate For Slaying</HEAD>
<DATELINE>HARARE, Zimbabwe (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A family tried to compensate the relatives of a man who was killed by turning over money, livestock and their 6-year-old daughter, but police intervened to stop the deal, it was reported Sunday. The compensation agreement was made between two families living near the town of <LOCATION> Murehwa </LOCATION>, 50 miles northeast of <LOCATION> Harare </LOCATION>, the Sunday Mail said. The newspaper said police ordered the family blamed for the slaying of villager <PERSON> Cyprian </PERSON> <PERSON> Nhamburo </PERSON> to exclude the child from the compensation deal. Nhamburo's relatives also demanded $ 1,620, 11 cattle and three goats from the family of a man they allege killed Nhamburo two weeks ago, the Sunday Mail said. That part of the deal was allowed. In <LOCATION> Zimbabwe </LOCATION>, relatives often claim compensation for family deaths, but this was the first reported case involving a child in the transaction. The <ORGANIZATION> Zimbabwe </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Child </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION> condemned the deal as `` tantamount to slave trading'' and said it would take legal action to ban tribal practices it said `` reduce a human being to the level of a commodity exchange.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880814-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-14-88 1139EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-BRF--Italy-Kidnap     08-14 0193</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Italy-Kidnap,0199</SECOND>
<HEAD>Pharmacist Kidnapped in Sardinia</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NUORO, Sardinia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A pharmacist was kidnapped by three masked gunmen as he was driving home early Sunday with a girlfriend, police said. <PERSON> Michelangelo </PERSON> <PERSON> Mundula </PERSON>, 27, who works in his father's pharmacy in <LOCATION> Dorgali </LOCATION> near <LOCATION> Nuoro </LOCATION> on <LOCATION> Sardinia </LOCATION>'s northeast coast, was abducted shortly after midnight by two men with pistols and a third man armed with an automatic rifle. Police said the men forced <PERSON> Mundula </PERSON> and his girlfriend out of the car, tied them up and then drove off with the two in the backseat. The kidnappers abandoned the car, with the woman still inside, a few miles away and fled on foot into the hills with <PERSON> Mundula </PERSON>. The woman managed to free herself a few hours later and alerted police. It was the latest in a series of kidnappings in <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>. Last week, the kidnappers of Roman builder <PERSON> Giulio </PERSON> <PERSON> De </PERSON> <PERSON> Angelis </PERSON> sent a piece of the hostage's ear to his family along with a ransom demand of $ 2.5 million. <PERSON> De </PERSON> <PERSON> Angelis </PERSON> was kidnapped June 12 from his home in <LOCATION> Porto </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Cervo </LOCATION> on <LOCATION> Sardinia </LOCATION>'s exclusive <LOCATION> Costa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Smeralda </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Sardinia </LOCATION> is an Italian island south of <LOCATION> Corsica </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880814-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-14-88 1142EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p AM-CVN--VeepSuspense Bjt   08-14 0825</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-CVN--Veep Suspense, Bjt,820</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush Plays the Veep Gambit for Suspense and Ratings</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP News Analysis</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By WALTER R. MEARS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Special Correspondent</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW ORLEANS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> is playing the vice president gambit for everything it's worth, which is n't very much. But then, it's the only bit of show business available this week at the Republican National Convention. His orchestrated surprise will be good theater for a few hours in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION>. And, obviously, the Republican presidential nominee's choice of a running mate is a crucial decision in the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> bid to keep the White House. But nobody is going to remember the theatrics once they are done. The <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> plan is to announce the selection on Thursday morning, with tight secrecy until then. Campaign manager <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Atwater </PERSON> said there'll be `` as much drama as we can have,'' the better to boost interest and television ratings. `` I'm for doing anything that will help build up a TV audience,'' <PERSON> Atwater </PERSON> said. `` There wo n't be any leaks of this one because I'm not gon na tell a soul,'' said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. Some souls may think there are clues, however. Take Gov. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION>, who telephoned <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> on Friday and asked not be considered for second spot on the ticket. Such requests often come from people who figure they are n't going to be chosen anyhow Having been there, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> knows the way the game is played. For <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, there was a hotel suite across the street from the <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION> convention hall in which President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> was nominated in 1980. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, a defeated rival for the <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> nomination that year, waited out a very long night of speculation that former President <PERSON> Gerald </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Ford </PERSON> would be the vice presidential nominee on the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> ticket. It was going on midnight when that deal fell apart, and <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> turned to <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. A quick telephone call, a quick acceptance, a joint appearance before the convention to quell the chaos and introduce the running mate. Now it is <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s turn to issue the summons. His presidential nomination is set, the vice presidency is the only unfilled role. Actually, what he is doing is choosing his candidate the old-fashioned way. Until relatively recent conventions, presidential nominees observed strict vows of silence on the vice presidency until after their own nominations. Advance discussion was presumptuous, gauche. On Wednesday night of convention week, after the roll call that delivered the nomination, the presidential nominee would summon his high command into late-night session to settle on No. 2. Prospects would come and go from the candidate's suite. In 1964, President <PERSON> Lyndon </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> chose Sen. <PERSON> Hubert </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Humphrey </PERSON> for his ticket, but summoned <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION> Sen. <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Dodd </PERSON>, too, just to keep people guessing. Latter-day candidates have taken to listing prospects in advance and, in some cases, to conducting pre-convention job interviews. They send out questionnaires, they look at fitness reports. That practice took on some urgency after the 1972 Democratic convention, at which nominee <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> McGovern </PERSON> chose Sen. <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Eagleton </PERSON> to run with him, and learned after the fact that <PERSON> Eagleton </PERSON> had been hospitalized for nervous exhaustion and fatigue, and had undergone electric shock treatments. <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Sargent </PERSON> <PERSON> Shriver </PERSON> replaced him on the ticket, which went down in flames, and presidential nominees have tended to conduct more thorough advance checks on prospective running mates ever since. In 1976, <PERSON> Jimmy </PERSON> <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> interviewed seven prospects, then chose <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Mondale </PERSON> for vice president. When his turn came, <PERSON> Mondale </PERSON> conducted a similar set of pre-convention auditions and chose Rep. <PERSON> Geraldine </PERSON> <PERSON> Ferraro </PERSON>. Democratic presidential nominee <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> interviewed a half-dozen prospects, then chose <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> Sen. <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> a week before the national convention that nominated that ticket in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>. In the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> selection game, a dozen names have floated into speculation encouraged by campaign stage managers. Two governors, <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> and Gov. <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Deukmejian </PERSON> of <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> said they do not want to be considered, as did Sens. <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> <PERSON> Kassebaum </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> and <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Armstrong </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION>. `` I would be a liability,'' protests Sen. <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> Simpson </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON> cited family concerns. He said he'd have to travel too much, and his wife could n't come because they have a 10-year-old in school. At face value, that would make him the first politician to shrink from seeking national office for want of a sitter. If they wo n't run, others will. Rep. <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> said he'd be glad to accept. Sen. <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION> said it would be an honor. Sen. <PERSON> Pete </PERSON> <PERSON> Domenici </PERSON> said he was n't too proud to campaign a little for it. <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> says he does n't want the job, but it would be arrogant to turn it down. Mark them down for honest men. The fact of the matter is that there are n't many Republican politicians who would say no if asked.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Mears </PERSON>, executive editor of The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>, has covered presidential politics since 1960.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880814-0025 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-14-88 1143EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-China-Superman     08-14 0609</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-China-Superman,0628</SECOND>
<HEAD>Superman And At Least Four Chinese Films Stopped</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN POMFRET</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A leading newspaper on Sunday criticized officials for banning `` Superman'' and at least four Chinese films that passed the censors and opened to packed movie houses. In a rare plea from the official press, the <ORGANIZATION> China </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Youth </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> called for measures to prevent such `` lawlessness.'' The report said `` Superman'' was one of at least five movies banned in the capital since 1985. It said unidentified officials decided the films were unfit for the masses. The officials had showings of `` Superman'' halted in early 1986 because they said the movie `` turned the world upside down'' and `` reversed the flow of time,'' according to the report. The officials did not want <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s `` youth to be inculcated with the film's impossible idealism,'' the report said. In the 1978 movie, <PERSON> Superman </PERSON> rescues <PERSON> Lois </PERSON> <PERSON> Lane </PERSON> from death in an earthquake by circling the earth at the speed of light and reversing time. Two of the other films that were banned in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>, `` The Fierce Battle in <LOCATION> Taierzhuang </LOCATION>'' and `` The Beach'' have won awards in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>. The controversial `` <LOCATION> Taierzhuang </LOCATION>'' depicts a battle between the Kuomintang, archrival to the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, and Japanese invaders in 1938. In the movie, the Kuomintang, who were forced out of <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> in 1949 and now occupy <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION>, are depicted as patriotic and even heroic, an image which clashes sharply with the one created by the Communist government. The report said that in April 1987 when `` <LOCATION> Taierzhuang </LOCATION>'' was playing across the nation, officials closed the film in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>. After eight months of agitation in the movie industry, the report said, the government let the film show in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>, but only for six months and no advertising was allowed. At the end of 1985, the report said, `` The Beach,'' a explicit love story, was suddenly pulled from <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> movie theaters even after official censors approved it. The paper said `` certain leaders thought the plot would have a bad affect on society.'' In the film, a woman is forced by her family into an arranged marriage. The scene of her wedding night portrays the tribulations of an unwilling bride in bed with her husband. The paper said that in many cases, the officials banning the films had no relation to the <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Culture </ORGANIZATION>, which is responsible for censorship. It did not say what department of government the officials were from. The report also said that since 1984 <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> has only allowed two copies each of popular martial arts movies to circulate in the capital's movie theaters, while other cities had 10 copies. `` This regulation might be a good one in order to limit the influence these movies have one young people,'' the paper said. `` But because there's no law to follow, who knows whether it's true. The report said banning movies after they have already been released has cost <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>'s theaters thousands of dollars. It also said officials who like unpopular movies have forced city film officials to order more copies of them, causing further losses. The report called for a law that would set clear regulations on the content of movies to counteract official capriciousness. A recent issue of Outlook magazine said officials at the Ministry of Culture are studying a proposed law setting censorship guidelines for movies. Among the topics being debated, the magazine said, is whether naked bodies or serious crimes should be depicted on <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s silver screen. The proposal would mark the first time since Communist <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> was established in 1949 that explicit standards have been set about what can and can not be included in a Chinese movie.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880814-0026 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-14-88 1150EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-PrinceofPork Bjt   08-14 0650</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Prince of Pork, Bjt,650</SECOND>
<HEAD>Flamboyant Congressman Ready for Retirement</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto WX8</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID FOX</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Rep. <PERSON> Kenneth </PERSON> <PERSON> J </PERSON>. <PERSON> Gray </PERSON>, a frizzy-haired, bow-tied magician who is retiring after 24 years in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, wants to be remembered as the Prince of Pork who brought billions in federal projects to his depressed district. But he's still trying to live down a reputation as the man who brought <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> Ray </PERSON> to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. `` It's a bum rap,'' <PERSON> Gray </PERSON> says of allegations that he had a personal relationship with <PERSON> Miss </PERSON> <PERSON> Ray </PERSON>, the `` I-can ` t-type'' secretary who claimed she was on a committee payroll only to provide sex for the chairman, then-Rep. <PERSON> Wayne </PERSON> <PERSON> Hays </PERSON> `` I hired her in 1972, fired her in'73 and she did n't even meet <PERSON> Wayne </PERSON> <PERSON> Hays </PERSON> until 1976,'' said <PERSON> Gray </PERSON>, an Illinois Democrat. `` I never had anything to do with <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> Ray </PERSON> personally. I'm no angel and do n't profess to be. People can say lots of things about me, and they do, but that's one thing I was not guilty of.'' <PERSON> Gray </PERSON>, 63, is guilty of wearing loud clothes, driving big cars and delivering by his own estimate about $ 7 billion worth of federal projects to his coal-mining district in southern <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION>. `` I've always been called the Prince of Pork, and I wear that label proudly,'' <PERSON> Gray </PERSON> said. `` It means we got 500 miles of Interstate highway, modern concrete roads, water and sewer and lights _ all things we needed in southern <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION>. We tried to build the infrastructure needed for local communities to pull themselves up by their bootstraps.'' Citing poor health, he announced last November that he will retire at year end after 12 terms that spanned 34 years. `` It was one of the most difficult decisions I've ever made,'' he said. `` To walk away from this kind of power, which gives you the vehicle to help other people, is a tremendously regretful situation.'' <PERSON> Gray </PERSON> has served on the <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Works </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> during his tenure and wields considerable clout through his seniority and friendship with the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> leadership, particularly with <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Speaker <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>. <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>, who often assigns <PERSON> Gray </PERSON> to preside over the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, cautions against judging <PERSON> Gray </PERSON> by his flamboyant dress and jocular nature. `` The more you know him,'' <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> says, `` the more convinced you become of his having a first-rate mind, a sincere purpose and the capacity to perform effectively.'' <PERSON> Gray </PERSON> said his retirement plans are sketchy at the moment. `` I've got a motor home, and I want to putter around the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and see a lot of places I have n't been,'' he said `` But who knows? I may get tired of it and want to get back into government. `` One thing is definite. I intend to become very active in feeding children and hungry people.'' A coal miner's son and amateur magician who spent his early years as a car dealer, airport operator and auctioneer, <PERSON> Gray </PERSON> became known for showmanship and his down-home style when he arrived in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. He often used magic tricks to illustrate his speeches, which he peppered with such folksy phrases as: `` When I meet somebody, I shake their hand twice'' and `` times are so bad down in southern <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> that the creeks are only running three days a week.'' <PERSON> Gray </PERSON> also developed an image that haunts him today: a reputation for flashy clothes, fancy cars and late-night parties. Velvet suits have given way to double-breasted sport coats and bow ties, and <PERSON> Gray </PERSON> describes his lifestyle as quiet today _ an impression shared by friends. `` It could be said we all mellow with age,'' said <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Minority Leader <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Michel </PERSON>, a Republican from <LOCATION> Peoria </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ill. </LOCATION> `` He is a different person, although <PERSON> Ken </PERSON> was always a very popular figure even during his early days.'' `` I'd like to be remembered for helping people with all those things,'' <PERSON> Gray </PERSON> said. `` But I'll be happy if they just remember me.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880814-0027 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-14-88 1157EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p AM-CVN--BushThemes     08-14 0559</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-CVN--Bush Themes,550</SECOND>
<HEAD>Laying Out the Bush Agenda Over Four Days</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TERENCE HUNT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW ORLEANS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Republicans are carefully orchestrating their convention to emphasize a different message each day for <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and insisting that their gathering will be issue-oriented and not `` a series of one-liners like you heard in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> himself says he ca n't guarantee that no one will `` take a swipe'' at Democratic rival <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, adding `` I ca n't control everybody. However, the vice president and his staff say the advice to convention speakers is to stay positive and focus on the issues. Each night of the four-day convention, opening Monday, will be devoted to broad themes, such as the successes of the Reagan-Bush years, the issues and ideas of <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and the differences between <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>. President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> will kick off the process with a prime-time address Monday night. The president will `` lay out the record of the last seven years, and there's not a better man in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> to do that than <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>,'' said campaign manager <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Atwater </PERSON>. `` The second night you will see a lot of comparative speeches, you will see comparative differences on quite a few vital issues,'' <PERSON> Atwater </PERSON> said. Among others, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Sununu </PERSON> will attempt to debunk what <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> calls the `` <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> miracle'' of economic recovery, while former presidential hopeful <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> will talk about values. `` The third and fourth nights will be devoted to two things: No. 1 pointing out <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s qualifications, pointing out what he has done with his life and why he is the best qualified man to be president and lastly, of course, Thursday night he will be front and center talking about where he wants to take country and what he believes in ... This will really be his first time in front of the <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> people front and center stage like this,'' <PERSON> Atwater </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s staff says there will be a clear distinction between the Republican convention and last month's Democratic convention in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Alixe </PERSON> <PERSON> Glen </PERSON>, a <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> campaign spokeswoman, said, `` It will be very issue-specific. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has said many times this is not going to be negative. `` It's not going to be a series of one-liners like you heard in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>,'' she said, referring to taunts that <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was `` born with a silver foot in his mouth'' and was `` a toothache of a man.'' Referring to the Democratic convention, she said, `` I think it was a little bit offensive to people watching it on television. People want to be informed on issues. It's not like tuning in -LRB- comedian -RRB- <PERSON> Joan </PERSON> <PERSON> Rivers </PERSON>.'' To underscore the daily message, <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> leaders will hold news conferences each day. Each news conference will feature two speakers, a political person such as <PERSON> Atwater </PERSON> and an issues expert prepared to deal in depth with a particular subject. To further cement the message, the campaign has assembled 10 caucus teams that, over the course of the week, will visit each of the 54 delegations. Each caucus team will include a member of <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s family, a Cabinet member, a campaign official, an elected official and a celebrity of some fashion. Ms. <PERSON> Glen </PERSON> described the overall operation as one that was `` blanketing the city. They're all hearing the same three messages'' of the Reagan-Bush record, the issues of <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and his differences with <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880814-0028 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-14-88 1201EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p AM-CVN--NewOrleansWelcome     08-14 0503</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-CVN--New Orleans Welcome,530</SECOND>
<HEAD>Vistors Get Rousing V.I.P. Welcome at New Orleans Airport</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARY FOSTER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW ORLEANS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
