<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880911-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-11-88 2343EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-NATO-ShipsCollide     09-11 0279</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-NATO-Ships Collide,0286</SECOND>
<HEAD>British And Canadian Ships Collide In NATO Maneuvers</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A British frigate collided with a Canadian support ship Sunday during <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> maneuvers off <LOCATION> Norway </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> said. A ministry spokesman said there were no injuries in the collision between the HMS <PERSON> Penelope </PERSON> and the Canadian vessel Preserver. He said the Preserver was not damaged and would continue to take part in the exercise. The <PERSON> Penelope </PERSON> headed for <LOCATION> Rosyth </LOCATION> on the Scottish east coast, where the extent of the damage would be determined. The spokesman, speaking on condition of anonymity, said the collision took place during a refueling operation about 7 a.m. -LRB- 1 a.m. EDT -RRB- Sunday in <LOCATION> Vestfjorden </LOCATION>, the waterway between the <LOCATION> Lofoten </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Islands </LOCATION> and the northwest Norwegian coast. <PERSON> Penelope </PERSON> is a 3,200-ton Leander class warship with 230 officers and crew. The much larger Preserver, 24,700 tons, has a complement of 290 and is mainly used for refueling other ships at sea. The vessels were taking part in Teamwork'88, a <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> exercise involving 45,000 land, sea and air personnel of the armed forces of nine <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> countries, 340 aircraft and 200 ships. The exercise is designed to test naval warfare, air force collaboration, anti-submarine, carrier and convoy operations and amphibious landings. The exercise began Aug. 31 and runs through Sept. 21. Sunday's collision was the second reported in nine days to a British warship. The destroyer HMS <ORGANIZATION> Southampton </ORGANIZATION> was rammed and badly damaged Sept. 3 in the Gulf of <LOCATION> Oman </LOCATION> by the British container ship Tor Bay it was protecting. Eleven sailors on the destroyer were injured, three having broken bones, but no one was hurt on the much larger merchantman.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880911-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-11-88 2345EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Burundi-Massacre     09-11 0277</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Burundi-Massacre,0284</SECOND>
<HEAD>Burundi President Visits Zone of Massacres</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NAIROBI, Kenya (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Burundi </LOCATION> President <PERSON> Pierre </PERSON> <PERSON> Buyoya </PERSON> has visited the area in northern <LOCATION> Burundi </LOCATION> where at least 5,000 people were killed last month in tribal violence, <ORGANIZATION> Radio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Burundi </ORGANIZATION> reported Sunday. The state-run radio said <PERSON> Buyoya </PERSON>, during his weekend tour, commended doctors for helping the wounded in the districts of <LOCATION> Ntega </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Marangara </PERSON>, the sites of the massacre of thousands of people of the majority <PERSON> Hutu </PERSON> tribe in the warfare that began Aug. 14. An estimated 55,000 people fled into neighboring <LOCATION> Rwanda </LOCATION> to escape the violence that claimed 5,000 lives, according to government estimates. Other sources have said the death toll was much higher. Radio <LOCATION> Burundi </LOCATION>, in a brief item monitored in <LOCATION> Nairobi </LOCATION>, said <PERSON> Buyoya </PERSON> claimed the killings were caused by dissident Hutus who infiltrated into the north to provoke attacks against the minority <PERSON> Tutsi </PERSON> tribe. <PERSON> Buyoya </PERSON>'s government had made the same allegation earlier. The Tutsis comprise only 15 percent of <LOCATION> Burundi </LOCATION>'s population of 5 million but control the tiny central African nation's government and army. About 84 percent of the population are Hutus. Some <LOCATION> Burundi </LOCATION> refugees in <LOCATION> Rwanda </LOCATION> have said Hutus initiated the killings by attacking Tutsis in <LOCATION> Ntega </LOCATION> but soldiers were responsible for most of the massacres that spread into <PERSON> Marangara </PERSON>. They said the troops began killing Hutus in reprisal for the slain Tutsis. <LOCATION> Burundi </LOCATION>'s government has acknowledged its military forces became involved but claims soldiers killed fewer than a dozen people and restored peace in the area by Aug. 17. The two tribes are longtime enemies. Following a Hutu-led coup attempt in the former <LOCATION> Belgium </LOCATION> colony in 1972 the Tutsi massacred an estimated 100,000 Hutus.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880911-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-11-88 2347EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF-HalfwayHotel     09-11 0108</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF-Halfway Hotel,0110</SECOND>
<HEAD>Closed Hotel To Be Used As Halfway House</HEAD>
<DATELINE>McKEESPORT, Pa. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A closed Sheraton hotel in this <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION> suburb will be converted into a halfway house for federal prisoners under a prison warden's plan. The federal <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Prisons </ORGANIZATION> has approved the plan, <LOCATION> Butler </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> Warden <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Fenton </PERSON> said recently. <PERSON> Fenton </PERSON> said he will have 45 days to open the center at the four-story, 100-room former Sheraton Inn after he signs a federal contract, which has been mailed to him. Under <PERSON> Fenton </PERSON>'s proposal, the halfway house would hold up to 50 non-violent prisoners. <LOCATION> Butler </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> would be paid a fee for each prisoner.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880911-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-11-88 2350EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-ForestFiresRdp 2ndLd-Writethru a0557 09-11 0942</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Forest Fires Rdp, 2nd Ld-Writethru, a0557,0963</SECOND>
<HEAD>Snow On Yellowstone Brings Hope For A Quiet Fire Day</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: SUBS 3rd graf to UPDATE with temperature reaching mid-30s
Sunday. INSERTS one graf after 6th graf `Fires have' to UPDATE with
Canadian air crews arriving. Subs 14th graf pvs `And in Washington'
to UPDATE with rapid spread of Olympic fire.</NOTE>
<HEAD>LaserPhotos GROX4,5,6, XYS1</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KURT J. REPANSHEK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>YELLOWSTONE NATIONAL PARK, Wyo. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Snow dusted parts of <ORGANIZATION> Yellowstone </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Park </ORGANIZATION> on Sunday, giving firefighters a break in their battle against forest fires, and people evacuated from park headquarters and several towns returned home. Federal officials said they would double the number of soldiers sent to battle the fires that have charred more than a third of the 2.2 million-acre park. After months of drought and heat, temperatures only reached the mid-30s Sunday, with humidity as high as 90 percent. Some sections of the park were dampened by light showers Saturday. `` The colder temperatures are going to raise the humidity and with the higher humidity, the wood will absorb some of that moisture. It'll be less likely to burn, although the fire should n't have much trouble,'' said <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Halliday </PERSON>, chief naturalist for the <LOCATION> west </LOCATION> district of <LOCATION> Yellowstone </LOCATION> Winds were expected to stay in a more manageable range of 15 to 30 mph, well below the gusts above 50 mph that had driven the flames the previous two days. Fires have charred 883,000 acres of <LOCATION> Yellowstone </LOCATION> since June in what firefighters call the worst fire season in the West in 30 years. About 80 Canadian air crew members hired to help drop fire retardant arrived in <ORGANIZATION> Coeur </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> D'alene </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION>, for training. Light snow and low temperatures also helped firefighters in <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION>, where wind gusted to 60 mph, and <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION>, where evacuated residents of some ranches and small communities were allowed to return home. Rain and lower temperatures dampened fires in <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION>, but 45 mph wind gusts whipped a <LOCATION> Boulder </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> fire to 1,830 acres and led six families to evacuate. Heavy rains later Sunday stalled the fire and residents were allowed to return home. Fires in the <ORGANIZATION> Routt </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> were left unattended because the weather was too cold and wet for firefighters. And in northwest <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION>, the state <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forestry </ORGANIZATION> shut down millions of acres of state-protected forests in an unprecedented effort to curb the number of fires caused by human carelessness. `` Given the number of human-caused fires we're seeing every day, this is the most viable option we have right now,'' said forestry department spokesman <PERSON> Doug </PERSON> <PERSON> Decker </PERSON>. Altogether, 13.3 million acres, or 83 percent of the state's forests, have been closed, <PERSON> Decker </PERSON> said A fire also burned in northern <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, where a mountain blaze whipped by hot winds burned 2,000 acres of brush and timber near the town of <LOCATION> Grass </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION>. There were no reports of injuries, but authorities described the blaze as a wall of fire a half-mile long that was headed toward affluent <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Wildwood </LOCATION>, a residential area of about 2,000 homes. And in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, a rapidly expanding fire started by an illegal campfire spread rapidly to more than 300 acres in Olympic National Park high country Sunday. Thin smoke from the <ORGANIZATION> Yellowstone </ORGANIZATION> fires has drifted as far east as <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> at an altitude of 15,000 to 20,000 feet, the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Weather </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> said Sunday. `` A couple days ago most of the smoke was over the <LOCATION> Midwest </LOCATION> and it has now gradually drifted eastward,'' said <PERSON> Brian </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Severe </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Storms </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mo </LOCATION>. `` It's just going to have a thin hazy appearance and might create some colorful sunsets, but it's not expected to present any health problems because it's so far up.'' The 263,400-acre North Fork fire in <LOCATION> Yellowstone </LOCATION> remained about a mile from park headquarters at <LOCATION> Mammoth </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hot </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Springs </LOCATION>, said spokeswoman <PERSON> Marty </PERSON> <PERSON> Tobias </PERSON>. That fire also has threatened <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Yellowstone </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mont. </LOCATION>, and destroyed several buildings at Old Faithful geyser. Park officials Saturday ordered all families and nonessential employees to leave Mammoth, near the park's north entrance. But they were allowed back after conditions improved. <PERSON> Tobias </PERSON> did not know how many people decided to return. The improved weather allowed park officials to reopen <ORGANIZATION> Yellowstone </ORGANIZATION>'s west entrance and the road from there to <LOCATION> Madison </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Junction </LOCATION> and Old Faithful. The rest of the park remained closed to visitors. Ten miles northeast of Mammoth, residents of <LOCATION> Jardine </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mont. </LOCATION>, also were allowed to return, <PERSON> Tobias </PERSON> added. They were evacuated Saturday when fire threatened the only exit road. Evacuated residents of <LOCATION> Cooke </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Silver </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gate </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mont. </LOCATION>, at the northeast gate to <ORGANIZATION> Yellowstone </ORGANIZATION>, were allowed to return home Sunday and the highway leading into the area was reopened, said fire information officer <PERSON> Nick </PERSON> <PERSON> Tafoya </PERSON>. A mile from <ORGANIZATION> Yellowstone </ORGANIZATION>'s headquarters, firefighters sprayed protective foam Sunday on buildings at the <ORGANIZATION> Young </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Adult </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conservation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corps </ORGANIZATION> camp, where fire destroyed a tent. `` Basically with this cold front that's moved in it's going to put us kind of in a holding pattern. We'll see how it goes from there,'' <PERSON> Tobias </PERSON> said. `` Let's just drop this wind and we'll be in business.'' However, <PERSON> Brian </PERSON> <PERSON> Morris </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> spokesman in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Yellowstone </LOCATION>, said: `` It's not going to be with us too long. We expect warmer weather and a drying trend this week.'' About 9,000 people are fighting the fires in <LOCATION> Yellowstone </LOCATION>. Deputy Defense Secretary <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Taft </PERSON> <PERSON> IV </PERSON> said 1,200 Marines from <LOCATION> Camp </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Pendleton </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, and two <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> battalions will join the 2,300 <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> soldiers from <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lewis </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wash. </LOCATION>, fighting the fires. `` So by the end of next week, we will see a doubled representation by the military in this effort,'' <PERSON> Taft </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880911-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-11-88 2356EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-EarlyActivists     09-11 0264</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Early Activists,0268</SECOND>
<HEAD>Civil Rights Leader Vows Movement Still Alive</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WILLIAMSTOWN, Mass. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The struggle for civil rights remains alive, although it has changed, says one of several activists honored for their work in the 1960s. `` The nature and the character of the movement has changed, but these changes are merely part of a natural process and do not spell doom for our hopes,'' said Rep. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON>, D-Ga., former chairman of the Student Nonviolent Coordinating Committee <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON>, who received an honorary doctorate at a convocation Saturday opening <ORGANIZATION> Williams </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION>'s 196th academic year, said the <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> people must elect leaders with the `` moral capacity'' of the Rev. <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Luther </PERSON> <PERSON> King </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> if civil rights are to improve with time. `` We have lost some of our finest leaders, but we are still very involved in that same movement for liberation,'' said <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON>, who was jailed 40 times and severely beaten during the Sixties for leading peaceful marches and demonstrations throughout the South. `` Our struggle is not for one day, or one week, or one year, but for a lifetime if that's what it takes.'' Among thos honored Saturday was <PERSON> Rosa </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Parks </PERSON>, whose refusal to surrender her seat to a white passenger on a <LOCATION> Montgomery </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ala. </LOCATION> bus sparked a boycott that was a milestone in the civil rights movement. She received a standing ovation from the audience of 1,000 students, faculty members and administrators. Also honored were the Rev. <PERSON> Ralph </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Abernathy </PERSON>, former president of the <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Leadership </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conference </ORGANIZATION>, and journalist <PERSON> Charlayne </PERSON> <PERSON> Hunter-Gault </PERSON>, the first black woman at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Georgia </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880911-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-11-88 2356EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-McKinleySeason     09-11 0260</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-McKinley Season,0268</SECOND>
<HEAD>McKinley Hosts Record Number of Climbers</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By SUSAN GALLAGHER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ANCHORAGE, Alaska (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A record 916 people tackled <LOCATION> Mount </LOCATION> <LOCATION> McKinley </LOCATION> during the mountaineering season, says the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Park </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>, which is thinking about putting another outhouse on <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s tallest mountain. Sanitation on the 20,320-foot mountain has been a growing concern, said <PERSON> Ranger </PERSON> <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON>. According to <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON>, 562 of the 916 people who registered to climb <PERSON> McKinley </PERSON> this spring and summer reported reaching the summit. Last year, 817 climbers tested themselves against the mountain. Only about a third finished the climb. Two people died climbing <PERSON> McKinley </PERSON> this year, <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Henry </PERSON>, a 71-year-old <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION> lawyer, this year became the oldest person known to have made the top. <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> attributed some of the increased mountaineering to foreigners who decided attractive currency exchange rates made this the year for the climb they had long wanted to make. Climbers began arriving in April and some waited until late July, but most planned their trips for May and June. `` We're trying to get more people to come in July,'' <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> said. Rangers attempting to deal with the environmental effects of increased activity want use of the mountain to be spread out. The Park Service asks climbers to use plastic bags for human waste and put the bags in crevasses, but officials do n't know how many comply, <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> said. There are two latrines on <PERSON> McKinley </PERSON>, one two-thirds of the way up the peak. The <ORGANIZATION> Park </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> hopes to install an outhouse at 17,000 feet next year.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880911-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-11-88 2357EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Pope-Mozambique Bjt   09-11 0724</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Pope-Mozambique, Bjt,0744</SECOND>
<HEAD>Pope's Visit To Marxist Mozambique Comes Amid Controversy</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Note pope visits Sept. 16-19.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By LAURINDA KEYS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MAPUTO, Mozambique (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Pope <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> II </PERSON>'s customary message of peace and reconciliation could be a controversial one when he visits <LOCATION> Mozambique </LOCATION>, a southern African nation wracked by 12 years of civil war, drought and systematic destruction of public facilities. A newsletter issued last year by <ORGANIZATION> Frelimo </ORGANIZATION>, the governing Marxist party, called the former <LOCATION> Portuguese </LOCATION> colony's <ORGANIZATION> Roman </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> bishops `` enemies of the people'' after they suggested the government meet with guerrillas of the Mozambican National Resistance. But Cardinal <PERSON> Alexandre </PERSON> <PERSON> dos </PERSON> <PERSON> Santos </PERSON> says he hopes the pope will call for reconciliation when he visits the country Sept. 16-19. President <PERSON> Joaquim </PERSON> <PERSON> Chissano </PERSON>, who was visiting the pope in the <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION> when the bishops made their plea, said it was impossible to negotiate with the guerrillas who, he charged, mutilate children, burn schools and hospitals, and massacre villagers. The guerrilla movement, known as <ORGANIZATION> RENAMO </ORGANIZATION>, denies such charges and says it is fighting to replace the Marxist government with a democratic one. `` We hope -LRB- the pope -RRB- will say something about peace since we are in this situation of war,'' said <PERSON> Dos </PERSON> <PERSON> Santos </PERSON>, who became a cardinal in June. `` We do n't see how we can end this struggle without reconciliation. ... It is necessary to have dialogue with these people.'' Foreign Minister <PERSON> Pascoal </PERSON> <PERSON> Mocumbi </PERSON> said the government hopes the pope will not appeal for negotiations with <ORGANIZATION> RENAMO </ORGANIZATION>. He said no one had the right to suggest that the government `` should talk with terrorists, with those who commit massacres, ... those who have been roundly condemned, not only by <LOCATION> Mozambique </LOCATION> but by the international community.'' Job Chambal, director of the government's <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Religious </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Affairs </ORGANIZATION>, is overseeing the return of some church property confiscated when <ORGANIZATION> Frelimo </ORGANIZATION> came to power at independence from <LOCATION> Portugal </LOCATION> in 1975. He said of the bishops: `` Our quarrel with them is not the fact that they called for negotiations _ any <LOCATION> Mozambican </LOCATION> is free to think that. The one thing that worried the government was to ... say that the government as well as <ORGANIZATION> RENAMO </ORGANIZATION> are responsible for the war.'' <PERSON> Chambal </PERSON> said the plan to return all confiscated church property used for worship came coincidentally three months before the pope's visit `` We were not trying to please the <PERSON> pope </PERSON>,'' he said. `` It's a way of showing we do n't belong to an evil empire.'' Since 1982, when the late President <PERSON> Samora </PERSON> <PERSON> Machel </PERSON> held meetings with church leaders, the government has sought to ease tension between the churches and <ORGANIZATION> Frelimo </ORGANIZATION>. The government invited the pope to visit <LOCATION> Mozambique </LOCATION> in his capacity as head of the <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION> state, and it is sharing expenses with the local church. `` It's very expensive, but it's very important,'' Chambal said. `` The willingness of the pope to come to <LOCATION> Mozambique </LOCATION> means there's been a very big improvement because people have understood what it means when we say we have a socialist state. `` We are Marxists, but all of us in government have some religious background,'' said <PERSON> Chambal </PERSON>, who was reared a Presbyterian. `` We still have some religious feeling. Even our revolutionary songs have a religious taste. But our children will be more Marxist, and teach their children to be Marxists.'' He said the government wants children to be influenced only by the state until they are 18, when they can choose whether to go to church, but this policy is not enforced. In the years immediately after independence, some churches were closed, services were interrupted and religious activity was officially discouraged. Now churches operate freely. Both cathedral services and prayer meetings in the <PERSON> bush </PERSON> are packed on Sundays. The Frelimo revolutionaries accused Roman Catholic bishops and priests of cooperating with the Portuguese colonial government and opposing independence in return for a favored position as a state church. The cardinal says some Portuguese clergymen supported colonialism, but denies the <ORGANIZATION> Mozambican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Roman </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> as a whole was against independence. All church-state problems are not resolved, Cardinal <PERSON> dos </PERSON> <PERSON> Santos </PERSON> said, but he maintained the government does not understand the church's goals. `` They suppose we want only to teach those who want to be religious leaders,'' he said. `` We also want to prepare the people for running the country.'' <PERSON> Dos </PERSON> <PERSON> Santos </PERSON> said that of <LOCATION> Mozambique </LOCATION>'s 14.5 million people, 2 million are Catholics.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880911-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-11-88 2358EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-AnotherLook-SoloSailor Bjt   09-11 0788</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Another Look-Solo Sailor, Bjt,0809</SECOND>
<HEAD>Young Sailor Still Learning Lessons Of World Voyage</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RONALD POWERS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The floor no longer moves beneath <PERSON> Tania </PERSON> <PERSON> Aebi </PERSON>'s feet The view from her window these days offers more than a vista of waves and billowing sail. And she no longer spends week after week alone. Life has changed for the young woman whose father sent her off at age 18 to sail alone around the world because she would n't do her homework. Instead of standing by the tiller, Ms. <PERSON> Aebi </PERSON> now spends hours in front of her computer keyboard, putting down the memories of months at sea and ports of call. But after working nearly a year on her book, Ms. <PERSON> Aebi </PERSON> still finds `` writing about myself is harder than sailing.'' The lessons of her 2 -LCB- - year, 27,000-mile voyage are coming slowly `` I'm ruminating about it,'' Ms. <PERSON> Aebi </PERSON>, now 21, said recently from her home in <LOCATION> Newport </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> R.I. </LOCATION> `` It's not like my life's a neat pattern yet. It probably never will be.'' Nonetheless, her life is starting to follow a more conventional path. The boat recently was sold. She's newly wed to a man she met on the other side of the planet. And Ms. <PERSON> Aebi </PERSON> and her father have bridged the personal gulf that sent her sailing around the globe. `` Before I left, he lost hope in me,'' she confided. `` He thought I was a total dud. He was an explorer and I did none of that. `` Father proposed the whole thing to me and did n't give me a whole lot of options.'' In 1985, <PERSON> Ernst </PERSON> <PERSON> Aebi </PERSON>, a well-known surrealist painter who lives in <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION>, suggested to his bicycle-messenger daughter an intriguing scheme: In lieu of a college education, he would buy her a boat to sail solo around the world. Ms. <PERSON> Aebi </PERSON>, a difficult student who graduated from an alternative high school, agreed. Her father says she was `` shanghaied.'' Soon, the 26-foot sloop <LOCATION> Varuna </LOCATION> was ordered, and on May 28, 1985, the neophyte sailor hoisted the sails and was on her way out of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Harbor </LOCATION>. Many thought she would n't make it. But by the time Ms. <PERSON> Aebi </PERSON> floated through the <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Canal </LOCATION> and reached the <LOCATION> Galapagos </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Islands </LOCATION> she had learned how to use the heavens as her map. Her seamanship would later be tested when the boat capsized during a <LOCATION> Mediterranean </LOCATION> storm and when it collided with a freighter. At the <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> island of <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Samoa </LOCATION>, Ms. <PERSON> Aebi </PERSON> gave a hitchhiker an 80-mile lift to another island, a generous oversight that ultimately cost her a pair of world's records. The people who keep the books say as a result of that gesture, the voyage could n't be classified as single-handed. Ms. <PERSON> Aebi </PERSON> would have been the youngest person and the first <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> woman to sail solo around the world. But if she lost something in the <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION>, she also found something: <PERSON> Olivier </PERSON> <PERSON> Berner </PERSON>, a fellow adventurer and solo sailor from <LOCATION> Switzerland </LOCATION> who was sailing to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Guinea </LOCATION> in search of gold. He changed course and, sailing his own boat, accompanied her to <LOCATION> Malta </LOCATION>. When Ms. <PERSON> Aebi </PERSON> returned to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> last Nov. 6, <PERSON> Berner </PERSON> was here to welcome her. The couple were married six months later. With the elation of accomplishment now displaced by the effort of writing her memoirs, Ms. <PERSON> Aebi </PERSON> says she has no regrets about the records she almost captured or the years away from her home, friends and family. `` I'll never be 18 again,'' she said. `` That trip gave me an opportunity for 2 -LCB- years to not worry about the future except for getting to the next port. I knew what I had to do, which was ultimately get back to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>.'' But, does the prosaic pale after a life before the mast? `` Life ca n't be a bore when you have a deadline,'' she said with a laugh. `` And there are too many things I want to do _ learn a couple of more languages, read a lot of books and get older.'' Still, her future remains `` a big question mark.'' `` I've seen a lot and I've met a lot of people doing different things, so I see there's a whole world of opportunity out there. I guess I have bigger horizons.'' Ms. <PERSON> Aebi </PERSON>'s next adventure will be a more conventional drive across the country in a van with her husband. Another solo voyage does n't figure into her plans, but neither does settling down. `` I could have bought a house last week,'' she said. `` But when it came down to paying the mortgage and being attached to one particular thing, I just could n't do it. I do n't need a house. I could get a boat.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880911-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-11-88 0039EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-Florence 3rdLd-Writethru a0629 09-11 0658</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Florence, 3rd Ld - Writethru, a0629,0672</SECOND>
<HEAD>One Dead; Minimal Property Damage</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: INSERTS two grafs after 4th graf ```All we..' to UPDATE with
Gilbert upgraded to hurricane, deletes outdated 19th and 20nd
grafs.</NOTE>
<HEAD>LaserPhotos NU1, NU2, NU3</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ALBERTO S. FRANCO</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW ORLEANS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The remnants of Hurricane <LOCATION> Florence </LOCATION> pushed inland Saturday as thousands of <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Coast </LOCATION> residents returned home, happy to find little damage from 80 mph winds and sheets of rain. `` I was expecting to see my little trailer gone. It is n't tied down or anything,'' <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Gibson </PERSON>, 58, said as he hauled away a 12-foot-long branch that had fallen from a tree next to his undamaged trailer house in <LOCATION> Venice </LOCATION>, near the mouth of the <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION>. One death _ that of an <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION> man who drowned Friday trying to secure a boat against the rising winds _ was linked to the storm, which was downgraded to a tropical depression by dawn Saturday. `` All we lost was a good night's sleep,'' said <PERSON> Wade </PERSON> <PERSON> Guice </PERSON>, civil defense director for <LOCATION> Harrison </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, Miss. `` This storm fizzled out. The hurricane did n't come.'' Meanwhile, Tropical Storm <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON> formed in the eastern <LOCATION> Caribbean </LOCATION> and strengthened into a hurricane Saturday night. The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hurricane </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> reported its position late Saturday night as near latitude 16.0 north, longitude 67.3 west, about 225 miles southeast of <LOCATION> Santo </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Domingo </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Dominican </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Republic </LOCATION>. Maximum sustained winds were estimated to be nearly 75 mph. <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON> was expected drop 5 to 10 inches of rain on <LOCATION> Puerto </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rico </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Dominican </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Republic </LOCATION> by Sunday, the hurricane center said. <LOCATION> Florence </LOCATION> hit on the 23rd anniversary of Hurricane <PERSON> Betsy </PERSON>'s 1965 landfall but packed little of <PERSON> Betsy </PERSON>'s punch. <PERSON> Betsy </PERSON> killed more than 70 people in <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION> and did an estimated $ 1.1 billion in damage. Damage estimates for <LOCATION> Florence </LOCATION> were unavailable but appeared to be relatively minor. Crews from the <ORGANIZATION> Louisiana </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Emergency </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Preparedness </ORGANIZATION> went out Saturday to assess the damage and start cleaning up, said state police Trooper <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Wood </PERSON>. Sheriff's deputies said property damage appeared to be minimal and limited mainly to downed power lines that knocked out electricity to 115,000 or more homes and businesses. Thousands of people ordered to leave homes in nine parishes Friday returned home when <LOCATION> Florence </LOCATION> dropped from hurricane to tropical storm. They found several broken branches and a few bent or broken signs. `` We were expecting the worst and hoping for the best, and we got the best out of it,'' said <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Ciko </PERSON>, a spokesman for the sheriff's office in <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Tammany </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Parish </LOCATION>, across <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Pontchartrain </LOCATION> from <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION>. A tornado was reported in neighboring <LOCATION> Tangipahoa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Parish </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Weather </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> said the tropical depression was pushing a wide band of showers and thunderstorms into northeast <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION>, extreme southwest <LOCATION> Arkansas </LOCATION> and central <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION>. At 5 p.m. CDT, the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Weather </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> said <LOCATION> Florence </LOCATION> was centered over central <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION>, moving toward the west-northwest and weakening. Winds unleashed by <LOCATION> Florence </LOCATION> never reached the 100 mph that had been feared. <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Tregre </PERSON>, a spokesman for the two companies that supply electricity to most of south <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION>, said the storm cut power to about 70,000 <ORGANIZATION> Louisiana </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Power </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <ORGANIZATION> Light </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> customers and about 33,000 customers of <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Orleans </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>. About 6,900 remained without power Saturday afternoon, but <PERSON> Tregre </PERSON> said he expected all would have their electricity restored before Sunday <PERSON> Ciko </PERSON> said <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Louisiana </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Electric </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> officials told him that 12,000 to 14,000 customers were without power at the height of the storm. Although the storm was expected to bring 5 to 10 inches of rain, less than 2 inches was reported around most of southeast <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION>. `` The fast movement of the storm kept a lid on the rains,'' said a weather service meteorologist who refused to give his name. <LOCATION> Florence </LOCATION>, the sixth named storm of the 1988 <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> storm season, was the second hurricane. The first, <PERSON> Debby </PERSON>, reached minimal hurricane strength briefly before hitting Mexican coast last month.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880911-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-11-88 0053EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-PostEditor     09-11 0207</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Post Editor,0212</SECOND>
<HEAD>C. David Burgin Named Editor-in-Chief of The Houston Post</HEAD>
<DATELINE>HOUSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The former editor of the <ORGANIZATION> Dallas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Herald </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Burgin </PERSON>, has been named vice president and editor-in-chief of <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Houston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION>, the newspaper announced. <PERSON> Burgin </PERSON>, 49, succeeds <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Sullivan </PERSON>, 39, who said he was resigning to pursue other opportunities, the <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> reported Saturday. <PERSON> Burgin </PERSON> was editor of the <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Herald </ORGANIZATION> until June and is a longtime associate of <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Dean </PERSON> <PERSON> Singleton </PERSON>, whose Houston-based <ORGANIZATION> MediaNews </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Group </ORGANIZATION> owns the <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Singleton </PERSON> said he has known <PERSON> Burgin </PERSON> since 1977. `` His newspapers have warmth. They have personality,'' <PERSON> Singleton </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Singleton </PERSON> also praised <PERSON> O'Sullivan </PERSON> for his accomplishments since taking over as editor in December 1983. `` The Post under <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> made dramatic improvements,'' he said. Earlier last week, the <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> announced that Publisher <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Hunt </PERSON> was moving to head a new international division of <ORGANIZATION> MediaNews </ORGANIZATION>. Hunt had stayed on at the newspaper after the <ORGANIZATION> Toronto </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sun </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Publishing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> sold it to <PERSON> Singleton </PERSON>'s company a year ago. <PERSON> Singleton </PERSON> replaced <PERSON> Hunt </PERSON> as publisher. <PERSON> Burgin </PERSON> said <PERSON> Ernie </PERSON> <PERSON> Williamson </PERSON> will remain as the paper's managing editor. <PERSON> Burgin </PERSON> also was editor of the <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> Star, the <ORGANIZATION> Peninsula </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tribune </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Palo </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Alto </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> Orlando </LOCATION> Sentinel and the <ORGANIZATION> San </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Francisco </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Examiner </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880911-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-11-88 0045EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p AM-DelawarePrimary 6thLd-Writethru a0401 09-11 0597</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Delaware Primary, 6th Ld - Writethru, a0401,0611</SECOND>
<HEAD>Lt. Gov. Woo Loses Primary Battle for Senate</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Inserts two grafs after 3rd graf to UPDATE with quotes from
Beard and Woo. Picks up 4th graf pvs `Beard faces...'</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By THERESA HUMPHREY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>DOVER, Del. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A wealthy civic activist won an upset victory over <LOCATION> Delaware </LOCATION>'s lieutenent governor Saturday in a <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> primary election for the right to challenge a <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> incumbent in the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>. With 97 percent or 330 of the 339 precincts reporting, <PERSON> Samuel </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Beard </PERSON> had 22,418 votes, or 53 percent, to Lt. Gov. S.B. Woo's 19,624 votes, or 47 percent Nine small precincts were not expected to report their results until Monday, but <PERSON> Woo </PERSON> conceded Saturday night. He apologized to his supporters for not running a winning campaign, and said in a statement, `` I always said it was a tough way to earn a living,'' according to his press secretary <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Siegel </PERSON>. `` It was a wonderful victory,'' <PERSON> Beard </PERSON> said, referring to himself as the underdog in the primary campaign. `` We ran a grassroots campaign from the beginning. We went into living rooms, all over the state. We walked through 19 pairs of shoes.'' Beard faces Sen. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> V. </PERSON> <PERSON> Roth </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> in the November general election. <PERSON> Roth </PERSON>, who did not have a primary opponent, is seeking a fourth term. The votes represented a little more than a 30 percent turnout of Democrats eligible to vote in the only statewide race in the primary, according to <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, state election commissioner. There were 133,386 Democrats eligible to vote, and average turnout for a primary is about 20 percent. Two Beard campaign workers were detained Saturday night after an officer caught them taking down about 50 Woo signs throughout <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Castle </LOCATION> before dawn Saturday, police said. Authorities planned to charge the men with theft and conspiracy, but a Woo assistant asked that no charges be filed, police said. There was no indication Beard had ordered the signs destroyed. `` They took them back to the New Castle Armory Building where <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> <PERSON> Beard </PERSON>'s headquarters are located, and they were putting them into a dumpster there when a town resident called to report the incident,'' New Castle Police Sgt. <PERSON> Patrick </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Cannon </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 Woo, 51, born in <LOCATION> Shanghai </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, had the financial support of Asian-American communities, for whom he has become a champion nationwide. Woo, a physics professor at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Delaware </ORGANIZATION>, was a political newcomer four years ago when he beat two legislators in a primary, then went on to win the lieutenant governor's seat by a slim 479 votes. Beard, 49, who inherited his wealth, had the support of party leaders and loyalists, as well as unions. He is a former staffer of the late <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, and runs a nonprofit company that helps attract grants and designs plans to attract economic development. Beard was far outspent by Woo. Campaign finance reports filed in late August showed Woo with $ 407,998 on hand. Beard had only $ 65,008. <PERSON> Roth </PERSON> had $ 734,933. Woo's ethnic background was targeted recently in an open letter supporting Beard that was written by <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> `` Pete'' <PERSON> Peterson </PERSON>, president of the state <ORGANIZATION> AFL-CIO </ORGANIZATION>. The letter said in part: `` It is up to you and I to save this country not only from the Asian influences the lieutenant governor refers to, but all foreign influence.'' Last week, <PERSON> Peterson </PERSON> wrote another letter, apologizing to anyone who might have been offended by the statement. <PERSON> Peterson </PERSON> said he was referring to Woo's claims that he has many contact with business leaders in <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880911-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-11-88 0157EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-MissAmerica 6thLd-Writethru a0418 09-11 1039</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Miss America, 6th Ld-Writethru, a0418,1067</SECOND>
<HEAD>Miss Minnesota Becomes Miss America 1989</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: CLARIFIES in 2nd graf year she will reign; clarifies tie in
11th graf `But getting...' and in 27th graf ``She also...''</NOTE>
<HEAD>LaserPhotoXACC1, XACC2</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOYCE A. VENEZIA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ATLANTIC CITY, N.J. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Miss Minnesota <PERSON> Gretchen </PERSON> <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> Carlson </PERSON>, who wants to be a Harvard-trained lawyer, became the first classical violinist to win the Miss <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> crown in a contest that required two polls of the judges Saturday night. Miss <PERSON> Carlson </PERSON> erupted in tears as her name was announced as Miss America 1989. She laughed and cried as she took her victory walk along the runway at Convention Center. The first runner-up was Miss Colorado <PERSON> Maya </PERSON> <PERSON> Walker </PERSON>, 23, of <LOCATION> Vail </LOCATION>; the second runner-up was Miss <PERSON> Oklahoma </PERSON> <PERSON> Lori </PERSON> <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Kelley </PERSON>, 23, of <PERSON> Clinton </PERSON>; the third runner-up was Miss <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> <PERSON> Marlise </PERSON> <PERSON> Sharleen </PERSON> <PERSON> Ricardos </PERSON>, 26, of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Pedro </LOCATION>; and the fourth runner-up was <PERSON> Miss </PERSON> <PERSON> Alabama </PERSON> <PERSON> Jenny </PERSON> <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, 21, of <LOCATION> Auburn </LOCATION>. Miss <PERSON> Carlson </PERSON>, 22, of <LOCATION> Anoka </LOCATION>, is a senior at the prestigious <ORGANIZATION> Stanford </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, majoring in organizational behavior. As part of her studies, she spent a semester at <ORGANIZATION> Oxford </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>. She plans to attend <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Law </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION>. `` I'm not a beauty queen. I aspire to go to <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Law </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION>. This is not just for someone who is beautiful. This is for someone who is educated and sophisticated,'' Miss <PERSON> Carlson </PERSON> told reporters after winning. She said she felt `` shocked inside. I'm trying to remain composed on the outside.'' Asked about the first thing she wanted to do, she replied, `` Eat pizza. That's all I can think about.'' The 5-foot-3, 108-pound Miss <PERSON> Carlson </PERSON> impressed judges with a spirited violin piece titled `` Gypsy Airs.'' The piece started slow and moving, then jumped into a splashy, fast-paced beat. Miss <PERSON> Carlson </PERSON>'s father, <PERSON> Lee </PERSON>, who attended the pageant, said his daughter is `` a winner. Everything she does she gives 110 percent. She does n't like to lose.'' Her mother, <PERSON> Karen </PERSON> <PERSON> Carlson </PERSON>, added: `` I think it feels wonderful. She said she knew she could win.'' But getting Miss <PERSON> Carlson </PERSON>'s name from the judges was not easy. As television host <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Collins </PERSON> walked to the judge's area in front of the stage to learn who had won, he was told there was a tie. It later turned out to be a tie for second and third places. In an affort to kill time, <PERSON> Collins </PERSON> nervously began making small talk with the contestants. There was a flurry of activity in the judge's box. Pageant Director <PERSON> Leonard </PERSON> <PERSON> Horn </PERSON>, sitting next to the judges, tapped his fingers on the edge of the stage as a discussion took place on what to do. Eventually, a second poll of the judges resulted in Miss <PERSON> Carlson </PERSON> taking the coveted rhinestone-studded headpiece. During the wait, Miss <PERSON> Carlson </PERSON> said things were tense on stage. `` At that moment, I thought, ` Oh, it's all over,''' she said. After winning a preliminary talent competition earlier in the week, Miss <PERSON> Carlson </PERSON> termed parts of her performance `` exquisite'' but vowed to do even better on the final night. She has studied the violin for 17 years. For her performance, the green-eyed blonde wore a black velvet gown with a sweetheart neckline with dramatic green lame-puffed sleeves and pleated layered skirts. Miss <PERSON> Carlson </PERSON>, who prides herself on being 100 percent Swedish, had taken special pains during the week to highlight her heritage. At the Miss <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> parade on Tuesday, her hair and dress were decorated with a traditional garland of flowers. However, for the evening gown competition, Miss <PERSON> Carlson </PERSON> chose a long-sleeved turquoise, beaded gown with a silver-beaded design on the bodice and back. <PERSON> Horn </PERSON>, in his first year as the pageant's executive director, has stressed that the new Miss <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> will fit into a different mold than tradition previously held. `` Multi-faceted young women who are more than just physically attractive and talented'' have become the ideal, he said. `` These are dynamic young college women.'' In an effort to prove that to a national television audience Saturday night, the pageant televised video clips of the finalists' interviews that was part of preliminary judging Also, the judges on Saturday night asked an unrehearsed question of each of the top 10 finalists during the evening gown competition. The new Miss <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> succeeds Miss <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> 1988 <PERSON> Kaye </PERSON> <PERSON> Lani </PERSON> <PERSON> Rae </PERSON> <PERSON> Rafko </PERSON>, 25, an outspoken nurse from <LOCATION> Monroe </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mich. </LOCATION>, who has championed AIDS education and safe sex, and preferred to make charity appearances rather than take paid engagements during the year. <PERSON> Collins </PERSON> returned for his seventh year as host of the finals to croon the pageant standard `` There She Is'' to the new queen. <PERSON> Collins </PERSON>' wife, <ORGANIZATION> Miss </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION> 1959 <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Ann </PERSON> <PERSON> Mobley </PERSON>, co-hosted this year's pageant with the theme `` Success.'' She also joined <PERSON> Collins </PERSON> in attempting to kill network air time as the judge's tried to come up with a winner. Pageant officials said there have been a number of tie situations in years past. The 67-year-old Miss America Pageant is the largest contributor of scholarships to young women, awarding more than $ 5 million in scholarships annually to more than 80,000 young women who compete on the national, state and local levels. The new Miss <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> receives a $ 30,000 cash scholarship and the income from a year of personal appearances. Miss <PERSON> Rafko </PERSON> estimates she earned more than $ 150,000 during her reign. The first runner-up receives a $ 17,000 scholarship and the next three runners-up receive $ 11,000, $ 8,000 and $ 6,000 in scholarships, respectively. The remaining finalists each receive $ 4,000 to be used toward their educations, and every remaining contestant receives a $ 2,000 scholarship. This year, a new judging system was introduced. The contestants were interviewed and judged in preliminary competitions by a preliminary panel of seven judges. On Saturday, a panel of 12 celebrity judges started from scratch after reviewing videos of the top 10 finalists' interviews. Saturday's celebrity judges were: actors <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Dysart </PERSON> and <PERSON> Blair </PERSON> <PERSON> Underwood </PERSON> of television's `` L.A. Law''; NBC News correspondent <PERSON> Deborah </PERSON> <PERSON> Norville </PERSON>; Miss <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> 1971 and broadcaster <PERSON> Phyllis </PERSON> <PERSON> George </PERSON>; actor <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Peppard </PERSON>; actress <PERSON> Eva </PERSON> <PERSON> Gabor </PERSON>; columnist Dr. <PERSON> Joyce </PERSON> <PERSON> Brothers </PERSON>; Olympic ice skating gold medalist <PERSON> Brian </PERSON> <PERSON> Boitano </PERSON>; movie producer <PERSON> Lili </PERSON> <PERSON> Fini </PERSON> <PERSON> Zanuck </PERSON>; model agency founder <PERSON> Eileen </PERSON> <PERSON> Ford </PERSON>; Parade magazine publisher <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON>; and <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Farley </PERSON>, chairman of <ORGANIZATION> Farley </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Industries </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880911-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-11-88 0205EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Delta-Investigation 1stLd-Writethru a0639 09-11 0421</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Delta-Investigation, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0639,0428</SECOND>
<HEAD>Physician Says Captain Not Well Enough To Be Interviewed</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: CORRECTS lead to flight 1141, sted 1411</NOTE>
<DATELINE>DALLAS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The captain of <ORGANIZATION> Delta </ORGANIZATION> Flight 1141 is not well enough to talk to federal investigators about the Aug. 31 crash that killed 13 people, his physician said Saturday. Dr. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON> issued a statement saying he alone is responsible for denying investigators from the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> or anyone else a chance to interview Capt. <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> about the crash. <ORGANIZATION> NTSB </ORGANIZATION> officials have complained that they were being kept away from the <ORGANIZATION> Delta </ORGANIZATION> captain by overprotective <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Line </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pilots </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Delta </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lines </ORGANIZATION> officials. <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> is at <LOCATION> Parkland </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Memorial </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION>, where he is being treated for back and facial injuries, a hospital spokesman said. He is listed in good condition. <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON> `` has n't given any permission to anyone to talk to Capt. <PERSON> Davis </PERSON>,'' said the hospital's administrative resident, <PERSON> Paula </PERSON> <PERSON> Turner </PERSON>. <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON>, the assistant director of surgery for the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Southwestern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION>, said <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> will cooperate with the <ORGANIZATION> NTSB </ORGANIZATION> investigation later, when his medical condition improves. `` Tentatively, Capt. <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> may talk with the <ORGANIZATION> NTSB </ORGANIZATION> early next week, depending on his condition, which may change from day to day,'' <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON> said in his statement. <PERSON> Davis </PERSON>, who was fitted with a back brace Thursday, was up and walking in his hospital room Friday, <ORGANIZATION> Delta </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Neil </PERSON> <PERSON> Monroe </PERSON> said. He also is recuperating from surgery on Tuesday for a fractured cheekbone. <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> was at the controls of the 15-year-old <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> 727 when it crashed at <LOCATION> Dallas-Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Worth </LOCATION> <LOCATION> International </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION> seconds after takeoff. Thirteen died and 95 others, including the three-man cockpit crew, survived. Co-pilot <PERSON> Carey </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> <PERSON> Kirkland </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, 37, who was released from <ORGANIZATION> Northeast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Community </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Bedford </LOCATION> on Friday, told investigators he could not remember anything from the time the plane left the terminal. Flight engineer <PERSON> Steven </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Judd </PERSON>, 31, told investigators that the aircraft's right wing dropped severely shortly after takeoff and that the airplane veered to the right. <PERSON> Judd </PERSON> said that he heard no abnormal engine sounds, but that someone in the cockpit had called out an engine failure. <ORGANIZATION> NTSB </ORGANIZATION> officials have said their inquiry is focusing on possible problems with the jet's wing flaps and its three <ORGANIZATION> Pratt </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> Whitney </PERSON> JT8D engines. Friends of <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> who have visited the pilot in the hospital said that <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> told them that the plane's wing flaps were properly set for takeoff but that the aircraft did not have enough power.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880911-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-11-88 0243EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a BC-MarketShootings     09-11 0286</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Market Shootings,0295</SECOND>
<HEAD>Man Convicted of Killing Five at Supermarket</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ST. LOUIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A 27-year-old man was convicted Saturday night for slaying five people and wounding two others during a supermarket robbery. <PERSON> Marvin </PERSON> <PERSON> Jennings </PERSON> showed no emotion as the verdict was read, but his mother and sister were in tears, as were the relatives of some victims. He was convicted of five counts of first-degree murder, two counts of first-degree assault, one count of first-degree robbery and eight counts of armed criminal action. Prosecutor <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Randall </PERSON> said he will seek the death penalty in sentencing hearings set for Tuesday. Defense attorney <PERSON> Brad </PERSON> <PERSON> Kessler </PERSON> said he would appeal the verdict. `` I ca n't second-guess what happened in the jury room,'' <PERSON> Kessler </PERSON> said, noting that the jury was earlier reported to be widely split on a decision. `` They were under tremendous pressure. You never know what a jury's going to do.'' After closing arguments Friday night, the jury met for several hours, then resumed deliberations Saturday morning. The verdict came more than 15 hours later. Another suspect, <PERSON> Donnie </PERSON> <PERSON> Blankenship </PERSON>, 26, is scheduled to go on trial later. <PERSON> Kessler </PERSON> maintained his client had nothing to do with the crime. He brought several witnesses to the trial in an effort to prove that police had used coercion on some of the initial suspects in the case. Investigators said <PERSON> Jennings </PERSON> and <PERSON> Blankenship </PERSON> entered the National supermarket in north <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Louis </LOCATION> after it had closed Sept. 4, 1987, possibly by posing as a cleaning crew. A security guard was taken by surprise and was killed, and six other employees were ordered to lie on the floor and were shot in the back of the head. Two of the shooting victims survived.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880911-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-11-88 0349EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Burma 2ndLd-Writethru   09-11 0836</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Burma, 2nd Ld-Writethru,a0572,0864</SECOND>
<HEAD>Parliament Approves Multiparty Elections</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: LEADS with 8 grafs to UPDATE with Parliament approval,
election supervisors appointed, other details; pickup 6th graf pvs,
`Power corrupts ...' Minor editing to TRIM</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By SEIN WIN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>RANGOON, Burma (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Maung </PERSON> <PERSON> Maung </PERSON> on Saturday bowed to massive pro-democracy protests and announced that the ruling party would relinquish its 26-year monopoly on power and hold multiparty elections. An emergency session of Parliament on Sunday approved multiparty elections in about three months and appointed a group of elders to supervise polling. But key opposition leaders pressed for more political concessions, including an interim government to cope with <LOCATION> Burma </LOCATION>'s growing chaos, and sporadic protests continued Millions of people have taken to the streets since March to call for democracy in <LOCATION> Burma </LOCATION>. The Parliament authorized the <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Burma </LOCATION>'s highest governent body, to hold elections in as early as 45 days or the postpone them beyond the tentative three-month date if necessary. It also empowered the council to make necessary changes in the constitution to reflect a multiparty system, enlarge an <ORGANIZATION> Elections </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supervision </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> if necessary and formulate election rules. Named to the <ORGANIZATION> Elections </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supervision </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> were three retired civil servants, a retired army brigadier and a former member of Parliament. All are more than 70 years old. On Saturday, speaking before 968 delegates at a special party congress, <PERSON> Maung </PERSON> <PERSON> Maung </PERSON> acknowledged that the party made major errors and said the interests of the people were paramount. `` Power corrupts, and absolute power corrupts absolutely,'' he said in a speech carried by the state-owned Radio <LOCATION> Rangoon </LOCATION>. `` As members of the ruling party for a long period, they tended to forget the interests of the people and lose public confidence.'' The Western-trained lawyer pledged fair and free elections as soon as possible. He said he would not be a candidate. The broadcast announcer said the decision was unanimously adopted by the delegates of the <ORGANIZATION> Burma </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Socialist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Program </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Maung </PERSON> <PERSON> Maung </PERSON> urged government employees, who have gone on strike in sympathy with the massive pro-democracy movement, to return to their jobs and revive his stalled government. The government move was another retreat in face of the sometimes bloody nationwide uprising. The movement has prompted the resignation of two hard-line presidents, the lifting of martial law and virtually unimpeded political activities that earlier would have drawn long prison terms or worse. Western observers noted that the anti-government surge came without any outside support or meaningful resort to arms, although demonstrators often have compared their movement with those of other <LOCATION> Asian </LOCATION> countries. `` They were inspired by the triumph of <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Power </ORGANIZATION> in the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION> ... They were encouraged by the establishment of democracy in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> last year,'' <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Rep. <PERSON> Steven </PERSON> <PERSON> Solarz </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.Y. </LOCATION>, said after returning from <LOCATION> Rangoon </LOCATION> earlier last week. In <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> took a cautious stance. `` It's still not clear the date or the manner of the elections that would be held, or whether the government's move will satisfy the desires of the people,'' spokesman <PERSON> Dennis </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Harter </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Maung </PERSON> <PERSON> Maung </PERSON>'s government originally planned to meet Monday to consider a referendum on a general election and a multiparty system. On Friday, opposition leader former prime minister <PERSON> U </PERSON> <PERSON> Nu </PERSON>, who was toppled from power in a 1962 military coup by <PERSON> Ne </PERSON> <PERSON> Win </PERSON>, defied <LOCATION> Burma </LOCATION>'s authoritarian rulers and declared the formation of a rival government and elections Oct. 9. But three top members of the rival goverment resigned Saturday, and reliable sources said U Nu had not consulted them about the announcement. Although U Nu, 82, is respected by a large number of Burmese, diplomats say his age makes it unlikely that he will be anything more than a `` symbol'' of continuing opposition to authoritarian diehards. <PERSON> Aung </PERSON> <PERSON> San </PERSON> <PERSON> Suu </PERSON> <PERSON> Kyi </PERSON>, an opposition figure and daughter of the deceased national hero <PERSON> Aung </PERSON> <PERSON> San </PERSON>, told reporters that Saturday's announcement was `` a positive step,'' but said it could take up to two years to form parties to contest in general elections `` Under the present economic and political situation, an interim government will be the best solution. It -LRB- interim government -RRB- would deal with economic problems and also hold general elections,'' she told newsmen. Many opposition figures demanded that an interim government be set up immediately. `` Every minute the economic, political and security situation deteriorates,'' one opposition lawyer said. `` Immediate formation of an interim government is the only solution. The country wo n't hold up until these general elections. Ne Win resigned as head of the ruling party in July, citing in part widespread street protests in March and June. Riots flared when the party chose as his successor <PERSON> Sein </PERSON> <PERSON> Lwin </PERSON>, who is widely hated for his brutal suppression of dissidents. Troops fired into crowds of protesters, and the government said 112 people were killed. Western diplomats said the number was much higher. <PERSON> Sein </PERSON> <PERSON> Lwin </PERSON> resigned Aug. 12 after 17 days in power, and <PERSON> Maung </PERSON> <PERSON> Maung </PERSON> was named to replace him. <PERSON> Maung </PERSON> <PERSON> Maung </PERSON> was <LOCATION> Burma </LOCATION>'s first civilian leader in 26 years.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880911-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-11-88 0423EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i BC-HurricaneGilbert     09-11 0339</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Hurricane Gilbert,0348</SECOND>
<HEAD>Hurricane Gilbert Heads Toward Dominican Coast</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RUDDY GONZALEZ</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SANTO DOMINGO, Dominican Republic (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Hurricane <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON> swept toward the <LOCATION> Dominican </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Republic </LOCATION> Sunday, and the <ORGANIZATION> Civil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> alerted its heavily populated south coast to prepare for high winds, heavy rains and high seas. The storm was approaching from the southeast with sustained winds of 75 mph gusting to 92 mph. `` There is no need for alarm,'' <ORGANIZATION> Civil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> Director <PERSON> Eugenio </PERSON> <PERSON> Cabral </PERSON> said in a television alert shortly before midnight Saturday. <PERSON> Cabral </PERSON> said residents of the province of <PERSON> Barahona </PERSON> should closely follow <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON>'s movement. An estimated 100,000 people live in the province, including 70,000 in the city of <LOCATION> Barahona </LOCATION>, about 125 miles west of <LOCATION> Santo </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Domingo </LOCATION>. Tropical Storm <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON> formed in the eastern <LOCATION> Caribbean </LOCATION> and strengthened into a hurricane Saturday night. The National Hurricane Center in <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> reported its position at 2 a.m. Sunday at latitude 16.1 north, longitude 67.5 west, about 140 miles south of <LOCATION> Ponce </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Puerto </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rico </LOCATION>, and 200 miles southeast of <LOCATION> Santo </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Domingo </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Weather </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Juan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Puerto </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rico </LOCATION>, said <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON> was moving westward at 15 mph with a `` broad area of cloudiness and heavy weather'' rotating around the center of the storm. The weather service issued a flash flood watch for <LOCATION> Puerto </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rico </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Virgin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Islands </LOCATION> until at least 6 p.m. Sunday. Strong winds associated with the <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON> brought coastal flooding, strong southeast winds and up to 12 feet feet to <LOCATION> Puerto </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rico </LOCATION>'s south coast. There were no reports of casualties. <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Juan </LOCATION>, on the north coast, had heavy rains and gusts Saturday, but they subsided during the night. On Saturday, Hurricane <LOCATION> Florence </LOCATION> was downgraded to a tropical storm and its remnants pushed inland from the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Coast </LOCATION>. Residents returned home, happy to find little damage from 80 mph winds and sheets of rain. <LOCATION> Florence </LOCATION>, the sixth named storm of the 1988 <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> storm season, was the second hurricane. The first, <PERSON> Debby </PERSON>, reached minimal hurricane strength briefly before hitting the Mexican coast last month.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880911-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-11-88 0423EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a BC-ColiseumStabbings 2ndLd-Writethru a0423 09-11 0264</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Coliseum Stabbings, 2nd Ld-Writethru, a0423,0268</SECOND>
<HEAD>Several Stabbed At Nassau Coliseum Rap Concert</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: CORRECTS spelling of victim in 6th graf, Julio, sted Julia,
and changes age.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>UNIONDALE, N.Y. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 At least 10 people were stabbed, one fatally, when violence erupted at a rap concert Saturday inside the Nassau Veterans Memorial Coliseum, police said. Three of the stabbing victims were critically injured and two teen-agers were hospitalized in stable condition, authorities said. It was unclear what led to the stabbings shortly before 9 p.m. or if they were related, said <LOCATION> Nassau </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> police spokesman <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Scibilia </PERSON>. There also were reports of several robberies and shots fired in the arena's vicinity, said Detective <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Sventoraitis </PERSON>. Police were planning to make arrests Sunday, <PERSON> Sventoraitis </PERSON> said. Some of the stabbing victims were taken to two nearby hospitals, police said. <PERSON> Julio </PERSON> <PERSON> Fuentes </PERSON>, 19, was stabbed in the heart and died at 10:15 p.m. Saturday, shortly after he arrived at the <ORGANIZATION> Nassau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>, said the center's spokesman, <PERSON> Ed </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>. Three other victims were listed in critical condition, <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> said. They were: <PERSON> Rodney </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>, 22, <PERSON> Dave </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>, 17, and <PERSON> Greg </PERSON> <PERSON> Donaldson </PERSON>, 28. Two teen-age boys were hospitalized in stable condition with multiple stab wounds at <ORGANIZATION> Hampstead </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION>, said acting administrator <PERSON> Marilyn </PERSON> <PERSON> Hurley </PERSON>. The violence came during a festival by six rap groups at the coliseum on <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Long </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION>. The groups scheduled to perform in the `` Jam'88'' show included <PERSON> Eric </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> and <PERSON> Rakim </PERSON>, <PERSON> Kool </PERSON> <PERSON> Moe </PERSON> <PERSON> Dee </PERSON>, <PERSON> Doug </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Fresh </PERSON> and the Get Fresh Crew, <PERSON> Big </PERSON> <PERSON> Daddy </PERSON> <PERSON> Kane </PERSON>, Boogie Down Productions and <PERSON> Biz </PERSON> <PERSON> Markie </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880911-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-11-88 0459EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a BC-BRF--Delta-Fatality     09-11 0150</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-BRF--Delta-Fatality,0155</SECOND>
<HEAD>Fourteenth Victim in Delta Crash Dies</HEAD>
<DATELINE>DALLAS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A 64-year-old man died Sunday morning from injuries suffered in the crash of <ORGANIZATION> Delta </ORGANIZATION> Flight 1141 last month, bringing the death toll to 14, officials said. <PERSON> Edmond </PERSON> <PERSON> Fadal </PERSON>, one of two severely burned victims from the Aug. 31 crash, died at 1:43 a.m., said <PERSON> Cindy </PERSON> <PERSON> Gambala </PERSON> of the <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> medical examiner's office. <PERSON> Fadal </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Waco </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, had suffered from third-degree burns over 60 percent of his body and from smoke inhalation, officials said. His wife, 65-year-old <PERSON> Marian </PERSON>, died in the crash. The 15-year-old <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> 727 crashed at <LOCATION> Dallas-Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Worth </LOCATION> <LOCATION> International </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION> seconds after takeoff. The three-man cockpit crew and 94 others survived. The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> is investigating the cause of the crash. <ORGANIZATION> NTSB </ORGANIZATION> officials said their inquiry is focusing on possible problems with the jet's wing flaps and its three <ORGANIZATION> Pratt </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> Whitney </PERSON> JT8D engines.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880911-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-11-88 1125EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-AirForce-Fees Bjt   09-11 0630</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Air Force-Fees, Bjt,590</SECOND>
<HEAD>Computer Firms Win Round in Legal Fight Against Air Force</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By NORMAN BLACK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Military Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Two of the largest <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> computer manufacturers have won the first round in a fight with the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> to be reimbursed at taxpayers' expense for their legal costs in challenging <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> contracting procedures. The <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Contract </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appeals </ORGANIZATION>, in an Aug. 17 opinion obtained late last week, decided that <ORGANIZATION> Digital </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Equipment </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Wang </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Laboratories </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> were entitled to some of the more than $ 1 million they are seeking, but did not say how much. Rather, in a partial victory for the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION>, the board ordered the firms to `` segregate'' legal expenses incurred in pursuing the portion of the original challenge that they won, and said they could recover only those costs. If the two sides ca n't reach a settlement, the board said, additional proceedings will be held to fix the award. The <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> had asked the board to reject completely <ORGANIZATION> Digital </ORGANIZATION>'s claim for $ 830,330 and <PERSON> Wang </PERSON>'s demand for $ 210,000 The six-page opinion, written by Administrative Judge <PERSON> Vincent </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> LaBella </PERSON> and endorsed by two other judges, marks the latest chapter in a two-year-old battle over what has been called the computer contract of the century. The <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> intends to buy about 20,000 mini-computers for use by all the armed services, at cost of up to $ 4.5 billion. The contract is expected to be awarded in the next month or so. Digital and <PERSON> Wang </PERSON>, like most other industry firms, expressed an interest in bidding on the contract in early 1987. But before the bidding deadline passed, they filed a challenge with the <ORGANIZATION> GSA </ORGANIZATION> board charging that the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> had rigged the competition. The companies complained specifically about a requirement the computers operate on a UNIX or UNIX-compatible program. UNIX is a proprietary system developed by <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Telephone </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ; </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Telegraph </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> and widely licensed to other vendors. The <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> says UNIX compatibility is essential if the military is ever to standardize its computer systems. The <ORGANIZATION> GSA </ORGANIZATION> board, in its initial ruling last October, backed the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> for the most part, concluding that UNIX had become an industry standard. `` The decision here is not unlike a determination to specify either VHS or Beta video recorders,'' it said. But the board also said the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> should have spelled out in greater detail how it intended to use an AT & amp; T test program to determine contract compliance. The <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> did that in November, when it issued two pages of amendments to its solicitation before restarting the competition. Digital and <PERSON> Wang </PERSON>, citing their partial victory, then filed requests for reimbursement of all legal expenses stemming from the challenge. Digital said failure to reimburse would discourage future challenges and result in `` loss of effective enforcement of the procurement laws.'' `` The loser would be competition and thus, ultimately, the taxpayer,'' the company said. <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> lawyers countered that <ORGANIZATION> Digital </ORGANIZATION> and <PERSON> Wang </PERSON> had `` lost this case'' after prevailing on a single, insignificant issue. As evidence, they pointed to the two companies's withdrawal from the competition in January. The board disagreed, saying that only after the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> corrected its solicitation were <ORGANIZATION> Digital </ORGANIZATION> and <PERSON> Wang </PERSON> able to determine whether they should compete on the government's terms. Their challenge produced the `` benefit of full and open competition, which is the touchstone and objective of procurement law,'' it said. <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> attorney <PERSON> Kevin </PERSON> <PERSON> Vincent </PERSON> said the board's decision was wrong but that the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> had not decided what to do next. <PERSON> Wang </PERSON> spokesman <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Roy </PERSON> indicated that the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> and the companies had begun discussing a possible settlement, as urged by the <ORGANIZATION> GSA </ORGANIZATION> board. A spokesman for <ORGANIZATION> Digital </ORGANIZATION> failed to return a phone call Friday.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880911-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-11-88 1129EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-RevivedMan     09-11 0246</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Revived Man,0253</SECOND>
<HEAD>Man Revived After Suffering Heart Attack During CPR Course</HEAD>
<DATELINE>HARTFORD, Conn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A 74-year-old man suffered a heart attack while practicing life-saving techniques in a cardiopulmonary resuscitation course, but was revived by his instructors. <PERSON> Melvin </PERSON> <PERSON> Bishop </PERSON>' eyes rolled up and he fell over while compressing the chest of a practice dummy during the CPR class Saturday at the <ORGANIZATION> Aetna </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Life </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ; </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Casualty </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> building, instructor <PERSON> Len </PERSON> <PERSON> Heroux </PERSON> said. Finding no pulse, <PERSON> Heroux </PERSON> began performing the same compression technique <PERSON> Bishop </PERSON> had been practicing. <PERSON> Heroux </PERSON> was joined by <PERSON> Carl </PERSON> <PERSON> Ireland </PERSON>, another instructor, who performed compression while <PERSON> Heroux </PERSON> blew air into <PERSON> Bishop </PERSON>'s lungs. They regained a pulse, then lost it again. The instructors were joined by <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON> <PERSON> K. </PERSON> <PERSON> Scierka </PERSON>, director of field operations for <ORGANIZATION> L </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; M <ORGANIZATION> Ambulance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Professional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ambulance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>, who was at the site demonstrating his paramedic equipment. <PERSON> Scierka </PERSON> put a cardiac monitor on <PERSON> Bishop </PERSON> and determined he had ventricular tachycardia _ an irregular heartbeat that keeps the heart from pumping blood _ and gave <PERSON> Bishop </PERSON>'s heart an electric shock with a defibrillator. As about 20 stunned students looked on, <PERSON> Bishop </PERSON>'s heart began pumping. He soon regained consciousness and began talking, smiling and thanking his rescuers. <PERSON> Bishop </PERSON> was given medicine intravenously and taken to <LOCATION> Hartford </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION>, where he was listed in stable condition. Dr. <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Pariser </PERSON>, <PERSON> Bishop </PERSON>'s cardiologist, said <PERSON> Bishop </PERSON> told him he wanted to learn the technique because `` he did n't want to have to stand there helpless'' if someone collapsed.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880911-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-11-88 1129EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w AM-DuneShacks     09-11 0402</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Dune Shacks,370</SECOND>
<HEAD>Lawmakers Push For Preservation Of Cape Cod's Rustic Dune Shacks</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CHRISTOPHER CALLAHAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Three members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> are urging the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Park </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> to abandon its plan to tear down the rustic shacks on remote dunes of <LOCATION> Cape </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Cod </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mass. </LOCATION>, that have inspired artists and authors including playwright <PERSON> Eugene </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Neill </PERSON>. The park service argues that the 18 dune shacks do not have architectural significance and therefore should not be placed on the National Register of Historic Places. Three <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> Democrats, Sens. <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> and <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kerry </PERSON> and Rep. <PERSON> Gerry </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Studds </PERSON>, who represents the <LOCATION> Cape </LOCATION>, are joining state and local officials in a fight to save the primitive huts from destruction. `` These buildings represent a unique aspect of American history and culture that should be preserved for future generations,'' they wrote <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Penn </PERSON> <PERSON> Mott </PERSON>, director of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Park </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>, last week. `` We believe the dune shacks are indeed historic structures.'' The shacks, nestled in a two-mile strip of dunes in <LOCATION> Truro </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Provincetown </LOCATION> at the far end of the <LOCATION> Cape </LOCATION>, were originally built by the <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> as shelters from harsh coastal weather. They became part of the park service's domain in 1961 when President <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> created the <LOCATION> Cape </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Cod </LOCATION> <LOCATION> National </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Seashore </LOCATION>. The shacks' preservation has become an emotional issue in recent years because the expiration of one-time leases signed when the national seashore was created, usually for the owner's lifetime or 25 years. Preservationists want the federal government to declare the shacks historic treasures and allow a private organization to mantain them for public use. A study commissioned by the park service concluded that the primitive structures do not qualify for National Register protection. But critics say the study focused on the buildings' lack of architectural importance and ignored their historical and cultural significance that some proponents compare to that of <LOCATION> Walden </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Pond </LOCATION>, home of <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Thoreau </PERSON> With local support growing in favor of preserving the shacks, the <ORGANIZATION> Massachusetts </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Historical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> is expected to vote Wednesday in <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> to urge federal officials to save the buildings. The park service said it will issue a statement at that meeting. `` I am hopeful that they will decide that in years to come, many more people will have the same oppportunity for inspiration that the dune shacks have offered <PERSON> Eugene </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Neill </PERSON>, <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON>, <PERSON> Norman </PERSON> <PERSON> Mailer </PERSON> and many others,'' <PERSON> Studds </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880911-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-11-88 1130EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-HarvardStudy     09-11 0633</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Harvard Study,0649</SECOND>
<HEAD>Harvard Freshman Want More Study Time, Less Class Time</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KEVIN GALVIN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CAMBRIDGE, Mass. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The typical Harvard freshman spends nearly 41 hours a week in class or studying, does n't go to sleep until after 1 a.m., and sometimes loses effectiveness because of weariness, depression and stress, according to a recent study. <PERSON> Keith </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Light </PERSON>, a doctoral candidate in education at <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION>, asked 63 first-year students to log their days 15 minutes at a time for one week in March and one week in April. `` We assume that because they're coming to <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> they have their acts together in every way,'' he said. `` I do n't think that's true, having been a proctor -LRB- adviser -RRB- living in a freshman dorm for three years. The study was intended to determine if a time-logging exercise might be useful to new students and their advisers in helping the students make better use of their time. `` I've always been interested in the freshman experience of getting used to college life,'' Light said. `` It seems to be that the actual use of time not only affects a first-year student academically but also their sense of fulfillment and enjoyment in the experience.'' Fifty-six percent of the students said on at least one day that they were too weary to be productive. Thirty-seven percent said depression, frustration or stress made them unproductive. In addition to logging each period's activities, students were asked to indicate which ones were most valuable and which were a waste of time. Television was listed as a common time-waster, but more students mentioned at least once that a class or a lab was a waste of time. Forty-four percent said they wasted time watching television on at least one day during the survey period, but 62 percent thought classes were a waste of time and 54 percent felt labs were little help. Just 6 percent reported that they wasted time on drinking or a hangover at least once during the survey period. The students said they devoted an average of 5.83 hours a day, or 40.8 hours a week, to academics, including class time, study time and lab time. Students generally spend about 15 hours a week in the classroom, Light said. Light said he did not seek a random sample for his survey, but he got a good cross-section of the freshman class by simply asking students in two sections of one dormitory to participate. He said the 63 respondents from the 1,600-member class was about twice the minimum sample group for a survey. `` It's a carefully done study, but it's modest,'' Light said. `` We're not trying to draw too many earth-shattering generalizations but get to something that will help them put their time togther.'' Seventy-three percent said in retrospect they would have changed the way they spent a day. `` While many students could tell you, ` Yes, I do procrastinate' and ` Yes, I do n't get enough sleep sometimes' and ` I know if I studied without heavy metal -LRB- rock music -RRB- in the background I might be able to concentrate,' the exercise seems to be able to give students a more realistic views of how they spend their time,'' Light said During school nights, the students got an average of 7.5 hours of sleep on a school night, but not by going to bed early. Seventy-five percent of the students said they did n't get to bed until after midnight and 61 percent said they were usually up past 1 a.m. Even at 3 a.m., some 12 percent were awake. Light conducted follow-up interviews with 24 students and said most of them found the exercise useful in evaluating the way they spend their time. This fall, officials asked Light to make the exercise available to all freshmen who might find it helpful.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880911-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-11-88 1136EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Charles-HongKong     09-11 0316</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Charles-Hong Kong,0324</SECOND>
<HEAD>Thatcher Suggests Prince Could Be Hong Kong Governor: Report</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Prime Minister <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> has suggested to Prince <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> that he become governor of <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> in time to hand the British colony over to <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> in 1997, a newspaper reported Sunday. The Sunday Times of <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> quoted from a new biography of the heir to the British throne, `` <PERSON> Charles </PERSON>,'' by journalist <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON> <PERSON> Holden </PERSON>. The paper owns the newspaper rights to the book. <PERSON> Holden </PERSON>'s book says the <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> suggestion was made during a March 25 meeting between <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> and Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> at the prince's <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> residence, <LOCATION> Kensington </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Palace </LOCATION> It followed `` a discussion of the prince's wish that he might in the longer term be accorded some sort of title to reflect his increased status in national affairs,'' <PERSON> Holden </PERSON> says in his book. However, the appointment of <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s governor to <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION>, one of the most sensitive posts in <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s diplomatic service, is made by <PERSON> Charles </PERSON>' mother, <PERSON> Queen </PERSON> <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> II </PERSON>, not the prime minister. Buckingham Palace had no comment on the report, and a spokesman for Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON>'s 10 Downing St. office said Sunday, `` We never comment on any contacts between the prime minister and members of the royal family.'' <PERSON> Holden </PERSON> attributes his information to two separate sources he says are confidants of the prince's, the newspaper said. The author said in a television interview Sunday that <PERSON> Charles </PERSON>, who celebrates his 40th birthday in November, `` still feels despite everything that people think he has n't got a proper job.'' <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> has been training all his life to succeed his mother, who is 62 years old and in good health. <PERSON> Holden </PERSON> said he thinks the prince would welcome the <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> job `` because it would be seen to give him a higher profile in national life ... he would be seen to be doing something on the forefront of the international stage.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880911-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-11-88 1137EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Eclipse-Bath     09-11 0296</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Eclipse-Bath,0304</SECOND>
<HEAD>Pilgrims Bathe In Sacred Rivers During Solar Eclipse</HEAD>
<DATELINE>KURUKSHETRA, India (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Hundreds of thousands of Hindu pilgrims plunged into sacred rivers and pools during a solar eclipse Sunday, believing they would be freed of sin and attain salvation. Authorities said a 12-year-old boy drowned. As the moon partially passed between the <LOCATION> Earth </LOCATION> and sun, worshipers chanted hymns and blew conch shells. About 3,000 naked holy men waded into the giant sacred pools of <LOCATION> Sannihit </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Brahmsarovar </PERSON>, followed in turns by an estimated 500,000 men and women, some clothed, others naked. Many carried coconuts, auspicious symbols for Hindus, and set them in the water. Others gave alms to beggars or Hindu priests, who offered prayers to the sun. There is an ancient belief that the sun is in pain during an eclipse and prayers must be offered for its relief. The scene was repeated, in smaller numbers, at rivers and pools across <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>. An epic Hindu poem, the `` Mahabharata,'' promises salvation to those who bathe or give alms at <LOCATION> Kurukshetra </LOCATION> during a solar eclipse. <LOCATION> Kurukshetra </LOCATION>'s larger pool, <PERSON> Brahmasarovar </PERSON>, has a two-mile perimeter. <PERSON> Sannihit </PERSON>'s perimeter is about half that size. The pools can accomodate 125,000 people. Thousands of police stood guard and directed traffic in the town of 25,000 people about 90 miles north of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Delhi </LOCATION>. Divers and lifeguards kept watch over the bathers but could not save the 12-year-old boy from drowning, authorities said. The eclipse, which lasted about 90 minutes, was the third in the past year. The others occurred on March 18 and Sept. 13, 1987. According to Hindu legend, <LOCATION> Kurukshetra </LOCATION> was created by the Hindu god Lord <PERSON> Brahma </PERSON> and was the scene of an ancient battle in which Lord Vishnu, the protector of the Hindu diety, pleaded for righteousness.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880911-0025 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-11-88 1137EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-BRF--Ecuador-Crash     09-11 0148</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Ecuador-Crash,0152</SECOND>
<HEAD>20 Killed In Bus Accident In Eucador</HEAD>
<DATELINE>GUAYAQUIL, Ecuador (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A crowded passenger bus slammed into a stalled cement truck on a coastal highway, killing 20 and injuring at least 20 others, police said. The crash occurred before dawn Saturday as the bus, carrying 60 passengers to a <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> beach, rounded a curve and struck the truck, which was pulled to the side of the highway but was not using emergency lights, police said. The bus, owned by the private bus line Cica, was on its way from <LOCATION> Guayaquil </LOCATION> to coastal <PERSON> Salinas </PERSON>, 72 miles to the northwest. Police said the accident occurred 25 miles northwest of <LOCATION> Guayaquil </LOCATION>. Police said 20 people were killed and 40 survived the crash. At least 20 of the survivors were injured, they said. The condition of the bus driver and any occupants of the cement truck was not available.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880911-0026 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-11-88 1138EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-BRF--Algeria-Blast     09-11 0108</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Algeria-Blast,0111</SECOND>
<HEAD>Gas Explosion Kills 11, Injures 15</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ALGIERS, Algeria (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A gas explosion destroyed a store and damaged a block of apartments in a suburb of <LOCATION> Algiers </LOCATION>, killing 11 people and injuring 15 others, a government official said Sunday. Five people were injured seriously after the Saturday morning blast, said the official, speaking on condition of anonymity. No further details were available on the condition of the injured or on the exact cause of the explosion in the suburb of Eucalyptus, near the town of el-Harrach, southeast of <LOCATION> Algiers </LOCATION>. The building residents who lost their apartments were given lodging by the government, the official said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880911-0027 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-11-88 1138EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-BagBaby     09-11 0325</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Bag Baby,0337</SECOND>
<HEAD>Woman Finds Infant In Grocery Bag</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LAKE WORTH, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
