<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880805-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-05-88 0158EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Gulf-Stress     08-05 1030</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Gulf-Stress,1062</SECOND>
<HEAD>Navy Strives To Deal With Stress Of Persian Gulf Duty</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</NOTE>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 The Pentagon inquiry into the shooting down of an Iranian civilian jetliner on July 3 is reported to have found that `` human error'' caused by the stress of first-time combat was a factor in the USS Vincennes mistakenly shooting down the plane. Here is a report on the conditions aboard <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> warships in the gulf.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>By RICHARD PYLE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MANAMA, Bahrain (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Inexperience, isolation and the need for a constant state of high alert are factors that contribute to high stress aboard the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> warships in the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION>. Just before the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> missile frigate <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> sailed into battle April 18, its skipper, Cmdr. <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Mann </PERSON>, noted that only two among the 225 men aboard had ever been in combat _ himself and his senior chief petty officer. The statistic is not unusual for a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> warship in the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION>, whose crews average about 23 years of age and usually include a few 18-year-olds away from home for the first time. <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> officers say such factors as inexperience, the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION>'s oppressive heat, isolation at sea and the demands of staying at high alert around the clock, add up to a `` high stress'' situation that can affect performance. <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> sources say the investigation of the July 3 shooting down of an Iranian jetliner with 290 people aboard by the missile cruiser <LOCATION> Vincennes </LOCATION> found `` human error,'' apparently caused by stress in first-time combat, led radar operators to mistake the A300 <ORGANIZATION> Airbus </ORGANIZATION> for a military attack plane. It was not the first time in <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> operations that radar signals have been misinterpreted by radar operators. In an April 18 clash between <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and Iranian forces, the <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>' radar indicated it and two other warships were under attack by Iranian Silkworm anti-ship missiles. The ships took evasive maneuvers and launched anti-missile chaff. Gen. <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Crist </PERSON>, commander of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Central Command, later said analysis of computer tapes showed no hostile missiles were fired and the blips were the tracks of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> missiles and what the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> called `` hits on the system.'' On Thursday, a Central Command spokesman, Maj. <PERSON> Barry </PERSON> <PERSON> Willey </PERSON>, said that study found no `` human error, lack of training or technical malfunction,'' and the ships' officers were justified in assuming they were under attack. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials would not comment on a report that one of the <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>' `` Stinger'' anti-aircraft missile operators was later sent home, suffering apparent psychological problems from his first combat exposure. `` He just kind of choked,'' said a friend, who spoke on condition of anonymity. The <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>'s methods for dealing with stress begin with intensive training, which officers say builds confidence, and includes other means ranging from sports, exercise and recreational diversions to personal counseling. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officers readily concede that such efforts are not foolproof. `` When a routine that's already full of tension suddenly becomes something a lot bigger, with real danger, maybe shooting, you ca n't predict how people are going to react, especially if they've never done it before,'' said one officer A key element in coping with stress is to assure sailors they are not alone in facing pressure, said another officer. `` We emphasize togetherness, that everybody's part of a team _ the combat information team, the gunnery team, the flight team, whatever. The better your relationships, the better you can function in a situation.'' Few ships promote a `` team'' concept as strenuously as the <LOCATION> Vincennes </LOCATION>. `` Team 49,'' alluding to its hull number, appears on bulletin boards, souvenirs and baseball caps, and is used by Capt. <PERSON> Will </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Rogers </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON> in addressing his crew. Skippers say their biggest concern is keeping crews in the high state of constant readiness needed in the gulf, where short distances require fast decisions. `` The hardest part of the mission is that you have to stay ready 24 hours a day. There's no time, really, to let your guard down,'' said Cmdr. <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> X. </PERSON> <PERSON> Rinn </PERSON>. Three weeks later, <PERSON> Rinn </PERSON>'s ship, the frigate <PERSON> Samuel </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Roberts </PERSON>, was nearly sunk when it hit an Iranian mine. Shipboard tensions and boredom are relieved as much as possible by recreational activities. Aboard the amphibious assault ship <LOCATION> Dubuque </LOCATION>, the crew recently was treated to boxing matches and a rock concert by a touring USO band. `` It's great way to let off steam,'' said a sailor after defeating one of his buddies in the day's featured three-round heavyweight match. Some <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> ships have spent virtually all of their three-month gulf tours escorting convoys or on patrol, and <PERSON> Crist </PERSON> said one reason for deploying a multipurpose warship like the <LOCATION> Vincennes </LOCATION> was to allow others more time in port. Many officers say the entire <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> was badly shaken by the shooting down of the Iranian jetliner. However, they say it has not caused any noticeable morale crisis, and the general view is that in the same situation, most commanders would act just as <PERSON> Rogers </PERSON> did. `` Every C.O. has to call his best shot, based on the information flow he gets at the time ... and live with that decision the rest of his life. That's what command is all about,'' said the <LOCATION> Dubuque </LOCATION>'s skipper, Capt <PERSON> Alex </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Balian </PERSON>, who won the Silver Star for valor in <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> traditionally relies on chaplains and doctors to counsel those in need, with psychological guidance available in extreme cases. Gulf-based <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> officers said no special stress counseling or confidence-building programs have been set up in the aftermath of the <LOCATION> Vincennes </LOCATION> affair. `` We do n't have a morale problem,'' said one. Capt. W.D. Center, commander of the missile cruiser <PERSON> Reeves </PERSON> and a friend of <LOCATION> Vincennes </LOCATION>' skipper <PERSON> Rogers </PERSON>, recalled that when the Airbus was shot down, his ship was just two days out of home port in <LOCATION> Yokosuka </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, bound for the gulf. `` We talked about it, then we put it behind us. Everybody understands that we have to get on with the job,'' he said.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Pyle </PERSON> has covered the the year-long <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> involvement in the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> and sailed on several of the American ships.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880805-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-05-88 0159EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-ForrestalGhost     08-05 0647</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Forrestal Ghost,0667</SECOND>
<HEAD>Shipboard Bumps In The Night? Maybe It's George, The Friendly
Ghost</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>MAYPORT NAVAL STATION, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Ghosts are fine, traditional things to have around ancient English castles, but the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> says rumors of one stalking the depths of the aircraft carrier <ORGANIZATION> USS </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forrestal </ORGANIZATION> have spooked a few sailors. Flickering lights. Bumps in the night. Locked doors opening. Voices on disconnected telephones. And a vanishing figure in a khaki uniform. The figure's even got a nickname: <PERSON> George </PERSON>. At least that's what some of the men say aboard the <ORGANIZATION> Forrestal </ORGANIZATION>, in its fourth month of a six-month deployment in the <LOCATION> Indian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ocean </LOCATION> and the North Arabian Sea. They were interviewed by Lt. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Brooks </PERSON>, who detailed the story of the ghost in a 12-page news release issued last month. The report about <PERSON> George </PERSON> has n't ruffled any <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> feathers, <ORGANIZATION> Mayport </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> spokesman Lt. <PERSON> Park </PERSON> <PERSON> Balevre </PERSON> said Thursday. `` I thought it was cute. I think most people did.'' `` What Lt. <PERSON> Brooks </PERSON> had in mind was a fluff piece to show the lighter side of the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>,'' said <PERSON> Balevre </PERSON>. But according to <ORGANIZATION> Brooks </ORGANIZATION>, some sailors do n't think the ghost story is at all cute. <PERSON> George </PERSON> lurks in two of the ship's below-the-waterline storage areas, one of them a former morgue, spooked sailors claim. `` I've got one guy working for me now who refuses to go down there alone. Our last chief petty officer in charge, who has since transferred, refused to go down there at all,'' says Petty Officer <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Balboa </PERSON>, in charge of the officers' mess. `` I've never seen any ghosts but you can hear weird things down there,'' said <PERSON> Balboa </PERSON>. `` I was taking inventory one night and heard a noise like deck grating being picked up and dropped,'' he recalled. `` I'd turn around and look but did n't see anything. When I turned around to begin my work again, the noise started again.'' One night, <PERSON> Balboa </PERSON> said, he was checking temperatures in food-storage freezers and kept finding open doors he had shut behind him. `` It is impossible for anyone to open the reefer -LRB- refrigerator -RRB- doors from the outside, behind me. To open them from the outside requires a key since the doors lock automatically. `` I had the only key with me. That incident puts me on the verge of believing,'' he said. Some say the ghost is a chief killed during a 1967 flight deck fire that killed 137 sailors in the Gulf of <LOCATION> Tonkin </LOCATION> off the coast of <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Brooks </PERSON> wrote. Others guess he's a pilot whose body was once stored on the ship. Petty Officer <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Hillard </PERSON> has n't ventured into the haunted areas since he saw <PERSON> George </PERSON> last year while checking out odd footsteps. `` He was wearing a khaki uniform, like an officer or chief would wear,'' he says. He followed the apparition into a compartment but `` there was nobody in there, and I swear that is where he went,'' <PERSON> Hillard </PERSON> said. Mess Specialist 2nd Class <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Weiss </PERSON> saw a khaki-clad ghost go down a ladder to pump room No. 1. Whoever went down into the pump room never came out and the ladder is the only access, he said. <PERSON> Hillard </PERSON> said he once was helping move supplies when a telephone that was reportedly disconnected kept ringing. `` The phone rang and I answered it. This time there was a faint voice calling, ` Help! Help! I'm on the sixth deck!' Rumor had it that a crew member was killed down there. I'm very scared to go down there alone. If I do, I get out of there as fast as I can,'' <PERSON> Hillard </PERSON> said. Others are dubious. `` I think it's the guys' imagination,'' said Senior Chief Petty Officer <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>. `` I'm not superstitious but when I go down there by myself, I find it uneasy. When that happens, your imagination is going to play tricks on you.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880805-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-05-88 0200EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-People-ReggieJackson     08-05 0225</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-People-Reggie Jackson,0232</SECOND>
<HEAD>Fire Destroys Part of Reggie Jackson's Car Collection</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BERKELEY, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A warehouse fire destroyed 35 cars owned by <PERSON> Reggie </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, and the retired baseball slugger and classic auto collector says he's `` hurting.'' <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, who lives in nearby <LOCATION> Oakland </LOCATION>, was visibly upset Thursday when he went to the warehouse, which was destroyed by fire Wednesday night. He refused to be interviewed at his <LOCATION> Berkeley </LOCATION> auto dealership, saying he was `` down'' and `` hurting'' about his loss. Thirty-five cars owned by <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> were lost, including Corvettes, Porsches, <ORGANIZATION> Mustangs </ORGANIZATION> and other `` high-value collector cars,'' said fire department Capt. <PERSON> Ron </PERSON> <PERSON> Littley </PERSON>. The fire apparently started in a furniture store and spread to the warehouse in the same cinderblock building, officials said. The blaze raged out of control in the 33,000-square-foot warehouse in an industrial area for more than an hour. `` Everything that was in there was gone,'' said fire Lt. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Allen </PERSON>. The cause of the blaze was not immediately known. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> began his car collection in 1971 when he bought a 1940 Chevrolet for $ 300 and a color television. By last October, the collection had grown to 97 vehicles. The rest of his collection was stored elsewhere. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> retired last fall from the <ORGANIZATION> Oakland </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Athletics </ORGANIZATION> after a stellar career that also included stints with the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Yankees </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Angels </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Baltimore </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Orioles </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880805-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-05-88 0203EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-PoliticalRdp Bjt   08-05 0778</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Political Rdp, Bjt,770</SECOND>
<HEAD>Dukakis Campaigns On Environment; Bush Continues Foreign Policy
Attacks</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: May be topped.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT GREENE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> is laying out his positions on environmental issues during a tour of the West, just as a poll indicated that region represents an untapped resource for Democrats. <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> invoked the names of <LOCATION> Kennedy </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Truman </PERSON> to show <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> has veered `` far outside the mainstream'' on foreign policy. As <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> tried to portray the Democratic presidential nominee as occupying the liberal extreme, his own Republican party's right wing was telling the vice president to avoid `` establishment blue bloods'' when choosing a running mate. The warning from the Coalition for a Winning Ticket came as Gov. <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Deukmejian </PERSON> of <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> took himself out of consideration. In another campaign matter, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> chief of staff <PERSON> Craig </PERSON> <PERSON> Fuller </PERSON> confirmed Thursday that <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON> would leave his post and become campaign chief before the Aug. 15 start of the Republican convention in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION>. Sources said the announcement could come today. `` We do n't have to make the false choice, the fool's choice, between economic growth or environmental quality,'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> told students at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION> at <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>, `` We can have both, and in fact we must have both.'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Coast </LOCATION> foray followed a trip into <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION>, a traditionally Democratic state that helped send President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> to the White House. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> lost the state to <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> in this year's Democratic primary. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> spoke at the <LOCATION> Neshoba </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> fair near where the bodies of three slain civil rights workers were found 24 years ago Thursday. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> campaigned at the fair in 1980 for his first term. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> failed to mention the killings when addressing the almost entirely white crowd, and referred only once to civil rights. `` I talked about economic opportunity because that's the most important single thing that concerns people,'' he explained. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, speaking to a Hispanic veterans group in <LOCATION> Corpus </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Christi </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, criticized <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> for his support for a nuclear freeze and opposition to a new MX missile, the Midgetman missile and the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration's proposed Star Wars nuclear defense system. `` His positions ... amount to a rejection of <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s role as a world leader and a repudiation of the <PERSON> Truman </PERSON> doctrine and the vision of <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said, referring to bipartisan foreign policy that evolved after World War II and focused on containing communism. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, when asked whether he still supports a nuclear freeze, said, `` Sure, and a comprehensive test ban treaty.'' Later aboard his plane, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> said he originally supported a freeze `` because we wanted to stop the administration from expanding the arsenal.'' `` Now, it's turned around and we're talking about reduction. I'm for reductions now,'' he said `` I favor the development of certain arms systems. I favor deep cuts in strategic weapons systems.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> also stabbed at the Democratic platform, calling it `` the black hole of American politics.'' `` Issues get sucked into it and lost, never to reappear again,'' he said. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> later detoured to <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> for the wake of a Polish-American leader. It was his third such appearance this week in an ethnic setting as the certain <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> nominee tries to keep <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, the multilingual son of immigrants, from winning that segment of the population. <PERSON> Deukmejian </PERSON> said he took himself out of consideration because Democrats would gain control of the Statehouse in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> if he dropped out. The <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> campaign said it accepted his decision. Sen. <PERSON> Gordon </PERSON> <PERSON> Humphrey </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-N.H. </LOCATION>, who heads the conservative coalition urging <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> to choose someone from the right, said Thursday: `` The problem of the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> campaign is that it is attracted to establishment blue-bloods. What the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> ticket needs is a transfusion of red corpuscles from the conservative wing of our party.'' He said Sen. <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION>, Rep. <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> and Gov. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Sununu </PERSON> of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION> would be acceptable. A recent analysis by The Gallup Organization seems to give the Democratic ticket hope in formerly pro-Reagan Western states. The analysis said Western voters are optimistic about their own financial future but dissatisfied with the general course of the nation, and they do n't find in <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> the anti-establishment leader they found in <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>. For example, `` traditionally anti-government voters in the <LOCATION> Rocky </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mountains </LOCATION> are now calling for more government action on social issues than is the average American voter,'' wrote <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> <PERSON> Kohut </PERSON>, head of the Gallup organization. <PERSON> Kohut </PERSON> said the regional analyses he released were developed from 8,500 detailed interviews taken between May and July. The margin of error is just under 2 percentage points. The analysis was done for the <ORGANIZATION> Times-Mirror </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880805-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-05-88 0208EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w BC-HouseInternmentRollCall 3Takes   08-05 0491</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-House Internment Roll Call, 3 Takes,450-1,200</SECOND>
<HEAD>With PM-Internment Bjt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here is the 257-156 roll call Thursday by which the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> gave final congressional approval to legislation to provide payments and an official government apology to Japanese-Americans sent to internment camps during World War II. A `` yes'' vote is a vote in favor of the legislation. Voting yes were 185 Democrats and 72 Republicans. Voting no were 56 Democrats and 100 Republicans. X denotes those not voting. Present denotes those who voted they were `` present'' at the time of the vote but did not vote `` yes'' or `` no'' on the issue. There are three vacancies in the 435-member House.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>ALABAMA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <PERSON> Bevill </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Erdreich </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Flippo </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Harris </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Nichols </PERSON>, N. Republicans _ <PERSON> Callahan </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Dickinson </PERSON>, N.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>ALASKA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Republican _ Young, Y.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>ARIZONA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrat _ <PERSON> Udall </PERSON>, <PERSON> Y. </PERSON> <PERSON> Republicans </PERSON> _ <PERSON> Kolbe </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Kyl </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Rhodes </PERSON>, Y; Stump, N.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>ARKANSAS</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> N. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> _ <PERSON> Hammerschmidt </PERSON>, N.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>CALIFORNIA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ Anderson, Y; <PERSON> Bates </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Beilenson </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Berman </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Bosco </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Boxer </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Coelho </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Dellums </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Dixon </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Dymally </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Fazio </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Hawkins </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Lantos </PERSON>, Y; <LOCATION> Lehman </LOCATION>, Y; <PERSON> Levine </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Martinez </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Matsui </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Miller </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Mineta </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Panetta </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Pelosi </PERSON> Y; <PERSON> Roybal </PERSON>, Y; Stark, Y; <PERSON> Torres </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Waxman </PERSON>, Y. Republicans _ <PERSON> Badham </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Dannemeyer </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Dornan </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Dreier </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Gallegly </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Herger </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Hunter </PERSON>, N; <LOCATION> Konnyu </LOCATION>, Y; <PERSON> Lagomarsino </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Lowery </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Lungren </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> McCandless </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Moorhead </PERSON>, N; Packard, N; <PERSON> Pashayan </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Shumway </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON>, Y.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>COLORADO</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <ORGANIZATION> Campbell </ORGANIZATION>, Y; <PERSON> Schroeder </PERSON>, Y, <PERSON> Skaggs </PERSON>, Y. Republicans _ <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Hefley </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Schaefer </PERSON>, N.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>CONNECTICUT</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ Gejdenson, Y; <PERSON> Kennelly </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Morrison </PERSON>, Y. Republicans _ <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>, Y; <LOCATION> Rowland </LOCATION>, Y; <PERSON> Shays </PERSON>, Y.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>DELAWARE</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrat _ Carper, N.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>FLORIDA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Chappell </PERSON>, X; <PERSON> Fascell </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Gibbons </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Grant </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Hutto </PERSON>, N; <LOCATION> Lehman </LOCATION>, Y; MacKay, X; <PERSON> Mica </PERSON>, X; <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON>, Y; Pepper, Y; <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, Y. Republicans _ <PERSON> Bilirakis </PERSON>, N; <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION>, N; <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Mack </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> McCollum </PERSON>, N; Shaw, N; Young, N.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>GEORGIA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <PERSON> Barnard </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Darden </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Hatcher </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Jenkins </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Ray </PERSON>, N; <LOCATION> Rowland </LOCATION>, N; <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON>, N. Republicans _ <PERSON> Gingrich </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Swindall </PERSON>, Y.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>HAWAII</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrat _ <PERSON> Akaka </PERSON>, <PERSON> Y. </PERSON> <PERSON> Republican </PERSON> <PERSON> _ </PERSON> <PERSON> Saiki </PERSON>, Y.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>IDAHO</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrat _ <PERSON> Stallings </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Y. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> _ <PERSON> Craig </PERSON>, Y.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>ILLINOIS</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <PERSON> Annunzio </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Collins </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Durbin </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Evans </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Gray </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Hayes </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Lipinski </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Rostenkowski </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Russo </PERSON>, Y; Savage, Y; <PERSON> Yates </PERSON>, Y. Republicans _ Crane, N; <PERSON> Davis </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Fawell </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Hastert </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Hyde </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Madigan </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Martin </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Michel </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Porter </PERSON>, Y.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>INDIANA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <LOCATION> Hamilton </LOCATION>, Y; <PERSON> Jacobs </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Jontz </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> McCloskey </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Sharp </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Visclosky </PERSON>, Y. Republicans _ <PERSON> Burton </PERSON>, N; Coats, N; <PERSON> Hiler </PERSON>, N; Myers, Y.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>IOWA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <PERSON> Nagle </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, Y. Republicans _ <PERSON> Grandy </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Leach </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Lightfoot </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Tauke </PERSON>, N.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>KANSAS</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <PERSON> Glickman </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Slattery </PERSON>, Y. Republicans _ <PERSON> Meyers </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Roberts </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Whittaker </PERSON>, N.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>MORE</NOTE>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880805-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-05-88 0209EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w BC-HouseInternmentRollCall 1stAdd   08-05 0397</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-House Internment Roll Call, 1st Add,400</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHN: Whittaker, N.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>KENTUCKY</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <PERSON> Hubbard </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Mazzoli </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Natcher </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Perkins </PERSON>, Y. Republicans _ <PERSON> Bunning </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Hopkins </PERSON>, N; <ORGANIZATION> Rogers </ORGANIZATION>, N.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>LOUISIANA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <PERSON> Boggs </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Hayes </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Huckaby </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Tauzin </PERSON>, N. Republicans _ <PERSON> Baker </PERSON>, N; <LOCATION> Holloway </LOCATION>, N; <PERSON> Livingston </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> McCrery </PERSON>, N.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>MAINE</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrat _ <PERSON> Brennan </PERSON>, <PERSON> Y. </PERSON> <PERSON> Republican </PERSON> <PERSON> _ </PERSON> <PERSON> Snowe </PERSON>, Y.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>MARYLAND</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <PERSON> Byron </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Cardin </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Dyson </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Hoyer </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> McMillen </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Mfume </PERSON>, Y. Republicans _ <PERSON> Bentley </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Morella </PERSON>, Y.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>MASSACHUSETTS</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <PERSON> Atkins </PERSON>, Y; <LOCATION> Boland </LOCATION>, Y; <PERSON> Donnelly </PERSON>, Y; Early, Y; <PERSON> Frank </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Markey </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Mavroules </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Moakley </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Studds </PERSON>, Y. Republican _ <PERSON> Conte </PERSON>, Y.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>MICHIGAN</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <PERSON> Bonior </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Carr </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Conyers </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Crockett </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Dingell </PERSON>, Y; <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION>, Y; <PERSON> Hertel </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Kildee </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Levin </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Traxler </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Wolpe </PERSON>, Y. Republicans _ <LOCATION> Broomfield </LOCATION>, Y; <PERSON> Davis </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Henry </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Pursell </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Schuette </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Upton </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Vander </PERSON> <PERSON> Jagt </PERSON>, N.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>MINNESOTA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <PERSON> Oberstar </PERSON>, Y; <ORGANIZATION> Penny </ORGANIZATION>, N; <PERSON> Sabo </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Sikorski </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Vento </PERSON>, Y. Republicans _ <PERSON> Frenzel </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Stangeland </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Weber </PERSON>, Y.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>MISSISSIPPI</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ Dowdy, X; <PERSON> Espy </PERSON>, X; <PERSON> Montgomery </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Whitten </PERSON>, Y. Republican _ <PERSON> Lott </PERSON>, X.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>MISSOURI</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ Clay, Y; <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON>, X; <PERSON> Skelton </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Volkmer </PERSON>, Y; Wheat, Y. Republicans _ <PERSON> Buechner </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Coleman </PERSON>, N; <LOCATION> Emerson </LOCATION>, N; <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON>, X.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>MONTANA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrat _ Williams, <ORGANIZATION> Y. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> _ <PERSON> Marlenee </PERSON>, N.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>NEBRASKA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Republicans _ <PERSON> Bereuter </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Daub </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, N.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>NEVADA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrat _ <PERSON> Bilbray </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Y. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> _ <PERSON> Vucanovich </PERSON>, Y.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>NEW HAMPSHIRE</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Republicans _ <PERSON> Gregg </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, N.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>NEW JERSEY</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <PERSON> Dwyer </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Florio </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Guarini </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Hughes </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Rodino </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Roe </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Torricelli </PERSON>, Y. Republicans _ <PERSON> Courter </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Gallo </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Rinaldo </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Roukema </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Saxton </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, Y.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>NEW MEXICO</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrat _ <PERSON> Richardson </PERSON>, <PERSON> Y. </PERSON> <PERSON> Republicans </PERSON> <PERSON> _ </PERSON> <PERSON> Lujan </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Skeen </PERSON>, Y.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>NEW YORK</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <PERSON> Ackerman </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Biaggi </PERSON>, X; <PERSON> Downey </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Flake </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Garcia </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Hochbrueckner </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> LaFalce </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Manton </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> McHugh </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Mrazek </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Nowak </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Owens </PERSON>, X; <PERSON> Rangel </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Scheuer </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Schumer </PERSON>, Y; Slaughter, Y; <PERSON> Solarz </PERSON>, Y; <LOCATION> Stratton </LOCATION>, N; Towns, Y; <PERSON> Weiss </PERSON>, Y. Republicans _ <PERSON> Boehlert </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> DioGuardi </PERSON>, N; Fish, Y; <PERSON> Gilman </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Green </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Horton </PERSON>, Y; <LOCATION> Houghton </LOCATION>, N; <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON>, X; Lent, N; <PERSON> Martin </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> McGrath </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Molinari </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Solomon </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Wortley </PERSON>, Y.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>NORTH CAROLINA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <PERSON> Clarke </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Hefner </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>, Y; <LOCATION> Lancaster </LOCATION>, Y; <PERSON> Neal </PERSON>, N; Price, Y; <PERSON> Rose </PERSON>, N; Valentine, Y. Republicans _ <PERSON> Ballenger </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Coble </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> McMillan </PERSON>, N.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>NORTH DAKOTA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrat _ <PERSON> Dorgan </PERSON>, N.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>MORE</NOTE>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880805-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-05-88 0209EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w BC-SocialSecurity-Figures     08-05 0356</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Social Security-Figures,350</SECOND>
<HEAD>With PM-Social Security</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here is an example of the information the <ORGANIZATION> Social </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> will provide in its new `` Personal Earnings and Benefit Estimate Statement.'' The figures are actual estimates for a 40-year-old `` John Q. Public'' based on a history of moderate wages for the past two decades. This person, born Dec. 16, 1947, must wait until 66 to qualify for full Social Security retirement benefits. He told Social Security he earned $ 23,938 in 1987, expects to earn $ 23,000 this year and the equivalent of $ 23,000 in future years. Social Security reported back that his earnings record showed nothing earned in 1963 and earlier, and the following in Social Security-taxed earnings and estimated taxes paid since then: 1964: $ 632 $ 22. 1965: $ 497 $ 18. 1966: $ 3,607 $ 151. 1967: $ 4,053 $ 178. 1968: $ 3,833 $ 168. 1969: $ 5,282 $ 253. 1970: $ 6,253 $ 300. 1971: $ 7,142 $ 371. 1972: $ 8,295 $ 431. 1973: $ 9,001 $ 526. 1974: $ 10,239 $ 599 1975: $ 11,163 $ 653 1976: $ 11,516 $ 673 1977: $ 12,663 $ 740 1978: $ 13,769 $ 833 1979: $ 15,158 $ 929 1989: $ 17,407 $ 1,067 1981: $ 18,495 $ 1,229 1982: $ 20,858 $ 1,397 1983: $ 22,485 $ 1,506 1984: $ 25,085 $ 1,680 1985: $ 26,587 $ 1,874 1986: $ 25,647 $ 1,833 1987: Not Yet Posted
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 Then it provided the following retirement benefit estimates: At age 62, a monthly benefit in today's dollars of $ 730. At age 66, $ 970. At age 70, $ 1,285.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 SURVIVORS: A surviving child could get $ 605 a month. If a child and a surviving spouse caring for a child both qualify, each could get $ 605. The surviving spouse could receive $ 810 a month when she or her reaches full retirement age. The maximum family benefit would be $ 1,420 a month.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 DISABILITY: This worker's monthly disability check would be $ 805. He and his family could receive up to $ 1,205 a month.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 The booklet will also explain the payroll tax rates, currently 7.51 percent on employees and employers and 13.02 percent on the self-employed. The tax pays for both Social Security and <ORGANIZATION> Medicare </ORGANIZATION>. The brochures notes that currently, the average monthly benefit for a retired worker 65 or older is $ 523, plus Medicare benefits valued at $ 202 a month.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880805-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-05-88 0215EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-BeachWaste-Congress     08-05 0589</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Beach Waste-Congress,580</SECOND>
<HEAD>Administration Backs Tough Penalties for Medical Waste Dumpers</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto WX10</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CHRISTOPHER CALLAHAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> is backing a congressional move to stiffen prison terms and fines for the kind of medical waste dumping that has left coastlines from <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION> littered with syringes, dirty bandages and other hospital refuse. Legislation drafted by Rep. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Hughes </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.J. </LOCATION>, would make medical waste dumping at sea a federal crime punishable by up to $ 250,000 in fines and five years in prison. A hauler dumping hospital debris less than three miles from shore today could face up to 15 years in prison and $ 250,000 in fines under the Clean Water Act, but violators outside the three-mile limit would face a maximum of $ 50,000 in fines and one year in prison under the applicable Marine Sanctuary Act. <PERSON> Hughes </PERSON> expressed concern that the current laws may not apply to liquid medical waste or cover streams and other non-navigable waters. `` It's clear that our existing state and federal laws dealing with the handling and disposal of medical wastes are inadequate and are not being properly enforced,'' <PERSON> Hughes </PERSON> said. `` It's equally clear that time has come to treat this problem as a criminal offense, not just a regulatory matter.'' <PERSON> Hughes </PERSON>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Judiciary </ORGANIZATION> subcommittee on crime, said he hoped the measure would act as a deterrent. And he said he would consider adding one provision to allow federal agents to claim the vessels and trucks used by illegal dumpers and a second provision to extend coverage to land dumping. <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Muszynski </PERSON>, deputy administrator of the <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> for the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York-New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> region, told the subcommittee the agency supports the measure. `` Clearly, it is the feeling of most people that up to a year -LRB- in prison -RRB- is insufficient,'' <PERSON> Muszynski </PERSON> said. Last year, the problem of medical waste washing up on beaches was relegated to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> shores. But in the past month, syringes and other hospital debris have been reported extensively on <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> beaches and sporadically in <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Rhode </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION>. Late Wednesday, <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION> reported its first case of medical waste. `` The sad fact is, there seems to be no scarcity of persons willing to dump these wastes anywhere and everywhere in order to avoid the cost of proper disposal or to reap the profits of improper disposal procedures,'' <PERSON> Hughes </PERSON> said. The congressman said it costs hospitals $ 50 to $ 60 a ton for disposal of non-infectious trash, but up to $ 2,000 a ton for `` red bag'' materials that must be handled by private incineration companies. An estimated 25 percent of the 150 million pounds of waste produced annually by hospitals is considered infectious, <PERSON> Hughes </PERSON> said. The Hughes bill was introduced Tuesday. On Wednesday, the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> passed a measure by Sen. <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Lautenberg </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.J. </LOCATION>, that would require a `` cradle-to-grave'' manifest system in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION> to help officials track medical waste. `` I can no more do my job in the area of environmental protection and enforcement without such a law than I could effectively attack organized crime without wiretaps and the latest surveillance technology,'' <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> Attorney General <PERSON> Cary </PERSON> <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON> said. `` It puts us back to the old gumshoe days.'' <PERSON> Lautenberg </PERSON> and other lawmakers have attacked <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> officials for failing to take action themselves. <PERSON> Muszynski </PERSON> said the agency does not have the authority to create a pilot program especially for three states. He added that the agency is considering a national manifest system for medical waste.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880805-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-05-88 0224EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-VoterRegistration     08-05 0382</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Voter Registration,380</SECOND>
<HEAD>Study Says Most Companies Do Little To Promote Voting</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JAMES HANNAH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The promotion of voting is not among the priorities of many of <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s companies even though the nation is facing a voter participation `` crisis,'' a private group says. People for the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Way </ORGANIZATION> said Thursday that 60 percent of the Fortune 500 companies surveyed conduct little or no organized non-partisan voter registration, education or get-out-the-vote activities. And only 6 percent have voter participation activities that reach beyond their own employees, the group said. Ninety-one of the Fortune 500's top 100 corporations responded to the group's phone and mail surveys, which were conducted in April and May. <PERSON> Melanne </PERSON> <PERSON> Verveer </PERSON>, vice president of the group, said the nation is facing the `` grim possibility'' that for the first time in its history, less than half of the eligible voters will be going to the polls in the presidential election. `` This crisis in participation is the result of a three-decade-long slide in voter participation that threatens to turn our government by all the people into government by less than half the people,'' Ms. <PERSON> Verveer </PERSON> said. She said new institutions must take the lead to stem declining voter participation and she noted that a few businesses have taken exciting initiatives. <PERSON> Sherrod </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> secretary of <ORGANIZATION> state </ORGANIZATION>, said many major corporations in <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> have printed up voter registration forms and mailed them to customers as part of their monthly billing procedures. `` We figure we will put literally millions of registration forms, without government spending ... into prospective voters' hands,'' <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> said <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Akers </PERSON>, vice president of the Cleveland-based <ORGANIZATION> Ameritrust </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION>, said his company began offering voter registration services in <LOCATION> Cuyahoga </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> to its customers and the general public in 1982. `` As a result of our success and the fact that we've had such a good response ... we're going to take this program to the 11 other counties in <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> where we have branches,'' <PERSON> Akers </PERSON> said. Nevertheless, <PERSON> Verveer </PERSON> said that `` the inescapable conclusion of our study is that for the majority of corporations, voter registration is nowhere to be found on their list of priorities.'' The Washington-based People for the American Way is a non-partisan constitutional liberties organization that conducts public education programs on constitutional issues.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880805-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-05-88 0226EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Wedtech-Thumbnails     08-05 0924</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Wedtech-Thumbnails,0981</SECOND>
<HEAD>Sketches Of People Connected To Wedtech</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Biaggi-Wedtech</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Thumbnail sketches of the seven defendants in the <ORGANIZATION> Wedtech </ORGANIZATION> corruption scandal:
</TEXT>
<HEAD>U.S. Rep. Mario Biaggi</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Has represented a <LOCATION> Bronx </LOCATION> district in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> since 1969. A former highly decorated city police officer, he walks with a cane due to a police-related injury. He was convicted Sept. 22, 1987, in <LOCATION> Brooklyn </LOCATION> for obstructing justice and accepting an illegal gratuity and was sentenced to 30 months in prison. That case charged <PERSON> Biaggi </PERSON> sought favorable treatment from the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> and city officials on behalf of <LOCATION> Brooklyn </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Coastal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Drydock </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Repair </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>. On Thursday, <PERSON> Biaggi </PERSON> was convicted of 15 felony counts in the <ORGANIZATION> Wedtech </ORGANIZATION> racketeering trial
</TEXT>
<HEAD>Richard Biaggi</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 39-year-old son of the congressman. A lawyer since 1982, he is a partner in the <ORGANIZATION> Biaggi </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> Ehrlich </PERSON> law firm and lives in <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lee </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.J. </LOCATION> On Thursday, he was acquitted of racketeering charges but convicted of bribe receiving, mail fraud and tax charges in the <ORGANIZATION> Wedtech </ORGANIZATION> scandal.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>John Mariotta</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Born in Spanish <LOCATION> Harlem </LOCATION> of Puerto Rican parents, now lives in <LOCATION> Scarsdale </LOCATION>, an affluent suburb. A tool-and-die maker, he founded <ORGANIZATION> Wedtech </ORGANIZATION> as a small machine shop in the <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bronx </LOCATION> in 1965. He was once described by President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> as a `` hero for the'80s'' for hiring former welfare recipients and ex-drug addicts. He was forced out as <ORGANIZATION> Wedtech </ORGANIZATION> chairman in February 1986. On Thursday, he was convicted of racketeering in the <ORGANIZATION> Wedtech </ORGANIZATION> trial.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>Stanley Simon</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Resigned his $ 80,000-a-year post as <LOCATION> Bronx </LOCATION> borough president on March 11, 1987, to fight the then-pending <ORGANIZATION> Wedtech </ORGANIZATION> indictment. A lawyer and former City Council member. On Thursday, he was convicted of racketeering in the <ORGANIZATION> Wedtech </ORGANIZATION> trial.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>Bernard G. Ehrlich</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 A partner in <ORGANIZATION> Biaggi </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> Ehrlich </PERSON> and a former <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> major general. He was acquitted in December on state charges of bribing then-National Guard Commander Maj. Gen. <PERSON> Vito </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Castellano </PERSON> in return for lobbying <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> on behalf of <ORGANIZATION> Wedtech </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Ehrlich </PERSON> was removed as commander of the 42nd Infantry Division during an investigation into another alleged bribery scheme. The trial in that case is pending in state court. On Thursday, he was convicted of racketeering in the <ORGANIZATION> Wedtech </ORGANIZATION> trial.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>Peter Neglia</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 A former <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> regional director of federal <ORGANIZATION> Small </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Business </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>. He was the <ORGANIZATION> SBA </ORGANIZATION> chief of staff in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> 1984-1986. He opened a law practice in <LOCATION> Brooklyn </LOCATION> after leaving government. On Thursday, he was convicted of racketeering in the <ORGANIZATION> Wedtech </ORGANIZATION> trial.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>Ronald J. Betso</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 A former city police officer who retired after 10 years service in 1978 on a disability pension. He is a friend of <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Neglia </PERSON>. He ran unsuccessfully for the state <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> in 1984. On Thursday, at the <ORGANIZATION> Wedtech </ORGANIZATION> racketeering trial, he was acquitted on all counts.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>OTHERS LINKED TO WEDTECH</HEAD>
<TEXT>

</TEXT>
<HEAD>Edwin Meese III</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Attorney General, former White House counseler. <ORGANIZATION> Then-White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> counselor <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> responded to memos from his friend <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Wallach </PERSON> on behalf of <ORGANIZATION> Wedtech </ORGANIZATION> by directing <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> staffers to ensure <ORGANIZATION> Wedtech </ORGANIZATION> got a fair hearing from the <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> in the company's efforts to obtain a $ 32 million no-bid engine contract. The company was awarded the contract after <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>'s deputy, <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Jenkins </PERSON>, intervened in the spring of 1982, calling a meeting at which officials of the <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Small </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Business </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Wedtech </ORGANIZATION> executives worked out their differences over price and the <ORGANIZATION> SBA </ORGANIZATION> agreed to contribute millions of dollars in advance payments and loans to assist the company A <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> subcommittee report concluded <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> violated a White House ban on intervening in government contracts on behalf of friends. No charges have been brought against <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>E. Robert Wallach</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Longtime friend and former personal lawyer to <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>. According to the report submitted by Special Prosecutor <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> McKay </PERSON> who investigated <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>, <PERSON> Wallach </PERSON> asked <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> to help <ORGANIZATION> Wedtech </ORGANIZATION> -LRB- then known as <ORGANIZATION> Welbilt </ORGANIZATION> -RRB- obtain a government contract. <PERSON> Wallach </PERSON> repeatedly sought and obtained <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>'s intervention on <ORGANIZATION> Wedtech </ORGANIZATION>'s behalf over the next 17 months <PERSON> Wallach </PERSON> faces trial next year on federal racketeering and conspiracy charges that include accepting funds to influence <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> on behalf of <ORGANIZATION> Wedtech </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>W. Franklynn Chinn</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>'s former financial adviser. <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> terminated partnership in May 1987. <PERSON> Chinn </PERSON> was forced to resign from the <ORGANIZATION> Wedtech </ORGANIZATION> board because of allegedly questionable financial transactions and was indicted with <PERSON> Wallach </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>R. Kent London</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Former consultant to <ORGANIZATION> Wedtech </ORGANIZATION> who will stand trial with <PERSON> Wallach </PERSON> and <PERSON> Chinn </PERSON> on charges of improperly siphoning hundreds of thousands of dollars from <ORGANIZATION> Wedtech </ORGANIZATION> after promising they could obtain favorable treatment for the company from <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> and other federal officials.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>Lyn Nofziger</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Former White House political director. <PERSON> Nofziger </PERSON> was convicted in February of urging <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> to intercede to help <ORGANIZATION> Wedtech </ORGANIZATION> get the $ 32 million Army contract. <PERSON> Nofziger </PERSON> was also convicted of illegally contacting <PERSON> Jenkins </PERSON> for the <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Engineers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Beneficial </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, which was seeking to expand civilian manning of <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> support ships. <PERSON> Nofziger </PERSON> was sentenced to 90 days in prison and fined $ 30,000. In his sentencing memo, prosecutor <PERSON> McKay </PERSON> urged a large fine, noting that <PERSON> Nofziger </PERSON> and his business partner, <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bragg </PERSON>, received stock in <ORGANIZATION> Wedtech </ORGANIZATION> as a result of the successful effort to lobby <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>. <PERSON> Nofziger </PERSON> and <PERSON> Bragg </PERSON> sold their stock for more than $ 600,000, according to congressional testimony.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>U.S. Rep. Robert Garcia</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Democratic congressman from the <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bronx </LOCATION>, where <ORGANIZATION> Wedtech </ORGANIZATION> was located. Former <ORGANIZATION> Wedtech </ORGANIZATION> Vice-Chairman <PERSON> Mario </PERSON> <PERSON> Moreno </PERSON> testified under immunity that he made illegal campaign contributions totalling $ 80,000 to <PERSON> Garcia </PERSON> at the request of the congressman and his wife for `` political favors and political introductions.'' <PERSON> Garcia </PERSON> is under investigation.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880805-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-05-88 0231EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Nicaragua     08-05 0518</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nicaragua,0532</SECOND>
<HEAD>Ortega Threatens To Hit Opposition If US Renews Contra Aid</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Shultz, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By FILADELFO ALEMAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MANAGUA, Nicaragua (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON> said the leftist <ORGANIZATION> Sandinista </ORGANIZATION> government would crack down harder on the domestic political opposition if the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> renews assistance to the Contra rebels. Also Thursday, the foreign minister sent <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Secretary of State <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> a note protesting a river boat ambush that the government and witnesses blamed on the rebels. <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> is touring <LOCATION> Latin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> this week and was in <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION> today. In <LOCATION> Uruguay </LOCATION> on Thursday, he accused the Soviets of building airstrips in <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>, and called the <ORGANIZATION> Sandinistas </ORGANIZATION> a cancer that the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> must cut out before it spreads. Aid to the Contras ran out in February, but <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> is considering new money for the insurgents the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has been financing since 1981. The government and the rebels agreed to a cease-fire on March 23, and the government unilaterally extended the truce to the end of August. Speaking at an electricity plant near <LOCATION> Momotombo </LOCATION> about 45 miles northwest of <LOCATION> Managua </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON> warned that the government would `` cut off the oxygen'' of the internal opposition and begin fighting the Contras again if a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> aid package is approved. In <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> on Thursday rejected a $ 27 million <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> proposal for humanitarian aid to the rebels but said <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration could still work out a compromise. `` Yankee pressure is not going to make the <ORGANIZATION> Sandinistas </ORGANIZATION> more flexible,'' <PERSON> Orega </PERSON> said. `` Yankee pressure is going to toughen the Sandinistas.'' The government jailed more than 30 opposition figures and cracked down on opposition media after police broke up a large anti-government rally on July 10. It expelled <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. Ambassador <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Melton </PERSON> and seven other American diplomats, and <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> responded by expelling eight Nicaraguan diplomats. In a note dated Wednesday, Foreign Minister <PERSON> Miguel </PERSON> <PERSON> D'Escoto </PERSON> reminded <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> that Tuesday's boat attack, which killed two people and wounded at least 24, was carried out `` a few hours from your stop in the region.'' `` Your visit to <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> once again has helped encourage the war and the state terrorism that your country practices against <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>, in flagrant violation of the norms and principles of international law,'' <PERSON> D'Escoto </PERSON> wrote. The note was read to The Associated Press by an official at the <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION>. Radio Liberacion, the rebels' station, blamed the attack on the <ORGANIZATION> Sandinistas </ORGANIZATION>. They called it a staged `` attack on themselves'' intended to dissuade the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> from approving new aid for the rebels. The <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> said the boat was hit by rifle and mortar fire about 150 mile southeast of <LOCATION> Managua </LOCATION> on the <LOCATION> Escondido </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION>, a major military supply route of the government. About 200 Nicaraguans and 10 Americans were on the boat, and an American, an Italian and a Costa Rican were among the injured. The Rev. <PERSON> Lucius </PERSON> <PERSON> Walker </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Demarest </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.J. </LOCATION>, who was grazed in the buttocks by a bullet in the attack, said Wednesday the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government was responsible for terrorism because of its financial support for the rebels.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880805-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-05-88 0232EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Israel-Economy     08-05 0777</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Israel-Economy,0801</SECOND>
<HEAD>Uprising, Labor Disputes Heat Up Inflation, Slow Growth</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By KARIN LAUB</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>JERUSALEM (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Palestinian uprising, election year politics and protracted labor disputes are undermining <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s economic recovery program by pushing up inflation and reducing growth Industrial production is down 3.5 percent, the first such drop in eight years, and inflation is expected to exceed 20 percent, up from 16 percent last year and a third higher than initially forecast. `` We had to scale down our expectations'' after more optimistic projections in early 1988, said <PERSON> Ruth </PERSON> <PERSON> Lowental </PERSON>, assistant director general of economic affairs in the <ORGANIZATION> Finance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION>. The gloomier prognosis is accompanied by a `` feeling of insecurity because nobody knows what's going to happen after the -LRB- Nov. 1 national -RRB- election,'' said <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Canaan </PERSON>, an <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> journalist who writes for two West German economic publications. A key reason for the slump is the 8-month-old Arab uprising in the occupied <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strip </LOCATION> already has eaten up more than half of this year's growth, initially projected at 3.7 percent. The uprising has cost more than $ 700 million in lost tourism, uncollected taxes and additional military expenses, said <PERSON> Amnon </PERSON> <PERSON> Neubach </PERSON>, an economic adviser to Foreign Minister <PERSON> Shimon </PERSON> <PERSON> Peres </PERSON>. In addition, fewer of the 1.5 million Palestinians in the occupied lands buy <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> products and about 20 percent of the 110,000 Palestinians working in <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> no longer report to their jobs as a result of a Palestinian boycott. `` When you have 1.5 million consumers who used to buy Israeli products, and they stopped doing it, it has a serious effect,'' said an <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> industrialist, speaking on condition of anonymity. Stability is also threatened by increasing wage demands, backed by numerous strikes by Israeli workers. Excluding Palestinian work stoppages, the Israeli economy lost 1.3 million work days due to strikes in 1987, more than triple the 1986 figure. The labor disputes indicate workers are no longer willing to make the kind of sacrifices they accepted during a 1985 austerity program. Workers then accepted wage cuts of up to 20 percent to help stem soaring inflation and reduce a $ 3 billion budget deficit. The program worked. Inflation dropped to 16.1 percent in 1987, and the budget deficit fell from 13.6 percent of the Gross Domestic Product of 1.2 billion shekels in 1984 to a surplus of 1.7 percent of the 1986 GDP of 1.3 billion shekels -LRB- $ 812 million -RRB-. But in the past two years, real wages have been rising faster than productivity, heating up inflation. And Finance Minister <PERSON> Moshe </PERSON> <PERSON> Nissim </PERSON> is under growing pressure to make concessions as the election campaign is heating up. `` Our basic target is to maintain stability,'' Ms. <PERSON> Lowental </PERSON> said. `` But nobody knows what's going to happen with the wages.'' Still unsigned is a tentative agreement for an 11 percent wage increase over two years for the 450,000 civil servants, one-third of the civilian labor force. Also unresolved are private sector negotzed national health system with months of strikes and slowdowns. The government agreed to emergency payments to ease the backlog of 15,000 Israelis waiting for operations, but there has been little progress in wage talks for doctors who earn an average $ 700 a month and are seeking wage hikes of more than 20 percent. If the doctors get large increases, `` it could affect the whole wage structure. If you give higher wages to one group of people, you have to give more to all the others,'' said <LOCATION> Canaan </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Nissim </PERSON> also is under pressure to devalue the Israeli shekel which has been fixed at a rate of about 1.6 shekels to the dollar since the days of hyperinflation. Manufacturers complain the strong shekel is making it difficult for Israeli exports to compete and is partly to blame for the drop in industrial production. <PERSON> Nissim </PERSON> has refused to devalue for fear of raising import prices and fueling inflation. Especially hard hit is <ORGANIZATION> Koor </ORGANIZATION>, the industrial conglomerate of the powerful <ORGANIZATION> Histadrut </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Trade </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federation </ORGANIZATION>, which lost $ 250 million in 1987, a record in Israeli industry. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, which gives <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> $ 1.2 billion a year in economic aid, urged <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> to sell off state-owned companies, lower taxes and cut government spending. The government has taken some steps in that direction. But <PERSON> Chaim </PERSON> <PERSON> Barkai </PERSON>, economics professor at <ORGANIZATION> Hebrew </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, said no unpopular steps would be taken during the three-month election campaign. `` The government must close down unprofitable factories and cut spending. But there wo n't be any changes in economic policy before the elections,'' <PERSON> Barkai </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880805-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-05-88 0016EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-UN-Gulf Bjt   08-05 0629</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-UN-Gulf, Bjt,0647</SECOND>
<HEAD>U.N. Chief Proposes Compromise In Persian Gulf Standoff</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By VICTORIA GRAHAM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>UNITED NATIONS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> would simultaneously halt their bloodshed and begin peace talks under a compromise solution proposed by the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> chief, but sources say <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> is cool to the idea. Secretary-General <PERSON> Javier </PERSON> <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Cuellar </PERSON> received a report Thursday from a <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> military team that visited both nations on arrangements for a U.N.-supervised cease-fire. The contents were not disclosed, but the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> chief said he would make a report to the <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> today. <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Cuellar </PERSON> has been trying to resolve a standoff between the two nations over the timing of a truce and the start of cease-fire talks in their 8-year-old war. `` I think both parties are interested in a peaceful solution.. The concept of direct talks is accepted by both sides and the matter is when -LRB- they will take place -RRB-. That is something on which I am working,'' he said Thursday. The issue of face-to-face talks between the bitter enemies has complicated the talks on implementing a truce and a <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> peace plan. <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> demands that direct talks be held before a cease-fire and <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> says they can begin only after a truce. Diplomatic sources, speaking on condition of anonymity, said <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Cuellar </PERSON> has proposed to both sides that he announce a cease-fire date and simultaneously invite both sides to hold direct talks on a comprehensive peace treaty. The sources say the talks and a truce could begin the same day, perhaps in a week if both sides are agreeable. <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> also is asking that the five permanent members of the <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> guarantee the truce and other elements of a peace plan. The five _ <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> _ are considering the issue, the sources said. <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Cuellar </PERSON> did not spell out his proposals for reporters and said he has not yet received a formal response from <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>. Diplomatic sources say <LOCATION> Baghdad </LOCATION> is not enthusiastic about the idea, but stopped short of outright rejection of the proposed simultaneous announcement. <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Cuellar </PERSON> said <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'s response, although not formal, has been `` constructive.'' `` Unfortunately, from the <LOCATION> Iraqi </LOCATION> side, I have not received the comments which I have asked for,'' <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Cuellar </PERSON> told reporters as he left <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> headquarters. Meanwhile, the official <ORGANIZATION> Iraqi </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> said in a dispatch from the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> that <LOCATION> Iraqi </LOCATION> Foreign Minister <PERSON> Tariq </PERSON> <PERSON> Aziz </PERSON>, who heads <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>'s negotiating team, met Thursday with the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> envoy to the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION>, Ambassador <PERSON> Vernon </PERSON> <PERSON> Walters </PERSON>, and visiting Indian Foreign Minister P.V. <PERSON> Narasimha </PERSON> <PERSON> Rao </PERSON>. The agency said the men discussed the cease-fire resolution and other issues, but gave no other details. <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Cuellar </PERSON> said that next week, probably Wednesday, he would deliver a comprehensive report to the council on the cease-fire declaration, troop withdrawal, prisoner exchange and other elements of a <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> peace plan. <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> have waged war since 1980, when <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> invaded Iranian territory. The death toll is estimated at 1 million. The <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> in July 1987 adopted a resolution calling for a cease-fire in the war, which has prompted an escalated <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> naval presence in the gulf. <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> accepted the proposal, but it was not until last month that <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>, after a series of battlefield defeats, said it, too, would accept the resolution. Since then, <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> has launched several attacks on <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> to bolster its bargaining position. Iranian Foreign Minister <PERSON> Ali </PERSON> <PERSON> Akbar </PERSON> <PERSON> Velayati </PERSON> met the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> chief for more than one hour Thursday. The Iranian envoy made no comments as he left the meeting. <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> says it needs the direct talks as a guarantee of sincerity from <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>, which it fears will seek only a temporary truce to regroup forces.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880805-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-05-88 0235EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-AIDS-Stats     08-05 0228</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AIDS-Stats,0248</SECOND>
<HEAD>CDC Statistics On U.S. AIDS Cases</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: May be used with PM-CDC-Military-AIDS, Bjt.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>ATLANTA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the latest statistics on acquired immune deficiency syndrome in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, as reported this week by the national Centers for Disease Control:
</TEXT>
<HEAD>Number of Cases</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Total cases reported since June 1981: 69,366. Cases, year to date: 18,942. Total deaths: 39,060, or 56 percent of all cases.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>Transmission Categories</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Homosexual or bisexual males: 42,831, or 62 percent. Intravenous drug abusers: 13,008, or 19 percent. Homosexual male and drug abusers: 5,020, or 7 percent. Heterosexual cases: 2,869, or 4 percent. Transfusion or blood cases: 1,863, or 3 percent. Hemophilia patients: 722, or 1 percent. Children of parents with AIDS or at risk: 861, or 1 percent. Undetermined transmission cause: 2,192, or 3 percent.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>Age and Race</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Childhood cases -LRB- under age 13 -RRB-: 1,108, or 2 percent. Cases among whites: 40,484, or 58 percent. Cases among blacks: 18,115, or 26 percent. Cases among Hispanics: 10,122, or 15 percent. Cases among other: 645, or 1 percent. -LRB- NOTE: These statistics are through Aug. 1 and have been rounded to the nearest whole percent. Cumulative totals are for AIDS cases reported since June 1981, and include 75 cases subsequently found to have occurred prior to that date. The `` other'' classification under Age and Race includes Asians, American Indians and native Alaskans. -RRB-
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880805-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-05-88 0228EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     08-05 0953</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0992</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in the News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>KUALA LUMPUR, Malaysia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> is so popular here that the government has decided he can not come for a concert in December, an official said today. <PERSON> Syed </PERSON> <PERSON> Zainal </PERSON> <PERSON> Abidin </PERSON>, secretary general of the <ORGANIZATION> Welfare </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION>, told reporters the <ORGANIZATION> Cabinet </ORGANIZATION> decided recently the concert could not be held because it would be too difficult to control the crowd. He said the ministry had wanted the American singer to perform here to raise money for the Welfare Fund, from which money is given out periodically to orphanages and charities. The ministry will appeal to the Cabinet to reconsider its decision, he added.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>SANTA ANA, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Jeana </PERSON> <PERSON> Yeager </PERSON>, who flew to fame as the co-pilot of Voyager, is experimenting with a more down-to-earth craft that uses only one horse power. Ms. <PERSON> Yeager </PERSON> has taken up amateur harness racing. `` I like trying things that are new, and this is very exciting,'' said the 36-year-old woman, who went from the cockpit to the sulky after her record-breaking round-the-world flight with Voyager co-pilot <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Rutan </PERSON>. Ms. <PERSON> Yeager </PERSON>, who at 5-foot-4 and 100 pounds is about the right size for harness racing, said recently that the sport enables her to indulge her passion for horses and her fiercely competitive spirit. She first participated in a celebrity harness race in April, and has since competed in a number of races as part of the Billings Amateur Trot Series. Ms. <PERSON> Yeager </PERSON> and <PERSON> Rutan </PERSON> piloted the Voyager 25,012 miles in nine days and four minutes for the first unrefueled non-stop flight around the world.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LOUISVILLE, Ky. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Stock car racer <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Elliott </PERSON> traded his Ford Thunderbird for a <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> forklift as he worked a shift at an auto plant. `` It was great,'' <PERSON> Elliott </PERSON> said after a 10-hour shift Thursday at the <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Motor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> assembly plant, but the <ORGANIZATION> NASCAR </ORGANIZATION> driver said he did n't intend to change careers. <PERSON> Elliott </PERSON> punched in at 6 a.m., then spot welded in the body shop, worked in the trim department, spray-painted and drove a forklift for the engine assembly line. Invited as a celebrity guest to the plant's 75th anniversary celebration in June, <PERSON> Elliot </PERSON> said he wanted to find out what work on the assembly line was like. Forklift driver <PERSON> Dennis </PERSON> <PERSON> Hayes </PERSON> said <PERSON> Elliott </PERSON> was `` obviously comfortable behind a wheel, but he did get behind on feeding pallets. In a couple of days, I'd have him up to speed.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>ATLANTA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 `` Godfather of Soul'' <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> was admitted to a hospital for oral surgery today to mend bone damage in his lower jaw, a spokeswoman said. The 2 -LCB- - hour operation was necessary because the 55-year-old singer has suffered degeneration of his jawbone, said <PERSON> Debra </PERSON> <PERSON> Bloom </PERSON>, a spokeswoman for <ORGANIZATION> Crawford </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Long </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION> In the procedure, an impression will be made of the singer's lower jaw An artificial support made from the impression will be implanted when <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> returns to the hospital in three to four weeks, Ms. <PERSON> Bloom </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> was accompanied to the hospital by his wife, <PERSON> Adrienne </PERSON>, with whom he has recently been involved in a much-publicized series of domestic problems. A <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> judge recently ordered him to perform a benefit concert as part of a probated sentence for drug and weapons charges stemming from the marital disputes.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WOODBRIDGE, Va. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Greyhound bus driver <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Knick </PERSON> says being picked to take the wheel of football color commentator <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Madden </PERSON>'s 40-foot-long, customized `` Maddencruiser'' has left him `` kind of numb.'' `` It's still all a shock,'' <PERSON> Knick </PERSON> said from <LOCATION> Oakland </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, where he was chosen Wednesday from among 10 Greyhound drivers to be <PERSON> Madden </PERSON>'s chauffeur during the pro football season. `` I do n't know what to expect.'' <PERSON> Madden </PERSON>, a color commentator for <ORGANIZATION> CBS-TV </ORGANIZATION>, says he's afraid to fly to games. The former <ORGANIZATION> Oakland </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Raiders </ORGANIZATION> coach travels in the Maddencruiser, a bus whose equipment includes an oversized shower, a queen-size bed and a satellite dish. It seats 10 and sleeps seven. The vehicle was built for Greyhound last year, said company spokeswoman <PERSON> Kristi </PERSON> <PERSON> Neal </PERSON>. For Knick, a 36-year-old <PERSON> Woodbridge </PERSON> man with a spotless 15-year record with Greyhound, the selection process included an interview with <PERSON> Madden </PERSON>. `` I walked into his bus and he was sitting there in a big chair with a big, long cigar,'' <PERSON> Knick </PERSON> said. `` He asked me about how my wife felt. ... He was very concerned about not damaging relationships.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actor <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Burns </PERSON>, actress <PERSON> Myrna </PERSON> <PERSON> Loy </PERSON> and choreographer <PERSON> Alvin </PERSON> <PERSON> Ailey </PERSON> are among five prominent Americans chosen this year to receive the Kennedy Center Honors for lifetime achievements in the performing arts. The other winners announced Thursday were violinist <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON> <PERSON> Schneider </PERSON> and <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Stevens </PERSON>, founding chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Kennedy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>. President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> will pay tribute to the medalists at a White House ceremony Dec. 4. That evening, they will be honored at a gala <ORGANIZATION> Kennedy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> performance that will be taped for later broadcast as a CBS television special. <PERSON> Stevens </PERSON>, 78, retired as the center's first chairman July 1. He was succeeded by former <ORGANIZATION> Time </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> executive <PERSON> Ralph </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Davidson </PERSON>. The center's board of trustees, who approved the 11th annual Kennedy Center Honors list, also voted <PERSON> Stevens </PERSON> the title of founding chairman.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>SALT LAKE CITY (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Mormon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> President <PERSON> Ezra </PERSON> <PERSON> Taft </PERSON> <PERSON> Benson </PERSON> observed his 89th birthday by spending the day in his office and gathering with family members. <PERSON> Benson </PERSON> was honored Thursday at the headquarters of the 6.5 million-member Church of <PERSON> Jesus </PERSON> <PERSON> Christ </PERSON> of Latter-day Saints by officials and workers of the faith. He and his wife, <PERSON> Flora </PERSON>, planned a private gathering with family members Thursday night. <PERSON> Benson </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> Mormon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> since 1985, was secretary of agriculture in the <PERSON> Eisenhower </PERSON> administration.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880805-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-05-88 0026EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Shultz Bjt   08-05 0589</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Shultz, Bjt,0609</SECOND>
<HEAD>Shultz: Sandinistas Threaten U.S. Because Of Soviet Presence</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PETER MUELLO</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BRASILIA, Brazil (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Secretary of State <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> brought his Latin American tour to <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION> after accusing the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> of building airstrips in <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> that threaten the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> arrived in the Brazilian capital Thursday night after a half-day visit to <LOCATION> Uruguay </LOCATION>, where he portrayed the leftist government in <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> as a `` cancer'' in <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>. `` <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> is a threat to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, not for what it might do, but because of the power of the Soviets who are building airstrips there which could pose a problem,'' he told a news conference in <LOCATION> Montevideo </LOCATION>, the Uruguayan capital. `` There exists a cancer which we have to cut out and we are going to do everything possible to stop its growth,'' the secretary added. <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> did not elaborate on the airstrips. The <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration repeatedly has ripped the pro-Soviet government in <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> and accused the Soviets of building airstrips there. Hundreds of students and workers from leftist and union organizations marched in downtown <LOCATION> Montevideo </LOCATION> near the Foreign Ministry to protest <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON>'s visit. No incidents were reported. <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> is again expected to be on the agenda during talks in <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION>, where <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> planned to meet today with Foreign Minister <PERSON> Roberto </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Abreu </PERSON> <PERSON> Sodre </PERSON> and President <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Sarney </PERSON>. Much of his visit is to focus on trade policy, a touchy topic here. Last month, the <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> announced its intention to impose sanctions on $ 200 million worth of Brazilian exports because this country refuses to recognize patents on <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> drugs. The <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION> stop is the fourth on <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON>' nine-nation Latin American tour. <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> began in <LOCATION> Guatemala </LOCATION> on Monday, where he failed to obtain a clear condemnation of <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> and its Sandinista government. Instead, <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> and four Central American foreign ministers signed a declaration that called for `` peace, democracy, security, social justice and economic development'' in the region. In <LOCATION> Uruguay </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> issued yet another harsh denunciation of the Sandinistas, who are fighting the <ORGANIZATION> U.S.-supported </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Contra </ORGANIZATION> rebels trying to overthrow the government. <LOCATION> Uruguay </LOCATION> backs efforts of the <ORGANIZATION> Contadora </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Group </ORGANIZATION> _ comprised of <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Venezuela </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> _ for a peaceful solution to the conflict in <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> presented the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> position in talks with President <PERSON> Julio </PERSON> <PERSON> Maria </PERSON> <PERSON> Sanguinetti </PERSON> and Foreign Minister <PERSON> Luis </PERSON> <PERSON> Barrios </PERSON> <PERSON> Tassano </PERSON>. The Uruguayan leaders issued no statement after the private meetings. `` We talked about many things and we are not necessarily in agreement in every case, but I can say, and the president -LRB- <PERSON> Sanguinetti </PERSON> -RRB- will be in agreement with me ... our relations are excellent,'' <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> said later. Socialist Deputy <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Diaz </PERSON> said <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> arrived with the intention of `` pressuring'' <LOCATION> Uruguay </LOCATION> to adopt the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> position of diplomatically isolating <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>. `` We will reaffirm to <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> the necessity to respect nations' right to self-determination, and we will keep searching for a Latin American solution to a problem that is Latin American,'' <PERSON> Diaz </PERSON> said The communist daily <ORGANIZATION> La </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hora </ORGANIZATION> put <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON>'s picture on page one and stamped on top of it, `` Undesirable.'' <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> planned to spend the weekend in <LOCATION> Rio </LOCATION> <LOCATION> de </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Janeiro </LOCATION>, 750 miles southeast of <LOCATION> Brasilia </LOCATION>, playing golf and holding private meetings. On Monday he leaves for <LOCATION> Bolivia </LOCATION>. The purpose of <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON>'s 10-day tour was to renew acquaintances with friends and allies of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and call attention to <LOCATION> Latin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s returning democracies. <PERSON> Sanguinetti </PERSON>'s March 1985 inauguration ended nearly 12 years of military rule. As he did in <LOCATION> Argentina </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> met with key opposition leaders as well as government figures.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880805-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-05-88 0305EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Unemployment Bjt   08-05 0537</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Unemployment, Bjt,490</SECOND>
<HEAD>Economists Expect Unemployment Rate To Stabilize</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDs: Will be topped with release at 8:30 a.m. EDT of figures for
July</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By MATT YANCEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Labor Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 With youths fully absorbed into the summer job market, economists are looking to the nation's unemployment rate to stabilize after a couple of months of large fluctuations. On the eve of today's release of labor market figures for July, most economists expected the rate either to remain at its 14-year-low 5.3 percent in June or to rise a tenth of a percentage point with an employment increase of 150,000 to 200,000. The jobless rate had bounced like a roller coaster from 5.6 percent in March, down to 5.4 percent in April and back up to 5.6 percent in May before the June decline. Both private analysts and economists for the <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Statistics </ORGANIZATION> said the monthly fluctuations were due primarily to two factors: One factor is the adjustments the government makes with the May and June figures to account for the out-of-school youths flooding the job market. The other factor is the calendar. The survey of 55,800 households upon which the rate is calculated is always taken on the 12th day of the month. Because the 12th occurred in the second week of May but the third week in June, economists said the real rate of joblessness was probably lower than what was reported in May and higher than the June figure. `` I think there will be an uptick to 5.4 percent for July,'' said <PERSON> Allen </PERSON> <PERSON> Sinai </PERSON>, chief economist of <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Boston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> `` But I would n't consider that as indicative of any new trend or a weakening of the economy.'' Payroll growth soared in June with 345,000 new jobs, compared with average monthly increases of 250,000 from January through May. After slowing down in the spring, factory and construction employment also resumed their upward paths in June. The <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> reported Thursday that new claims for unemployment insurance _ seasonally adjusted _ jumped by 51,000 in the third week of July to 371,000, the highest since last January. `` If the unemployment claims are rising that rapidly, then new job creation may be a little skinny in July,'' said <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Evans </PERSON>, a private <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> economist who also expected the rate of joblessness to rise to 5.4 percent. However, other analysts attributed the increase in applications for unemployment benefits to temporary layoffs in the auto industry as manufacturers retooled their assembly lines for the 1989 models. Meanwhile, fears that continuous months of unemployment rates in the range of 5.3 percent to 5.7 percent might trigger wage inflation so far appear unfounded. Although employers in tight job market areas along the <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Coast </LOCATION> and in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> are finding they have to pay much more than the minimum wage to attract workers for entry-level jobs, pay increases in general are still below inflation. Hourly wages actually fell 2 cents an hour in June to a seasonally adjusted $ 9.27, according to the <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>. `` Real wage rates have not yet recovered from a decade of price shocks and slow economic growth,'' said <PERSON> Wendy </PERSON> <PERSON> Rayack </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Wesleyan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> economist. `` They are still nearly 7 percent below their 1978 level.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880805-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-05-88 0227EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-DefenseSpending Bjt   08-05 0660</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Defense Spending, Bjt,650</SECOND>
<HEAD>Congressional Democrats Try To Devise Pentagon Bill Acceptable To
Reagan</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Senate scheduled to return to defense bill by 10:30 a.m. EDT.
Pre-noon top expected</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By TIM AHERN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Congressional Democrats are trying again to fashion a <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> bill that President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> would sign in the wake of his rejection of their first attempt to write a defense budget. The Democratic-controlled <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> was scheduled today to return to work on a bill appropriating money for the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> in the fiscal year starting Oct. 1. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> vetoed an earlier <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> budget bill because he objected to its reductions in his request for Star Wars anti-missile spending and Democratic-added arms control policy restrictions he opposes. When he vetoed the bill Wednesday, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> indicated he might be able to accept the appropriations measure, which contains the same cuts in spending for the Strategic Defense Initiative, as Star Wars is formally known, but none of the arms control limitations. However, those restrictions could be added as the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> tries to finish work on the bill befores its adjourns next week for a summer recess that wo n't end until after Labor Day. The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> also may add to the bill a proposal to send new humanitarian aid to <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>'s Contra rebels, but to restrict sharply the possibility of future military help. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> is seeking a package that includes immediate military aid. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> vetoed the bill which authorized the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> budget. That measure is the first half of the two-step congressional budget process which also includes an appropriations bill that has money to pay for programs in the earlier authorization measure. Although the vetoed measure authorized $ 299.5 billion worth of <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> spending and the appropriations bill proposes $ 282 billion, the legislation is essentially the same. Dollar totals in authorization bills generally are higher because they cover more projects in future years. When the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> finishes work on the appropriations bill, it will go to a <ORGANIZATION> House-Senate </ORGANIZATION> conference committee to be reconciled with separate legislation enacted by the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> six weeks ago. <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Democratic leaders are considering adding the vetoed bill as an amendment to the appropriation measure, which could force another showdown with <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>. Democrats have decided not to attempt to override the veto, because they could n't muster the two-thirds vote needed in each chamber. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> had sought $ 4.8 billion for <ORGANIZATION> Star </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wars </ORGANIZATION> next year, compared with the program's current budget of $ 3.9 billion. The vetoed bill would have cut his request to $ 4 billion and added other restrictions on what type of anti-missile systems could be developed. The appropriations bill contains $ 3.7 billion for <ORGANIZATION> Star </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wars </ORGANIZATION>, and a separate appropriation measure for the <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> included another $ 300 million for related research. That would bring the total for next year to the $ 4 billion level rejected by <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>. The bill also contains a 4.3 percent pay raise for the nation's 2.1 million uniformed military personnel Conservatives have praised <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s veto, saying it could energize the presidential candidacy of Vice President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> met Thursday with some of his conservative backers, including former Sen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Tower </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> Republican who once chaired the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Armed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Comittee </ORGANIZATION>. `` I think the president having vetoed the bill and having drawn the issue clearly is going to make it more politically perilous for the Democratic majority in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to repeat the bad legislation that appeared in this bill,'' Tower said after the meeting. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Perle </PERSON>, former assistant secretary of defense and now a fellow at the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Enterprise </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION>, said, `` The key issue was the future of SDI. This is not a dispute over details or precise funding levels. The action taken by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> ... was intended to kill the program without taking political responsibility.'' <PERSON> Kenneth </PERSON> <PERSON> Adelman </PERSON>, former head of the <ORGANIZATION> Arms </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Control </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Disarmament </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION>, called the veto `` the start of the issue-focused <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> campaign and the staving off of creeping lame duckism for the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880805-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-05-88 0310EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Bush     08-05 0646</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bush,640</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush Films Commercial; Focuses Again On Running Mate</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: May be topped</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By TOM RAUM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
