<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881022-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-22-88 0011EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Obit-Campbell 1stLd-Writethru a0800 10-22 0262</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Obit-Campbell, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0800,0268</SECOND>
<HEAD>Longest Tenured Federal Judge, Capone Prosecutor</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: SUBS 2nd graf, `Campbell, who ..., to deletel reference to
prison.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>WEST PALM BEACH, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Campbell </PERSON>, who prosecuted gangster <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> Capone </PERSON> and was the longest-tenured federal judge in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, has died of complications from surgery. He was 83. <PERSON> Campbell </PERSON>, who died Wednesday, was one of the prosecutors who got the notorious <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> hoodlum convicted on tax-evasion charges. <PERSON> Capone </PERSON> died in 1947. <PERSON> Campbell </PERSON>, appointed to the federal bench in 1940 by President <PERSON> Franklin </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Roosevelt </PERSON>, rose to become chief judge in <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION>' northern district and twice declined a seat on the 7th <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION> Circuit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appeals </ORGANIZATION>. He also was considered for a position to the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>. `` As a judge, he brought a dignity to the office that has seldom been matched,'' said <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> attorney <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Reuben </PERSON>. `` When you were in his courtroom, you knew you were in a courtroom.'' A New Deal liberal, he fought passionately against a <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> social club that refused to admit a black federal judge and for a public defender program in the federal courts. During the stormy 1968 Democratic National Convention in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Reuben </PERSON> said <PERSON> Campbell </PERSON> calmed a group of protesters in his courtroom with demands for `` proper courtroom behavior.'' <PERSON> Campbell </PERSON> retired in 1970 but continued to hear federal cases in <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> and for the past nine years at the federal courthouse here. Funeral services were scheduled Friday. He is survived by his wife, <PERSON> Marie </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Campbell </PERSON>, five daughters and three sons.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881022-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-22-88 0011EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-AcupunctureOrder     10-22 0214</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Acupuncture Order,0219</SECOND>
<HEAD>Judge Orders Acupuncture For Man Facing Fifth Drunken Driving
Charge</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BOULDER, Colo. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A judge has ordered a man facing his fifth drunken-driving charge to undergo acupuncture in an attempt to overcome a drinking problem that his lawyer says has resisted conventional treatment. `` I'm not sure if acupuncture works, but it's obvious nothing else works with you,'' <LOCATION> Boulder </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> Judge <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Reed </PERSON> told <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Ball </PERSON>, 31. <PERSON> Reed </PERSON> issued the order Thursday at the request of Public Defender <PERSON> Cary </PERSON> <PERSON> Lacklen </PERSON>, a defense attorney who believes acupuncture can play a valuable role in fighting substance abuse. <PERSON> Reed </PERSON> also ordered Ball to use <PERSON> Anabuse </PERSON>, a drug that reacts violently with alcohol in a person's body, to ensure that he does no more drinking. `` By ordering -LRB- acupuncture -RRB-, I'm not advocating it as a cure,'' <PERSON> Reed </PERSON> said later. `` It ca n't hurt, right?'' Prosecutors Thursday charged <PERSON> Ball </PERSON> with driving under the influence, reckless driving, two counts of hit-and-run, and driving without a valid license. He is accused of running into a line of parked cars in <LOCATION> Boulder </LOCATION> on Oct. 14 and driving off, later slamming into another car several blocks away. <PERSON> Lacklen </PERSON> said he got the idea for acupuncture therapy after reading about a <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> program that uses acupuncture to treat crack addicts.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881022-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-22-88 0025EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-SupportiveOpponent     10-22 0305</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Supportive Opponent,0317</SECOND>
<HEAD>Challenger In Connecticut State Senate Race Thinks Opponent Would
Do Better</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SHELTON, Conn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 For most political candidates, it usually goes without saying that they think they could do a better job than their opponents. Not so in a state <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> race. <PERSON> Steven </PERSON> <PERSON> Debish </PERSON>, 20, of <PERSON> Shelton </PERSON> says he would n't mind voting for <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> incumbent <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Gunther </PERSON> on Nov. 8. Debish is the Democrat challenging <PERSON> Gunther </PERSON>. `` -LRB- <PERSON> Gunther </PERSON> -RRB- would probably do a better job, be more effective in the next two years because of his long standing in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>,'' <PERSON> Debish </PERSON> said earlier this week. `` Most of the things I see in the newspaper that he stands for, I agree with.'' Debish, a sophomore at <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Connecticut </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> in nearby <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Haven </LOCATION>, gives himself a very slim chance of defeating the 11-term incumbent. `` I just do n't want to upset anybody,'' <PERSON> Debish </PERSON> said. `` He's doing his job. Many challengers demand face-to-face confrontations in debates, but a few weeks ago <PERSON> Debish </PERSON> declined to meet <PERSON> Gunther </PERSON> in a debate. `` We decided he has so much experience, he would probably just kill me,'' <PERSON> Debish </PERSON> said. `` He's just an old pro. I wish I had his experience in public speaking and debating.'' <PERSON> Debish </PERSON>'s entry into the contest was n't exactly a direct result of a mandate or groundswell of support by local party leaders. `` Well, they needed a person to go up against him and I guess they could n't find anyone. Almost anyone who goes up against him would probably lose,'' he said. <PERSON> Debish </PERSON> said he wanted to get some experience running for office and has his sights set on something other than the Legislature. `` I want to be mayor of <PERSON> Shelton </PERSON> someday,'' he said. Despite <PERSON> Debish </PERSON>'s deference to the incumbent, <PERSON> Gunther </PERSON> ca n't quite remember his challenger's name. `` What is it? <PERSON> Devlin </PERSON>? <PERSON> Dempsey </PERSON>?'' <PERSON> Gunther </PERSON> asked recently.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881022-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-22-88 0026EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Trump-Shuttle     10-22 0348</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Trump-Shuttle,0357</SECOND>
<HEAD>Trump Plans Major Upgrading of Eastern Shuttle</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARCY GORDON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Developer <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Trump </PERSON> says he's considering such amenities as valet parking in upgrading <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION>' shuttle service, and plans to spend `` tremendous amounts of money. <PERSON> Trump </PERSON> agreed Oct. 12 to purchase the profitable <ORGANIZATION> Northeast </ORGANIZATION> shuttle from parent <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> for $ 365 million in cash. If it survives government scrutiny and a legal challenge by some of <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION>'s unions, the sale is expected to be completed by Dec. 15. The operation, which links <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> with <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> and is used mostly by business travelers, will be renamed the Trump Shuttle. The blue-silver <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION> aircraft will be redecorated and emblazoned with red, black and gold stripes, and will carry <PERSON> Trump </PERSON>'s name on their tails `` I want to run an absolutely quality operation,'' <PERSON> Trump </PERSON> said Friday in a telephone interview. The real estate magnate said he is ready to spend `` tremendous amounts of money on each individual airplane'' to accomplish his goal. The interiors of the 17 <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> 727s will be completely redone using high-quality leather, carpeting and other materials, <PERSON> Trump </PERSON> said. He pledged to also stress safety by having each plane thoroughly checked and X-rayed, using procedures <PERSON> Trump </PERSON> claimed would be more stringent than Miami-based Eastern currently employs. The shuttle's airport terminals in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> also will be refurbished, <PERSON> Trump </PERSON> said. He said he is thinking seriously about introducing valet parking at the three airports for shuttle customers _ a service that would likely be an industry first. <PERSON> Trump </PERSON> said these improvements would take priority over possible plans to expand the shuttle service to <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.J. </LOCATION>, where he owns three casino-hotels. The developer runs a helicopter service between <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Trump </PERSON> asserted that he will be able to carry out his expensive plans without raising fares on the shuttle, which competes with a rival service operated by <ORGANIZATION> Pan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Am </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> `` I'm just going to do it,'' he said. `` It's a substantial investment, but it's something that has to be done.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881022-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-22-88 0026EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lottery     10-22 0025</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lottery,0024</SECOND>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the winning weekly state lottery numbers picked Friday:
</TEXT>
<HEAD>CONNECTICUT</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Lotto: 01; 04; 06; 08; 13; 21.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881022-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-22-88 0026EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-LotteryRdp     10-22 0083</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lottery Rdp,0087</SECOND>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the winning weekly state lottery numbers picked so far this week:
</TEXT>
<HEAD>CONNECTICUT</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Lotto: 01; 04; 06; 08; 13; 21.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>DELAWARE</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Play 4: 2-9-2-0.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>MASSACHUSETTS</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Wednesday Megabucks: 03; 06; 20; 22; 23; 31.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>NEW JERSEY</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Pick 6 Lotto: 13; 23; 26; 28; 35; 38. Bonus: 03741.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>NEW YORK</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Wednesday Lotto 54 Game: 17; 24; 30; 36; 37; 42. Supplementary 18.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>PENNSYLVANIA</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Big 4 Lottery: 1-5-9-8.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>RHODE ISLAND</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Grand Lot Game: 9-5-2; 2-6-1-1; 0-9-1-9-6; 7-1-3-8-5-6.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881022-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-22-88 0026EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--CocaineClergy     10-22 0170</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Cocaine Clergy,0173</SECOND>
<HEAD>Priest, 77, Sentenced For Cocaine Smuggling</HEAD>
<DATELINE>GENEVA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A 77-year-old Brazilian priest caught carrying 20 pounds of cocaine into <LOCATION> Switzerland </LOCATION> was convicted and sentenced to eight years in prison for breaking narcotics laws. A <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> jury court Friday sentenced three Brazilian co-defendants to jail terms of up to 15 years for membership in a ring smuggling the drug from <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Milan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>. The Rev. <PERSON> Lino </PERSON> <PERSON> Christ </PERSON>, a Roman Catholic parish priest in <LOCATION> Rio </LOCATION> <LOCATION> de </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Janeiro </LOCATION>, admitted he frequently traveled to <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> to raise funds for charity. But a co-defendant implicated him in the ring, where couriers were rewarded with $ 10,000 a trip. Christ shared an apartment with a mistress in <LOCATION> Rio </LOCATION>'s plush <LOCATION> Copacabana </LOCATION> district, the court was told. `` All Brazilian priests have a little business on the side,'' Christ testified in court, but he did not elaborate. He was arrested in December after <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> airport customs officials seized cocaine with a street value of $ 1.8 million hidden under a false bottom of his suitcase.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881022-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-22-88 0026EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--ArtTheft     10-22 0150</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Art Theft,0153</SECOND>
<HEAD>Police Recover Stolen Paintings</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ARNHEM, Netherlands (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A missing painting worth $ 175,000 was found in the home of a 62-year-old woman who allegedly lifted the masterpiece off its hook at a museum and tucked it in her shopping bag, Dutch television reported. `` Landscape With Farmhouse And Haystack'' by the 17th-century Dutch master <PERSON> Jan </PERSON> <PERSON> van </PERSON> <PERSON> Gooyen </PERSON>, was stolen from the <ORGANIZATION> Twenthe </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Museum </ORGANIZATION> in Enschede on Wednesday, according to the television report Friday. The report said the woman had simply lifted the painting off its hook and hidden it in a shopping bag during the museum's opening hours. According to the report, the woman had also taken a self portrait by modern Dutch artist <PERSON> Charley </PERSON> <PERSON> Toorop </PERSON> from the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Museum </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Kroeller-Mueller </ORGANIZATION> near this eastern Dutch city in June. That painting was worth $ 20,000, the report said. The report did not whether the woman has been charged.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881022-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-22-88 0028EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-PoliticalRdp Bjt   10-22 0557</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Political Rdp, Bjt,560</SECOND>
<HEAD>Dukakis Goes On The Attack As Bush Stays Home Today</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RICHARD L. VERNACI</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrat <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> went on the attack heading into a weekend of campaigning from the deep South to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>, while Republican <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was staying home today as the race for the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> approached its final two weeks. The Democratic presidential nominee, lagging behind <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> in the polls, was taking his case to television, both in a series of new, fiery commercials and in news interviews as he sought to raise his stock among the voters. In his television commercials, unveiled Friday, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> calls <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s attacks on his record `` full of lies and he knows it.'' However, the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> campaign has responded that the ads are truthful. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, who has been criticized for lacking passion, appears angry in an ad titled `` Counterpunch.'' `` I'm fed up with it,'' he says as he clicks off a television set showing a `` negative'' commercial for <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. The <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> commercial, showing <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> riding in a tank, attacks the <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> governor on defense issues. But <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> says in his ad that both candidates want a strong defense. `` So this is n't about defense issues. It's about dragging the truth into the gutter. And I'm not going to let them do it,'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> says. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, meanwhile, called for an international agreement allowing on-site inspections on demand to enforce a ban on chemical weapons. `` The eventual combination of chemical weapons and ballistic missiles could put new destructive power in the hands of governments with terrorist records,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> told an audience of about 1,200 at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Toledo </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>. However, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> did not mention that as vice president, he cast tie-breaking votes in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> in 1983 and 1986 in favor of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> chemical weapon arsenals. Those votes disturbed <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s mother, <PERSON> Dorothy </PERSON>, who criticized him after the second vote and then received a call from President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> explaining why her son voted as he did. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> today was meeting at his home in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> with <PERSON> Armando </PERSON> <PERSON> Valladares </PERSON>, who was freed six years ago after serving 22 years in a <LOCATION> Cuban </LOCATION> prison. <PERSON> Valladares </PERSON>, who wrote about his ordeal in the book `` Against All Hope,'' has been cited by the vice president as one of his heroes. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> also planned to attend an Italian-American dinner tonight in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, too, was to attend that dinner, but his appearance was scheduled for later in the evening. The Democrat was starting his day with a joint appearance with vice presidential running mate <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> before a group of pipefitters in <LOCATION> Beaumont </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, before heading to a barbecue in <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION> and then a television interview in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>. Later he was flying to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> and then to <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, who was taping an interview today with <ORGANIZATION> CNN </ORGANIZATION>, has made himself available for network television interviews over the last couple of days as he seeks to seize the offensive in the remaining days of the presidential campaign. But Republican vice presidential candidate <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> said the Democrats' fall in the polls is so steep, there can be no return. `` We have a strategy to win <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> said. `` Actually, I think the man from <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> ... they might end up on election night maybe having a one-state strategy or maybe they'll just have a <LOCATION> District </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION> strategy.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881022-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-22-88 0029EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-O'Connor Bjt   10-22 0695</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-O'Connor, Bjt,690</SECOND>
<HEAD>Justice O'Connor Undergoes Surgery for Breast Cancer</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JAMES H. RUBIN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Justice <PERSON> Sandra </PERSON> <PERSON> Day </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Connor </PERSON>, the first woman on the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>, is recovering from surgery for breast cancer and expects to return to work in 10 days. <PERSON> O'Connor </PERSON>, 58, underwent surgery Friday at <ORGANIZATION> Georgetown </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION>. But few details on the procedure or follow-up treatment were provided. `` I underwent surgery for breast cancer. It was found to exist in a very early form and stage,'' <PERSON> O'Connor </PERSON> said in a statement released by <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman <PERSON> Toni </PERSON> <PERSON> House </PERSON>. `` The prognosis is for total recovery. I do not anticipate missing any oral arguments,'' <PERSON> O'Connor </PERSON> said. The court is on a two-week recess and returns to hear arguments Oct. 31. The justices also will meet in private conference Oct. 28, but it was not known whether <PERSON> O'Connor </PERSON> will attend. Dr. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Siegel </PERSON>, assistant professor of medicine and director of a cancer treatment unit at <ORGANIZATION> George </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION>, said <PERSON> O'Connor </PERSON>'s plan for a quick return to the bench would be `` a remarkably fast recovery'' and may be good news for her prognosis. He said the speed also may indicate the cancer was caught at a very early time and there is no indication it has spread to other organs in the body. <PERSON> Siegel </PERSON> is not involved in <PERSON> O'Connor </PERSON>'s case. It was not disclosed whether <PERSON> O'Connor </PERSON>'s surgery was for removal of a lump or the entire breast. There also were no details on whether the justice will receive any form of continuing treatment and when the cancer was discovered. <PERSON> Siegel </PERSON> said that typically when breast cancer is detected at a very early stage, the patient can choose to have either a lumpectomy, in which only the tumor is removed from the breast, or a modified radical mastectomy, in which the entire breast is removed. Either procedure usually involves removal of the lymph glands under the arm. For a lumpectomy, patients generally are released from the hospital in three to four days, <PERSON> Siegel </PERSON> said, but return in two weeks to start radiation therapy. The radiation usually is given once a day, four to five days a week, for four to six weeks. For most patients, this is a difficult period because the radiation causes fatigue. `` It would be difficult to maintain a full schedule'' while receiving radiation, said <PERSON> Siegel </PERSON>. But he noted that some patients handle it much more easily than others. Patients receiving a modified radical mastectomy do not require radiation therapy and usually return to work within two to three weeks. <PERSON> O'Connor </PERSON>'s operation came just a year after first lady <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> underwent surgery to remove her left breast after laboratory tests revealed a quarter-inch cancerous lesion. Mrs. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, then 66, recovered quickly from the Oct. 17, 1987 surgery, a modified radical mastectomy. <PERSON> O'Connor </PERSON>'s health, as far as is publicly known, has been good. She underwent an appendectomy in March and was soon back at work. <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> justices generally jealously guard the details of their health. In 1986, The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> inquired about a tremor _ a nodding motion of <PERSON> O'Connor </PERSON>'s head _ that has been apparent to court watchers for years. At times, the justice will rest her chin on her hands during the court's public oral argument sessions. <PERSON> O'Connor </PERSON> sent back this reply through the court's public information office: `` I was unaware of such a tendency.'' As for resting her chin on her hands, she said it is `` an old and perhaps unfortunate habit.'' <PERSON> O'Connor </PERSON>'s appointment to be a justice by President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> in 1981 ended 191 years of male exclusivity on the high court. A political and judicial conservative, she has been a champion of states' rights and enhanced police power. But while she generally sides with the conservative wing of the court anchored by Chief Justice <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Rehnquist </PERSON>, she has cast important moderate votes in such areas as sex discrimination and affirmative action. She was a virtual unknown on the national scene when <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> picked her to replace <PERSON> Potter </PERSON> <PERSON> Stewart </PERSON>, who had retired. <PERSON> O'Connor </PERSON> served as an <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION> state judge and before that was a member of that state's <ORGANIZATION> Legislature </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881022-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-22-88 0029EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-LieDetectors     10-22 0490</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lie Detectors,470</SECOND>
<HEAD>Most Private Employers Will Be Barred From Using Lie Detector
Tests</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MATT YANCEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Labor Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Beginning in December, most private employers will be barred by law from using polygraphs and other types of lie detectors to screen job applicants or test the current employees except in rare circumstances. Under new regulations issued Friday by the <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, employers can be fined up to $ 10,000 for requiring a job seeker or employee already on their payrolls to submit to a polygraph exam for voice stress analysis. The regulations, which take effect Dec. 27, implement legislation passed by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and signed by President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> last June outlawing about 85 percent of the current use of lie detector tests. The congressional <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Technology </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assessment </ORGANIZATION> had estimated that 2 million polygraph examinations were conducted last year _ 90 percent of them by private employers. Some 7.2 million employers nationwide will be required to put up posters in December summarizing the prohibitions and exemptions and outlining the rights of any worker asked to take a lie detector test. <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> Alvarez </PERSON>, assistant labor secretary for employment standards, said the posters will be mailed out in the next three or four weeks. In addition to the fines, anyone required to take the test in violation of the new law can sue employers in federal and state courts for relief, such as employment reinstatement, promotion and any payment of lost wages and benefits. Exempted from protection under the ban are employees of federal, state and local governments or of federal contractors engaged in national security, intelligence or top secret activities. Also exempted from the ban are prospective employees of armored car, security alarm and security guard firms hired to protect operations affecting health and safety, national security or money. Pharmaceutical concerns or companies manufacturing, distributing or dispensing controlled substances also can require job applicants to submit to a lie detector test, but only for those people who would have direct access to the drugs. Polygraphs still can be used by employers to investigate specific incidents of theft, embezzlement or sabotage, but not a persistent problem, such as recurring inventory shortages. But any workers asked to submit to a polygraph exam under those conditions must be given at least 48 hours advance notice and a statement in advance telling them of their rights, including the right to refuse the test or to terminate it at any time. The pre-test statement also must explain the specific incident or activity being investigated and the basis for the employer's suspicion that the person asked to take the exam was involved in it Results of a polygraph test or refusal to submit to such an exam can not be used alone as a basis for taking any action against an employee. The regulations also forbid disclosure of the test results to anyone other than the employee without the employee's consent or a court order
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881022-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-22-88 0030EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-FetalTissue     10-22 0527</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Fetal Tissue,510</SECOND>
<HEAD>Committee Recommends Fetal Tissue Research</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JERRY ESTILL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BETHESDA, Md. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institutes </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> advisory </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> committee </ORGANIZATION> says it is `` acceptable'' to use the tissue from intentionally aborted fetuses in medical research. However, the panel's 13-3 vote making that fundamental finding _ the core question it was asked to decide _ carefully avoided taking a position on the morality of abortion itself or, for that matter, the morality of using the remains of planned abortions for research. `` It is of moral relevance that human fetal tissue for research has been obtained from induced abortions,'' said the draft document completed Friday. `` However, in light of the fact that abortion is legal and that the research in question is intended to achieve significant medical goals, the panel concludes that the use of such tissue is acceptable public policy.'' It went on to say that the committee position `` must not obscure the profound moral dimensions of the issue of abortion, nor the principled positions that divide scholars, scientists and the public at large. It is not the charge of this panel to attempt to settle the issue of abortion or to weigh the worthiness of competing principled perspectives on abortion itself.'' Researchers are hopeful that transplanting fetal brain cells into the brains of people with diabetes and Parkinson's disease could provide an effective treatment _ perhaps in three to five years _ and that more study could lead to similar treatments for a number of other serious diseases for which there now is no cure. The new procedure has been used experimentally on a handful of patients in other countries with promising results. The advisory committee was formed to examine moral, ethical, legal and scientific issues after <ORGANIZATION> NIH </ORGANIZATION> scientists sought permission to transplant fetal brain cells into some Parkinson's sufferers. The committee's agreement on a lengthy draft document Friday will not become final before Nov. 30, the date for submission of mail ballots on whether to adopt the exact language that will be written by <ORGANIZATION> NIH </ORGANIZATION> employees working to polish the principles adopted by the panel over five days of discussion going back to last month. In the draft version approved Friday, the panel laid out a number of recommended safeguards once research proceeds: _ `` The decision to terminate a pregnancy and the procedures of abortion should be kept independent from the retrieval and use of fetal tissue.'' _ `` Proper and informed consent should be obtained from the pregnant woman.'' _ `` Payments and other forms of remuneration and compensation associated with the procurement of fetal tissue should be prohibited, except payment for reasonable expenses occasioned by the actual retrieval, storage, preparation and transportation of the tissues.'' _ `` Potential recipients of such tissues, as well as any and all other participants, including researchers, hospital personnel and other service-providers, should be properly informed as to the source of the tissues in question.'' The panel also concluded that donations of fetal tissue to a family member or acquaintance for medical purposes should be banned to discourage women from becoming pregnant with the intention of having an abortion and donating the tissue to a sick relative or close friend.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881022-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-22-88 0032EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-AIDSTesting     10-22 0764</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AIDS Testing,750</SECOND>
<HEAD>Panel Recommends Changes In AIDS Testing</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Kraemer is cq in final graf</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By PAUL RECER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Science Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Screening tests for the AIDS virus are more accurate than two years ago, but medical practitioners should have at least two tests performed before informing an infected patient that he has the disease, according to a study by experts. <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Brien </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Du </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pont </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> expert on AIDS testing, said some medical workers are still telling patients that they have the disease after only a single test. `` The current tests are very, very good, but they are not 100 percent,'' <PERSON> O'Brien </PERSON> said Friday. He noted that only 10 percent of patients testing positive in an initial screening test for AIDS actually have the disease. <PERSON> O'Brien </PERSON> presented a report compiled by testing experts after three days of discussion at the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Standards </ORGANIZATION>. The report recommends that AIDS testing should not be considered definitive until both screening and confirmatory tests are completed. And, in some cases, even further testing is needed. He said the testing sequence should start with a screening test called ELISA -LRB- for enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay -RRB-. For those with a positive ELISA test, he added, there should then be a confirmation test called a <LOCATION> Western </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Blot </LOCATION>. Both laboratory tests are based on the presence in the patient's bloodstream of antibodies to the human immunodeficiency virus, or HIV, which causes AIDS, or acquired immune deficiency syndrome `` If you test 10,000 people for HIV, the current tests would give an ELISA positive on 0.2 percent -LRB- or 20 -RRB-,'' said <PERSON> O'Brien </PERSON>. `` Out of the 10,000, the Western Blot -LRB- confirming test -RRB- would be needed only on those 20 samples.'' <PERSON> O'Brien </PERSON> said that only about 10 percent of people testing positive by the ELISA test are actually infected with AIDS. As a result, he said, `` You do n't tell someone that they are HIV positive on ELISA alone.'' Some samples, <PERSON> O'Brien </PERSON> said, can not be confirmed as positive or negative even with both <ORGANIZATION> ELISA </ORGANIZATION> and Western Blot. He said the expert panel recommended that this `` indeterminate'' group undergo additional and different tests before a final report is made to the patient. AIDS is a contagious disease that attacks the body's immune system and makes it incapable of defending against infection. The disease is not now curable, and no one has been known to recover from it. As of Monday, there have been 75,768 AIDS cases reported in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, and 42,653 have died. AIDS testing was one of four subjects addressed in a unique gathering of medical testing experts at the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Standards </ORGANIZATION>. The group included testing specialists from government agencies, industry and hospitals. Officials said the purpose of the three-day meeting was to draw up recommendations for assuring that the nation's laboratories are providing accurate testing. The group issued recommended ways to improve testing for AIDS, for drug abuse, for cholesterol, and for the Pap smear cancer screening test. Among the recommendations were: _ Though testing for cholesterol was found generally to be accurate in hospital laboratories, the group recommended that cholesterol measurements made in a physician's office laboratory should be studied, since these labs often are not part of a routine quality control program _ A common system of measuring the presence and concentration of drugs in urine tests should be established nationally The experts said that there now exists a common reference material -LRB- a sample containing pure drugs at known concentrations -RRB- for marijuana, but not for other controlled drugs such as cocaine, PCP or amphetamines. The report said that such a common reference material would increase the accuracy of drug testing. _ The panel also said that the analysis of urine specimens can identify an exposure to drugs, but it does not measure the level of impairment The experts recommended that research be conducted to determine how such impairment can be measured accurately. _ The experts said that false-negative findings in Pap smears, a test for the presence of cervical cancer, are running as high as 4 percent to 8 percent, but that these errors often are a result of poor technique in collecting specimens The panel recommended that the Pap specimen collection technique be standardized and that women patients receive better instructions in how to prepare for this test. Dr. <PERSON> Beverly </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kraemer </PERSON>, a laboratory director at <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> John </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mercy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Louis </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mo. </LOCATION>, said though there are inaccuracies in Pap smear tests, the procedure is still `` a woman's best friend'' in the war against cancer and `` one of the most successful lifesaving laboratory procedures'' now commonly
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881022-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-22-88 0036EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Gallaudet-DeafPresident     10-22 0399</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Gallaudet-Deaf President,390</SECOND>
<HEAD>Gallaudet Installs First Deaf President</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The first deaf president in the history of 124-year-old <ORGANIZATION> Gallaudet </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, the nation's only university for the hearing impaired, challenged the students in his inaugural address to `` try and do everything under the sun.'' `` Today Gallaudet is not simply installing its eighth president,'' said Dr. I. <PERSON> King </PERSON> <PERSON> Jordan </PERSON>, who was selected as president last March after a tumultuous week of protests over the naming of a hearing woman to the post. `` We are recognizing the right of every disabled person to have unlimited goals and expectations,'' <PERSON> Jordan </PERSON> told about 2,400 faculty, staff and students jammed into the school's gym for his installation as president Friday. The hearing woman who initially was named to the post, Dr. <PERSON> Elisabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> Ann </PERSON> <PERSON> Zinser </PERSON>, eventually stepped aside and <PERSON> Jordan </PERSON>, 45, was selected. <PERSON> Jordan </PERSON>, who lost his hearing in a motorcycle accident in 1968, is a 1973 <ORGANIZATION> Gallaudet </ORGANIZATION> graduate who earned masters and doctorate degrees from the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tennessee </ORGANIZATION>. He served as dean of <ORGANIZATION> Gallaudet </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Arts </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sciences </ORGANIZATION> before being chosen as president. He pledged to expand programs preparing <ORGANIZATION> Gallaudet </ORGANIZATION>'s 2,200 undergraduate and graduate student for a larger place in the hearing world. `` I challenge every person in this room to take up his motivation, and have the courage to try and do anything under the sun,'' <PERSON> Jordan </PERSON> said. `` I challenge you to succeed.'' Urging the school to use the energy generated during the week of protests to continue lobbying for the rights of the hearing impaired everywhere, <PERSON> Jordan </PERSON> said, `` Gallaudet must become a working model for open access everywhere. Take the events of last March to your hearts and your hands to make the world responsive to deaf people.'' <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> <PERSON> Newman </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> the </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Deaf </ORGANIZATION>, told the crowd that <PERSON> Jordan </PERSON>'s installation `` marks the emancipation of deaf people from the shackles of limitations.'' Sen. <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Harkin </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Iowa </LOCATION>, whose brother is deaf, delivered part of his remarks in sign language, which drew appreciative cheers from the audience. He called those who struggled for selection of a deaf leader `` my heroes,'' and told an anecdote about how far the story of <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION>'s selection had spread: `` Last summer, I was in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, and a group of deaf students wanted to know about the president,'' <PERSON> Harkin </PERSON> said. `` They were n't interested in <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> They wanted to hear about Dr. <PERSON> Jordan </PERSON>.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881022-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-22-88 0037EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-TVA-Nuclear     10-22 0674</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-TVA-Nuclear,660</SECOND>
<HEAD>TVA Charged With Violating NRC Regulations Through False Statement</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GUY DARST</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Repeated false statements by the head of the <ORGANIZATION> Tennessee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Valley </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Authority </ORGANIZATION>'s nuclear program constitute a violation of federal regulations by the <ORGANIZATION> TVA </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Nuclear </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Regulatory </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> charges. However, the commission said it has decided not to take action on the original statements by <PERSON> Steven </PERSON> <PERSON> A </PERSON>. White, a former head of the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>'s nuclear submarine program, `` as a matter of prosecutorial discretion.'' The <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION> also decided, according to a letter sent Friday to <ORGANIZATION> TVA </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Marvin </PERSON> <PERSON> Runyon </PERSON>, not to assess a fine because `` a civil penalty for this matter is not necessary to further focus the attention of either <ORGANIZATION> TVA </ORGANIZATION> or the industry on the importance of complete candor'' in dealing with the commission, the letter said. The <ORGANIZATION> TVA </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Directors </ORGANIZATION>, in a statement read by spokeswoman <PERSON> Becky </PERSON> <PERSON> Akers </PERSON>, defended White while praising the <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION>'s decision not to assess a fine. `` We continue to believe that Admiral <PERSON> White </PERSON> did not intend to mislead the <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION> on this or any other matter,'' the statement said. `` We are pleased that the <ORGANIZATION> Nuclear </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Regulatory </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> did not fine <ORGANIZATION> TVA </ORGANIZATION> upon completion of this investigation,'' according to the statement. `` However, we are disappointed that <ORGANIZATION> TVA </ORGANIZATION> received a notice of a violation on statements relating to Appendix B. ... The <ORGANIZATION> TVA </ORGANIZATION> board is fully committed to operating a safe and reliable nuclear power program.'' The <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION>'s letter said the <ORGANIZATION> TVA </ORGANIZATION> has 30 days to admit or deny the allegations and to show what corrections it has undertaken if the charge is admitted. The case concerns a March 1986 letter <PERSON> White </PERSON> wrote to the commission. White had been hired a few months earlier to shape up <ORGANIZATION> TVA </ORGANIZATION>'s nearly collapsed nuclear effort that had seen the closure of five reactors. <PERSON> White </PERSON> wrote the <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION> that there had been `` no pervasive breakdown of the quality assurance program'' at the Watts Bar plant under construction near <LOCATION> Spring </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Tenn </LOCATION>. He repeated that assurance in a follow-up letter and in statements to <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION> investigators, adding that he had received a review of the program by outside experts. In fact, according to previous commission testimony to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and according to Friday's letter, <PERSON> White </PERSON> had not even spoken with seven of the nine people he identified as constituting the outside review group, and the two people he did speak with had not reviewed <ORGANIZATION> TVA </ORGANIZATION>'s quality assurance efforts but had only given opinions of the work of an earlier in-house group. `` No one identified by Mr. <PERSON> White </PERSON> as being a member of the second group understood there to be such a group,'' the letter said. In April, <PERSON> Ben </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Hayes </PERSON>, director of the <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION>'s Office of Investigations testified before a congressional panel that White was playing word games. <PERSON> Hayes </PERSON> told the investigations subcommittee of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> that <PERSON> White </PERSON> apparently was intending `` pervasive'' to mean `` 100 percent.'' While technically true, <ORGANIZATION> TVA </ORGANIZATION>'s quality assurance had serious and widespread problems, he said. At the <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION> staff, an internal group headed by <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON>, assistant executive director for operations, concluded that White's statements were not deliberately false The matter was referred to the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, which has refused to comment on the status of the case. White has denied any wrongdoing and has been supported by the <ORGANIZATION> TVA </ORGANIZATION> board. He is retiring in January. The letter, signed by <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON>, now deputy executive director for regional operations, said the violation was being assessed even though White is leaving because `` <ORGANIZATION> TVA </ORGANIZATION> management as a whole is responsible for the quality of communications with the <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION>.'' `` Both the individuals involved and the organization must share responsibility for the actions giving rise to these violations, but the fundamental premise of our regulatory system makes <ORGANIZATION> TVA </ORGANIZATION>, as the licensee, ultimately responsible,'' the letter said. `` The <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION> must be confident that it can rely on the information furnished by a licensee,'' the letter said. `` ... Anything less than accurate and complete statements to the commission can not and will not be tolerated.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881022-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-22-88 0038EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Quayle     10-22 0572</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Quayle,560</SECOND>
<HEAD>Quayle Sees ``One State Strategy'' For Democrats</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Political Rdp Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MIKE GLOVER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SAVANNAH, Ga. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Democratic slide in the polls is so steep that <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> could be left with a `` one state strategy'' on election day, <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> vice presidential nominee <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> said. And as he stumped through the South on Friday, <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> worked to steal a line his Democratic counterpart used to devastating effect in the vice presidential debate. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, he declared, `` is no <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> Truman </PERSON>'' and wo n't be making a comeback. A confident-sounding <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> said there's a sharp contrast between Republican and Democratic election strategies. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> told college students in <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> that the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> has a `` 50-state strategy'' and made light of reports that <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> is narrowing his focus to about 18 states with enough electoral votes for a win. `` We have a strategy to win <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> said. `` Actually, I think the man from <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> ... they might end up on election night maybe having a one-state strategy or maybe they'll just have a <LOCATION> District </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION> strategy.'' The quip that <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> `` is no <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> Truman </PERSON>'' comes straight from Democrat <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> who scored the premier moment of the vice presidential debate when he told <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>, `` You're no <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>.'' <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> described a conversation between <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> Sen. <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, and his father, a former senator. `` I guess he -LRB- Gore Jr. -RRB- called home and talked to his dad, when his father told him that this reminded him of the <PERSON> Truman </PERSON> campaign in 1948,'' <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> said. `` Let me tell you something, I do n't know <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, I never served with <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> is not a good friend of mine. `` But I know this: <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> is no <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> Truman </PERSON>,'' said <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>. <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> used precisely that cadence in setting up <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> for his debate zinger, and aides said Friday's speech was the first time <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> had referred to the put-down in a campaign appearance. Republican presidential nominee <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> had also set the stage when he used a similar line in a self-deprecating fashion during a dinner in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> on Thursday night. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> insisted the comparison was apt because many were `` trying to compare the <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> campaign to the <PERSON> Truman </PERSON> campaign.'' <PERSON> Truman </PERSON> was perceived to be trailing throughout the 1948 campaign, but ended up defeating Republican <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Dewey </PERSON>. Most polls show the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> ticket this year with a persistent lead, and <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> insisted there will be no comeback this time around. During his Southern swing, <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> spoke to the college students in <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> at a noisy rally where critics and backers competed for attention, repeatedly interrupting the candidate. `` They've always been negative and they always will be,'' <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> said. `` They are the party of failure. We are the party of success. `` They can go ahead and yell,'' he said. `` We're going to talk about issues and ideas.'' Throughout his Southern swing, <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> took a tough stance against a tax increase and in favor of defense as he courted conservative voters in a region where most polls suggest <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> is strong. At a flag-waving riverside rally in <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> made a frank appeal for backing from conservative southern Democrats. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, he argued, is `` not in the southern Democratic tradition of national defense. Disenchanted Democrats are fed up with liberalism.'' He got some cheering news from the crowd, including one sign which read `` Thank God Quayle is no JFK.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881022-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-22-88 0040EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Bush     10-22 0651</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bush,650</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush Takes Weekend Campaign Break After Praising Quayle in Ohio</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Political Rdp Bjt</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: No PMs top likely</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By CHRISTOPHER CONNELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Vice President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> is taking a weekend breather from the campaign trail after warning <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> supporters against complacency and boasting that running mate <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> has been `` tested by steel.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was keeping a light schedule today, meting with <PERSON> Armando </PERSON> <PERSON> Valladares </PERSON>, author of `` Against All Hope,'' a harrowing account of his years as a political prisoner in a <LOCATION> Cuban </LOCATION> prison. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> mentioned the book in his last debate with <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> tonight was attending an Italian-American banquet in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> where <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> also was putting in a separate appearance. After taking Sunday off, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> heads back on the road Monday for a swing through <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>, with stops in <LOCATION> Waterford </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Conn. </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Portland </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION>, and <LOCATION> Burlington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Vt. </LOCATION>. On Tuesday, he launches a drive-to-the-wire, cross-country trip for the final two weeks of the campaign, starting with a return to <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> for the sixth time since the GOP convention In a high school gym in <LOCATION> Lancaster </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, and earlier in a hockey arena in Troy, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> laid the rhetorical wood to his opponent's policies and lauded his running mate. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said the <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION> senator has `` been tempered by steel. He's been taking a pounding out there Steel gets tough when it's under fire.'' <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, with 23 electoral votes, `` is a critical state,'' said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. `` The election still hangs in the balance, and I am running _ even though things feel pretty good _ just as though I were 10 points back,'' he told 2,000 people at <ORGANIZATION> Lancaster </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> High </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION>, where he was surrounded by cheerleaders in a gym festooned with balloons and a huge, hand-lettered `` Good Night, <PERSON> Mike </PERSON>'' banner. `` He does n't like the L-word anymore because he's trying to move to the middle ... and we're not going to let him,'' said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. Although the <LOCATION> Buckeye </LOCATION> state went twice for <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> is ahead in polls in <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> press secretary <PERSON> Sheila </PERSON> <PERSON> Tate </PERSON> said, `` It's not locked up by any means.'' <PERSON> Tate </PERSON> was questioned about Friday's indictment of former <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION> dictator <PERSON> Ferdinand </PERSON> <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON>, as <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> has criticized <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> for praising <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON>' commitment to democracy during a 1981 visit to <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION>. `` His view is that the judicial process should go forward,'' <PERSON> Tate </PERSON> said. In Troy, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> recited his full anti-Dukakis litany, attacking the <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> governor for vetoing a mandatory Pledge of Allegiance law, ridiculing his prison furlough program and taking a double-edged swipe at the Democrat's economic and environmental record. `` There just is n't any <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> miracle. The last miracle in <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> was when they found a fish alive in <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Harbor </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> quipped. At the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Toledo </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> decried the `` terrible scourge'' of chemical warfare and called Friday for sanctions against nations that resort to germ warfare, on-site inspection of suspicious plants and an overture to the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> to help stop the spread of ballistic missiles. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has long said one of his goals as president would be to banish all chemical weapons from the earth _ an issue given new urgency by the use of nerve gas in the Iran-Iraq war. He spoke of his horror at seeing photographs of a Kurdish mother `` trying to protect her child, waving her arms against the invisible winds of death'' after an Iraqi attack. The <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> campaign has challenged <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s credibility on this issue, citing three tie-breaking votes the vice president cast in the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> in 1983 and 1986 to fund <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> production of new chemical weapons. <PERSON> Dennis </PERSON> <PERSON> Ross </PERSON>, a <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> policy aide, said the old <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> stockpiles were deteriorating and the new, binary weapons were safer. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s octogenarian mother, <PERSON> Dorothy </PERSON>, criticized her son after the second chemical weapons vote in 1983 _ and got a phone call from <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> explaining why her <PERSON> George </PERSON> voted that way.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881022-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-22-88 0041EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Marcos-NoPromises     10-22 0637</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Marcos-No Promises,630</SECOND>
<HEAD>Officials: Never Promised Marcos Anything</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-US-Marcos Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID BRISCOE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Indicted former Philippine President <PERSON> Ferdinand </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> received no promises from <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials to persuade him to leave his country without bloodshed during a popular, military-based revolt in 1986, officials say. More than 2 -LCB- years after he fled the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON>, his wife, <PERSON> Imelda </PERSON>, and six others were indicted Friday on racketeering charges involving a vast fortune the Marcoses allegedly stole from the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION>. Action by the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, a federal appeals court and the <LOCATION> Philippine </LOCATION> government opened the final doors to that indictment which came in a <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> investigation that began shortly after <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> was airlifted to <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION> in February 1986. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Rich </PERSON>, a former <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> official in <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION> who was <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> liaison with <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> during his first three months of Hawaiian exile, said Friday that no high official, including President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, made any promises to <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON>. `` We offered refuge because the prospect of violence threatened him and his family and to avoid a very bloody confrontation in the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Rich </PERSON> said in a telephone interview from <LOCATION> Belize </LOCATION>, where he is now the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> ambassador. `` There is no indication that anyone at high levels offered anything inappropriate.'' <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> claims in a lawsuit filed in <LOCATION> Honoluu </LOCATION> that he was deceived into leaving his country against his will. The case against <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> has involved discussions with <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION> officials and months of dealings among the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>. Both State and <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> department sources confirmed that there were disagreements over how to handle the case, with <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> wanting to indict prior to plea bargaining with <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> and State urging a pre-indictment attempt to bargain. A plea bargain which <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> rejected was described by one official as an attempt to get <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> to return his vast wealth to the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION>, which is the main objective of the case. The government of President <PERSON> Corazon </PERSON> <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON> alleges that <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> and his associates took out of the country $ 5 billion to $ 10 billion, much of it stashed in Swiss banks. The way was cleared for the indictment after a <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> announcement Thursday that <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> would `` not prevent the law from taking its course.'' White House spokesman <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> later said <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> was saddened by the court action because <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> was a friend. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> had invited <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, and administration officials were concerned about the impact the indictment would have on <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> credibility in dealing with foreign rulers in the future. <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said after the indictment, `` We did n't make any promises we could n't keep. Any foreign leader can take our word on anything.'' Another administration official, speaking on condition of anonymity, said <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> apparently came to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> because it was where he `` felt safest and most comfortable. If he went to another place, he might end up ripped off by another authoritarian ruler.'' But <PERSON> Rich </PERSON> said he believes that <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> in 1986 probably planned to stay in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> only for a few months, miscalculating the viability of the Aquino government and the lack of interest other countries had in taking him. He and his wife are restricted to the island of <LOCATION> Oahu </LOCATION> because of his attempt last year to return to the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials say they are honoring a <LOCATION> Philippine </LOCATION> government request that he not be allowed to return. On Wednesday, the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appeals </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> upheld a civil contempt finding against <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> and his wife for failing to turn over evidence to the grand jury that handed up the indictments. That decision also rejected <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON>' pleas for immunity. Last week, the Philippine government issued a formal waiver of any immunity <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> might be allowed from prosecution as a former head of state.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881022-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-22-88 0048EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-DisasterRelief     10-22 0376</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Disaster Relief,360</SECOND>
<HEAD>Congress Passes Bill Reforming Distribution of Disaster Relief</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JEFF BARKER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A bill reforming the way the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Emergency </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Management </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> distributes aid after natural disasters has been approved by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and sent to President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> for his signature. The Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Amendments of 1988 had their roots in the government's response to tornadoes that raced through <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> before hitting <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> on May 31, 1985, killing 90 people. Rep. <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Ridge </PERSON>, R-Pa., authored the bill after complaining that the help offered by <ORGANIZATION> FEMA </ORGANIZATION> in 1985 failed to meet the needs of residents and municipalities facing major repairs At a hearing on the bill last year, Rep. <PERSON> Leon </PERSON> <PERSON> Panetta </PERSON>, D-Calif., said reform was necessary because <ORGANIZATION> FEMA </ORGANIZATION> `` has gained the notoriety of being very cumbersome and tortuous for the citizens of this nation to understand. The bill died in the 99th Congress, was introduced again last year, and the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> finally passed it in the spring. The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> passed a companion bill by voice vote Friday. Since the measure was slightly different from the version the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> had passed earlier, it was sent back to the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, which approved it Friday night. The legislation was sent to <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, who was expected to sign it. Among other reforms, the bill would bar <ORGANIZATION> FEMA </ORGANIZATION> from paying less than a 75 percent share of aid to local governments qualifying for public repair projects following a disaster. It would add guidelines to speed the distribution of post-disaster aid and would permit federal funds to be used for the first time for local projects designed to lessen the effect of disasters before they strike. The measure also would make temporary housing assistance through <ORGANIZATION> FEMA </ORGANIZATION> available for up to 18 months, six months longer than under the current system. Originally, the measure was opposed by the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration, which said its initial price tag _ $ 15 to $ 20 million per year above what <ORGANIZATION> FEMA </ORGANIZATION> pays now _ was too high. But the bill's cost was trimmed down to zero by eliminating some administrative expenses and by asking state and local governments to share some of the cost of aid in a federally declared emergency, among other changes.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881022-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-22-88 0051EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Politics-Quotes     10-22 0322</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Politics-Quotes,300</SECOND>
<HEAD>Quotes From the Presidential Campaign Trail</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are some comments from the presidential campaign trail Friday: <PERSON> MICHAEL </PERSON> <PERSON> DUKAKIS </PERSON>, slamming the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> camp for emphasizing the fact that convicted murder <PERSON> Willie </PERSON> <PERSON> Horton </PERSON> escaped while on furlough and terrorized a <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION> couple: `` To play politics with that kind of human tragedy, I think, is one of the most cynical things you can do.'' Sen. <PERSON> SAM </PERSON> <PERSON> NUNN </PERSON>, D-Ga., speculating on what he would do if he were in <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' shoes: `` I would n't have been a punching bag on some of these issues There are some very unfair allegations going on, and what I've been amazed at is how the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> campaign has been able to get away with it and to be fairly successful at it so far. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> has really got to take off the gloves; he's got to defend himself.'' <PERSON> GEORGE </PERSON> <PERSON> BUSH </PERSON>, advocating an international ban on chemical weapons but failing to mention his tie-breaking votes in 1983 and 1986 in favor of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> chemical weapons arsenals: `` The eventual combination of chemical weapons and ballistic missiles could put new destructive power in the hands of governments with terrorist records.'' <PERSON> DAN </PERSON> <PERSON> QUAYLE </PERSON>, saying the Democrats will not stage a Harry Truman-style comeback this year, copying a line used against him in the vice presidential debate: `` I do n't know <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, I never served with <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> is not a good friend of mine. `` But I know this: <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> is no <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> Truman </PERSON>.'' <PERSON> RONALD </PERSON> <PERSON> REAGAN </PERSON>, praising <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> for keeping a cool head in times of crisis: `` ... I have given him some of the most sensitive and difficult tasks that we've had, and he's never let me or the country down.'' <PERSON> LLOYD </PERSON> <PERSON> BENTSEN </PERSON>, seeking to assuage Texans' fears that <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> is soft on defense: `` I would n't be running on a ticket with a candidate who would weaken <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s defense.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881022-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-22-88 0054EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-TrappedWhales-Soviets     10-22 0382</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Trapped Whales-Soviets,360</SECOND>
<HEAD>Soviets Offer To Break Path To Trapped Whales</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Trapped Whales Bjt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> has offered to start moving an icebreaking ship today toward the stranded whales in <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> if current rescue efforts do n't succeed, according to a teleprinter message sent from Soviet officials to <ORGANIZATION> Greenpeace </ORGANIZATION>. `` We are taking efforts on assisting in whales rescue operations,'' said the message sent Friday by the <ORGANIZATION> Soviet </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> on Hydrometeorology. The ship, the Admiral <PERSON> Makarov </PERSON>, was 300 miles north of <LOCATION> Point </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Barrow </LOCATION> and would be able to move toward the whales today after finishing work on establishing a research station on the ice and rescuing an ice-trapped Soviet ship, the <LOCATION> Arseniev </LOCATION>, the message said. The offer was made in the event the three gray whales still are trapped by the gathering ice next Wednesday, when the Soviets anticipated the icebreaking ship could arrive at the scene. <PERSON> Campbell </PERSON> <PERSON> Plowder </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> Greenpeace </ORGANIZATION> said that as a shot in the dark, he asked on Monday, through scientific contacts in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, if any Soviet icebreaker was in a position to help the whales. The answer was Friday's cable. The Soviet message, which requests <ORGANIZATION> Greenpeace </ORGANIZATION>'s help in obtaining <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government permission to sail in <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> territorial waters, expresses some doubts about the success of the mission. `` We do not have complete assurance in this venture because of shallow waters for icebreaker in the area of rescue,'' the message said. In addition, the Soviets said, the `` ice ridge is about 120 miles from that area and we are in doubts ... that whales would be able to pass through the channel made by icebreaker.'' <PERSON> Plowder </PERSON> said he has asked the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> for immediate clearance for the ship to enter <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> waters and was told the department would `` assess the technical aspects'' first. The <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, meanwhile, said it has asked Soviet authorities what assets they may have available to help free the whales. The Soviets responded with information on where they have ice breakers and how long it would take them to arrive at the scene, said a <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> official who asked not to be identified. According to the official, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> authorities are evaluating the Soviet information and are comparing it with other options for rescuing the whales.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881022-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-22-88 0056EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Dukakis     10-22 0541</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Dukakis,540</SECOND>
<HEAD>Dukakis Takes To Airwaves To Battle Bush</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Political Rdp Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DONALD M. ROTHBERG</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Political Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BEAUMONT, Texas (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> is on the air with four new hard-hitting commercials and tonight is delivering a five-minute televised appeal for support. The <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> governor got a rousing reception Friday night from several thousand people who filled the gymnasium on the campus of the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Orleans </ORGANIZATION>. `` At the rate we're going, we're going to be importing 50 percent of our oil by 1990,'' he said. `` Even before we're inaugurated, <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> and I are going to call a bipartisan energy summit for this country ... and that summit will be chaired by the vice president-elect of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>.'' The commercials and television speech are the latest effort by the Democratic presidential candidate to pick up momentum in his race against Republican <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. `` The central point -LRB- of the new ads -RRB- is the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> campaign and their advertising are not to be believed,'' said campaign press secretary <PERSON> Dayton </PERSON> <PERSON> Duncan </PERSON>. The new <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> ads started running Friday in key states. Television was the latest weapon in the <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> effort to overtake <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and emerge as an upset winner on Election Day, a little more than two weeks away. His five-minute speech will air at 10:55 p.m. EDT, on <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>. Aides said the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> candidate also would appear Tuesday night on the <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> show `` Nightline.'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> campaigned Friday in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION>, and <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION> before flying to <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> for the night. At <LOCATION> Bethel </LOCATION> African <ORGANIZATION> Methodist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Episcopal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Harlem </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> renewed his pledge to wage a war on drugs and said, `` Our determination to win this war should know no bounds.'' His next stop was <LOCATION> McKeesport </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION>, where he told a crowd that waited in the rain, `` Do n't let anyone tell you the steel industry is dead in this country. It is n't, it's not going to be and we are going to help bring it back.'' Actor <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Brooks </PERSON>, who starred in the movie `` Broadcast News,'' was on the platform with <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> and told the crowd, `` I'm a liberal and I'm a great guy. Then turning to <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, he said, `` This guy's a liberal, he's a great guy.'' Two of the new <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> television ads were responses to <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> attacks on the <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> prison furlough program and on <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' positions on defense issues. `` <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> wo n't talk about the thousands of drug kingpins furloughed from federal prisons while he led the war on drugs,'' says one <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> ad. `` The real story about furloughs is that <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has taken a furlough from the truth.'' The <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> campaign is running a television ad that shows <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> riding in a tank and describes him as opposed to a range of major weapons systems. The <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> response shows the Democratic nominee watching the opening moment of that ad and then turning it off. `` I'm fed up with it,'' says <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>. `` Have n't seen anything like it in 25 years of public life, <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s negative TV ads.'' The other two ads attack <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> for failing to stop the flow of drugs into the country and for planning to cut the capital gains tax, what <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> describes as `` tax breaks to the rich.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881022-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-22-88 0104EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-El-Alamein     10-22 0755</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-El-Alamein,0782</SECOND>
<HEAD>Hundreds Converge On Village To Remember War Heroes</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: First available for Saturday AMs</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By MIMI MANN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> EL-ALAMEIN </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION> -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> -RRB- _ This dusty coastal village of Bedouin houses, car repair shops, a rest house and two gas stations has little to offer for the living _ except memories of the dead. On Sunday, 2,000 people are expected here to mourn those who fell in World War II in the Battle of el-Alamein. Since 1978, the Service of Remembrance for the more than 70,000 casualties of the battle has been held on the Sunday nearest to Oct. 23. That was the night 46 years ago when English Gen. <PERSON> Bernard </PERSON> <PERSON> Law </PERSON> <PERSON> Montgomery </PERSON> launched a devastating attack on the elite Axis divisions of `` The Desert Fox,'' German Field Marshal <PERSON> Erwin </PERSON> <PERSON> Rommel </PERSON>. The decisive battle began at 9:40 p.m. when <PERSON> Montgomery </PERSON>'s guns opened fire under a full moon after a day of blistering heat. Rain had turned the desert to mud by the time the battle was won early Nov. 4, ending <PERSON> Rommel </PERSON>'s relentless march across <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> toward <ORGANIZATION> Suez </ORGANIZATION>. It cleared the way for the Allies to open a second front in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>. This year's main ceremony will be held beneath the pink and green foliage of the Commonwealth Cemetery, an English garden setting against a desert backdrop. Among those who will take part is <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s defense secretary, <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Younger </PERSON>, who arrived with a delegation of 41, including about a dozen war widows and 17 veterans. The cemetery, with its rows of marked and unmarked graves, is an emotional reminder of the battle wedged in the 30 miles of wasteland between the quicksand-filled Qattarra Depression to the south and the <LOCATION> Mediterranean </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sea </LOCATION> to the north. The largest war cemetery in <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>, it contains the graves of <ORGANIZATION> Commonwealth </ORGANIZATION> soldiers who died at <LOCATION> el-Alamein </LOCATION> as well as some who fell earlier in the <LOCATION> Sahara </LOCATION>. English architect Sir <PERSON> Hubert </PERSON> <PERSON> Worthington </PERSON> came to el-Alamein in the summer of 1943, just months after <PERSON> Rommel </PERSON> was repelled, to design a garden cemetery in the harsh surroundings. He determined that walls were necessary to keep out drifting sand, and cloisters with hearty plants to make visits pleasant even in the hottest months. Of the 7,352 graves, 815 bear unknown remains. Jew and <PERSON> Arab </PERSON> lie side by side. English soldiers and Canadians are buried beside Australians, Indians, East Africans, <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africans </LOCATION>, Sudanese, Belgians, Frenchmen, Greeks, Poles, troopers from the old High Commission Territories and unknown Allied dead from other North African campaigns. On the walls in front of the cemetery are listed names of 11,495 others lost in all desert campaigns. East of the Commonwealth Cemetery is a separate smaller memorial to Greek combatants, and monuments to Axis losses are to the west. <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>'s mausoleum, dazzling white against the azure sea, holds the remains of 3,241 soldiers. A short distance away, the dark, round, fortress-like German memorial dominates a sandy hill beside the shore. Its walls shelter 4,280 remains. In its center courtyard, a tablet reads: `` The price of pride is high, and paid by the young.'' There has been occasional talk of halting the annual commemoration, but Wing Cmdr. <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON> <PERSON> Edmunds </PERSON>, who heads this year's program, said that is not being seriously considered. `` For the younger generations, World War II is becoming part of a deep, dark past, but for others this time of year recalls el-Alamein,'' he said. `` <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION> still has large Italian and Greek communities who gather for the ceremony.'' <PERSON> Edmunds </PERSON> remembers studying about el-Alamein in detail as a child because `` it was such a turning point for the Allies. We were doing OK in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, awful in the <LOCATION> Far </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> and had n't done well in <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>. After el-Alamein, all that changed.'' The Sahara's constantly shifting sands have made it impossible to know the exact numbers of el-Alamein's dead. Untold thousands of men are hidden. From time to time the featureless landscape, too dry even for shrubs, releases a stilled skeleton or exposes a mine. Estimates of casualties _ dead, wounded, captured and missing _ total 72,500: the Axis suffered 59,000 and the Commonwealth sustained 13,500. <ORGANIZATION> El-Alamein </ORGANIZATION> tells the story of its 12 days in world history in a small museum. The visitor passes large Nazi and <ORGANIZATION> Commonwealth </ORGANIZATION> flags on the way to display cases of weaponry, uniforms, battle plans and related documents. Department-store dummies are decked out as the meticulous and calculating <PERSON> Montgomery </PERSON> and lean <PERSON> Rommel </PERSON>. Outside is a row of tanks, gathering dust, including the Italians' M-13 that <PERSON> Montgomery </PERSON>'s tankmen called the `` self-propelled coffin.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881022-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-22-88 0013EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Hostages 2ndLd-Writethru a0783 10-22 0813</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Hostages, 2nd Ld-Writethru, a0783,0835</SECOND>
<HEAD>Kidnappers Threaten Hostages In Retaliation For Israeli Air Strike</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: LEADS with 7 grafs to UPDATE with photograph confirmed as
same as April photo, PICKS UP 8th pvs `The 29-line...'</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By FAROUK NASSAR</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BEIRUT, Lebanon (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Shiite Moslem kidnappers on Friday threatened to harm two American hostages to retaliate for Israeli air attacks on <LOCATION> Palestinian </LOCATION> and pro-Iranian guerrilla bases in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>. `` Committing this stupidity and this attack shall not pass without a punishment,'' said a typewritten statement in Arabic signed by <ORGANIZATION> Islamic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Jihad </ORGANIZATION>, the pro-Iranian faction holding <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> journalist <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> and educator <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Sutherland </PERSON>. The typewritten Arabic statement was delivered to the independent <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> newspaper An-Nahar hours after the attack. An authenticating color picture of <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> was delivered to the <ORGANIZATION> Reuters </ORGANIZATION> news agency with a copy of the statement, but it was the same photograph the group released of <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> in April. The statement praised the Shiite Moslem suicide car bomber who killed seven Israeli soldiers and wounded eight soldiers and two <LOCATION> Lebanese </LOCATION> women in <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s self-declared security zone in south <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> on Wednesday. That attack prompted <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s retaliatory air strike, which killed 15 people and wounded 35 in south <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> on Friday. The instant photo showed <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON>, 40, chief <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> correspondent for <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>, wearing a Commodore Hotel T-shirt and a bushy beard and mustache. He looked straight into the camera without his glasses. It was the 11th picture released of <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>'s longest-held foreign captive, abducted in Moslem west <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> March 16, 1985. It was the same photograph released of <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> on April 10, when <LOCATION> Islamic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jihad </LOCATION> threatened to harm the hostages if a Kuwaiti jetliner hijacked to <LOCATION> Larnaca </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Cyprus </LOCATION> was stormed to free the passengers. The 29-line statement began with several verses from the Koran, <ORGANIZATION> Islam </ORGANIZATION>'s holy book, and deplored <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s air attack as a `` challenge to the will of our oppressed people.'' It accused the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> administration of giving <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> advance approval to attack <LOCATION> Palestinian </LOCATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Hezbollah </ORGANIZATION> guerrillas in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>. The pro-Iranian <ORGANIZATION> Hezbollah </ORGANIZATION>, or Party of God, had claimed responsibility for the suicide bombing. `` The criminal <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> must realize it will not get away with what it has done, especially in connection with the hostages we hold, so that will be a lesson to whoever strikes at the dignity and glory of our people and mujahedeen -LRB- holy fighters -RRB-,'' it said. <PERSON> Sheik </PERSON> <PERSON> Fadlallah </PERSON>, considered to be <ORGANIZATION> Hezbollah </ORGANIZATION>'s spiritual leader, said he would do his best to protect the hostages. `` We continue to respect our previous commitments to defend human rights in order to see these hostages free and safe as soon as possible,'' he said. `` We will do our utmost to see that nothing happens to any of them.'' He spoke in <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> with <PERSON> Ray </PERSON> <PERSON> Barnett </PERSON>, a Canadian representative of <ORGANIZATION> Ambassadors </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aid </ORGANIZATION>, a group that helps orphans in Third World countries. In <LOCATION> Cadiz </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ky. </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON>'s sister, <PERSON> Peggy </PERSON> <PERSON> Say </PERSON>, issued a statement asking his captors to `` recognize that <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> is totally innocent and has never been involved in the continuing <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> strife except as a captive for 3 -LCB- years.'' `` It is totally unjust to hold him responsible for the military actions of another country,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Say </PERSON> said. Friday's statement was the first since Aug. 18, when the group said none of its hostages would be released soon. <PERSON> Sutherland </PERSON>, 56, of <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Collins </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Colo. </LOCATION>, was acting dean of agriculture at the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Beirut </ORGANIZATION> when he was abducted June 9, 1985. <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> and <PERSON> Sutherland </PERSON> are among nine Americans believed held by pro-Iranian extremist factions linked to <ORGANIZATION> Hezbollah </ORGANIZATION>. Others held are three Britons, an Irishman and an Italian. In <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Redman </PERSON> called for an end to violence between <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> and urged the kidnappers to free their hostages. Asked about the Islamic Jihad warning, he said: `` These are innocent victims. They are being held through no fault of their own ... And the appeal to the hostage-holders has to be always, ` Release these innocent people.''' In a separate development Friday, the weekly <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> magazine <PERSON> Ash-Shiraa </PERSON> said the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> were working out a new deal to free the American hostages before the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> presidential election on Nov. 8. <PERSON> Ash-Shiraa </PERSON> said the deal would ensure the victory of Vice President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> in exchange for a commitment from the <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> candidate to rearm <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>. There was no way to verify the report. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has stressed that it has no contacts with <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>. Ash-Shiraa, which has access to Iranian hardliners, gained international fame in Nov. 1986 when it broke the story of the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> secret arms sales to <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>. But most of its subsequent reports about the hostages have been inaccurate. Other reports have said both <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and Democratic candidate <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> sent envoys to work out a deal with the Iranians on the hostages. Both candidates denied the reports.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881022-0025 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-22-88 0116EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Fashion     10-22 0626</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Fashion,0645</SECOND>
<HEAD>Lagerfeld Shows Longer Skirts, Merry Widow Waistlines</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: First available for Saturday AMs</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By SUZY PATTERSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Fashion Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PARIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Merry widow corset effects gave definition to <PERSON> Karl </PERSON> <PERSON> Lagerfeld </PERSON>'s summer ready-to-wear collection. But even with these ribbed waistlines, his show was full of softness, a new note on the fashion scene. The new, easy clothes were appealing, but lacked the firm dynamics that the fashion world has come to expect of <LOCATION> Lagerfeld </LOCATION>. Most of the clothes shown Friday were nice without being sensational. A lot of pants, very straight and not too wide, looked excellent in off-white topped by deep rose or dusty green blazers. Seen on soft green jersey dresses, the merry widow touch of ribbed seams was a detail that never cinched the waist in. Another option was pinstriped trouser suits, and high hats gave them trouser suits a raffish, 19th century charm. A few short skirts cropped up, notably in some white knit `` tennis'' style dresses with red or green stripes at hem and turtle neck. But they were just a few inches above the knee. <LOCATION> Lagerfeld </LOCATION> announced long ago that longer skirts were coming in, and he sees that they do, showing most skirts way below knee level. With a few pastels and plenty of black and white in linens, knits and cottons, the effect was nearly subdued. For those who love knits and do n't want the ribbed corset effect, a lot of easy pleated midcalf skirts were belted near the hip with wide and handsome belts with gobby metal decor. <PERSON> Lagerfeld </PERSON> played around with jackets, making some hems in tulip shapes, belting others, cutting out some fitted numbers with rounded decolletes. Coat dresses at <LOCATION> Lagerfeld </LOCATION> were long and full, almost ending up looking like housecoats in a wallpaper flower print. The navy wool crepe full-skirted coat dress was topped by a big organdy bow _ also added to a simple but easily-cut trouser suit. <PERSON> Lagerfeld </PERSON> also came up with an excellent suite of tiered and pleated ivory crepe de chine numbers with fullish leg o' mutton sleeves and wide brown belts. The evening wear was sparse but did feature some fitted and full-skirted dresses, some with chiffon halter necklines and skirts, others with long, fitted torsoes in black lace and white pique. Easy-to-wear was also the idea at <PERSON> Popy </PERSON> <PERSON> Moreni </PERSON>, an Italian-born designer who has been showing in <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> for several years now. Her clothes were often based on gray _ in full shiny wool trench coats, in wool and silk trouser suits and dresses with full skirts. The overall effect was always girlish. To contrast with all the gray, lilac and yellow also came out in wide knit culotte suits or paired with charcoal in draped tops. With details like jabots on pinstriped shirt-jackets, or full skirts under fitted torsoes, the clothes were feminine and young. For the sporty set, <PERSON> Moreni </PERSON> also showed a line of striped wide Bermudas and shorts. The dressy touch here was also disarmingly girlish in a series of long-skirted ivory silks and a big line of white cottons with ruffles and tiers that looked like simplified versions of 18th century frilliness. For garden parties or dressy barbecues, the pretty flowered chiffon dresses or multicolored rainbow numbers had unsophisticated charm. Like all of <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Bernard </PERSON> <PERSON> Perris </PERSON> showed plenty of pants, from buttoned, tight toreador style to the widest pyjamas. His lines were always soft, but jackets for long skirts and trousers were cut with big wing lapels and swallow-tails. The color scheme was subdued, with soft pearl gray and pastels in light wools, cotton and silks. Even the boleros were waist-nipped, and while the emphasis was on dressier clothes, <PERSON> Perris </PERSON> also brought out wide street shorts with cuffs and spencer jackets.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881022-0026 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-22-88 0126EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Deaths 1stLd-Writethru a0843 10-22 0382</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Deaths, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0843,0390</SECOND>
<NOTE>Eds: ADDS Jones; Separates moved for AMs as a0800 on Campbell and
as a0815 on Isbell. Isbell also moved on the business wire.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>William Campbell</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WEST PALM BEACH, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Campbell </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District judge who prosecuted gangster <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> Capone </PERSON> and was the longest-tenured federal judge in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, died Wednesday of complications from surgery. He was 83. <PERSON> Campbell </PERSON> was one of the prosecutors who got the notorious <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> hoodlum convicted on tax-evasion charges. <PERSON> Capone </PERSON> died in prison in 1947. <PERSON> Campbell </PERSON>, appointed to the federal bench in 1940 by President <PERSON> Franklin </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Roosevelt </PERSON>, rose to become chief judge in <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION>' northern district and twice declined a seat on the 7th <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION> Circuit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appeals </ORGANIZATION>. He retired in 1970 but continued to hear federal cases in <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> and for the past nine years at the federal courthouse in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Palm </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>Marion Isbell</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SCOTTSDALE, Ariz. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
