<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881105-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-05-88 0004EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-GenocideTreaty Bjt   11-05 0869</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Genocide Treaty, Bjt,890</SECOND>
<HEAD>Reagan Signature on Ratification Ends 40-Year Battle</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LAWRENCE L. KNUTSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A treaty banning genocide finally has the force of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> law, bringing to a close 40 years of opposition by conservatives and putting a final feather in the political cap of retiring Sen. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Proxmire </PERSON>. President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> signed legislation Friday to implement the treaty, which was ratified by the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> on Feb. 11, 1986. By the time the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> acted, 95 other nations had ratified the treaty. The implementing legislation was passed last month. <PERSON> Proxmire </PERSON> had delivered more than 3,000 speeches over 19 years before the ratification vote. Conservatives fought it all the way. They contended the treaty undermined rights of Americans under the Constitution and infringed on <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> sovereignty. The legislation signed by <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> implements the treaty by making genocide _ the deliberate destruction of a specific population _ punishable under <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> law and setting stern penalties for violators. The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> version of the genocide implementation bill is officially called `` The Proxmire Act'' to honor the long crusade of the <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION> Democrat who is closing out a 31-year <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> career. Speaking Friday in <ORGANIZATION> Eau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Claire </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Wis </LOCATION>.. <PERSON> Proxmire </PERSON> said he was not given enough advance notice to attend the bill signing ceremony `` I was sorry I could not be there, but the important thing is that it was signed,'' <PERSON> Proxmire </PERSON> said. `` It should have been done long ago.'' The treaty was drafted after World War II as a response to the Nazi Holocaust that killed millions of <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>'s Jews and other ethnic minorities. It was approved by the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> at the end of 1948 and submitted to the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> early the next year by President <PERSON> Truman </PERSON>. The <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> frequently embarrassed American diplomats by claiming that the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> failure to ratify the pact was evidence the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> lacked a complete commitment to human rights. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> signed the genocide bill at a ceremony at <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> O'Hare </LOCATION> <LOCATION> International </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION>, saying he was `` delighted to fulfill the promise made by <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> Truman </PERSON> to all the peoples of the world _ and especially the Jewish people.'' The president recalled the <ORGANIZATION> Nazi </ORGANIZATION> death camps that claimed millions of Jews, Slavs, Gypsies and others and said similar atrocities have since taken place in <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> Ukraine </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Ethiopia </LOCATION>. These events `` only renew our rage and righteous fury and make this moment all the more significant for me and all Americans,'' <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said. Addressing the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> on Oct. 14, shortly before the genocide bill was passed, <PERSON> Proxmire </PERSON> said the treaty was made necessary `` by the deliberate murder of 6 million Jews.'' `` They were gassed, lined up and shot and they were worked to death,'' he said. `` Why? Only because they worshipped God in a different way.'' <PERSON> Proxmire </PERSON> drew praise from his colleagues for his `` long and often lonely'' fight and Sen. <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Biden </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, D-Del., told the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>: `` I have no single doubt in my mind that there would be no treaty without Senator <PERSON> Proxmire </PERSON>. `` The senator from <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION> never stopped talking; his was a kind of moral filibuster,'' said <PERSON> Seymour </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Reich </PERSON>, international president of B'Nai B'rith, at a reception honoring <PERSON> Proxmire </PERSON> a few days later. The Proxmire Act defines genocide as an action taken with a `` specific intent to destroy, in whole or in substantial part, a national, ethnic, racial or religious group.'' It would apply to activities in which members of those groups were killed, seriously injured or permanently impaired through the use of drugs, torture or `` similar techniques'' or were subjected to conditions aimed at causing `` the physical destruction of the group.'' Also included are efforts to prevent births within a group or forcefully removing children. If death results, people found responsible could be fined up to $ 1 million and imprisoned for life. Where no death is involved, the punishment is set at a fine of up to $ 1 million and 20 ears in prison. Under the law, anyone convicted of inciting another to violate its terms could be fined up to $ 500,000 and imprisoned for up to five years. Legalistic and conservative objections to <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> ratification of the genocide treaty were raised from the beginning. Dr. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Korey </PERSON>, director for international policy research for B'nai B'rith International, wrote in a recent account about the struggle to ratify the pact that part of the problem arose over the treaty's attempt to outlaw genocide `` in whole or in part.'' `` Fears were apparent in various segregationist circles that the reference to `` in part'' might be applied to a limited form of race violence, such as lynchings,'' <PERSON> Korey </PERSON> said. `` The phrase ` mental harm' also raised concerns.'' Other critics said the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> might be embarrassed by an international show trial based on alleged atrocities against <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Indians </ORGANIZATION> in the 19th century. Still others expressed fear that ratification could result in American citizens being tried against their will by an international tribunal, without the protections accorded by the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Constitution. These fears were dealt with in 1986 when the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> adopted reservations asserting the right of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> citizens to contitutional protections and giving the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> the right to exempt itself from compulsory jurisdiction in genocide cases before the World Court.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881105-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-05-88 0006EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-PentagonAudits Bjt   11-05 0547</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Pentagon Audits, Bjt,550</SECOND>
<HEAD>Audits Indicate Questionable Payments By Pentagon</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BRYAN BRUMLEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A Pentagon audit says vague guidelines are to blame for millions of dollars in questionable payments to major defense contractors for work performed by outside consultants. <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Contract </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Audit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION>, in a review of 12 of the top 100 defense contractors, questioned the validity of claims for $ 43 million out of the $ 236.5 million charged to the government over the past year for consultants. A separate audit, by the Pentagon Inspector General's office, estimated that an <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> logistics center in <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION> paid an estimated $ 104 million for spare parts that did not meet contract specifications, amounting to 89 percent of its inventory. The review of consultants' fees by the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Contract </ORGANIZATION> agency involved 12 major contractors: <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dynamics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Hughes </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aircraft </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> IBM </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Litton </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Industries </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Lockheed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Martin </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Marietta </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> McDonnell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Douglas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Northrop </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Raytheon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> UNISYS </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, and <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Technologies </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp </ORGANIZATION>. The audit, released Friday, found that the internal business discipline one would expect at a large company for hiring outsiders is, `` in most cases, non-existent.'' If anything, the total for questionable claims is `` understated,'' the audit added. Often, contractors simply could not explain what work their consultants had performed, the auditors wrote. And in some cases, it appears the consultants performed lobbying or publicity work that should not have been reimbursed. The <ORGANIZATION> DCAA </ORGANIZATION> audit, spawned by a massive fraud investigation at the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION>, depicts a clubby atmosphere in which major contractors rarely ask that consultant contracts be put in writing and frequently hire consultants without soliciting competitive bids. The <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION>, in releasing the audit, announced it already had written new regulations to address the <ORGANIZATION> DCAA </ORGANIZATION>'s concerns. The audit was ordered last July after disclosures that federal prosecutors were conducting a wide-ranging fraud investigation focusing on contractors and their outside consultants along with selected <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> employees. The separate audit on the procurement of spare parts by the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> concluded that the service `` did not receive the quality parts it paid for.'' A spokesman for <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Logistics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Command </ORGANIZATION> at <ORGANIZATION> Wright-Patterson </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Base </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Dayton </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, took sharp issue with the draft Inspector General's report, which was obtained and distributed by the Project on Military Procurement, a private watchdog group in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. `` The figure is very misleading,'' said <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Ken </PERSON> <PERSON> Perrotte </PERSON>. `` They tested a sample and made projections,'' he said, challenging both the methods and the calculations used by the Inspector General's office. To make their estimate, auditors from the inspector general's office visited the <ORGANIZATION> Warner </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Robbins </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Logistics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>, 18 miles south of <LOCATION> Macon </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ga. </LOCATION>, and checked samples of inventory items ranging from a bolt costing $ 6.95 to more complicated hardware costing thousands of dollars per item The total value of the items checked was $ 114.4 million, of which $ 48.4 million worth were found to have major `` nonconformances'' which made them unfit for service and $ 55 million had less serious problems, known as minor nonconformances. The auditors checked 1,027 samples of 46 different items, and projected their results against a total of 685,925 spare parts calculated to have been at the center. Those projections showed that 89 percent of the spares did not meet contract specifications.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881105-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-05-88 0006EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-ColliderCost     11-05 0312</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Collider Cost,300</SECOND>
<HEAD>Budget Office Says Cost of Super Collider May be Underestimated</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID FOX</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Energy Department's estimate of the cost of building a superconducting super collider could be nearly 50 percent too low, a government study says. The <ORGANIZATION> Congressional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Budget </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> study said the price tag could be $ 6.4 billion if costs follow the pattern for atom smashers already built. It offered a second estimate, which it said was based on more conservative assumptions, of $ 5.1 billion. The Energy Department has put the project's cost at $ 4.4 billion, a figure it said was accurate within 10 percent given that final design studies will not be done until a site is chosen. The collider would be a 53-mile, underground ring of magnets capable of whipping proton beams together with 20 times the force of the most powerful existing accelerator, the Tevatron at the <ORGANIZATION> Fermi </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Accelerator </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Laboratory </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Batavia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ill. </LOCATION>. Scientists hope to learn more about the nature of matter from studying the subatomic particles created by the proton collisions The study released this week by the <ORGANIZATION> Congressional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Budget </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> said the <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> may have underestimated the price of collider components such as proton-collision detectors and overestimated savings expected from advances in the manufacture of superconducting magnets. Superconductors transmit electricity without resistance. <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> has appropriated $ 205 million for the collider, including $ 100 million for research and development in the fiscal year that began Oct. 1, but has not authorized its construction. <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> were chosen as finalists from among 25 states bidding for the collider, which will provide its host with thousands of construction jobs and permanent work for as many as 3,000 people. Energy Secretary <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Herrington </PERSON> is expected to announce a tentative site selection this month and confirm the choice by January 1989.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881105-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-05-88 0008EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-CannonMishap     11-05 0439</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Cannon Mishap,430</SECOND>
<HEAD>Criminal Charges Dismissed Against Aspiring Weapon-Maker</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KATHERINE RIZZO</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ARLINGTON, Va. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A decorated former <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> colonel who inadvertently shot a 30mm anti-tank shell into a service station gasoline pump has escaped criminal charges. <LOCATION> Arlington </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> General District Judge <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Sheridan </PERSON> on Friday dismissed a misdemeanor charge against <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Dilger </PERSON>, saying, `` I'm convinced that you have suffered enough. The judge noted that <PERSON> Dilger </PERSON> scraped together $ 50,000 to help compensate the people injured by flying shrapnel in the August 1986 explosion. <PERSON> Dilger </PERSON> had pleaded no contest a little over a year ago to the misdemeanor charge of discharging a firearm in a public place. <PERSON> Sheridan </PERSON> had postponed sentencing in order to give <PERSON> Dilger </PERSON> a chance to try to compensate the people hurt in the explosion. Three of the four people injured sued <PERSON> Dilger </PERSON> and the federal government. Attorneys for the injured said the government was partly at fault for supplying <PERSON> Dilger </PERSON> with ammunition. The Army never admitted liability, but one of <PERSON> Dilger </PERSON>'s attorneys said the government had agreed to pay 80 percent of the settlement to the victims. That agreement was reached about two weeks ago. `` It seems to me that the injured people have been satisfied,'' <PERSON> Sheridan </PERSON> said. The local prosecutor did not object to the dismissal of the charge. <PERSON> Dilger </PERSON>, who was trying to market the 30mm anti-tank cannon to the Pentagon at the time of the accident, refused comment after the hearing. <PERSON> Dilger </PERSON> told authorities he had been filling his pickup truck with gasoline when he noticed his companion, <PERSON> Raymond </PERSON> <PERSON> Donohue </PERSON>, was examining the cannon. When he tried to show <PERSON> Donohue </PERSON> how the weapon worked, `` it went off. Nobody could have been more surprised than myself.'' Following the explosion, <PERSON> Dilger </PERSON> said, he picked up one victim and pulled her away from the burning pumps, then moved the truck and another vehicle away from the pumps. <PERSON> Dilger </PERSON> and <PERSON> Donohue </PERSON> drove away from the scene, but had second thoughts and said they had started circling back toward the station when stopped by police. <PERSON> Sheridan </PERSON> said he considered criminal penalties because <PERSON> Dilger </PERSON> _ winner of three Silver Stars and four Distinguished Flying Crosses in <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> _ left the scene of the accident. `` The only upsetting part of this was the walking away,'' the judge said. `` That is the only reason I would have denied the -LRB- dismissal -RRB- request.'' <PERSON> Theresa </PERSON> <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON>, a former gas station employee, had sought $ 2.4 million in damages. <PERSON> Elda </PERSON> and <PERSON> Domenico </PERSON> <PERSON> Gargani </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Arlington </LOCATION>, who were sitting in a nearby car when the pump exploded, sought $ 1 million each. All three were injured by metal fragments from the explosion.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881105-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-05-88 0011EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-VitaminDeficiency-Deaths     11-05 0476</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Vitamin Deficiency-Deaths,460</SECOND>
<HEAD>FDA Says Three Patients Dead From Vitamin B1 Deficiency; Warns
Doctors</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PAUL RECER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Science Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Three people receiving intravenous feedings have died from a vitamin B1 deficiency, the <ORGANIZATION> Food </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Drug </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> announced as it urged doctors to be sure patients being fed by needle are getting the essential nutrient. Identities of the patients were not released, but the <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> said Friday the deaths were indirectly due to a national shortage of a multivitamin preparation usually added to the liquid given patients receiving intravenous feedings. The shortage occurred after a <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> manufacturer of the multivitamin supplement, <ORGANIZATION> Lyphomed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, had to cut production after the <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> ordered a recall in July of some of the company's product. <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Grigg </PERSON>, an <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> spokesman, said that as a result of the shortage, the federal agency was concerned that patients receiving the IV feedings would not receive vitamin B1, or thiamine, which is essential to the body. `` Potentially fatal thiamine deficiencies could result because thiamine is consumed at a high rate in patients receiving intravenous feedings of glucose sugar,'' said the <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> announcement. The announcement came after the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION> for Parentral and <ORGANIZATION> Enternal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nutrition </ORGANIZATION>, an organization of experts in IV feedings, warned its 5,000 members that three patients receiving IV feedings have died as a result of thiamine deficiency. <PERSON> Marsha </PERSON> <PERSON> Regenstein </PERSON>, a spokeswoman at <LOCATION> ASPEN </LOCATION>, confirmed the deaths, but said the organization's legal counsel had advised against identifying the patients. <PERSON> Grigg </PERSON> said he had no further details on the deaths. Intravenous, or IV, feedings are used for patients who are unable to take food by mouth. This would include those who are unconscious or who do not have an intact digestive system due to surgery, injury or disease. <PERSON> Janet </PERSON> <PERSON> Gannon </PERSON>, a dietician for <LOCATION> ASPEN </LOCATION>, said those most at risk are patients receiving what is called parentral feedings. She said such patients receive liquid feedings of 70 percent glucose through a needle that leads directly into the aorta. A shortage of thiamine in such patients can develop in as little as a week because the vitamin is essential for metabolizing the glucose. About 10,000 to 15,000 patients in the nation are on parentral feeding, she said. Vitamin B1 is essential for functioning of the cardiovascular and nervous system, and for metabolism. A deficiency results in a disease called beriberi. Severe cases can lead to heart failure and death. Thiamine easily can be added to the routine IV feedings, Ms. <PERSON> Gannon </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Melissa </PERSON> <PERSON> Marsden </PERSON>, a spokeswoman at <ORGANIZATION> Lyphomed </ORGANIZATION>, the company chose to close its <LOCATION> Orlando </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION> plant for a time after <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> inspectors found a problem that involved keeping products sterile. She said the problem has been corrected and <ORGANIZATION> Lyphomed </ORGANIZATION> is now back into full production. <PERSON> Grigg </PERSON> said it is expected that the shortage of the vitamin supplement will be corrected soon.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881105-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-05-88 0012EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Reagan-AIDS     11-05 0527</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Reagan-AIDS,520</SECOND>
<HEAD>President Signs Into Law Bill Raising AIDS Spending</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> has signed into law legislation boosting spending on AIDS testing, research and education by up to $ 870 million a year. The compromise measure, stripped of controversial elements that had tied it up for months, was approved by the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> in separate voice votes on Oct. 13. White House officials traveling with <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> on Friday announced in <LOCATION> Voorhees </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Township </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.J. </LOCATION>, that the president had signed the measure. Fearful that no legislation expanding spending on AIDS programs would be passed because of opposition from conservatives _ particuarly Sen. <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Helms </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-N.C. </LOCATION> _ the measure's chief backers agreed to bring it up as part of an overall health package that skirted the controversial matters of confidentiality for AIDS test results and antidiscrimination protection for those found to carry the virus. As finally approved, the measure authorizes $ 100 million a year for AIDS testing over the next two years and an additional $ 100 million in each of the next two years for home health care of people with AIDS. It also includes up to $ 300 million in new research funds in each of the next three years and $ 370 million additional for AIDS education. Although disappointed they were not able to push through provisions guaranteeing confidentiality and antidiscrimination protection, AIDS activists in and out of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> said a bill that essentially just expanded spending without breaking new policy ground was better than no bill at all. The main authors, Rep. <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Waxman </PERSON>, D-Calif., and Sen. <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, D-Mass., have vowed to continue their quest for confidentiality and antidiscrimination protection when the new <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> convenes in Whatever the outcome of the presidential election next Tuesday, backers of such provisions are encouraged they will have more support from the White House. Both Republican <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and Democrat <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> have said they support the White House AIDS commission's call last summer for federal antidiscrimination legislation as the single most important tool in fighting the disease. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> has made no such declaration, referring the matter to the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> for study. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s top health adviser told reporters this week that the vice president, if elected, would push for antidiscrimination legislation. Health professionals maintain that the best way to curb the spread of the virus, which federal officials estimate has already infected up to 1.5 million <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> residents, is to do everything possible to encourage people to come forward for testing and counseling. And the best way to do that, they argue, is to insure that people who carry the virus will not be punished by arbitrarily losing their jobs, homes and health insurance. The chief victims of acquired immune deficiency syndrome have been homosexual men and intravenous drug users, although a small percentage of cases are attributed to transfusions of contaminated blood, heterosexual contact and spread from infected pregnant women to their offspring. As of Monday, AIDS had been diagnsed in 76,932 Americans, of whom more than half, or 43,177, have died since June 1, 1981, according to the federal <ORGANIZATION> Centers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Disease </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Control </ORGANIZATION>. No one is known to have recovered from AIDS.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881105-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-05-88 0051EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lottery     11-05 0025</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lottery,0025</SECOND>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the winning weekly state lottery numbers picked Friday:
</TEXT>
<HEAD>CONNECTICUT</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Lotto: 08; 11; 25; 26; 31; 34.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881105-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-05-88 0053EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Hirohito     11-05 0165</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Hirohito,0170</SECOND>
<HEAD>Antibiotics Lower Emperor's Fever</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Emperor <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON>'s temperature fell today after doctors gave him antibiotics to alleviate intestinal inflammation brought about by a slight discharge of blood, a palace spokesman said. Court doctors said antibiotics were administered Friday for the first time since mid-October to alleviate the inflammation of <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON>'s upper intestinal area. The world's longest-reigning living monarch, 87, has been bedridden since Sept. 19 when he vomited blood because of internal hemorrhaging. He has continued to bleed intermittently, including Friday night, mostly in the upper intestinal area where he underwent a bypass operation last year. <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON> has received 34.2 pints of blood to combat anemia and internal bleeding since his health worsened. Meanwhile, <PERSON> Kyoto </PERSON> <PERSON> Gosho </PERSON>, a palace in western <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> where the imperial family lived until 1868, will open to the public for five days starting today for a biannual festival. But some attractions, including music and dancing, were called off in deference to <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON>'s illness, palace officials said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881105-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-05-88 0054EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Bentsen     11-05 0432</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bentsen,430</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bentsen Returns To California In Search of `Big Prize'</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By STEVEN KOMAROW</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> is in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> for a final day of campaigning there in hopes of putting <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> over the top in that most important state. `` This is the big prize. Forty-seven electoral votes,'' he said on arrival Friday night at the <LOCATION> Burbank </LOCATION> airport. `` We win this one, we win it all,'' he said. <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> claimed the latest polls showed the Republican lead collapsing and insisted the Democrats still had time to catch them by election day. <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> planned to attend a get-out-the-vote rally this morning in <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>. `` The Republicans are dropping like a rock in those polls,'' he told the cheering crowd of several hundred at the airport rally. <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> was in <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> earlier in the day. In <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> worked to highlight the Democratic ticket's commitment to the space program, which has a major presence in <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> industry and with the <ORGANIZATION> Johnson </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Space </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION> The <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> senator toured the Challenger Center at the <ORGANIZATION> Houston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Museum </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Natural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Science </ORGANIZATION>. The center was founded as part of an effort, in the wake of the 1986 Challenger space shuttle tragedy, to boost interest in science and technology among the young. <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> looked at a mock space station to watch fourth graders operate various devices, and he took an electronic stress test. A girl held wires to <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>'s finger and measured only 1.6 on a scale in which 5 is considered normal. `` That means I'm cool,'' the senator quipped. <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> also met with a student audience in the museum auditorium, and made an unusual miscue. The man <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> has said would head up his cabinet council on space asserted that the next space shuttle launched, the Atlantis, would be unmanned. In fact, the ship will have a crew of five for its secret military mission later this month. Aides attributed the mistake to an incorrect briefing paper. On his way to <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> stopped in <LOCATION> Las </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Cruces </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.M. </LOCATION>, for a rally at that airport with about 500 supporters, hosted by Sen. <PERSON> Jeff </PERSON> <PERSON> Bingaman </PERSON>, <PERSON> D-N.M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> said he wanted to `` set'em straight'' on issues the Republicans have distorted, such as gun control and defense. The <LOCATION> Las </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Cruces </LOCATION> area is near the <LOCATION> White </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sands </LOCATION> testing area, and government research dollars are important to the area economy. <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> told the crowd a Democratic administration would spend $ 1 billion a year on research on Star Wars. The Democrats currently oppose deployment of a space-based missile defense system.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881105-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-05-88 0054EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w AM-Obit-Tippett     11-05 0148</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Obit-Tippett,130</SECOND>
<HEAD>Mary Whitney Tippett, Longtime Horsebreeder, Dead at 82</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> Whitney </PERSON> <PERSON> Tippett </PERSON>, a horsebreeder for more than 50 years, died of cancer at her <LOCATION> Llangollen </LOCATION> Farm near <LOCATION> Upperville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>. She was 82 Mrs. <PERSON> Tippett </PERSON> had raised horses in <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION> since her 1930 marriage to <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Hay </PERSON> <PERSON> Whitney </PERSON>. He later became <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> ambassador to <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> and was a publisher of the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Herald </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tribune </ORGANIZATION>. Mrs. <PERSON> Tippett </PERSON> died Oct. 30. An accomplished horsewoman, she received <ORGANIZATION> Llangollen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Farm </ORGANIZATION>, a 3,300-acre estate, from <LOCATION> Whitney </LOCATION> as a wedding gift. When the couple divorced in 1940, Mrs. <PERSON> Tippett </PERSON> established the farm as a major racing stables in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. As early as 1933, her 2-year-old colt Singing Wood won the Belmont Futurity. By the late 1950s, Mrs. <PERSON> Tippett </PERSON> had one of the largest privately-owned horse breeding businesses in <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881105-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-05-88 0103EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Forman     11-05 0399</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Forman,0410</SECOND>
<HEAD>Forman's Films to be Shown in Czechoslovakia</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: First available for Saturday AMs</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By ONDREJ HEJMA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PRAGUE, Czechoslovakia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The complete works of filmmaker <PERSON> Milos </PERSON> <PERSON> Forman </PERSON>, Oscar-winning director of `` One Flew Over the Cuckoo's Nest'' and `` Amadeus,'' are being bought for distribution in <LOCATION> Czechoslovakia </LOCATION> 20 years after he left his native land A report in Friday's <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> daily newspaper Rude Pravo announced the purchase, confirming rumors in <LOCATION> Prague </LOCATION> that <PERSON> Forman </PERSON> movies such as `` Hair'' finally will be seen in the country where he spent his first 36 years. `` It is great that they will show his films at last, I just do n't know why they could n't do so before,'' actress <PERSON> Vera </PERSON> <PERSON> Kresadlova </PERSON>, <PERSON> Forman </PERSON>'s first wife and mother of his twin sons, told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> by phone `` I guess they finally realized that if <PERSON> Milos </PERSON> ` walks' the streets of <LOCATION> Prague </LOCATION> again, it does n't have to cause a riot.'' A <LOCATION> Prague </LOCATION> film critic who asked to remain anonymous welcomed the news and opined it indicated that `` those friends and colleagues of his -LRB- <PERSON> Forman </PERSON>'s -RRB- who managed to keep the lid on his work for a long time are finally retiring.'' <PERSON> Forman </PERSON>'s first films were made in <LOCATION> Czechoslovakia </LOCATION> in the 1960s, including `` Fireman's Ball,'' which is enjoying another run in <LOCATION> Prague </LOCATION> right now, according to Rude Pravo. <PERSON> Forman </PERSON> moved to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> in 1968, when <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION> Pact tanks ended the `` Prague Spring'' reforms, and started his second career with `` Taking Off'' in 1971. But it was `` One Flew Over the Cuckoo's Nest'' that brought him worldwide fame, winning five Oscars and becoming a symbol of artistic skill for Czechoslovaks who were not able to see the film officially. In 1977, <PERSON> Forman </PERSON> was given American citizenship and went on to make `` Hair'' and `` Ragtime.'' Neither was purchased by <LOCATION> Czechoslovakia </LOCATION>'s state-run film distribution firms With the spread of video in the 1980s, bootleg copies spread on the black market in <LOCATION> Czechoslovakia </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Forman </PERSON> returned to <LOCATION> Czechoslovakia </LOCATION> in 1983 to shoot `` Amadeus'' in <LOCATION> Prague </LOCATION>. The film was shown in 1986 as <LOCATION> Czechoslovakia </LOCATION>'s most other famous exile in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, tennis star <PERSON> Martina </PERSON> <PERSON> Navratilova </PERSON>, returned to her native land to play in the Federation Cup tournament. In 1987, <PERSON> Forman </PERSON> went to <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>'s international film festival as signs emerged that the Soviet drive for more openness in the arts was breaking down some previous tabus in <LOCATION> Czechoslovakia </LOCATION>'s state-run arts.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881105-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-05-88 0036EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p AM-MinnesotaPoll     11-05 0174</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Minnesota Poll,170</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush Erases Longstanding Dukakis Lead in Minnesota</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ST. PAUL, Minn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrat <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> has lost his lead over Republican <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> among likely <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION> voters for the first time in their presidential race, according to a poll released Saturday. The Northstar Poll found <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> with a 48 percent to 45 percent lead among likely <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION> voters, the <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Paul </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pioneer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dispatch </ORGANIZATION> reported in its Saturday editions. The poll is conducted by the <ORGANIZATION> Pioneer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dispatch </ORGANIZATION>, WCCO_TV and WCCO-Radio in the Twin Cities. Since the poll has a margin of error of plus or minus four percentage points, the race amounts to a dead heat in the state. The survey of 646 likely voters was conducted from Monday through Thursday, a time of heightened publicity about <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>. The <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> governor was in the Twin Cities Tuesday night and Wednesday morning to visit his wife, <PERSON> Kitty </PERSON>, who was being treated at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Minnesota </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION> for a viral infection. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> once had a double-digit lead in <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881105-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-05-88 0109EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-NewCaledonia     11-05 0595</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-New Caledonia,0611</SECOND>
<HEAD>French to Vote on Future of Restive Pacific Territory</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: First available for Saturday AMs</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By JEFFREY ULBRICH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PARIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The French vote Sunday on a referendum the government hopes will bring peace to the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> territory of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Caledonia </LOCATION> following a campaign that has generated little enthusiasm and confusion about what they're voting on. Polls leading up to the vote indicate only 38 percent of the eligible voters will cast ballots. Of those who said they would go to the polls, 84 percent said they would approve the plan. Periodic violence has broken out in the territory since November 1984 between native Melanesians, known locally as Kanaks, and white settlers, called Caldoches. Nearly 40 people have been killed. On April 22, Melanesians attacked a police station on the island of <LOCATION> Ouvea </LOCATION>, killing four policemen and taking 27 others hostage. On May 5, an assault on a cave where the kidnappers held the hostages killed two more policemen and 19 Kanaks. The latest attacks sobered Caledonians, native and European, and caused them to rethink their attitudes. The plan to be voted on Sunday has attracted great support in mainland <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>. Governing Socialists, Communists, and center-right <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> French </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democracy </ORGANIZATION> all are backing a `` yes'' vote on Sunday. Premier <PERSON> Michel </PERSON> <PERSON> Rocard </PERSON> has taken a front-line role in the campaign. `` I do n't want there to be any more violence and deaths in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Caledonia </LOCATION>,'' the premier said. `` I say no to civil war, and the only means of preventing this danger is the ` yes' in the referendum,'' he said. The conservative Rally for the Republic is campaigning for absention. It says it can not disavow its local arm, which agreed to the plan, but also can not vote for it because of constitutional objections. <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>'s Socialist government is asking voters Sunday to approve measures set out in 96 articles of a long draft law that few people have read and, because of its legalistic language, even fewer have understood. Some people interviewed by newspapers and television seem to think they are voting directly on independence for <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Caledonia </LOCATION>. Others are not sure exactly what they are voting for, though some say they will vote anyway. The essential provision is for a local referendum in 10 years to decide if the territory becomes independent or remains French. Meanwhile, the new law would divide <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Caledonia </LOCATION> into three provinces, each with its own local assembly, and an elected territorial congress with no pre-determined ethnic breakdown. The territory would be ruled directly from <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> until next summer, when the new bodies and local administration would take over. The population of the archipelago, controlled by <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> since 1853, is 145,000. Forty-three percent are native Melanesians mostly favoring independence. But they are in the minority because most Polynesians and Asians support the European community of 37 percent that generally wants to remain French. The plan to be put before French voters Sunday came out of June discussions between <PERSON> Jean-Marie </PERSON> <PERSON> Tjibaou </PERSON>, leader of the <ORGANIZATION> Kanak </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Socialist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION>, and <PERSON> Jacques </PERSON> <PERSON> Lafleur </PERSON>, head of anti-independence <ORGANIZATION> Rally </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Caledonia </ORGANIZATION> in the Republic. They met in <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> with <PERSON> Rocard </PERSON>, and the resulting plan was lauded as one of the successes of <PERSON> Rocard </PERSON>'s new government. A referendum on independence was held in the territory Sept. 13, 1987, when local voters supported remaining French by 98.3 percent to 1.7 percent. But the main Melanesian group had called for a boycott, keeping turnout to 59 percent. All eligible French voters, including those in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Caledonia </LOCATION> and other overseas territories, may vote Sunday.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881105-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-05-88 0122EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Hirohito-News     11-05 0626</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Hirohito-News,0645</SECOND>
<HEAD>Gathering News of Emperor's Illness Wearies Palace And Press</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: First available for Saturday AMs</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By TERRIL JONES</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Keeping the public informed about the illness of Emperor <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON> has proved to be a marathon job for an overworked palace staff and weary press corps. Hundreds of journalists stake out the <ORGANIZATION> Imperial </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Household </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> and the seven gates to the moated palace in hopes of snaring visitors who have just seen <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON>, or of gleaning a clue to his health from seeing who is entering the palace _ the chief doctors, or a blood-delivery car. Dozens of Japanese reporters and cameramen fill the vaulted halls of the palace agency, rolled up in blankets on the floor, slumped over lawn chairs or vacantly reading comic books. Others scribble away elbow to elbow at tiny desks in the press room. Some go home so rarely that the media have virtually taken over nearby hotels. `` We've had a couple of reporters hospitalized out of sheer fatigue,'' said a reporter for <ORGANIZATION> Tokyo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Broadcasting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> System </ORGANIZATION>, a major private TV network. News reports have consisted almost entirely of detailed updates on <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON>'s pulse, temperature, blood pressure, respiration, blood transfusions and vague palace comments that the monarch is `` resting.'' The 87-year-old <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON> began suffering from internal bleeding Sept. 19 and since has been given many blood transfusions. The sole official source for such news is <PERSON> Kenji </PERSON> <PERSON> Maeda </PERSON>, who until July was police chief in northern <LOCATION> Aomori </LOCATION> prefecture. <PERSON> Maeda </PERSON>, 49, is head of the <ORGANIZATION> Imperial </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Household </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Affairs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Division </ORGANIZATION>, which means he is in charge of security as well as palace spokesman. When he took the job, he hastily studied up on imperial history and traditions, but concedes there is no time for that now. The 20-year police veteran still is getting used to the intricacies of the imperial household and the specialized language used to talk to and about family members. `` I admit it all makes me nervous,'' he says carefully, his eyes fluttering from lack of sleep. `` It's been true on-the-job training.'' <PERSON> Maeda </PERSON>, works 12 to 13 hours daily, seven days a week, then faces more telephone calls and reporters when he gets home. The palace press club is a tightly knit grouping of nine big newspapers and six TV networks. Following a Japanese media tradition that gives them exclusive coverage rights, other Japanese media and foreign reporters are barred from membership. `` We understand the media's deep interest,'' said <PERSON> Maeda </PERSON>. `` But they want everything. We just tell them what we feel is necessary.'' His office view of black pine, camphor and sweet acorn trees is marred by a parking lot jammed with media vans bristling with antennae and microwave dishes. Six black telephones sit beside <PERSON> Maeda </PERSON>'s desk, linked with other extensions in the agency, the Fukiage palace where <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON> is bedridden and the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION>. A portrait of the imperial family hangs on a wall next to a huge photograph of the emperor hosting a banquet for President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>. Once viewed as a living god, the emperor still is seen by many as a hallowed symbol of state. According to <ORGANIZATION> Imperial </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Household </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> rules, he may be seen but not heard on television, except in rare appearances before the public, and palace officials refuse to describe his private conversations. <PERSON> Maeda </PERSON>, like any Japanese bureaucrat, refuses to talk about what happens once <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON> dies, dismissing such questions as `` hypothetical.'' For the media, it has been an enormous expense. <ORGANIZATION> Kyodo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> estimates it spends $ 160,000 a day on emperor coverage, while TV networks face daily bills of $ 240,000. But the reporting has been a windfall for some. One <ORGANIZATION> Kyodo </ORGANIZATION> correspondent said he earned $ 4,000 in overtime during the first month of <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON>'s illness.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881105-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-05-88 0130EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a BC-Opera     11-05 0279</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Opera,0293</SECOND>
<HEAD>Met Presents Season's First `Cav' and `Pag'</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: No PMs Planned</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By MARY CAMPBELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The old-favorite pairing of `` Cavalleria Rusticana'' and `` Pagliacci'' returned to the Metropolitan Opera Friday night after three years away. Both had their thrilling moments as well as moments that were n't. <PERSON> Ghena </PERSON> <PERSON> Dimitrova </PERSON>, singing her first <PERSON> Santuzza </PERSON> in `` Cav'' at the Met, has wonderful vocal power which she put on the boil as a woman scorned. Her voice can simultaneously have a harsh delivery, showing <PERSON> Santuzza </PERSON>'s bitter feelings, and a beautiful, big sound. She and tenor <PERSON> Ermanno </PERSON> <PERSON> Mauro </PERSON>, singing Turiddu, blended well, though they did n't always attack the notes at the same time. Their duet in which she pleads with him to return contained passionate singing. Baritone <PERSON> Bruno </PERSON> <PERSON> Pola </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Rovereto </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>, made his Met debut as the farmer whose bride has taken up with Turiddu. He did n't make a favorable impression. Soprano <PERSON> Ilona </PERSON> <PERSON> Tokody </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Szeged </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>, also made her Met debut Friday, as <PERSON> Nedda </PERSON> in `` Pagliacci.'' She has a strong vibrato which sounds unpleasant to Americans, who usually prefer a clear tone. <PERSON> Mauro </PERSON> sang in `` Pag'' also. He sounded good in both but did n't quite make the most of his big `` Pagliacci'' aria `` Vesti la giubba. His finale was stirring. The strongest impressions in the second opera were made by <PERSON> Juan </PERSON> <PERSON> Pons </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Ciudadela </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, singing the Prologue in a focused voice which held the ear's rapt attention without shouting and baritone <PERSON> Gregg </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Memphis </LOCATION>, whose singing as <PERSON> Nedda </PERSON>'s lover sounded intensely romantic. <PERSON> Alessandro </PERSON> <PERSON> Siciliani </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Florence </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>, made his Met debut conducting, with more graceful results in `` Cavalleria Rusticana'' than in `` Pagliacci.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881105-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-05-88 0132EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Congress-CampaignFinances     11-05 0467</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Congress-Campaign Finances,500</SECOND>
<HEAD>Congressional Incumbents Set to Outspend Challengers in Waning Days</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Political Rdp Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ALAN FRAM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 House and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> incumbents, perennially better able to raise money than their challengers, have 14 times more financial ammunition left to fire than their opponents in the campaign's final days. A report released Friday by the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Election </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION>, based on candidates' financial activities through Oct. 19, showed that office-holders had $ 94.7 million left to spend, compared to $ 6.4 million for their opponents. Democratic incumbents held a $ 13.7 million to $ 900,000 edge over <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> challengers in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> and a $ 45.6 million to $ 1.2 million advantage in the House. Republican lawmakers had an advantage over their Democratic challengers of $ 5.9 million to $ 2.2 million in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> and $ 29.5 million to $ 2.1 million in the House. Overall, the report said <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> hopefuls had so far raised $ 157.5 million, barely $ 1 million more than in 1986. There are 33 <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> seat contests this year, one less than there was two years ago. Candidates for the 435 House seats have reported raising $ 202.3 million, 8 percent more than the $ 187.6 million they collected for their warchests in 1986. Of the total, $ 119.7 million has been contributed by political action committees, which are formed by corporations, labor unions, issue-oriented groups and other organizations to donate money to candidates. On average, <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> candidates have raised two-thirds of their money from individuals and 24 percent from PACs, the same percentages as two years ago. House contenders have garnered 49 percent of their money from individuals, down from 51 percent in 1986, and 40 percent from PACs, up from 35 percent in 1986. So far, Democratic incumbents have done a better job of raising money than their <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> challengers by $ 47 million to $ 19.6 million in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> and $ 88.5 million to $ 14.7 million in the House. At the same time, Republican office-holders have collected more than their Democratic opponents by $ 41.8 million to $ 21.7 million in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> and $ 62.9 million to $ 17.2 million in the House. The five top <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> money raisers, and the amounts they have collected overall and from PACs, are Sen. <PERSON> Pete </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON>, R-Calif., $ 9.9 million, $ 1.6 million; Sen. <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Texas </LOCATION>, $ 7.8 million, $ 2.1 million; <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Voinovich </PERSON>, a Republican running in <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, $ 7.1 million, $ 1.2 million; Sen. <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> <PERSON> Metzenbaum </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Ohio </LOCATION>, $ 6.6 million, $ 884,000; <PERSON> Pete </PERSON> <PERSON> Dawkins </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> candidate in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION>, $ 6.6 million, $ 734,000 The five top House money raisers, and the amounts they have collected overall and from PACs, are Rep. <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dornan </PERSON>, R-Calif., $ 1.4 million, $ 62,000; Rep. <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> DioGuardi </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-N.Y. </LOCATION>, $ 1.3 million, $ 314,000; Rep. <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, D-Mass., $ 1.3 million, $ 250,000; <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> K. </PERSON> <PERSON> Hart </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> candidate in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>'s 19th District, $ 1.3 million, $ 408,000; Rep. <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Moody </PERSON>, D-Wis., $ 1.2 million,
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881105-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-05-88 0136EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Quayle     11-05 0467</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Quayle,460</SECOND>
<HEAD>Quayle Criticizes Dukakis Fiscal Policy</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Political Rdp Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MERRILL HARTSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MONROE, La. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Sen. <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> says Governor <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> can not reconcile talk of the `` <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> miracle'' with the fact that a state current-accounts fund is nearly $ 190 million in the red. `` We know, right now, that state's revenue collections are way below estimates,'' <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> vice presidential candidate, told a campaign rally in this northeastern <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION> city. Appearing later Friday before some 5,000 to 6,000 <ORGANIZATION> Auburn </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> students, one of the largest <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> crowds of the campaign, the senator mocked `` tax hike Mike'' and said young people should trust <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> to ensure continued economic prosperity. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> was touring the mid-Atlantic states of <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> today as the long campaign for the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> neared its conclusion. In the <PERSON> Monroe </PERSON> speech, <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> excoriated <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> for the current-accounts problem, saying it was evidence of mistaken tax-and-spend policies. `` This week the citizens of <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> awoke to find out that their state's bank accounts have been overdrawn up to $ 190 million for the past 30 days,'' he said. `` He likes to talk about a <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> miracle,'' <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> said. `` But the only miracle involving <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> will be the one he needs to get out of the mess he created for his state.'' <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> said that `` despite the totally false denials made by Gov. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> in his last debate with <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, we knew the fiscal situation was bad.'' The state constitution in <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> requires a balanced budget. But the amount of tax receipts that have been coming into the state's coffers have been less than anticipated by the office of state treasurer <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Crane </PERSON>. Consequently, the balance in the current account accrued a deficit of close to $ 190 million. Governors faced with less-than-expected state tax revenues often issue what are called revenue anticipation bonds, meaning they borrow money against the revenue they expect to come in, thus closing the gap. But in the <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> situation, state officials apparently opted to pay the interest on the $ 190 million overdraft rather than face a higher prevailing interest rate on the floating of such bonds. The state has over $ 1 billion in separate accounts, but these monies are untouchable; they involve funds raised through other bond issues for projects such as highway construction and public works. Under the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration, the federal debt has more than doubled, surpassing $ 2 trillion. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> made his fourth visit to <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION>, and boasted that he and <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> have a `` Southern strategy'' that will produce big victories in the region next Tuesday. During the <PERSON> Monroe </PERSON> speech the <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION> senator said, `` I doubt if <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> has been spending too much time in the South. ... He thinks alligators are something you buy in a shoe store.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881105-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-05-88 0126EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-UN-Afghanistan Bjt   11-05 0686</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-UN-Afghanistan, Bjt,0708</SECOND>
<HEAD>Suspension Of Soviet Troop Pullout Follows Months of Protests</HEAD>
<HEAD>AP News Analysis</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By VICTORIA GRAHAM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> UNITED </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> NATIONS </ORGANIZATION> _ The <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> announcement that it is suspending its troop withdrawal from <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> culminates months of protests against the continued arming of Afghan rebels by <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. The Friday announcement could mark an unraveling of the carefully crafted <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> Afghanistan Agreement, signed April 13 in <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> by the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>. That accord was considered the first <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> victory in years, resolving a regional conflict and showing <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> was trying to extricate itself from such conflicts worldwide. The development comes one day after the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION> adopted its first consensus resolution in which the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> agreed on <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> diplomats say some nations may have overestimated <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> determination to withdraw from <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>, end an unpopular war and cut its losses at any cost. <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> proudly admits arming the Moslem rebels and denies it is violating the <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> agreement, but it accuses <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> of violating it by aiding the <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION> government and, most recently, by providing SS-1 Scud missiles and using Backfire bombers. Secretary-General <PERSON> Javier </PERSON> <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Cuellar </PERSON>, in <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> for <LOCATION> Iran-Iraq </LOCATION> peace talks, had not seen the <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> report and had no immediate comment, <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> officials said. The Soviets on Friday announced the suspension of their troop withdrawal because of recent Afghan rebel successes and indicated they might not meet the Feb. 15 withdrawal deadline unless the attacks stop. It was the clearest Soviet statement that continued arming of Afghan rebels by <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> would not be tolerated and could jeopardize the withdrawal schedule. Soviet Foreign Minister <PERSON> Eduard </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shevardnadze </PERSON> has repeatedly protested such Pakistani aid, saying it violates the <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> agreement's call for non-interference in Afghan and Pakistani internal affairs. <PERSON> Shevardnadze </PERSON> has said the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> might have to reconsider and possibly extend its withdrawal schedule if violations and aid to the rebels continue and that the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, as a guarantor, must bear some responsibility. In September, <PERSON> Shevardnadze </PERSON> said the Soviets have not yet started the second phase of their withdrawal. `` Let's wait and see. It is necessary to stop the violations that take place.'' He told the <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION>, `` As soon as Soviet troops began to withdraw, a non-stop production line of violations was set in motion.'' <PERSON> Shevardnadze </PERSON> appealed to the five permanent members of the <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> to discuss agreement violations. The five are the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. Under the Afghanistan Agreement, the <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION> agreed to withdraw half its 100,000 troops from <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> by Aug. 15, and the remainder by Feb. 15. The <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> observer group of 50 soldiers certified the Soviet pullout, but the Soviets complained the group operates poorly and has not investigated violations _ the arming of rebels. The agreement also requires non-interference by <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> in each other's internal affairs. <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION> say the arming of rebels by <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> violates the agreement. Most of the aid comes from the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and is funneled through <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>. But diplomats say the Americans and Soviets tacitly agreed if one side continues aiding and arming clients, the other side may do the same. The <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> says the Soviets have used SS-1 Scud missiles against rebel positions and Backfire bombers to aid Afghan forces under attack. <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> says the introduction of Soviet missiles violates the accord. <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> says arming the rebels is a violation. On Thursday, for the first time in nine years, when <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> troops moved in to <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION> by consensus adopted its annual <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> resolution without a divisive vote calling for Soviet withdrawal or criticisms of the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. This year, a milder resolution expressed satisfaction with the troop withdrawal and expectation of its completion by Feb. 15. It was adopted by acclamation, with agreement among the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Victoria </PERSON> <PERSON> Graham </PERSON> is chief correspondent for <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> at the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881105-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-05-88 0157EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Politics-Quotes     11-05 0289</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Politics-Quotes,300</SECOND>
<HEAD>Quotes From the Presidential Campaign Trail</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are some comments Friday from the presidential campaign trail: <PERSON> MICHAEL </PERSON> <PERSON> DUKAKIS </PERSON>, saying there's nothing wrong with talking to terrorists as long as no concessions are made: `` I've never said that you do n't negotiate. You talk, you make every effort to get those hostages back home, but you never make concessions to the hostage takers.'' <PERSON> GEORGE </PERSON> <PERSON> BUSH </PERSON>, denying Americans are turned off by negative campaigning: `` The idea that this campaign is so different from others _ I do n't believe it. I do n't think the <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> people believe it, all this stuff about being turned off. You can always go out and find people to say that. Our people do n't say that when I get off this airplane.'' <PERSON> LLOYD </PERSON> <PERSON> BENTSEN </PERSON>, asked by young <PERSON> Houston </PERSON> student how he got to be vice president: `` I have n't done it yet.'' <PERSON> MICHAEL </PERSON> <PERSON> DUKAKIS </PERSON>, blasting <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> for borrowing the Democrat's standard rallying cry on Thursday: `` Four days before the election, after all the symbols and slogans, four days before the election, he tells you he's on your side Who's he kidding?'' <PERSON> DAN </PERSON> <PERSON> QUAYLE </PERSON>, citing a nearly $ 190 million overdraft in <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION>' current bank account as evidence <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> is ill-equipped to manage the federal government: `` The <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> people are not only just beginning to find out how bad it really is, but they are finding, as we are, that the fiscal situation in <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> is a time bomb set to explode in the faces of its citizens.'' <PERSON> RONALD </PERSON> <PERSON> REAGAN </PERSON>, stumping for <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>: `` If you want to know who's on the side of the little guy, well, I'll tell you, it's the big guy, the big guy from <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881105-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-05-88 0202EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-LithuanianReforms Bjt   11-05 0729</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lithuanian Reforms, Bjt,0753</SECOND>
<HEAD>Emigre Lithuanians See Freedom, Danger In Perestroika</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By THOMAS GINSBERG</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Ground-breaking reforms in <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lithuania </LOCATION> are fueling cautious hope among Lithuanian emigres, but also stirring discord over the prospect that some degree of independence may be on the horizon. `` We are all a little bit shocked'' by the changes, said <PERSON> Algis </PERSON> <PERSON> Klimaitis </PERSON>, a Lithuanian dissident who lives in <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> and works with the <ORGANIZATION> Baltic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>. He said some people are too quick to accept the Soviet reforms, `` and some people are too skeptical. We must find a middle way.'' The debate over tactics has heated up in the last two weeks following an inaugural conference in the Lithuanian capital of <LOCATION> Vilnius </LOCATION> of the officially sanctioned <ORGANIZATION> Movement </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Restructuring </ORGANIZATION>, which takes its name from Soviet President <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s plan of economic and social reform. About 20,000 people gathered for the Oct. 22-23 conference, where more than 1,000 delegates, including many <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> members, adopted resolutions demanding sweeping reforms for <LOCATION> Lithuania </LOCATION>, already one of the most progressive of the 15 Soviet republics. Emigres who participated in the conference said that within a few days, the <LOCATION> Lithuanian </LOCATION> party began to reduce food and medical privileges enjoyed by its elite members. And last week, the newly installed party chief, <PERSON> Algirdas </PERSON> <PERSON> Brazauskas </PERSON>, announced plans to free several prominent political prisoners. <PERSON> Vytautas </PERSON> <PERSON> Bieliauskas </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> Lithuanian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Community </ORGANIZATION> and one of a few <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> citizens allowed to attend the conference, said `` enthusiasm is quite high'' in <LOCATION> Lithuania </LOCATION>. `` People were sitting at the television _ it was transmitting everything from the conference _ and people were crying,'' he said after returning home to <LOCATION> Cincinnati </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Bieliauskas </PERSON>, whose organization says it represents a quarter of the world's 1 million expatriate Lithuanians, received a visa to attend the conference. But many other emigre activists were refused permits. Some claim that by this move, Soviet authorities were trying to drive a wedge into the Lithuanian emigre community. `` They -LRB- the people of <LOCATION> Lithuania </LOCATION> -RRB- are after independence, but the Soviets only want the economic advantage of free enterprise. People expect more freedom than they'll get,'' said <PERSON> Ancietas </PERSON> <PERSON> Simiutis </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Lithuania </LOCATION>'s consul general-in-exile in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. The <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> absorbed the Baltic republics of <LOCATION> Lithuania </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Latvia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Estonia </LOCATION> in 1940 under a secret pact with <ORGANIZATION> Nazi </ORGANIZATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>. Nationalists denounced the pact, and several countries, including the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, continue to recognize Baltic diplomats who maintain offices in the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Simiutis </PERSON> is one of many nationalists who are skeptical of <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s campaign to reform the Soviet system and permit more openness about controversial issues. `` We think -LRB- Bieliauskas -RRB- is doing a good job, but -LRB- he -RRB- might be a bit naive because he expects more than the Soviets will give,'' <PERSON> Simiutis </PERSON> said. He said the Soviets need Bieliauskas to help legitimize their `` occupation'' and called his admission to the conference a `` Soviet trick.'' <PERSON> Bieliauskas </PERSON> responded that the Lithuanian organization's executive committee voted 8-1 in favor of him attending the conference `` -LRB- <LOCATION> Lithuania </LOCATION> -RRB- is occupied by the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, but it does n't mean it does n't exist I deal with people, not with the government,'' <PERSON> Bieliauskas </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Bieliauskas </PERSON> said independence could be possible for <LOCATION> Lithuania </LOCATION>. `` But people are not ready. The process has just started. ... I believe in the process, but it will take time,'' he said. Klimaitis of the <ORGANIZATION> Baltic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> said the older generation wants `` only the reconstruction of the Baltics of the 1918-1940 period -LRB- when they were independent -RRB-. But it looks like there are other possibilities ... more creative ideas for a new state,'' he said, speaking by telephone from <LOCATION> Strasbourg </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Klimaitis </PERSON> envisioned the republics in a loose confederation with the central government in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> that would have control only over military and some foreign affairs. `` I think this will be possible,'' <PERSON> Klimaitis </PERSON> said, because <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> realizes the region could become the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>'s `` big duty-free shop.'' Soviet Politburo member <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON> <PERSON> N. </PERSON> <PERSON> Yakovlev </PERSON> last week appeared to rule out independence for the <ORGANIZATION> Baltic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> republics </ORGANIZATION> by saying in a published interview that <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> would n't let the Baltic states conduct their own foreign affairs or print their own currency. But <PERSON> Bieliauskas </PERSON> maintains his hope for independence, pointing to a younger generation of activists in <LOCATION> Lithuania </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Klimaitis </PERSON> called the youth's participation the most encouraging sign he saw. `` They have had some days of real freedom, and they will never forget that.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881105-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-05-88 0151EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-ComputerVirus-Source 3rdLd-Writethru a04Ld-Writethru
11-05 0714</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Computer Virus-Source, 3rd Ld - Writethru, a0423,0729</SECOND>
<HEAD>Report: Cornell Grad Student Created `Virus' Program</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: LEADS with 7 grafs to UPDATE with statement from Cornell
saying school was investigating and Morris had computer passwords
that didn't belong to him. Picks up 7th graf pvs, `Several telephone
...'</NOTE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The `` virus'' program that infected computers across the country was created by a graduate student at <ORGANIZATION> Cornell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> whose father is one of the government's most respected computer security experts, <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> reported in Saturday's editions Two sources with detailed knowledge of the case told the <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> that <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> T. </PERSON> <PERSON> Morris </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, 23, a computer science graduate student whom friends describe as `` brilliant,'' wrote the set of computer instructions as an experiment. The student could not be reached for comment Friday, the newspaper reported. <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Stuart </PERSON> <PERSON> Lynn </PERSON>, vice president of <ORGANIZATION> Cornell </ORGANIZATION>'s information technologies, said in a statement early Saturday that the university had not talked to <PERSON> Morris </PERSON> but confirmed that he was a graduate student at <LOCATION> Cornell </LOCATION>. `` We are investigating his computer files at <ORGANIZATION> Cornell </ORGANIZATION>, and so far we have determined that his account contains files that appear to hold passwords for some computers at <ORGANIZATION> Cornell </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Stanford </ORGANIZATION> to which he is not entitled,'' <PERSON> Lynn </PERSON> said. `` We also have discovered that <PERSON> Morris </PERSON>' account contains a list of passwords substantially similar to those found in the virus.'' Earlier, <PERSON> Lynn </PERSON> said the university `` can not say whether or not he was responsible for this activity,'' adding: `` We've tried to reach him but he's not at home. Apparently he's left for <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. He's apparently not in <LOCATION> Ithaca </LOCATION> right now. Several telephone calls to <PERSON> Morris </PERSON> senior's home in Silver Spring, <LOCATION> Md. </LOCATION>, near <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, went unanswered. Later, an answering machine was attached and there was no immediate response to requests for calls to be returned. The virus was introduced into the Arpanet, the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> computer network, the Times said. It was intended to live there innocently and undetected, slowly making copies that would move from computer to computer, the report said. But a design error caused it instead to replicate madly out of control, ultimately jamming more than 6,000 computers nationwide. The virus apparently caused no damage other than the thousands of hours that computer scientists and programmers were spending to remove it from their systems. By Friday, universities and research centers turned their computers back on. Sources told the Times the younger <PERSON> Morris </PERSON> flew to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> Friday and is planning to hire a lawyer and meet with officials of the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Communications </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION>, in charge of the Arpanet network, to discuss the case. His father, <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Morris </PERSON> <PERSON> Sr. </PERSON>, has written widely on the security of the Unix operating system, the computer master program that was the target of his son's virus program, of which, the sources said, he had no prior knowledge. The 56-year-old <PERSON> Morris </PERSON> told the Times in a telephone interview Friday, that the virus was `` the work of a bored graduate student.'' He said his son was `` for his age very well trained in computer science: he studied it in college and held various summer jobs at various places.'' The Times reported Friday that an anonymous caller to the newspaper claimed that a graduate student had created the virus as a harmless experiment and became terrified of the consequences when it got out of hand. The elder <PERSON> Morris </PERSON> spoke in the presence of officials and lawyers of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> and would not discuss the case in detail. He is chief scientist at the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Computer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Bethesda </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Md. </LOCATION>, the arm of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> devoted to protecting computers against outside attack. The elder <PERSON> Morris </PERSON> told the Times that he believed the virus might ultimately have a positive effect. `` It has raised the public awareness to a considerable degree,'' he said. `` It is likely to make people more careful and more attentive to vulnerabilities in the future.'' Earlier, the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> said it was launching a preliminary inquiry to determine whether federal law had been violated. Contacted about the <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> report, <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Lane </PERSON> <PERSON> Betts </PERSON> said he could add nothing beyond the prepared statement earlier in the day. `` As the matter is currently under investigation, it would be inappropriate for me to comment on it,'' <PERSON> Betts </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881105-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-05-88 0212EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     11-05 0935</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0971</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names In The News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actor <PERSON> Roddy </PERSON> <PERSON> McDowall </PERSON> has been star-crossed on the Hollywood Walk of Fame. <PERSON> McDowall </PERSON>, a child actor in `` My Friend Flicka'' and `` Lassie Come Home'' before moving on to grown-up movies like `` The Planet of the Apes'' and `` The Poseidon Adventure,'' was honored with a star on the famous walk in 1960. Last summer, the walk was refurbished and his star was replaced. But when <PERSON> Ana </PERSON> <PERSON> Martinez-Holler </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Hollywood </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chamber </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> inspected the replacement stars, she discovered <PERSON> McDowall </PERSON>'s star read `` MacDowll.'' So a third star has been ordered, Ms. <PERSON> Martinez-Holler </PERSON> said. It should take about a week or two to get the new star in place, she said. <PERSON> McDowall </PERSON>, who won an Emmy for his role in `` Not Without Honor'' and a <PERSON> Tony </PERSON> for his work in `` The Fighting Cock,'' can take some consolation in that it should n't take long to right his misguided star. It took 28 years to correct the star belonging to director <PERSON> Mauritz </PERSON> <PERSON> Stiller </PERSON>. His star, planted in 1960, read <PERSON> Maurice </PERSON> <PERSON> Diller </PERSON> until last spring.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WESTPORT, Conn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Sales by <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Newman </PERSON>'s food company are up about 25 percent this year, partly because of the highly publicized civil suit against <PERSON> Newman </PERSON>, the actor said. <LOCATION> Westport </LOCATION> delicatessen owner <PERSON> Julius </PERSON> <PERSON> Gold </PERSON>'s suit claims he was promised 8 percent of the stock of <PERSON> Newman </PERSON>'s Own in exchange for his help in starting the company. <PERSON> Newman </PERSON> says the allegation is without merit. A four-week trial ended last summer in a mistrial. A new trial has not been scheduled. On Friday, <PERSON> Newman </PERSON> released a statement saying that net sales from his food products were $ 30 million from Jan. 1 through Oct. 31. He said sales were $ 24 million in the first ten months of 1987. Sales increased 28 percent during the trial, <PERSON> Newman </PERSON>'s Own said. `` Charity and good intentions sometimes triumph over bad taste and pastrami,'' <PERSON> Newman </PERSON> said in a statement. <PERSON> Newman </PERSON>'s Own products include spaghetti sauce, salad dressing, popcorn and lemonade. Profits are donated to charity; last year that amounted to more than $ 5 million.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Tony </PERSON> Award-winner <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Langella </PERSON> had to leave the stage during a matinee performance of `` Les Liaisons Dangereuses'' with a sudden stomach ailment, but it appears his absence will be brief. The actor, best known for stage and screen portayals of Dracula, went to the theater's wings, leaving co-star <PERSON> Lynn </PERSON> <PERSON> Redgrave </PERSON> on stage Thursday afternoon. The stage was dark for about 15 minutes while it was determined whether <PERSON> Langella </PERSON> could continue. Ultimately, the final half-hour of the performance was completed by understudy <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Castellanos </PERSON>. `` He looked a littled peaked during Act 2 and left at the top of Scene 5,'' said <PERSON> Joyce </PERSON> <PERSON> Friedmann </PERSON>, spokeswoman for the Ahmanson Theater. `` He left the stage with something like a stomach flu and proceeded to get very ill.'' <PERSON> Castellanos </PERSON> also acted in Thursday's evening show, but <PERSON> Langella </PERSON> visited a doctor Friday and was cleared to return for Friday night's <PERSON> Langella </PERSON>, 48, who won a <PERSON> Tony </PERSON> for his work in `` Seascape,'' plays a <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Juan-type </PERSON> character in the comedy about decadent <LOCATION> Parisienne </LOCATION> aristocracy in the final days before the French Revolution.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>KANSAS CITY, Mo. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Yoko </PERSON> <PERSON> Ono </PERSON> brought her three-exhibit art show to <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> this week, including a do-it-yourself piece that once caught the eye of her late husband, ex-Beatle <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Lennon </PERSON>, and led to their 1960s romance. <PERSON> Ono </PERSON>, 55, held a news conference Friday to discuss her `` Three Events'' art show that opens Sunday and hammered the first nail into the piece called `` Nail It,'' which consists of a painted wooden panel hung on the gallery wall. Gallery visitors are invited to hammer their own nails into the piece. A display similar to `` Nail It'' caught <PERSON> Lennon </PERSON>'s eye at <PERSON> Ono </PERSON>'s showing in 1968 at a <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> art gallery The piece _ smaller then and called `` Hammer a Nail In'' _ prompted an exchange between <PERSON> Lennon </PERSON> and <PERSON> Ono </PERSON> that led to their highly publicized romance.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>ST. MARYS, Ga. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 `` Today'' show weatherman <PERSON> Willard </PERSON> <PERSON> Scott </PERSON> kept a promise he did n't make. In late July a woman visited the <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Marys-Kingsland </LOCATION> area and said she was with <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>. Local officials said she began making plans for <PERSON> Scott </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> newsman <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Palmer </PERSON> to do a documentary on the community impact of the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>'s nearby <LOCATION> Kings </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION> submarine base. But <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> officials said the woman did not work for the network; the plan was a hoax. No matter. <PERSON> Scott </PERSON> came to this town of about 3,500 anyway Friday. Of the mystery woman, <PERSON> Scott </PERSON> said: `` Little did she know that she was dealing with <PERSON> King </PERSON> <PERSON> Kong </PERSON> when she made a promise in my name. I've never let anybody make a promise in my name that I did n't fulfill in some way.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Paulsen </PERSON> pulled out of his third presidential campaign just days before the election, wearily acknowledging that tongue-in-cheek candidacy never did get off the ground this year. But the deadpan comedian promised Friday that he would be back soon after the election to launch a run for the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> in 1992. <PERSON> Paulsen </PERSON>, 61, traced his failure to a misguided start. `` I did n't go to the <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> caucuses,'' he quipped about the first big test of the political season. `` I got mixed up and went to <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION>.'' <PERSON> Paulsen </PERSON>, a fixture on the old <ORGANIZATION> Smothers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Brothers </ORGANIZATION> comedy show who offered the nation comic relief as a write-in candidate in 1968 and 1972, said his slogan for next time is `` <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Paulsen </PERSON> for president: He's got to sleep somewhere.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881105-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-05-88 0159EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Thatcher Bjt   11-05 0676</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Thatcher, Bjt,0698</SECOND>
<HEAD>Thatcher Balances Message In Visit to Poland</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY5</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN DANISZEWSKI</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WARSAW, Poland (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 British Prime Minister <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> pressed communist authorities to open negotiations with the opposition during her visit to <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> but also advised the opposition to act with restraint. The <ORGANIZATION> Conservative </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> prime minister, who returned home late Friday after a three-day visit, performed a balancing act in her meetings with government officials and leaders of the outlawed Solidarity union movment. She declared she had no intention of meddling in the country's internal affairs but then encouraged social strivings for greater freedom and human rights while urging the government to stay tough in restructuring its economy After her visit ended, the official <ORGANIZATION> PAP </ORGANIZATION> news agency reported public opinion polls showed Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> was viewed favorably by 52 percent of the Polish population, which it said made her more popular in <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> than in <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>. A `` poll of polls'' issued today by the <ORGANIZATION> British </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Broadcasting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> showed support in <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> for Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> Conservative </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> at 47 percent, with <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> second at 35 percent, and smaller groups trailing far behind. The poll covered the period of Oct. 19-30. Saying farewell Friday night to <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>'s communist party leader, Gen. <PERSON> Wojciech </PERSON> <PERSON> Jaruzelski </PERSON>, Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> thanked him for allowing her to meet with different leaders. During her visit she went to <LOCATION> Gdansk </LOCATION>, the birthplace of Solidarity, and met with Solidary founder <PERSON> Lech </PERSON> <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> as thousands of defiant people cheered her and hooted the government. Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON>, who arrived Wednesday, also spent hours in conversation with <PERSON> Jaruzelski </PERSON> and Prime Minister <PERSON> Mieczyslaw </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Rakowski </PERSON>, hearing their appeals for greater cooperation from the West in helping <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> tackle its foreign debt problem. She was told the government is serious about economic and political reforms, and that the West should recognize <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>'s achievements Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> expressed sympathy for the goals, at one point telling <PERSON> Rakowski </PERSON> he was pursuing the same type of restructuring she had done in <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>. And she also told him he might have to endure criticism en route to success. She also seemed to express doubts about the pace of reforms and the government's attempts to set up talks with the opposition, while showing enthusiasm for Solidarity. She was the first Western leader to make the significant gesture of traveling to <LOCATION> Gdansk </LOCATION> to talk with <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON>. Solidarity was created at the <ORGANIZATION> Lenin </ORGANIZATION> shipyards in <LOCATION> Gdansk </LOCATION> in fall 1980 and became the first legally chartered free union movement in the Soviet bloc. In December 1981, the union was suspended and it was outlawed the next year by <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION>. Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> told <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> his `` leadership has achieved so much.'' `` I knew that I had to come and feel the spirit of <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> for myself,'' she told 20,000 Poles who gave her a sustained greeting outside the <LOCATION> Lenin </LOCATION> shipyard where <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> works as an electrician. The government announced Monday it would close the shipyard on Dec. 1. It said the subsidized state industry is losing money. Opponents called the decision a political attack on Solidarity. Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> avoided commenting on the dispute, telling a news conference, `` That's not for me. It is for the people of <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> to decide.'' The official media gave the Thatcher visit heavy coverage but omitted mention of her meeting with <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON>. Solidarity leaders had hoped she would press authorities to `` recognize reality'' and again make Solidarity a legal organization. At a Thursday banquet given by <PERSON> Jaruzelski </PERSON> she linked Western financial assistance to a government dialogue with the opposition and said <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> needs political freedom to achieve economic progress. That pleased the opposition. `` It was beautiful what she said,'' a senior Solidarity adviser, historian <PERSON> Bronislaw </PERSON> <PERSON> Geremek </PERSON>, told reporters. <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> has a crippling $ 39 billion foreign debt. Government spokesman <PERSON> Jerzy </PERSON> <PERSON> Urban </PERSON> said Friday night it was too early to assess the visit. Urban was asked about Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON>'s suggestion that Western economic aid would be forthcoming if a `` real dialogue'' was undertaken with Solidarity. `` We are skeptical of such attempts to define conditions, and of such promises,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881105-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-05-88 0202EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-China-Quake     11-05 0156</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-China-Quake,0162</SECOND>
<HEAD>Severe Quake Recorded Near Tibet</HEAD>
<DATELINE>HONG KONG (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A severe earthquake rocked the <LOCATION> Qinghai </LOCATION> region in central <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> on Saturday, the <ORGANIZATION> Hong </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Kong </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Observatory </ORGANIZATION> reported. The observatory said the quake occurred at 10:19 a.m., and registered a preliminary magnitude of 6.1 on the <PERSON> Richter </PERSON> scale. The quake's epicenter was in the western region of <LOCATION> Qinghai </LOCATION>, about 372 miles north of the Tibetan capital of <LOCATION> Lhasa </LOCATION>, the observatory said. Further details were not immediately available. The Richter scale is a gauge of the energy released by an earthquake, as measured by the ground motion recorded on a seismograph. Every increase of one number means that the ground motion is 10 times greater. A quake of magnitude 2 is the smallest normally felt by humans. A quake of magnitude 6 can cause severe damage in populated areas. A top-scale quake of magnitude 8 is a `` great'' earthquake, capable of tremendous damage in populated areas.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881105-0025 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-05-88 0222EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-SaloonSingers Bjt   11-05 0535</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Saloon Singers, Bjt,0560</SECOND>
<HEAD>Company Fulfills Dreams Of Being A Singing Star</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto CX2</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARIO FOX</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CHICAGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
