<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880724-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-24-88 2332EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-Trans-AtlanticChallenge     07-24 0279</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Trans-Atlantic Challenge,0285</SECOND>
<HEAD>Proud Bird Takes Aim at Atlantic Record</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A six-man crew determined to break the record for a trans-Atlantic voyage set off Sunday from <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> aboard a $ 6 million speedboat. <LOCATION> Honolulu </LOCATION> businessman <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Gentry </PERSON>, 57, and his crew passed Ambrose Light just outside <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Harbor </LOCATION> at 11:26 a.m. Sunday to start the race across the <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Bishop </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rock </LOCATION> off <LOCATION> Great </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s Isles of <LOCATION> Scilly </LOCATION>, race spokesman <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Jaffe </PERSON> said. The 110-foot, 11,460 horsepower Gentry-Continental Proud Bird, sponsored by <ORGANIZATION> Continental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION>, will attempt to cross the <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> in less than 72 hours. The current record time of 3 days, 8 hours and 31 minutes was set in 1986 by Englishman <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Branson </PERSON>. <PERSON> Branson </PERSON>, who owns <ORGANIZATION> Virgin </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Atlantic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airways </ORGANIZATION> and several other companies, set his record on June 29, 1986, in the <LOCATION> Virgin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> Challenger II. It was <PERSON> Branson </PERSON>'s second attempt at the crossing. His first attempt, in May 1985, failed when the original <ORGANIZATION> Virgin </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Atlantic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Challenger </ORGANIZATION> sank 138 miles short of the finish. Crew member <PERSON> Jeffery </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>, speaking by radio-telephone, said the Proud Bird had passed over the Nantucket Shoals about 3:30 p.m. Sunday. The vessel was cruising at 50 knots through six-foot swells and fog, he said. `` We'd like a little smoother seas,'' <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> said. `` Basically the autopilot is doing the driving and we're just kind of cruising along,'' he said. However, the boat's size, speed and sea conditions were making for a rough passage. `` It's not a comfy ride. There's a rolling and pitching motion and when you hit these swells. You feel a few inches shorter and like you've been punched in the stomach,'' <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> reported.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880724-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-24-88 2342EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Philippines-Communists     07-24 0366</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Philippines-Communists,0377</SECOND>
<HEAD>Filipino Rebels Say Washington May be Forced to Send Troops</HEAD>
<HEAD>With AM-Philippines, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CLARO CORTES</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MANILA, Philippines (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Communist rebels said Sunday that President <PERSON> Corazon </PERSON> <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON> has failed to lift the country out of crisis and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> may have to send troops to prop up the government. The rebels, who have been battling for power for 20 years, issued a statement on the eve of the president's state of the nation address. Meanwhile, four soldiers, a policeman and two guerrillas were killed in three separate battles across the country during the last 24 hours, the military said Sunday. The rebels said Mrs. <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON> `` can not cover up the basic truth that the Filipino nation remains in deep crisis, that <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> control and interference continue to fetter national development, that the nation is being ever more polarized along class and political lines. `` Direct armed intervention by <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> troops is a distinct possibility _ meaning a much bloodier war for the Filipino people _ should the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> imperialists judge that the Aquino regime can no longer stop the general advance of the people's democratic revolution and protect strategic American interests.'' Copies of the statement were were delivered to news agencies by the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION>. The front is an umbrella for 12 rebel groups, including the outlawed <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> and its 25,000-member <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>. The government gave no official response to the rebels' statement Mrs. <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON> is to address the nation Monday when <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> reconvenes for its second session after a month-long recess. In the fighting, the army said that on <LOCATION> Panay </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION>, 230 miles southeast of <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION>, communist rebels ambushed and killed four soldiers Saturday. On <LOCATION> Luzon </LOCATION> island, one of three attackers Saturday shot and killed a policeman as he left his home near the <ORGANIZATION> U.S.-run </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Clark </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Base </ORGANIZATION>, about 50 miles north of <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION>. Also Saturday, two suspected communist rebels were killed in a gun battle after they wounded a <LOCATION> Philippine </LOCATION> constabulary captain in <LOCATION> Cabanatuan </LOCATION>, 30 miles northeast of the base. The military said last week nearly 2,000 people have been killed in insurgency-related violence across the country in the first six months of the year.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880724-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-24-88 2351EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-BRF--Peru-Drugs     07-24 0132</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Peru-Drugs,0135</SECOND>
<HEAD>Eleven Killed in Battle Between Rival Drug Dealers</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LIMA, Peru (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Two drug-dealing gangs waged a gunfight over control of the local cocaine trade, killing 11 people and wounding dozens of others, police reported Sunday. They said the battle in the village of <LOCATION> Dos </LOCATION> <LOCATION> de </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mayo </LOCATION>, 240 miles northeast of <LOCATION> Lima </LOCATION>, began Thursday when a Colombian gang ambushed Peruvians as they transported about 260 pounds of cocaine paste to a rural airfield. The firefight lasted for several hours and at least six Peruvian traffickers and five Colombians were killed, according to police. Witnesses told police that dozens of people were wounded, but officials had no specific figures. A Peruvian police patrol arrived in the area shortly after the battle ended and confiscated the cocaine, according to the authorities.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880724-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-24-88 2357EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-InauguralRules Bjt   07-24 0571</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Inaugural Rules, Bjt,550</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHINGTON WIRE: Proxmire Rains on Next Inaugural's Hoopla</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LAWRENCE L. KNUTSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Whether it's <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> or <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, the next taker of the presidential oath of office may find the federal government more miserly about paying part of the tab when he kicks up his heels at the end of the day. The reason: Sen. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Proxmire </PERSON>, D-Wis., has slipped new rules into the conference report of the new defense authorization bill now awaiting President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s signature They require the next <ORGANIZATION> Presidential </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inaugural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> to reimburse the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> for equipment and personnel it supplies for inaugural balls and other private inaugural events. So, <PERSON> Proxmire </PERSON> says, when President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> or President <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> steps out on the dance floor at an invitation-only inaugural ball next Jan. 20, `` the <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> taxpayer will no longer have to foot part of the bill.'' <PERSON> Proxmire </PERSON>, citing a recent <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Accounting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> study, said that when <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> was inaugurated for the second time in 1985, `` many of the events were largely planned, staffed and executed by federal employees at a cost to the taxpayer of $ 15.5 million.'' The Pentagon alone spent $ 10 million,'' <PERSON> Proxmire </PERSON> says. And it used 8,400 military personnel. According to <PERSON> Proxmire </PERSON> staff members and the <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Accounting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION>, hundreds of uniformed military personnel were used at <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s nine inaugural balls and galas to do everything from checking the fur coats to playing in the bands and orchestras. Service members served as VIP escorts, driving visiting celebrities around the capital. The cars were lent by American auto makers, but the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> maintained them, and filled the gas tanks. Members of the inaugural committees had military drivers for as long as six weeks. <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corps </ORGANIZATION> personnel served as escorts at inaugural events, under orders to mix and mingle and to see that no guests were ignored. They also were used to set up the events themselves, and to organize receiving lines once they were under way. Military photographers and cameramen took still and video pictures of the guests, providing copies on request free of charge. `` They took tens of thousands of pictures,'' a <PERSON> Proxmire </PERSON> staff member said. Under the new guidelines, the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> or <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> inaugural committee must reimburse the Pentagon for the costs of whatever resources or personnel are used to supply private inaugural events. The inaugural ceremony itself would not be included because by tradition and history it is a public event. Nor would the inaugural parade down <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> Avenue from the Capitol. But compensation would be required for <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> services to private inaugural functions. The new Proxmire inaugural rules have one other twist. In the past, a <PERSON> Proxmire </PERSON> staff member said, members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> have received complaints that service men and women were being required to take part in private, partisan inaugural events, often to perform duties they felt were beneath the dignity of the uniform. Under the new rules, uniformed members of the armed services could be used at private, partisan inaugural celebrations _ but only if they volunteer to take part. And the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> would have to be reimbursed for the time spent. `` These new provisions provide clear and strict guidelines for the future,'' <PERSON> Proxmire </PERSON> said. `` It has taken eight years to get movement on this issue, and while not every loophole has been closed, the major abuses now are corrected,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880724-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-24-88 0010EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Philippines-Killing     07-24 0136</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Philippines-Killing,0139</SECOND>
<HEAD>Gunmen Kill Policeman Outside U.S. Base</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MANILA, Philippines (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Three attackers shot and killed a policeman near his house in front of his wife and two children near the <ORGANIZATION> U.S.-run </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Clark </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Base </ORGANIZATION>, police reported Sunday. Police Capt. <PERSON> Marcelino </PERSON> <PERSON> Ibanez </PERSON> identified the victim as Patrolman <PERSON> Jerico </PERSON> <PERSON> Gabiola </PERSON>. He said the attack occurred Saturday in <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, 50 miles north of <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION>. The officer was opening the gate to his home when the gunmen approached and one fired at close range with a 45-caliber pistol, according to <PERSON> Ibanez </PERSON>. He said the killers escaped but a suspect was picked up Sunday and was being questioned. There have been numerous killings in the vicinity of the <ORGANIZATION> Clark </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Base </ORGANIZATION> and police blame communist rebels who have been fighting the government for more than 19 years.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880724-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-24-88 0029EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Japan-SeaCollision 2ndLd-Writethru   07-24 0549</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Japan-Sea Collision, 2nd Ld - Writethru,a0674,0562</SECOND>
<HEAD>Fishing Boat And Submarine Collide; One Person Dead And 29 Missing</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: LEADS with nine grafs to UPDATE with two bodies found; picks
up 11th graf pvs: Police officials...</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By K.P. HONG</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A chartered fishing boat with 48 people aboard collided with a <LOCATION> Japanese </LOCATION> navy submarine and quickly sank Saturday near <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION>, leaving at least three people dead and 27 missing, police said. The 92-foot boat, chartered for a weekend fishing expedition, sank less than two minutes after the collision, said police in the nearby port city of <LOCATION> Yokosuka </LOCATION>. They said 19 people were rescued from the boat but a 38-year-old man died in a hospital. Divers subsequently recovered two bodies on Sunday, said a spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> Maritime </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s coast guard None of the 75 men aboard the diesel-powered submarine were reported injured, said officials with the <ORGANIZATION> Maritime </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Self-Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s navy. Officials said Sunday that divers located the boat at a depth of more than 150 feet. Officials said about 80 divers and 40 boats were taking part in the search. The <ORGANIZATION> Maritime </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> spokesman said the cause of the accident was still under investigation and captains of both vessels had been called in for questioning. According to <ORGANIZATION> Japan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Broadcasting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> television, the collision occurred after one of the vessels swerved to the right to avoid another boat. Television news reports showed the submarine floating on the surface near the accident site with no apparent damage. A handful of men on its deck and hull scanned the surrounding waters and life rafts were lined along its top. Police officials said the submarine, the 2,200-ton Nadashio, hit the fishing boat, the 154-ton No. 1 Fujimaru, Saturday afternoon about two miles off the port of <LOCATION> Yokosuka </LOCATION> near the mouth of <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Yokosuka </LOCATION> is 28 miles south of <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION>. Capt. <PERSON> Yoshiaki </PERSON> <PERSON> Nishimura </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> navy </ORGANIZATION> spokesman, told a nationally televised news conference that the submarine was cruising on the surface on its way back to <LOCATION> Yokosuka </LOCATION> after a training exercise in the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION>. The fishing boat, from the nearby port of <LOCATION> Yokohama </LOCATION>, was leaving <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION>, he said. Authorities were still investigating the cause of the incident, he said. Visibility at the time of the accident was reportedly good. More than 700 ships a day pass through the entrance of the bay, <ORGANIZATION> Kyodo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> reported. Prime Minister <PERSON> Noboru </PERSON> <PERSON> Takeshita </PERSON>, who was attending meetings of his <ORGANIZATION> Liberal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Karuizawa </LOCATION>, returned to <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION> after hearing of the accident, news reports said. <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> chief <PERSON> Tsutomu </PERSON> <PERSON> Kawara </PERSON> expressed regret over the accident, the worst involving <ORGANIZATION> Maritime </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Self-Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> vessels and civilian boats since World War II, defense officials said. It was the first collision in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> between a submarine and a Japanese civilian ship since 1981, when a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> nuclear submarine hit a freighter, killing two people, <ORGANIZATION> Kyodo </ORGANIZATION> said. The mouth of <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION> is known for its congestion of military vessels, including <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> naval ships, ocean-going vessels, ferries, fishing boats and privately owned yachts and sightseeing boats. <LOCATION> Yokosuka </LOCATION> is the site of a major <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. Naval base. The submarine, built by <ORGANIZATION> Mitsubishi </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Heavy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Industries </ORGANIZATION>, was commissioned in March 1984. It has two diesel engines and is equipped with six torpedo tubes.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880724-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-24-88 0034EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-ForestFiresRdp 4thLd-Writethru a0681 07-24 1015</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Forest Fires Rdp, 4th Ld - Writethru, a0681,1036</SECOND>
<HEAD>Forest Fires Force Evacuation Of Homes, Two Areas In Yellowstone</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: DELETES 2nd graf pvs, `Residents also ...,'' now outdated;
SUBS 19th graf pvs, `Hundreds of ...,' to UPDATE with portion of
Montana wilderness closed due to fire, other details. Picks up 20th
graf pvs, `A brush ...'.</NOTE>
<HEAD>Stands for AM-Drought-Fires on AM-News Advisory</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Two areas of Yellowstone National Park were evacuated Saturday because of forest fires in <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION>, while residents of 20 homes near <LOCATION> Spokane </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wash. </LOCATION>, returned after the forest fire that forced their evacuation was controlled. Fires also burned in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION>, and several large fires burned in remote areas of <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>. Yellowstone National Park officials said Saturday the south entrance to the park will be closed for several days. The Grant Village Hotel and a campground in <LOCATION> Yellowstone </LOCATION> were closed earlier in the day, and visitors and employees moved out as a precaution because a fire had crept to within one-half mile of <LOCATION> Lewis </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION>. `` We had strong and erratic winds -LRB- Friday -RRB-, a windstorm blew trees down on the road,'' said park fire information officer <PERSON> Joan </PERSON> <PERSON> Anzelmo </PERSON>. `` The same wind also kicked the fire in and had it moving toward <PERSON> Grant </PERSON> <PERSON> Village </PERSON>.'' In <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION> near the <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION> border, 200 firefighters were strung out along the two-mile-long northern flank of the North Fork fire on the Idaho-Wyoming border that was burning mainly inside <ORGANIZATION> Yellowstone </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Targhee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Fox </PERSON> said. Officials had worried that high winds forecast for Saturday would aggravate the 600-acre blaze. But cloud cover kept both the temperature and the wind from getting out of control, and crews made progress on fire lines on the north flank, he said. `` We were anticipating it could double today if we got the wind. But if we have another day like this, we might be coming close -LRB- to containment -RRB-,'' <PERSON> Fox </PERSON> said. Other fires in <LOCATION> Yellowstone </LOCATION> included the 14,000 - to 15,000-acre Clover fire in a remote backcountry area Wind created problems for the 830 firefighters trying to contain the <LOCATION> Mink </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Creek </LOCATION> fire in northwestern <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION> that charred 21,300 acres in the <LOCATION> Bridger-Teton </LOCATION> <LOCATION> National </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Forest </LOCATION> and burned to within a mile of <ORGANIZATION> Yellowstone </ORGANIZATION>'s boundary. A containment line had been established around about 80 percent of the fire's southern end, said <PERSON> Ed </PERSON> <PERSON> Waldapfel </PERSON>, fire information officer. In southern <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> Poison </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Creek </LOCATION> fire in Sawtooth National Forest southwest of Twin Falls was burning out of control Saturday. More than 150 firefighters battled the blaze, which had charred over 2,000 acres of the tinder-dry high desert since Thursday. Residents evacuated from about 20 homes bordering the <LOCATION> Spokane </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Wash. </LOCATION> -RRB- Indian Reservation returned home Saturday after firefighters cut a containment line around a 2,420-acre blaze on the reservation. However, officials were not yet calling the fire contained because 40 percent of the material inside the line was unburned, said <PERSON> Norm </PERSON> <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Wenatchee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> official. About 200 firefighters, including volunteers and crews from the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Indian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Affairs </ORGANIZATION>, used bulldozers and hand tools to cut the line around most of the fire, with the <LOCATION> Spokane </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> forming the rest of the boundary, <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> estimated the fire got within 50 yards of at least one home. The houses were evacuated Friday. Also Saturday, a 1,500-acre fire at the adjacent <LOCATION> Colville </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Wash. </LOCATION> -RRB- Indian Reservation was contained, said <ORGANIZATION> BIA </ORGANIZATION> fire control officer <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Quill </PERSON>. The blaze was blamed on farm equipment operating in high grasses. About 50 people who were forced from their homes by a forest fire on the outskirts of <LOCATION> Kalispell </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mont. </LOCATION>, were allowed to return Saturday after crews managed to get a line around the 120-acre blaze. No homes were lost although several were threatened. `` We only have one road closed, and that's to try to find out where it -LRB- the fire -RRB- started,'' said <LOCATION> Flathead </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> Deputy Sheriff <PERSON> Phil </PERSON> <PERSON> Caperton </PERSON>. Authorities believed the blaze, which broke out Friday, was man-caused. Hundreds of firefighters battled about a half-dozen other fires in western <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION>. Two fires were being allowed to run their course because they are in wilderness areas, including the <LOCATION> Canyon </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Creek </LOCATION> fire in the Scapegoat Wilderness north of <PERSON> Ovando </PERSON>. Authorities closed about 75,000 acres of the 250,000-acre wilderness on Saturday due to the blaze. <PERSON> Marcia </PERSON> <PERSON> Hogan </PERSON>, a forest spokeswoman, said the blaze grew substantially Saturday but that no estimate on its size was available because smoke obscured much of the area. Earlier, the fire was reported to have consumed 2,000 acres. A brush fire about eight miles north of <LOCATION> Canon </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Colo. </LOCATION>, grew to 1,700 acres Saturday afternoon as about 330 firefighters and aircraft battled the blaze in steep terrain on <LOCATION> Cooper </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mountain </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Land </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Management </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Ken </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> blamed the growth of the fire on winds. `` The wind has changed directions about three times today, and now it's fairly calm again,'' <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> said. The blaze, which broke out Thursday, is named the `` Dinosaur fire'' because it is near a fossil site. Before the Dinosaur fire, fires had burned about 21,000 acres across <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION> since last weekend. The other fires were all contained by Thursday. In <LOCATION> Southern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, a fire sparked by fireworks was contained Saturday after it burned about 420 acres of the <ORGANIZATION> San </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bernardino </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> near <ORGANIZATION> Yucaipa </ORGANIZATION>, said <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman Melody Fountain. And in <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, firefighters finally contained two fires in <LOCATION> Calaveras </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> after the blazes charred about 10,800 acres. <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Craig </PERSON>, a spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forestry </ORGANIZATION>, said full control of the blazes was expected by Monday night. Damage from the fires totaled $ 11 million, including timber and property losses and fire suppression efforts, said <PERSON> Sharon </PERSON> <PERSON> Torrence </PERSON>, a spokeswoman for the <ORGANIZATION> CDF </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Rail </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Road </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Flat </LOCATION>, 150 miles east of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> and a few miles west of the fires. Six homes, nine other buildings and eight vehicles were lost since the arson-suspected blazes broke out Tuesday. Also Saturday, firefighters battled a 200-acre brush fire near Flaming Gorge Dam on the Utah-Colorado border and several small fires near <LOCATION> Salt </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, authorities said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880724-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-24-88 0042EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-PolicemanKilled 1stLd-Writethru a0679 07-24 0232</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Policeman Killed, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0679,0236</SECOND>
<HEAD>Lewiston Officer Is Shot At Car Accident Scene</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Leads with 6 grafs to UPDATE with murder charge and type of
gun used. Picks up 7th graf pvs `Payne, a...'</NOTE>
<DATELINE>LEWISTON, Maine (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A police officer was shot to death Saturday when he responded to a car accident, authorities said. Officer <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Payne </PERSON>, 26, was pronounced dead from a gunshot wound after he was taken to <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Maine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Lewiston </LOCATION>, said Police Chief <PERSON> Gregory </PERSON> <PERSON> Hanscom </PERSON>. Deputy Attorney General <PERSON> Fermand </PERSON> <PERSON> LaRochelle </PERSON> said <PERSON> Nicolo </PERSON> <PERSON> Leone </PERSON>, a former <LOCATION> Lewiston </LOCATION> resident who lives in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, was charged with murder. <PERSON> Leone </PERSON> was in critical condition with gunshot wounds at the medical center, a nursing supervisor said. A police guard was posted at the hospital. <ORGANIZATION> Hanscom </ORGANIZATION> said <PERSON> Payne </PERSON> and two other officers responded to a report of a car accident and that <PERSON> Payne </PERSON>, the first to arrive, approached a man who ducked into the woods near the car. `` There was an exchange of gunfire,'' <ORGANIZATION> Hanscom </ORGANIZATION> said. A .44 - caliber handgun was used in the killing, <PERSON> LaRochelle </PERSON> <PERSON> Payne </PERSON>, a father of two children ages 5 and 3, had been on the police force two years. `` We grieve and feel terribly at the loss of this police officer,'' <ORGANIZATION> Hanscom </ORGANIZATION> said. The last time a <LOCATION> Lewiston </LOCATION> policeman was killed in the line of duty was 30 years ago this month.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880724-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-24-88 0205EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Thailand-Election 1stLd-Writethru   07-24 0478</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Thailand-Election, 1st Ld - Writethru,a0687,0487</SECOND>
<HEAD>Moslems Burn Schools In Election Violence</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: SUBS 6th graf to add damage to additional school, clinic;
picks up 7th graf pvs: Moslems, who...</NOTE>
<DATELINE>BANGKOK, Thailand (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Moslem separatists burned seven rural schools in the southern province of <LOCATION> Narathiwat </LOCATION> in an apparent attempt to disrupt <LOCATION> Thailand </LOCATION>'s general elections on Sunday, a district official said. The official, who asked not to be identified, said the rebels torched the schools and a health clinic in isolated areas of three districts in the province after midnight Saturday. Polling booths had been set up in some of the schools and the official linked the raids to efforts by Moslems to disrupt the voting that began at 8 a.m. -LRB- 9 p.m. EDT -RRB-. A total of 3,606 candidates from 16 parties are vying for 357 seats in the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Representatives </ORGANIZATION>. Since no party is expected to gain a majority, several parties will probably team up to choose a prime minister, who then forms a government. Prime Minister <PERSON> Prem </PERSON> <PERSON> Tinsulanonda </PERSON>, who does not belong to any party, is widely predicted to return to his post, heading a coalition of several parties. He has held office since 1980. The district official, contacted by telephone, said four of the schools burned to the ground while three others and the clinic were damaged. But he said polling at the schools was able to proceed despite the nighttime raid. Moslems, who form a minority in <LOCATION> Thailand </LOCATION>, are the majority in the province bordering <LOCATION> Malaysia </LOCATION>. The country as a whole is predominantly <ORGANIZATION> Buddhist </ORGANIZATION>. Several hundred Moslem separatists, believed to be supported by radical groups in the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION>, operate in the <LOCATION> Thai-Malaysian </LOCATION> border area. The separatists have called for a merger with <LOCATION> Malaysia </LOCATION> or various forms of autonomy. <PERSON> Prem </PERSON> called the election 24 months early after he dissolved parliament April 29, disbanding his faction-ridden coalition government. The 67-year-old former army commander voted in the provincial capital of <LOCATION> Korat </LOCATION> northeast of <LOCATION> Bangkok </LOCATION>. But he has not said whether he would accept another term. Thai elections are largely centered on personalities, not political platforms, and the main contention has been whether Prem should return or not. Although his popularity has been waning, most leaders of the four current coalition parties back his return. And he remains favored by three institutions which figure in the choice of a prime minister: the military, bureaucracy and constitutional monarchy. Whoever emerges as the new prime minister is almost certainly to keep <LOCATION> Thailand </LOCATION> on the same general course of economically conservative, politically pro-Western policies. The economy has boomed in the past two years. The present coalition government comprises the <ORGANIZATION> Democrat </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Deputy </ORGANIZATION> Prime Minister <PERSON> Bhichai </PERSON> <PERSON> Rattakul </PERSON>; the Chart Thai -LRB- Thai Nation -RRB- of Deputy Prime Minister <PERSON> Chatichai </PERSON> <PERSON> Choonhavan </PERSON>; the <ORGANIZATION> Social </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Action </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> Minister <PERSON> Siddhi </PERSON> <PERSON> Savetsila </PERSON>, and the Rassadorn -LRB- Citizens -RRB- Party of Deputy Prime Minister <PERSON> Thienchai </PERSON> <PERSON> Sirisamphan </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880724-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-24-88 0531EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i BC-Iran-Iraq     07-24 0289</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Iran-Iraq,0296</SECOND>
<HEAD>Iranian Diplomat Calls On U.N. Head To Halt Iraqi Attacks</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NICOSIA, Cyprus (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'s foreign minister said Sunday that <LOCATION> Iraqi </LOCATION> raids into <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> were a violation of a <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> resolution calling for an end to the 8-year-old <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> war. Foreign Minister <PERSON> Ali </PERSON> <PERSON> Akbar </PERSON> <PERSON> Velayati </PERSON> called on <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> Secretary-General <PERSON> Javier </PERSON> <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Cuellar </PERSON> to take `` timely and preventive action'' to halt the incursions, <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION> radio reported. <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'s official <ORGANIZATION> Islamic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> said <PERSON> Velayati </PERSON> left <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION> for the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> on Sunday for the cease-fire talks. <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> said Saturday that Iraqi troops backed by tanks, warplanes and chemical weapons thrust nearly 40 miles into <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> said its aim was to capture a large number of prisoners before the opening of cease-fire talks in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> this week. It claimed it did not plan to keep Iranian territory and the <ORGANIZATION> Iraqi </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> reported Saturday that <LOCATION> Iraqi </LOCATION> forces began withdrawing from the newly captured territory. <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION> radio reported earlier that <PERSON> Velayatiati </PERSON> had sent a letter to Perez de Cuellar charging that renewed Iraqi aggression threatened action on a cease-fire. `` Does the first article of the resolution not state that one of the first steps towards reaching a solution is that of observing a cease-fire and halting all military operations? However, <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> has not only not observed a cease-fire but has been conducting new acts of aggression by occupying Iranian territory and has blatantly violated this article,'' <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION> radio quoted <PERSON> Velayati </PERSON>'s letter as saying. A <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> technical team planned to arrive in <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION> on Sunday to begin working out details of a cease-fire. <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> announced on Monday that it was accepting the resolution, adopted by the <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> one year ago and previously endorsed by <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880724-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-24-88 0949EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w BC-EmbassyFire     07-24 0194</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Embassy Fire,190</SECOND>
<HEAD>Officials Investigating Fires At Madagascar Embassy</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Two fires broke out at the <ORGANIZATION> Madagascan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> early Sunday. Lt. Ransom <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fire </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, said officials were investigating a fire that occurred at 2:17 a.m. EDT and a second fire that erupted about two hours later. `` I smelled the smoke of the fire, so I decided to awaken my family,'' said <PERSON> Leon </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Rajaobelina </PERSON>, the ambassador from <LOCATION> Madagascar </LOCATION>. `` We called immediately the <ORGANIZATION> Secret </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> and within a minute they were there, and the fire department was there within five minutes.'' Battalion Chief <PERSON> Dennis </PERSON> <PERSON> Boatman </PERSON>, who was at the scene of the first fire, said firefighters worked for about 10 minutes to bring the blaze under control. Fire officials told the ambassador and his staff that the blaze started in the reception area of the building. <PERSON> Jocelyn </PERSON> <PERSON> Rafidinarivo </PERSON>, the embassy's counselor for public affairs, said the fire may have been started by a lit cigarette. The fire department spokesman said he did not know if the second fire occurred in the same room. No injuries were reported in either fire. Damage estimates were not available.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880724-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-24-88 1128EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-GlennGould Bjt   07-24 0739</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Glenn Gould, Bjt,0756</SECOND>
<HEAD>Exhibition Offers Intimate Look at Canada's Eccentric Musical
Genius</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JEFF BRADLEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>OTTAWA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 He wore a wool scarf and gloves in summer and lived like a hermit, communicating with the outside world mostly by telephone. But when <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON> <PERSON> Gould </PERSON> died of a stroke nine days after his 50th birthday in 1982, <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> lost not only a notorious eccentric but one of its greatest musicians. For the first time since the pianist's death, an exhibition at the National Library in <LOCATION> Ottawa </LOCATION> provides an intimate look at <PERSON> Gould </PERSON>'s life, from his checkered cloth cap to the room keys he collected at hotels across the continent, including an entire set from <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>'s Stanhope Hotel Fortunately for posterity, <PERSON> Gould </PERSON> was a pack rat who set aside one room of his apartment on <LOCATION> Toronto </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Clair </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Avenue </LOCATION> for scores, scripts, letters, programs, souvenirs and assorted junk. `` He wrote everything down on pads. You can almost follow him through each day,'' said <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> Willis </PERSON>, head of the library's music manuscript collection The exhibit runs through mid-September. A packing list reminds <PERSON> Gould </PERSON> to bring Valium and <LOCATION> Librium </LOCATION> for his nerves, and a TV Guide. A 1966 commentary for the Canadian <ORGANIZATION> Broadcasting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> says in red ball point, `` Sometimes it seems to me that <PERSON> Mozart </PERSON> has had a rather better press than he deserves.'' A letter from his grandmother recommends a mustard pack for his sore back, and <PERSON> Gould </PERSON> commiserates with an ailing <PERSON> Leonard </PERSON> <PERSON> Bernstein </PERSON> -LRB- `` Dear Leonardo'' -RRB- by offering some tips on hypochondria. `` I have several titles for diseases which I am expecting to have in later life but have not yet had occasion to make use of.'' After a piano technician dislocated <PERSON> Gould </PERSON>'s shoulder with a backslap, the pianist distributed a notice requesting that no one offer to shake his hand. `` This will eliminate embarrassment all around,'' it said. A Canadian celebrity at 15, <PERSON> Gould </PERSON>'s international career had a sensational start. He landed a lucrative <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Records </ORGANIZATION> contract the day after his <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> debut in 1955, and the first of more than 100 discs, <PERSON> Bach </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> Goldberg </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Variations </ORGANIZATION>, is still rated a classic. He suddenly abandoned the concert platform in 1964 in pursuit of what he saw as a purer musical experience in the recording studio. He eventually became his own producer, controlling a mixing board the way a conductor directs an orchestra. He loved the microphone and dedicated much of his time to radio and TV documentaries. A night owl, <PERSON> Gould </PERSON> rented a studio at <LOCATION> Toronto </LOCATION>'s Inn on the Park because it was the only place in town he could get something to eat in the early hours, <PERSON> Willis </PERSON> said. The exhibit features <PERSON> Gould </PERSON>'s favorite Steinway, his cluttered pigeon-hole desk and the rickety card-table chair his father modified as a piano stool. <PERSON> Gould </PERSON> preferred a low-slung chair so that his fingers lay flat along the keyboard, the antithesis of the pounding romantic style he abhorred. An animal lover, <PERSON> Gould </PERSON> left his worldly goods to the <ORGANIZATION> Toronto </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Humane </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Salvation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>. The library was allowed to purchase the collection of 20,000 items, packed in 226 boxes, on condition it organize an exhibit. The display tours the rest of <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> later this year, and negotiations are under way with <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and European museums. The most personal documents were withheld, but <PERSON> Willis </PERSON> said there was evidence of `` two or three relationships'' with women that did not last long. In retrospect, <PERSON> Gould </PERSON>'s career is filled with irony. He searched for musical clarity and control in what he termed the `` backbone'' of a score and dismissed virtuoso playing and tonal beauty for its own sake. However, he marred some recordings by humming along with the music, a habit critics considered an affectation. `` Readers will find the groans and croons intolerable,'' the Penguin Guide says of one Bach recording. <PERSON> Gould </PERSON> preferred the piano to the harpsichord and played no part in the rediscovery of original instruments and pitch that has revolutionized baroque listening in the 1980s. He saw nothing wrong with splicing dozens of takes for one definitive performance and envisioned an era when recordings, adjusted electronically by home listeners, would entirely replace public concerts. <PERSON> Gould </PERSON> holds an Olympian place in Canadian music. `` As a cultural symbol, he grows in stature every year, both as a true Canadian original and as a certified hero of modernist performers,'' said <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Everett-Green </PERSON>, music critic for The Globe and Mail.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880724-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-24-88 1129EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-BRF--MongoliaQuake     07-24 0117</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Mongolia Quake,0118</SECOND>
<HEAD>China Reports Earthquake in Mongolia</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A strong earthquake shook desolate <LOCATION> Mongolia </LOCATION> and sent shocks across the border into <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Xinjiang </LOCATION> Uygur Autonomous Region, the official <ORGANIZATION> Xinhua </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> said Sunday. Chinese seismological stations said the quake occurred at 4:38 p.m. Saturday and measured 6.4 on the <PERSON> Richter </PERSON> scale, signifying a tremor capable of causing severe damage in populated areas. <PERSON> Xinhua </PERSON> did not say if there were any reports of damage. It said the quake was centered in far western <LOCATION> Mongolia </LOCATION> near where the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mongolia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> meet. It is a desolate and sparsely inhabited region. The <PERSON> Richter </PERSON> scale is a measure of ground motion as recorded on seismographs.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880724-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-24-88 1129EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Philippines-Fire     07-24 0127</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Philippines-Fire,0129</SECOND>
<HEAD>Fire Breaks Out In Posh Department Store</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MANILA, Philippines (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Fire broke out in <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION>'s most exclusive department store and burned through the night, but firefighters were able to contain it and there were no reports of injuries, authorities said Sunday. <PERSON> Francisco </PERSON> <PERSON> Adriano </PERSON>, a firefighter, said the blaze broke out Saturday night on the third floor of the seven-story Rustan's, in the Makati Commercial Center. He said it burned more than 15 hours and that firefighters had trouble extinquishing the flames because of the building's poor ventilation. It was the second blaze to hit a major store in the <LOCATION> Makati </LOCATION> commercial complex. In May, a fire that lasted for several days razed the <LOCATION> Makati </LOCATION> branch of Shoemart, the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION>' biggest department store chain.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880724-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-24-88 1129EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-BRF--India-Accident     07-24 0081</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--India-Accident,0084</SECOND>
<HEAD>11 Killed In Bus Collision</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW DELHI, India (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Two buses collided head-on in central <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>, killing at least 11 passengers and injuring 50 others, <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> India </ORGANIZATION> reported Sunday. The accident occurred Saturday night in <LOCATION> Uttar </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Pradesh </LOCATION> state near the town of <LOCATION> Unnao </LOCATION>, about 260 miles southeast of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Delhi </LOCATION>. Among the dead were the drivers of the buses, owned by the <ORGANIZATION> Uttar </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pradesh </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transport </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corporation </ORGANIZATION>. The report gave no cause for the accident.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880724-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-24-88 1129EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Japan-USBase     07-24 0239</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Japan-US Base,0249</SECOND>
<HEAD>Demonstrators Form Human Chain Around US Naval Air Station</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By HIROYUKI KACHI</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ATSUGI, Japan (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 About 20,000 people formed a human chain around the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> air station in <LOCATION> Atsugi </LOCATION> on Sunday to protest noisy night landings at the base. Three times during the peaceful, 40-minute protest the demonstrators joined hands for about five minutes around the 10-mile perimeter of the base. Participants shouted `` Give us a quiet night!'' There was no immediate reaction to the demonstration by <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> authorities at the base. <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> pilots use <LOCATION> Atsugi </LOCATION>, 25 miles southwest of <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION>, to practice night landings, leading to frequent protests about jet noise from residents of the densely populated area. Sunday's demonstration was sponsored by the <ORGANIZATION> Japan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Socialist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, the country's largest opposition party, and by the labor federation <PERSON> Sohyo </PERSON> and civic and religious groups. The mood was festive, and police reported no violence or arrests. Organizers said 27,750 people took part in the demonstration, but police estimated the number at 19,000. <PERSON> Tadashi </PERSON> <PERSON> Abe </PERSON>, one of the organizers, said more people showed up than expected. Noise from the landings has gone beyond `` permissible levels,'' <PERSON> Abe </PERSON> said, `` mainly because the base has increased its force.'' The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> maintains military bases in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> under the U.S.-Japan security treaty. Last summer, 25,000 people formed an 11-mile human chain around <LOCATION> Kadena </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Air </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Base </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Okinawa </LOCATION> to protest the presence of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military bases.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880724-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-24-88 1135EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-OlympicAnniversary     07-24 0460</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Olympic Anniversary,0472</SECOND>
<HEAD>Olympic National Park Celebrates 50th Birthday</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PORT ANGELES, Wash. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Vigilance is needed if the beauty of Olympic National Park is to be preserved, the director of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Park </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> said at the park's 50th birthday party. `` There are those who suggest that having already established the park lands, their preservation is assured, and there is little more to be done with them, for them, to provide for this adequate protection and maintenance,'' <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Penn </PERSON> <PERSON> Mott </PERSON> said Saturday. But there's `` much to be done if these places are to fulfill their heritage,'' he warned the more than 500 people at Saturday's ceremonies <PERSON> Mott </PERSON> noted that more than 300 million people annually visit the nation's parks, compared with 16 million visitors in 1938. `` Our park system continues to grow. And we need to continue to grow,'' to preserve such outdoor areas for future generations, he said. President <PERSON> Franklin </PERSON> <PERSON> Delano </PERSON> <PERSON> Roosevelt </PERSON> voiced those same sentiments before signing the legislation, sponsored by local Congressman <PERSON> Mon </PERSON> <PERSON> Wallgren </PERSON>, that created the park five decades ago. `` I think you can count on my help in getting that national park, not only because we need it for us old people and you young people, but for a whole lot of young people who are going to come along in the next hundred years of <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Roosevelt </PERSON> told <LOCATION> Port </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> residents in 1937. On June 29, 1938, <PERSON> Roosevelt </PERSON> signed a bill setting aside 634,000 acres to be preserved as Olympic National Park. Today, the park is 922,000 acres of glacier-capped mountains, alpine meadows, temperate rain forest and ocean coastline. The nation's third-most-visited national park, with more than 3 million a year, Olympic remains one of the wildest. The non-profit <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Parks </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conservation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, as part of a nationwide assessment of land-acquisition needs, has proposed about 180,000 acres be added to further protect important watersheds and habitat. A study of ways to maintain national parks' integrity into the 21st century is under way by a task force of <ORGANIZATION> Park </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> managers, <PERSON> Mott </PERSON> said. Entrance fees, such as those which were imposed last year at Olympic National Park, help provide such research funds, along with local resource management, he added. Along with preserving the parks, officials also need `` to continue to explore the cultural and recreational interests of special populations, minorities and international visitors to ensure that the parks are truly available for the benefit and enjoyment of all,'' <PERSON> Mott </PERSON> said. Other issues to be addressed include protection of endangered species, air and water pollution and encroaching development outside the parks, <PERSON> Mott </PERSON> said. He also called for `` improved cooperation among adjacent land owners and land management agencies'' outside the park, as well as the academic and scientific communities' expanded involvement with park affairs.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880724-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-24-88 1132EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p AM-GOP-ConventionFund Bjt   07-24 0578</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-GOP-Convention Fund, Bjt,550</SECOND>
<HEAD>New Orleans Struggles To Meet Financial Obligations For Convention</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KEVIN McGILL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW ORLEANS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Hosting the Republican National Convention will cost the city of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION> roughly $ 5.5 million in cash, and the effort to raise that money through donations apparently will go right down to the wire. `` We've raised $ 4.2 million as of last Tuesday,'' said <PERSON> Ron </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>, president of the <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coca-Cola </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bottling </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> and head of the fund drive. `` That puts us pretty much on target. Maybe a little behind,'' he added. `` We wanted to finish up Aug. 1 _ I think we're more likely to finish up that first or second week of August.'' The convention begins the third week of August, running Aug. 15-18 in the <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION> Superdome. Raising money in a city still beset by hard economic times has n't been easy, <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> concedes. But he insists the money is being scraped together with a minimum of arm-twisting. `` In a community like <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION>,'' said <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>, `` the private sector and individuals in the community are prepared to come to the table to help out the city.'' Without question, the city needed help. Reeling from 10 percent unemployment and declining tax revenue, Mayor <PERSON> Sidney </PERSON> <PERSON> Barthelemy </PERSON> and the city council tirelessly pursued the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> in 1986, luring the party to the <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION> Superdome with the promise of $ 8 million in financial support for the convention. <PERSON> Barthelemy </PERSON> and company are banking on the convention being a huge economic boon to the community, not only because of it will spur a projected $ 137 million in spending, but also because all the publicity could attract new business. `` The $ 8 million was both in cash and in kind,'' said <PERSON> Kurt </PERSON> <PERSON> Steiner </PERSON>, <PERSON> Barthelemy </PERSON>'s chief administrative officer. `` In kind'' contributions, with an estimated value of $ 2.5 million to $ 3 million, included use of the city's parks, a performing arts theater, the municipal auditorium and other places for meetings, office space and entertainment. Cash contributions, <PERSON> Steiner </PERSON> said, include money for a new million-dollar light system and a half-million-dollar sound system to be used by the Republicans in the Superdome. Security, including overtime for police, will eat up a lot of the money, <PERSON> Steiner </PERSON> said, along witth the cost of building stages, media platforms, seats and a raised `` false floor'' to hide cables. There's also a computer system for the convention staff, and insurance. The city's prospects for coming up with the money looked dim for a time earlier this year. The Greater New Orleans Convention Fund, headed by oil millionaire <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON>, was struggling. After raising about $ 2 million in contributions, <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON> publicly complained in May that donations were lagging. That prompted the <PERSON> Barthelemy </PERSON> administration to appoint a new committee, the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION> Special Events Fund, headed by <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>, <PERSON> Mervin </PERSON> <PERSON> Trail </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> Greater </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Orleans </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tourist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Convention </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION>, and by <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Moffett </PERSON>, president of <ORGANIZATION> Freeport-McMoRan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corporation </ORGANIZATION> and chairman of the local Chamber of Comerce. Still assisted by <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON>'s group, the special events fund took an aggressive, more focused approach, zeroing in on individual chamber members, the tourist and hotel industry and major corporations. So far, <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> said, the tactic has worked, netting contributions ranging from $ 150 from small businesses to more than $ 200,000 from major corporations. The city has so far been able to meet contractural obligations arising from construction in the dome and Republican convention officials said last week preparations for the convention were progressing on schedule.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880724-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-24-88 1133EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Philippines Bjt   07-24 0725</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Philippines, Bjt,0747</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bloodshed Brings Fears Of Breakdown</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT H. REID</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MANILA, Philippines (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A grisly cycle of murders and reprisal killings by leftists and rightists is raising fears of a breakdown in law and order and threatening efforts to promote democracy and protect human rights. `` Hardly a day passes without a murder or more being headlined in our newspapers,'' the <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bishops </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conference </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> the </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Philippines </ORGANIZATION> said in a recent statement. `` Our sensibilities are being battered day in and day out, with reportage of killings and ambuscades, of slaughter and violence _ acts of terrorism all,'' the bishops said. According to the military's <ORGANIZATION> Capital </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Regional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Command </ORGANIZATION>, at least 65 people, most of them police, soldiers and anti-communist civilians, were slain in the <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION> area by the rebel <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> in the first six months of the year Those attacks have led to formation of right-wing `` death squads,'' which methodically target trade unionists, leftists and social activists in an apparent bid to undercut their influence in politics. Victims of the rightists include at least five Filipino human rights lawyers. A prominent leftist university president, <PERSON> Nemesio </PERSON> <PERSON> Prudente </PERSON>, has been wounded twice in two assassination attempts in the past seven months. The violence is not limited to <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION>. Nearly 40 people have been slain this year in politically motivated violence in <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>, home of the <ORGANIZATION> U.S.-run </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Clark </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Base </ORGANIZATION> 50 miles north of <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION>. Similar killings have been reported in <LOCATION> Cebu </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Bacolod </LOCATION> and other major cities. Several regional officials of the pro-government <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Patriotic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Alliance </ORGANIZATION> have dropped out of the organization in fear since the group's national chairman, <PERSON> Lean </PERSON> <PERSON> Alejandro </PERSON>, was slain last September. The murder was not solved. <PERSON> Alejandro </PERSON>'s group was among the social activist organizations that rallied behind <PERSON> Corazon </PERSON> <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON> in the February 1986 revolt that toppled President <PERSON> Ferdinand </PERSON> <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON>. Mrs. <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON>, who became president on the promise of restoring democracy and human rights, has called for an end to the violence. She warns that the unbridled killings will erode public confidence in her government. But Mrs. <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON>'s pledge to restore democracy has not been enough to quell the 19-year Communist insurgency, which expanded during the 20-year rule of her ousted predecessor. The killings underscore Mrs. <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON>'s fragile control of the police and armed forces. Military dissidents were responsible for a series of coup attempts that rocked the Aquino government, and leftists claim police and soldiers have been behind many of the right-wing killings. Those arrested in a June 30 attack on Prudente include five <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION> policemen and a member of a government-backed anti-communist vigilante group organized by police. <PERSON> Prudente </PERSON>, who was jailed under <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> for alleged ties to a leftist assassination team, had been accused by police of harboring communists at his <ORGANIZATION> Polytechnic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> the </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Philippines </ORGANIZATION>. `` Their interpretation of democracy is some kind of police state,'' <PERSON> Prudente </PERSON> said of his attackers. `` It's no different from the communist society that they have been castigating.'' `` We are one of those victims caught in the cross fire between the extreme left and the extreme right,'' he was quoted as saying by the Sunday Inquirer Magazine. Inability to curb the violence also threatens to undermine public support for the policy of all-out war against the communists, which Mrs. <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON> unveiled after peace talks with the rebels collapsed in January 1987. Liberal Filipinos have begun to complain that the `` total war'' campaign is polarizing society and encouraging violence not only against doctrinaire Marxists but also against those campaigning legally for social and economic reform. `` The human rights issue calls for an urgent reassessment of the counterinsurgency policy that has forced the government to trade its humanist soul in exchange for short-term political stability provided by support of the <ORGANIZATION> Armed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forces </ORGANIZATION>,'' wrote prominent columnist <PERSON> Amando </PERSON> <PERSON> Doronila </PERSON> in The <ORGANIZATION> Manila </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chronicle </ORGANIZATION>. Earlier this year, the rebels claimed they would scale down assassinations because of the alarm the killings generated among the urban middle class, which the communists hope to recruit to their cause. But last week, <PERSON> Arnel </PERSON> <PERSON> Sandoval </PERSON>, spokesman of the rebel <PERSON> Alex </PERSON> <PERSON> Boncayao </PERSON> <PERSON> Brigade </PERSON>, said killings would continue as long as the Aquino government fails to curb the rightists. `` As the Aquino government continues to protect and refuse to punish criminals in uniform, so shall the <ORGANIZATION> ABB </ORGANIZATION> resolve the bring these people the revolutionary justice they deserve,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880724-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-24-88 1141EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-MedicalWastes Bjt   07-24 0564</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Medical Wastes, Bjt,570</SECOND>
<HEAD>Coal Burner Could Curtail Hospital Waste Woes</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JEFF BARKER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Hospitals grappling with mounting infectious waste may soon get help from an unlikely source: the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION>'s coal research program. A specialized boiler could solve problems associated with disposing of surgical gloves, gowns, syringes and needles _ and at the same time, boost coal production by as much as 5 million tons per year, <PERSON> DOE </PERSON> said. Department officials said in interviews last week that <PERSON> DOE </PERSON> has entered a cost-sharing agreement with Good Samaritan Hospital of <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION>, for a demonstration project involving the boiler. An early stumbling block could be cost. A boiler of the size needed for a large hospital may not yet be economical, although the government believes research will ultimately lower the cost, said <ORGANIZATION> DOE </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Porter </PERSON>. The problem of medical waste disposal has been graphically demonstrated this summer by the needles, syringes and other debris washing up on beaches in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> and other states. Some beaches have been closed, and the source of the pollution has not yet been found. `` Applying clean-burning coal technology to hospital waste disposal is a possible ` spin-off' of our program that could not have come at a better time,'' said <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Allen </PERSON> <PERSON> Wampler </PERSON>, assistant energy secretary for fossil energy. `` Hospitals are struggling with the problem of growing amounts of infectious waste, and it translates directly into a dollars and cents issue. The expense of discarding this material is increasing the costs of medical care.'' The experimental coal-burning device is called a `` fluidized bed boiler.'' As envisioned by <PERSON> DOE </PERSON>, it would enable hospitals to burn waste while producing energy for heat or steam at the hospital. Widespead use of the boiler could create a market for as much as 3 million to 5 million tons of additional coal production a year, the department said. But the main objective of the experiment is for hospitals to efficiently dispose of infectious materials and avoid burdensome hauling costs. Large hospitals, particularly those treating AIDS patients, can pay up to $ 300,000 per year to transport waste to incinerators or other disposal facilities. The boiler is part of an effort by the federal government and private industry in the last 10 years to develop new ways of burning coal without harming the environment. Most conventional boilers burn coal rapidly at a temperature of up to 3,000 degrees. In a fluidized bed boiler, the coal burns more slowly at a lower temperature, giving it time to interact with limestone, which acts as a sponge to absorb pollutants. `` It's at about 1,600 degrees, which is almost ideal for disposing of the waste material in hospitals,'' <PERSON> Porter </PERSON> said. `` That's the temperature at which the toxins break down or are destroyed.'' The boiler has been used commercially to produce energy, but has not been tried as an incinerator for medical wastes, according to <PERSON> Kenneth </PERSON> <PERSON> Markel </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> DOE </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Technology </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Morgantown </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> W. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Va </LOCATION> While coal is among the least expensive of fuels, the boiler can also run on other materials such as wood chips or rubber tires. <PERSON> DOE </PERSON> said it has already paid $ 93,000 to help design the one-year project, whose total cost of $ 961,800 is to be shared by the department, the Commonwealth of <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> York-Shipley </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION>, which is one of the contractors.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880724-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-24-88 1146EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Drought-LowRiver     07-24 0537</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Drought-Low River,0550</SECOND>
<HEAD>River Channel Straighter, But No Longer Moves With Easy Abandon</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By WOODY BAIRD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MEMPHIS, Tenn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corps </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Engineers </ORGANIZATION>' efforts to tame the <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> are enabling barge traffic to scrape along in spite of this summer's record low water and the river's natural tendencies, <ORGANIZATION> Corps </ORGANIZATION> officials say. `` What the river wants to do is wiggle back and forth. What we're trying to do is stabilize the channel,'' said <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON>, a historian with the <ORGANIZATION> Corps </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Vicksburg </LOCATION>, Miss. Strangled by a lack of rain, the <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> has dropped to more than 20 feet below normal at <LOCATION> Memphis </LOCATION> and sand buildups have caused traffic jams involving hundreds of barges. The <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION>'s flow is expected to fall to 20 percent of normal at <LOCATION> Memphis </LOCATION> before the drought is over, and towboat operators say they'll lose more than $ 60 million this summer because of reduced traffic. On July 10, the <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> registered a record low of 10.7 feet below zero on the river gauge at <LOCATION> Memphis </LOCATION> and the flow of water rushing past the city was 115,000 cubic feet per second. Zero is an arbitrary mark set at 183.91 feet above sea level. At what the <ORGANIZATION> Corps </ORGANIZATION> calls `` full bank,'' the flow at <LOCATION> Memphis </LOCATION> is 1.3 million cfs and the river measures 34 feet above zero. The normal flow for July is 411,000 cfs. The record low flow of 78,000 cfs was set in 1936 when the river measured zero on the <LOCATION> Memphis </LOCATION> gauge. Since then, the main channel has been made narrower and deeper. In the old days when the river was left to wander, the <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> often split into two or more channels and formed big winding loops. In the 1930s and'40s, the <ORGANIZATION> Corps </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Engineers </ORGANIZATION> cut off 16 of those loops to straighten the channel and shortened the Lower <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> by 150 miles. This year's low water has revealed stone dikes and huge concrete slabs that <ORGANIZATION> Corps </ORGANIZATION> officials say are more critical than ever to keeping the river open to barges. The dikes, sticking out into the water like long, skinny fingers, force the <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION>'s main channel toward the middle of the riverbed, while mile upon mile of concrete revetment _ a blanket of concrete slabs _ keeps the river from forming loops by eroding into the bank. The river can be more than a mile across from bank to bank, but its main channel is often only 500 to 600 feet wide. The drought has cut that to less than 200 feet in some areas. Narrowing the river and preventing it from flowing slowly around a series of bends causes the main channel to dig itself deeper. In spite of record lows, the Lower <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> remains 25 to 40 feet deep in some places. But towboats are running into trouble at the so-called `` crossings'' where the river channel winds back and forth across the riverbed. The current slackens and sand and sediment settle out, sometimes putting the river at less than nine feet deep, the minimum generally needed for barges and towboats. The Corps has identified more than 30 troublesome crossings where dredging will likely be needed this summer between <LOCATION> Caruthersville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mo. </LOCATION>, and <LOCATION> Greenville </LOCATION>, Miss.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880724-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-24-88 1147EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Soviet-Dispute Bjt   07-24 0816</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Soviet-Dispute, Bjt,0843</SECOND>
<HEAD>Territorial Dispute Exposes Limits of Glasnost</HEAD>
<HEAD>AP News Analysis</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ANDREW KATELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MOSCOW (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> moved away from quiet diplomacy and got tough last week as he sought to resolve a dispute over an obscure mountain region whose importance has grown far beyond its contested borders. The Soviet leader's handling of the problem offers some insight into how far he is prepared to go in allowing more openness and giving people a greater say in how they are governed. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> said the struggle over <LOCATION> Nagorno-Karabakh </LOCATION>, a mostly Armenian enclave in the republic of <LOCATION> Azerbaijan </LOCATION>, has inflicted immense damage on perestroika, his reform program. He warned it could doom his plans to modernize Soviet society. Addressing the Soviet leadership Monday at a special session of the Supreme Soviet's Presidium, <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> said: `` If we fail to find the solution to this question today _ and we must find it _ this would have far-reaching consequences and would affect all perestroika.'' The immediate issue is the future of the sparsely populated, largely undeveloped region in the <LOCATION> Caucasus </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mountains </LOCATION>. The ethnic Armenian majority set out in February to secede from largely Moslem <LOCATION> Azerbaijan </LOCATION> and join predominantly <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <LOCATION> Armenia </LOCATION>. But in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, a patchwork quilt of 15 republics shared by more than 100 distinct ethnic and national groups, redrawing maps is a dangerous business. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> and the Presidium, the top executive body of government, served notice they were not about to open that <PERSON> Pandora </PERSON>'s box. Clearly, <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s policy of glasnost, or openness, is not a guarantee of free speech as practiced in Western democracies, and democratization does not sanction a challenge to one-party rule. The government has tolerated massive demonstrations _ including some in the Armenian capital of <LOCATION> Yerevan </LOCATION> that have drawn hundreds of thousands, perhaps even a million people, according to witness accounts. But <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> said redrawing the borders would constitute an abuse of democratization `` fundamentally at variance with the aims of perestroika.'' Giving in to nationalist demands, he told the Presidium, would `` poison public mentality with nationalist venom and thereby spoil relations between the peoples for many, many years to come.'' In unanimously rejecting <LOCATION> Nagorno-Karabakh </LOCATION>'s attempt to secede against <LOCATION> Azerbaijan </LOCATION>, the Presidium warned that a series of strikes that began in <LOCATION> Nagorno-Karabakh </LOCATION> and spread to <LOCATION> Armenia </LOCATION>, crippling the local economy, had exhausted the Presidium's patience. The <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION> authorized police to `` take essential measures'' to end the strikes and `` activities directed at kindling national strife and attempts to misuse democratic rights for anti-democratic purposes.'' Troops stationed in the strife-torn areas were reinforced. <PERSON> Paruyr </PERSON> <PERSON> Ayrikyan </PERSON>, a leader of the annexation drive who was arrested in March on a charge of defaming the state, was stripped of his Soviet citizenship and ordered expelled from the country. The state-run national press attacked strike leaders by name. First indications showed the new tough tactics were having an impact. Most workers in <LOCATION> Armenia </LOCATION> returned to their jobs, although the general strike continued in <LOCATION> Nagorno-Karabakh </LOCATION>. The central leadership clearly has acted with more restraint and tolerance than would have been expected in previous Soviet regimes. Not long ago, the <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION> would have quickly turned to force to put down the turmoil. This time, the Kremlin first tried the power of persuasion. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> made a personal appeal Feb. 26 for `` civic maturity and restraint,'' and the mass demonstrations in <LOCATION> Yerevan </LOCATION> subsided. But two days later, a riot broke out in the Azerbaijani city of <LOCATION> Sumgait </LOCATION>, and at least 32 people were killed, 26 of them Armenians. The <ORGANIZATION> Kremlin </ORGANIZATION> also tried changing the local leadership, installing new party chiefs in <LOCATION> Armenia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Azerbaijan </LOCATION>. The new officials quickly acknowledged that Armenians in <LOCATION> Nagorno-Karabakh </LOCATION> had been deprived culturally and socially under previous regimes. In March, the central government announced a major remedial program to improve cultural and social conditions in <LOCATION> Nagorno-Karabakh </LOCATION>, with much of the aid going to the Armenian majority. But Armenians outside the region, perhaps encouraged by the new latitude given them by glasnost, made annexation of <LOCATION> Nagorno-Karabakh </LOCATION> a crusade. Those who died in <LOCATION> Sumgait </LOCATION> were its martyrs. The legislatures of both <LOCATION> Nagorno-Karabakh </LOCATION> and the Armenian republic sought the annexation, claiming the right of self-determination guaranteed by the Soviet Constitution. But <LOCATION> Azerbaijan </LOCATION>, citing another constitutional provision requiring consent of affected republics before redrawing boundaries, rejected the appeals. That set the stage for intervention by the central government. `` Democratic rights and the new conditions opened up and created by perestroika are being clearly misused for anti-democratic purposes,'' <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> told the Presidium. Both sides, he said, were using territorial claims to stir up national sentiments and `` conceal the really difficult, crying problems that had accumulated.'' Victory can only come by finding a common course, <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> said, adding that the search for that course must continue.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> <PERSON> Katell </PERSON>, an <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> correspondent in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>, has covered the <LOCATION> Nagorno-Karabakh </LOCATION> dispute extensively since it began in February.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880724-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-24-88 1150EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w AM-Maize     07-24 0571</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Maize,530</SECOND>
<HEAD>New Corn Plant Could Help Third World</HEAD>
<HEAD>By CARL HARTMAN</HEAD>
<HEAD>Associated Press Writer</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A new plant that could turn corn into a health food and help nourish protein-starved children in the Third World is being promoted by the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government's <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>. It's called QPM for quality-protein maize because it contains about twice the usable protein of ordinary varieties. Maize is the international word for corn. A small research team, working for 10 years, developed QPM at the same laboratories where Nobel Peace Prize winner <PERSON> Norman </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Borlaug </PERSON> produced the new wheat varieties that brought the `` green revolution'' in the 1950s. <PERSON> Noel </PERSON> <PERSON> Vietmeyer </PERSON>, an expert on useful but neglected plants for the research council, calls <PERSON> Borlaug </PERSON>, 74, the `` spiritual godfather'' of QPM, although he was not directly involved in the project at the International Center for the Improvement of Maize and Wheat near <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Borlaug </PERSON> still works at the center. `` Maize is often the crop of the poor, and in the maize-growing areas of the world, millions of children living in poverty are not thriving,'' says the newly published report of a panel appointed by the council. `` Here is an opportunity to explore this new approach to relieving an intolerable situation,'' it says. The world produces enough corn to provide each inhabitant with about 200 pounds a year. It is a staple food for nearly half the world's chronically undernourished people. `` A typical diet might consist of 20 or more tortillas a day, supplemented with hot peppers, some native greens, and little or nothing else,'' says the council's monthly `` News Report'' for July. Tortillas are generally made in <LOCATION> Latin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> with corn meal. People in wealthier countries get their protein from meat, fish, cheese and a variety of other foods. Small children get it from milk. Tens of millions of poor people in the Third World survive on corn, cassava, yams, plantain and other foods low in protein. When small children are weaned in those countries, they can not eat enough of the beans or rice to provide the protein milk has given them, and millions suffer from kwashiorkor, a protein-deficiency disease that stunts growth. The report suggests distributing QPM in areas that already depend heavily on corn to feed small children: the highlands of the Andes mountains in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, most of <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Bangladesh </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Indonesia </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION>. It sees QPM as also having important advantages for industrial countries. `` There is, for instance, distinct promise for breakfast cereals and snack foods, both of which are constantly criticized for their low nutritional value,'' it says. The new maize variety is not yet ready for use in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, It was created with the Third World in mind and its pollen is spread naturally by the wind. In the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, farmers use hybrid seeds produced in greenhouses or on special plots of land, so that the seeds always breed true. One of the problems with QPM is that it looks and tastes like ordinary corn, and so do the gruels, cakes and tortillas made from it. This makes it more palatable than some earlier varieties but there is a danger that a field of QPM might interbreed with a field of ordinary maize and the QPM would soon lose its special quality. The report says that for this reason it will be especially important to introduce QPM in an organized way.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880724-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-24-88 1151EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w AM-MilitaryEx-Wives     07-24 0583</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Military Ex-Wives,560</SECOND>
<HEAD>Ex-Wives Say They're Paying For Husband's Debts; Hearings Planned</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JENNIFER DIXON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Vivian </PERSON> <PERSON> Filemyr </PERSON>'s health is frail and money is tight, so when the government suddenly slashed her share of her ex-husband's military pension, she had to plead with doctors and creditors to accept less than usual when bills came due. The 66-year-old <LOCATION> Austin </LOCATION> woman says her main source of income was cut without warning in May, from about $ 1,100 a month to $ 900, and she's spent the last two months trying to find out why. She thinks the cut came because her es-husband, a retired colonel, may have incurred a debt to the government many years after their 1972 divorce. The military wo n't say more, she said, because it would be an invasion of his privacy. `` My credit rating is being hurt; I have to call my creditors and say my check is reduced and I do n't know why and I ca n't pay you,'' Ms. <PERSON> Filemyr </PERSON> said. Congressional officials and members of an ex-wives support group in <LOCATION> Alexandria </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, say Ms. <PERSON> Filemyr </PERSON>'s case is not unique and may illustrate a growing trend as the government cracks down on its bad debts. `` The government _ they'll get their money any way they can,'' said <PERSON> Shirley </PERSON> <PERSON> Taft </PERSON>, former president of EX-POSE, or Ex-Partners of Servicemen-women for Equality. `` We've heard from quite a few -LRB- women -RRB- and it's quite devastating. They do n't even know why it's being reduced and the finance centers wo n't tell them. They only know the man's gone into debt for something,'' Ms. <PERSON> Taft </PERSON> said. She said representatives of the group met with <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> officials earlier this month to argue that the ex-wives should not be held liable for debts incurred by their former spouses after the divorce is final. But the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> told the group `` chances of an administrative change are very slim,'' she said. Congressional hearings on the matter and other related issues are planned in September before a subcommittee of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Armed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, says a spokeswoman for Rep. <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Schroeder </PERSON>, D-Colo., who sponsored the 1982 Former Spouse Protection Act Under the bill, courts can award a portion of a serviceman's retirement check to the former spouse If the couple were married at least 10 years, the ex-wife can receive the money directly through the military's finance centers, Ms. <PERSON> Taft </PERSON> said. Maj. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Super </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> spokesman, said the military is looking into the situation but continues to `` operate with existing administrative rules and laws.'' Ms. <PERSON> Taft </PERSON> said her organization plans to poll its 3,500 members about the problem this month. `` This is not an isolated case,'' Ms. <PERSON> Filemyr </PERSON> wrote in a letter to Rep. <PERSON> Jake </PERSON> <PERSON> Pickle </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Texas </LOCATION>. `` I have spoken with various women across the country who have related to me that they are in the same situation.'' Mrs. <PERSON> Filemyr </PERSON> said she was divorced after 25 years of marriage and was on welfare for years as she fought for the 1982 law. `` I only had a little job here, a little job there, and I kept getting sicker,'' she said. `` I've had it rough, yes I've had it rough. Her only other source of income is a monthly Social Security check of about $ 160, she said. Rep. <PERSON> Schroeder </PERSON>'s spokeswoman said the congresswoman plans to introduce legislation that would divide retirement pay according to a formula based on the number of years of service and the length of the marriage, rather than leaving the decision to individual courts or states.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880724-0025 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-24-88 1152EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p AM-Democrats-Labor Bjt   07-24 0790</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Democrats-Labor, Bjt,760</SECOND>
<HEAD>Union Leaders Confident Of Vote-Getting Strength For Dukakis</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Booe, graf 7, cq</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By MATT YANCEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Labor Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ATLANTA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Bolstered by their highest delegate strength ever at a Democratic convention, union leaders believe they can deliver 2.5 million votes for <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> in November. Although the <ORGANIZATION> AFL-CIO </ORGANIZATION> will not officially endorse <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> until Aug. 24, after the Republican convention, its political operatives left here with no intention of waiting for what one called the `` pro forma announcement'' to begin working on <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' behalf. An $ 8 million voter registration campaign _ put on a back burner while unions concentrated on collecting convention delegates in the primaries and caucuses _ is being reignited this week. After breakfasting with <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> last week, <ORGANIZATION> AFL-CIO </ORGANIZATION> President <PERSON> Lane </PERSON> <PERSON> Kirkland </PERSON> said in an interview that unions will have less difficulty than they did four years ago in getting their members to vote a Democratic ticket. `` In 1984 there was a swell of support in favor of <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>,'' he said. `` We stemmed that tide better than the others. This year there is an entirely different set of circumstances. There's no incumbency and people want a change.'' Despite the union label on 1,054 or more than one-fourth of the Democratic convention delegates, labor still is maintaining a lower profile in comparison with its all-out boosterism of <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> Mondale </PERSON> four years ago. `` We worked harder in 1984 and all we got for it was fewer delegates and more abuse,'' said <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Booe </PERSON>, secretary-treasurer of the <ORGANIZATION> Communications </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Workers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION>. It was two of labor's more consistent supporters in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> _ <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Hart </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION> _ who cried `` special interest'' after the <ORGANIZATION> AFL-CIO </ORGANIZATION> endorsed <PERSON> Mondale </PERSON> in October 1983. That was four months before the first <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> caucuses and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION> primary. <PERSON> Kirkland </PERSON> takes satisfaction that both <PERSON> Hart </PERSON> and <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON> `` went down the chute'' afterwards and that no candidate for national office has repeated what he views as a slur since. But the scar is still there. To provide <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> with a winning margin, labor leaders believe they will have to get at least a 65 percent vote for him from a rank-and-file membership that cast 39 percent of its votes four years ago for <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>. `` There is a mythology that it was the blue-collar workers that brought <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> in,'' said <PERSON> Kirkland </PERSON>. `` Sixty percent of our people voted for <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> Mondale </PERSON>. But if we have to get two-thirds of our membership, which encompasses a wide cross-section of the country, to elect a decent candidate, it tells me there is a strong conservative bias in the rest of the population.'' The <ORGANIZATION> AFL-CIO </ORGANIZATION> plans to have at least 300,000 volunteers working the polls on Election Day, said <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Perkins </PERSON>, director of the federation's <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> on </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Political </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Education </ORGANIZATION>. But first it has to ensure that its members are registered. Labor political activists are working on a three-part formula that could allow unions to provide enough votes to counter the acknowledged more conservative views of the rest of the electorate. It calls for: _ Voter registration that is 15 percentage points above the national average of 72 percent. <ORGANIZATION> AFL-CIO </ORGANIZATION> officials estimate that about 80 percent of the federation's 14.1 million members are now registered. _ Turnout on election day that is 15 percentage points higher than the 53 percent of the voting age population that went to the polls in 1984. _ And a vote among union members for the labor-endorsed candidate that is at least 15 percentage points higher than the electorate at large gives him. The <ORGANIZATION> AFL-CIO </ORGANIZATION> achieved that in 1984 with the 61 percent of its membership voting for <PERSON> Mondale </PERSON>, compared with 41 percent of the total electorate. With all three, <PERSON> Kirkland </PERSON> estimates trade union support of a candidate is worth a net 2.5 million votes nationwide. `` That's not something to be sneezed at,'' he says with pride. According to political directors for individual unions, the effort faltered last time on making sure members were registered and getting them to the polls on election day. Even though <PERSON> Mondale </PERSON> had an early lock on the labor endorsement, many believed he could not win and support waned, according to one labor activist. What's different this year is a belief among labor activists that <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has so many negatives that a strong union turnout could provide <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> with the edge to beat him. `` Our rank and file by a slim margin voted for <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>,'' said <PERSON> Loretta </PERSON> <PERSON> Bowen </PERSON>, the Communication Workers' political director. `` But they've indicated overwhelmingly they will come back to the Democratic side. If <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> were a warm individual, the fact he has been a supporter of <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> would help him. But our members think he's arrogant and a snob.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880724-0026 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-24-88 1157EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-US-Vietnam Bjt   07-24 0713</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-US-Vietnam, Bjt,740</SECOND>
<HEAD>Vietnam Shows Friendlier Face But US Shows Little Interest</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GEORGE GEDDA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
