<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881008-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-08-88 1336EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>'' said Sen. Bentsen,
who was wrapping up a three-day swing through his home state on</FIRST>
<SECOND>aturday, then making a quick trip to a Navajo reservation in
New</SECOND>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>. `` <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> may try to run away from his running mate, but he really ca n't hide,'' said <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>, who called the selection of <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> `` a big mistake.'' `` While the Republicans are running from the issues, and running from <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>, we do n't intend to let them change the tune; we're going to see that they face the music,'' <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> said Democratic presidential nominee <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> has been facing the music in <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> on the issues of crime and gun control in a barrage of Republican ads portraying him as a coddler of criminals who wants to disarm honest citizens. <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> attacked what he said were distortions of <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' record, and said <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> would see through them. `` Texans wo n't buy a bill of goods on gun control from a man who wanted to sell Hawk missiles to the ayatollah,'' he said. <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> denied Republican assertions that the Democrats had given up on \* wnnning the South. `` That is obviously not true. It sounds like some of his comments during the debate. Not true at all,'' he said. `` I was in <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> the other day and they tell me we're ahead there I was in <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION>, they said that's a dead heat. I think we're ahead in <LOCATION> Arkansas </LOCATION>. We've seen a nice improvement here in <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> -LRB- where -RRB- the momentum is back in our direction,'' he said, citing a recent poll showing the ticket only five points behind. <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> also discussed his relationship with the late President <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, which some have questioned since <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> said that they were friends. He said that during the debate just before telling <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> he was `` no <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>.'' <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>, who served in the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> with <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, said he was the <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> senator's finance chairman in <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION> when <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> ran for presid `. w He also said he received from <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> an inscribed copy of his Pulitzer Prize-winning book, `` Profiles in Courage.'' <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> invited him to his wedding, <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> said, but he was already scheduled to make a speech in south <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> and missed it. `` If I had knor. # he was going to be president, I'd have gone,'' he said
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881008-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-08-88 0006EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Children'sPackage Bjt   10-08 0631</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Children's Package, Bjt,620</SECOND>
<HEAD>Democrats Vow To Resume Battle For Family Issues In 1989</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JILL LAWRENCE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 When Sen. <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>'s son was undergoing cancer treatment, the senator was absent from the Capitol for three days every three weeks for two years. He did n't lose his job. When Sen. <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Biden </PERSON>, D-Del., had surgery that laid him up for months, he did n't lose his job either <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, D-Mass., used those examples to underscore why Democrats will be back next year pressing for a parental and medical leave bill that died Friday along with a major child care initiative `` These two items will be top priorities in the next <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>,'' <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> said. Backers of the two family bills failed Friday to get the 60 votes they needed to limit debate and complete action on the measure. The vote was 50-46. The package, which also included a crackdown on child pornographers, was on the floor for the better part of two weeks amid intense political and parliamentary maneuvering. Supporters found some solace in the heightened visibility of their causes. `` It was an extraordinarily wonderful job of educating both members of the <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and the <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> public,'' said <PERSON> Judith </PERSON> <PERSON> Lichtman </PERSON>, executive director of the Women's Legal Defense Fund. Sen. <PERSON> Christopher </PERSON> <PERSON> Dodd </PERSON>, D-Conn., sponsor of the child care and parental leave bills, said he would re-introduce them on the first day of the 101st <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> in January Accusing Republicans of waging `` a filibuster by silence,'' he declared, `` The stonewall prevailed. They defeated the American family. But we're not going to lose forever. We're going to win these issues.'' Rep. <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Schroeder </PERSON>, D-Colo., sponsor of the parental leave bill in the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, said the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> vote marked the beginning of the fight and predicted supporters would have renewed strength next year `` The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>'s got to learn that you ca n't keep playing'' with family issues, she said. `` People are going to be angry that there's been such a high level of rhetoric and so little produced.'' But the groups who fended off the parental-leave and child-care provisions this year vowed to be back in force next year as well. `` This was round one, but it was very much indicative what the proponents of -LRB- child care -RRB- and parental leave will face in the future. They're going to face a battle again and again, not only from the business community but from groups like ours,'' said <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> Kepley </PERSON>, a lobbyist for Concerned Women for <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>. She said the conservative group's nearly half-million members are active in every congressional district in the nation. The three elements of the family package included: _ <PERSON> Dodd </PERSON>'s original bill requiring employers of more than 50 people to offer workers at least 10 weeks of unpaid, job-protected leave when they have newborn, newly adopted or sick children, or have serious medical problems themselves _ An anti-pornography initiative sponsored by Sen. <PERSON> Strom </PERSON> <PERSON> Thurmond </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-S.C. </LOCATION>, which creates new crimes and punishments for those who possess, sell or distribute child pornography or obscene materials It was added to the parental leave bill on a unanimous vote. _ The $ 2.5 billion Act for <ORGANIZATION> Better </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Child </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Care </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION>, also sponsored by <PERSON> Dodd </PERSON>, aimed at helping low-income parents pay for child care at centers or homes It was presented as a compromise between <PERSON> Dodd </PERSON> and Sen. <PERSON> Orrin </PERSON> <PERSON> Hatch </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Utah </LOCATION>, and was to have included a tax credit for poor families in its final form. Republicans maintained <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> had more pressing matters to deal with, such as drug and tax bills, and refused to offer amendments or strike a compromise on the family bills. `` What we've done in effect is say slow down,'' said Republican leader <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION>. `` This is n't an urgent measure that needs to be passed in the waning days of the 100th <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881008-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-08-88 0008EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Business-Education     10-08 0542</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Business-Education,530</SECOND>
<HEAD>Educators Rap Bush, Dukakis On Education Priorities</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVE SKIDMORE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>HOT SPRINGS, Va. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Educators addressing the nation's top business leaders say both presidential candidates have failed to fulfill their promises to make education a priority of their campaigns. Republican <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has said he wants to be known as `` the education president'' and Democrat <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> has said `` no issue ... means more to me.'' However, over the past year there's been `` a strange silence,'' said <PERSON> Ernest </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Boyer </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> Carnegie </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION> for the Advancement of Teaching. `` A few little pieces have come along, revolving mainly around college loans and grants, but I have not seen a coherent program from either candidate.'' `` I am disappointed with the lack of a sense of urgency,'' said <PERSON> Marian </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> <PERSON> Edelman </PERSON>, president of the Children's Defense Fund, which takes a liberal approach to family issues. `` Never have we heard so much discussion. But the proof of the pudding is in the concrete proposals, the willingness to invest,'' she said. <PERSON> Boyer </PERSON>, <PERSON> Edelman </PERSON> and other education leaders spoke Friday during private sessions of the Business Council, composed of 62 chief executives of the country's biggest companies. They talked with reporters afterward. The executives were gathered for their twice-a-year meeting in this resort town in the mountains of western <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Shanker </PERSON>, president of the 665,000-member <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Teachers </ORGANIZATION>, said he agreed that neither candidate had a well-developed education program, but he said he preferred <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> to <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> because the Republican tilts toward providing federal assistance to private schools. `` For us that's a life and death difference. If you move away from the public schools ... that's abandoning the major institution we have in our society for improvement of education,'' he said. However, former <LOCATION> Delaware </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Pete </PERSON> <PERSON> du </PERSON> <PERSON> Pont </PERSON>, who ran unsuccessfully for the Republican presidential nomination, said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> should more strongly emphasize using free market competition to improve education. `` The school system is terrified of -LRB- competition -RRB-. They have a government monopoly. They do n't have to compete for their kids. Why would they want to change? The problem is, of course, they're giving everyone a lousy education,'' he said Both <PERSON> Boyer </PERSON> and <PERSON> Edelman </PERSON> said they were encouraged that business leaders recognized education's importance to the future of the country. `` They are voices that are listened to -LRB- by politicians -RRB-. They're not going to listen to a third grade teacher They are going to listen to the president of a major corporation. Even the president of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> will answer a phone call from the people in this conference,'' <PERSON> Boyer </PERSON> said. Also scheduled to speak to the business executives finishing a two-day conference today were <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Volcker </PERSON>, a forme chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reserve </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION>; <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Verity </PERSON>; Sen. <PERSON> Lawton </PERSON> <PERSON> Chiles </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Fla </LOCATION>., and Rep. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Gray </PERSON>, D-Pa., the chairmen of the congressional budget committees, and <PERSON> Drew </PERSON> <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON> and <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Strauss </PERSON>, the co-chairmen of a blue-ribbon commission studying the budget The council, formed in 1933 as an advisory panel to the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION>, selected <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, chairman of <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Motors </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, to serve as its chairman in 1989 and 1990. He replaces S.D. <PERSON> Bechtel </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, chairman of <ORGANIZATION> Bechtel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Group </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, a worldwide construction firm.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881008-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-08-88 0009EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Panama     10-08 0394</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Panama,0409</SECOND>
<HEAD>Panama Declares Election Season Open</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ALINA GUERRERO</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PANAMA CITY, Panama (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The government on Friday declared the campaign season open for general elections to be held May 7 of next year and said the ballot will not be affected by strained diplomatic relations with the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. A president and two vice presidents will be elected by simple majority of votes in May, to serve five-year terms beginning June 7. Elections for the legislative <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION> and local offices will be held June 4. The <ORGANIZATION> Electoral </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tribunal </ORGANIZATION> said in a communique the campaign schedule will be respected despite <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s political and economic crises. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has imposed economic sanctions and diplomatic pressure on <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> trying to force Gen. <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> to resign as the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forces </ORGANIZATION> commander and as such, <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s de facto ruler. <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> is under <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> indictment on drug trafficking and money laundering charges, which he denies. When President <PERSON> Eric </PERSON> <PERSON> Arturo </PERSON> <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON> tried to fire <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> last February, <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON> himself was dismissed by the Noriega-controlled <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION>. The <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration still recognizes <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON> as <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s legitimate president <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> economic sanctions have helped push <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s economy into its worst depression since the 1930s. Under election code changes approved by the assembly in August, mayoral elections were eliminated in 68 towns and cities. Beginning in 1989, the president will appoint mayors. The changes also require public office-holders who are presidential candidates to resign three months before the election. <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> has given no indication whether he plans to resign as <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forces </ORGANIZATION> commander and run for president as standard-bearer of the governing <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Revolutionary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>. Since a military coup in 1968, the presidency has been a ceremonial post dominated by the armed forces. <PERSON> Nicolas </PERSON> <PERSON> Ardito </PERSON> <PERSON> Barletta </PERSON> ran as the government candidate and won the presidential election in 1984, the first in 16 years. He resigned under pressure in 1985 over differences with the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forces </ORGANIZATION>. With the military's support, <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON> succeeded <PERSON> Barletta </PERSON>. The opposition has not yet said whether it will take part in the election. Legally registered opposition parties include the <ORGANIZATION> Authentic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Panamanian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Liberal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Movement </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Action </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>. More than 1.1 million Panamanians are registered to vote in May. In the 1984 presidential elections, 917,000 voters were registered.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881008-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-08-88 0018EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lottery     10-08 0025</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lottery,0025</SECOND>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the winning weekly state lottery numbers picked Friday:
</TEXT>
<HEAD>CONNECTICUT</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Lotto: 01; 02; 09; 24; 28; 30.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881008-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-08-88 0018EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-LotteryRdp     10-08 0083</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lottery Rdp,0088</SECOND>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the winning weekly state lottery numbers picked so far this week:
</TEXT>
<HEAD>CONNECTICUT</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Lotto: 01; 02; 09; 24; 28; 30.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>DELAWARE</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Play 4: 7-3-4-5.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>MASSACHUSETTS</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Wednesday Megabucks: 05; 14; 17; 24; 26; 30.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>NEW JERSEY</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Pick 6 Lotto: 05; 08; 26; 29; 31; 36. Bonus: 50699.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>NEW YORK</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Wednesday Lotto 54 Game: 01; 11; 14; 22; 51; 52. Supplementary 02.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>PENNSYLVANIA</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Big 4 Lottery: 5-2-9-6.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>RHODE ISLAND</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Grand Lot Game: 5-0-9; 2-8-0-3; 3-5-4-6-9; 1-4-1-8-1-1.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881008-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-08-88 0021EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-BRF--Germany-Escape     10-08 0151</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Germany-Escape,0154</SECOND>
<HEAD>East German Man Swims River To Escape To West</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BAD BRAMSTEDT, West Germany (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A 24-year-old East German man climbed his communist homeland's border barriers Friday and swam a river to flee to the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION>, border police said. The man, whose identity was not released, eluded East German police border patrols at the frontier nearly 50 east of <LOCATION> Hamburg </LOCATION>, scaled barriers and then swam the <LOCATION> Wakenitz </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION>, said the West German border police. On Thursday, police said two East German men fled from the Baltic coast in a rubber dinghy and were rescued in stormy seas in Danish territorial waters by a Greek freighter. On Wednesday, an East German man waded through the shallows of the <LOCATION> Werra </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> and scaled barriers to escape just east of <LOCATION> Kassel </LOCATION> in north-central <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>. More than 333 East Germans have fled to <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> this year, according to government statistics.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881008-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-08-88 0021EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-BeanMurder     10-08 0236</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Bean Murder,0242</SECOND>
<HEAD>Killer of Heir to Baked Bean Fortune Gets 30 Years</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PORTLAND, Maine (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A trucker convicted of murdering the heir to the <ORGANIZATION> Burnham </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> Morrill </PERSON> baked bean fortune was sentenced Friday to 30 years in prison during an emotional hearing in which the victim's son urged the judge to be lenient. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Savage </PERSON> <PERSON> Sr. </PERSON>, 53, of <PERSON> Gardiner </PERSON>, faced a minimum of 25 years in prison for the slaying of <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Sumner </PERSON> <PERSON> Morrill </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>, who was shot four times at his farm in <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Baldwin </LOCATION> on Nov. 7, 1987. Justice <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Fritzsche </PERSON> called the incident `` a horrible tragedy.'' <PERSON> Savage </PERSON> had maintained that he acted in self-defense when <PERSON> Morrill </PERSON>, 51, attacked him after <PERSON> Savage </PERSON> arrived at the farm to discuss his recently ended 14-month affair with <PERSON> Morrill </PERSON>'s wife, <PERSON> Jessie </PERSON>. The prosecution had claimed that <PERSON> Savage </PERSON>, armed with a loaded pistol, had intended to provoke <PERSON> Morrill </PERSON>. His voice cracking, <PERSON> Savage </PERSON> told the judge he had been used by Mrs. <PERSON> Morrill </PERSON>. `` I gave up everything I had,'' he said. The victim's son, <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Sumner </PERSON> <PERSON> Morrill </PERSON> <PERSON> IV </PERSON>, backed up <PERSON> Savage </PERSON>'s account, saying he had told the truth about his stepmother `` He was a pawn, just like my father was a pawn,'' <PERSON> Morrill </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Morrill </PERSON> urged the judge to impose the 25-year minimum prison term. The prosecution sought 30 years. <PERSON> Morrill </PERSON> and <PERSON> Savage </PERSON> were members of a bluegrass band that had broken up earlier last year.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881008-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-08-88 0024EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Strauss-Service     10-08 0225</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Strauss-Service,0232</SECOND>
<HEAD>World Dignitaries Attend Strauss Memorial Service</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MUNICH, West Germany (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Heads of state and dignitaries from around the world attended memorial services Friday for Bavarian leader <PERSON> Franz </PERSON> <PERSON> Josef </PERSON> <PERSON> Strauss </PERSON>, one of <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>'s most dynamic and colorful politicians. <PERSON> Strauss </PERSON>, 73, governor of <LOCATION> Bavaria </LOCATION> and chairman of the conservative <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Social </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> party </ORGANIZATION>, died Monday in <LOCATION> Regensburg </LOCATION>. He was an original founder of <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> when its government was formed in 1949, and his influence reached far beyond its borders. Thousands of prominent politicians, dignitaries, industrialists, and religious leaders attended memorial proceedings, including former <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Secretary of State <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> Kissinger </PERSON>, President <PERSON> Pieter </PERSON> <PERSON> Botha </PERSON> of <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> and Soviet Deputy Premier <PERSON> Ivan </PERSON> <PERSON> Silayev </PERSON>. Proceedings began with a <ORGANIZATION> Roman </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mass </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Munich </LOCATION>'s Liebfrauendom Cathedral, followed by a state memorial service in nearby Wittelsbacher Residence building and a funeral procession through the city <PERSON> Strauss </PERSON>' daughter and two sons and his sister attended. His wife <PERSON> Marianne </PERSON> died in 1984 in a car accident. West German President <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> von </PERSON> <PERSON> Weizsaecker </PERSON> and Chancellor <PERSON> Helmut </PERSON> <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON> delivered eulogies. At the Mass, Cardinal <PERSON> Friedrich </PERSON> <PERSON> Wetter </PERSON>, archbishop of <LOCATION> Munich </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Friesin </PERSON>, read aloud a telegram from the <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION>, in which Pope <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> II </PERSON> praised <PERSON> Strauss </PERSON> as a `` great Christian statesman.'' <PERSON> Strauss </PERSON> was to be buried Saturday alongside his wife in <ORGANIZATION> Rott </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> am </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inn </ORGANIZATION>, a small Bavarian village near <LOCATION> Rosenheim </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881008-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-08-88 0027EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-ChallengerTape     10-08 0240</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Challenger Tape,240</SECOND>
<HEAD>Court Says It Will Reconsider Order To NASA To Release Challenger
Tape</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A federal appeals court has agreed to reconsider its decision ordering the nation's space agency to release the audio tape recording of space shuttle astronauts moments before they died in the 1986 Challenger disaster. The full <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Circuit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appeals </ORGANIZATION> granted the government's request for a rehearing of the case by all of its 11 members The decision, contained in an Oct. 5 order made public Friday, came two months after a split panel of three appellate judges ruled the tapes of the Jan. 28, 1986, shuttle disaster should be made public under the Freedom of Information Act. The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aeronautics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Space </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> has refused to give up the tapes, contending their release would subject the survivors of the seven astronauts to emotional stress when they are played repeatedly on radio and television. Two members of the court's liberal wing, <PERSON> Spottswood </PERSON> <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON> and <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON>, joined in the July 29 ruling that drew a blistering dissent from Circuit Judge <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Ginsburg </PERSON>, a member of the court's 6-5 conservative majority. The brief order granting the petition for a rehearing en banc stated only that a majority of the 11 judges had agreed to reconsider the earlier decision. The order said a briefing schedule would be announced later. A <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman, <PERSON> Patricia </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Riep </PERSON>, praised the decision Friday evening.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881008-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-08-88 0028EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Reagan     10-08 0437</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Reagan,430</SECOND>
<HEAD>Reagan Invokes Quayle's Name More Often</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MERRILL HARTSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> is broadening his campaign stump speech to heap praise on besieged <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> vice presidential candidate <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>. During the latest in a series of campaign-style trips aimed at helping <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> keep the White House in Republican hands, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> on several occasions Friday put <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>'s name in a favorable light. This was in addition to the usual <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> plaudits for <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. The president departed from the text of a dinner speech to tell his audience that `` someone I know and respect came through for us and all Americans the other night.'' `` I have to say, I was n't surprised,'' <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said of <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>'s performance in debate with Democratic rival <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> `` Sure, the <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> establishment was betting against him, but I can tell you, the smart money was riding on a great senator by the name of <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>,'' he added. `` I tell you, he got my vote. How about you?'' the president asked, bringing applause from the audience. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> had seldom mentioned <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>'s name in recent campaign outings, but White House officials were unwilling to talk about the apparent change in strategy. The kind words for <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> on Friday started the moment <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> left the White House in the morning en route to <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION>, when he made mention of the <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION> senator while commenting on the latest drop in unemployment figures. `` We've talked about the record 70 months of economic expansion, but these figures tell the real story that people can understand,'' he said. `` And that's what <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> stand for and it's what the administration has worked out for the last eight years.'' Once he arrived in <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION>, the president continued the pro-Quayle statements he had commenced Thursday in the wake of criticism of the <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION> senator's performance in Wednesday's vice presidential debate. Speaking to a luncheon of business executives in <LOCATION> Macomb </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said that `` one thing's even clearer to me after watching the debate Wednesday night: the <ORGANIZATION> Bush-Quayle </ORGANIZATION> ticket will continue the policies of peace and prosperity that have _ as <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> said _ made this great nation ` the envy of the world.''' Then, in his address to a $ 1,000-a-plate fund-raising dinner, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> repeated that refrain. The president had talked glowingly of <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> in the days immediately following the Republican National Convention in August, tossing the senator's name prominently into a speech he made Aug. 24 in a joint appearance with <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>. But <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> in the past few weeks had not alluded to <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> in these stump speeches.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881008-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-08-88 0029EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-CoalFire     10-08 0168</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Coal Fire,0175</SECOND>
<HEAD>Underground Coal Fire Extinguished</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NELSONVILLE, Ohio (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The fire chief of this southeast <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> community says he's relieved that an underground coal fire was extinguished before reaching any homes. `` We were lucky to get to it in its infancy,'' Fire Chief <PERSON> Tim </PERSON> <PERSON> Baden </PERSON> said. Thought the eight-day fire threatened as many as 30 homes, none in the town of 5,000 people was damaged. <PERSON> Baden </PERSON> said the blaze was extinguished Friday after firefighters poured water and a synthetic foam into holes bored into the earth. The fire, which covered a 40-by-40-foot area, was discovered Sept. 30 when children playing on a hillside poked sticks into the ground and saw that the sticks were on fire when they pulled them out. The fire, which extended downward four feet, burned refuse coal that was believed to have come from an unmapped mine abandoned in the 1920s. <PERSON> Baden </PERSON> said the fire entered a coal seam and could have burned indefinitely had it not been extinguished so soon.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881008-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-08-88 0030EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--WaywardWarbler     10-08 0152</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Wayward Warbler,0155</SECOND>
<HEAD>Birds Of A Feather Get Lost Together</HEAD>
<DATELINE>FAIR ISLE, Scotland (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A windswept and probably weary Blackburnian warbler has been spotted on a Scottish island, the first recorded sighting of the tiny American bird in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, a wildlife warden says. The bird flew 3,000 miles across the <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ocean </LOCATION>, apparently swept off course by westerly gales while migrating to <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> for the winter, said <PERSON> Nick </PERSON> <PERSON> Riddiford </PERSON>, a warden at the Fair Isle Bird Observatory. It was found recently on <LOCATION> Fair </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Isle </LOCATION>, midway between the islands of <LOCATION> Orkney </LOCATION> and Shetland north of the Scottish mainland, he said. Another trans-Atlantic traveler, a northern oriole, arrived in the southwest English county of <LOCATION> Cornwall </LOCATION> Tuesday and an American robin has been spotted on the Isle of <PERSON> Wight </PERSON>, off the southern coast of <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>. Much of <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> has been swept by high winds blowing in from the <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> in recent days.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881008-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-08-88 0031EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Candidates-Speech     10-08 0595</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Candidates-Speech,610</SECOND>
<HEAD>Speech Coach Says Both Candidates Have Improved Their Oratory</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LISA WOLFSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BEVERLY HILLS, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 `` There is no index of character so sure as the voice,'' British statesman and orator <PERSON> Benjamin </PERSON> <PERSON> Disraeli </PERSON> once said. If <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> presidential candidates were judged by that standard alone, neither Republican <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> nor Democrat <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> would have a chance of winning the election, in the view of speech pathologist <PERSON> Lillian </PERSON> <PERSON> Glass </PERSON>. `` It's about time the candidates begin to work with consultants,'' she said. `` They have to realize, we do n't live in a democracy in terms of appearance.'' Politicians often are judged by how they look and sound, not by their policies, she said. Ms. Glass, 34, the author of `` Talk to Win: Six Steps to a Successful Vocal Image,'' has been analyzing the voices of <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> since the early stages of their campaigns. Prior to the Republican National Convention last July, Ms. <PERSON> Glass </PERSON> said that <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s high-pitched, nasal voice negated his strong physical presence and made him appear `` wimpy.'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, she said, spoke in a monotone and was unemotional. `` An election can be lost solely on how you sound,'' Ms. <PERSON> Glass </PERSON> said. Both candidates, however, demonstrated a vastly improved speaking style during their first debate on Sept. 25, she said. `` <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> is not perfect ... but he's lost the wimp factor,'' Ms. <PERSON> Glass </PERSON> said after the debate, noting his slower, more methodical approach, lower-pitch and stronger inflection. The changes in the vice president, for the most part, are being attributed to the coaching of <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> Ailes </PERSON>, a former <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> television producer who serves as the campaign's senior media advisor in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Ailes </PERSON> denied molding <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s image. He said any changes are in the eyes of the public. `` People are starting to view him as a president and not as -LRB- President -RRB- <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s assistant,'' he said. `` I mean the man is the vice president of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. You do n't get there because three months ago you decided to do something about your voice.'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> has a lot of potential as an orator but has not yet mastered a presidential style, Ms. <PERSON> Glass </PERSON> said. `` He did n't go up as much at the end of sentences like he used to,'' she said after the Sept. 25 debate. `` He had better diction and less staccato in his voice.'' As for the diction of the vice presidential candidates, there is no comparison, said Ms. Glass. `` <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' best asset is <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>,'' she said. `` He blows everybody away with his beautiful projection, posture and good inflection. His security and warmth come across.'' The <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> senator has a take-charge persona that <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> can learn from, Ms. <PERSON> Glass </PERSON> said. <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION> Sen. <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>, on the other hand, comes across unsophisticated and `` twice as wimpy'' as <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> ever did, the speech therapist said. `` He's a good-looking man with a high, nasal voice and that does n't reflect a lot of self-confidence.'' `` <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> looks like a star and is beginning to sound more like a star,'' she said. `` If he had a star running mate, it would certainly help the ticket be more powerful.'' Ms. <PERSON> Glass </PERSON> said all the candidates should use <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> as a role model. `` Whether you agree with his politics or not, you feel his compassion and dedication to the country,'' she said. `` He has a very calming effect.'' What makes <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> so good? `` His excellent posture, his body movement, how he uses the camera,'' Ms. <PERSON> Glass </PERSON> said. `` It's his friend. When he's angry, you see it. When he's up, it's reflected in his voice.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881008-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-08-88 0036EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF-NukeSquad     10-08 0161</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF-Nuke Squad,0166</SECOND>
<HEAD>Official: Secret Plans In Place to Protect Nukes From Terrorists</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BONN, West Germany (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> has confidential agreements with its <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> allies on ways to protect nuclear weapons from terrorist attacks or theft, an <ORGANIZATION> Interior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> spokesman says. But the spokesman, <PERSON> Roland </PERSON> <PERSON> Bachmeier </PERSON>, refused to confirm reports that members of a special <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> anti-terrorist team were stationed in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>. `` I am not prepared to discuss details,'' <PERSON> Bachmeier </PERSON> told reporters Friday at a press conference. He said plans to protect nuclear weapons against terrorist attempts to seize them were part of `` secret agreements.'' Reports of the presence of the special team, called the <ORGANIZATION> Nuclear </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Emergency </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Search </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Team </ORGANIZATION>, surfaced during recent government hearings on a scandal-plagued nuclear waste transport company. <PERSON> Ingrid </PERSON> <PERSON> Matthaeus-Maier </PERSON>, who chairs the parliamentary investigative committee, said that the panel had come across indications of the team's presence in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> `` by pure chance'' as it sifted through documents. No other details were released.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881008-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-08-88 0008EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Nicaragua-LaPrensa     10-08 0366</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Nicaragua-La Prensa,0374</SECOND>
<HEAD>La Prensa Publishes Government Warning</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RODOLFO GARCIA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MANAGUA, Nicaragua (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>'s only opposition newspaper, <PERSON> La </PERSON> <PERSON> Prensa </PERSON>, published a government notice in its Friday editions that condemned what it called the newspaper's `` defamatory'' reporting of the shootings of three labor activists. The <ORGANIZATION> Interior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> notice criticized a <ORGANIZATION> La </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Prensa </ORGANIZATION> editorial Thursday that accompanied the texts of two government protests of the newspaper's reporting of the Sunday shootings. <PERSON> La </PERSON> <PERSON> Prensa </PERSON> printed the protests under government order. Friday's notice, was an `` admonition.'' Under a new emergency law approved by the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION> on Wednesday, the president can shut down print and broadcast media for `` the maintenance of public order,'' but <PERSON> La </PERSON> <PERSON> Prensa </PERSON> was not ordered to close. The ministry notice said <ORGANIZATION> La </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Prensa </ORGANIZATION> `` insists in its defamatory campaign of portraying the government of <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> as responsible for criminal events.'' It accused <PERSON> La </PERSON> <PERSON> Prensa </PERSON> of depicting the government as generating `` a climate of threats against all persons and organizations that say something against the Sandinista party.'' In its Thursday editorial titled, `` An unjust order without right and without reason,'' <PERSON> La </PERSON> <PERSON> Prensa </PERSON> said the government protests were `` two precipitous documents ... that, lamentably, once again incorrectly cite the country's laws and once again display an ignorance of the legal norms that apply to the exercise of freedom of expression in <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>.'' <PERSON> La </PERSON> <PERSON> Prensa </PERSON> also said that `` it is obvious that in recent days, gangs of uniformed men with weapons only the army has have committed brutal crimes that, inevitably, show common or similar elements.'' On Tuesday, <ORGANIZATION> La </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Prensa </ORGANIZATION> reported three activists with the <ORGANIZATION> Confederation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Trade </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Unity </ORGANIZATION> were fatally shot Sunday by three men wearing Sandinista army uniforms in <LOCATION> Leon </LOCATION>, about 45 miles west of <LOCATION> Managua </LOCATION>. The report said the assailants used Soviet-made AK-47 rifles, standard issue in the Sandinista army. <PERSON> La </PERSON> <PERSON> Prensa </PERSON> identified the slain activists as <PERSON> Fernando </PERSON> <PERSON> Torres </PERSON>, <PERSON> Alejandro </PERSON> <PERSON> Peralta </PERSON> and <PERSON> Norberto </PERSON> <PERSON> Espinoza </PERSON>. It attributed its information to <PERSON> Alvin </PERSON> <PERSON> Guthrie </PERSON> <PERSON> Rivers </PERSON>, secretary-general of the anti-government confederation. On Wednesday, the <ORGANIZATION> Interior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> said <PERSON> Espinoza </PERSON> was a Sandinista army first lieutenant and that <PERSON> Torres </PERSON> was a former member of the <ORGANIZATION> Sandinista </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION>. It described Sunday's episode as a common crime.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881008-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-08-88 0054EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--ChinaTV     10-08 0151</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--China TV,0153</SECOND>
<HEAD>China Has 600 Million Television Watchers</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Once the world's largest untapped source of television viewers, <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> now boasts nearly 60 percent viewership among its 1.08 billion people. National radio and television officials reported at a seminar this week in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> that 600 million Chinese watch television daily, the official <ORGANIZATION> China </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> said today. <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> now has 116 million television sets, 37 times more than a decade ago, with an average of one set for every 10 people. The national and international news program broadcast by <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> Central Television Station now reaches 42 percent of the population each evening, the paper said. The country's 118 television assembly lines have a combined annual production of 15 million. But demand for televisions, particularly color sets, far outstrips supply, <ORGANIZATION> Xinhua </ORGANIZATION> said. Figures were not available for the number of sets imported annually, but Japanese brands are very popular.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881008-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-08-88 0102EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-OceanSludge     10-08 0254</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Ocean Sludge,250</SECOND>
<HEAD>Congress Expected To Act On Sludge-Dumping Ban</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> is expected to vote next week on compromise legislation to ban disposal of sewage sludge in the ocean by the nation's only remaining ocean dumpers. The new agreement, struck Friday by <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> conferees, sets a Dec. 31, 1991, deadline for dumping in the <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> by nine authorities in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION>. The legislation imposes stiff fines aimed at making the dumping exorbitantly expensive, and pools the fines to pay for alternatives. `` The agreement is tough but fair. Clearly the end of ocean dumping is in sight,'' said Rep. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Hughes </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.J. </LOCATION>, the prime <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> sponsor. `` This bill is a major step in cleaning up our oceans,'' added Rep. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Roe </PERSON>, D-N. The compromise reconciles differing sludge-dumping bills passed by the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> in August and by the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> earlier this week. <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> votes on the compromise are expected Wednesday. President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> is expected to sign the bill. Some 8 million tons of sludge a year are dumped by the nine agencies at a site about 106 miles east of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> closed a site just 12 miles offshore in 1987. Experts differ on the environmental threat posed by the dumping of sludge. The new bill requires dumpers to pay fees of $ 100 per ton of sludge beginning on Jan. 1 of next year. Any authority still dumping sludge in the ocean by 1993 would have to pay penalties in addition to the fees.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881008-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-08-88 0118EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Dukakis     10-08 0760</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Dukakis,750</SECOND>
<HEAD>Dukakis Strikes Theme of Economic Nationalism</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Top prospects uncertain.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By WILLIAM M. WELCH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BOSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> is hammering the Republicans on a theme of economic nationalism, saying <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> hung a `` do not disturb sign'' on his door while foreign competitors and investors battered and bought <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> industries. The Democratic presidential nominee was campaigning back in his native <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> today, visiting <ORGANIZATION> Bates </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Lewiston </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION>, on a sentimental stop at the place where his parents attended college only a few years after emigrating from <LOCATION> Greece </LOCATION>. The trip to <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION>, capping a campaign week highlighted by his running mate <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>'s debate with <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>, was bringing <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> to a small state but one the campaign hopes to carry on Nov. 8 _ despite <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s summer mansion on the coast at <LOCATION> Kennebunkport </LOCATION>. `` We want to carry all of <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s home states,'' quipped press secretary <PERSON> Dayton </PERSON> <PERSON> Duncan </PERSON> in a remark lampooning the vice president's loose ties to several states. The <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> governor returned to <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> late Friday after campaigning in <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>, assailing the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration's record on foreign trade and <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>'s debate remark praising foreign investment in <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> companies for creating jobs. But the campaign was embarrassed to learn that the <ORGANIZATION> Moog </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Automotive </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Wellston </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mo. </LOCATION>, where <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> delivered a speech blasting the Republicans on the foreign investment issue, was actually owned by an Italian auto-making conglomerate through a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> holding company. And the company was bought out 11 years ago, during a Democratic administration. <PERSON> Duncan </PERSON> said some in the campaign knew of its ownership, but top campaign officials did not know and neither did Rep. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Mo </LOCATION>., who accompanied <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> to the plant <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>'s blasts at foreign ownership set off murmers among workers at the plant, and aides acknowledged <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> was unaware of the ownership when he praised the company and its workers as `` survivors'' in the fight for American businesses and products `` If anyone asks you what's at stake in this election, just remind them of that moment in the debate Wednesday night when <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> said he's happy that foreign owners are buying up <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> said. `` Maybe the Republican ticket wants our children to work for foreign owners, pay rent to foreign owners, and owe their future to foreign owners, but that's not the kind of future <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> and I and <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> and all of you want for <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>,'' he said. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> `` has spent the last eight years with a ` do not disturb' sign hanging on his office door,'' ignoring the trade issue. He said the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> enjoyed a trade surplus of $ 7 billion in 1981, when the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration took over, and that by 1987 the nation suffered a trade deficit of $ 154 billion. In the debate, <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> said: `` I would rather have people come over here and to make investments in this country, rather than going elsewhere. Because by coming over here, and making investments in this country, we are seeing jobs.'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> borrowed some of the rhetoric of former rivals <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> from the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> primaries as he lamented the decline of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> as the leading manufacturer of consumer electronics such as color televisons, video cassette recorders and telephones. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> and <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> are calling for a new trade policy that they say will require reciprocity, or prohibiting foreign companies from flooding the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> with products when <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> manufacturers are locked out of those countries. They also support limited restrictions on imports of some foreign products, including textiles, so long as <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> companies respond by modernizing to become competitive. Before heading home, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> stopped in <LOCATION> Ashville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.C. </LOCATION>, and spoke to a crowd of 2,000 people jammed around the home of the late author <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Wolfe </PERSON>. Now restored, the two-story white frame house with stained glass windows, which was <PERSON> Wolfe </PERSON>'s mother's boarding house that he recalled in the book `` Look Homeward Angel,'' served as <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' backdrop and he recalled traveling to <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> in 1960, fresh out of law school, just to visit the house. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> cited a Wolfe quotation that approximated the candidate's own often-repeated theme _ that `` the best <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> is yet to come'' _ and declared the two debates between the Democratic and Republican tickets have changed the complexion of the race. `` I think some things happened on that stage, and some things happened around the country ... that have made this a brand new campaign,'' he said. `` We're starting to move folks. You can feel it.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881008-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-08-88 0121EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Norelco-Filter     10-08 0312</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Norelco-Filter,0319</SECOND>
<HEAD>Water Purifier Added Chemical As it Filtered, FTC Judge Says</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An administrative judge has ruled that a company falsely advertised a water purifying device by failing to disclose it added a probable carcinogen to the water it filtered, a newspaper reported today. Last month's ruling by <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Timothy </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Trade </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> said <ORGANIZATION> North </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Philips </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> showed `` utter disregard for the welfare of its consumers and blatant disregard for the law'' in marketing its <ORGANIZATION> Norelco </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Clean </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Water </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Machine </ORGANIZATION>, according to <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> FTC </ORGANIZATION> had filed an administrative complaint against the company in August 1987. The complaint said that while ads for the machine claimed the product made tap water clean or cleaner, they failed to disclose that filters formerly used in the product actually added a potentially hazardous chemical to the water. The filters, which the company recalled in 1986, added the chemical methylene chloride to the water that passed through them, the complaint said. The chemical, used as a solvent in glues, paints and other substances, has been shown to cause cancer in laboratory animals, according to the <ORGANIZATION> Consumer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Product </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION>. The company sold 186,000 of the filters between 1982 and the start of the recall in 1986, the Times reported. The company said distributing the tainted filters was a management mistake, and that it would not appeal the judge's decision, which would become final after review by the five-member commission, according to the newspaper `` We have never had that kind of accident in our 50 years of business in <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, and we feel it has reflected too negatively on our corporation,'' said <PERSON> Winfried </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> va n't <PERSON> Hoff </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Norelco </ORGANIZATION> executive vice president. `` Many of the people involved with this thing are no longer with the company,'' said <PERSON> Samuel </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Rozen </PERSON>, the company's general counsel.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881008-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-08-88 0140EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-MedicalWaste     10-08 0402</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Medical Waste,360</SECOND>
<HEAD>Senate Approves Medical Waste Bill, Sends It Back to House</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Legislation to combat midnight dumping of medical wastes has won <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> approval and now goes back to the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> for further action next week. The bill, which was passed in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> by voice vote Friday night, sets up a system to track infectious waste like that which fouled <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> beaches last summer. The <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> approved a similar bill on Thursday, but now the two pieces of legislation must be reconciled before moving toward final congressional approval. `` Spending a day at the beach should n't have to be followed by a day at the doctor,'' said Sen. <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Lautenberg </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.J. </LOCATION>, a sponsor of the bill. <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> approval came after several minor changes were made in a version that had been passed by the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, requiring it to be reconsidered by the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> next week. The legislation was prompted by the waves of used syringes, vials of AIDS-infected blood and other hospital waste that washed up on beaches along the <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Coast </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Erie </LOCATION> during the summer. The waste became a health problem, closing some beaches because of the threat of hepatitis and other diseases. The bill would require the <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> to set up a system to track dangerous waste from hospitals, labs and clinics to its disposal. Initially, the program would cover just 10 states: <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION>. Later, the program could be made national in scope if other states petition to subject their medical waste to the same cradle-to-grave monitoring system for medical supplies. Included in the paper-trail tracking system would be blood, hypodermic needles, scalpels and surgical and laboratory waste that has been in contact with infectious agents. They would have to be segregated from other medical waste and tracked to make sure they reached a proper disposal facility. The problem has received substantial publicity this year after fouled stretches of beach in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> were closed, ruining vacations and causing lost revenues for oceanside businesses and resorts. <PERSON> Lautenberg </PERSON> said the waste problem appears to be the result of illegal dumpers who `` threaten the well-being of their fellow citizens to save a few dollars in disposal costs.'' Lawmakers criticized the <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION>, which they said has had authority to regulate the wastes but has ignored the problem.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881008-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-08-88 0144EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     10-08 0710</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0738</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names In The News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PINEVILLE, N.C. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Aides to <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> and <PERSON> Tammy </PERSON> <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON> say the couple will continue to try to regain control of <ORGANIZATION> PTL </ORGANIZATION>, but they'll have to take aim at the television mininstry from a slightly greater distance Volunteers on Friday moved furniture into the new headquarters of <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> and <PERSON> Tammy </PERSON> <PERSON> Ministries </PERSON>, a house on a 300-acre <LOCATION> Pineville </LOCATION> estate owned by <PERSON> Dexter </PERSON> <PERSON> Yager </PERSON>, a regional <ORGANIZATION> Amway </ORGANIZATION> products distributor. The couple had been operating out of a storefront in a shopping center five miles to the south in <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mill </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> S.C. </LOCATION>, home of <ORGANIZATION> PTL </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Heritage </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> USA </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> theme park, but that office was leased to someone else, <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON> spokesman <PERSON> Hal </PERSON> <PERSON> Sweigart </PERSON> said PTL bankruptcy trust M.C. `` Red'' <PERSON> Benton </PERSON> announced earlier this week that he had accepted a $ 115 million offer for <ORGANIZATION> PTL </ORGANIZATION>'s assets from <LOCATION> Toronto </LOCATION> businessman <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> Mernick </PERSON>, but aides to the <ORGANIZATION> Bakkers </ORGANIZATION> say they have n't given up hope of regaining control of the ministry they founded. <PERSON> Mernick </PERSON>'s bid awaits a judge's approval. `` We consider the new office an interim step on the way back to <LOCATION> Heritage </LOCATION> <LOCATION> USA </LOCATION>,'' said <PERSON> Lin </PERSON> <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON>, a volunteer at <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> Tammy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministries </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON>'s $ 172 million offer to buy back <ORGANIZATION> PTL </ORGANIZATION> last month fell through when he could not prove he had financial backing. <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON> resigned from <ORGANIZATION> PTL </ORGANIZATION> in March 1987 after admitting a sexual encounter with church secretary <PERSON> Jessica </PERSON> <PERSON> Hahn </PERSON> seven years earlier. Three months after <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON> made his admission, the ministry filed for bankruptcy reorganization.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> Baryshnikov </PERSON> next year will make his stage debut in a drama, playing the lead in an adaptation of <PERSON> Franz </PERSON> <PERSON> Kafka </PERSON>'s existential masterpiece `` Metamorphosis.'' The dancer and artistic director of <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ballet </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Theater </ORGANIZATION> will portray a man who wakes to discover he has become a giant cockroach. The five-character, one-act play, adapted and directed by British-born playwright <PERSON> Steven </PERSON> <PERSON> Berkoff </PERSON>, was presented earlier this year in <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> with film director <PERSON> Roman </PERSON> <PERSON> Polanski </PERSON> playing the lead. The <PERSON> Baryshnikov </PERSON> version will begin rehearsals in January and play out of town before opening here in March, said <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Powers </PERSON>, a spokesman for the production.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>PROVIDENCE, R.I. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A <ORGANIZATION> Rhode </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Island </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Design </ORGANIZATION> instructor says the controversial book `` The Lives of <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Lennon </PERSON>'' accurately tells the story of his brief affair with <PERSON> Yoko </PERSON> <PERSON> Ono </PERSON>. The unauthorized biography by <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Goldman </PERSON> describes the former Beatle as an anorexic bisexual addled by drugs. It has been sharply criticized by <PERSON> Lennon </PERSON>'s widow and associates, with <PERSON> Ono </PERSON> calling it `` totally fiction.'' But <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> Wunderlich </PERSON>, associate professor of painting at <ORGANIZATION> RISD </ORGANIZATION>, said <PERSON> Goldman </PERSON> dealt truthfully with his small part in the story. `` He was quite thorough and professional when he interviewed me,'' <PERSON> Wunderlich </PERSON> said. `` He impressed me by knowing a lot of the details already _ it seemed like ancient history to me.'' <PERSON> Wunderlich </PERSON> was a friend of <PERSON> Ono </PERSON>'s second husband, <PERSON> Tony </PERSON> <PERSON> Cox </PERSON>, and joined <PERSON> Cox </PERSON> and <PERSON> Ono </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> for some avant-garde art happenings. <PERSON> Goldman </PERSON>'s book says that <PERSON> Wunderlich </PERSON> had a brief affair with <PERSON> Ono </PERSON>, believing that her relationship with <PERSON> Cox </PERSON> was over.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>CHICAGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Singer <PERSON> Whitney </PERSON> <PERSON> Houston </PERSON>, actress <PERSON> Delta </PERSON> <PERSON> Burke </PERSON> and actor <PERSON> Burt </PERSON> <PERSON> Reynolds </PERSON> have `` <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s greatest smiles,'' the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hygienists </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ' </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> says. The three celebrities were cited by the Chicago-based association as part of <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hygiene </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Week </ORGANIZATION>, Oct. 16-22. The group says that good oral hygiene habits and proper care by a dentist and hygienist are the keys to a healthy, attractive smile.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LINCOLN, Neb. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Orr </PERSON>, husband of Gov. <PERSON> Kay </PERSON> <PERSON> Orr </PERSON>, hopes that Governor's Loaf will help make the home life of the next <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION> governor a little more comfortable. A recipe for the meatloaf is among 200 that <PERSON> Orr </PERSON> will include in the `` First Gentleman's Cookbook'' he is writing. Profits from the book, which is scheduled to appear in February, will be used to redecorate the Governor's Mansion, he said Friday. Although the mansion has been adequately maintained, the decor of certain rooms in the second-floor living quarters has remained unchanged since the building was constructed 30 years ago, <PERSON> Orr </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Orr </PERSON> said his status as `` First Gentleman'' draws attention when he accompanies the Republican governor to national gatherings, and he said he hopes the book will capitalize on that fact.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881008-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-08-88 0146EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FDA-Toothpaste     10-08 0219</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-FDA-Toothpaste,190</SECOND>
<HEAD>FDA Cites Violations By Makers of Toothpaste, Mouthwash</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The government has accused six toothpaste and mouthwash producers of violating the law by claiming their products can prevent plaque or gum disease, according to a published report. In letters to the companies last July, the <ORGANIZATION> Food </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Drug </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> instructed them to stop making the claims or provide supporting evidence, <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> reported in today's editions The Post identified the companies and their products as: <ORGANIZATION> Warner-Lambert </ORGANIZATION>, Listerine mouthwash; <ORGANIZATION> Colgate-Palmolive </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Colgate </ORGANIZATION> toothpaste; <ORGANIZATION> Beecham </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Products </ORGANIZATION>, Aquafresh toothpaste; <ORGANIZATION> Vipont </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, Viadent oral rinse; <ORGANIZATION> Oral </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Laboratories </ORGANIZATION>, Plax dental rinse; and <ORGANIZATION> Rydelle-Lion </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, Checkup toothpaste. <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman <PERSON> Faye </PERSON> <PERSON> Peterson </PERSON> said other companies had agreed voluntarily to change their labeling. In its letters, the <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> said the companies had not submitted evidence proving that toothpaste or mouthwash is safe or effective for dealing with plaque or gingivitis. `` We are not aware of any evidence establishing that the product is generally recognized as safe and effective for gingivitis,'' the letters said. The <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> added that if no evidence was forthcoming, the product is considered as being `` marketed in violation of the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Food </ORGANIZATION>, Drug and Cosmetic Act and at risk of regulatory action.'' The letters were sent by <PERSON> Rudolf </PERSON> <PERSON> Apodaca </PERSON>, director of the division of labeling compliance at <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881008-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-08-88 0148EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Wallace-Westmoreland     10-08 0197</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Wallace-Westmoreland,0201</SECOND>
<HEAD>Wallace Says He Softened His Style After Libel Suit</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> correspondent <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Wallace </PERSON> says the `` sobering'' experience of the 18-week <PERSON> Westmoreland </PERSON> libel trial 3 -LCB- years ago led him to tone down his aggressive interviewing style. `` You learn how it feels to be the object of the press's scrutiny,'' <PERSON> Wallace </PERSON> said in an interview appearing in Sunday's Parade `` I learned how it must feel for someone I am covering to believe he is being treated unfairly. That gave me sobering second thoughts.'' Gen. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Westmoreland </PERSON> filed a $ 120 million libel suit against <PERSON> Wallace </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> for a 1982 `` 60 Minutes'' piece narrated by <PERSON> Wallace </PERSON> that claimed <PERSON> Westmoreland </PERSON> deceived the <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> public about enemy troop strength during the Vietnam War. <PERSON> Westmoreland </PERSON> dropped the charges in February 1985 before the case went to a jury. <PERSON> Wallace </PERSON> said he is less interested now in riling an interviewee to produce dramatic television. `` I used to say I was after light, not heat. But the fact remained that the heat, more than the light, generated the attention I got,'' <PERSON> Wallace </PERSON> said. `` Then you grow, you understand more. Over the years, light has taken precedence.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881008-0025 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-08-88 0150EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-TaxBill     10-08 0690</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Tax Bill,650</SECOND>
<HEAD>Land Battle Delays Action On Tax Benefits Package</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JIM LUTHER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Tax Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A catchall package of special tax benefits that has been two years in the making faces a new challenge because of efforts to protect the site of one of the Civil War's bloodiest battles. On a 50-25 vote Friday night, the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> attached to the tax bill an amendment by Sen. <PERSON> Dale </PERSON> <PERSON> Bumpers </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Ark </LOCATION>., that would seize 540 acres of land on which the Second Battle of <LOCATION> Manassas </LOCATION> was fought in 1862 The aim of the provision _ which the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> already has approved _ would be to block development of a shopping mall on the land. Interior Secretary <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Hodel </PERSON> has said he would recommend that President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> veto any legislation to which the amendment was attached. `` You are asking the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> to follow you in a <PERSON> Pickett </PERSON>'s charge to the president's veto pen,'' Sen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Warner </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Va </LOCATION>., told <PERSON> Bumpers </PERSON> But without his amendment <PERSON> Bumpers </PERSON> said, the promontory where Confederate Gen. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> had his headquarters during the battle will be paved over. `` And I can see a big granite statue in that mall -LRB- with the inscription -RRB-: ` General <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> stood on this spot,''' <PERSON> Bumpers </PERSON> said. In siding with <PERSON> Bumpers </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> turned down a substitute plan by <ORGANIZATION> Warner </ORGANIZATION>, which would have allowed the federal government to take 80 acres of the privately owned land and allow housing construction on adjacent areas. Debate over the Manassas amendments and several other non-tax proposals delayed final action on the bill, whose main purpose is to correct errors and clear up confusion arising from the big 1986 tax overhaul. The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Finance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> already has attached to the measure dozens of special tax benefits worth about $ 2.76 billion plus the assorted tax increases necessary to pay for them. The package includes a `` bill of rights'' for taxpayers involved in disputes with the <ORGANIZATION> Internal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Revenue </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>. The bill relieves farmers from the federal tax on diesel used for off-road purposes and from the `` heifer tax'' on livestock-production expenses. Other beneficiaries include free-lance artists, corporate investments in research, first-time homebuyers, contributors to college athletic funds, and workers who receive employer-financed legal or education aid. The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> has agreed to a final vote on the bill Tuesday night, but only after considering another two dozen amendments. Congressional leaders hope negotiators can then work out a compromise between the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> bill and the $ 7.5 billion version already approved by the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>. The tax bill is one of two major measures standing in the way of adjourning the 100th <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>; the other contains tools to fight drug abuse. For that reason, senators know that if they have any hope of getting a pet project approved in the closing days of the session, it will have to be tacked onto the tax bill. At nightfall Friday, more than 100 amendments were waiting to be considered, and Majority Leader <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON>, D-W. <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, was not `` This list is crazy, nuts and getting crazier all the time,'' <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON> said. `` We ought to settle down and get our senses.'' Within two hours, <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON> announced senators had agreed to drop all but 29. `` This is the typical tax bill,'' said Republican Leader <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION>. `` Everybody cleans out their desks and their trash cans and says ` we'll put it on the tax bill.' We've reached the point that if somebody does n't take the bull by the horns, we'll never finish. The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> rejected amendments calling for:
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 _ An end to what Sen. <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, D-Tenn., termed discrimination against owners of home satellite dishes by television His amendment, aimed at helping the 2 million dish owners, would have required that programs provided to cable systems be made available to dish owners. Opponents said the amendment was unnecessary. _ An 18-month study of whether government workers should get equal pay for jobs of comparable worth _ A symbolic endorsement of the right of the <LOCATION> District </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION> to finance abortions for poor women _ Raising from $ 17 a month to $ 38 the maximum tax-free mass-transit benefits that an employer could furnish workers
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881008-0026 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-08-88 0155EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-TearGasTycoon     10-08 0199</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Tear Gas Tycoon,0205</SECOND>
<HEAD>Tear Gas Magnate Had Highest Income; Dynamite King Was Third</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SEOUL, South Korea (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A woman who heads a tear gas company earned more money than anybody else in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> last year, the result of a surge in violent protests, tax officials said today. The <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tax </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> said in a report to the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION> that Mrs. <PERSON> Han </PERSON> <PERSON> Young-ja </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> Sam </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Young </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chemical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, earned $ 7.3 million last year and paid $ 3.4 million in income tax. Mrs. <PERSON> Han </PERSON>'s company holds a monopoly on the production of tear gas, a frequently used form of riot control in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>. The officials attributed <PERSON> Han </PERSON>'s high income to frequent demonstrations by radical students, striking factory workers and other anti-government groups. The nation's second highest income earner last year was <PERSON> Cho </PERSON> <PERSON> Joong-hoon </PERSON>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Hanjin </ORGANIZATION> group comprised of about two dozen subsidiaries including Korean Air, the South Korean flag carrier. Cho reported $ 6.3 million in personal income, the officials said. Coming in third was <PERSON> Kim </PERSON> <PERSON> Sung-hyun </PERSON>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Korea </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Explosives </ORGANIZATION> group, who reported an income of $ 4 million. The group's holding firm is <ORGANIZATION> Korea </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Explosives </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> which produces dynamite.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881008-0027 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-08-88 0150EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-PedestriansKilled 2ndLd-Writethru a0405 10-08 0348</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Pedestrians Killed, 2nd Ld - Writethru, a0405,0352</SECOND>
<HEAD>Five Girls Killed By Speeding Car</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: CORRECTS name to Weitzel sted Weitezel throughout.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>PULASKI, Wis. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A speeding car hit a utility pole Friday night and careened into a group of five girls on a sidewalk, killing all of them, authorities said. The car hit a tree after striking the girls, said <LOCATION> Brown </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> Sheriff's Lt. <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Weitzel </PERSON>. He said the driver of the car, who a school principal said was a teen-ager, and his sister were taken to hospitals and were believed to be in serious condition. Four of the girls were dead at the scene and a fifth was pronounced dead at a hospital, <PERSON> Weitzel </PERSON> said. All were elementary school students and believed to be between ages 12 and 14. The accident occurred at 6:49 p.m. in <LOCATION> Pulaski </LOCATION>, a village of 1,875 located about 15 miles northwest of <LOCATION> Green </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION> in northeastern <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION>. `` The entire community is in a state of shock,'' said <ORGANIZATION> Pulaksi </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> High </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> Principal Guy <PERSON> David </PERSON>. He said the driver of the car was a 16-year-old student at the high school. The victims' identities were not immediately available pending notification of relatives. `` We heard they -LRB- the girls -RRB- were coming from a birthday party or slumber party, either coming or going. All were on the sidewalk when it happened,'' <PERSON> Weitzel </PERSON> said. `` We got one vehicle with a brother and sister evidently driving at a high rate of speed. The vehicle hits a power pole, strikes five girls _ four dead at the scene and one dies at a hospital _ and then the car hit a tree,'' he said. <PERSON> David </PERSON> said the five girls were all students at <ORGANIZATION> Glenbrook </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Elementary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION>. The children were walking near the village post office and police station when they were struck, he said. `` This is going to be a real problem for the community to deal with. It will be very difficult,'' he said. `` In a small community like this, everybody knows everybody.'' Saturday's high school football game was canceled because of the tragedy, the principal said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881008-0028 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-08-88 0152EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Yugoslavia 1stLd-Writethru   10-08 0594</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Yugoslavia, 1st Ld - Writethru,a0446,0607</SECOND>
<HEAD>Protests Spread In Yugoslavia; Party Promises Changes</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: LEADS with three grafs to CORRECT spelling of Vojvodina in
3rd graf; picks up 4th pvs: More than...</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By DUSAN STOJANOVIC</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BELGRADE, Yugoslavia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Thousands of demonstrators nationwide marched on goverment buildings and demanded an overhaul in the communist hierarchy in a spreading wave of ethnic and economic unrest. <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> leaders, trying to control the strife, promised urgent personnel changes and economic reforms later this month. The protests Friday came just one day after 30,000 people surrounded a government building in the province of <LOCATION> Vojvodina </LOCATION>, battling police and eventually forcing the resignations of the 15-member provincial Politburo. More than 10,000 people, some chanting `` You betrayed us,'' staged a similar rally in <LOCATION> Titograd </LOCATION> on Friday in the republic of <LOCATION> Montenegro </LOCATION>, demanding the immediate ouster of the local communist party leadership. The rally in front of the Montenegrin <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION> building was triggered by a strike of about 1,000 construction firm workers who put down their tools earlier Friday to protest low wages and falling living standards, state-run media reports said. Several similar protests, triggered by the country's worst economic and social crisis in history, were staged Friday in eastern and southern parts of the country. Meanwhile, the ruling national <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> presidium issued a statement saying the policy-making <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> plenum to meet Oct. 17 `` will make necessary personnel changes in the presidium, which should contribute to the more efficient work of the organ.'' There have been increasing calls in <LOCATION> Yugoslavia </LOCATION> for top-level personnel changes as the unrest continues. The public protests stem from a general dissatisfaction with a crippled economy and long-simmering fueds between ethnic groups. Communist leaders have been blamed for failing to defuse tensions between the mostly Christian Slav minority and the largely Moslem ethnic <PERSON> Albanian </PERSON> majority in the southern <LOCATION> Kosovo </LOCATION> province _ a hotbed of unrest _ in the republic of <LOCATION> Serbia </LOCATION>. In <LOCATION> Belgrade </LOCATION>, 400 high school students from <LOCATION> Kosovo </LOCATION> marched Friday on the national <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION>, chanting that Serbs will never give up power in <LOCATION> Kosovo </LOCATION>, an autonomous province bordering <LOCATION> Albania </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Belgrade </LOCATION> radio reported. Serbs, who are mainly Christian, charge that persecution by <LOCATION> Kosovo </LOCATION>'s ethnic Albanians is forcing them to emigrate. Mostly Moslem ethnic Albanians make up 90 percent of the province's population In <LOCATION> Krusevac </LOCATION>, 90 miles south of <LOCATION> Belgrade </LOCATION>, several thousand workers demonstrated Friday to demand higher wages and the ouster of <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> leaders, the radio said. The presidium statement appealed for urgent changes in the country's political and economic system to help in resolving the current crisis, which includes growing labor unrest, a 217 percent annual inflation and a $ 21 billion foreign debt. In a recent interview, Yugoslav Premier <PERSON> Branko </PERSON> <PERSON> Mikulic </PERSON> said the country `` will introduce a completly new market-oriented economic system as of 1989.'' Currently, <LOCATION> Yugoslavia </LOCATION>'s economy is a mixture of Western-style free market system and Soviet-style central planning. Nearly 100 people, including 14 policemen, were injured in Thursday's rioting in <LOCATION> Vojvodina </LOCATION>, in the city of Novi Sad. Demonstrators hurled rocks and bottles at police. The protest eventually caused the mass resignation of the <LOCATION> Vojvodina </LOCATION> leadership, which was considered a major victory for the <LOCATION> Serbian </LOCATION> communist boss <PERSON> Slobodan </PERSON> <PERSON> Milosevic </PERSON>. <PERSON> Milosevic </PERSON>, hailed by his supporters as political heir to the late President <PERSON> Josip </PERSON> <PERSON> Broz </PERSON> <PERSON> Tito </PERSON>, has been demanding more central control for his republic over its two provinces, <LOCATION> Kosovo </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Vojvodina </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Kosovo </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Vojvodina </LOCATION> are the country's only two autonomous provinces. Thursday's shake-up in <LOCATION> Vojvodina </LOCATION> has prompted speculation that <LOCATION> Kosovo </LOCATION> party leaders could also be on their way out too.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881008-0029 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-08-88 0207EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-ChlorineLeak 2ndLd-Writethru a0439 10-08 0356</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Chlorine Leak, 2nd Ld - Writethru, a0439,0360</SECOND>
<HEAD>Pool Company Fire Forces Evacuations in Palm Springs</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: LEADS with 5 grafs to UPDATE with residents allowed to return
home. Picks up 5th graf pvs, `Chlorine, a common...'</NOTE>
<DATELINE>PALM SPRINGS, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A fire at a swimming pool company spewed a cloud of gas over this desert resort, forcing the evacuation of several hundred residents Friday evening and the closing of an airport, officials said. Thirteen people, including three firefighters, were treated by ambulance crews for breathing difficulties and burning eyes, but no serious injuries were reported, said city spokeswoman <PERSON> Ann </PERSON> <PERSON> Erdman </PERSON>. The gas, apparently a brew of pool cleaning and treatment chemicals, spewed from a warehouse during a fire that broke out about 5:30 p.m., Ms. <PERSON> Erdman </PERSON> said. Shortly before 10 p.m., the cloud dissipated, residents were allowed to return home and the airport was reopened, Ms. <PERSON> Erdman </PERSON> said. There was no immediate determination of the cause of the fire at <ORGANIZATION> Ocean </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pool </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mart </ORGANIZATION>, or a complete analysis of the chemical released, she said. Chlorine, a common pool chemical, is hazardous, and other chemicals used in pools include acids. The cloud spread over a neighborhood of upper-middle-class homes and people were evacuated from an area about one-half mile square, she said. `` It's smack in the middle of <LOCATION> Palm </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Springs </LOCATION>,'' Ms. <PERSON> Erdman </PERSON> said, adding that the evacuated area included homes and a few businesses, but none of the city's hotels. Officials were n't immediately able to determine what gases were in the cloud or the danger posed by the gas, which Ms. <PERSON> Erdman </PERSON> described as having a stinging, acidic taste. No estimate of the number of evacuees was immediately available, but they probably numbered in the hundreds, the spokeswoman said. Commercial flights and private jets en route to <LOCATION> Palm </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Springs </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Regional </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION> were diverted to <LOCATION> Ontario </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION>, about 50 miles to the west. Outgoing flights were canceled and the airport was evacuated, Ms. <PERSON> Erdman </PERSON> said. <LOCATION> Palm </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Springs </LOCATION> is about 110 miles east of <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>. As darkness fell, the cloud appeared to be dispersing and drifting east, toward the communities of <LOCATION> Cathedral </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> and Rancho Mirage.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881008-0030 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-08-88 0215EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Hirohito     10-08 0265</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Hirohito,0275</SECOND>
<HEAD>Ailing Emperor Would Object to Cancellations, His Son Says</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARI YAMAGUCHI</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The son of Emperor <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON> discouraged people today from canceling public events in deference to his ailing father, news reports said. `` We appreciate the people's warm consideration very much, but if it affects their daily lives, I'm afraid it would not make the emperor happy,'' Crown Prince <PERSON> Akhito </PERSON> was quoted as saying. <PERSON> Akihito </PERSON>'s remarks, quoted by the domestic <ORGANIZATION> Kyodo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>, underscored the worry of many Japanese over the proper way to act during their monarch's illness. <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON>, the world's longest reigning monarch, has been bedridden since Sept. 19, when he vomited blood from intestinal homorrhaging. Domestic news media have said he has cancer, but officials have declined to comment on the reports. The 87-year-old monarch remained in stable condition today, officials at the Imperial Palace said. His temperature fell to 98 degrees from 99.5 the previous night, and a new antibiotic to treat his inflamed bile duct was apparently working, they said. His normal temperature is said to be about 96, but today's reading was the lowest since last weekend Scores of festivals, events and even official state visits by foreign dignitaries have been canceled since he fell ill. A government spokesman said earlier that the wave of cancellations would disappoint <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON> and could hurt social and economic activity Palace officials have not said exactly what <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON> knows about how Japanese are reacting to his illness. <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON>, who has reigned since 1926, remains a symbol of the Japanese state with only ceremonial duties.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881008-0031 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-08-88 0226EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Chile Bjt   10-08 0618</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Chile, Bjt,0636</SECOND>
<HEAD>Street Clashes Mar Rally to Celebrate Pinochet Setback</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto SCL1</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ED McCULLOUGH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SANTIAGO, Chile (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Nearly 350,000 Chileans took to the streets in a joyous rally to celebrate President <PERSON> Augusto </PERSON> <PERSON> Pinochet </PERSON>'s defeat in a referendum, but at least 40 people were injured in violent clashes with police Half a dozen people lay on the street behind <LOCATION> Santiago </LOCATION>'s national palace Friday evening after police fired tear gas and water cannons at a crowd of several hundred anti-government demonstrators and then charged, nightsticks swinging. The demonstrators had come from the peaceful rally at an outdoor park, where the crowd estimated by police at 350,000 swayed and sang to popular Chilean music. About 18 foreign reporters also were injured Friday in the demonstration at the national palace and other incidents, which they described as unprovoked attacks by police. At least six were treated at clinics for head injuries. Earlier Friday, soldiers at an army barracks near the rally site fired birdshot and pellets at passengers in cars who flashed the victory sign at them, <ORGANIZATION> Radio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cooperativa </ORGANIZATION> reported. Fifteen people were injured, including one who underwent surgery to remove a pellet from his head, the radio said. A spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> Santiago </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Emergency </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION> told The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> that nine people were treated there for gunshot wounds, and a tenth was taken to a neurological hospital for surgery. A spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION> said there was no one available to comment on the incidents. Friday's rally was organized by the opposition political groups that urged Chileans to vote `` no'' in Wednesday's referendum in which <PERSON> Pinochet </PERSON>, 72, lost his bid to remain president until 1997. His defeat sets the stage for presidential elections in December 1989 and the inauguration in March 1990 of the first freely elected president since <PERSON> Pinochet </PERSON>, commander of the army, toppled <PERSON> Salvador </PERSON> <PERSON> Allende </PERSON> in a bloody coup in 1973. Opposition leaders want <PERSON> Pinochet </PERSON> to move up the date of next year's elections, and vowed Friday to press that demand even though the aging commander-in-chief firmly rejected it Thursday during a speech broadcast nationwide. `` If we -LRB- opposition groups -RRB- join together with more force, I think the situation will change,'' said moderate Socialist <PERSON> Ricardo </PERSON> <PERSON> Lagos </PERSON>, a leader of the 16-group opposition coalition. `` You have to give the defeated a couple of days to recover from the shock.'' Many of the 3.8 million Chileans who voted against <PERSON> Pinochet </PERSON> also want early elections. `` <PERSON> Chi </PERSON> <PERSON> Chi </PERSON> <PERSON> Chi </PERSON>. <PERSON> Le </PERSON> <PERSON> Le </PERSON> <PERSON> Le </PERSON>. Get Out <PERSON> Pinochet </PERSON>,'' chanted the crowd at the rally. Funerals for two people killed during anti-government demonstrations Thursday night were set for today. Police acknowleged they shot a 31-year-old man and said a 14-year-old boy was shot by an unidentified gunman, police said. Two others who were shot by unidentified gunmen was hospitalized in serious condition Friday, police said, adding that eight officers were injured in clashes with demonstrators Thursday. Dozens of people were arrested Thursday and Friday. Most were released after brief detentions. Among the foreign journalists injured were <PERSON> Christopher </PERSON> <PERSON> Morris </PERSON>, an American freelance photographer for <ORGANIZATION> Newsweek </ORGANIZATION>, and <PERSON> Liliana </PERSON> <PERSON> Nieto </PERSON>, an <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> photographer for the <LOCATION> Long </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION> daily <ORGANIZATION> Newsday </ORGANIZATION>. They and at least three others were treated at <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Maria </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Clinica </LOCATION> for head injuries. A group of about 50 foreign journalists, mostly Latin American, walked to a <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION> station and filed a complaint protesting `` the lamentable events against the dignity of reporters ... by national police and other security forces'' and asked for guarantees of their safety. <PERSON> Eva </PERSON> <PERSON> Miranda </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Argentina </LOCATION>, a spokeswoman for the journalists, said two reporters _ <PERSON> Eduardo </PERSON> <PERSON> Sanjuan </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jordy </PERSON> <PERSON> Villaroel </PERSON> from TV-3 in <LOCATION> Barcelona </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION> _ were hospitalized Friday after they were beaten by police.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881008-0032 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-08-88 0242EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lites     10-08 0439</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lites,0456</SECOND>
<HEAD>On The Light Side</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CRAB ORCHARD, Tenn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
