<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880831-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-31-88 2333EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-OilTankerExplosion     08-31 0237</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Oil Tanker Explosion,0243</SECOND>
<HEAD>Blast On Tanker Knocks Workers Into Long Island Sound</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NORTHPORT, N.Y. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An explosion on an oil tanker docked at a loading platform in the <LOCATION> Long </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> Sound Wednesday night knocked several people into the water, authorities said, and at least one person was missing. The blast shook the area and could be heard for miles around at about 10 p.m. `` I've never experienced an earthquake but it must be something like this,'' police Sgt. <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON> <PERSON> Iannone </PERSON> said. `` We've had several residents report that their windows were blown out.'' The Coast Guard was searching the water for a missing person, Chief Warrant Officer <PERSON> Myron </PERSON> <PERSON> Verville </PERSON> said. He said he was unaware of any injuries. The tanker, the <PERSON> Fiona </PERSON>, was unloading oil, which is then piped to the <LOCATION> Northport </LOCATION> plant of the <ORGANIZATION> Long </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Island </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lighting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, said <PERSON> Gene </PERSON> <PERSON> Geisinger </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Northport </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fire </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>. The platform is located about 2 miles north of the plant in the Sound, he said. `` We have reports of people in the water and scuba divers are out there trying to find them,'' <PERSON> Geisinger </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Geisinger </PERSON> and county police said the explosion did not start a fire. But it could be felt more than 10 miles away, said <LOCATION> Suffolk </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> Police Officer <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Droscoski </PERSON>. <PERSON> Ray </PERSON> <PERSON> Golden </PERSON>, a spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> Long </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Island </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lighting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, said he had received reports of the explosion but did not have details.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880831-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-31-88 2345EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-PreschoolMolest 1stLd-Writethru a0779 08-31 0639</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Preschool Molest, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0779,0655</SECOND>
<HEAD>Key Witness in Molestation Trial Admits Romance With Reporter
Covering Story</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Leads with 10 grafs to UPDATE with judge ruling jury should
not hear about romance, picking up 9th graf pvs, `He also ....'</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By LINDA DEUTSCH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The jury in the McMartin Pre-School molestation trial may not hear about a romance between a social worker who gathered evidence from children in the case and a newscaster who covered the story, a judge ruled Wednesday. Superior Court Judge <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Pounders </PERSON> said the defense had not shown that it was relevant to the trial. The defense had suggested that <PERSON> Wayne </PERSON> <PERSON> Satz </PERSON>, a former <ORGANIZATION> KABC </ORGANIZATION> reporter, influenced the interviews that <PERSON> Kee </PERSON> <PERSON> MacFarlane </PERSON> conducted with children from the preschool as part of her job at Children's <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> The attorneys also argued that her credibility might be damaged if jurors knew about the relationship. `` I do n't see from what's been presented that there's a substantial issue for the jury,'' <PERSON> Pounders </PERSON> said after hearing Ms. <PERSON> MacFarlane </PERSON> testify about the relationship outside the presence of the jury. Ms. <PERSON> MacFarlane </PERSON>, whose testimony in pretrial hearings concerned her use of games and picture coloring to get children to talk of the alleged abuse, told the judge that her romance with <PERSON> Satz </PERSON> began after the interviews were completed. <PERSON> Raymond </PERSON> <PERSON> Buckey </PERSON>, 30, and his mother, <PERSON> Peggy </PERSON> <PERSON> McMartin </PERSON> <PERSON> Buckey </PERSON>, 61, are on trial on 100 molestation and conspiracy charges linked to their now defunct <ORGANIZATION> McMartin </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pre-School </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION>. The case has been in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> courts for five years. `` We're not trying to demonstrate that <PERSON> Wayne </PERSON> <PERSON> Satz </PERSON> obtained information from <PERSON> Kee </PERSON> <PERSON> MacFarlane </PERSON> to enhance his career,'' said defense attorney Dean Gits. `` What we're trying to show is that <PERSON> Kee </PERSON> <PERSON> MacFarlane </PERSON> had a relationship with <PERSON> Wayne </PERSON> <PERSON> Satz </PERSON> to enhance her career.'' Ms. <PERSON> MacFarlane </PERSON> has denied being a source for <PERSON> Satz </PERSON>'s stories broadcast on <ORGANIZATION> KABC-TV </ORGANIZATION> on the <PERSON> McMartin </PERSON> case, although she acknowledged Wednesday that they discussed it at the time. <PERSON> Satz </PERSON>, who is no longer with the television station, sat in the courtroom while Ms. <PERSON> MacFarlane </PERSON> was questioned. But <PERSON> Pounders </PERSON> ruled he was protected from testifying by <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>'s news reporter shield law. <PERSON> Pounders </PERSON> said that although `` the relationship has an impact on the case,'' he would allow only general testimony about the affair during Wednesday's hearing and no exploration of minute details, which he said would be prejudicial and might violate Ms. <PERSON> MacFarlane </PERSON>'s privacy rights. He also limited testimony to late 1983 to March 1984, when Ms. <PERSON> MacFarlane </PERSON> ended her interviews with children and indictments were issued. He is previewing the testimony before jurors hear it. Ms. <PERSON> MacFarlane </PERSON> said they met when <PERSON> Satz </PERSON> came to interview her for a general story on child molestations. In late 1983, before stories about the case broke, Ms. <PERSON> MacFarlane </PERSON> said she received a phone message from <PERSON> Satz </PERSON> saying he wanted to discuss <PERSON> Raymond </PERSON> <PERSON> Buckey </PERSON>, who would later become a defendant. She said she turned to a co-worker, <PERSON> Sandra </PERSON> <PERSON> Krebbs </PERSON>, and said, `` My God, <PERSON> Sandy </PERSON>, he's gotten wind of the case.'' `` He knew a lot of things about this case,'' she said. `` Some of them were things I knew. Some were things I did n't know.'' At another point she said, `` I remember being shocked at what kind of information he had. It was startling to me. He seemed to know everything.'' `` Did you ever become boyfriend and girlfriend with <PERSON> Wayne </PERSON> <PERSON> Satz </PERSON>?'' Gits asked Ms. <PERSON> MacFarlane </PERSON>. `` Yes,'' she answered after a brief pause. `` When, in your best estimation, did that happen?'' he asked. `` It was after March 1984,'' she said, but added she could not be sure because `` relationships evolve over time.'' Ms. <PERSON> MacFarlane </PERSON> did not say when the relationship ended. She has since married someone else. <PERSON> Satz </PERSON> was fired by <ORGANIZATION> KABC-TV </ORGANIZATION> last year in a dispute unrelated to the <PERSON> McMartin </PERSON> case.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880831-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-31-88 0007EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-APArts:Santana     08-31 0697</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AP Arts: Santana,0712</SECOND>
<HEAD>Santana Strikes Chord in Musical Scene after Two Decades</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By ANTHONY MARQUEZ</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SAN FRANCISCO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 When jazz great <PERSON> Miles </PERSON> <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> recently praised the originality of <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Santana </PERSON>, the low-key musician expressed satisfaction that he still strikes a singular chord on the musical scene after two decades. `` For Miles to tell me this, hey, that's a great compliment, but it shows that I'm not on stagnant water,'' said <PERSON> Santana </PERSON>, who's admired for his stirring guitar solos `` Stagnant water stinks. You need water to go out, you need water to come in _ all the time. And in order to do it, you have to become a student. Once you have a master's and you know everything, it's a drag.'' To keep his music flowing, <PERSON> Santana </PERSON> will release a three-record LP early next month and has launched a tour that reunites <PERSON> Gregg </PERSON> <PERSON> Rolie </PERSON>, <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> `` Chepito'' Areas and <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Shrieve </PERSON>, three original members of the band that evolved during jam sessions in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION>'s heavily Hispanic Mission District. The <ORGANIZATION> Santana </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Blues </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Band </ORGANIZATION> made its debut in 1968 at the Fillmore West where <PERSON> Santana </PERSON> recently held court at a small side table overlooking busy <PERSON> Geary </PERSON> <PERSON> Street </PERSON>, talking about his new album, the feelings behind his music and the popularity of Latin-rhythm groups. The Mexican-born <PERSON> Santana </PERSON> arrived in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> in 1961, entering the national spotlight with a show-stopping performance at <LOCATION> Woodstock </LOCATION> in 1969. He has gone on to earn 14 gold albums, nine platinum albums and sell more than 25 million records worldwide. Despite a pocketful of popular hits _ including `` Evil Ways,'' `` Black Magic Woman,'' `` Oye Como Va,'' `` Soul Sacrifice'' and `` Europa'' _ the 41-year-old <PERSON> Santana </PERSON> has continued experimenting. The new anthology, including some unreleased cuts, serves to `` give a testimony of the things we have become and lived.'' `` We're looking to take the music further. I mean, play the music and respect it for the way you play it, but also embrace the future and take some new chances,'' said the slender, mustachioed <PERSON> Santana </PERSON>. `` We want to serve the people with our music,'' he said. `` Music is a healing force if played correctly. I really believe that, aside from being the universal language, it's a healing force and reminds us that we have more things in common than we think.'' For <PERSON> Santana </PERSON>, who began playing guitar at age 8, music has never been a strictly commercial endeavor. `` Music is not to make a living,'' he said. `` Music is to help the conditioning of life. People play for many different reasons and all of them according to their heart's capacity. My capacity tells me that I can do a great service by doing music correctly. People know when you're playing something from your heart and when you're just giving lip service.'' Before <PERSON> Gloria </PERSON> <PERSON> Estefan </PERSON> and the <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> Sound Machine began doing the `` Conga'' and <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lobos </LOCATION> started playing `` Tex-Mex,'' <PERSON> Santana </PERSON> was infusing his music with the `` Latin rhythm.'' In past cuts such as `` Samba Pa Ti,'' `` Oye Como Va'' and `` Black Magic Woman,'' <PERSON> Santana </PERSON> showcased `` salsa'' when it was still considered something to add to Mexican dishes. Still, most of the recent publicity surrounding Hispanic-theme movies _ `` <LOCATION> La </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bamba </LOCATION>,'' `` Stand and Deliver'' and `` Milagro Beanfield War'' _ and Latin-rhythm musical groups fail to even mention <PERSON> Santana </PERSON>. `` For <PERSON> Gloria </PERSON> <PERSON> Estefan </PERSON> and <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lobos </LOCATION> and all the other Spanish-speaking people today, if they want to go to the future, they got to go through me first,'' <PERSON> Santana </PERSON> said. On the other hand, <PERSON> Santana </PERSON> expressed satisfaction his music has not been easily categorized, and points out his innovative music has endured for two decades. `` I consider myself a musician and a stylist, in bringing forth a certain thing that all generations can relate to,'' he said. `` That's better for me than being something mega-everything for three years.'' The new album, titled `` <PERSON> Viva </PERSON> <PERSON> Santana </PERSON>!,'' is the latest of 25 LPs released during his career. He also cut albums with Buddy Miles and <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> McLaughlin </PERSON>. The tour began on Aug. 26 at <LOCATION> Tacoma </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wash </LOCATION>. Some scheduled stops include <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Louis </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Richmond </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880831-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-31-88 0011EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-TiberRenaissance     08-31 0742</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Tiber Renaissance,0763</SECOND>
<HEAD>Tiber Lovers Try To Turn The Tide For Rome's Polluted River</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By FRANCES D'EMILIO</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ROME (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Smelly sewage notwithstanding, the <LOCATION> Tiber </LOCATION> is having a renaissance. Once the river was the lifeline of <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION>. From ancient times to just a century ago, Romans bathed, fished and washed their clothes in it. <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION>'s unplanned development boom after World War II, however, proved too much for the river. In 20 years, the population swelled from 1 million to more than 3 million. Anyone foolish enough to swim in the Tiber risks fatal infection from the untreated sewage that pours into it daily. Today's Romans do n't have the habit of going down to the river _ a stroll there means sidestepping broken bottles, rats and syringes discarded by drug addicts. But this summer gave Tiber lovers hope the tide is turning their way in the battle against pollution and neglect. With an eye on developing tourist attractions for 1990, when <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION> hosts the World Cup soccer games, the city offered free boat rides during July. The response was so great that the promotion was extended into September. Tickets sold out for sunset cruises to the romantic setting of a play performed at the Roman amphitheater at <LOCATION> Ostia </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Antica </LOCATION>, the Tiber's ancient port. Hot, breezeless nights found young Romans playing cards and dancing on <LOCATION> Tiberina </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION>. `` The fish will return, there will be pleasure boats. This is n't the Thames, but there's reason to believe the Tiber can be made livable for flora and flauna,'' said <PERSON> Aurelio </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Misiti </PERSON>, a sanitary engineer and professor at <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> La </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sapienza </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> His department works closely with the city on <LOCATION> Tiber </LOCATION> projects. While dictator <PERSON> Benito </PERSON> <PERSON> Mussolini </PERSON> had declared the river contaminated and banned swimming and transport in 1924, <PERSON> Misiti </PERSON> noted, postwar governments did n't get around to prohibiting the dumping of sewage into it until 1976. `` In 1974, <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION> started building the first purification plant,'' <PERSON> Misiti </PERSON> said in an interview. `` Now there are four plants, but they can only handle a bit less than half the discharge, and that's just talking about urban waste, not industry's, which is supposed to be handled by the factories themselves.'' The sewage treatment program was supposed to have been completed years ago. <PERSON> Misiti </PERSON> said it should be finished by 1992 and `` after that the Tiber should return to normal.'' Just outside the city, fisherman pull in edible catch from the river, which begins its 251-mile course in the <LOCATION> Etruscan </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Apennines </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Paola </PERSON> <PERSON> Ruggeri </PERSON> of the World Wildlife Fund says the city for the most part does n't enforce regulations forcing factories to purify their wastes before spilling them into the Tiber. Since 1982, her group has rented from the city a stretch of riverbank and intends to keep it as a green oasis. Willows, poplars, even a fig tree, lean out to the water, making that stretch look more like <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Twain </PERSON>'s <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> than a river channeled through a noisy, traffic-plagued international city. `` Every week volunteers come to clean it and every week we find a mountain of garbage,'' Ms. <PERSON> Ruggeri </PERSON> said. Until about a century ago, the city spilled down to the river banks, leaving <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION> vulnerable to devastating floods, roughly every couple of hundred years. After many suggestions, including those of <PERSON> Giuseppe </PERSON> <PERSON> Garibaldi </PERSON>, the unification hero, the government began walling off the <LOCATION> Tiber </LOCATION> and demolishing buildings at river-level. Now pedestrians and cars move along, at bridge-deck level, with the Tiber's murky green waters are out of sight below. Earlier this year, when the city planned its annual April 21 celebrations of the legendary founding of <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION> by <PERSON> Romulus </PERSON> along the left bank of the <LOCATION> Tiber </LOCATION>, it hosted an exhibit about excavations done in the last 10 years, when the river became a distinct department within the city's Superintendency of Archaeology. Tourists walking along the river can see the excavation of a three-level storehouse for jars of oil, wine and fish sauce left dockside by barges at the ancient port near what is now <LOCATION> Testaccio </LOCATION>, a blue-collar workers' neighborhood. `` In the past, the city lived on its river. <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION> was a kind of <LOCATION> Venice </LOCATION>, a <LOCATION> Copenhagen </LOCATION>, a <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> or a <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION>,'' said <PERSON> Claudio </PERSON> <PERSON> Mocchegiani </PERSON> <PERSON> Carpano </PERSON>, head of the city's underwater archaeology department. `` A thousand years from now, when they dig up artifacts from the 20th century, they'll find out that the Tiber just ran through <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION> and served as a sewer,'' <PERSON> Carpano </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880831-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-31-88 0011EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-ShortestMan     08-31 0587</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Shortest Man,0607</SECOND>
<HEAD>In Crowded Indian Bazaar, Lonely 25-Inch-Tall Man Longs For Wife</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By DILIP GANGULY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW DELHI, India (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 In the narrow and crowded lanes of the old bazaar, a 25-inch-tall man sits in a store selling candy and hoping to find a wife. `` It is a hard life to be a dwarf, and to be the world's shortest living matured man is even harder,'' <PERSON> Gul </PERSON> <PERSON> Mohammad </PERSON> said in his whispery voice as he counted coins and handed sweets to children much taller than he <PERSON> Mohammad </PERSON> is 3.3 inches shorter than the shortest living adult listed by the 1988 <ORGANIZATION> Guinness </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Book </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Records </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> la </PERSON> <PERSON> Rosa </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Santo </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Domingo </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Dominican </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Republic </LOCATION>. `` No one noticed me before, until a local newspaper reporter had a chance meeting with a friend of mine, who told her about me,'' <PERSON> Mohammad </PERSON>, 32, said in an interview Tuesday. He is the eldest of four children of <PERSON> Noor </PERSON> <PERSON> Mohammad </PERSON> and <PERSON> Fatma </PERSON> <PERSON> Begum </PERSON>. `` My first issue were twins, <PERSON> Gul </PERSON> and <PERSON> Zahoor </PERSON>. Both were dwarfs,''' <PERSON> Fatma </PERSON> said in her one-room home in the <LOCATION> Ballimaran </LOCATION> district of <LOCATION> Old </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Delhi </LOCATION>. `` <PERSON> Zahoor </PERSON> died after four years, but <PERSON> Gul </PERSON> lived to become a man.'' Her other children, a boy and a girl, grew to normal size. <PERSON> Gul </PERSON>, which means flower in the <LOCATION> Urdu </LOCATION> language, is lonely and wants to get married. He was 10 when his father died. His mother soon remarried, and <PERSON> Gul </PERSON> was sent to live with his maternal uncle, where he stays today. `` I want to marry someone who is of normal height so that she can carry me around, feed me and give me bath. ... I do not want to live on the charity of my relatives forever,'' he said. His arms are so short that his hands `` ca n't reach his head while bathing,'' said his aunt, <PERSON> Nargis </PERSON> <PERSON> Begum </PERSON>. <PERSON> Mohammad </PERSON> started his candy business with an investment of about $ 35, but he has been robbed twice. `` I could not do anything. I have decided when I marry I will ask my wife to sit with me in the candy store,'' he said with a broad smile. <PERSON> Mohammad </PERSON>, whose only vice is smoking, giggles constantly. `` I used to get very upset when people laughed at me, but I figured out if I laughed back that fixes them,'' he said. `` Being the shortest man is not a joke. It is a hard existence,'' <PERSON> Mohammad </PERSON> said. Walking is difficult for <PERSON> Mohammad </PERSON>, who pays about 30 cents a day to teen-agers who piggyback him where he wants to go. `` I ca n't get onto a rickshaw or sit on a bicycle. It is difficult to balance,'' he said. <PERSON> Mohammad </PERSON>'s neighbors are fond of him. `` He is our pride. When he becomes world-famous, we will all be very, very happy,'' said <PERSON> Ashraf </PERSON> <PERSON> Rizvi </PERSON>, a travel agent who brought <PERSON> Mohammad </PERSON> to the attention of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Herald </ORGANIZATION> newspaper. <PERSON> Mohammad </PERSON>'s uncle, <PERSON> Manzoor </PERSON> <PERSON> Hussain </PERSON>, said a circus once tried to buy him. `` I would have gladly agreed to let <PERSON> Mohammad </PERSON> work in the circus but to lose him forever is something impossible.'' He said the circus offered the equivalent of $ 14,285 for <PERSON> Mohammad </PERSON>, a staggering amount in <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> where the per capita annual income is $ 290. <PERSON> Hussain </PERSON> hopes <PERSON> Mohammad </PERSON> will find a bride. `` But who will marry him? Maybe one day when he is famous someone will come and offer him her hand,'' the uncle said. `` But the problem is that <PERSON> Mohammad </PERSON> wants a normal-height women, not a dwarf like him.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880831-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-31-88 0021EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-AirShow-Grief     08-31 0429</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Air Show-Grief,0438</SECOND>
<HEAD>`Am I Going to Die?' Burned Girl Asks GI</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By KEVIN COSTELLOE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>FRANKFURT, West Germany (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A burned and terrified German girl, not yet in her teens, asked of the <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> soldiers holding her, `` Am I going to die? Am I going to die?'' `` I just ca n't get that face out of my mind,'' one of them said later. A young airman said <PERSON> God </PERSON> helped him save injured people after the crash Sunday at the <LOCATION> Ramstein </LOCATION> air show. A woman told of the anguish she felt when her husband was assigned to retrieve the remains of victims. The unofficial <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military newspaper <ORGANIZATION> Stars </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Stripes </ORGANIZATION> published an account Tuesday of moving stories told at `` grief clinic'' that was closed to other news media. City Editor <PERSON> Betty </PERSON> <PERSON> Luman </PERSON> said a reporter from the newspaper attended the clinic on the condition that the participants not be identified. `` One of the tech sergeants from my squadron was holding a 10-to 12-year-old German girl,'' a soldier said. `` She was burned, but I could n't tell how bad. `` She just kept looking at me asking ` Am I going to die? Am I going to die?' And I could n't tell her one way or the other, so I just kept looking at her and saying: ` You're all right. You'll be fine.' And she kept screaming for her mom. And I just ca n't get that face out of my mind.'' A 21-year-old airman said: `` I was actually putting my hands inside their backs and sides to keep their veins shut. I think God put my feeling aside so that I could get in there and help.'' Tears welled in a woman's eyes as she told of her husband's assignment to collect the remains `` I knew he had to talk about it,'' she said. `` I did n't want to talk about it, but I knew I had to. I'm here for me, but I'm here for him, too.'' 1st Lt. <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Sattler </PERSON>, a spokesman for the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Air Base at <LOCATION> Ramstein </LOCATION>, told The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> the general news media were not invited to the session Monday because, `` after all, this was aimed at healing the people involved.'' Stars and Stripes said the meeting of eight survivors with mental health experts was the first of several the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> is sponsoring to help people deal with the tragedy. Its report said: `` Survivors spoke of experiencing depression, lack of sleep, loss of appetite, decreasing interest in things they usually do, guilt and recurring visions. And they cried.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880831-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-31-88 0022EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Olympics-AIDS     08-31 0691</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Olympics-AIDS,0712</SECOND>
<HEAD>Concern About Olympic AIDS Threat To South Korea</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By BARRY RENFREW</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SEOUL, South Korea (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Women's groups and other organizations are demanding compulsory AIDS tests for the thousands of foreigners who will visit <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> for the Olympics. The groups contend the influx of visitors could spread acquired immune deficiency syndrome in a nation that has reported just a few AIDS cases and enacted tough laws to curb the spread of the disease. `` It must be compulsory for all foreign visitors during the Olympic period to show medical certificates confirming they are free from the disease,'' said So Mi-yong of the Women's Hot Line. The government, worried about offending foreigners, has said there will be no mandatory AIDS tests. Health officials say it would be impossible to test the 200,000 expected visitors. Health authorities have reported two AIDS deaths and about 30 cases of the AIDS virus, mainly among prostitutes, since the first case was reported in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> in 1985. But Olympics authorities and government officials are adopting a number of measures to try to ensure the Games do not expose the nation to AIDS any more than is necessary. <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION> residents have been receiving handbills headlined `` AIDS'' and warning people that they must take every precaution to avoid the disease. `` It is a horrible disease that can not be stopped by any method except preventative measures,'' the leaflet warns. City health officials said the warning was being distributed on the eve of the Olympics to raise public awareness before the visitors arrive. Leaflets are being sent to all households in the city of 10 million people. The pamphlet makes no reference to the Olympics, but it does say the first diagnosed case discovered in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> was an American. It also stresses the high number of AIDS cases overseas. Free condoms will be distributed at the Olympic Athletes Village that will house 13,000 athletes and officials, officials said. Officials did not know if condoms would be provided to the 6,000 journalists in the Press Village. Health authorities and police will watch the city's prostitutes during the Olympics to make sure they have been tested for AIDS as required by law, officials say. `` We will be taking special measures during the Olympics,'' said Dr. <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Sung-woo </PERSON>, director general of the <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION>. <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION> officials also have conducted a public education campaign in recent months to alert the public to AIDS. Posters have been put up in subways and other places. But some civic groups and opposition lawmakers say the measures are not enough. They contend the only certain defense against the disease is to require all foreigners to prove they are not infected with AIDS. National Assemblyman Park <PERSON> Sil </PERSON> called for mandatory testing of all foreigners coming to the Olympics. `` There is no guarantee they wo n't bring this deadly disease,'' he said. Women's groups say it is unfair to test prostitutes and not foreigners who may infect them. Civic groups formed a council to press for mandatory testing. `` It is ridiculous to require AIDS tests only on hostesses with frequent contacts with foreigners,'' said Ms. So of the Women's Hot Line. Tough laws were enacted this year to limit the spread of AIDS. The law allows authorities to monitor and regulate people infected with AIDS or the AIDS virus. Under the law, people with AIDS who have intercourse without using protection such as condoms face up to three years in prison, officials have the power to isolate AIDS sufferers, and doctors who fail to report cases face jail terms. Most South Koreans see AIDS as a `` foreign'' disease and insist their nation can be spared if controls are imposed on foreigners. The government has rejected demands for mandatory AIDS tests for foreigners for fear of offending other nations and discouraging business and tourism. Health officials admit it is only a matter of time before AIDS spreads in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> and testing of foreigners would do little to stop the disease. The government hopes its public campaigns will do more to limit its spread.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880831-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-31-88 0022EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-SAfrica-Detainees     08-31 0172</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-SAfrica-Detainees,0177</SECOND>
<HEAD>Government Lists Detainees Held More Than 30 Days</HEAD>
<DATELINE>JOHANNESBURG, South Africa (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The white-led government has released the names of 801 people held without charge for at least 30 days under state-of-emergency regulations. The great majority are black. The list, released Tuesday, includes many prominent anti-apartheid activists who have been held for most or all of the state of emergency declared on June 12, 1986. Among them are <PERSON> Zwalakhe </PERSON> <PERSON> Sisulu </PERSON>, editor of the black-oriented newspaper <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nation </ORGANIZATION>, and <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON> <PERSON> Morobe </PERSON>, chief spokesman for the now-banned <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION> coalition. Virtually all the detainees on the list are black, but among them are a handful of whites. The only white held for the entire emergency is <PERSON> Raymond </PERSON> <PERSON> Suttner </PERSON>, a law lecturer at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> the </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Witwatersrand </ORGANIZATION>. The government is not required to report the names of detainess held less than 30 days and has never issued comprehensive figures for the number of detentions during the emergency. Monitoring groups estimate that 30,000 people have been held for varying periods.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880831-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-31-88 0023EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-DrunkenDriver-Mother     08-31 0307</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Drunken Driver-Mother,0315</SECOND>
<HEAD>Mother Urges Leniency For Driver Who Killed Her Son</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOUISVILLE, Ky. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A mother said she asked the court for leniency on behalf of the drunken driver who killed her son because the 21-year-old former soldier deserved the chance to change his ways. <ORGANIZATION> Jefferson </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Circuit </ORGANIZATION> Judge <PERSON> Ellen </PERSON> <PERSON> Ewing </PERSON> granted <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>'s request and ordered <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Brinkley </PERSON> to serve 90 days in jail <PERSON> Ewing </PERSON> suspended the rest of a five-year prison term and placed him on five years' probation. Ms. <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> said it had been hard to accept the loss of her 25-year-old son, <PERSON> Patrick </PERSON>, in such an accident. `` I feel like the most important thing in my life has been taken away from me,'' she told the judge Monday. `` Every time I go by ... I'll be reminded of where my son died, and that hurts very much. `` But I feel like Mr. <PERSON> Brinkley </PERSON> is very young, too, and he should have the chance to maybe change his ways.'' <PERSON> Brinkley </PERSON>, of <LOCATION> Decatur </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ark. </LOCATION>, had been charged with second-degree manslaughter. But in July he pleaded guilty to the reduced charge of reckless homicide as part of an agreement with Assistant Commonwealth's Attorney <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Wine </PERSON>. The accident occurred Dec. 12 as <PERSON> Brinkley </PERSON> was driving the wrong direction in the westbound lanes of the <ORGANIZATION> Gene </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Snyder </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Freeway </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Brinkley </PERSON>'s pickup collided with <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>'s car, and <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> died at the scene of multiple injuries. A test showed <PERSON> Brinkley </PERSON>'s blood-alcohol level was 0.14 percent, above the state's 0.1 percent at which a person is presumed intoxicated. At the urging of <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>'s mother, Wine had recommended that <PERSON> Brinkley </PERSON> be placed on probation so he could give public talks about the dangers of drunken driving. <PERSON> Brinkley </PERSON>, who had been stationed at <ORGANIZATION> Fort </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Knox </ORGANIZATION>, was discharged from the Army this month, primarily because of the accident, said defense attorney <PERSON> Doug </PERSON> <PERSON> Miller </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880831-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-31-88 0027EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lites     08-31 0244</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lites,0255</SECOND>
<HEAD>On The Lght Side</HEAD>
<DATELINE>EAST WINTHROP, Maine (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Camp owners on <LOCATION> Little </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Cobbossee </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> discovered a new island, and it floats as the wind shifts. `` It's pretty wild to see,'' <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Gordon </PERSON>, of the Cobbossee Watershed District, said Tuesday. `` You can have a stretch of beach one day and the next day have wetland.'' The island, covered with cattails, grass and wild rice, is apparently a chunk of wetland that broke off from the mainland and floated out into the lake, <PERSON> Gordon </PERSON> said. `` It is a real inconvenience for property owners,'' <PERSON> Gordon </PERSON> said. One resident, <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Kendall </PERSON>, said he thought he could push the island, with help from other boaters, to shore in a less bothersome area. There, he said, it would have to be tied down to prevent it from floating back out. But <PERSON> Kendall </PERSON> also had another idea for getting rid of the island. `` Hey,'' he asked a visitor, `` you want some land?''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>HIGHLAND PARK, Mich. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Beginning soon, the Jeep name will be seen not only on the rear of the vehicles made by <ORGANIZATION> Chrysler </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, but on the rears of people. <ORGANIZATION> Chrysler </ORGANIZATION> has agreed to a licensing deal with <PERSON> Murjani </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> City-based clothing marketer, allowing the Jeep name to adorn blue jeans and other sportswear. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Kirkwood </PERSON>, manager of Jeep licensing for the No. 3 automaker, said the clothing will be unveiled in March in department stores, catalogs and `` Jeep gear'' stores.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880831-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-31-88 0001EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-Jet-Turbulence     08-31 0167</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Jet-Turbulence,0171</SECOND>
<HEAD>Eight Injured As Jet Hits Turbulence, Lands In Savannah</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SAVANNAH, Ga. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Eight passengers and two crew members were injured Tuesday when a <ORGANIZATION> USAir </ORGANIZATION> jet, traveling from <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lauderdale </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>, encountered severe turbulence over <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>, officials said. The plane made an unscheduled stop in <LOCATION> Savannah </LOCATION>, where the injured were taken to Memorial Medical Center for treatment, mostly of bruises and scrapes. One passenger, an unidentified pregnant woman, was admitted for overnight observation, said <PERSON> Dave </PERSON> <PERSON> Shipley </PERSON>, a spokesman for <ORGANIZATION> USAir </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. About 100 other passengers on the flight were put on other planes to continue their travel, <PERSON> Shipley </PERSON> said. The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> will investigate, he added. <PERSON> Shipley </PERSON> said the pilot of the <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> 737-300 was passing some thunderstorms when a sudden jolt hit the plane 30 miles south of <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> S.C. </LOCATION> `` There were thunderstorms in the area and none of them were painted -LRB- reflected -RRB- on his radar,'' <PERSON> Shipley </PERSON> said. `` He was maneuvering around them visually when it hit.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880831-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-31-88 0020EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-OrindaFire 2ndLd-Writethru a0405 08-31 0443</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Orinda Fire, 2nd Ld - Writethru, a0405,0453</SECOND>
<HEAD>Fire Guts Five $1 Million Homes</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: SUBS 3rd graf to CORRECT to Dashnor sted Dashner.</NOTE>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto OAT3</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KATHLEEN MACLAY</BYLINE>
<HEAD>Associated Press Writer</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ORINDA, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A grass and brush fire raged out of control Tuesday afternoon, quickly destroyed five expensive homes and badly damaged two others. The blaze was controlled about two hours after it began in this rural community about 20 miles east of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION>, said Fire Capt. <PERSON> Greg </PERSON> <PERSON> Holm </PERSON>. There were no reports of injuries. <ORGANIZATION> Orinda </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION> Chief <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Dashnor </PERSON> said police and fire investigators are canvassing the area to check out second-hand reports that a teen-ager was seen shortly before the fire carrying a bottle rocket, a homemade fireworks device. Several people reported hearing sounds like firecrackers minutes before the blaze broke out, said <PERSON> Holm </PERSON>. `` We are investigating it as a suspicious fire, but the cause has not been determined,'' he added. Five houses, each worth about $ 1 million, were destroyed and two others had an undetermined amount of damage, said Fire Chief <PERSON> Ed </PERSON> <PERSON> Lucas </PERSON>. Many residents were not at home when the fire broke out. The flames rapidly spread through the dry brush and tree-covered hills, destroying several houses in just minutes. About 10 acres were burned, said firefighter <PERSON> Marty </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Connell </PERSON>. <PERSON> Beverly </PERSON> <PERSON> Hopp </PERSON>, whose 33-year-old home was destroyed in the blaze, said several children helped her rescue her four dogs from the flames. The only property she and husband, <PERSON> Al </PERSON>, were able to save was a desk containing money and insurance papers. `` This has been the worst time of my life,'' she said `` What do you do after all these years?'' <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> <PERSON> Artist </PERSON>, a homeowner and 18-year resident, said the fire came within yards of her home. `` The hills are steep, and when the wind comes up, it makes those hills like chimneys with flames just coming right up them,'' Artist said. Shifting winds, gusting up to 22 mph, made it difficult for firefighters to contain the blaze. The fire shifted directions several times because of the winds, officials said. `` One time it's going down the hills, then seconds later it's going up the hills faster than it came down,'' Artist said <PERSON> Lynne </PERSON> <PERSON> Cechettini </PERSON>, 16, was napping when her sister woke her up and told her about the fire. `` I looked out the kitchen and there was this huge flame wall and I thought for sure our house was gone,'' said <PERSON> Cechettini </PERSON>, whose hair was filled with ashes. Only the roof of the Cechettini's home burned. The homes were situated among grassland dotted by patches of <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> scrub oaks, pine and eucalyptus trees and low-lying bushes.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880831-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-31-88 0054EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-US-JapanAttitudes     08-31 0414</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-US-Japan Attitudes,410</SECOND>
<HEAD>U.S. Style Marriage and Divorce Criticized by Americans, Japanese</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GENE KRAMER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Japanese attitudes toward marriage, divorce and the family are changing but the American model is an unattractive one, young adults from both countries said at a cultural exchange. Thirty university students from <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> and 30 from the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, ranging in age from 17 to 25, compared cultural and social traditions at a gathering that produced strong criticism from both sides of the high <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> divorce rate. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> in 1985 had five divorces and 10.2 marriages per 1,000 people. Comparable Japanese figures were 1.39 divorces and 6.2 marriages per 1,000. `` Americans seem so crazy about kids, but when they divorce are n't they forgetting about the children?'' said <PERSON> Tadakatsu </PERSON> <PERSON> Tsuruno </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION> at the daylong session last week in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> co-sponsored by <ORGANIZATION> Nihon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Keizai </ORGANIZATION>, a Japanese economic newspaper, and <ORGANIZATION> Konica </ORGANIZATION>, the photographic and electronics company. The Japanese, from 11 universities, were winners of an essay contest on the two countries' roles in the world. The Americans were engaged in Japanese or other foreign studies at <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> universities. University of <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION> student <PERSON> Scott </PERSON> <PERSON> Larson </PERSON> said the high <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> divorce rate `` is a sign of how individualism has gone out of control'' in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. He called it `` individualism with no altruism.'' But despite their criticism of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> trends, Tsuruno and other Japanese said things also are changing at home. `` The Japanese attitude to marriage is approaching the American way ... with people thinking more for themselves,'' Tsuruno noted. `` We still have arranged marriages, but 99 percent of my generation will find wives by themselves.'' <PERSON> Noriko </PERSON> <PERSON> Takahashi </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Tokyo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> medical student, said she will make the final decision on her future husband although she will consult with her parents. She said that if someone simply wants romance, `` you can have it without marriage. But the reason for marriage is to have children and propagate generation after generation'' of the family. <PERSON> Laura </PERSON> <PERSON> Pochop </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> Brown </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> said <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s divorce rate is likely to rise as Japanese women acquire the ability to support themselves. Without it, she said, many Japanese wives are forced to accept their husbands' liaisons with other women, `` a situation <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> women would find intolerable.'' A moderator, Prof. <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Weinstein </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Illinois </ORGANIZATION> and <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Strategic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Studies </ORGANIZATION>, said <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s divorce rate is rising, with more older women divorcing after raising their children to adulthood.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880831-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-31-88 0054EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Housing-Homeless     08-31 0327</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Housing-Homeless,320</SECOND>
<HEAD>Judge Says HUD Must Consider Homeless When Selling Foreclosed
Houses</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TOM SEPPY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Housing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Urban </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION> must consider the needs of the homeless before the agency auctions off government-owned, foreclosed homes to the highest bidder, a federal judge says. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> Harold </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Greene </PERSON> temporarily barred <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> on Tuesday from selling 170 single-family homes in the metropolitan <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> area. The sale was scheduled for today. Last week, another federal judge in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> blocked <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> from selling 200 foreclosed homes in <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION>. The actions are part of a broader effort to force the federal government to make some of <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION>'s inventory of 47,000 foreclosed houses available to the homeless. <PERSON> Greene </PERSON>, in issuing his temporary restraining order, said <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> had violated federal laws by refusing to make a survey of its stock of buildings and properties and determine which might be transferred to non-profit groups that provide services for the homeless. He also said <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> has not complied with the law which calls for `` the realization as soon as feasible of the goal of a decent home and a suitable living environment for every American family.'' `` <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> can not just sell to the highest bidder,'' he said. `` The government can not not just consider the amount of revenue coming in.'' <PERSON> Greene </PERSON> said his temporary restraining order would last until Sept. 14 while Judge <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> <PERSON> Gasch </PERSON>, who has jurisdiction over the case, schedules further action. <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> is acquiring foreclosed properties at a rate of about 7,000 each month. Because it has been selling between 6,000 and 7,000 of the properties monthly, the agency has accumulated a `` rolling inventory'' of about 47,000 homes, the largest backlog in its history. The surge in <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION>'s stock of properties reflects a rash of foreclosures on properties in the oil-producing states, and an increase in the overall volume of homes insured by <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> in the wake of lower interest rates two years ago.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880831-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-31-88 0056EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-US-Poland Bjt   08-31 0788</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-US-Poland, Bjt,770</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHINGTON TODAY: Polish Developments Test US-Soviet Relations</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP News Analysis</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BRYAN BRUMLEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 U.S.-Soviet relations were in a whirlwind of confusion even before Polish workers staged their latest occupation strikes. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> is engaged in the always disorienting process of choosing a new president. And the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> is emerging from a tumultuous <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> conference filled with boisterous calls for economic reform and greater democratization. `` Not only is it a period of great flux, but as far as the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> is concerned, it is in the most fluid state since the -LRB- 1917 Russian -RRB- revolution,'' said <PERSON> Madeleine </PERSON> <PERSON> Albright </PERSON>, the chief foreign policy adviser to Democratic presidential nominee <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>. Ms. <PERSON> Albright </PERSON>, born in <LOCATION> Czechoslovakia </LOCATION>, is an expert on <ORGANIZATION> East-West </ORGANIZATION> relations and a professor at <ORGANIZATION> Georgetown </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. The latest Polish upheaval poses, loud and clear, one of the unanswered questions about the reform program of <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION> leader <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>: How much political power are communist authorities willing to hand over to their people in return for a popular commitment to invigorate the economy? The wrong answer from <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> or <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION> to that question will present the next American president with a dilemma. `` The problem that the next president is going to have to decide is whether to continue to demand perfection from the Soviet bloc, or whether to just declare victory and accept any change for the better. And there is no question that things are getting better,'' said <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Hough </PERSON>, a Soviet expert at <ORGANIZATION> Duke </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. `` It seems that everybody is holding his breath,'' said <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Fairbanks </PERSON> of the <PERSON> Johns </PERSON> <PERSON> Hopkins </PERSON> center for advanced international studies. `` There is a marked movement toward detente, but no one is sure how much momentum it has.'' A new explosion of violence in <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> could delay or derail the train. Two weeks ago Polish workers, with their backs to the economic wall, began a second wave of occupation strikes this year, demanding that the government recognize and negotiate with the banned Solidarity trade union. The strikes forced Polish leaders to meet today with Solidarity's leader, <PERSON> Lech </PERSON> <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON>, with whom they had vowed not to negotiate since releasing him from martial law internment in 1982. Polish leader Gen. <PERSON> Wojciech </PERSON> <PERSON> Jaruzelski </PERSON> has introduced reforms which, like <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s program, loosen central controls and allow a greater role for market forces. But the Polish reforms have not stimulated the economy: production remains sluggish and the foreign debt has risen to $ 40 billion. The government's decision to meet with <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> could be a major step on the road toward a healthier <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> has been silent on the Polish predicament, but he said in <LOCATION> Yugoslavia </LOCATION> earlier this year that there were many paths to socialism. Many people interpreted that to mean the Soviets would not force Polish communists to smash a resurgent Solidarity, as they did in the military crackdown of December 1981. The head of the largest <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> trade union, <ORGANIZATION> AFL-CIO </ORGANIZATION> President <PERSON> Lane </PERSON> <PERSON> Kirkland </PERSON>, last week urged the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration to invoke provisions of the new trade bill calling for sanctions against nations that violate workers' rights. <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>'s communist authorities `` should be denied access to the American market under those provisions since they are in violation of worker rights,'' <PERSON> Kirkland </PERSON> said. <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> is desperately trying to break into Western markets and to secure credits from the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Monetary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fund </ORGANIZATION>. The <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration has lifted most of the sanctions it imposed against <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> and is in no hurry to slap them back on just as U.S.-Soviet relations are improving. But new credits are out of the question until <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> stabilizes its political situation. The administration, says <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman <PERSON> Phyllis </PERSON> <PERSON> Oakley </PERSON>, hopes Polish communist authorities can find the path to `` national reconciliation.'' `` Free labor unions can help the Polish economic reform effort, not hinder it, `` Mrs. <PERSON> Oakley </PERSON> says. `` Indeed, it is hard to see how economic reform can succeed without the participation of free trade unions.'' Another State Department official said `` we've been telling the Polish government very consistently that their ability to reform the economy and our ability to support that process will depend on national reconciliation''; in other words, give Solidarity a slice of the political pie. `` That's not ideology, that's practicality. No one is going to accept the kind of austerity needed for economic reform without making sure they get political reforms first,'' said the official, who spoke on condition of anonymity. This is one area in which the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration and the would-be <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> administration are pretty close, <PERSON> Albright </PERSON> says. Last week, the <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> campaign urged <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> to legalize Solidarity.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Bryan </PERSON> <PERSON> Brumley </PERSON> covers international affairs for <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> from <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880831-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-31-88 0059EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-SovietNavy     08-31 0682</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Soviet Navy,650</SECOND>
<HEAD>Soviets Focusing on Futuristic Submarine Force</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By NORMAN BLACK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Military Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> is committed to a highly advanced, nuclear-powered submarine force even though the <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION> faces the same type of funding woes confronting the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION>, according to a new blueprint for the <LOCATION> Russian </LOCATION> navy now being studied in the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION>. The blueprint is a book blessed by Fleet Adm. <PERSON> Sergei </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorshkov </PERSON>, known as the `` father'' of the modern <LOCATION> Russian </LOCATION> navy. It envisions submarines that can travel at 50 knots to 60 knots underwater `` in the near term'' and ultimately up to 100 knots, while diving to depths of 6,600 feet and carrying thermal-and laser-homing torpedoes that can travel at 300 knots. The book, `` The <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>: Its Role, Prospects for Development and Employment,'' was published in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> earlier this year and is now being translated and analyzed by the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Naval </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Intelligence </ORGANIZATION>. That office already has prepared a three-page summary, however, that concludes the book `` in its scope is the most powerful Soviet monograph on the navy since <PERSON> Gorshkov </PERSON>'s ` Sea Power of the State' -LRB- in 1976 -RRB- and is clearly intended to demonstrate why the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> navy must continue the <PERSON> Gorshkov </PERSON> legacy of fielding a high-technology, high-seas navy despite evident fiscal constraints.'' The book apparently was authored by several individuals but was edited and carries a foreword by <PERSON> Gorshkov </PERSON>, for three decades the driving force behind the Soviet navy. According to the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> intelligence office, the book `` offers the West an insight into the future composition and employment of the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> navy,'' highlighting `` three key naval missions.'' They include hunting and destroying <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and other Western submarines before they could launch their missiles in a war; destroying Western military and economic targets through nuclear strikes from Soviet submarines; `` and destroying hostile naval forces to gain command of the sea around the Eurasian periphery.'' Throughout the book, special attention is given to anti-submarine warfare and the threat posed by American subs, the summary continued. `` The authors project a highly dynamic undersea warfare environment with goals of 2,000-meter -LRB- 6,600 feet -RRB- diving depths; high-speed submarines, 50 to 60 knots in the near term and 100 knots in the out-years; future high-speed torpedoes, 200 to 300 knots, with thermal and laser homing; 50-kilometer -LRB- 30-mile -RRB- anti-submarine warfare missiles; and improved acoustic and non-acoustic submarine sensors.'' A knot is equal to 1.15 miles per hour, meaning the submarines ultimately envisioned by the Soviets would be able to travel 115 mph. The <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> already has the fastest nuclear-powered submarines in the world; its Alfa and Akula attack subs can exceed 40 knots underwater. The <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> in the past has deliberately eschewed the goal of building faster submarines, preferring instead to emphasize quiet operation. As for the `` strike mission'' of attacking Western targets with submarines, the book makes `` specific reference to ` covert launches from short ranges against targets and areas covered by anti-missile defense systems' in order to decrease reaction time and increase missile survivability,'' the summary said. `` Such comments highlight the potential importance of recent Soviet sea-launched ballistic missile launches to test short-range, short time-of-flight trajectories.'' The book appears to be `` the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> navy's first salvo in staking out its future role in Soviet national security policy under the newly proclaimed defensive doctrine and ` reasonable sufficiency' philosophy,'' the American analysts added. <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION> leader <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> and top Soviet defense officials have insisted to <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials in recent months that they are shifting their military orientation from an offensive to a defensive stance and intend to maintain only a force that is sufficiently large for protection. <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Carlucci </PERSON> has pressed the Soviets for more details of their plans in several high-level meetings while expressing doubts the Soviets are really changing their offensive-minded doctrine. The new book reflects the current Soviet emphasis on defense by devoting `` considerable attention ... to the defensive roles of the Soviet navy,'' the summary said. The book says, though, that `` naval force composition is likely to continue to emphasize nuclear submarines both for defensive anti-submarine warfare missions and strategic nuclear strike.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880831-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-31-88 0104EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-StrikingMom     08-31 0429</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Striking Mom,0447</SECOND>
<HEAD>Striking Mom Reaches Settlement With Kids After 42 Days</HEAD>
<DATELINE>KENOSHA, Wis. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 It took 42 days to settle their labor dispute, but <PERSON> Gretchen </PERSON> <PERSON> Schulte </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Kenosha </LOCATION>'s striking mom, has put down her picket signs and signed a negotiated contract with her children. `` It was 100 percent worth it,'' she said. `` I do n't even care about the publicity and criticism. Even that was worth it. All that matters is here in this house. And I think we've all learned something.'' `` It's great to be free,'' daughter <PERSON> Heidi </PERSON> said Tuesday, as she relished the lifting of her grounding restrictions. <PERSON> Schulte </PERSON> went on strike July 18 to protest what she said was disrespect and disobedience by her four children, 14-year-old twins <PERSON> Eric </PERSON> and <PERSON> Julie </PERSON>; <PERSON> Heidi </PERSON>, 13; and <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON>, 8. She hung picket signs and nixed such duties as cooking, cleaning, chauffering and laundering. A possible turning point came recently when she refused to pay for her children's school clothes. Final negotiations Sunday lasted from noon until 6:40 p.m. when the detailed contracts were signed. `` It was very emotional, traumatic,'' said <PERSON> Schulte </PERSON>, 42. `` There was a lot of crying and screaming.'' The family had to take a break when debate became too heated, but the talks resumed after <PERSON> Schulte </PERSON>'s husband, <PERSON> Theodore </PERSON>, cooked dinner and family members cooled off. Even before the pact was signed, the children were outside celebrating. `` Before I finished writing my name, they were jumping around at the street corner, yelling, ` It's over! It's over!''' the mother said with a smile. `` Yesterday was the best day of my life and I plan to have another one today,'' <PERSON> Eric </PERSON> said Tuesday. But in case anyone gets complacent, the contracts are taped on the walls as reminders. <PERSON> Schulte </PERSON> no longer tells the children what needs to be done but simply has them review their contracts. The handwritten documents contain specific instructions for practically every chore and privilege. For example, the `` rec room'' contract states that parents will provide a recreation room, and all radios, newspaper delivery bags, shoes and jackets will be kept there. It also calls for removal of all cans, bottles and wrappers from the room by 6 p.m. and specifies that failure to obey is punishable by loss of television privileges for one week. The contracts, 11 of them in all, fill a notebook. <PERSON> Schulte </PERSON> had no regrets about the strike and insisted she would have kept the children grounded and out of school if they had not shaped up. `` But I knew they would come around,'' she said. `` I knew I had the hammer.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880831-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-31-88 0108EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FarmScene     08-31 0825</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Farm Scene,820</SECOND>
<HEAD>Farm Prices up in August but Trend Moderating</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DON KENDALL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Farm Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Farm commodity prices as a group were still going up last month, although a new <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> report shows that some major items were starting to level off in August. The department's overall price index rose 2.1 percent from July, averaging 13 percent more than in August 1987. Also, the new figures released on Tuesday showed that the index rose only 2.9 percent in July instead of the preliminary reading of 3.6 percent announced a month ago. Since April, as drought cut into this year's harvest prospects, farm commodity prices overall have climbed 10.8 percent. However, there were some indications in the August report that the upward spiral began to weaken. The department's <ORGANIZATION> Agricultural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Statistics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> said in its preliminary report that higher prices for cattle, apples, tomatoes and lettuce contributed most to the August increase, while prices declined for cotton, corn, onions and soybeans. In the earlier months, corn and soybeans helped lead the way for rising prices. However, by late July, widespread rains began to dampen further increases, although the drought of 1988 has not been broken by any means. At the <ORGANIZATION> Chicago </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Trade </ORGANIZATION> on Tuesday grain and soybean futures closed sharply higher, but it was on the strength of new export business, not further crop losses due to drought, analysts said. Moreover, they said, the corn and soybean crops have passed their most critical stages of development. Based on Aug. 1 estimates, this year's corn harvest may drop 37 percent from 1987; wheat, 13 percent; and soybeans 23 percent. `` All feed grain and soybean prices declined from July, but rough -LRB- unmilled -RRB- rice and all wheat prices increased slightly,'' the report said. `` Average prices of beef cattle and calves increased sharply from July but were below the high levels recorded during February through May of this year.'' Prices of some major commodities are based on mid-month averages and then are revised the following month when additional information is available. As a commodity group, prices of feed grains and hay dropped 2.8 percent from July to August, but still averaged 68 percent above a year ago, the report said. Prices of meat animals rose 4.3 percent as a group but averaged 0.6 percent below the year-earlier mark. Beef cattle prices averaged $ 66.40 per 100 pounds of liveweight, up $ 3.20 from July. Hog prices increased $ 1 from July to $ 46.80 in August. Apple prices at the farm level, rose to 26.1 cents per pound in August from 19.7 cents in July and 16 cents a year ago. Lettuce was reported at $ 12.20 per 100 pounds, up from $ 7.62 in July but far below the $ 18 of last year. Tomatoes, at $ 41.70 per 100 pounds, were up from $ 31 in July and $ 17.30 in August 1987. Overall, the August all-crops price index was up 2.3 percent from July, averaging 33 percent above the year-ago level. The August price index for all livestock and livestock products was up 3.4 percent from July and averaged 1.3 percent more than a year earlier. Higher prices for cattle, hogs, milk, turkeys and eggs accounted for the increase from July. Consumer food prices are expected to rise 3 percent to 5 percent this year, compared with a 4.2 percent average increase in 1987. Before the drought took hold, <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> was predicting a 1988 food price hike of 2 percent to 4 percent. Department officials have predicted that the drought may add 2 percentage points to food prices in 1989, above the expected increase in inflation, currently forecast at around 4 percent. That could mean a 1989 food price increase in the range of 6 percent to 7 percent. Tuesday's report said: _ Cattle averaged $ 66.40 per 100 pounds of live weight nationally, up from $ 63.20 in July and $ 61.90 reported for August 1987 Those are averages for all types of cattle sold as beef. _ Hogs averaged $ 45.40 per 100 pounds, compared with $ 44.10 in July and $ 58.60 a year earlier _ Corn, at $ 2.66 a bushel, was down from $ 2.72 in July and the average of $ 1.47 per bushel a year earlier _ Wheat prices at the farm, according to preliminary figures, averaged $ 3.56 per bushel, compared with $ 3.50 in July and $ 2.36 a year earlier _ Rice averaged $ 7.61 per 100 pounds, compared with $ 7.51 in July and $ 3.74 a year earlier _ Soybeans were $ 8.40 per bushel, compared with $ 8.50 in July and $ 5.02 a year earlier _ Upland cotton was reported at 55.2 cents per pound, compared with 58.6 in July and 63.7 cents in August 1987 _ Eggs were 59.9 cents per dozen, compared with 62.2 cents in July and 51.9 cents a year earlier _ Milk was $ 11.60 per 100 pounds, compared with $ 11.40 in July and $ 12.20 a year earlier _ Broilers were 41.9 cents per pound, live weight, compared with 42.1 cents in July and 31.7 cents a year ago
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880831-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-31-88 0110EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-CrossSuit     08-31 0443</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Cross Suit,440</SECOND>
<HEAD>Government Can't Claim Cross Is `Non-Religious,' Judge Says</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TOM SEPPY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A huge Christian cross is an inappropriate government war memorial at a Marine base in <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION>, according to a federal judge who says a non-religious monument would be more suitable. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Hogan </PERSON> ruled Tuesday that the 65-foot wooden cross that is lit each night at Camp <PERSON> H.M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> in the <LOCATION> Honolulu </LOCATION> suburbs on <LOCATION> Oahu </LOCATION> must be removed or replaced by a secular symbol. The judge said the cross amounts to an unconstitutional endorsement of religion by the government. The cross was challenged by the Jewish War Veterans of the <LOCATION> U.S.A. </LOCATION> `` The needless use of means that are inherently religious makes a message of endorsement likely if not unavoidable,'' the judge wrote in his opinion. `` The 65-foot lighted cross on <LOCATION> Bordelon </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Field </LOCATION> at Camp Smith may fairly be considered to convey a message of governmental endorsement of Christianity,'' <PERSON> Hogan </PERSON> said. `` The use of a cross as a memorial to fallen or missing servicemen is a use of what to some is a religious symbol where a non-religious one likely would have done as well.'' The judge stayed his order for 60 days to give the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration, the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corps </ORGANIZATION> an opportunity to seek another stay from an appellate court while they appeal his decision. The Jewish War Veterans of the <ORGANIZATION> U.S.A. </ORGANIZATION> contended in its lawsuit that the wooden cross on a prominent point at the Marine base violated the Constitution's ban on governmental endorsement of a particular religion. The government argued during a hearing in May that the cross, erected 22 years ago, served purely a secular purpose of honoring Marines killed in the <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> war or are missing in action. But the Jewish veterans' group argued that the cross can not be considered a secular object because it is the `` symbol of the passion, death and resurrection of <PERSON> Jesus </PERSON> <PERSON> Christ </PERSON>.'' The government did not deny the religious significance of the cross, but said `` the history of the memorial is clear; it was erected as a secular monument.'' <PERSON> Hogan </PERSON>, however, noted evidence that the original cross was built in April 1966 for Easter sunrise services and that it was rebuilt, after a fire, in time to be lit at Christmas 1983. `` Unfortunately, the government's choice of the principal and universally recognized symbol of Christianity to achieve a secular goal can not withstand scrutiny in this instance,'' <PERSON> Hogan </PERSON> said. `` The principal symbol of Christianity, this nation's dominant religion, simply is too laden with religious meaning to be appropriate for a government memorial assertedly free of any religious message.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880831-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-31-88 0110EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-ShuttleSchedule     08-31 0240</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Shuttle Schedule,230</SECOND>
<HEAD>NASA Backs Up Project Schedule</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Delays in getting the space shuttle back into operation have led <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> to postpone its most ambitious scientific mission, the launch of the $ 1.5 billion Hubble Space Telescope. The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aeronautics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Space </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> said Tuesday that by moving the telescope launch from June 1 next year to Feb. 1, 1990, it can stay on schedule for launching three major scientific probes that are dependent on planets being in favorable position. Those launches are: <ORGANIZATION> Magellan </ORGANIZATION>, which will map the planet <PERSON> Venus </PERSON>, in April 1989; <ORGANIZATION> Galileo </ORGANIZATION>, a U.S.-German project to survey Jupiter and its moons, scheduled October 1989; and <PERSON> Ulysses </PERSON>, a cooperative project with the <ORGANIZATION> European </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Space </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION>, in October 1990. The first space shuttle flight since the Challenger exploded in January 1986 has been postponed five times. <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> said it wo n't set a new date until after a flight readiness review on Sept. 13-14, but that it hopes to make the flight late next month or in early October. The space telescope is in storage, but is costing the space agency $ 7 million a month to keep it in working order. In space, the telescope is expected to be able to look at objects 14 billion light years away _ almost to the beginning of the universe. Ground-based observatories, which must look through Earth's atmospheric veil, can only see light that originated about 2 billion light years ago
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880831-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-31-88 0111EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-International-Drugs     08-31 0485</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-International-Drugs,470</SECOND>
<HEAD>Officials Claim Success in Drug Crackdown</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOAN MOWER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Authorities say a 30-nation narcotics crackdown resulted in more than 1,200 arrests in the past month and should lead to further drug busts in this hemisphere. `` Some operations are still going on,'' <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Gutensohn </PERSON>, head of cocaine investigations at the <ORGANIZATION> Drug </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Enforcement </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>, said Tuesday. Attorney General <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON> and a host of other <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and foreign officials said Tuesday that 30 countries had participated in a series of anti-drug trafficking operations this month, primarily in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON> said authorities seized 11 tons of cocaine and destroyed 244 tons of marijuana, 118,000 coca plants and 13 cocaine laboratories. Authorities also demolished seven hidden airstrips and seized $ 3.8 million in cash, he said. While <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON> said the effort did not represent victory in the war against drugs, he said the `` cooperative nature'' of the operations represented a new avenue in stamping out trafficking. `` Heretofore, each of the nations of the <LOCATION> Americas </LOCATION> has been pursuing the war on drugs in a more or less unilateral or bilateral fashion,'' he said. The participating countries, all members of the <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Drug </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Enforcement </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conference </ORGANIZATION>, shared resources and intelligence and, in a few cases, staged cross-border operations. <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON> said the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> did not orchestrate the drug busts, though it did serve as a clearinghouse for data. Instead, each country planned and executed its drug operations, often in concert with other countries. `` By doing it all over at once, you disrupt the operation,'' <PERSON> Gutensohn </PERSON> said. Since many drug traffickers ignore national boundaries, it is vital to close in on traffickers on many fronts, he said. In <LOCATION> Peru </LOCATION>, for instance, military authorities seized cocaine laboratories in the <LOCATION> Upper </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Huallaga </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION> that are used by members of the powerful <LOCATION> Medellin </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Calli </PERSON> drug cartels, based in <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION>. Cocaine labs also were seized in <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION> itself, as well as <LOCATION> Bolivia </LOCATION>. Among some other actions cited by the officials: _ About 100 <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guardsmen </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> helped border patrol officials inspect vehicles that crossed into the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> _ As a result of information developed abroad, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> officials seized two tons of cocaine and about $ 2 million in cash _ Military officers from <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Venezuela </LOCATION> operated along the joint border _ Officials in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Costa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rica </LOCATION> worked together to seize chemicals used for cocaine at points along the border <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> participated in the operation as a member of the conference, but did not receive any `` centralized intelligence'' from the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON> said. <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s military dictator, Gen. <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>, has been indicted by two federal grand juries in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> on charges of drug trafficking and money laundering. <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> has sought his ouster since early this year, applying economic sanctions that have hurt <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s economy. _ European nations and <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> stepped up monitoring of vessels, cargo and aircraft arriving from <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880831-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-31-88 0112EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-NixonTapes Bjt   08-31 0636</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nixon Tapes, Bjt,620</SECOND>
<HEAD>Nixon Was Reluctant To Tape White House Sessions, Former Aide Says</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By HARRY F. ROSENTHAL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON>'s former top aide says the 37th president not only was reluctant to install an extensive taping system in the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, but that he quickly lost awareness that his every conversation was being recorded. `` The historiography of the <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> administration will eventually be much the richer as a result of <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON>'s decision to tape-record his meetings and telephone conversations,'' writes H.R. <PERSON> Haldeman </PERSON>, <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON>'s onetime chief of staff. `` <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> was not thinking of historians when he made this decision, but they will be the ultimate beneficiaries.'' <PERSON> Haldeman </PERSON> discusses the origin of the taping system, which provided the evidence that eventually drove <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> from office in the Watergate scandal, in the summer issue of Prologue, the quarterly publication of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Archives </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Haldeman </PERSON>'s latest account is much softer in tone and less critical of <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> than when he described the same events in a 1978 book, `` The Ends of Power.'' `` It is amazing to me when I think back to the first days, weeks and months of the taping system's existence how quickly I forgot about it,'' <PERSON> Haldeman </PERSON> writes. `` For a short time, I worried that it might not be working, and I dispatched someone to test the machinery. But the worry quickly passed, as did any awareness at all that <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON>'s conversations _ my conversations, often _ were being taped. I think <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> lost his awareness of the system even more quickly than I did.'' That dovetails with <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON>'s own memory that `` initially I was conscious of the taping, but before long I accepted it as part of the surroundings.'' <PERSON> Haldeman </PERSON> says his book 10 years ago focused on the Watergate scandal that drove <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> from office in 1974 and that, `` It was unfortunately sensational in many instances where I would have preferred it to be more reasoned and thorough.'' <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> fired <PERSON> Haldeman </PERSON> in April 1973 at the height of the coverup of the break-in at <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> headquarters in the Watergate complex in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Haldeman </PERSON> served an 18-month prison term for his part in the affair. In the book he said <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> had `` fudged'' the tape story in various ways, `` climaxing with the assertion on television in 1977 that he had ordered me to destroy all of the tapes.'' There is no reference to that in the Prologue article. The former aide said he chose to write about the taping system because the archives next year will release 60 hours of the recordings for public listening. `` <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> abhorred the idea of taping the president's meetings and telephone conversations,'' <PERSON> Haldeman </PERSON> writes. He said he and <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> discovered the taping system of his predecessor, <PERSON> Lyndon </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>, on inauguration day and that the new president ordered it removed. The major reason for the system, <PERSON> Haldeman </PERSON> says now as before, was <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON>'s failed attempt to halt inaccurate reports that came out of his meetings with various people. Other reasons, he said, were that <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> wanted records for his memoirs and an accurate account of what foreign leaders said to him. `` Something had to be done, both <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> and I agreed, to ensure that we possessed an accurate record of what was said in meetings,'' <PERSON> Haldeman </PERSON> writes. They had tried using note-takers but quit because they inhibited conversations, and they had tried debriefing visitors as they left the Oval Office. In late 1970 or early 1971, <PERSON> Haldeman </PERSON> recalls, word got to <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> that <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> felt he was foolish for not keeping a record of what was going on and that such a record was necessary for memoirs. `` <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> suddenly was receptive to the idea of taping his meetings,'' <PERSON> Haldeman </PERSON> says. `` Finally, still reluctantly, <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> agreed that taping was the best way.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880831-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-31-88 0113EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-DukakisOrganizing Bjt   08-31 0703</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Dukakis Organizing, Bjt,700</SECOND>
<HEAD>State Organizations Say Groundwork Is Strong</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By WILLIAM M. WELCH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Some state and local <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> leaders say that while <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' Republican rivals have made their grab for the national spotlight, his campaign has been making important organizational gains in the field. Around the country, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> field leaders and <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> state and local leaders contend the appearance of flagging momentum on the part of the <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> campaign is at worst a temporary problem _ a part of the ups and downs of a campaign that will balance in the end. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> campaign officials have said they were devoting much of their summer efforts to building organization in the states, and party officials in some key states point to organizational gains. `` Now is the time for quiet organizational activity that does n't get much publicity but pays off at the end,'' said <PERSON> Lanny </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Davis </PERSON>, Democratic national committeeman from <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION> `` <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> has put together perhaps the best field organization ever put together by a presidential candidate. None of that gets headlines, but you'll see evidence of it in the fall.'' In <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, a critical industrial state, party spokeswoman <PERSON> Carol </PERSON> <PERSON> Rowan </PERSON> said the party has hired 15 field coordinators to work with the <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> campaign. `` We are getting everything into place in the grass roots, and that's where this election will be won,'' she said. <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> state <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Speaker <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Avenson </PERSON> said a <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> organization has been built in regional areas of the state far earlier than in previous Democratic campaigns. Party chairman <PERSON> Bonnie </PERSON> <PERSON> Campbell </PERSON> said there are 12 <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> field workers and six administrators in this important Midwestern farm state that has gone Republican in recent years. `` We're seeing organizational work developing very, very early in a campaign,'' <PERSON> Avenson </PERSON> said. `` Compared to recent years, it's unprecedented. In <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION>, a good state for <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, the campaign has opened 15 state offices, compared with one for Republican <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, according to <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> campaign director <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Forciea </PERSON>. But in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>, a difficult state for <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, state campaign director <PERSON> Det </PERSON> <PERSON> Bowers </PERSON> said, `` We're operating almost totally on volunteers.'' In <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Erie </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> chairman <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Crangle </PERSON> acknowledged some `` sluggishness'' in the <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> campaign in recent weeks and said the problem has been discussed at local organizational meetings. He said some <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> supporters may have become overconfident in view of <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>'s lead in the polls after the Democratic convention. That lead vanished in the glare of attention on <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and the GOP convention in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION>. The focus on the Republican ticket was prolonged after the convention because of the controversial selection of Sen. <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION> as vice presidential nominee. In <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION>, a battleground state for the fall campaign, party executive director <PERSON> Todd </PERSON> <PERSON> Patterson </PERSON> said `` the <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> mess'' had drawn publicity to the Republican ticket _ and that it had hurt <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, even though much of the attention was critical. `` Right now, they've cut <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> off at the knees in terms of publicity,'' <PERSON> Patterson </PERSON> said. `` I believe in my heart that <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> will eventually win <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION>, but I think we have to get back on track.'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> himself voiced frustration on Monday that he has been unable to draw attention to his economic themes because of the attention on <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> and on <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s attacks on him. `` The <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> campaign has lost some of its early momentum,'' said <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Lodge </PERSON>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Executive </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION>. `` I think <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has controlled the debate, but he has done it through the traditional Republican trick of distorting Governor <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>'s record.'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> sought to take the offensive Tuesday, aggressively attacking <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> on crime, defense spending and his role in the Iran-Contra affair. `` I do n't think Democrats have been pushing forward as aggressively and quickly as the Republicans,'' said <PERSON> Patterson </PERSON>, the <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION> Democrat. `` The Republicans have been forced to move quickly because they've had to stir the dust up so voters wo n't see where they're at in the road.'' Some state Democrats dismissed talk of the campaign stalling, or said it's so early it does n't matter. `` The campaign is won in the last two weeks, not the first two weeks,'' <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION> party chairman <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880831-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-31-88 0114EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Quayle-Press     08-31 0711</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Quayle-Press,680</SECOND>
<HEAD>Boos Follow Quayle On Campaign Trail, But They're For the Press</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By EILEEN PUTMAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 There are plenty of boos on the campaign trail with <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> vice presidential nominee <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>, but they're not for the candidate They're for the press entourage traveling with him. The press is generally seen by pro-Quayle audiences as the skunk at the picnic as he makes his way around the country, because of reporters' questions about the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION>, his academic record, his resume and various other personal details <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> has called `` side events.'' `` Let him alone!'' the audience shouts as reporters try to waylay the vice presidential nominee. Some of the shouts are less polite. Signs like `` Media Beware,'' `` Cut <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> <PERSON> Donaldson </PERSON>'s Tongue Out'' and `` Press Go Home'' greet the traveling press. Last week, on <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>'s seven-state trip, at almost every stop were identical signs with the word `` Press'' encircled in red and with a red slash mark through the word, leading some to suspect an organized effort. At a stop in <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mo. </LOCATION>, one unidentified teen-ager held such a sign and told reporters, `` Someone gave it to me when I came in the door and I liked it.'' <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Prosperi </PERSON>, <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>'s spokesman, said he had no idea where the signs came from. `` I'm quite confident that it is nobody affiliated with the <ORGANIZATION> Bush-Quayle </ORGANIZATION> organization in any way, shape or form,'' he said. `` That's just not the way we do business.'' <PERSON> Prosperi </PERSON> said <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> does not intend to `` have a fight with the press.'' `` We're here to have a fight with the other guys on the issues,'' he said. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> was asked Sunday as he flew home whether he felt at times as if he were running against the news media, instead of the Democrats. `` I'm running with <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>,'' he replied. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> wo n't say whether he thinks the press is out to get him, telling reporters `` only you can answer that question.'' But he says he does not disagree with his wife, <PERSON> Marilyn </PERSON>, who last week said she felt the press was biased against <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> because he was a conservative. But <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> has made it clear he dislikes the intensive media scrutiny that has followed him since he became <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s running mate and allegations surfaced that he pulled strings to get into the National Guard during the Vietnam War and into law school after an average performance in college. At the <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> State Fair in <LOCATION> Sacramento </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> petted a <LOCATION> Labrador </LOCATION> retriever guide dog and when the dog just lay there with his eyes rolled up, <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> said, `` Now I know how it feels to be hounded.'' He tends to make sarcastic references to the press in his stump speech, often referring to `` my newfound friends in the news media'' or `` my cheering section.'' The references are not lost on the audiences. At one appearance in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carrollton </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, reporters who tried to ask <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> about the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> issue as he made his way shaking hands were dealt with roughly. A large woman hit one female reporter's arm and shoulder and turned and dealt another one a hefty body block. She said the two women were endangering a group of Scouts. `` I'm just trying to protect the children,'' she shouted. The hostility reached its peak at a rally in <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>'s hometown of <LOCATION> Huntington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ind. </LOCATION>, as he and <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> campaigned together on their first day after the Republican convention. At a news conference that was piped to the crowd over the public address system, the crowd cheered <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>'s answers and booed reporters' questions. `` B-o-r-i-n-g,'' they shouted. On Tuesday, <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> could n't resist another reference to the press, when he spoke to the <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fire </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chiefs </ORGANIZATION>. `` I feel that I am very accustomed to fighting fires these last couple of weeks.'' When he was presented with a fire chief's hat, <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> said: `` This is going to be prominently displayed on my airplane ... right in front of where the press is sitting.'' The hat will join another memento. At a <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> stop last week, <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>'s aides quickly grabbed up a bumper sticker which stated: `` I Do n't Love the Liberal Media.'' It is affixed it to the cabin door that faces the press section of the aircraft.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880831-0025 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-31-88 0114EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-TreasuryAuction     08-31 0080</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Treasury Auction,80</SECOND>
<HEAD>20-Day Bills Yield 7.93 Percent</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Yields averaged 7.93 percent on 20-day cash management bills in the <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>'s latest auction. The discount rate understates the actual return to investors: 8.08 percent with a $ 10,000 bill selling for $ 9,955.90. A total of $ 10.1 billion in bills were sold Tuesday out of bids totaling $ 40.6 billion. The <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> sells cash management bills at irregular intervals and with varying terms to smooth out government cash flow.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880831-0026 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-31-88 0120EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Nielsens     08-31 0335</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nielsens,0345</SECOND>
<HEAD>Emmys Highest Rated Show Yet for Fox</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KATHRYN BAKER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Television Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
