<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881107-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-07-88 2326EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Greece-BankingScandal     11-07 0552</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Greece-Banking Scandal,0569</SECOND>
<HEAD>Minister Resigns After Gree-American Banker Escapes</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KERIN HOPE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ATHENS, Greece (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Public Order Minister <PERSON> Tassos </PERSON> <PERSON> Sehiotis </PERSON> resigned Monday after a Greek-American banker indicted in a $ 30 million financial scandal fled the country, apparently aboard a yacht. The conservative opposition immediately demanded the resignation of Premier <PERSON> Andreas </PERSON> <PERSON> Papandreou </PERSON>'s socialist government, claiming it was staging a cover-up. Banker <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Koskotas </PERSON>, 34, disappeared Saturday afternoon. A police officer, speaking on condition of anonymity, said <PERSON> Koskotas </PERSON> fled abroad on Sunday, apparently by yacht from the seaside village of <LOCATION> Megalo </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Pefko </LOCATION>, 20 miles from <LOCATION> Athens </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Sehiotis </PERSON> said a warrant had been issued for <PERSON> Koskotas </PERSON>' arrest. One week ago, <PERSON> Koskotas </PERSON> was banned from leaving <LOCATION> Greece </LOCATION> pending the outcome of an official enquiry into alleged financial irregularities at the <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Crete </ORGANIZATION>, which he controls. <PERSON> Sehiotis </PERSON>, whose ministry was responsible for police surveillance of <PERSON> Koskotas </PERSON>, said he was resigning `` since such -LRB- public order ministry -RRB- omissions ... create an issue of political sensitivity.'' The scandal has shaken the government because of accusations in Greek newspapers that senior socialist officials were involved in illegal deals set up by the <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Crete </ORGANIZATION>. The socialists also have been criticized for permitting <PERSON> Koskotas </PERSON> to build a multi-million dollar banking and media empire in <LOCATION> Greece </LOCATION> since 1984 without adequate checks by the central bank on his financial background. The government last week pledged `` absolute clarity'' in uncovering the scandal and warned there will be `` no pardons' for members of the ruling <ORGANIZATION> Panhellenic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Socialist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Movement </ORGANIZATION> -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> PASOK </ORGANIZATION> -RRB- who may be implicated. `` The Greek people are left with the conviction that <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Koskotas </PERSON> was spirited away so that he would not speak. The responsibility goes all the way to the top of the government pyramid,'' <PERSON> Constantine </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitsotakis </PERSON>, leader of the New Democracy main opposition party party, said in a statement demanding the government resign. <PERSON> Koskotas </PERSON> was suspended Oct. 20 as chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Crete </ORGANIZATION> and indicted on five counts of forgery and embezzlement. Last week <PERSON> Koskotas </PERSON> appeared before a district attorney on a charge of forging documents purporting to show that the <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Crete </ORGANIZATION> had $ 13 million invested with the American brokerage firm <ORGANIZATION> Merrill </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lynch </ORGANIZATION>. He was not detained but given until Nov. 14 to prepare his defense. <PERSON> Koskotas </PERSON> also is accused of forging documents purporting to show his bank had another $ 17 million in an account with an <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> bank, <ORGANIZATION> Irving </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Trust </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp </ORGANIZATION>. Both <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> firms have said they had no record of the deposits. <PERSON> Koskotas </PERSON>, who holds both <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> and Greek citizenship, bought a controlling interest in the <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Crete </ORGANIZATION> in 1984 after working in its central <LOCATION> Athens </LOCATION> branch for six years as an accountant. Rival newspapers have claimed <PERSON> Koskotas </PERSON> illegally used <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Crete </ORGANIZATION> money to fund his publishing group <PERSON> Grammi </PERSON>, which controls three daily newspapers, five magazines and a radio station. <PERSON> Koskotas </PERSON> resigned Oct. 29 as chairman of <PERSON> Grammi </PERSON>, the day after the premier's son, Education Minister <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Papandreou </PERSON>, denounced as a forgery a <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Crete </ORGANIZATION> statement showing a $ 2.3 million transfer to a <ORGANIZATION> Merrill </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lynch </ORGANIZATION> account in his name. The younger <PERSON> Papandreou </PERSON> showed reporters a letter from a <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> lawyer saying there was no record at <ORGANIZATION> Merrill </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lynch </ORGANIZATION> of such a transfer. <PERSON> Koskotas </PERSON>' parents, brother, wife and five children all have left <LOCATION> Greece </LOCATION> during the past week.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881107-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-07-88 2349EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--DisturbingPolice     11-07 0151</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Disturbing Police,0153</SECOND>
<HEAD>Drunken Polish Police Sentenced To Jail for Offending Worshippers</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WARSAW, Poland (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Two police officers who entered a pro-Solidarity church in <LOCATION> Gdansk </LOCATION> drunk during a Mass and offended worshippers have each been sentenced to more than a year in prison, the official <ORGANIZATION> PAP </ORGANIZATION> news agency reported. The officers behaved rudely in <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Brygida </LOCATION>'s Roman Catholic church, a center for the banned Solidarity trade union movement, during the July 22 service and physically attacked people who tried to evict them, worshippers reported at the time. <ORGANIZATION> PAP </ORGANIZATION> said in its report Monday that one of the officers was sentenced to 1 \ years in prison, the other to one year and two months for `` insulting religious feelings of the believers. The officers, who were not identified, were also fined the official equivalent of $ 167 each by the <LOCATION> Gdansk </LOCATION> court, <ORGANIZATION> PAP </ORGANIZATION> said. <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> is more than 90 percent Roman Catholic.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881107-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-07-88 2350EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-Homeless-Protest 3rdLd-Writethru a0747 11-07 0485</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Homeless-Protest, 3rd Ld-Writethru, a0747,420</SECOND>
<HEAD>Dozens Arrested in Capitol Protest of Homelessness</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: SUBS 8th graf pvs, bgng: ``Snyder organized...'' with 2 grafs
to add details; picks up 9th graf pvs, bgng: ``The rally...''</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By TIM AHERN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Police arrested 377 people, including prominent pediatrician and social activist <PERSON> Benjamin </PERSON> <PERSON> Spock </PERSON>, on Monday in the culmination of a long series of protests on <LOCATION> Capitol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION> called to focus attention on the plight of the homeless in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>. `` We're here to show the politicians that there is a crisis in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, a crisis that they are not responding to, a crisis that we want answers for,'' said <PERSON> Mitch </PERSON> <PERSON> Snyder </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> advocate for the homeless and organizer of the protests. <PERSON> Snyder </PERSON> led a march and 90-minute rally across Constitution Avenue from the Capitol building, capping the event with his exhortation to the crowd to sit down in the middle of the street and be arrested as way of showing concern for the homeless. Some 377 followed <PERSON> Snyder </PERSON>'s appeal and were arrested by police on charges of disorderly conduct and obstructing traffic on Capitol grounds, said <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Nichols </PERSON>, a spokesman for the Capitol police. The protest and arrests had been coordinated with Capitol police and were generally quiet. About 2,000 persons attended the rally, <PERSON> Nichols </PERSON> said. One of the speakers was the Academy Award-winning actress <PERSON> Cher </PERSON>, who had originally taken part in the march to the Capitol from a motel five miles away. She left the march to promote her new line of perfume, `` Uninhibited,'' but returned to the rally in a black van limousine. She left shortly before the arrests began. `` I'm sorry I'm late, but I had to go do my job,'' she explained. `` I'm here to show my concern and my support for the homeless. I'm very committed to the cause of the homeless People have to have it brought into their consciousness that the plight of the homeless is very serious.'' <ORGANIZATION> Snyder </ORGANIZATION>, of the Community for Creative Non-Violence, organized a series of protests beginning Sept. 26 to call attention to the plight of the homeless. <PERSON> Carol </PERSON> <PERSON> Fennelly </PERSON>, a member of the organization who also joined in the fast, has been bedridden and did not participate in Monday's protest. A total of 239 people have been arrested by Capitol police during the protest, <PERSON> Nichols </PERSON> said. Most were charged with unlawful entry. The rally took on the trappings of a political gathering, with dozens of people in the crowd sporting `` Dukakis-Bentsen'' buttons and signs in support of the Democratic presidential ticket. No signs in support of Vice President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, the Republican presidential nominee, were apparent. `` We've already seen what <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> can do during the eight years of the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration,'' said <PERSON> Snyder </PERSON>. `` Whoever wins the election, it will be a long fight to improve the situation for the homeless, but I think it will be easier if <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> wins.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881107-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-07-88 2349EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-NewAPBureau     11-07 0145</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-New AP Bureau,0146</SECOND>
<HEAD>New Bureau Opened In Northern Michigan</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TRAVERSE CITY, Mich. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> has opened a bureau in this northern <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION> city and appointed <LOCATION> Paige </LOCATION> <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> John </LOCATION> as its first correspondent. <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> Ackerman </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> chief of bureau in <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION>, announced the opening of the new Traverse City office Monday. It is the fourth AP bureau in <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION> and the 142nd in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. Ms. <PERSON> St. </PERSON> <PERSON> John </PERSON>, 27, has been a newswoman in <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION>'s <LOCATION> Charleston </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> W. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, bureau since joining the news cooperative in 1985 She is a native of Limestone, <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION>, and a graduate of <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Illinois </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. Before joining the AP, she worked on weekly newspapers in <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION>. In 1987, she received the <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Dougherty </PERSON> Award, which is presented annually by the <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> Managing Editors association for outstanding work by a young AP writer.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881107-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-07-88 0012EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Children'sTV Bjt   11-07 0672</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Children's TV, Bjt,680</SECOND>
<HEAD>Lawmakers Predict Next President Will Face New Children's TV Bill</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DEBORAH MESCE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Lawmakers angered by President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s veto of a bill to limit advertising in children's TV programs say <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> will be back next year with another, possibly tougher measure. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> killed the bill late Saturday night with a pocket veto, even though the measure had overwhelming support in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. Critics likened his action to `` ideological child abuse'' and called his administration `` morally bankrupt.'' <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said the bill to impose ad limits and make children's informational programming a condition of station license renewals would violate constitutional guarantees of free speech and might discourage commercial networks from financing quality children's But Rep. <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Markey </PERSON>, D-Mass., co-author of the bill, said the veto was another example of the administration putting `` commercial considerations and ideological precepts ahead of children's interests. `` The president's actions represent a victory for the toy and cereal hucksters, but a major defeat for our nation's children,'' said <PERSON> Markey </PERSON>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> telecommunications subcommittee. Rep. <PERSON> Matthew </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Rinaldo </PERSON> of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION>, ranking Republican on the subcommittee, said <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> acted on bad advice in killing the measure. `` It was a rather conservative piece of legislation with a minimal amount'' of regulation, far less onerous than earlier proposals that were considered but set aside in favor of the bipartisan compromise, he said. `` Next year, whoever is president will be faced with a tougher bill and a more determined <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>,'' <PERSON> Rinaldo </PERSON> predicted. The measure would have limited advertising in children's shows to 10 -LCB- minutes per hour on weekends and 12 minutes per hour on weekdays. The <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Communications </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> had imposed similar limits on broadcasters but scrapped them four years ago in the belief that self-regulation by the industry would determine what was best for children. The bill also would have required TV broadcasters to provide educational and informational programming for children as a condition of license renewal. The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> approved the measure on a voice vote last month. The <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> passed it by a margin of 328-78 in June. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said that while he supports efforts to improve the quality of children's programs, `` this bill simply can not be reconciled with the freedom of expression secured by our Constitution.'' He said, `` the Constitution simply does not empower the federal government to oversee the programming decisions of broadcasters in the manner prescribed by this bill.'' Children's television advocates had pushed for the bill because they said that under the <ORGANIZATION> FCC </ORGANIZATION>'s philosophy of deregulation, children's TV has become overcommercialized and the quality of programs has suffered. <PERSON> Peggy </PERSON> <PERSON> Charren </PERSON>, president of the <LOCATION> Cambridge </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Mass.-based </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Action </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Children </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Television </ORGANIZATION>, which has worked 20 years for passage of the measure, said she was `` flabbergasted'' by the veto. `` Here was a bill that was not going to raise the deficit, not going to raise taxes, was going to get a little bit of education for children ... and what <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said was you do n't have to do anything for children. I call it ideological child abuse,'' she said. The measure was a bipartisan compromise that had been stripped of proposals to outlaw shows, called `` program-length commercials'' by critics, that feature toy manufacturers' products and to require broadcasters to air an hour of educational programming per day. The final measure had the tacit support of the broadcasting industry after the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Broadcasters </ORGANIZATION> lobbied effectively against the stronger versions of the bill. <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> O. </PERSON> <PERSON> Fritts </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> NAB </ORGANIZATION>, said that `` while we recognize this legislation charted some new territory, we were willing to accept its outcome.'' The veto puts back on track an <ORGANIZATION> FCC </ORGANIZATION> inquiry into the commercialization of children's TV. The commission is considering whether it is necessary to impose advertising limits and regulate program-length commercials and interactive toys that respond to inaudible signals beamed through TV sets. But lawmakers and children's TV advocates say they do not expect the current <ORGANIZATION> FCC </ORGANIZATION> to depart from the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration's philosophy of deregulation
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881107-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-07-88 0021EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Cavazos     11-07 0692</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Cavazos,680</SECOND>
<HEAD>Education Secretary Wants To Be Hispanic Role Model</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto WX6</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JENNIFER DIXON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 On a recent trip back to <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, Education Secretary <PERSON> Lauro </PERSON> <PERSON> Cavazos </PERSON> insisted on shaking hands with every student who goes to school on the huge ranch where he was born. As they filed past the first Hispanic member of a president's Cabinet, the son of a ranch hand told each child how he too had once studied in the tiny schoolhouse nestled among the prickly brush and mesquite trees on the King Ranch `` You can do it if you just stay in school,'' <PERSON> Cavazos </PERSON> told them. `` When we talk to young people about opportunity through education, it helps to have a man at the top who proves through his own life and experience that the American system of opportunity through education works,'' says Sen. <PERSON> Phil </PERSON> <PERSON> Gramm </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Texas </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Cavazos </PERSON> was born on the King Ranch, which is the largest in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and covers 914,000 acres in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>. The ranch, which includes parts of six counties between <LOCATION> Harlingen </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Corpus </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Christi </LOCATION>, is the bedrock of one of the nation's biggest oil and gas fortunes and is credited with the development of the <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gertrudis </LOCATION> cattle breed, the first native to this country. <PERSON> Darwin </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, chairman and chief executive of <ORGANIZATION> Kimberly-Clark </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, is chairman of the privately held ranch. <PERSON> Cavazos </PERSON>, who began his schooling along with other cowboys' Spanish-speaking children at the ranch, became education secretary on Sept. 20 His nomination by President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> to replace <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON> from a list of Latino candidates was criticized by Hispanic leaders as a political ploy to bolster Republican presidential nominee <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> in the Hispanic community. Rep. <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Bustamante </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Antonio </LOCATION> Democrat and chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Congressional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hispanic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Caucus </ORGANIZATION>, said at the time: `` It seems that the administration has just discovered that Hispanics exist.'' But he praised <PERSON> Cavazos </PERSON>, the president of <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tech </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> and its medical school since 1980, as `` well respected, well prepared, with a history in education that is second to none.'' <PERSON> Cavazos </PERSON> will serve until Jan. 20 unless reappointed by the next president and brushes aside questions about the next turn in his career, saying he reached his life's goal when he became a full professor. He is firm in insisting no deal has been struck for him to remain in the Cabinet if <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> wins on Tuesday, but speculation is strong that <PERSON> Cavazos </PERSON> would be asked to stay. <PERSON> Cavazos </PERSON> has campaigned for the Republican ticket in trips that include visits to local schools, and emphasizes the need to keep students from dropping out and to educate the illiterate, handicapped and dyslexic to their fullest potential. In <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, he says, 45 percent of Hispanics do n't finish high school, while the rate for blacks is 32 percent. The national average is 28.5 percent. While economic troubles, early marriage, drugs or alcohol are blamed for the Hispanic dropout rate, <PERSON> Cavazos </PERSON> sees those as merely symptoms of an unraveling family structure unable to give children the support and confidence they need. `` If the family structure is tight and intact and if it values education, if it really wants to see these young people move ahead; I think therein is the fundamental problem. ... If that family structure is not a good, tight structure that supports education and encourages education and raises the vision of young people and says ` Yes son, yes daughter, you will educate yourself,' ... they can fall into the social ills I talked about.'' <PERSON> Cavazos </PERSON> credits his parents _ a cattle foreman and a homemaker who never went to college _ with encouraging their five children to get degrees. One son, <PERSON> Dick </PERSON>, became a four-star Army general, and another, <PERSON> Bob </PERSON>, was an all-America running back who now owns a ranch. A father of 10, <PERSON> Cavazos </PERSON>' voice fills with emotion when he recalls graduating from <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tech </ORGANIZATION> with his bachelor's degree. `` I was so proud, so proud, when I looked at my father when I got my baccalaureate degree,'' he says. `` And his pride in me when I went up the academic ladder there was so clear.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881107-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-07-88 0028EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FishingSafety     11-07 0584</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Fishing Safety,600</SECOND>
<HEAD>Voluntary Safety Programs Fail To Reduce Fishing Deaths</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LES BLUMENTHAL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Coast Guard's voluntary safety programs have failed to reduce the number of accidents and deaths in the nation's most dangerous industry, commercial fishing, says the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION>. The two agencies are about to lock horns again over the issue, with the <ORGANIZATION> NTSB </ORGANIZATION> pressing for mandatory licensing of captains and mandatory safety training for crews. Coast Guard officials insist their voluntary programs already have reduced the number of fishing boat accidents and fatalities, a contention disputed by the <ORGANIZATION> NTSB </ORGANIZATION>. `` Despite the <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> statement that fishing vessel casualty rates for 1986 and 1987 have decreased, safety board accident investigations indicate that major marine fishing vessel and property loss rates have not decreased from January 1978 until July 1988, and the death rate has increased in recent months,'' the <ORGANIZATION> NTSB </ORGANIZATION> said in a recent report. The report focused on the sinking of the Seattle-based fishing vessel UYAK II in the <LOCATION> Bering </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sea </LOCATION> almost a year ago. Two crew members, including the captain, were rescued but the bodies of four others were never recovered. The <ORGANIZATION> NTSB </ORGANIZATION> said the 115-foot vessel began to list, but it was not equipped with a general alarm system that could have alerted the crew to the problem. In the report and in a mid-October letter to <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> Commandant <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Yost </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, the safety board once again urged the <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> to seek congressional approval for a series of mandatory regulations including captain licensing, vessel inspection and crew safety training. `` We laid out what we think needs to be done, but our recommendations have no force of law,'' said <PERSON> Ted </PERSON> <PERSON> Lopatkiewicz </PERSON>, an <ORGANIZATION> NTSB </ORGANIZATION> spokesman. The <ORGANIZATION> NTSB </ORGANIZATION> says the fishing industry has the poorest safety record of any industry in the nation and the death rate for fishermen is seven times the national average for all industry groups. From January 1978 to April 1987, the safety board investigated 207 major fishing accidents which involved the loss of 147 lives and a total property loss of more than $ 165 million. That breaks down to 1.8 accidents, $ 1.4 million worth of property loss and 1.3 deaths per month. This year, <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> did approve legislation requiring commercial fishing vessels to carry such basic safety equipment as life rafts, survival suits and emergency transmitters. The <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> has 90 days to respond to the latest <ORGANIZATION> NTSB </ORGANIZATION> recommendations, most of which it has rejected outright over the past three years. For instance, since early 1986 the <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> has at least three times rejected the recommendation that it seek authority from <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to license fishing vessel captains. `` Before taking the more radical step of requiring these masters to be licensed, the voluntary program should be given a chance to demonstrate how effective it can be,'' the <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> said in a letter to the <ORGANIZATION> NTSB </ORGANIZATION> in March. The <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> said casualty rates declined in 1986 and 1987 and `` in our view, part of this improvement may be attributed to the voluntary program.'' The <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> also said mandatory licensing would require 225 new employees, cost $ 9 million to set up and $ 800,000 a year to run. <PERSON> Lopatkiewicz </PERSON> said agencies often are reluctant to adopt <ORGANIZATION> NTSB </ORGANIZATION> recommendations and that it takes time to win them over. `` We hope eventually they see the light,'' he said, adding that because it has only the power of recommendation the <ORGANIZATION> NTSB </ORGANIZATION> sometimes has to `` regulate by raised eyebrow.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881107-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-07-88 0029EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Jordan-Economy     11-07 0666</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Jordan-Economy,0686</SECOND>
<HEAD>Jordan Curbs Its Posh Life Style To Cut Deficit</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</NOTE>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN RICE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>AMMAN, Jordan (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The days of champagne and plastic roses are coming to an end in <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION>, a country running short of imported money to pay for imported goods. The government Saturday imposed taxes and restrictions on imports aimed at saving $ 200 million a year in foreign currency for this country of 2.8 million people. `` We started developing a champagne budget on a beer pocketbook ... This is why -LRB- the economy -RRB- has to be adjusted,'' said a senior government official, who spoke on condition of anonymity. The belt-tightening move appeared to be the first step in what the official said would be a three - to five-year period during which <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION> hopes to slash its $ 6 to $ 7 billion foreign debt The government banned new letters of credit to finance cars and trucks, video recorders, refrigerators, microwave ovens, television sets, chandeliers, marble, plastic flowers and fruit, and a dozen other goods. Finance Minister <PERSON> Hanna </PERSON> <PERSON> Odeh </PERSON> announced on television Sunday night that banning chandeliers alone will save $ 3 million. Goods already financed were slapped with stiff import duties, sending the price of some TV sets up 40 percent. To help cushion the blow, the government cut electricity and water bills. The blacklist targets the posh Western lifestyle many Jordanians adopted in the early 1980s, when their country was flush with money, much of it imported by hundreds of thousands of <LOCATION> Palestinians </LOCATION> with Jordanian passports who worked in the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION>. `` It will touch the conspicuous consumer class, which unfortunately we have developed,'' said <PERSON> Kamel </PERSON> <PERSON> Abu </PERSON> <PERSON> Jaber </PERSON>, a political scientist at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Jordan </ORGANIZATION>. He noted that `` the large masses of people'' would not be affected by the restrictions. Some officials have said privately that the economy has been hurt by King <PERSON> Hussein </PERSON>'s decision in July to renounce sovereignty over Palestinians in the Israeli-occupied <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION>, which <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION> governed from 1948 to 1967. Plans to remove their citizenship and give them two-year instead of five-year passports led some Palestinians to withdraw savings from <LOCATION> Jordanian </LOCATION> banks because of the uncertainty of their status in <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION>, one official said. One Western diplomat who requested anonymity estimated that nearly 30 percent of <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION>'s currency is held by Palestinians in the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> and the Israeli-occupied <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strip </LOCATION>. The new restrictions also follow a slide in the value of <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION>'s once - stable currency, the dinar, which was worth about $ 3 last year, drifted to about $ 2.66 last month and is now hovering around $ Bankers said the effective devaluation would help curb imports by raising their prices. More than half of the residents of <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION> are in a sense imports themselves _ families from <LOCATION> Palestine </LOCATION>, which is now <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>, who fled as refugees from their homeland in 1948 and 1967 and were granted citizenship. Many went to work in the gulf during the oil boom of the late 1970s. They sent a total of more than $ 1 billion back to families in <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION>, or through <LOCATION> Jordanian </LOCATION> banks to relatives in the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION>. The other mainstay of <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION>'s economy, <PERSON> Arab </PERSON> aid, has also been slipping. About $ 360 million a year have come from <LOCATION> Saudi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arabia </LOCATION> since 1979, but other Arab states have fallen short of the total $ 1.25 billion a year in aid they pledged to <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION> as a state on the front line with <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>. Since 1982, the slumping oil market also has been responsible for the reduction in foreign capital. But most Jordanian bankers and analysts seemed optimistic about the long-term prospects for a country rich in educated manpower. `` We've been living beyond our means and I believe that right now we have to adjust,'' said <PERSON> Jawad </PERSON> <PERSON> Anani </PERSON>, an economist who heads the <ORGANIZATION> Royal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Scientific </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Amman </LOCATION>. With the new policies discouraging imports and encouraging greater production, `` there's a very good chance for Jordanians to pull out of this,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881107-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-07-88 0032EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-FangLizhi     11-07 0796</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Fang Lizhi,0820</SECOND>
<HEAD>Astrophysicist Emerges As Communist China's Top Dissident</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</NOTE>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAN BIERS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Astrophysicist <PERSON> Fang </PERSON> <PERSON> Lizhi </PERSON> is happiest pondering the mysteries of the universe, but he has become embroiled in the more worldly affairs of politics by fearlessly speaking out against <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s communist government. <PERSON> Fang </PERSON>, 52, has emerged as <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s top dissident by publicly championing democracy and questioning Marxism in this one-party state. `` We hope we have a good government, but there is no guarantee,'' says the <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> Observatory professor with the easy manner and impish smile. `` The only guarantee comes from people's pressure.'' `` I like to speak freely,'' he said in a recent interview in his airy <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> apartment. `` I think I just show ... we have the right of speech.'' <PERSON> Fang </PERSON> emerged during pro-democracy student demonstrations that rocked major <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> cities in late 1986 and early 1987. Authorities said speeches he gave to students at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Science </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Technology </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Hefei </LOCATION> helped incite the protests. When <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s leaders cracked down on the protests, <PERSON> Fang </PERSON> was kicked out of the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> and fired from his university post. The demonstrations died down, but <PERSON> Fang </PERSON> refused to be silenced. Since his purge, he has given a series of interviews to foreign journalists, criticizing one-party rule and claiming Marxism is outdated and widely unpopular. No other Chinese of his stature has dared to publicly launch such attacks on the system. During a summer visit to <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Fang </PERSON> mentioned rumors that many Chinese leaders and their children maintained foreign bank accounts. Chinese authorities, reportedly displeased with his statements, subsequently withdrew permission for <PERSON> Fang </PERSON> to travel to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> later this year. <PERSON> Fang </PERSON> said he does not regret any of his comments and will continue to speak out. `` I'm a soldier who already crossed the river,'' he said. `` There's no way to turn back.'' Authorities are reluctant to allow <PERSON> Fang </PERSON> to speak before an audience, even on non-political topics, he said. At an informal gathering on the <ORGANIZATION> Beijing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> campus to mark the school's 90th anniversary in May, he was treated like a hero by several hundred students who came to hear him speak on science and democracy. When <PERSON> Fang </PERSON> was leaving, a crowd formed around him and students thrust forward books, envelopes, handkerchiefs and even money for the professor to sign. Letters of support come to <PERSON> Fang </PERSON> almost daily from around the country. He says they encourage him to continue his activities. The last person to embody support for democracy in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> was <PERSON> Wei </PERSON> <PERSON> Jingsheng </PERSON>, a former electrician at the <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> Zoo. He was sentenced to 15 years in jail in 1979 on charges of supplying military secrets to a foreign power and agitating to topple the Chinese communist system. The government, however, generally has attempted to show leniency toward <PERSON> Fang </PERSON> in an effort to improve the country's image. When reporters last year suggested his apartment on the <ORGANIZATION> Beijing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> campus was too small, authorities immediately gave him new quarters about twice the size. `` They want to use me. I know that,'' <PERSON> Fang </PERSON> said. `` On one side they do n't like me, they criticize me. -LRB- On -RRB- the other side, they want to show they are open.'' The official <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Review </LOCATION> in May published a lengthy feature on <PERSON> Fang </PERSON> and other official media ran articles about his scientific work. But the <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong-based </LOCATION> newspaper <ORGANIZATION> South </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> China </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Morning </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> says Chinese publications recently were instructed not to mention the professor's name. <PERSON> Fang </PERSON> was born to the family of a postal clerk in the southern coastal city of <LOCATION> Hangzhou </LOCATION> and was admitted to <ORGANIZATION> Beijing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> in 1952, at age 16, to study physics and nuclear reactor theory. He became one of <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s pioneer researchers in laser theory and won international attention with his research in cosmology, the study of the universe. <PERSON> Fang </PERSON> said his break with Marxism began over cosmology. According to the professor, former Politburo member <PERSON> Hu </PERSON> <PERSON> Qiaomu </PERSON> had questioned the need to study cosmology since Marxism already maintained the universe was infinite. `` This is an open question right now,'' <PERSON> Fang </PERSON> said. `` In cosmology, Marxism is not right.'' <PERSON> Fang </PERSON> lives with his wife, <PERSON> Li </PERSON> <PERSON> Shuxian </PERSON>, a professor of physics at <ORGANIZATION> Beijing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, and the younger of their two sons in an apartment about 780 square feet in size _ huge by <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> standards. A poster of <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Einstein </PERSON> hangs near the entrance and the apartment has a new personal computer and a video cassette recorder _ both rare items in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Fang </PERSON>, who earns $ 73 a month, receives $ 2,688 a year for research. He devotes much of his energy to writing scientific papers, and the 14 published this year include `` Physics and Beauty'' and `` Why Does n't the Universe Go Into Heat Death?''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881107-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-07-88 0033EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Grenada-MedSchool     11-07 0772</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Grenada-Med School,0794</SECOND>
<HEAD>Five Years On, Hard Times For American Medical School</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</NOTE>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT GLASS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ST. GEORGE'S, Grenada (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The American medical school in <LOCATION> Grenada </LOCATION> has fallen on hard times in the five years since invading <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> troops evacuated its students and flung the once-obscure school into the news. St. <PERSON> George </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medicine </ORGANIZATION>, whose students President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said were saved from becoming hostages of a Marxist government, is still turning out doctors on this lush tropical island at the southern tip of the <LOCATION> Caribbean </LOCATION>. The 11-year-old private school now boasts 1,390 graduates licensed in 45 <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> states, and clinical training programs at hospitals in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>. But as one of several so-called offshore schools in the region catering to to students rejected by <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> medical schools, St. <PERSON> George </PERSON>'s is straining from a steep decline in the overall number of young people going into medicine. Since the invasion of October 1983, enrollment at the school's two <LOCATION> Grenada </LOCATION> campuses has plunged from 480 to 226 It has cut its work force from 120 to 90 and put expansion plans on hold. Tuition has nearly doubled _ to $ 17,000 a year from $ 8,700 in 1983. A few years ago, <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> George </ORGANIZATION>'s accepted only one of every 10 applicants. Now it's taking one of every two. `` The caliber of our students has declined; I'll be candid about it,'' Chancellor <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Modica </PERSON>, said in an interview. `` But the American medical schools' pool of applicants has gone down.'' Despite the fall in enrollment, <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> George </LOCATION>'s still has 33 full-time professors, down just two from 1983, and 44 part-time visiting professors, down four. Officials say the school is in no danger of closing. `` There's no thinking in that respect,'' said spokesman <PERSON> Arthur </PERSON> <PERSON> Massolo </PERSON>. `` It's alive and kicking, and we intend to keep it that way.'' The <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> medical establishment has long denounced St. <PERSON> George </PERSON>'s and other offshore medical schools as `` diploma mills,'' but teachers and adminstrators say <PERSON> St. </PERSON> <PERSON> George </PERSON>'s students are highly motivated and score well on qualifying exams `` My kids get as good training in gross anatomy as they can get anywhere in the world,'' said Dr. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Christensen </PERSON>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Anatomy </ORGANIZATION>, who held the same post for seven years at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Missouri </ORGANIZATION> at <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. `` We could sell diplomas,'' he said, `` but a diploma does not permit you to practice medicine. You still have to take board-qualifying exams.'' <PERSON> Modica </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> lawyer, founded St. <PERSON> George </PERSON>'s at the age of 29 after being rejected by four <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> medical schools and spending a fruitless year in <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION> trying to become a doctor. The school grew steadily but attracted little attention until the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> decided to overthrow a radical pro-Cuban junta that seized power and murdered left-wing Prime Minister <PERSON> Maurice </PERSON> <PERSON> Bishop </PERSON>. In justifying the invasion, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said the students at <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> George </LOCATION><LOCATION> 's </LOCATION>, most of whom were Americans, were in danger of being taken hostage. They were evacuated in army helicopters by some of the 6,000 <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Marines </ORGANIZATION> and paratroopers who landed on the island Oct. 25, 1983, along with a token <LOCATION> Caribbean </LOCATION> force. A stately bronze monument bearing the engraved signatures of the 19 <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> servicemen killed in action reminds visitors St. <PERSON> George </PERSON>'s main campus on <LOCATION> Grand </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Anse </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION> was once a war zone Initially, school officials strongly opposed the invasion, saying <LOCATION> Grenada </LOCATION>'s rulers assured them the students would not be harmed. But within days, they changed their minds. <PERSON> Modica </PERSON> says today that he was briefed at the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> and shown documents of discussions within the revolutionary government that persuaded him the students might have been taken hostage. `` After the briefing, I felt that there was some justification for military action,'' he said. `` It was a close call, and I would n't have wanted to make the decision.'' <PERSON> Modica </PERSON> said enrollment peaked around the time of the invasion and has been falling for the past 2 -LCB- years. The reason, he said, is the medical profession, with its long, hard years of training and costly malpractice suits, has become much less attractive to <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> graduates over the past decade. Applications to <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> medical schools have dropped from 42,624 in 1974 to 28,123 last year, with the biggest decline occurring over the past four years, according to the Asssociation of American Medical Colleges. As a result, the nation's 127 accredited medical schools are opening their doors to students who just a few years ago would not have qualified, officials say. And that has shrunk the pool of applicants for schools like <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> George </ORGANIZATION>'s.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881107-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-07-88 0036EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-HouseRdp     11-07 0882</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-House Rdp,870</SECOND>
<HEAD>Likely Bush Win Seen Helping Few GOP House Hopefuls</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Election Rdp Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ALAN FRAM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Knox </PERSON> <PERSON> White </PERSON> wants the good people of <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>'s 4th Congressional District to think of him every time they hear <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s name _ a strategy many Republican hopefuls are pursuing this year. White, 34, a city councilman from <LOCATION> Greenville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> S.C. </LOCATION>, is trying to oust freshman Democratic Rep. <PERSON> Liz </PERSON> <PERSON> Patterson </PERSON> in a district that the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> presidential nominee is expected to sweep. So White's speeches and advertisements are studded with references to the vice president and, like <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, he repeatedly pledges to oppose tax increases, protect jobs and battle illegal drugs. `` Every Republican south of <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION>, is linking himself to <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>,'' says <PERSON> White </PERSON>'s campaign manager, <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Knight </PERSON>. Maybe so. But on the eve of what national polls indicate is likely to be a <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> victory over Democrat <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, few people expect either candidate to provide much of a boost to more than a few House hopefuls. Politicians and observers unanimously expect the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> to remain solidly Democratic, whatever the presidential race's outcome. And they agree that if <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> wins and if he pulls <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> contenders to victory at all, it is likely to be in only a handful of races scattered across the country, mainly in the conservative South. `` As <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> does better, it helps the image of the <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>,'' says <ORGANIZATION> North </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Carolina </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> chairman <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Hawke </PERSON>, in whose state there are four tight <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> races. `` But in the past we just have n't seen coattails that significantly in <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>.'' For the coattail effect to work, a presidential candidate must be so appealing that he draws large numbers of people to the polls who dutifully vote for other candidates of the same party. But in recent decades, strict party-line voting has been going the way of candidates who lack blow-dried coiffures. Beginning with President <PERSON> Eisenhower </PERSON>'s re-election in 1956, more than one quarter of the country's 435 House districts have voted for one party for president and the other party for its representative. In 1984, such ticket splitting between the presidential and <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> candidates occurred in 196 districts, or 45 percent. `` Most House races are pretty insulated from the presidential election,'' says spokeswoman <PERSON> Peggy </PERSON> <PERSON> Connolly </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Congressional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Campaign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>. The reasons are many. Increasing numbers of voters identify themselves as independents, and often decide congressional races on local issues, not national ones. And incumbents of both parties usually enjoy insurmountable fund-raising advantages and represent districts drawn to maximize their re-election prospects. Not only do most <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> incumbents seeking re-election win these days _ the success rate was 98 percent in 1986 _ but they are doing it so convincingly that they are usually invulnerable to defeat by their party's presidential candidate. Two years ago, nearly nine out of every 10 incumbents were re-elected with at least 60 percent of the major party vote, putting them far out of range of the 1 or 2 percent vote swing that a strong presidential candidate can bring to <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> contenders on his ticket. `` For there to be coattails this year, it would have to be in a race that's very close and in an area where <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> will do very well,'' says <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Wattenberg </PERSON>, a political science professor at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION> at <LOCATION> Irvine </LOCATION> who studies voting behavior. `` We're talking about a pretty minimal impact there.'' Political pros on both sides say about a dozen such races do exist. Besides the contest between White and <PERSON> Patterson </PERSON> _ who mentions <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' name as infrequently as possible _ others where presidential coattails might help are Republican <PERSON> Lyons </PERSON> <PERSON> Gray </PERSON>'s bid to oust Democratic Rep. <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> Neal </PERSON> in <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>'s 5th District; GOP Rep. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Hiler </PERSON>'s fight to hold off <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> challenger <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Ward </PERSON> in the <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION> 3rd; and Democrat <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnston </PERSON>'s fight with Republican <PERSON> Ken </PERSON> <PERSON> Adams </PERSON> to retain an open Democratic seat in the <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> 14th. But even though Republicans might pick up a few seats this year that may be attributed to <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s victory, it is possible that for the first time since 1960, the party that wins the presidential race might suffer a net loss of seats in the House. That is largely because while the 70 contests considered reasonably close are split evenly between Democratic and Republican seats, the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> holds 15 of the 27 open seats that are not being defended by an incumbent. Open seats are where turnover from one party to the other is most likely. It is even possible that in a losing effort, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> might still help Democrats in tight <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> races in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>, including Democratic Rep. <PERSON> Fernand </PERSON> <PERSON> St </PERSON> <PERSON> Germain </PERSON>'s effort to retain his 1st District <LOCATION> Rhode </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> seat against Republican <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Machtley </PERSON>, and Democrat <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Donchess </PERSON>'s fight for the open <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> seat in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION>'s 2nd District against Republican <PERSON> Chuck </PERSON> <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON>. Since the <ORGANIZATION> Democrats </ORGANIZATION> lost 20 <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> seats when President <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> was elected in 1960, the party of the winning presidential candidate has picked up seats in the chamber every four years. Since then, the presidential year swings have ranged from the 38 seats the Democrats won in President <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>'s 1964 victory to the two Democratic pickups that accompanied President <PERSON> Carter </PERSON>'s 1976 triumph.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881107-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-07-88 0036EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Jane's-Terrorism     11-07 0309</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Jane's-Terrorism,0317</SECOND>
<HEAD>Defense Publisher Issues Book on Security and Counter-Insurgency</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Jane </PERSON>'s defense publishers today expanded its series with a new volume on riot control, counter-insurgency weapons and equipment to detect and protect against terrorist action. `` The amount of effort and research being put into the defense of every realm against traditional threats is dwarfed by that going into the defense of the realm and the populace against the terrorist, the insurgent, the freedom fighter or the guerrilla under whatever color of ideological cloak,'' editor <PERSON> Ian </PERSON> <PERSON> Hogg </PERSON> says in his foreward to `` <PERSON> Jane </PERSON>'s Security and Counter-Insurgency Equipment.'' The new book by the respected defense information publisher lists equipment in five categories. The firearms section includes standard infantry weapons as well as guns for specialized security tasks. Operational equipment includes land, sea and air vehicles, surveillance aids such as night vision goggles, thermal imagers, explosives detectors and robots to set off discovered bombs. The riot control section lists a wide range of tear gas devices, stun grenades, plastic bullets and fragmentation grenades. Armor and protection includes bulletproof vests, flak jackets and even a bulletproof undershirt that wo n't be conspicuous under a business executive's shirt. The fifth section covers, transmitters, receivers, a fingerprint identification system, security fences and laser barriers. Not only does the terrorist `` have new types of ideology,'' <PERSON> Hogg </PERSON> says, `` they are familiar with new types of weaponry and in their ranks are people to whom technology is simply a better method of vanquishing their enemies. Moreover, they appear to have inexhaustible reserves of funds and backers with unlimited reserves of weapons and equipment.'' The new book was produced by <PERSON> Jane </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> Publishing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Ltd. </ORGANIZATION>, which publishes `` <PERSON> Jane </PERSON>'s Fighting Ships,'' `` <PERSON> Jane </PERSON>'s All The World's Aircraft'' and a variety of other yearly volumes on military hardware and other The company also publishes the magazine `` <PERSON> Jane </PERSON>'s Defense Weekly.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881107-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-07-88 0037EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-DowryDeaths     11-07 0236</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Dowry Deaths,0241</SECOND>
<HEAD>Four Sisters Commit Suicide, Fearing Father Can't Afford Dowries</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW DELHI, India (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Fearing their father could not raise enough money for their dowries, four sisters in southern <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> committed suicide, Indian news agencies said. The sisters hanged themselves with their saris from the ceiling of their house at <LOCATION> Alappulli </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Kerala </LOCATION> state, <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> India </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Trust </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> India </ORGANIZATION> reported Sunday. The four young women were concerned about the financial problems their father, a police constable, had after providing a dowry for their eldest sister, the news agencies said. The sisters _ <PERSON> Santha </PERSON>, 25, <PERSON> Sumati </PERSON>, 23, <PERSON> Anaka </PERSON>, 21 and <PERSON> Sasikala </PERSON>, 18 _ took their lives Friday while their father was away on duty and their mother was working in the family's rice paddy, according to the reports. Last February, three sisters between the ages of 18 and 22 hanged themselves over dowry problems in the northern state of <LOCATION> Uttar </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Pradesh </LOCATION>. Although <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> outlawed dowry in 1962, the practice of paying the groom's family is still widespread. Many marriages are still arranged by families before the bride and groom ever meet, and there are frequent reports of young women being set on fire by in-laws in dowry disputes that continue after the weddings. Such `` kitchen fires'' are reported almost every day by Indian newspapers. Last year, the government reported 1,572 cases of the crime, which is known as `` bride-burning.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881107-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-07-88 0039EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--Gandhi     11-07 0170</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Gandhi,0173</SECOND>
<HEAD>Indian Independence Leader Reinstated As Lawyer</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Forty years after his death, Indian independence leader <PERSON> Mohandas </PERSON> <PERSON> K. </PERSON> `` Mahatma'' <PERSON> Gandhi </PERSON> has been reinstated as a lawyer by the legal society in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> that disbarred him in 1922, a member of the society said. <PERSON> Gandhi </PERSON>, who protested British colonial rule with a campaign of passive resistance, was arrested and imprisoned in <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> several times in the 1920s. Because of that he was disbarred in 1922 by the <ORGANIZATION> Inner </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Temple </ORGANIZATION>, one of the four Inns of Court with exclusive right to call lawyers to the English bar. <PERSON> Gandhi </PERSON> was reinstated Sunday, the 100th anniversary of the start of his legal career at the Inner Temple. <PERSON> Patrick </PERSON> <PERSON> Sheehan </PERSON> of the legal society said the posthumous reinstatement indicated a changed point of view. `` I believe people were n't used to the idea of the revolting dominions, colonies, seeking their independence in that way,'' he said. <PERSON> Gandhi </PERSON> was assassinated in 1948 by a Hindu nationalist. <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> gained its independence the previous year.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881107-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-07-88 0040EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Veterans-Cost     11-07 0562</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Veterans-Cost,560</SECOND>
<HEAD>VA Expansion Will Cost More Than $9 Million</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TIM AHERN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Changing the Veterans Administration into the Department of Veterans Affairs may be relatively cheap as government programs go, but officials say it will still cost upwards of $ 9 million over the next decade. Much of that money will go for new signs and stationery for the government's fifth-largest agency, according to officials from the <ORGANIZATION> VA </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Congressional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Budget </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION>. But `` given the relative size, the cost impact is n't expected to be significant, particularly in any one given year,'' said <PERSON> Nina </PERSON> <PERSON> Shepard </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> CBO </ORGANIZATION> analyst who helped develop the cost projections. When the new department comes into being next March 15, it will be little different from the current VA, according to <PERSON> Bonner </PERSON> <PERSON> Day </PERSON>, a spokesman for the agency. `` I do n't think much has to be done before March 15. The essential duties have not been changed. The biggest difference is that the head of the agency will now be a member of the Cabinet,'' he explained. The agency wo n't move from any of its more than 500 buildings around the country, nor will its operations be greatly affected. `` Really, except for the different name and what that requires, we'll be the same as we are now,'' he explained. `` I do n't think you will see changes day to day.'' What is required by the name change are new signs _ thousands of them _ along with stationery with the new name. The <ORGANIZATION> VA </ORGANIZATION> has a $ 30 billion annual budget, much of which is disbursed in payments to the nation's veterans. There are about 27 million veterans and 49 million dependents of veterans or survivors, although only about 2.5 to 3 million use VA services on a regular basis. The bill creating the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Veterans </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Affairs </ORGANIZATION> as the 14th seat in the Cabinet was signed by President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> on Oct. 25, shortly after it had been given overwhelming approval by both the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>. Veterans organizations had long had the bill at the top of their legislative agenda and said moving the agency into the Cabinet would elevate the status of veterans. The VA is estimating a cost of $ 9.8 million for the switch, including $ 8.5 million for signs and the rest for changing stationary and the names on veterans publications. The signs will have to be changed at the more than 500 VA buildings around the country, Day said. The VA is still trying to figure out just exactly how many new signs it will need. The <ORGANIZATION> VA </ORGANIZATION> does n't plan to change all its signs or buy new stationery right away, Ms. <PERSON> Shepard </PERSON> said. `` We tried to find out the number of signs, but they did n't have an exact figure at hand.'' `` As the old stationary runs out, they will buy new stuff,'' she said. Similarly, the signs will be redone over the next five years. During the congressional debate over changing the <ORGANIZATION> VA </ORGANIZATION>'s status, some legislators said the total cost might be $ 33 million, far higher than the $ 9.8 million figure. But that estimate was for a different bill, which would have substantially expanded the staff of the agency's inspector general department, the office which guards against wrongdoing. The bulk of the additional money would have gone to hire new staff members, Ms. <PERSON> Shepard </PERSON> said. Those provisions were dropped.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881107-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-07-88 0044EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Candidates-Deficit     11-07 0761</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Candidates-Deficit,740</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush, Dukakis Pledge To Cut Deficit, But Propose Spending More</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Election Rdp, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ALEXANDER G. HIGGINS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> each promise to cut the federal deficit if elected president, but their proposals for new programs could put the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> deeper in debt, economic and political analysts say. Each candidate has described or endorsed plans covering areas from defense to child care that could total billions of dollars in increased spending if adopted by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> without offsetting cuts in other spending. `` These guys are going in the opposite direction,'' said Professor <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Thurber </PERSON>, director of the <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Congressional </ORGANIZATION> and Presidential Studies at <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. `` They're talking about spending money rather than saving money.'' <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Aaron </PERSON>, senior fellow in economic studies at the <ORGANIZATION> Brookings </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institution </ORGANIZATION>, cited `` the failure of both candidates in my view to deal responsibly with the deficit problem.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> have expressed concern about the budget deficit, which was $ 155 billion in fiscal 1988, which just ended. The national debt, under $ 1 trillion when <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> took office, is now more than $ 2.6 trillion. Concerns about the deficit's potential effect on the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and global economies played a role in last year's drop in world stock markets and led to an agreement between <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and the <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to limit spending. <PERSON> Thurber </PERSON> said the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> budget deficit remains one of the main concerns to foreign investors, who now are loaning the money to pay for more than half of the debt and are concerned about the security of their funds. `` They do n't have very many other places to send their money, but they're wondering if they'll ever get their money out of this situation,'' said <PERSON> Thurber </PERSON>. <PERSON> Marvin </PERSON> <PERSON> Kosters </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Enterprise </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> said new programs could be adopted without increasing the budget deficit if other programs are cut, but `` not painlessly, and not without political conflict, certainly.'' <PERSON> Aaron </PERSON> said he thinks pressures in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> will keep any new programs small and have them `` self-financed'' by eliminating tax benefits or cutting other programs. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> has said he would cut some nuclear weapons, but his pledge to build up conventional arms could prove `` very costly,'' said <PERSON> Thurber </PERSON>. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has criticized <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> for opposing both the mobile MX and Midgetman missiles, but acknowledges he can not afford to press ahead with both. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> says <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> is naive to let the Soviets know in advance what missiles he will eliminate. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s proposals include a $ 3.7 billion `` Invest In Our Children'' package aimed at children of low-income families that would help provide day care, more pre-school education and better health care. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> endorsed the concept, but not the exact dollar amount, of the $ 2.5 billion `` A Better Child'' day care bill that failed to win approval in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> this year. It would set federal standards and funnel money to states to expand day-care slots. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> wants to spend $ 100 million on prenatal health care that he claims would pay for itself in a year because infants born under the plan would be healthier and require less hospital care after birth. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> also wants to require all but the smallest employers to offer basic health insurance to workers and their families _ a move he says will cost the government nothing, but which <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> says amounts to a new tax of at least $ 35 billion on those businesses. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> says his plan would insure 22 million of the nation's 37 million uninsured. <PERSON> Aaron </PERSON> said that over time it would reduce tax revenues because it would shift some income from the taxable category to the untaxable fringe-benefit category. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> proposes a reduction in capital gains taxes, which would benefit people with investments in the stock market and elsewhere, at a cost estimated by the <ORGANIZATION> Congressional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Budget </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> at $ 3.9 billion a year. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> claims the tax reduction would free up money for more private investment, creating jobs and stimulating the economy; thus, in the end it would work toward reducing the deficit, because the government would have more people paying taxes. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> vows he would adopt `` no new taxes'' and claims he would eliminate the deficit by putting a `` flexible freeze'' on government spending to keep total growth at the inflation rate. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> says he would increase enforcement of tax collection and would raise taxes only as a last resort. But `` they're just not going to get that much more money out of it,'' said <PERSON> Thurber </PERSON>, adding that the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration has already increased the number of agents pursuing tax cheats.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881107-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-07-88 0047EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-PresidentialPolls     11-07 0830</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Presidential Polls,810</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush Leads in National Polls; Margin Ranges from Five to 12</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Election Rdp Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GARY LANGER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A barrage of pre-election polls has given <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> a lead for popular votes in the presidential contest and an even greater advantage in the more critical race for electoral votes. With Election Day looming, a 50-state poll by <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> put 25 states firmly in <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s column and another 16 leaning his way. Only the <LOCATION> District </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION> was firm for Democrat <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>. Though the poll did not jibe with all other individual state assessments, it assigned <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> a daunting lead: His 25 firm states alone would provide more than the 270 electoral votes needed for election. In national popularity, the <ORGANIZATION> ABC-Post </ORGANIZATION> poll gave <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> a 10-point lead among likely voters, 54-44 percent. Gallup found <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> up by 12 points, a <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> poll said nine points and a <ORGANIZATION> USA </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Today-CNN </ORGANIZATION> poll said 11. <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News-Wall </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Street </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Journal </ORGANIZATION> and <PERSON> Harris </PERSON> polls found a closer race, with a 5-point <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> lead. The differing results indicated continuing indecision and dissatisfaction among some voters, factors that can accentuate the effect of differences in polling dates and methods, such as identifying likely voters. There was room for movement: One in five respondents in the Gallup and NBC-Journal polls were undecided or said they could change their minds, and in Gallup's poll only about half of each candidate's support was strong. Gallup, however, said its undecided respondents appeared likely to split evenly, on the basis of their background and ideology. Voter dissatisfaction was clear. Two-thirds in the <ORGANIZATION> NBC-Journal </ORGANIZATION> poll said the campaign was one of the worst in recent history, as many were unhappy with the nominees' discussion of the issues and six in 10 said they wished other candidates were running. As it was, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> led in most ratings on presidential ability. Likely voters by 62-25 percent said he would be better able to maintain a strong defense, and he outranked <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> on crime, the economy and foreign policy. The ABC-Post's state-by-state poll underlined the difficulty of <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' position: He needed to win all his firm and leaning states, all the tossup states, all the leaning <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> states and at least one firm <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> state. The poll, conducted by re-interviewing most of the respondents in a 50-state survey in early October, found 17 states moving toward <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and only three moving toward <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>. The number of states firmly or leaning for <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> actually declined from eight to four. The results did not agree with all recent state polls. <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> was rated as leaning to <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, for example, although a recent state poll put <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> slightly ahead in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> state also was said to be leaning for <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, although a poll there last week put <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> ahead by 10 points. <ORGANIZATION> USA </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Today </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> CNN </ORGANIZATION> conducted five separate state polls, finding <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> ahead in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, 54-45; in <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, 58-42; and in <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION>, 53-46. It was about even in <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION>, 51-48 for <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, and <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION>, 51-49 for <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. Although the other new national surveys were not large enough for state-by-state results, Gallup found the race tight in the East and <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> leading strongly in all other regions, particularly the South. The closer NBC-Journal poll found <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> leading well in the South and West with tight races in the East and <LOCATION> Midwest </LOCATION>. In popularity nationwide, the <ORGANIZATION> ABC-Post </ORGANIZATION> poll found a slight decline from a 13-point <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> lead late last month. The other polls Sunday also found some tightening, although they disagreed on its extent. The ABC-Post poll was weighted to an effective sample size of 1,500 likely voters for the national popularity figure, with a margin of error of plus or minus three points. Margins of error varied state-by-state, and <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> made characterizations of the state results without releasing numbers. In addition to the <LOCATION> District </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION> firmly for <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, it said <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION> were leaning his way. Tossups were <ORGANIZATION> Illinois </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Rhode </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Vermont </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>. Leaning for <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> were <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. The rest were rated as firm for <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> and the Journal polled 1,721 likely voters Tuesday through Saturday; Gallup, 1,969 Thursday through Saturday; <PERSON> Harris </PERSON>, 2,114 Wednesday through Saturday; <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 1,585 Friday and Saturday; <LOCATION> USA </LOCATION> Today-CNN 2,506 nationally and about 500 in each of the five states, Thursday through Sunday. The Gallup and <PERSON> Harris </PERSON> polls had margins of error of plus or minus two percentage points; the NBC-Journal and <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> polls, three points; the <ORGANIZATION> USA </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Today-CNN </ORGANIZATION> polls, two points for the national sample, four for the states. In addition to the ABC-Post finding of 54-44 percent <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, the numerical results were: <LOCATION> USA </LOCATION> Today-CNN, 55-44; Gallup, 53-41; <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 51-42; <PERSON> Harris </PERSON>, 50-45; NBC-Journal, 48-43. All included leaning voters except the <ORGANIZATION> NBC-Journal </ORGANIZATION> poll; including them, its result was 50-45.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881107-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-07-88 0049EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Smoking     11-07 0634</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Smoking,580</SECOND>
<HEAD>Cigarette Use Down, Spending Up</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDS: stands for PM-Farm Scene</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By DON KENDALL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Farm Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Despite a decline in smoking, annual spending by Americans on cigarettes is climbing and probably will continue to do so through the rest of this century, says an Agriculture Department economist. `` Manufacturers will face falling domestic volume and will need to raise prices to maintain profits,'' <PERSON> Verner </PERSON> <PERSON> Grise </PERSON> said. `` Tax rates of state and local governments will continue to rise. The need for additional tax revenues is mounting, and tobacco taxes, especially cigarettes, have been a mainstay of state revenue systems for many years.'' <PERSON> Grise </PERSON>, who specializes in tobacco analysis for the department's <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>, said that in addition to federal and state taxes `` a growing number of local jurisdictions are looking to the same revenue source. Reporting in the agency's latest <ORGANIZATION> Agricultural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Outlook </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> magazine </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Grise </PERSON> said there have been dramatic changes in the last decade. `` Spending for cigarettes is double what it was 10 years ago,'' he said. `` But the rise reflects higher prices, not more use. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> consumption has fallen 10 percent from its peak of 640 billion cigarettes in 1981. Retail cigarette prices, on the other hand, have risen about 90 percent since 1980.'' Most of the increase has been from higher manufacturer and wholesale prices, and from the boosts in taxes. Prices go up to maintain or enhance profits as well as to cover rising manufacturing costs. Last year, <PERSON> Grise </PERSON> said, Americans spent about $ 33.5 billion on cigarettes, a little more than 1 percent of consumer disposable income and approximately the same proportion as 10 years ago. Cigarette excise taxes totaled about $ 9.7 billion in 1987, compared with $ 6.6 billion in 1980, he said. Federal taxes accounted for 49 percent, with state and local governments the remainder. But looked at another way, total excise taxes only accounted for 29 percent of consumer expenditures on cigarettes in 1987, down from 34 percent in 1980. <PERSON> Grise </PERSON> said that although taxes rose, the marketing bill for manufacturing, distributing and merchandising cigarettes increased faster. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has had an excise tax on cigarettes since 1862, <PERSON> Grise </PERSON> said, and since 1969 all states have imposed such taxes, along with an increasing number of local governments. <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> was the first state to impose a cigarette tax in 1921, and by 1950 40 states and the <LOCATION> District </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION> were taxing cigarettes. Rates now range from 2 cents per pack of 20 cigarettes in <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> _ the leading producer _ to 38 cents in <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Grise </PERSON> said that makes a weighted <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> average tax of about 18 cents per pack. `` The increase in spending on cigarettes in the 1980s has largely gone to manufacturers,'' he said. `` The farm value of cigarette expenditures was actually $ 100 million less in 1987 than in 1980.'' Tobacco farmers in 1980 received 7.5 cents of each dollar spent by cigarette users, but in 1987 growers got only 4 cents, <PERSON> Grise </PERSON> said. `` Meantime, the manufacturer's share -LRB- of each dollar spent -RRB- rose from 35 cents to 44,'' he said. `` The distributor's share stood at 24 cents in 1980 but retreated to 23 cents in 1987.'' Federal excise taxes edged to 14 cents of the consumer dollar last year from 13 cents in 1980. Back in the 1950s and 1960s, federal taxes accounted for up to 35 cents of each cigarette dollar. <PERSON> Grise </PERSON> said state and local taxes rose to more than 20 cents of each dollar in the 1970s and early 1980s but dropped to about 15 cents in 1987. Of about $ 33.5 billion spent on cigarettes last year, <PERSON> Grise </PERSON> said the farm value was approximately $ 1.35 billion; the manufacturing share, $ 14.9 billion; wholesaling and retailing, $ 7.62 billion; federal taxes, $ 4.73 billion; and state and local taxes, $ 4.95 billion.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881107-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-07-88 0050EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-SenateRdp     11-07 0837</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Senate Rdp,830</SECOND>
<HEAD>Democrats Confident of Retaining Senate Lead; GOP Talking Momentum</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Election Rdp Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LAWRENCE L. KNUTSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats are confident they will keep their controlling grip on the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> no matter which party wins the White House in Tuesday's election. Party organizers even hope to chip away at <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> seats, perhaps bolstering their 54-46 majority by one or more seats. Republicans, however, say the momentum is turning in their favor in races across the country, while conceding that every tight race will have to break in their favor if they are to stand even a chance of regaining the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> control they lost two years ago. Strategists in both parties say an unusual volatility in the electorate this year adds an element of uncertainty that could lead to election-night surprises. As the campaign moved into its final hours, GOP <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> candidates in states in which polling has given Vice President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> wide margins over Democratic rival <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> have moved to identify themselves with <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and his political themes. Political money flowed freely. The <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Election </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> reported that as of Oct. 19, <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> candidates of both parties had raised a total of $ 157.5 million. The most expensive race in the country to date: <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, where Sen. <PERSON> Pete </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON>, R-Calif., spent more than $ 10 million and Democratic Lt. Gov <PERSON> Leo </PERSON> <PERSON> McCarthy </PERSON> spent more than $ 5 million. The race was a tossup on the eve of the election. Overall, it appeared to be a good year for most incumbents, who attracted the lion's share of campaign contributions. In many of their races it appears to be a case of no contest. Most of the 15 Democratic incumbents seeking re-election appear to be safe, cushioned by leads of 10 or more points. Only three of the 12 Republicans seeking further six-year terms appear to be in trouble. Among Democrats, late polling showed Sen. <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Lautenberg </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.J. </LOCATION>, pulling ahead of former <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Brig </ORGANIZATION>. Gen. <PERSON> Pete </PERSON> <PERSON> Dawkins </PERSON> after weeks of harshly negative campaigning. Sen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Melcher </PERSON>, D-Mont., was locked in a head-to-head contest with rival Republican <PERSON> Conrad </PERSON> <PERSON> Burns </PERSON> with <PERSON> Melcher </PERSON> recycling television ads featuring talking cows from his 1982 campaign In this case, the cows call <PERSON> Burns </PERSON> a `` greenhorn'' who would be out of his depth in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. Among Republican incumbents, strong challenges are being mounted for the seats held by Sen. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Karnes </PERSON>, R-Neb.; Chic Hecht, R-Nev.; and <PERSON> Lowell </PERSON> <PERSON> Weicker </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Conn </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Karnes </PERSON> appeared headed for defeat, while <PERSON> Hecht </PERSON> and <PERSON> Weicker </PERSON> were battling down to the But much of the action revolves around three of the six seats being vacated by retiring senators, three Republicans and three Democrats. There are clear favorites in <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Vermont </LOCATION>. Former Democratic Gov. <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Robb </PERSON> is widely expected to capture the seat being vacated by one-term Sen. <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Trible </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Va </LOCATION>. Rep. <PERSON> Trent </PERSON> <PERSON> Lott </PERSON>, R-Miss., the House Republican whip, is favored to take the seat of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>'s most senior Democrat, <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Stennis </PERSON>, who is And Rep. <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Jeffords </PERSON>, R-Vt., is favored to win the seat of retiring Sen. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Stafford </PERSON>, R-Vt The three others _ in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION> _ are tossups, and may contain a key to the final outcome of the 1988 <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> campaign. In <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION>, millionaire businessman <PERSON> Herb </PERSON> <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON>, the Democrat, has outspent Republican <PERSON> Susan </PERSON> <PERSON> Engeleiter </PERSON>, the minority leader of the state <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> and held onto a shrinking lead despite criticism he has never before held public office. In <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>, Republican Rep. <PERSON> Connie </PERSON> <PERSON> Mack </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON> was locked in a tight battle with Democrat Rep. <PERSON> Buddy </PERSON> <PERSON> MacKay </PERSON> for the seat being vacated by Democrat <PERSON> Lawton </PERSON> <PERSON> Chiles </PERSON>. A dead heat for the seat being left by Sen. <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Evans </PERSON>, R-Wash., has developed between former GOP Sen. <PERSON> Slade </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorton </PERSON> and Rep. <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Lowry </PERSON>, D-Wash. <PERSON> Lowry </PERSON> has run a series of negative ads, including one accusing <PERSON> Gorton </PERSON> of voting `` against the environment'' in his previous <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> The Gorton camp retaliated, recruiting <PERSON> Evans </PERSON> for a television spot in which he accuses <PERSON> Lowry </PERSON> of distorting <PERSON> Gorton </PERSON>'s record and tells him: `` <PERSON> Mike </PERSON>, you've been spreading so much stuff I've had to change my shoes.'' The camera then pulls back, the picture widens and <PERSON> Evans </PERSON>, dressed in a three-piece business suit, displays dirt-splattered work boots. Viewing the horseraces, Democratic and <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> strategists saw it this way: Sen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Kerry </PERSON>, D-Mass., chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Campaign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>: `` The Democrats will hold 54 seats at a minimum and I believe have a very good chance to add ... There is a unique volatility in the electorate.'' <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Mason </PERSON>, spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Campaign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>: `` We are probably more enthusiastic about our chances now than at any point in the cycle. We think the momentum is going our way almost across the board. But we will have to win all the close ones. ... But it's still quite volatile out there and we could still end up on Election Day minus two. But we could just as easily be plus two or better.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881107-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-07-88 0102EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FarmBriefs     11-07 0258</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Farm Briefs,240</SECOND>
<HEAD>Jamaica Will Neld Help Restoring Poultry Flock</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Jamaica </LOCATION>'s poultry flock was almost wiped out in mid-September by <PERSON> Hurricane </PERSON> <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON>, and the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> says the <LOCATION> Caribbean </LOCATION> nation will need additional aid to get it reestablished. A report by the department's <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> says only about 150,000 of <LOCATION> Jamaica </LOCATION>'s normal flock of 5 million birds were spared by the storm. Beef and dairy operations apparently were damaged less severely, but heavy losses were reported for crops, including sugar cane, bananas and tree products. Poultry accounts for nearly 60 percent of the meat consumption of <LOCATION> Jamaica </LOCATION>'s 2.5 million people. About 60 percent is produced domestically, the rest from imports, mainly from the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. Loans under various <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> credit programs have been stepped up to help <LOCATION> Jamaica </LOCATION> buy food, breeding stock, hatching eggs and other items needed to recover from the storm, the agency said.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 This year is the 30th anniversary of the first sales of instant noodles in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, and a report from <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION> says the noodles have become a regular part of the Japanese diet and lifestyle. Originally a snack food for children, the noodles _ known as ramen _ now are consumed at the annual rate of 4.5 billion packets, based on 1987 figures by the <ORGANIZATION> Japan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Instant </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Food </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Industry </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>. The report said that Japanese men, on the average, consume 3.7 packets a month; women, 2.8; and young people, 4.6. Overall, the instant noodles make up an estimated 5 percent of Japanese food expenditures.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881107-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-07-88 0105EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-NewCaledonia     11-07 0482</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-New Caledonia,0495</SECOND>
<HEAD>French Voters Approve Plan For New Caledonia, But White Islanders
Vote No</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JEFFREY ULBRICH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PARIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 French voters have approved a program to grant more autonomy to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Caledonia </LOCATION> and permit an independence referendum in 1998 on the <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> territory, but turnout was light and many white islanders voted no. The government of Socialist Premier <PERSON> Michel </PERSON> <PERSON> Rocard </PERSON> is hoping the statute, which passed Sunday, will buy 10 years of peace in the islands that have suffered from intercommunal violence since 1984. The statute includes a development program for native Melanesians. With all votes in except from a few <LOCATION> Caribbean </LOCATION> territories, 80 percent of the vote was in favor of the new statute and 20 percent against. Turnout, however, was a mere 37.3 percent, the worst showing for any national election since the end of World War II. The archipelago of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Caledonia </LOCATION>, 11,000 miles from <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION>, has been rent by periodic violence between the native Melanesians, known as Kanaks, and white European settlers. Kanaks, most of whom favor independence, make up 43 percent of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Caledonia </LOCATION>'s 145,000 inhabitants. The settlers, most of whom want to remain French, are 37 percent. The rest of the population is made up of Polynesians and Asians, who generally favor <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>. After another round of violence last spring that left 25 people dead, <PERSON> Kanak </PERSON> leader <PERSON> Jean-Marie </PERSON> <PERSON> Tjibaou </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jacques </PERSON> <PERSON> Lafleur </PERSON>, leader of the anti-independence forces, signed an agreement with <PERSON> Rocard </PERSON> on the island's future. Tjibaou and <PERSON> Lafleur </PERSON> demanded a referendum to seal the deal. But <PERSON> Tjibaou </PERSON>, <PERSON> Lafleur </PERSON> and <PERSON> Rocard </PERSON> did not get strong national backing for their plan. Only 14.5 million of <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>'s 38 million voters cast ballots. And of them, 13 percent cast blank or invalid ballots. In <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Caledonia </LOCATION> itself, turnout was much higher at 63.7 percent, but the approval much less. `` Yes'' received 57.03 percent and `` no'' 42.9. The opposition vote was largely in the south, where most of the European population lives. In <LOCATION> Noumea </LOCATION>, the capital and white settler heartland, 63.7 percent voted against the plan. `` Democracy has spoken,'' <PERSON> Rocard </PERSON> said after the polls closed. `` It appears that 12 million French have just approved the statute. This statute is from now on the law of <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>.'' The draft law voted on in the referendum proposes a new local autonomy statute for <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Caledonia </LOCATION>, the seventh since the end of World War II. It divides the archipelago into three provinces, each with its own provincial assembly and local administration. The law also provides amnesty for any person charged with actions of a political nature before Aug. 20, except murder. It also provides for a program of economic development in Melanesian areas and training of local residents to assume administrative tasks. <PERSON> Tjibaou </PERSON> admitted that the 42.9 percent `` no'' vote `` is very large. It is a significant handicap for the future. We must be very vigilant.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881107-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-07-88 0110EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-People-Kean-Dog     11-07 0353</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-People-Kean-Dog,0365</SECOND>
<HEAD>New Jersey Governor Steps In To Save Dog</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MILFORD, N.J. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
