<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880218-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-PX-02-18-88 2345EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Mexico-Protest     02-18 0385</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Mexico-Protest,0400</SECOND>
<HEAD>Thousands Demonstrate Against Government Economic Plan</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JUAN MALTES</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MEXICO CITY (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 About 60,000 demonstrators gathered Thursday night in the main Zocalo plaza to protest the government's new inflation-fighting program which has sparked higher prices throughout the economy. The protesters demanded that the government place controls on prices, nearly triple the minimum daily wage and halt payments on its foreign debt of $ 105 billion, the second highest in the developing world after <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION>. There were no reports of arrests or violence. <PERSON> Ignacio </PERSON> <PERSON> Betancourt </PERSON>, who spoke on behalf of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Resistance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION>, said the government of President <PERSON> Miguel </PERSON> de la <LOCATION> Madrid </LOCATION> has `` stabbed the people by implementing the -LRB- Economic Solidarity -RRB- Pact.'' He said de la <LOCATION> Madrid </LOCATION>'s Cabinet should be fired because it `` has brought the country to disaster.'' The resistance front represents the opposition <ORGANIZATION> Revolutionary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Workers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Workers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> the </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Autonomous </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mexico </ORGANIZATION> and a dissident wing of the governing <ORGANIZATION> Institutional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Revolutionary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Cuauhtemoc </PERSON> <PERSON> Cardenas </PERSON>, who left the governing party to run as the presidential candidate of small opposition parties, was among the protest leaders. The Economic Solidarity Pact was put into effect in mid-December. As part of the plan, the government boosted prices on a variety of regulated goods and services by an average of 78 percent. The minimum daily wage was boosted 38 percent and now stands at 7,765 pesos, about $ 3.40. On March 1, the government will begin an indexation plan that will increase wages and prices a certain amount each month based on projected inflation. The government's aim is to reduce the monthly rate of inflation to 1 percent to 2 percent by year's end. Consumer prices soared 15.5 percent in January. Prices rose a record 159.2 percent last year. Private analysts estimate that workers have lost half their purchasing power since 1982. <ORGANIZATION> De </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> la </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Madrid </ORGANIZATION> said Wednesday that inflation is `` the most serious problem we face'' and will be managed `` in a prudent, sensible and realistic way.'' De la <LOCATION> Madrid </LOCATION> spoke during an appearance in <LOCATION> Toluca </LOCATION>, 45 miles northwest of <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. Despite the government's efforts, some private analysts predict that inflation will be in the range of 150 percent to 200 percent this year. Labor leaders are threatening massive strikes in March unless major salary increases are granted.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880218-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-PX-02-18-88 2353EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Salvador-Americans     02-18 0323</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Salvador-Americans,0333</SECOND>
<HEAD>Two California Women Detained, Released In El Salvador</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SAN SALVADOR, El Salvador (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Police on Thursday detained and questioned two <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> women working in a resettlement camp then turned them over to the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION>, officials said. An Episcopal minister, the Rev. <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON> of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Marino </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, identified the two as <PERSON> Kathleene </PERSON> <PERSON> Hoy </PERSON> and <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Parmenter </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Pasadena </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif </LOCATION>. He claimed their detention was a part of increased harassment of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> ecumenical workers by Salvadoran authorities in recent months. The two <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> women were detained `` for entering restricted areas without authorization,'' said agent <PERSON> Orlando </PERSON> <PERSON> Ramirez </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION>, whose jurisdiction includes investigations of customs and immigration violations. <PERSON> Ramirez </PERSON> said they were apprehended at the Copapayo camp near <LOCATION> Suchitoto </LOCATION>, about 25 miles northwest of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>. Guerrillas frequently carry out operations in the area. He said the women, along with seven Salvadorans, were detained Thursday morning and brought to the capital. The two <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> citizens were released into the custody of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Vice Consul <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Schall </PERSON> after several hours of questioning, he said. <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Jacob </PERSON> <PERSON> Gillespie </PERSON> said the Privacy Act prevented him from confirming the women's names or details of the incident. But he agreed with the <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION> report that two <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> women were detained and later released. <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON>, chairman of a diocesan task force for Salvadoran resettlement, said he was informed of the detention by telephone by a <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> official in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>. He said the military has been harassing Americans providing humanitarian assistance in <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION> since about 20,000 Salvadoran refugees in <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION> decided to return to their homeland last fall. `` Since then, the government nervousness and harassment of ecumenical workers has increased ... Our concern is that this kind of caseworker harassment has happened to others who are strictly down there for humanitarian reasons,'' he said. Guerillas from five leftist groups have been fighting since 1980 to overthrow the U.S.-backed government.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880218-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-18-88 0248EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-APAppointment     02-18 0195</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AP Appointment,0199</SECOND>
<HEAD>Tokyo, London News Editors Named</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Thorson </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> news editor in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> for the past five years, has been named <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION> news editor, based in <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION>, and will be succeeded in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> by correspondent <PERSON> Marcus </PERSON> <PERSON> Eliason </PERSON>. The appointments were announced Wednesday by <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> President <PERSON> Louis </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Boccardi </PERSON>. <PERSON> Thorson </PERSON>, 47, has been stationed overseas for the <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> since 1976, beginning with seven years in <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>. He was <LOCATION> Tel </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Aviv </LOCATION> bureau chief in 1980-83. He joined <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION> in 1970. In 1972, he was transferred to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, where he worked primarily on the <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Desk </ORGANIZATION>, with stints on the <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Desk </ORGANIZATION> and at the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION>. Before joining <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> he served as a Peace Corps volunteer in <LOCATION> Thailand </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Eliason </PERSON>, 41, joined <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Tel </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Aviv </LOCATION> in 1967 and became correspondent in charge of the <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION> office in 1972. In 1978 he was transferred to <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> and returned to <LOCATION> Tel </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Aviv </LOCATION> in 1980 as news editor. Since 1984 he has been based in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>, where he has been a general assignment newsman and has regularly covered <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION>, as well as major international conferences.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880218-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-18-88 0320EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-BusyRe-Enactors     02-18 0680</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Busy Re-Enactors,0698</SECOND>
<HEAD>Re-Enactors Finding It Hard To Make All Civil War Activities</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By RON HARRIST</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>VICKSBURG, Miss. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 History buffs organizing re-enactments of major Civil War battles this summer are running into the same problem <PERSON> Gens </PERSON>. <PERSON> Ulysses </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Grant </PERSON> and <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> faced 125 years ago _ not enough <PERSON> Billy </PERSON> <PERSON> Yanks </PERSON> and <PERSON> Johnny </PERSON> <PERSON> Rebs </PERSON> to go around. `` There are so many re-enactments planned that you could stay busy just about every weekend,'' said <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON>, a member of `` <ORGANIZATION> Stanford </ORGANIZATION>'s <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> Battery.'' But the Civil War fanatics who dress up in blue or gray to camp out and charge through fields in battlefield re-enactments have a manpower solution that was not available in the Civil War _ fight for both sides. `` Sometimes you have to hastily reorganize your loyalties if you want to be part of something,'' said <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON>, who in more sedate moments is chairman of the social studies department at <ORGANIZATION> Mississippi </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Gulf </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Junior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION>. `` This summer is an especially busy period because two of the key battles of the Civil War _ <LOCATION> Vicksburg </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Gettysburg </LOCATION> _ occurred at virtually the same time,'' he said. <LOCATION> Gettysburg </LOCATION> activities will take place in the weeks leading up to the 125th anniversary of the battle, which was fought July 1-3, 1863, while the <LOCATION> Vicksburg </LOCATION> re-enactment is planned for the July Fourth weekend, when that Rebel stronghold on the <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> fell to <PERSON> Grant </PERSON>'s army. Last year more than 40,000 people watched as 6,000 buffs recreated the bloody battle of <LOCATION> Shiloh </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION>, where Confederate troops surprised <PERSON> Grant </PERSON>'s troops on April 6, 1862. The Rebels were defeated in a two-day battle. Thousands of re-enactors belong to groups of Civil War buffs, but demand has been so intense that several events, including an annual re-creation of the Battle of Champion Hill, have had to be rescheduled. Champion <PERSON> Hill </PERSON> was fought on May 16, 1863, and paved the way to <LOCATION> Vicksburg </LOCATION> for Union troops. It will be observed in March this year because it would have conflicted with preparations for the <LOCATION> Gettysburg </LOCATION> event. <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON> said that to deal with changing demands, many re-enactors carry two sets of uniforms so that at a moment's notice they can march as either a Rebel or a Yankee. Leyland French, operator of an antebellum tour home here, said that by staging <LOCATION> Vicksburg </LOCATION> activities immediately after those at <LOCATION> Gettysburg </LOCATION>, `` It may be possible for more people to make both events.'' `` We've talked with representives of 41st Illinois Infantry who plan a weekend encampment and we had a call this week from a gentleman in <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION> who wants to bring a group,'' said <PERSON> Lenore </PERSON> <PERSON> Barkley </PERSON>, executive director of the <ORGANIZATION> Vicksburg </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Convention </ORGANIZATION> and Visitors' Bureau. While <LOCATION> Gettysburg </LOCATION> is perhaps the best-remembered clash of the Civil War, the fall of <LOCATION> Vicksburg </LOCATION> on July 4, 1863, was a vital strategic loss to the South, leaving the Confederacy almost cut in two and giving control of the <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> to the North. The siege began May 18, 1863, and ended when Confederate Gen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Pemberton </PERSON>, out of food and water, surrendered on July Fourth. The battle, fought in trenches, enventually involved 100,000 men, some 50,000 fewer than marched into battle at <LOCATION> Gettysburg </LOCATION>, where <PERSON> Lee </PERSON>'s invasion of <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> was turned back. <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON> said that despite the expense of uniforms, equipment and the time and travel, most re-enactors were anxious to participate in as many events as possible. `` We are talking about salesmen, bookkeepers, teachers, truck drivers, doctors, and lawyers _ all united by a common love of history,'' <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON> said. `` It's like a time machine, providing a feeling of history you ca n't get any other way,'' he said. He said many buffs, both from <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> South </LOCATION>, preferred to march as Confederates, perhaps because of the romance of the Lost Cause. `` Re-enactors were used when they made the television movie <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> South </LOCATION>, and just about everyone wanted to be a Confederate, including most of the <ORGANIZATION> Yankees </ORGANIZATION>,'' he said. `` In the end, they had to make our group go in as Union troops.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880218-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-18-88 0321EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Sunnyvale-ESLProfile     02-18 0253</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Sunnyvale-ESL Profile,0260</SECOND>
<HEAD>Shooting Puts Low-Key Defense Firm in Spotlight</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Sunnyvale Shooting</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>SUNNYVALE, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> ESL </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, the <LOCATION> Silicon </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION> defense contractor whose offices were the scene of a deadly shooting rampage, is best-known for a product dubbed Guardrail, a light plane modified with radio eavesdropping equipment. The <ORGANIZATION> TRW </ORGANIZATION> subsidiary was the sixth-largest <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Clara </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> defense contractor in 1986 with $ 89.8 million in government contracts. On Tuesday <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Wade </PERSON> <PERSON> Farley </PERSON>, 39, of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jose </LOCATION>, surrendered to police after a six-hour siege which began when he allegedly entered a building with four guns and began shooting. He apparently had been spurned by a woman who was an engineer there. Seven people were killed and four hurt in the attack. The company employs about 2,800 people, working on radar-jamming hardware and software and intelligence-gathering equipment. Customers include the <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION>. ESL stands for <ORGANIZATION> Electro-Magnetic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Systems </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Laboratories </ORGANIZATION>. Founded in 1964, it was purchased by giant Redondo-Beach, Calif.-based <ORGANIZATION> TRW </ORGANIZATION> in 1978. `` Of all of <ORGANIZATION> TRW </ORGANIZATION>'s divisions, they keep the lowest profile and do very little in the way of advertising and public relations,'' <PERSON> Dave </PERSON> <PERSON> Boutacoff </PERSON>, managing editor of <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Electronics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> magazine </ORGANIZATION>, told the <ORGANIZATION> San </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Francisco </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chronicle </ORGANIZATION>. Security at the company is reportedly tight, with a guard at the front door checking identification badges. However, <PERSON> Lenny </PERSON> <PERSON> Siegel </PERSON>, director of the <ORGANIZATION> Pacific </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Studies </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>, a defense watchdog organization, said it's not like an airport. `` They do n't necessarily check everybody's belongings or frisk anybody,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880218-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-18-88 0324EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Dragon     02-18 0562</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Dragon,0579</SECOND>
<HEAD>Dragon Still Important Symbol For Chinese</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By CHARLENE L. FU</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 As <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> enters the Year of the Dragon, the symbol of good fortune is everywhere in the capital _ in neon and plastic, on posters and in newspapers _ despite the official communist line against superstitious beliefs. The dragon is considered the most auspicious of the 12 animals in the Chinese zodiac, and it continues to be <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s favorite symbol of luck, power and grandeur. The Chinese, who call themselves `` descendents of the dragon,'' regard the dragon year as lucky for marriage, birth and business. Throughout <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>, neon dragons beam from atop buildings, plastic dragons twine around pillars, and the character for dragon is on signs welcoming the new year. Red banner headlines in Chinese newspapers Wednesday hailed the start of the new lunar year and devoted extensive space to articles on the dragon's history, development and significance. Even the state-run <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> Review linked the dragon to hoped-for economic success this year. On the cover of the authoritative magazine's Feb. 15 issue, the headline read, `` Coastal Areas: Boom expected in Year of Dragon.'' The dragon's role in Chinese culture dates back as early as the New Stone Age. A dragon made of shells was discovered last year in a tomb from the 7,000 year-old <LOCATION> Yangshao </LOCATION> civilization unearthed in <LOCATION> Henan </LOCATION> province. In dynastic times, the yellow dragon was the symbol of the emperor, and anyone found using the motif was punished severely. It is said that no mortal has ever seen the dragon, but ancient writers described the dragon as having the antlers of a deer, the head of a camel, the eyes of a ghost, the neck of a serpent, the belly of a sea snake, the scales of a carp, the claws of an eagle, the paws of a tiger and the ears of a bull. Artists portrayed this fantastic creature in a variety of ways, but most dragons look something like reptilian serpent with four sharp-clawed feet and a horse-like head with sharp horns. The dragon is one of the most prominent figures in Chinese art, architecture, clothing and even furniture, and it remains an important symbol to the Chinese. A pair of red dragons flying amid clouds dominated the top corner of the Wednesday edition of the official <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION>, mouthpiece of the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>. Other national newspapers published photographs of dragon dances and spectacular dragon lanterns. A five-hour Spring Festival television special Tuesday night showed dragon ice sculptures in <LOCATION> Harbin </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Heilongjiang </LOCATION> province, <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s northeasternmost major city, and fiery dragon dances in <LOCATION> Canton </LOCATION>. A 10-part TV series on the dragon will be shown across the nation. The Forbidden City, formerly the imperial palace, is holding a <ORGANIZATION> Dragon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Art </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Exhibition </ORGANIZATION>, and a display at <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Nationalities </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Museum </ORGANIZATION> shows how the dragon is depicted in the folk art of the Miao minority people from southern <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>. In <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s major cities and tourist centers, dragons of all sizes and shapes adorn doorways to hotels and tourist shops, grinning from signs welcoming tourists. Special dragon-related activities are planned throughout the year, which officials have designated The International Year of Tourism. Visitors will be treated to events ranging from a dragon kite show in <LOCATION> Weifang </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Shandong </LOCATION> province, to traditional dragon boat races in several major cities.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880218-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-18-88 0326EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-China-Population     02-18 0764</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-China-Population,0790</SECOND>
<HEAD>China Grapples With Failure Of Population Policies</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By KATHY WILHELM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s controversial family planning policies have failed for the second straight year. The growing willingness of couples to defy the one-child limit threatens to send the population zooming out of control. <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> has estimated that to hold its population within the planned limit of 1.2 billion in 2000 and 1.5 billion in 2050, it must keep the birth rate below 1.5 percent. But the birth rate hit 2 percent in 1986 and stayed there in 1987. If that pace is maintained, <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s 1 billion people will become 2 billion by 2030, according to a recent estimate by the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> Fund for Population Activities. In a recent front-page commentary, the official <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> declared the family planning situation was `` out of control'' in some provinces. `` One false move may lose the game,'' it said. `` <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s continuously growing population is in fact facing a crisis. The surge is fueled largely by newly prosperous peasants who have enough money to pay government fines for breaking the one-child limit and incentives under the new economic reforms to do so. Since the breakup of communes in the early 1980s, families have been responsible for farming their own plots of land. More children to help plant and harvest means more profit. Even urban residents, who surveys indicate are less eager than peasants to have large families, envy the ease with which newly rich peasants have been able to `` buy'' extra children. Fines vary from region to region but generally amount to about $ 270 per year for five years. The amount is n't prohibitive if several family members chip in. The average rural income is about $ 270 per couple, but annual family incomes of several times that amount are increasingly common. City residents face not only fines but suspension from work for one or two years for having a second child. Officials responded to the high 1986 birth rate with calls for better birth control education. But when the 1987 figures came out, the family planning minister, <PERSON> Wang </PERSON> <PERSON> Wei </PERSON>, was sacked. The government also announced measures to tighten local enforcement of the one-child limit by linking it to officials' paychecks At an urgent meeting of family planning officials early this year, acting Premier <PERSON> Li </PERSON> <PERSON> Peng </PERSON> ordered that officials be rewarded or punished based on how well they enforce the one-child policy. But <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> authorities, sensitive about past <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> congressional charges of coerced abortions, said at a recent news conference that officials will not be rewarded for high numbers of abortions in their jurisdictions. `` Efforts are to be made to raise the use of birth control and contraceptive methods and reduce the number of abortions,'' said <PERSON> Liang </PERSON> <PERSON> Jimin </PERSON>, director of the <ORGANIZATION> Family </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Planning </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION>'s general office. He insisted that only `` education and persuasion'' would be used to encourage abortions when families already have a child. In an apparent reflection of the new tough attitude, medical workers in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> said hospitals recently have begun refusing admission to women about to give birth to a second or third child. Family planning authorities also have gotten tougher on migrant worker families who have taken advantage of their roving status to flout the one-child limit. The official <ORGANIZATION> Xinhua </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> said some migrant couples have as many as five or six children. In the northeastern city of <LOCATION> Shenyang </LOCATION>, officials ruled in January that employers must issue `` planned birth cards'' to all migrant workers so their family sizes can be recorded and monitored. Family planning education programs have been stepped up. Almost the only propaganda posters still seen in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> are those touting the one-child policy. <ORGANIZATION> China </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Television </ORGANIZATION>, mindful that half of all Chinese homes have televisions, broadcast weekly programs on family planning last year. But a combination of demographics and superstition make it likely births will increase rather than drop in 1988. The population of child-bearing women increased by 7 million in 1987 and will grow by 8 million this year, to 297 million, as the products of <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s baby boom of the 1960s reach maturity. Furthermore, 1988 is the year of the dragon in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s traditional 12-year astrological cycle The dragon is a symbol of good luck and power, and many young couples are expected to try to have their one child this year. The official Workers' Daily recently tried to debunk traditional beliefs about lucky `` dragon babies.'' If birth control limits are ignored, it warned, `` the dragon year will not be lucky for an over-populated nation.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880218-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-18-88 0250EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-LoeweMemorial     02-18 0339</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Loewe Memorial,0347</SECOND>
<HEAD>Red Skelton, Mary Martin Among Mourners For Broadway Composer</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PALM SPRINGS, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Comedian <PERSON> Red </PERSON> <PERSON> Skelton </PERSON> and singer <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> were among the friends who gathered to remember composer <PERSON> Frederick </PERSON> <PERSON> Loewe </PERSON> as a man who could make life laugh and sing like the Broadway musicals he helped create. `` The tragedy of my life is that I never did get to do a musical with him,'' <PERSON> Miss </PERSON> <PERSON> Martin </PERSON>, stage star of `` <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION>,'' and `` The Sound of Music,'' told about 75 friends and fans at an outdoor memorial service at <LOCATION> Loewe </LOCATION>'s estate here Wednesday. <PERSON> Skelton </PERSON>, a friend for 32 years, called <PERSON> Loewe </PERSON>'s music `` the pomp and splendor of life _ a celestial sound that inspires happiness.'' <PERSON> Loewe </PERSON>, who combined his music with the words of <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Jay </PERSON> <PERSON> Lerner </PERSON> to create such Broadway classics as `` Brigadoon,'' `` My Fair Lady,'' `` Paint Your Wagon'' and `` Camelot,'' died Sunday of heart failure. He was 86. The two-time Tony Award winner and co-writer of memorable tunes like `` I Could Have Danced All Night,'' `` If Ever I Would Leave You,'' and `` Thank Heaven for Little Girls'' was buried after a private graveside service in nearby <LOCATION> Cathedral </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. At the public gathering, <PERSON> Skelton </PERSON> recalled flashes of <PERSON> Loewe </PERSON>'s humor: His responding to a compliment that the music in `` Gigi'' grew on people by calling the show `` a musical fungus,'' and quipping that the best thing about rock music was that a listener could n't tell if his record was scratched `` Life was truly a feast for him,'' said friend <PERSON> Gloria </PERSON> <PERSON> Greer </PERSON>, `` and he wanted to enjoy and savor every bit of it.'' <PERSON> Dorothy </PERSON> <PERSON> Hart </PERSON>, sister-in-law of composer <PERSON> Lorenz </PERSON> <PERSON> Hart </PERSON>, said <PERSON> Loewe </PERSON> had a flair for the extravagant even before he made it big. `` If he had $ 90 to his name, then he'd buy $ 90 worth of caviar,'' Ms. <PERSON> Hart </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Loewe </PERSON> grew up in <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Austria </LOCATION>, in a musical family and came to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> in his 20s. His marriage of 26 years to the former <PERSON> Ernestine </PERSON> <PERSON> Zerline </PERSON> ended in divorce, without children.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880218-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-18-88 0252EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-ZZZZBest-Lasko     02-18 0152</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-ZZZZ Best-Lasko,0156</SECOND>
<HEAD>Man Pleads Guilty to Helping ZZZZ Best Owner Siphon Money</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A man pleaded guilty Wednesday to charges he helped whiz-kid businessman <PERSON> Barry </PERSON> <PERSON> Minkow </PERSON> siphon off $ 320,000 from his <ORGANIZATION> ZZZZ </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Best </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> before the carpet cleaning company collapsed. <PERSON> Eugene </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Lasko </PERSON>, 56, of <LOCATION> Reseda </LOCATION> pleaded guilty to conspiracy and could receive up to five years in prison and a $ 250,000 fine at sentencing March 28 Assistant <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Attorney <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Asperger </PERSON> said <PERSON> Lasko </PERSON> laundered the money in <LOCATION> Las </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vegas </LOCATION> casinos at <PERSON> Minkow </PERSON>'s behest. <PERSON> Minkow </PERSON>, 21, founed ZZZZ Best his parents' garage at age 15 and built it into a $ 50 million a year business before its collapse last year amid allegations of financial wrongdoing. <PERSON> Minkow </PERSON> and nine others face trial March 8 on racketeering, securities fraud, bank fraud and money laundering charges. <PERSON> Minkow </PERSON> and others are accused of stealing half a million dollars from <ORGANIZATION> ZZZZ </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Best </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880218-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-18-88 0334EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-BlackSchool-Georgia Bjt   02-18 1194</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Black School-Georgia, Bjt,1228</SECOND>
<HEAD>Black Christian Schools Flourish in Macon</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Suggested for side-by-side use with PM-Black School-Arkansas.</NOTE>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 The overall percentage is still tiny, just 4.7. But that represents a big increase, of 33 percent, in the number of black children attending private schools over a decade and a half. Black enrollment in Catholic schools was even more remarkable, growing from 4.8 percent in 1971 to 8.5 percent in 1985, according to the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Independent </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Schools </ORGANIZATION>. Two stories report on such schools in <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION> and in <LOCATION> Arkansas </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>By STRAT DOUTHAT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MACON, Ga. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Happy noises hum down the halls of the <ORGANIZATION> Progressive </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION> and filter into the paneled office. Principal <PERSON> Betty </PERSON> <PERSON> Tolbert </PERSON> stops her paperwork to listen attentively. A substantial, gray-haired woman, she seems frozen in her swivel chair as she strains to catch the sounds coming from the classrooms, a buzz of song, recitation and prayer. Relaxing after a moment, she nods approvingly. A smile melts the concentration that had creased her forehead. `` Yes,'' she says. `` It's a good sound, the sound of children learning.'' A bell rings and the halls are filled with children. The girls are immaculately dressed in green plaid jumpers and white blouses. The boys wear green pants, white shirts and black ties. The children have something in common besides the uniforms: All 482 have dark skins. `` Welcome to the <ORGANIZATION> Progressive </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION>, the only large-scale, all-black, private <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> school I know of,'' said Mrs. <PERSON> Tolbert </PERSON>, the 53-year-old founder and driving force behind the school. `` Our motto is ` All things are possible within the Lord.''' The non-profit academy is housed in a one-story brick building atop a hill near downtown <LOCATION> Macon </LOCATION>. Until 1983, the building was a public elementary school. Progressive Christian is leasing it with an option to buy. `` You're looking at a miracle here,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Tolbert </PERSON> said proudly as she walked down the hall, past photographs of the Rev. <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Luther </PERSON> <PERSON> King </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, <PERSON> Diana </PERSON> <PERSON> Ross </PERSON> and <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Cosby </PERSON>. `` This place was a total wreck when we moved in 18 months ago. Now we're a family. We're also a vital education center that is serving the needs of black children.'' Mrs. <PERSON> Tolbert </PERSON> said she came to perceive those needs in the 18 years she was a public schoolteacher and principal. `` It was clear to me that the public school system was n't providing the moral guidance, the loving discipline and the positive self-image reinforcement that many children need in order to flourish,'' she said In the summer of 1985, <PERSON> Betty </PERSON> <PERSON> Tolbert </PERSON> took the plunge with $ 50,000 in savings and loans. She opened a trial summer school at the <LOCATION> Progressive </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Baptist </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Church </LOCATION>, where her husband is pastor. `` We had 75 children and taught remedial reading and math with an emphasis on Christian principles and the development of positive self-esteem,'' she said. `` It was incredible. I began to see a change in those children on a daily basis and so did their parents. They kept telling me their kids were so excited about the school that they did n't even have to get them up in the mornings. `` That fall I quit my job -LRB- as principal of an integrated public magnet school -RRB- and opened this school, which goes from K4 -LRB- pre-kindergarten -RRB- through the eighth grade. We started with 175 students. By the summer of'86, we had 400 students enrolled and had to move out of the church. Now, with 482 students and 38 employees, we've got cramped quarters once again.'' The <ORGANIZATION> Progressive </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION> is one of four mostly black private schools, including a tiny class run by Seventh-day Adventists, in <LOCATION> Bibb </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>. Some 5,000 of the county's 30,000 school-age children attend private schools, most of them white. `` Most of our children came to us from the public schools, where many were doing poorly,'' she said. `` They were developing poor self-images and their parents were afraid their children were going to be lost.'' <PERSON> Kendall </PERSON> <PERSON> Reid </PERSON>, a sixth-grader, feels he was one such student. `` I was a little mouse. I was so scared I just could n't speak up,'' he recalled of his three years in public school. `` I had a white teacher in the first grade who told my parents I was retarded. She and the kids used to make fun of me. Now I'm on the honor roll, and I know I'm not retarded.'' Other students said they had to work harder at <ORGANIZATION> Progressive </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> and had fewer social and athletic activities yet still preferred their private school to public classrooms. `` The kids here are n't as mad as they were in public school,'' said <PERSON> Latonya </PERSON> <PERSON> Raines </PERSON>, an eighth-grader. `` And the teachers really seem to care about you here.'' <LOCATION> Bibb </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> Commissioner <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Randall </PERSON>, who worked to integrate the county's schools two decades ago, said he found the present situation ironic. `` I've got two grandchildren in Mrs. <PERSON> Tolbert </PERSON>'s school, including a grandson who was n't doing well in public school,'' <PERSON> Randall </PERSON> said. `` My grandson is doing much better now that he's in the private school.'' Mrs. <PERSON> Tolbert </PERSON> said her school, in addition to providing a Christian atmosphere, gives the children positive role models. `` They get to see black people in charge,'' she said. `` We also strive to instill in them the belief that everybody is somebody special. We stress the worth of the individual.'' She said her school also accommodates the students' special needs and schedules. `` For one thing, she said, `` we're open from 6 a.m. until 6 p.m., which especially helps single parents. We provide a warm, loving atmosphere, but we also stress academics and have volunteer tutors for high-risk failures. Then, too, we supervise the homework of those students who stay after school.'' She said the parents pay $ 30 a week for one child and $ 50 for two or more. They must provide books, uniforms and lunches for their children. Several mothers, interviewed as a group, agreed they were thrilled with the school even though tuition money is hard to spare. `` My little boy is happy now. There has n't been a day he has n't gotten up and gotten himself ready for school Morning can be an especially tense time for a single parent, and I simply ca n't tell you how much this means to me,'' said <PERSON> Natalie </PERSON> <PERSON> Coggins </PERSON>, a Social Security claims examiner with two children at the school. Mrs. <PERSON> Tolbert </PERSON> said parents of eighth-graders want her to offer high school classes so children wo n't have to return to public school. `` I'm also getting requests from parents outside the area to start a boarding school,'' she added. `` I'd like to do that, but first we need to raise enough money to pay off our bills and complete our library, which we need to do to be fully accredited.'' The school now has provisional accreditation and plans a library fund-raising drive. `` I feel certain these things will all come in time. Meanwhile, I must be doing something right. It's all I can do, when I go out in the hall, not to get knocked down by all the hugs I get.''
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Strat </PERSON> <PERSON> Douthat </PERSON> is the <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Southeastern </ORGANIZATION> regional reporter, based in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880218-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-18-88 0248EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-EnergyMachine Bjt   02-18 0590</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Energy Machine, Bjt,580</SECOND>
<HEAD>Purported `Energy Machine' Inventor in Patent Battle</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JAMES ROWLEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An inventor who claims he has devised a machine that produces more energy than it uses says he will appeal a judge's refusal to force the government to give him a patent for his invention. `` I am pleased the judge has finally ruled because I am counting on getting up to the higher court,'' <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Newman </PERSON> said Wednesday after <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Penfield </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> rejected his lawsuit against the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Patent </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Trademark </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION>. `` I was very certain he was going to be consistent and rule against me,'' said <PERSON> Newman </PERSON>, 51, of <LOCATION> Lucedale </LOCATION>, Miss. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> upheld the <ORGANIZATION> Patent </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION>'s refusal to grant a patent for the device, saying there was insufficient scientific evidence to support <PERSON> Newman </PERSON>'s claim the machine converted matter into energy. Patent examiners rejected <PERSON> Newman </PERSON>'s application after ruling that such a machine would violate the second law of thermodynamics. That law of physics holds that energy is inevitably consumed by any mechanical process so that a machine can not produce more energy than is used to power it. The same law rules out the existence of similar, so-called `` perpetual motion'' machines that some inventors have claimed at various times to have produced. <PERSON> Newman </PERSON> and his attorney, <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Flannery </PERSON>, contended that <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> had improperly rejected the findings of court-appointed expert <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Schuyler </PERSON>, himself a former patent commissioner, that the machine worked as <PERSON> Newman </PERSON> claimed it did. `` We have an expert ... who agrees with our view and we have a district court judge's opinion that differs with that,'' <PERSON> Flannery </PERSON> said. `` So I think we will have to go the Court of Appeals for a tie-breaker.'' Ruling on the five-year-old lawsuit, <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> said <PERSON> Newman </PERSON> had only produced evidence to support his theory that was `` anecdotal and largely qualitative rather than quantified measured data.'' Nor had <PERSON> Newman </PERSON>, the judge found, rebutted the findings of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Standards </ORGANIZATION>, which tested the machine and concluded: `` The device did not deliver more energy than it used.'' <PERSON> Newman </PERSON>, who has demonstrated his motor to a congressional subcommittee, claims that it converts matter he calls `` gyroscopic particles'' into energy. But the judge found that `` aside from <PERSON> Newman </PERSON>'s own somewhat metaphysical writings which appear at multiple points throughout his patent application there is no evidence whatsoever ... from which to find the existence of such ` gyroscopic particles,' their observable -LRB- or measurable -RRB- ` release' or ` reaction' within the device.'' <PERSON> Newman </PERSON>'s machine resembles an ordinary electric motor except for a large coil of wire used to create an electromagnetic field when powered by batteries. `` At best,'' the judge said, `` the evidence supports a finding that <PERSON> Newman </PERSON>'s device will operate, for reasons not explained at all but must be merely guessed at, on dry cell batteries for longer periods of time than others which may or may not be comparable. `` But such a device is not the one for which <PERSON> Newman </PERSON> seeks a patent,'' <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> said in his 20-page opinion. `` He is unequivocal in his insistence that the device he has tendered as patent-worthy produces more useable energy output than the energy required to power it. The court finds the evidence of it insufficient.'' The bitterly fought lawsuit included a 1986 episode when <PERSON> Flannery </PERSON> was cited for contempt of court for pressing <PERSON> Newman </PERSON>'s demand that <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> disqualify himself from the case because he was biased `` I have had just about enough of your insolence in this case,'' the judge told <PERSON> Flannery </PERSON>. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> later withdrew the contempt citation.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880218-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-18-88 0040EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-CostaRica Bjt   02-18 0748</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Costa Rica, Bjt,0775</SECOND>
<HEAD>Costa Ricans Question Timing of Release of U.S. Study on Aid</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PAULINE JELINEK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SAN JOSE, Costa Rica (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Government officials and businessmen say charges they enriched themselves on <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> foreign aid are false or misleading and were timed to embarrass <LOCATION> Costa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rica </LOCATION> before <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> voted on rebel funding. <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> sources and several other businessmen say some of the accusations are true. Local officials are reacting angrily to a <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> memo which charges that <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Embassy officials in <LOCATION> Costa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rica </LOCATION> misspent and mismanaged millions of dollars in foreign aid, including providing college scholarships for children of influential citizens and creating a development agency that largely benefited politicians. A Costa Rican government spokesman, who agreed to be interviewed only on condition of anonymity, said no formal response was planned until the memo can be clarified. `` When something like this hits the public, people have the right not only to feel angry but to feel extremely angry,'' he said. The memo said actions by <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials and wealthy and influential Costa Ricans who helped distribute the aid `` closely approach criminal conduct.'' Portions of the memo first were disclosed in a story written by the <ORGANIZATION> Scripps </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Howard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> and published in several <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> newspapers in late January, just two weeks before <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> voted on an aid proposal for rebels fighting <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>'s leftist Sandinista government. The Associated Press carried a lengthy story on the memo last week from <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> rejected the Contra rebel proposal in early February. But Costa Rican officials say release of the memo before the vote was designed to muddy the image of the country and its president, <PERSON> Oscar </PERSON> <PERSON> Arias </PERSON>, who has been an influential opponent of the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration's Contra policy. <PERSON> Arias </PERSON> won the Nobel Peace Prize last fall for a <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> peace plan that forbids foreign funding of rebel groups in the region and calls for a negotiated political settlement to the area's conflicts. The peace plan has, at least temporarily, pre-empted the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration policy of using military pressure on the <ORGANIZATION> Sandinistas </ORGANIZATION>. The confidential memo was written Oct. 9, 1987, by the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>'s inspector general, <PERSON> Herbert </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Beckington </PERSON>, to <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Woods </PERSON>, administrator of the <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION>, known as AID, that distributes the money. In the memo, <PERSON> Beckington </PERSON> claimed the former AID director in <LOCATION> Costa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rica </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Chaij </PERSON>, personally approved loans and grants that benefited some of the country's most prominent business and political figures. Most of the alleged activities took place before <PERSON> Arias </PERSON> was elected in 1986. After the memo was first published Jan. 20, <LOCATION> Costa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rica </LOCATION>'s ambassador to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Guido </PERSON> <PERSON> Fernandez </PERSON>, questioned `` why confidential reports supplied more than four months ago should be leaked to the press at this particular time. <LOCATION> Costa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rica </LOCATION>'s finance minister, <PERSON> Fernando </PERSON> <PERSON> Naranjo </PERSON>, told reporters that the story was `` a complete unmitigated lie.'' Both <PERSON> Fernandez </PERSON> and <PERSON> Naranjo </PERSON> were identified as beneficiaries of AID programs. Several sources in the <LOCATION> Costa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rican </LOCATION> government and private sector say they believe some of the accusations are valid. `` There was some poor judgment used in how they decided some of these projects,'' said one <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> source, speaking on condition of anonymity. Other officials said parts of the memo were false and written in inflammatory language to make legitimate activities appear illegal or questionable. They said a second audit exonerated many of the people mentioned in the Oct. 9 memo, but the audit has not been released. <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Harris </PERSON>, a Costa Rican business executive also named in the memo, said some of the facts in it appear to be true, but were `` mischievously distorted and given sinister and malicious interpretations.'' <PERSON> Harris </PERSON> and others said one example is a charge that a small group of Costa Ricans set up a system by which they were able to evade local taxes on money earned from AID contracts. They said the memo made the practice seem illegal, although it is a legally established tax shelter system in <LOCATION> Costa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rica </LOCATION>. `` It is not done this way in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, but in <LOCATION> Costa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rica </LOCATION> it is,'' <PERSON> Harris </PERSON> said. `` It's a shelter _ legal, decent, upheld by law. There is absolutely nothing wrong with it, but the insinuations made in the memo are insidious.'' Legislators in <LOCATION> Costa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rica </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> are planning investigations into how AID money was used in <LOCATION> Costa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rica </LOCATION>. The Costa Ricans say they also will look into why the critical memo was leaked to the press.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880218-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-18-88 0249EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-ArcticOil Bjt   02-18 0542</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Arctic Oil, Bjt,560</SECOND>
<HEAD>Arctic Oil: Administration 1, Environmentalists 0</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID GOELLER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration and the oil industry have narrowly bested the environmentalists in Round 1 of their intense fight over petroleum development in the <ORGANIZATION> Arctic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wildlife </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Refuge </ORGANIZATION>. The administration's victory came Wednesday as the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> voted 10-9 to open the 1.5 million-acre coastal plain to oil rigs, a controversial step that the <ORGANIZATION> Interior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Big </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Oil </ORGANIZATION> have been urging on <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> for a year. Under the committee's plan, drilling rigs could join the caribou and musk oxen on the refuge's frigid tundra as early as 21 months after enactment of a law repealing the current prohibition against development in the refuge. The issue has become a major battleground. The environmental lobby is trying to protect the fragile ecosystem from any development. The other side says the area's potentially huge reserves could rival those of nearby <LOCATION> Prudhoe </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION>, which accounts for about 20 percent of domestic oil production. Drilling foes like Sen. <PERSON> Tim </PERSON> <PERSON> Wirth </PERSON>, D-Colo., said that even though the committee was readying legislation for the full <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>, they think they can hold their ground this year in hope that the next president will oppose development In fact, <PERSON> Wirth </PERSON> said, <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> action in 1988 may be academic: `` Nothing's going to happen this year in the House _ zero. The <ORGANIZATION> Interior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> is n't going to bring it up.'' <PERSON> Syd </PERSON> <PERSON> Butler </PERSON>, conservation vice president of the <ORGANIZATION> Wilderness </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION>, said that while he was disappointed in the committee action, `` I'm real happy with the division: a 10-9 vote is not a clear mandate for opening ANWR.'' The <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Petroleum </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION>, the oil industry's lobbying arm, said in a statement that `` the committee has taken a step toward ensuring the future energy security and economic well-being of our country. ... The time has come to proceed with the legislation. We urge the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> to move expeditiously.'' <PERSON> Wirth </PERSON> and his allies tried to persuade the committee to defer a decision on drilling until the administration could study the nation's long-term energy needs and formulate a policy to meet them. But Interior Secretary <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Hodel </PERSON>, the point man for the development forces, told the committee in a letter that new oil from the <LOCATION> Arctic </LOCATION> is needed under any scenario, including increased conservation. <PERSON> Hodel </PERSON> criticized the direction being taken by the committee as it continues work on the refuge legislation. He objected to proposals for detailed environmental safeguards and a 10-year stretchout in the oil-tract leasing process. <PERSON> Hodel </PERSON> was also critical of a decision made two weeks ago by the committee to earmark 80 percent of the federal revenues from refuge oil to conservation and species protection programs, with only 20 percent available for general use. `` ANWR's resources belong to all Americans,'' <PERSON> Hodel </PERSON> said. `` Federal revenues generated by an ANWR leasing program should go to the <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> where they can benefit all taxpayers and serve national priorities.'' <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Walker </PERSON>, an <ORGANIZATION> Interior </ORGANIZATION> spokesman, said he did not know whether <PERSON> Hodel </PERSON>'s problems with the bill could lead to a recommendation that it be vetoed. <PERSON> Walker </PERSON> said <ORGANIZATION> Interior </ORGANIZATION> officials were pleased by Wednesday's vote because `` we're still moving in the general direction we want to go.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880218-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-18-88 0048EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w PM-BudgetLegacy Bjt   02-18 0535</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Budget Legacy, Bjt,550</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHINGTON WIRE: Reagan Budget Reveals Hoped-for Legacy</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By W. DALE NELSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The budget President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> sent to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> today is n't likely to survive long but it embodies a philosophy of government that he hopes will be a legacy of his administration. It also demonstrates some changes in approach that the president has either embraced or had thrust upon him since he took office more than seven years ago. The budget makes a strong pitch for <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s long-held position that government should not perform functions which, in his conservative view of things, can be done better by private organizations. It proposes, for instance, the `` complete privatization'' of military housing and construction of waste water treatment plants. It also calls for a new private entity to mediate disputes that now choke the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tax </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>. In line with his firm belief in an economy governed by market forces, the president reiterates proposals to cut back federal programs that prop up commodity prices and protect farmers' incomes. And, as he so often has, he calls for the elimination of federal programs that he says are unneeded. This time he lists nine of them, ranging from the rural housing insurance fund to discretionary grants for urban mass transit. Notable by its absence, however, is the idea, which he put forward in 1982, of abolishing the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Education </ORGANIZATION>. Instead, the president proposes an increase of $ 650 million over the current appropriation of $ 16.2 billion for the department's discretionary programs Adopting arguments of Secretary of Education <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON>, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> now says education and training are one of the highest priorities of the federal government. Under a compromise worked out with <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, the president agrees to a slowdown in the military buildup that has been a hallmark of his administration. But he pointedly says in his budget message that he wants the full $ 229.5 billion compromise figure appropriated, declaring, `` I have kept my side of the bargain and trust that <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> will keep its side.'' As he enters the twilight of his presidency, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> has increasingly expressed his commitment, most recently in a speech to conservative political activists last week, to making what has been called the `` <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> revolution'' of restrained government a permanent feature of American life. However that may be, the particulars of his budget blueprint undoubtedly are in for drastic alteration by a <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, controlled in both houses by the opposition party, facing a president whose political clout is weakened as he nears the end of his tenure. In his budget message, the president says that `` the budget process has so degenerated in recent years that the presidential budget is routinely discarded'' after it arrives on <LOCATION> Capitol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION>. What the president calls degeneration many in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> would describe as a healthy assertion of their constitutional power over the purse strings. Either way, however, it makes the president's budget more of an outline of goals and philosophy than a map of actual spending for the fiscal year that will begin Oct. 1 and last for more than eight months after <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> leaves office.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880218-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-18-88 0059EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Colombia-Pipeline 1stLd-Writethru a0846 02-18 0678</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Colombia-Pipeline, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0846,0694</SECOND>
<HEAD>Rebels Have Attacked Main Oil Pipeline 20 Times in Five Weeks</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: New thruout to CORRECT export figures in 3rd graf, ``The
National...,'' CORRECT date pipeline opened in 10th graf, ``The
pipeline...,'' CORRECT time frame for 40 atttacks in 13th graf,
``Between June...'' Subs 2nd graf ``The attacks...'' and 17th graf,
``Ecopetrol was...'' to UPDATE that pipeline was reopened
Wednesday. No pickup.
^By TOM WELLS</NOTE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BOGOTA, Colombia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Leftist guerrillas have struck 20 times in the past five weeks at the lifeline of the nation's oil industry _ a 500-mile pipeline that runs through some of the most rugged terrain in <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION>. The attacks have raised the question of whether this South American nation will be able to maintain its oil exports. The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> has blown up parts of the pipeline 13 times since Jan. 12, temporarily shutting down the line and forcing <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION> to suspend its 137,000 barrels a day of oil exports. Another seven attacks did not damage the pipeline, according to sources with <ORGANIZATION> Occidental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Petroleum </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> who asked to remain anonymous for security reasons. The pipeline carries oil from the <LOCATION> Canon </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Limon </LOCATION> field in the northeast state of <LOCATION> Arauca </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Puerto </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Covenas </LOCATION> on the <LOCATION> Caribbean </LOCATION> coast. The field is owned half by the state oil company <ORGANIZATION> Ecopetrol </ORGANIZATION> and half by <ORGANIZATION> Occidental </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Royal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dutch </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Shell </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Canon </PERSON> <PERSON> Limon </PERSON>, discovered four years ago by <ORGANIZATION> Occidental </ORGANIZATION>, was one of the world's biggest oil discoveries in a decade. With a billion barrels of reserves, it was hailed as <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION>'s economic salvation. At the time, the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>, known as the <ORGANIZATION> ELN </ORGANIZATION>, appeared to be a ragtag band of rebels. The series of attacks has shown that the <ORGANIZATION> ELN </ORGANIZATION> has grown considerably in strength and that the army is incapable of defending the pipeline. The bombings have caused 100,000 barrels of oil to be spilled, much of it into rivers and streams. The pipeline was put into service Dec. 7, 1986, allowing <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION> to export oil for the first time since 1972. The <ORGANIZATION> Canon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Limon </ORGANIZATION> field is capable of producing 300,000 barrels of oil a day, but <ORGANIZATION> Ecopetrol </ORGANIZATION> initially limited production to 180,000 barrels a day. That limit was increased to 215,000 barrels in December. An <ORGANIZATION> Ecopetrol </ORGANIZATION> source said the limit will be raised to 300,000 barrels a day sometime this year. The source spoke on condition of anonymity because all information about the pipeline is supposed to come from the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION>, which refused to comment. Between December 1986 and December 1987, there were about 40 dynamite attacks on the pipeline. Many bombs did n't go off. The few that exploded did little damage, and the pipeline would be out of service for only a few hours. But between Jan. 12 and Jan. 29, the <ORGANIZATION> ELN </ORGANIZATION> attacked the pipeline every day. On Jan. 12 there were two explosions that caused a spill of 27,200 barrels of oil and forcing <ORGANIZATION> Ecopetrol </ORGANIZATION> to close down the pipeline. The army and President <PERSON> Virgilio </PERSON> <PERSON> Barco </PERSON> said army patrols along the pipeline would be increased. The line was opened again Feb. 5. Barely enough pressure had built up to begin full pumping when an attack on Feb. 9 destroyed 120 feet of pipeline. <ORGANIZATION> Ecopetrol </ORGANIZATION> was forced to close the pipeline again. It reopened Wednesday, and <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION> resumed its oil exports, according to a news release issued by the Minister of Mines, <PERSON> Guillermo </PERSON> <PERSON> Perry </PERSON>. Crews in helicopters have little chance of spotting guerrillas in the dense jungles through which the pipe runs. The rebels initially just tried to blow up pipe, but more recently they have started keying on the line's big valves, which can not be repaired or replaced quickly. The <ORGANIZATION> ELN </ORGANIZATION> first emerged in 1960, shortly after <PERSON> Fidel </PERSON> <PERSON> Castro </PERSON>'s triumph in <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> It was organized by a Roman Catholic priest, <PERSON> Camilo </PERSON> <PERSON> Torres </PERSON>, who was later killed in a battle with troops in 1966. The army estimates that the <ORGANIZATION> ELN </ORGANIZATION> has fewer than 500 combatants. There are believed to be a total of about 7,000 armed rebels in <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION>'s five leftist rebel groups.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880218-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-18-88 0108EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a PM-Names     02-18 0871</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0903</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names In The News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ALBANY, Ore. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actor <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Rasche </PERSON>, who plays Sledge Hammer in the <ORGANIZATION> ABC-TV </ORGANIZATION> comedy series of the same name, told high school drama students that persistence and fate are the keys to acting success. <PERSON> Rasche </PERSON>, whose mother-in-law teaches at <ORGANIZATION> West </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Albany </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> High </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION>, stopped by the school Tuesday and was swarmed by teen-age fans. <PERSON> Rasche </PERSON>, 43, plays a macho, trigger-happy police detective in the series, which is a parody of police shows. `` Sledge Hammer!'' is in its second season. He said he has been plugging away at acting since the first grade, when he played <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Washington </PERSON> in a school play. `` I was good. I was very, very good,'' <PERSON> Rasche </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>MALIBU, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A man who actor <PERSON> Sean </PERSON> <PERSON> Penn </PERSON> accused of intruding on his property and punching him pleaded innocent to misdemeanor charges of prowling and assault. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Barcelo </PERSON>, 20, of <PERSON> Chino </PERSON> entered the pleas Wednesday in <ORGANIZATION> Municipal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>, where Judge <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> <PERSON> Mira </PERSON> ordered him to return March 8 for pretrial motions. <LOCATION> Penn </LOCATION> and his wife, pop singer <PERSON> Madonna </PERSON>, told authorities they discovered <PERSON> Barcelo </PERSON> and two 17-year-old boys at their estate when they returned home from the grocery store shortly after midnight Jan. 20. <LOCATION> Penn </LOCATION>, who plays a policeman in his latest movie, `` Colors,'' subdued <PERSON> Barcelo </PERSON> by striking him on the head with a newly purchased bottle of salad dressing, sheriff's deputies said. The star of `` Bad Boys'' and `` The Falcon and the Snowman'' has had several brushes with the law for scuffles in bars and on movie sets, but reported being the victim twice last month. An <LOCATION> Anaheim </LOCATION> man allegedly crashed his pickup truck through <LOCATION> Penn </LOCATION>'s gate Jan. 7, and is scheduled for a Feb. 24 court appearance. Prosecutors withheld details of the two juveniles' court cases.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actor <PERSON> Matthew </PERSON> <PERSON> Broderick </PERSON>, who had faced up to five years in prison for his role in a fatal car crash in <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION>, defended a magistrate's decision to fine him for the lesser charge of careless driving. `` I'm glad the court decided that there was no basis for charging me with reckless driving,'' <PERSON> Broderick </PERSON> said in a statement Wednesday. `` There was never any evidence for that charge. They also determined that the details of the accident will never be fully known. However it happened, it was a tragedy.'' <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Gallagher </PERSON>, whose wife, <PERSON> Anna </PERSON>, 28, and mother-in-law, <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Doherty </PERSON>, 60, were killed in the crash Aug. 5, denounced the decision reached Monday in <LOCATION> Enniskillen </LOCATION>, which amounted to a $ 175 fine. Publicist <PERSON> Wendy </PERSON> <PERSON> Morris </PERSON> said <PERSON> Broderick </PERSON>, who was allowed to remain in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> while his lawyer entered his guilty plea, planned to try to speak with the victims' family, `` but he does n't think now is the right time.'' The 25-year-old star of the movies `` War Games'' and `` Ferris Bueller's Day Off'' suffered a broken leg in the collision. His passenger, actress <PERSON> Jennifer </PERSON> <PERSON> Grey </PERSON>, was not hurt.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>INDEPENDENCE, Mo. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Truman </PERSON>'s hometown is honoring CBS news correspondent <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Kuralt </PERSON> with the 1988 <ORGANIZATION> Truman </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Award </ORGANIZATION> because of the attention he brings to traditional values, the mayor said. `` We felt <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Kuralt </PERSON> focuses our attention on the pulse of <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> that President <PERSON> Truman </PERSON> really represented, and on the average <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> or <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> living on the farm or in a small town, living out those values that President <PERSON> Truman </PERSON> has come to be recognized for,'' Mayor <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Potts </PERSON> said Wednesday. <PERSON> Kuralt </PERSON>, known for his `` on the road'' reports and as host of `` CBS Sunday Morning,'' will be honored May 6 at the <ORGANIZATION> Truman </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Library </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Potts </PERSON> announced. Special recognition awards will go to <PERSON> Sue </PERSON> <PERSON> Gentry </PERSON>, a reporter who covered <PERSON> Truman </PERSON> for <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Examiner </ORGANIZATION> newspaper here, former Independence Mayor <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Weatherford </PERSON> and <PERSON> Ben </PERSON> <PERSON> Zobrist </PERSON>, director of the <ORGANIZATION> Truman </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Library </ORGANIZATION> since 1971.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Prince <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> took the oath of allegiance to his mother, <PERSON> Queen </PERSON> <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> II </PERSON>, in the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lords </ORGANIZATION>, a formality allowing him to speak if he wants to during the current session of Parliament. Apart from state occasions, Wednesday was the first time <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> had gone before the unelected upper house since 1975, when he spoke about voluntary service. Members of the royal family are automatically in the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lords </ORGANIZATION> but rarely go there and traditionally never speak on politically sensitive topics. After swearing his allegiance, the crown prince signed the Test Roll, confirming he accepts the queen as head of the Church of <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>. The 50 or so lords and ladies present of the 1,200 entitled to sit there cried, `` Hear, hear,'' _ the customary words of approval _ as the popular prince shook hands with the lord chancellor, Lord <PERSON> Mackay </PERSON> of Clashfern, and left the chamber.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Economist <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Kenneth </PERSON> <PERSON> Galbraith </PERSON> and Mexican poet <PERSON> Octavio </PERSON> <PERSON> Paz </PERSON> were among those receiving the Encyclopaedia Britannica's annual award for communicating knowledge for the benefit of mankind. Also tapped Wednesday for the award were Australian historian <PERSON> Geoffrey </PERSON> <PERSON> Blainey </PERSON>, Canadian author <PERSON> Jane </PERSON> <PERSON> Jacobs </PERSON> and Chinese anthropologist and sociologist <PERSON> Fei </PERSON> <PERSON> Xiaotong </PERSON>. Each will receive a $ 25,000 cash award, a gold medal and an allowance to travel to a forum where they will be invited to speak, the encyclopedia publisher said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880218-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-18-88 0110EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-AIDSPrinciples     02-18 0502</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-AIDS Principles,0517</SECOND>
<HEAD>Big Companies Endorse Active Role in AIDS Education</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Thirty employers, including some of the nation's biggest corporations, on Wednesday endorsed a 10-point `` bill of rights'' on AIDS in the workplace formulated by a citizens group The companies committed themselves to taking an active role in educating their employees about AIDS and protecting job rights of AIDS sufferers. Among the principles formulated by the <ORGANIZATION> Citizens </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> on AIDS for <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> is a statement that people with AIDS or its virus `` are entitled to the same rights and opportunities as people with other serious or life-threatening illnesses.'' In addition, it states, AIDS victims `` do not pose a risk of transmission of the virus to coworkers through ordinary workplace contact.'' Another principle is that `` employers should provide employees with sensitive, accurate and up-to-date education about risk reduction in their personal lives.'' Requiring workers or job applicants take blood tests for the virus is specifically rejected, as is divulging medical information about an employee. <ORGANIZATION> IBM </ORGANIZATION> was the first company to endorse the principles, said <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Zucotti </PERSON>, co-chairman of the commission. Others endorsing the principles included <ORGANIZATION> AT </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ; </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> T </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Time </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Johnson </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Warner-Lambert </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> ITT </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Dow </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Chemical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION>, the City of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> and the teachers' unions of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Newark </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.J. </LOCATION> Also, <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Jersey </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Banks </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Shubert </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mirror </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Atlantic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Industries </ORGANIZATION>; Ms., <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION>, Sassy and <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> and World Report magazines; <ORGANIZATION> Rubenstein </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associates </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Rockefeller </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Brothers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fund </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Urban </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> League </ORGANIZATION>. Also, the Girl Scouts, <ORGANIZATION> Salvation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Greater </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Jersey </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> A. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Philip </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Randolph </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Lambda </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Legal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> and Education Fund, Fund for the City of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, Wildcat Services and <ORGANIZATION> Archie </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Comics </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Zucotti </PERSON> said the commission would pursue other employers and umbrella organizations of business and labor to endorse the principles. A number of businesses have asked for time to study the principles and a few rejected them, on grounds they might open themselves to lawsuits, said <PERSON> Zucotti </PERSON>. <PERSON> Zucotti </PERSON> declined to identify the rejecting companies, but a commission member, <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Stoddard </PERSON>, executive director of the Lambda fund for gay rights, said he thought the companies feared stigma more than lawsuits. State and federal statues prohibit discrimination against people who have AIDS but can work, so the principles require no more of a company legally than laws already on the books, <PERSON> Stoddard </PERSON> said. `` Those companies that have subscribed to these principles have been very courageous,'' said <PERSON> Stoddard </PERSON>. `` They have been willing to take the heat because they understand the gravity of the problem. We will continue to have the problem of stigmatization until all companies subscribe to these principles.'' Proposing and promoting the principles were the first public act of the 15-member commission, which was established in July and funded by 17 local foundations. <PERSON> Zucotti </PERSON> said the commission's mission was to marshal information and mobilize effort to improve care for AIDS sufferers, promote prevention and education about the fatal disease and address its social impact.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880218-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-18-88 0418EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-ContraAid     02-18 0643</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Contra Aid,650</SECOND>
<HEAD>Democrats' Contra Aid Package Maintains Current Funding Level</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JIM DRINKARD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A new package of purely `` humanitarian'' aid being drafted by House Democrats for <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>'s Contra rebels will continue supplying the resistance at the current rate of about $ 1.8 million a month. But House Speaker <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> said Wednesday that other crucial questions about the aid package, which is scheduled to come to the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> floor next week, remain unanswered. Unresolved are such difficult issues as how the aid will be delivered, its duration, and what kinds of incentives might be offered to <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>'s leftist <ORGANIZATION> Sandinista </ORGANIZATION> government to encourage compliance with a regional peace accord. `` It is taking shape,'' <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Texas </LOCATION>, said of the proposal. A group of <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> members, primarily Democrats, has been meeting daily to work out details of the bill, which was promised as an alternative to the administration's $ 36.2 million aid package rejected on Feb. 4. In contrast with the administration's package, which included $ 3.6 million for ammunition and anti-aircraft missiles and millions more for non-lethal military supplies, <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>'s proposal would be limited to food, clothing and medical supplies and assistance. The $ 1.8 million monthly figure does not include transportation costs, which currently are costing a like amount each month but could be lower if the aid were delivered by an international, neutral organization such as the <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION>. Rep. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Bonior </PERSON>, D-Mich., who is leading the drafting sessions, said the bill also will include a program to aid children injured during the six-year civil war <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> said under consideration as well is a possible lifting of trade sanctions against <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> and economic aid to other countries in the region, contingent on fulfillment of promises of democratization made in the five-nation peace agreement. But he emphasized that such moves could be made only with the `` enthusiastic'' backing of the administration, which would be charged with carrying them out. So far, the administration and <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> congressional leaders have declined to participate in drafting the legislation. <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> said the bill will seek to provide `` balanced incentives'' to encourage both the Contras and the <ORGANIZATION> Sandinistas </ORGANIZATION> to work out a cease-fire and live up to the peace agreement signed last Aug. 7. Both <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> and <PERSON> Bonior </PERSON> appeared cool to the idea, mentioned earlier by <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Majority Whip <PERSON> Tony </PERSON> <PERSON> Coelho </PERSON>, D-Calif., that the legislation would include a ban or restriction on fund-raising for the Contras by private <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> citizens `` I know of no provision contemplated,'' <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> said when asked about the issue. Meanwhile, a congressional opponent of aid to the Contras asked President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> to strengthen assurances that <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government personnel will not again become mired in private fund raising for the rebels as it did in the Iran-Contra affair. Rep. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Obey </PERSON>, D-Wis., also asked that <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> clarify the tax-exempt status of a fund the Contras have established to solicit private contributions from <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> citizens Last week, White House chief of staff <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> and national security adviser <PERSON> Colin </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Powell </PERSON> issued a memorandum directing that `` no administration official'' provide aid to private fund-raising efforts for the Contras. But because the memorandum was not issued by the president himself and was addressed only to White House and <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> staff members, <ORGANIZATION> Contra </ORGANIZATION> opponents have questioned whether the directive contained an important loophole. Obey, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Appropriations foreign operations subcommittee, noted that federal law prohibits such activity and that all federal officials, including those at the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION>, should be covered by the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> prohibition. He also raised questions about the Contras' fund-raising arm, the <ORGANIZATION> Nicaraguan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Resistance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Education </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION>. Contributions to the fund are tax-deductible. Obey noted that the fund had been created last October simply by changing the name of another organization that already had tax-exempt status, the <ORGANIZATION> John </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Davis </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lodge </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Studies </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880218-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-18-88 0600EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-US-Soviet 480   02-18 0483</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-US-Soviet, 480</SECOND>
<HEAD>Shultz Unlikely To Set Summit Date In Moscow Talks</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BARRY SCHWEID</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Diplomatic Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> is unlikely to agree on a date for the next superpower summit meeting until the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> ratifies a treaty to ban intermediate-range nuclear missiles, a senior <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> official says. `` I really think the Soviets probably would wait for the INF ratification,'' the official said Wednesday. `` Do n't ask me why. But I just sense it's going to be important to them to have this process that was started by the signature at the <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> summit completed.'' The official, whose identity was shielded under briefing rules at the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, referred to the Intermediate-range Nuclear Forces treaty to scrap about 2,700 <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> nuclear missiles. It was signed by President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and General Secretary <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> in December and is before the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> for ratification. In the meantime, Secretary of State <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> will hold talks in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> next Sunday and Monday on preparations for their next summit meeting. It is to be held in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>, possibly in late May or early June. The centerpiece of that fourth and final meeting between the two leaders is supposed to be a more ambitious treaty to reduce by 30 percent to 50 percent the overall <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and Soviet arsenals of long-range bombers, land-based missiles and submarines. But the official said negotiations in <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> had slowed down for several reasons. The Soviets are trying to restrict <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s Strategic Defense Initiative, the program to develop a space-based shield against ballistic missiles, and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> is resisting various restrictions on cruise missiles <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> will meet on Sunday with Foreign Minister <PERSON> Eduard </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shevardnadze </PERSON> and on Monday with <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> and <PERSON> Shevardnadze </PERSON>. He is due to fly to <LOCATION> Brussels </LOCATION> on Tuesday to brief the <ORGANIZATION> North </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Atlantic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Treaty </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> allies on the results. Meanwhile, <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Redman </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> spokesman, announced <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> also will meet with <PERSON> Andrei </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Sakharov </PERSON>, the noted Soviet dissident, while he is in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>. `` Human rights is high on his agenda,'' <PERSON> Redman </PERSON> said Wednesday. `` Mr. <PERSON> Sakharov </PERSON> obviously is a person well-placed to talk about these kind of issues.'' Assistant Secretary of State <PERSON> Rozanne </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Ridgway </PERSON>, in a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government telecast to <LOCATION> Western </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, said human rights has `` pride of place'' in <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON>' plans. Other key items are the slowed-down negotations in <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> to produce a new arms control agreement, the prospective withdrawal of 120,000 Soviet troops from <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> efforts to arrange Arab-Israeli negotiations. <PERSON> Sakharov </PERSON>, winner of the Nobel peace prize in 1975, is a physicist who helped develop the Soviet hydrogen bomb in the 1950s. His subsequent outspoken support for human rights and opposition to the <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> invasion led to his banishment to the closed city of <LOCATION> Gorky </LOCATION> in 1980. He remained there until 1986, when he was permitted to return to <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> amid <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s liberalization policy.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880218-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-18-88 0706EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-IceHouseHookers     02-18 0430</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Ice House Hookers,0440</SECOND>
<HEAD>Authorities: Stories Of Sex On Ice May Be Fish Tales</HEAD>
<DATELINE>GARRISON, Minn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Stories abound that prostitutes frequently visit ice fishing houses on <LOCATION> Mille </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lacs </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION>, where as many as 10,000 men gather on winter weekends, but authorities say they may just be fish stories. `` Personally, I've never run across the hooks, but I remember they were supposed to be working the lake back in the'60s,'' said <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON>, a fishing guide on the large central <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION> lake whose shoreline includes this town. `` At least it makes a nice story. January and February can be a real boring time of year up here,'' he said. But <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Forbord </PERSON>, a state conservation officer who has worked the lake for nine years, said he would n't be surprised if truth is found in one of two theories: Prostitutes peddle their wares fishhouse door to fishhouse door, or they do business in their own fishhouse. `` When you check houses you run into everything under the sun,'' he said. `` You do n't know if they're girlfriends, boyfriends, wives or what. Sometimes I have to let them pull on a blanket before I come in.'' Authorities say no arrests or prosecutions on prostitution charges have been made in any of the three counties that include parts of the lake. Last fall, however, an <LOCATION> Aitkin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> sheriff's deputy investigated a report that two local women were operating as prostitutes on the southeast shore, said Sheriff <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Sobey </PERSON>. The report seemed credible, but there was n't enough evidence to make an arrest, he said. `` I used to always figure it was just talk,'' <PERSON> Sobey </PERSON> said. `` I've never had a fishhouse myself, so I've never had a chance to find out. He believes authorities would know if prostitutes were active in the area. `` You'd hear something. People talk,'' he said. <ORGANIZATION> Crow </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> Attorney <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> Rathke </PERSON> said, `` I'd heard of it for years and I guess I've always assumed it was true because it's so logical You know, literally thousands of men in these little fish houses.'' This winter, there are nearly 4,000 fish houses on the lake, giving the frozen lake a bigger population than any of the cities on its shore. `` You've got to realize you get a real rowdy crew out there,'' said <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON>. `` There's gambling, seeing who can drink the most. Maybe that's how the stories start.'' <PERSON> Forbord </PERSON> has his own theory about the stories: `` Fishermen like to talk a pretty good brag. When you spend all weekend staring at a bobber, you start thinking about something else to do.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880218-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-18-88 0133EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i BC-Japan-Stocks     02-18 0025</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Japan-Stocks,0025</SECOND>
<HEAD>Stocks Up</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Nikkei Stock Average closed at 24,675.36 points, up 245.41 points, on the <ORGANIZATION> Tokyo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Stock </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Exchange </ORGANIZATION> Thursday.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880218-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-18-88 0144EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Historian-Waldheim Bjt   02-18 0744</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Historian-Waldheim, Bjt,0772</SECOND>
<HEAD>Historian Says U.S. or U.K. Could Have Records on Commando Murders</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MAUREEN JOHNSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
