<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880412-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-12-88 2344EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-Lowenfield 3rdLd-Writethru a0852 04-12 0753</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Lowenfield, 3rd Ld - Writethru, a0852,0771</SECOND>
<HEAD>Immigrant Convicted Of Killing Five Faces Execution</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: LEADS with 7 grafs to UPDATE with condemned man huddled with
LSU basketball coach, spurning last meals; picking up 6th graf pvs
``Lowenfield, a...'' ADDS byline. Ruling from federal appeals court
is still pending and execution could be as late as 4 a.m. EDT.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By KENT PRINCE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ANGOLA, La. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A Guyanese immigrant convicted of killing his girlfriend and four members of her family in a jealous rage lost appeals Tuesday in state and federal courts in his last-minute bid to avoid the electric chair. The <ORGANIZATION> Louisiana </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> and then <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Beer </PERSON> refused to put off the execution of <PERSON> Leslie </PERSON> <PERSON> Lowenfield </PERSON>, 34, which is set for early Wednesday. <PERSON> Lowenfield </PERSON>'s attorneys then went to the 5th <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Circuit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appeals </ORGANIZATION> with the plea that he is mentally ill and therefore unable to understand the death penalty. At the <ORGANIZATION> Louisiana </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Penitentiary </ORGANIZATION>, Warden <PERSON> Hilton </PERSON> <PERSON> Butler </PERSON> said <PERSON> Lowenfield </PERSON> was still hoping for a fifth delay of as many execution dates. <PERSON> Butler </PERSON> said <PERSON> Lowenfield </PERSON> spurned the condemned's customary last meal and spent the evening with <PERSON> Dale </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>, the head basketball coach from <ORGANIZATION> Louisiana </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>, widely recognized as a motivational speaker, had been corresponding with <PERSON> Lowenfield </PERSON> since he took the <ORGANIZATION> LSU </ORGANIZATION> team on a tour of <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION>'s death row in 1984, <PERSON> Butler </PERSON> said. A Catholic priest and nun also were with <PERSON> Lowenfield </PERSON>, the warden said. <PERSON> Lowenfield </PERSON>, a welder from <LOCATION> Guyana </LOCATION> who came to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> in 1981 on a work permit, was convicted in 1984 in the August 1982 slayings of his estranged girlfriend, who was a <ORGANIZATION> Jefferson </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Parish </ORGANIZATION> sheriff's deputy, and four others. The case has already been appealed unsuccessfully to both the state's highest court and the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>. Lawyers based their latest appeal on a recent psychological study that found the prisoner to be a paranoid schizophrenic. `` There is a serious question about <PERSON> Leslie </PERSON>'s competency to be executed due to his mental illness,'' said <PERSON> Judith </PERSON> <PERSON> Menadue </PERSON>, attorney for the <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION> Capital Defense Project. She said the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> has ruled that people who can not understand what it means to be executed may not be put to death. Before the trial, <PERSON> Lowenfield </PERSON> was found competent, and he refused to allow his lawyers to use insanity as a defense, insisting instead that he was in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> at the time the family was killed. But no witnesses backed up his story of being out of state. The denial of the stay was issued without further comment from the state <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> majority, but the one member who backed the appeal issued a brief dissent. `` The clinical psychologist who spent five hours with the defendant concluded: ` Lowenfield indicated that he is currently unable to understand the death penalty,''' Justice <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Dixon </PERSON> wrote. He noted that criminal law calls for halting prosecution when there are reasonable grounds to doubt a defendant's sanity, and for going ahead after that only when the defendant is found to have the mental capacity to do so. Prosecutors said <PERSON> Lowenfield </PERSON> barged into his girlfriend's house in <LOCATION> Marrero </LOCATION>, a <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION> suburb, and shot everybody there. The victims were the girlfriend, <PERSON> Sheila </PERSON> <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON>, 27; her daughter, <PERSON> Shantel </PERSON> <PERSON> Osborne </PERSON>, 4; her stepfather, <PERSON> Owen </PERSON> <PERSON> Griffin </PERSON>, 45; her mother, <PERSON> Myrtle </PERSON> <PERSON> Griffin </PERSON>, 44; and the little girl's father, <PERSON> Carl </PERSON> <PERSON> Osborne </PERSON>, 33. The prosecution said <PERSON> Lowenfield </PERSON> was jealous of Miss <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON>. They said the couple had lived together in a stormy relationship until earlier in the summer of 1982 when he set the house on fire and she moved out. Investigators found a notebook full of obscenities and threats. In one place he wrote, `` She have to go to the wormes she took all I work for then leave to go and be with <PERSON> Carl </PERSON> but I just can not take it eany more.'' <PERSON> Lowenfield </PERSON> was arrested two months later in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>. Parts of the evidence against him were letters he wrote Miss <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON>' relatives while he was jailed in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>. One said <PERSON> Osborne </PERSON> had grabbed the child as a shield and <PERSON> Lowenfield </PERSON> had shot both of them. On trial, <PERSON> Lowenfield </PERSON> insisted on an alibi defense, saying he was in <LOCATION> Jacksonville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>, looking for work at the time of the murders. After a separate trial to determine the penalty, jurors came back three times saying they could not decide whether he should die. Prodded on by the judge, they decided on the fourth try to condemn him to death.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880412-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-12-88 0514EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--HeartTransplant     04-12 0095</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Heart Transplant,0098</SECOND>
<HEAD>Jarvik-7 Recipient Dies</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PITTSBURGH (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A man who was sustained six days by a Jarvik-7 artificial heart until undergoing a transplant has died. <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gabriel </PERSON>, 38, of <ORGANIZATION> Arnold </ORGANIZATION>, died Sunday at Presbyterian-University Hospital of <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Gabriel </PERSON> received the transplant April 7, six days after surgeons implanted the mechanical heart. He had suffered a massive heart attack March 30. <PERSON> Gabriel </PERSON> was the 18th person to receive an artificial heart at the hospital, officials said Monday. <PERSON> Gabriel </PERSON> was a production underwriter for <ORGANIZATION> Pennsylvania </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Insurance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Murrysville </LOCATION> for 14 years.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880412-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-12-88 0001EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-LongHijackings     04-12 0184</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Long Hijackings,0188</SECOND>
<HEAD>Longest Ordeals of Captives of Hijacked Planes</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Hijack Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 The hijacking drama of a Kuwaiti airliner seized April 5 entered its second week today. Here is a list of prolonged hijack incidents: JULY 23-SEPT. 1, 1968 _ <ORGANIZATION> El </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Al </ORGANIZATION> flight from <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Tel </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Aviv </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>, is diverted to <LOCATION> Algeria </LOCATION> by <PERSON> Arab </PERSON> nationalists Forty days later, <LOCATION> Algeria </LOCATION> releases the last 12 passengers held hostage. SEPT. 6-30, 1970 _ Palestinian commandos hijack three airliners to a desert airstrip outside <LOCATION> Amman </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION>. Most passengers are released by Sept. 12, when the Palestinians blow up the three planes, but 54 people are held hostage for 24 days. JUNE 15-JULY 1, 1985 _ Shiite Moslem gunmen hijack <ORGANIZATION> TWA </ORGANIZATION> Athens-to-Rome flight to <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>. Some passengers are released but 40 men are held hostage. One hostage, <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> diver <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Stetham </PERSON>, is shot dead; 17 days later the remaining 39 are released. MARCH 2-15, 1981 _ Pakistani hijackers commandeer Pakistani jet, diverting it to <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> and on to <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION>. All 148 hostages are released after 13 days aboard the plane.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880412-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-12-88 0002EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Singleton     04-12 0539</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Singleton,0554</SECOND>
<HEAD>Convicted Rapist-Mutilator Says He's Pursuing Legal Action Against
Victim</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SAN QUENTIN, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A man convicted of raping and maiming a teenager almost 10 years ago is seeking a criminal investigation into his allegation that the woman actually kidnapped him, a newspaper reported Monday. <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> <PERSON> Singleton </PERSON>, who is scheduled to be freed April 25 after serving seven years and nine months in prison and a year on parole, said he filed a complaint in <ORGANIZATION> Superior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Placer </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Marin </LOCATION> counties requesting the woman's arrest, the <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ledger </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Antioch </ORGANIZATION> reported. <PERSON> Singleton </PERSON>, 60, was convicted in 1979 of raping <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Vincent </PERSON>, then 15, and hacking off her forearms with an ax on Sept. 29, 1978. He was sentenced to 14 years and 4 months in prison, which was reduced for good behavior and work credit. <PERSON> Singleton </PERSON> said he will move to <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION> to spend his `` first few days'' of freedom with a church group after his release, the newspaper said, but he did not rule out a return to <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Singleton </PERSON> has spent the last 10 months of his parole in a trailer on the grounds of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Quentin </LOCATION> state prison for his own protection after residents of several northern <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> communities protested against his planned parole last year. <PERSON> Vincent </PERSON>, who expressed anxiety about his parole at that time, has moved to the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Northwest </LOCATION> and recently told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> through an intermediary that she did not want to be interviewed further about <PERSON> Singleton </PERSON>. The Ledger said it obtained a copy of a 12-page, typewritten complaint in which <PERSON> Singleton </PERSON> alleges <PERSON> Vincent </PERSON> committed kidnap for the purpose of robbery and use of two deadly weapons. According to the Ledger, the complaint said <PERSON> Singleton </PERSON> was heading to <PERSON> Sparks </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Nev. </LOCATION>, when he picked up <PERSON> Vincent </PERSON> hitchhiking in <LOCATION> Berkeley </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, and agreed to take her to <PERSON> Reno </PERSON>. The complaint said <PERSON> Vincent </PERSON> began smoking PCP, a hallucinogen, then said she wanted to go to <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>, became abusive and poked <PERSON> Singleton </PERSON> with a three-foot surveyor stick, the newspaper reported. `` -LRB- She -RRB- told me that if I did not comply with her wishes she would poke out my eyes, smash my face, and hurt, hurt, hurt me and say that I raped her,'' the newspaper quoted the complaint as saying. The complaint also alleges <PERSON> Vincent </PERSON> threatened <PERSON> Singleton </PERSON> with a six-inch fish-scaling knife, the newspaper reported. <PERSON> Singleton </PERSON> claims he drove <PERSON> Vincent </PERSON> to <LOCATION> Galt </LOCATION>, 20 miles south of <LOCATION> Sacramento </LOCATION>, where he picked up two male hitchhikers who joined <PERSON> Vincent </PERSON> in extorting money from <PERSON> Singleton </PERSON> to buy drugs, the newspaper reported. The complaint says <PERSON> Singleton </PERSON> drove north and left <LOCATION> Vincent </LOCATION> in a `` low-rent district'' in <LOCATION> Sacramento </LOCATION> and never saw her again, the newspaper reported. Although not in the complaint, <PERSON> Singleton </PERSON> has repeatedly claimed he allowed one of the hitchhikers to drive while he was drinking, passed out, then awoke to find <PERSON> Vincent </PERSON> was gone but her clothes were still in the van. The hitchhikers, he has contended, committed the crimes. Authorities, however, have maintained the two hitchhikers never existed. <PERSON> Singleton </PERSON> said in a telephone interview he mailed the complaint Saturday to authorities in the two counties, but court clerks in both counties said Monday morning they had not received the complaints, the Ledger reported.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880412-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-12-88 0003EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FarmScene     04-12 0642</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Farm Scene,640</SECOND>
<HEAD>Brazilian Drought, European Demand Raise Soybean Prices</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DON KENDALL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Farm Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Soybean market prices are averaging the most in three years because of greater world demand and a tightening of available supplies, an <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> analysis shows. Drought has damaged <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION>'s soybean crop, and the <ORGANIZATION> European </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Community </ORGANIZATION> has increased its demand for the oilseed, the department's <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> said Monday. That has helped whittle down <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> soybean stockpiles and boost prices. The supply-and-demand report said soybean prices now could average in the range of $ 5.50 to $ 5.80 per bushel in the marketing year that began last Sept. 1, up from $ 5.35 to $ 5.75 forecast in March. Prices averaged $ 4.78 per bushel in the 1986-87 season. According to <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> records, that would be the most since soybeans averaged $ 5.84 per bushel in 1984-85. They were $ 7.83 in the 1983-84 marketing year. Soybean exports were forecast at 785 million bushels, up from 760 million indicated last month and the 757 million bushels shipped in 1986-87. Wheat exports also have improved, due mainly to subsidized sales to the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> under the department's Export Enhancement Program, or EEP. In all, exports in the wheat marketing year that runs through May 31 are estimated at 1.6 billion bushels, a 60 percent increase from 1 billion bushels shipped in 1986-87. Average market prices for this season were put at $ 2.55 per bushel, up from $ 2.42 last year. Corn exports also are up, rising to an estimated 1.7 billion bushels in the corn marketing year that began last Sept. 1, compared with 1.5 billion bushels in 1986-87. Market prices of corn were forecast to average $ 1.65 to $ 1.85 per bushel this season, up from $ 1.50 in 1986-87.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Agriculture Department scientists are looking at the neem tree of <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> as a possible source of material to prevent the formation of aflatoxin, a food toxin that occurs in nature. Aflatoxin can be produced by fungi that forms on some farm crops under certain conditions, including corn and oilseeds. Laboratory tests with animals have shown that aflatoxin is among the most powerful cancer-causing agents known, and <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> has called it a `` potential'' hazard to humans. <PERSON> Deepak </PERSON> <PERSON> Bhatnagar </PERSON> said in a report released here that as a child in <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> his parents used to put leaves of the neem tree inside containers of wheat to keep insects from the grain. Now, as a <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> scientist, he has found that the leaves may also block fungi from producing aflatoxin. In tests at the department's <ORGANIZATION> Agricultural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> center in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> La. </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Bhatnagar </PERSON> made solutions containing neem leaves. He found that the solutions did n't kill the fungi but did block more than 98 percent of the aflatoxin they normally would have produced. The fungi that produce the toxin are Aspergillus flavus and A. parasiticus. <PERSON> Bhatnagar </PERSON> said the results were `` promising, but preliminary'' and that greenhouse studies with cotton are now being planned. The ornamental neem is also known as margosa and nim. More than 80 insect pests, including Mexican bean beetles, <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION> potato beetles, tobacco budworms and carpet beetles are repelled by neem extracts.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Spice imports totaled about $ 439 million last year, up 12 percent from 1986, says the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>. The rise was due mainly to larger imports of vanilla beans, white pepper, nutmeg and mace, cassia, cumin, anise, capsicum peppers, laurel and thyme, the department's <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agricultural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> reported Monday. Higher prices of many of the items also were a factor. `` Saffron prices have soared in recent months, reflecting a short Spanish crop,'' the report said. Also, it added, cesium contamination from the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>'s nuclear mishap at <LOCATION> Chernobyl </LOCATION> two years ago `` has kept supplies tight and prices firm for several Mediterranean-area herbs such as oregano, laurel, rosemary and sage.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880412-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-12-88 0016EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-TaxReturns Bjt   04-12 0751</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Tax Returns, Bjt,750</SECOND>
<HEAD>Young People Are Feeling The Tax Bite, Too, As Friday Approaches</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JIM LUTHER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Tax Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Millions of young Americans are filling out federal tax returns for the first time as Friday's filing deadline approaches, and many of them are learning that you do n't always get a refund. Several new provisions affecting students who work part-time and youngsters under the age of 14 took effect in 1987 and are being felt on returns filed this year. The net effect is to complicate the finances of these people and, in many cases, of their parents. The <ORGANIZATION> Internal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Revenue </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> estimates 3.3 million people are having to file returns for the first time because a section of the 1986 law denies a personal exemption, worth $ 1,900 for 1987, to those who can be claimed as a dependent by a parent or someone else. In addition, young people can lose a good portion of their $ 2,540 standard deduction by being claimed by a parent. And thresholds for filing are lower than in the past. Two other new provisions:
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 _ Any child 5 or older who is claimed as a dependent must have a Social Security number, which must be listed on the parents' The <ORGANIZATION> IRS </ORGANIZATION> has waived the penalty for not listing the number on 1987 returns, but it's still required. _ Any investment income exceeding $ 1,000 received by a child under 14 is now taxed at the parents' higher rate, assuming that is higher than the child's rate These calculations must be made on Form 8615, which must be attached to the child's return. <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> imposed this requirement to block mainly higher-income parents from avoiding taxes by shifting income-producing property to a child. Under the old law, a parent could have avoided $ 390 of tax on $ 1,000 worth of interest that was credited to the child's account, paying $ 110 instead of $ 500 This `` kiddie tax'' provision has been a source of anguish for taxpayers, experts say. `` There is more confusion in trying to fill out the forms than there is surprise about so many minors having to file for the first time,'' says <PERSON> Vern </PERSON> <PERSON> Martens </PERSON>, senior tax attorney at <ORGANIZATION> Merrill </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lynch </ORGANIZATION> headquarters in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>. Three other new forms are causing questions, too, although relatively few of the 107 million couples and individuals who are expected to file returns this year will have to face them. They are: _ 8598, which fewer than 1 million people will have to file to calculate how much of their home mortgage interest is deductible It generally applies only to those whose outstanding mortgage and home equity loans total more than the purchase price of the home and any improvements. _ 8606, required mainly of middle - and upper-income taxpayers who make non-deductible contributions to an _ 8582, for calculating losses on rental operations and other `` passive-activity'' investments If you do n't feel ready to tackle any of these forms _ or the basic 1040 or 1040A _ you might consider filing Form 4868. Filing this form, and your check for what you estimate you owe, by midnight Friday will give you an extra four months to file your return. If you underestimate your taxes, you will be liable for interest and penalty on the shortage. But the four-month reprieve might keep you from rushing into a mistake. The <ORGANIZATION> IRS </ORGANIZATION> expects about 6 \ million couples and individuals to ask for the automatic delay, about 1 million more than last year <ORGANIZATION> IRS </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> <PERSON> Fadely </PERSON> cautions: `` If you wait until the last day to look at the library or Post Office for the form, you may not find one.'' The <ORGANIZATION> IRS </ORGANIZATION> expects 37 million returns during the three weeks ending April 22. More than 58 million had been received by April 1. Some of the remainder will be filed after the deadline; some will come later from military personnel stationed abroad; and some taxpayers have different deadlines. The <ORGANIZATION> IRS </ORGANIZATION> has processed 81 percent of the returns received so far, down slightly from last year. More than 77 percent are getting refunds, compared with 78 percent at this time last year. Refunds are averaging $ 825, up from $ 806. Although tax rates were cut, many people are paying more tax because all or parts of several deductions were lost. These include sales taxes, consumer interest, medical expenses, such miscellaneous itemized writeoffs as union dues, the special deduction for two-earner couples, and _ in many cases _ some or all the deduction for Individual Retirement Account contributions.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880412-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-12-88 0017EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FinanceMinisters     04-12 0596</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Finance Ministers,590</SECOND>
<HEAD>Baker Plan Receiving Warm Reception</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARTIN CRUTSINGER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Treasury Secretary <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON> seems to be making progress in his drive to get the world's top economic powers to use the price of gold and other commodities to help them coordinate economic policies. <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> took economic leaders by surprise when he advanced the idea last September, with some countries openly skeptical. But <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> has demonstrated considerable skill as one of the administration's top negotiators and officials indicated Monday that the world's seven top industrial countries are likely to give formal approval to <PERSON> Baker </PERSON>'s commodity-index proposal on Wednesday. The seven nations, the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>, will hold high-level talks in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> as part of the spring meeting of the 151-nation <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Monetary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fund </ORGANIZATION>. A senior <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> official, briefing reporters Monday, said the administration is `` hopeful there will be some agreement'' by the seven countries to adopt the commodity-basket proposal. The official spoke on condition his name not be used. <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> has stressed that he is not proposing a return to the gold standard, the system in use for 25 years after World War II. For most of that time, the price of gold was fixed at $ 35 an ounce and the currencies of other countries were pegged at fixed exchange rates to the dollar. That system broke down in the early 1970s under the weight of higher inflation and a rising flow of international capital between countries. It was replaced with today's floating exchange rate system under which the value of each nation's currency is set on the open market. But the extreme volatility in floating rates, especially for the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> dollar, has driven the big industrial countries in search of ways to stabilize exchange rates. One method that <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> has pushed since the <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION> economic summit in 1986 has been the use of a variety of economic indicators to monitor each country's performance in helping to sustain worldwide growth. This group of indicators includes individual growth rates, inflation and trade balances. <PERSON> Baker </PERSON>'s proposal would add gold and other commodity prices to the list of economic yardsticks the countries use to coordinate policies. This approach would introduce a price-sensitive measure into the economic planning process. In addition to gold, other commodities which might be included are iron ore, copper, rubber, cotton, wheat, rice, corn, coffee and tea. If the price of these commodities rose in particular countries, those nations would be encouraged to boost interest rates to fight inflation. But if commodity prices were falling, the countries would know they had room to cut interest rates and stimulate economic growth without danger of inflation. Some countries, in particular <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, have opposed the commodity index because they see it as a device that would be used to goad them into achieving faster growth at the risk of sparking inflation. But in a television interview Monday, <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> said the seven top industrial countries were in basic agreement at present over the steps needed to stabilize exchange rates. `` The major industrialized countries of the world obviously favor stability of exchange rates and we have been very pleased with the stability we have seen since our last meeting in December,'' <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> said on <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Today'' program. Last Dec. 22, the seven countries pledged to support the dollar, which at the time was under heavy selling pressure. That commitment was backed up by massive intervention, the process by which governments buy weak currencies such as the dollar to drive up the price.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880412-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-12-88 0022EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-TeacherStudy Bjt   04-12 0627</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Teacher Study, Bjt,0645</SECOND>
<HEAD>After 10 Years of Reform, Teachers Still Not Full-Fledged
Professionals</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LEE MITGANG</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Education Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A decade of school reform has produced stacks of legislation, higher teacher pay and tighter teaching requirements but has left unresolved whether teachers are full-fledged professionals, a report says. `` By sheer volume of legislation, it is clear that teaching has been ` reformed,''' said the 80-page <ORGANIZATION> Rand </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> report, `` The Evolution of Teacher Policy,'' released Monday. `` Teaching policy is up for grabs _ and there are lots of people grabbing,'' it said. The net result of hundreds of education-related bills enacted during the past decade has been contradiction and confusion, concluded the report by researchers <PERSON> Linda </PERSON> <PERSON> Darling-Hammond </PERSON> and <PERSON> Barnett </PERSON> <PERSON> Barry </PERSON>. School reform has yet to settle whether teachers are professionals possessing a body of knowledge and capable of dealing with the individual needs of students, or whether they are merely `` semiskilled workers'' needing constant supervision, the researchers said. Still, the report found that average salaries rose 31 percent from 1981 to 1986 to $ 25,240, and 19 states adopted minimum salary schedules. More recent figures from the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Education </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> estimate average salaries at $ 28,000 this year. Starting salaries are also up, but not enough to close the gap between teaching and other professions. According to NEA figures, the average was $ 17,500 in 1987, while beginning accountants, chemists, computer specialists and engineers, for example, all earned in excess of $ 20,000. Overall, the average teacher's purchasing power is practically unchanged from 1971-72 levels, according to the analysis. Nearly all states considered performance-based pay systems, including merit pay, from 1983 to 1986. But such programs often have encountered delays because of teacher opposition and lack of funds. Twenty-seven states enacted tougher teacher training requirements, including testing of academic ability and minimum grade-point averages. States are increasingly stressing liberal arts background over education courses. `` Paradoxically, for a number of states, improving teacher preparation seems to mean reducing the amount of time devoted to traditional teacher education,'' the report said. By 1986, 46 states required teacher competency testing for admission to teacher education or certification or both. But such testing has stalled in many states because of lack of funding or questions about the tests's validity. In a contradiction, 46 states have cleared the way for substandard, limited emergency certification. Twenty-seven of those states issue certificates to people lacking even a bachelor's degree to solve teacher shortages `` This practice undermines the tenet ... that only those who have mastered a specialized knowledge base will be admitted to practice,'' the report said. <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Education </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> President <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Hatwood </PERSON> <PERSON> Futrell </PERSON> called the Rand report `` right on target.'' <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Goldberg </PERSON>, assistant director of educational issues for the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Teachers </ORGANIZATION>, called the report `` obviously correct. If teaching is to become a true profession, then teachers will have to be granted the kind of autonomy required of any other profession.'' The Rand study is being published nearly five years after the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration issued the report `` A Nation at Risk,'' which blasted mediocrity in <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> schools. While initial reform efforts aimed at boosting salaries and toughening teacher certification requirements, a more recent wave of reforms has stressed freeing teachers from unnecessary regulations and boosting their status. In effect, reformers in the last two years have come to believe that there should be higher standards to enter teaching, but fewer rules about what and how to teach. `` This is, in essence, the bargain that all professions make with society,'' the report said. `` The next generation of teacher policy reform will need to focus on the content and nature of effective teaching, its assessment, and its deployment within schools to ensure that the long-range goals of the reformers are met,'' the report concluded.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880412-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-12-88 0030EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-BudgetSurvey     04-12 0501</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Budget Survey,490</SECOND>
<HEAD>Congress More Resistant than Public to Social Security Changes</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Budget</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By STEVEN KOMAROW</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Americans are more willing than their representatives in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to consider changes in the Social Security system, but no single option for cutting costs has broad public support, according to a survey. The public also strongly favors pulling <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> troops out of <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> as a way to reduce the federal budget deficit, according to the survey by the League of Concerned Americans, a <LOCATION> Charlotte </LOCATION>, N.C.-based non-profit group. The league commissioned the nationwide poll as part of a project called `` <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s Budget,'' an effort to determine national spending priorities from a non-Washington perspective. It planned to release a suggested budget today. `` A lot of things that are perceptually true in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> ... are not that way across the country,'' said <PERSON> Scott </PERSON> <PERSON> Rasmussen </PERSON>, founder of the league. For example, an informal congressional survey showed 80 percent of the members favored leaving the Social Security system untouched. Only 34 percent favored that option in the nationwide poll. However, people differed over what changes should be made, the poll showed. From a list of options, 21 percent favored making the system voluntary and 25 percent supported raising the retirement age to allow a drop in the Social Security tax. Only 6 percent favored cutting cost-of-living adjustments for retirees _ the most frequently mentioned option when <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> considers cutbacks. <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> has been holding hearings this year on what lawmakers call `` burden sharing'' _ forcing <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> allies to take on more of the cost of defending against the Soviet bloc. The informal survey of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> showed only 12 percent said they would favor gradually withdrawing `` a substantial portion'' of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> troops from <LOCATION> Western </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> over the next 20 years. However, more than three out of four citizens polled supported the idea. The poll was conducted for the league by <ORGANIZATION> Marketwise </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> , </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc </ORGANIZATION>. The random sample of 519 respondents has a margin of error of 4.3 percentage points. Despite the 1983 changes in the Social Security, which included raising taxes to build up big surpluses over the next few years, more than a fourth of the people polled still doubt whether their benefits will be there when they retire, according to the survey. `` I think there is a real temptation -LRB- to spend the money -RRB- if there are surpluses,'' said <PERSON> Rasmussen </PERSON>. Sen. <PERSON> Lawton </PERSON> <PERSON> Chiles </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Fla </LOCATION>., chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Budget </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, said Monday he would propose a resolution to put <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> on record opposing the current accounting system which allows Social Security surpluses to hide the true size of the government's operating deficit <PERSON> Rasmussen </PERSON>, a business entrepreneur who with his father founded the <ORGANIZATION> ESPN </ORGANIZATION> sports network in 1978, said he hoped the league would help prod the politicians to keep working toward a balanced budget. The results were being presented to the new national commission on the deficit, which will make recommendations for the next president and <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> on ways to cut red ink, he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880412-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-12-88 0030EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Jet-Windshield     04-12 0181</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Jet-Windshield,0186</SECOND>
<HEAD>Damaged Window Forces Jet To Make Emergency Landing</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SAN FRANCISCO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A jumbo jet bound for <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> from <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> made a successful emergency landing here Monday after the plastic layers in one of the cockpit side windows began to come apart, an airport spokesman said. Pan Am Flight 150, with 322 passengers on board, left <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> for <LOCATION> Frankfurt </LOCATION> about 3 p.m., turned back about an hour and a half later, and made a safe emergency landing at <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> <LOCATION> International </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION> about 5:30, said spokesman <PERSON> Ron </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON>. The pilot of the <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> 747 turned back after he heard a loud snap and saw a window on his left begin to `` delaminate,'' <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> said. `` Obviously the aircraft could not fly at any altitude or great speed with that,'' <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> said. `` I do n't think there was ever any danger. The pilot did what he was supposed to do.'' The pilot had to reduce the plane's altitude and depressurize the cabin somewhat on the way back, <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> said. He said the window would be repaired at the airport.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880412-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-12-88 0032EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-GovernmentDefined Bjt   04-12 0752</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Government Defined, Bjt,720</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHINGTON WIRE: Politics? Here's What it Really Means ...</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LAWRENCE L. KNUTSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A new book offers some timely definitions in this season of taxes and politics, including the observation that a `` front-runner'' these days is someone who claims to be the underdog for fear of going the way of his predecessors. Or, for example, that the art of taxation has been defined as `` so plucking the goose as to obtain the largest amount of feathers with the least amount of hissing.'' Front-runner is `` what all candidates want to be, but do n't want to be called,'' says the recently published `` <ORGANIZATION> Dorsey </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dictionary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Politics </ORGANIZATION>,'' a product of <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Dorsey </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>. With 4,000 entries, the book compiled and written by <PERSON> Jay </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shafritz </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pittsburgh </ORGANIZATION> graduate school aims to capture in dictionary form the nuts and bolts of American constitutional government, including the slang and stories of its 199 years of existence. It provides descriptions of government agencies, court decisions, people, places, things and states of mind. A box charts the rise of the federal budget deficit from $ 2.8 billion under President <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> in 1970 to $ 220.7 billion under President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> in 1986. One entry recalls <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Jefferson </PERSON> asking <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Washington </PERSON> why the constitutional convention _ over which <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> had presided _ had created a <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> as well as a House. `` Why do you pour your coffee into your saucer?'' <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> is supposed to have asked <PERSON> Jefferson </PERSON>. `` To cool it,'' <PERSON> Jefferson </PERSON> replied. `` Even so,'' concluded <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. `` We pour legislation into the senatorial saucer to cool it.'' Flipping through the pages, one finds that one possible origin of the word <ORGANIZATION> Yankee </ORGANIZATION> to designate Americans in general or <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Englanders </LOCATION> in particular is from `` a corruption of <PERSON> Jan </PERSON> <PERSON> Kees </PERSON>, an unkind Dutch nickname meaning <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Cheese </PERSON>.'' `` The Dutch, who first settled <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, applied the name to the English who followed,'' the dictionary says. Then there is `` stand pat.'' It is described as a phrase originating in the game of poker that has been extended to mean one who accepts a present situation or stands by an existing policy. `` Nobody in American politics today is in favor of standing pat,'' the dictionary maintains and adds: `` There is a classic piece of film from the 1960 presidential campaign in which <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON>, with his wife, <PERSON> Pat </PERSON>, seated behind him, energetically tells an audience that _ ` We ca n't stand pat.''' `` Subsequently, to Mrs. <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON>'s presumed relief, he changed that line to ` <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> can not stand still.''' As his term nears an end, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> is at times referred to as a `` lame duck.'' The dictionary says the phrase originated in the early days of the <ORGANIZATION> London </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Stock </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Exchange </ORGANIZATION> which then operated out of Exchange Alley. The dictionary: `` A broker who went bankrupt would ` waddle out of the alley' like a lame duck.'' The expression has long since crossed the <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> and expanded its meaning to any soon-to-be-out-of-office leader whose authority is consequently impaired. Most of the dictionary's topics involve serious subjects. Deregulation, deterrence, devaluation and dictators, for example. But it does have flashes of humor. One such flash: How to tell the difference between Republicans and Democrats. The dictionary quotes from the anonymous wit whose musings were inserted in the Congressional Record some years ago by the late <PERSON> Craig </PERSON> <PERSON> Hosmer </PERSON>, then a Republican congressman from <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>. To wit: `` Democrats buy most of the books that have been banned somewhere. Republicans form censorship committees and read them as a group. `` Democrats give their worn-out clothes to those less fortunate. Republicans wear theirs. `` Republicans employ exterminators. Democrats step on the bugs. `` Democrats name their children after currently popular sports figures, politicians and entertainers. Republican children are named after their parents or grandparents, according to where the most money is. `` Republicans tend to keep their shades down, although there is seldom any reason why they should. Democrats ought to, but do n't. `` Republicans study the financial pages of the newspaper. Democrats put them in the bottom of the bird cage. `` Republicans raise dahlias, Dalmatians and eyebrows. Democrats raise Airedales, kids and taxes. `` Democrats eat the fish they catch. Republicans hang them on the wall. `` Republican boys date Democratic girls. They plan to marry <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> girls but feel they're entitled to a little fun first. `` Democrats make up plans and then do something else. Republicans follow the plans their grandparents made. `` Republicans sleep in twin beds _ some even in separate rooms. This is why there are more Democrats.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880412-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-12-88 0033EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-BRF--ItalianDeportation     04-12 0185</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Italian Deportation,180</SECOND>
<HEAD>Pizza Parlor Owner Wanted In Italy Ordered Deported</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ARLINGTON, Va. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A pizza parlor owner wanted in <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION> in connection with the murder of an Sicilian judge on Monday was ordered deported by an <ORGANIZATION> Immigration </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Naturalization </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> judge. <PERSON> Salvatore </PERSON> <PERSON> Inzerillo </PERSON>, part-owner of a restaurant in <LOCATION> Woodbridge </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, had asked to be allowed to leave the country voluntarily. But Judge <PERSON> Joan </PERSON> <PERSON> V. </PERSON> <PERSON> Arrowsmith </PERSON> denied the request, saying that would allow <PERSON> Inzerillo </PERSON> to go to the country of his choice. She said he should be returned to <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION> for trial. <PERSON> Inzerillo </PERSON> has been in <ORGANIZATION> INS </ORGANIZATION> custody since Feb. 23. Italian authorities have issued an arrest warrant for him in the 1980 slaying of Judge <PERSON> Gaetano </PERSON> <PERSON> Costa </PERSON>, who was investigating drug trafficking in <LOCATION> Sicily </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> agent <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Glass </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> testified that <PERSON> Inzerillo </PERSON> had connections with the Mafia, but <PERSON> Inzerillo </PERSON> denied being a member of the Mafia and said he is not a drug dealer. <PERSON> Inzerillo </PERSON> said he hired a smuggler to get him into the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> in 1981 to seek work. His attorney said he will appeal the deportation ruling.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880412-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-12-88 0034EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-BasketballChamps     04-12 0291</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Basketball Champs,290</SECOND>
<HEAD>Reagan Praises Jayhawks, Lady Techsters For Championships</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> saluted the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Kansas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Jayhawks </ORGANIZATION> and the Lady Techsters of <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION> Tech for winning <ORGANIZATION> NCAA </ORGANIZATION> basketball championships, calling them `` fighters'' who overcame adversity. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> met the teams Monday in the White House Rose Garden to honor them for earning the national titles last week. `` Now it's no secret that at the beginning of the <ORGANIZATION> NCAA </ORGANIZATION> tournament, you <PERSON> Jayhawks </PERSON>, well I suppose the way to put it is to say you were n't exactly favored to win,'' said <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>. `` So what happened is a testament to determination, to hard work, lots and lots of hard work, to pride, to teamwork and the courage to dream.'' The <ORGANIZATION> Jayhawks </ORGANIZATION> defeated the <ORGANIZATION> Oklahoma </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sooners </ORGANIZATION> 83-79 a week ago to win the men's title, and finished the season 27-11. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> recounted how the Lady Techsters overcame a 12-point halftime deficit to defeat <ORGANIZATION> Auburn </ORGANIZATION> 56-54 in the final moments of their championship game. `` You had a lot of great games this season, but none was greater than the last,'' the president told the <ORGANIZATION> Louisiana </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tech </ORGANIZATION> team. Star guard <PERSON> Teresa </PERSON> <PERSON> Weatherspoon </PERSON> presented <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> with an autographed basketball. <PERSON> Danny </PERSON> <PERSON> Manning </PERSON>, who scored 31 points in the <ORGANIZATION> Jayhawks </ORGANIZATION>' championship win, gave <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> two KU letter jackets _ one bearing the president's nickname, `` Dutch,'' and the other for his wife, <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> `` We're very thrilled and it's especially an honor to be here,'' said <PERSON> Manning </PERSON>. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> also took note of an announcement by KU Coach <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> last week that he intended to remain at KU and not accept the <ORGANIZATION> UCLA </ORGANIZATION> coaching job. To applause, the president said, `` I know <ORGANIZATION> Jayhawk </ORGANIZATION> fans everywhere are rejoicing that next year I'm the only one moving back to <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880412-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-12-88 0034EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--China-Soviets     04-12 0140</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--China-Soviets,0144</SECOND>
<HEAD>China Hoping To Increase Trade With Soviet Union</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, hoping to increase trade with the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, has set up five new trade ports and plans eight more, the official <ORGANIZATION> China </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> newspaper said today. <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> says it has a large surplus of labor, arable land and industrial commodities but is short of timber, electricity and fertilizer. The <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> suffers shortages of labor, agricultural products and light industrial and textile products but has good supplies of timber, coal and petroleum, the paper said. Presently, <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> has only three trade ports, all in <LOCATION> Heilongjiang </LOCATION> province, bordering the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. The State Council has given provincial authorities the power to approve its own export projects, to set up barter trade, to set up joint projects with the Soviets and to exchange technology.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880412-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-12-88 0039EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-WorldPoverty     04-12 0311</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-World Poverty,310</SECOND>
<HEAD>French Agriculture Minister Advocates Agriculture Development Plan</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CARL HARTMAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, western <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> and other big grain producers should create a fund that would help develop farming in the Third World, French Agriculture Minister <PERSON> Francois </PERSON> <PERSON> Guillaume </PERSON> says. <PERSON> Guillaume </PERSON> says such a plan would help narrow the growing gap between rich and poor countries. <PERSON> Guillaume </PERSON> spoke Monday at an open meeting with <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> officials and farm experts. `` Public opinion can not understand that politicans in the developed countries are unable to put the grains stored in American and <LOCATION> European </LOCATION> silos into the stomachs of men and women in developing countries,'' he said. Meanwhile, both the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and western <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> are each spending about $ 30 billion a year to subsidize farmers, he said. During a news conference he described his proposal, under which grain producers would fix a floor price for grain at a level that would not stimulate new production. They would then contribute part of the difference between the floor price and actual selling prices to a fund that <PERSON> Guillaume </PERSON> likened to the Marshall Plan, which helped western <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> recover from World War II. The fund would be used to improve farming in Third World countries. He estimated that it could furnish $ 1.8 billion to $ 4 billion a year from exporters of grain amd could be increased by voluntary countributions from rich importers, such as <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Amstutz </PERSON>, chief <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> negotiator for world farm issues, came out strongly against any plan to set prices and limit production. He said one reason it would not work is that all producers could not be included and those who did not join would increase their production. The <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration has been pushing a plan to phase out by the end of the century all subsidies affecting world trade in farm products.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880412-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-12-88 0042EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Nicaragua-Talks 1stLd-Writethru a0736 04-12 0599</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Nicaragua-Talks, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0736,0614</SECOND>
<HEAD>Sandinistas Propose Renewed Technical Talks With Contras</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Subs 4th graf pvs bgng: Marta Sacasa... with 3 grafs rebels
responding to government proposal for techical meeting to resume
Wednesday. Pick up 5th graf pvs: A preliminary peace...</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By BRYNA BRENNAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MANAGUA, Nicaragua (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The government on Monday proposed a resumption of talks with rebels on details of a cease-fire plan after negotiations ended last week in disagreement over arms shipments. The Sandinista government suggested the technical discussions be resumed Wednesday or Thursday in <LOCATION> Managua </LOCATION>, the capital. It also proposed that the rebels, known as Contras, send an advance team to <LOCATION> Managua </LOCATION> on Tuesday to prepare for discussions Sandinista and rebel political leaders are scheduled to hold on Friday. In <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Contra </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Bosco </PERSON> <PERSON> Matamoros </PERSON> who is a member of the special negotiating commission released a statement late Monday saying the technical talks should resume at noon on Wednesday in the border village of <LOCATION> Sapoa </LOCATION>. The statement said the <ORGANIZATION> Contra </ORGANIZATION>'s ranking political leaders would travel to <LOCATION> Managua </LOCATION> on Friday for negotiations, based on progress at the <LOCATION> Sapoa </LOCATION> talks. There was no immediate response from the government. <PERSON> Matamoros </PERSON>' statement said the Contras would send an advance delegation to <LOCATION> Managua </LOCATION> Thursday to prepare for the political talks. It said the Contra representatives would include <PERSON> Roberto </PERSON> <PERSON> Ferrey </PERSON>, secretary of the directorate of the Contras' umbrella Nicaraguan Resistance group, and <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Stadhagen </PERSON>. A preliminary peace plan signed March 23 in <LOCATION> Sapoa </LOCATION> called for the two sides to hold technical discussions to work out details of a 60-day cease-fire that went into effect April 1. The talks between military commanders are to spell out how the Contras are to gather in cease-fire zones. During the truce, the two sides are to hold negotiations leading to a permanent agreement to end more than six years of war between the U.S.-backed Contras and the government. Military leaders have held six days of technical talks since March 28 at <LOCATION> Sapoa </LOCATION>, 90 miles south of <LOCATION> Managua </LOCATION> and beside the Costa Rican border. They have agreed only on seven zones in which the Contras are to gather but have failed to decide on security measures and how the rebels are to receive supplies in the zones. The meetings ended Friday after the Contras asked for a recess of several days to discuss a 25-point plan the government proposed. The Contras earlier offered a 34-point plan. Last week the <ORGANIZATION> Sandinistas </ORGANIZATION> suggested the technical talks be resumed Friday, when the political leaders are to hold their discussions. <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Reichler </PERSON>, an American lawyer negotiating for the <ORGANIZATION> Sandinistas </ORGANIZATION>, said over the weekend that there were only two points of contention in the proposal presented by the Contras. The Contra proposals would allow the rebels to receive arms, ammunition and war materiel while in the zones. It also would ban the <ORGANIZATION> Sandinistas </ORGANIZATION> from receiving any military aid, which is supplied by the Soviet bloc. <PERSON> Reichler </PERSON> described those two points as `` absolutely unacceptable.'' The original cease-fire plan would permit the Contras to receive only food and basic supplies channeled through a neutral organization, such as the <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION>. Political leaders of both sides had been scheduled to meet last Wednesday in <LOCATION> Managua </LOCATION>. The rebels postponed them, saying the technical talks had not advanced enough to move toward political issues. The rebels also have said they will not participate in this week's high-level political talks unless they are free to meet with opposition leaders. The government maintains that the peace agreement specifies Contra representation in politics begins only after the rebels move into the cease-fire zones.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880412-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-12-88 0043EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--RareOx     04-12 0185</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Rare Ox,0188</SECOND>
<HEAD>Scientists Reportedly Sight Rare Ox In Vietnam</HEAD>
<DATELINE>GLAND, Switzerland (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Vietnamese biologists reportedly have sighted a rare Indochinese gray ox for the first time in nearly 20 years, raising hopes the endangered species can be saved from extinction. A newspaper published Monday by the <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wildlife </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fund </ORGANIZATION> said the animal, called a kouprey, was seen last year by a Vietnamese team in a densely forested area near the Laotian border. The sighting was revealed in January at an international conservation meeting in <LOCATION> Hanoi </LOCATION>, the fund said. It was important because scientists had begun to fear the animal might be extinct, at least in <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>, said <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> Kemf </PERSON>, who edits the newspaper. Experts are especially interested in the kouprey because it may be immune to rinderpest, an often fatal infectious disease that afflicts cattle, sheep and goats, Ms. <PERSON> Kemf </PERSON> told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>. Scientists want to study the possibility of cross-breeding kouprey with cattle to render them immune to the intestinal disease, she said. The kouprey is a migratory animal found chiefly in <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Laos </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION>, and also in <LOCATION> Thailand </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880412-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-12-88 0050EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-ArmsMeetings     04-12 0361</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Arms Meetings,380</SECOND>
<HEAD>Soviet Team Arrives To Discuss Logistics Of INF Inspections</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Top prospects uncertain; arrival expected in mid-to-late
afternoon.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By NORMAN BLACK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Military Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A team of Soviet officials is readying for a second round of talks aimed at sorting through arrangements for verifying the arms treaty eliminating intermediate-range nuclear weapons. The Soviet team of 10 to 14 military and civilian officials was due in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> today and planned to meet behind closed doors with an American group starting on Wednesday, the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> said Monday. According to one <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> official who asked not to be named, the talks will extend at least to Saturday and will focus on a variety of `` housekeeping details'' that must be settled before the two sides begin compliance inspections. `` Some of the topics on the plate include living quarters for inspectors, call signs for aircraft traveling in each country, the logistics of moving and putting in place the equipment we'll need and what equipment we're planning to use, and even how we deal with the news media,'' said the source. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> want to reach agreement on such details in advance of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> vote on ratifying the new treaty to ensure a smooth start for the compliance inspections, the official added. Signed by President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and Soviet leader <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> on Dec. 8, the new treaty specifies that all nuclear missiles in the two superpower arsenals with a range of roughly 300 miles to 3,500 miles be destroyed within three years. Within the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government, the Pentagon has created an organization known as the <ORGANIZATION> On-Site </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inspection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> to verify <LOCATION> Russian </LOCATION> compliance with the new treaty. The head of that agency, <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Brig </ORGANIZATION>. Gen. <PERSON> Roland </PERSON> <PERSON> Lajoie </PERSON>, will lead the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> team in this week's discussions. The two sides held their first round of talks in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> last month. The <ORGANIZATION> OSIA </ORGANIZATION> will be responsible for escorting Soviet inspectors who travel to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Western </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> to monitor the removal and destruction of <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> nuclear weapons, as well as performing the same role inside the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> by visiting Russian facilities and deployment sites.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880412-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-12-88 0052EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-MostDistantGalaxy Bjt   04-12 0637</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Most Distant Galaxy, Bjt,0657</SECOND>
<HEAD>Discovery Of Most Distant Galaxy Could Change Theories Of Universe</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PAUL RAEBURN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Science Editor</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Astronomers may have to change their ideas about the early universe because of the discovery of the oldest and most distant galaxy ever observed, researchers said. The galaxy, about 10 times the size of the Milky Way, was formed before the universe was a mere 2 billion years old, said its discoverer, <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> <PERSON> Lilly </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hawaii </ORGANIZATION> at <LOCATION> Manoa </LOCATION>. Researchers have previously found indirect evidence of galaxies forming at extreme distances, but this is the first clear observation of a mature galaxy at those distances, <PERSON> Lilly </PERSON> said Monday in a telephone interview. `` This pushes back the time at which galaxies formed in the early universe,'' he said. The discovery could force a revision in astronomers' conception of the universe, <PERSON> Lilly </PERSON> said. `` If we find more objects like this, the cold-dark-matter scenario will be in trouble,'' he said. That scenario says that most of the universe exists in the form of cold, dark material that we can not observe. It also predicts that massive galaxies like the one discovered should not exist so early in the history of the universe, <PERSON> Lilly </PERSON> said. In January, <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Elston </PERSON> and <PERSON> George </PERSON> and <PERSON> Marcia </PERSON> <PERSON> Rieke </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Arizona </ORGANIZATION> reported the possible existence of even older, more distant galaxies, but those results are not yet confirmed, <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Rieke </PERSON> said Monday. `` I would say he has claim to the most distant galaxy,'' <PERSON> Rieke </PERSON> said. `` We have claim to having found candidates that may be even more distant, but that's different from having it nailed down.'' Nevertheless, <PERSON> Rieke </PERSON> said, the two lines of research mesh nicely, because `` the existence of his galaxy implies that something like the galaxies that we have candidates for must exist.'' <PERSON> Harding </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, a physicist at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Diego </LOCATION>, who has studied distant galaxies, said <PERSON> Lilly </PERSON> `` has made a substantial jump, and I do think it's an important result.'' It will help astronomers understand the processes that form galaxies, <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> said. `` We do n't understand when they form and how they form, and both of these are very interesting questions because they may tell us more about what happened even earliier in the universe,'' <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> said. A report of <PERSON> Lilly </PERSON>'s work has been accepted for publication in the <ORGANIZATION> Astrophysical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Journal </ORGANIZATION>, he said. To determine an object's distance and age, astronomers observe the so-called redshift of light emitted by the object. The higher the redshift, the older and more distant the object. <PERSON> Lilly </PERSON>'s galaxy has a redshift of 3.4, he said. The oldest and most distant galaxy observed before his had a redshift of 1.8, he said. The <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION> researchers are searching for evidence of new galaxies at redshifts of 6 to 25, <PERSON> Rieke </PERSON> said. The age of the universe can not be precisely determined, <PERSON> Lilly </PERSON> said, but the best estimates put it at between 10 billion and 20 billion years. If a figure of 15 billion years is arbitrarily chosen as a starting point, then the redshift of <PERSON> Lilly </PERSON>'s galaxy means the light that <PERSON> Lilly </PERSON> observed left the galaxy when the universe was about 3 billion years old. Observations of the galaxy itself indicate it was then 1 billion or 2 billion years old, he said, meaning it was formed when the universe was 1 billion to 2 billion years old. <PERSON> Lilly </PERSON> said his research involved identifying the source of a distant emission of radio waves that was recorded in 1981. He used the Canada-France-Hawaii optical telescope and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kingdom </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Infrared </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Telescope </LOCATION> _ both located atop <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Mauna </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kea </LOCATION> volcano _ to pick up light and infrared radiation from the precise point where the radio emission had been detected Those observations allowed him to identify it as a mature galaxy.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880412-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-12-88 0106EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--Sweden-Afghanistan     04-12 0113</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Sweden-Afghanistan,0115</SECOND>
<HEAD>Sweden &amp; Finland Asked To Monitor Troop Withdrawal From
Afghanistan</HEAD>
<DATELINE>STOCKHOLM, Sweden (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> has asked <LOCATION> Sweden </LOCATION> to monitor the withdrawal of Soviet troops from <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>, a government spokeswoman said. <LOCATION> Finland </LOCATION> already has agreed to a similar request, <LOCATION> Sweden </LOCATION>'s national television reported Spokeswoman <PERSON> Annika </PERSON> <PERSON> Wiren </PERSON> on Monday said the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> request was informal and that the Swedish government had not yet made a decision. However, she said <LOCATION> Sweden </LOCATION>'s `` stand in principal is positive'' in such matters. The <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> recently announced an agreement to end the war between Moslem guerrillas and <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>'s Soviet-backed government and clear the way for the removal of an estimated 115,000 Soviet troops.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880412-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-12-88 0118EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Jackson-ForeignPress     04-12 0506</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Jackson-Foreign Press,510</SECOND>
<HEAD>Jackson Campaign Attracts Hordes Of Foreign Reporters</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RITA BEAMISH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Riding the <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> press bus at times can be like attending a meeting of the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> has attracted intense interest by the international news media _ in part, because of what one Frenchman called his `` star'' quality. News agencies from all over the world have sent writers and TV crews to cover his bid for the Democratic presidential nomination. `` The campaigns of the other candidates are so boring that <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> is the only one to emerge,'' said <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> Match correspondent <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> <PERSON> Royant </PERSON>. The foreign coverage is increasing in anticipation of the crucial <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> primary on April 19, his aides say. Traveling with <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s entourage last weekend were reporters from <LOCATION> Ecuador </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Great </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>. Off and on, the campaign also has seen representatives from news agencies of other nations including <LOCATION> Denmark </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Holland </LOCATION>. At one point campaign aides even considered having a news conference just for the foreign press _ because all wanted interviews with the candidate and their questions were of a different nature than those asked by <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> reporters, said press secretary <PERSON> DelMarie </PERSON> <PERSON> Cobb </PERSON>. The interest seems to center on <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> as a person and international celebrity, his eloquence and flair, and on the historical significance of his candidacy. Foreign reporters said they were looking for those kinds of stories more than at <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s stance on issues. <PERSON> Cobb </PERSON> said the foreign press also asks a lot of questions about whether the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> is ready to elect a black president. On the other hand, <PERSON> Raghida </PERSON> <PERSON> Dergham </PERSON> of the London-based Lebanese magazine <ORGANIZATION> Al-Hawadress </ORGANIZATION> said editors in the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> are very interested in the foreign policies of <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, who enjoys considerable support in the Arab-American community. <ORGANIZATION> British </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Broadcasting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> correspondent <PERSON> Kent </PERSON> <PERSON> Barker </PERSON> said <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> was `` certainly the most interesting to foreign eyes. He's the most colorful, dramatic'' presidential candidate this year The <ORGANIZATION> BBC </ORGANIZATION>'s audience is also interested in <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s liberalism and sees him as aligned with the philosophies of the <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Great </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>, he said. In <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>, people are more aware of <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> than the other candidates, even though <ORGANIZATION> RAI </ORGANIZATION> television has done a profile on <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, said RAI cameraman <PERSON> Michele </PERSON> <PERSON> Capasso </PERSON>. He cited `` the style and excitement around him'' as reasons <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> makes a good story. `` In <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>, every <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> election, people want to know two things,'' said <PERSON> Royant </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> Match. `` Are we going to find a Kennedy this year? ... Who is the star? This year <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> is the star.'' <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> Match did a profile of <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> in October, and <PERSON> Royant </PERSON> is working on a second profile that will appear some time before the summer nominating conventions. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> has visited <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> in the past and is well-known there, said <PERSON> Royant </PERSON>. Additionally, there is interest in the candidacy of a black man 20 years after the death of civil rights leader <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Luther </PERSON> <PERSON> King </PERSON>, <PERSON> Royant </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880412-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-12-88 0130EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Candidates-Layoffs     04-12 0640</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Candidates-Layoffs,610</SECOND>
<HEAD>Stumping In Union Stronghold Of New York, Democrats Back Layoff
Notices</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MATT YANCEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Labor Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Democratic presidential contenders are telling <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to disregard President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s threat to veto a trade bill if it calls for mandatory advance layoff notices. <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> Sen. <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> sent letters over the weekend urging Sen. <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Texas </LOCATION>, a key architect of the sweeping trade bill, to resist further weakening of the labor-sought notice provision. <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> earlier had sent a similar letter to <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>, urging him to retain the notice provision `` regardless of the president's intentions.'' The letters arrived on Capitol Hill as <PERSON> Gore </PERSON>, <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> and <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> are engaged in an intense competition for the 255 convention delegates at stake in the April 19 primary in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, a state where one in every three workers carries a union card. `` I can only conclude that the real reason many companies oppose a notice requirement _ and the reason those same companies do not give advance notice now _ is that they do not care what happens to workers or their communities,'' <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> said in his letter. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> said his campaign speeches on the need for advance layoff notices have received enthusiastic responses and that `` it is difficult to believe that <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> would not override such an ill-advised veto.'' `` The inclusion of the provision in the trade bill has been helpful in making working people aware that the <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> is responding to some of their very fundamental concerns,'' he said in his letter to <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>. The <ORGANIZATION> AFL-CIO </ORGANIZATION>, which has made the trade bill its top legislative priority for six years, has threatened to withdraw its support for it entirely if the layoff notices are eliminated. `` I could understand our so-called trading partners being opposed to the bill,'' <ORGANIZATION> AFL-CIO </ORGANIZATION> Secretary-Treasurer <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Donahue </PERSON> said Monday. `` But he's -LRB- <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> -RRB- supposed to be the president of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>.'' Under the provision, companies with more than 100 employees would be required to give 60 days advance notice when they intend to close a plant or lay off one-third or more of its workforce. However, the layoffs would have to total at least 50 workers to trigger the mandatory notices. <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> and other <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> `` superconferees'' are scheduled to start meeting today in hopes of getting a final version of the trade bill by Thursday or Friday for separate votes in each house on final passage. Without citing specific provisions, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said in his weekend radio address Saturday he still has `` very _ underline very _ serious reservations'' about the bill. `` The bottom line is this: I will veto a bad trade bill before I let a bad trade bill veto our economy.'' While administration officials have outlined objections to several provisions, congressional leaders describe most of the protests as `` padding'' for its vehement opposition to the mandatory layoff notices. `` It's a classic game of everybody trying to figure out what the other guy's bottom line is,'' said one legislative aide, who acknowledged one purpose of the candidates' letters is to counter administration veto threats. Just a week ago, <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Ann </PERSON> <PERSON> McLaughlin </PERSON> wrote <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Democratic Leader <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON> she would be `` forced to recommend that the president veto the bill ... if these protectionist mandatory plant closing and layoff requirements remain.'' A <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> task force last year called advance notices `` an essential component of a readjustment program'' for helping laid off workers get new jobs, but stopped short of saying the notices should be mandated. According to the <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Statistics </ORGANIZATION>, two of every three workers laid off in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> receive no advance notice. The average notice, according to a separate survey by the <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Accounting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION>, is 14 days for white-collar workers and seven days for blue-collar workers.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880412-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-12-88 0137EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lites     04-12 0483</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lites,0502</SECOND>
<HEAD>On The Lite Side</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEVADA CITY, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 This Sierra <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION> foothill community had a bear of a weekend, and loved it. Some 10,000 teddy bears were on hand to be cuddled, admired and enjoyed by 6,000 humans, who also indulged in music, food, clown performances, shopping and story telling. Besides the bears of all shapes and sizes at the <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>'s Fifth Annual International Teddy Bear Convention, there were grown men in furry bear suits and teenagers wearing fuzzy ears There were toddlers and grandmothers alike clutching favorite teddy bears. And if some looked askance at the goings-on at the American <ORGANIZATION> Victorian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Museum </ORGANIZATION> and the nearby teddy-bear castle, 3 -LCB- - year-old <PERSON> Sydney </PERSON> <PERSON> Gerson </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> was n't among them After getting a couple of big hugs from a shaggy brown cinnamon bear, <LOCATION> Sydney </LOCATION> beamed and said, `` I love teddy bears a lot because they are so soft and snuggly.'' The `` teddy'' bear title, according to the story repeated at the convention, was given a small stuffed bear by a <LOCATION> Brooklyn </LOCATION> candy store owner who read of the refusal of President <PERSON> Theodore </PERSON> `` Teddy'' Roosevelt to shoot a small bear cub while on a hunting trip in 1902. The vendor, who later founded the <ORGANIZATION> Ideal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Toy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, sent his creation to the president, who kept it for his children.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>SALIDA, Colo. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON> <PERSON> Harrington </PERSON>'s rhinoceros may be an unlikely cross between a bull and a <ORGANIZATION> Buick </ORGANIZATION>, but he says he'll miss the life-size, metallic sculpture when it moves to a <LOCATION> Ripley </LOCATION>'s Believe It Or Not museum `` The mountains are no place for an 8-year-old rhinoceros,'' <PERSON> Harrington </PERSON> said. `` It's time he moved to a lower elevation and a warmer climate.'' The rhino was made about eight years ago from old steel automobile bumpers by `` bumper sculpture'' artist <PERSON> Jon </PERSON> <PERSON> Bedford </PERSON>, a former <LOCATION> Salida </LOCATION> resident. <PERSON> Harrington </PERSON> bought it for display in front of his hardware business on <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> 50. When the business closed a year ago, the rhino moved to the front lawn of <PERSON> Harrington </PERSON>'s home. `` We felt it did n't belong in a private yard,'' <PERSON> Harrington </PERSON> said. `` It should be in a public place, where people can see and appreciate it.'' So <PERSON> Harrington </PERSON> put the rhino up for sale, advertising it at a gallery in <LOCATION> Taos </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.M. </LOCATION>, where <ORGANIZATION> Bedford </ORGANIZATION> now works. Last week, word came that the rhino was sold to <PERSON> Ripley </PERSON>'s Believe It Or Not Museum in <LOCATION> Laguna </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif </LOCATION>. Still, <PERSON> Harrington </PERSON> says, he'll miss the old beast. `` The rhino brought a lot of interesting comments and situations when we were at the store,'' he said. `` There was the old rancher from <LOCATION> Saguache </LOCATION>, for example. He showed up one morning, just as I was opening the store, and he stood outside for a long time, studying that rhinoceros. `` ` When he finally came in he said, ` I know where that came from. ... It's a cross between a Brahma bull and a Buick.'''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880412-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-12-88 0019EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-CommunistPresident 1stLd-Writethru a0666 04-12 0320</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Communist President, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0666,0323</SECOND>
<HEAD>Student Judiciary Board To Settle Communist Election Dispute</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: LEADS with 8 grafs to UPDATE with evening hearing. Picks up
8th graf pvs ``He's more.''</NOTE>
<DATELINE>AMHERST, Mass. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Massachusetts </ORGANIZATION> student judiciary board agreed Monday to settle a dispute over a communist's election as co-president of the student body. The three-member student <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> heard a motion Monday night that would declare the election invalid. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Sanchez </PERSON>, the panel's chief judge, said a ruling on the motion would be issued Wednesday prior to a scheduled meeting of the undergraduate Student Senate. <PERSON> Jason </PERSON> <PERSON> Rabinowitz </PERSON>, a member of the <ORGANIZATION> Young </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> League </ORGANIZATION>, and his co-candidate, non-communist <PERSON> Shari </PERSON> <PERSON> Silkoff </PERSON>, were elected March 15. <PERSON> Rabinowitz </PERSON> is believed to be the first YCL member elected campus president since the group was formed five years ago. Student Attorney General <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Collins </PERSON> filed the motion asking the judiciary board to declare the Rabinowitz-Silkoff ticket invalid because the student government constitution allows only one person to hold the office of president. `` I think I'm winning,'' <PERSON> Collins </PERSON> said after the session, `` but the point is I ca n't just win. I have to win convincingly.'' Monday night's hearing was mostly spent on arguments by a student lawyer representing <PERSON> Rabinowitz </PERSON> and <PERSON> Silkoff </PERSON>, who attempted to show that the writers of the student constitution did not mean to prevent more than one person from serving. Conservatives on the 90-member undergraduate student <ORGANIZATION> senate </ORGANIZATION> filibustered last week to keep the election from being ratified and stop <PERSON> Rabinowitz </PERSON> and <PERSON> Silkoff </PERSON> from taking office. <PERSON> Collins </PERSON> said his motion had nothing to do with the candidates' political beliefs, but <PERSON> Rabinowitz </PERSON> contended otherwise `` He's more interested in petty factional politics than the well-being of the whole student government,'' said <PERSON> Rabinowitz </PERSON>, a 20-year-old junior from <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Rabinowitz </PERSON> and <PERSON> Silkoff </PERSON>, also 20, won 1,454 votes, 391 more than conservative candidate <PERSON> Aram </PERSON> <PERSON> Hamparian </PERSON>, at the 19,000-student campus.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880412-0025 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-12-88 0020EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-Oscars-Douglas     04-12 0255</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Oscars-Douglas,0262</SECOND>
<HEAD>Michael Douglas Awarded First Acting Award, Second Oscar for
``Wall Street''</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON>, the ruthless inside trader of `` Wall Street,'' won his second Oscar and first acting award Monday night at the 60th Annual Academy Awards ceremony. <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON> previously won an Oscar for being one of the producers of `` One Flew Over the Cuckoo's Nest,'' best picture of 1975. When accepting the award, <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON> credited `` Wall Street'' director <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> <PERSON> Stone </PERSON> `` for having the courage to cast me in a part that not many people thought I could play.'' <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON> described the character of Wall Street king <PERSON> Gordon </PERSON> <PERSON> Gekko </PERSON> as `` the best part that I've ever had in my career.'' The actor also thanked his wife and his parents, especially his father, actor <PERSON> Kirk </PERSON> <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON>, `` for helping a son step out of the shadow.'' <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON> also had been considered by the Academy for his performance in the psycho-thriller `` Fatal Attraction,'' which was nominated for best picture, but the actors branch of the <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION> decided to nominate him for `` Wall Street.'' <PERSON> Marlee </PERSON> <PERSON> Matlin </PERSON>, who won the best actress Oscar last year for `` Children of a Lesser God,'' presented the award, using sign language, but speaking aloud the names of nominees <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON>, <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Hurt </PERSON>, <PERSON> Marcello </PERSON> <PERSON> Mastroianni </PERSON>, <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Nicholson </PERSON>, and <PERSON> Robin </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>. <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON>' film debut was with `` Hail, Hero.'' He spent four years with the <ORGANIZATION> ABC-TV </ORGANIZATION> series `` The Streets of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION>,'' and became established as a movie star with the smash-hit adventure films `` Romancing the Stone'' and `` Jewel of the Nile.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880412-0026 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-12-88 0146EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Shearson-Takeover     04-12 0462</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Shearson-Takeover,460</SECOND>
<HEAD>Shearson Defends Role In Koppers Takeover Attempt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JEFF BARKER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The investment banking firm <ORGANIZATION> Shearson </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lehman </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hutton </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> came under attack during a congressional hearing for what one senator said was its role as a corporate raider in a hostile takeover. `` In effect, what we have is a bank acting as a corporate raider,'' Sen. <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Sasser </PERSON>, D-Tenn., said Monday at a hearing of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Banking </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> The committee met for three hours on the attempted takeover of Pittsburgh-based <ORGANIZATION> Koppers </ORGANIZATION> by <ORGANIZATION> Beazer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> PLC </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>, which is being advised by <ORGANIZATION> Shearson </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lehman </ORGANIZATION>. `` Shearson is only the first to cross a line that Wall Street believes will be obliterated by others racing across it in the future,'' said Sen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Heinz </PERSON>, R-Pa., referring to the distinction between banking and commerce <PERSON> Steven </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Wolitzer </PERSON>, managing director of <ORGANIZATION> Shearson </ORGANIZATION>, said the firm's role was limited to providing short-term, or `` bridge,'' financing for <ORGANIZATION> Beazer </ORGANIZATION>'s tender offer and giving advice. Such financing is `` typical for investment banks in deals of this kind,'' he said. <PERSON> Wolitzer </PERSON> acknowledged that <ORGANIZATION> Shearson </ORGANIZATION> is contributing equity of its own _ $ 23 million _ to the bidding group, but he said management and control of the group would be held by <ORGANIZATION> Beazer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> PLC </ORGANIZATION>. But <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Pullin </PERSON>, chairman and chief executive officer of <ORGANIZATION> Koppers </ORGANIZATION>, said <ORGANIZATION> Shearson </ORGANIZATION> `` has dominated and actively guided every aspect of the planning and execution of the <ORGANIZATION> Koppers </ORGANIZATION> takeover attempt since its secret initiation one year ago.'' <PERSON> Brian </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Beazer </PERSON>, chairman and chief executive officer of the British company, defended the takeover attempt, saying his company's goal is `` not to make a quick buck by laying off employees, and selling the company's operations piecemeal.'' `` I am not a corporate raider,'' <ORGANIZATION> Beazer </ORGANIZATION> said. He said <ORGANIZATION> Koppers </ORGANIZATION>' management has mounted `` a massive campaign of disinformation'' about his bid <ORGANIZATION> Beazer </ORGANIZATION> led a group that made an unsolicited cash tender offer of $ 45 a share for <ORGANIZATION> Koppers </ORGANIZATION> on March 3, a deal that has since been sweetened to $ 60 per share, or $ 1.7 billion. <ORGANIZATION> Koppers </ORGANIZATION> produces construction materials and chemicals. `` From an <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Express </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> viewpoint, not only do we think this to be a <ORGANIZATION> Shearson </ORGANIZATION> transaction and activity in the normal course of its business, but we also view the uproar by some allies of <ORGANIZATION> Koppers </ORGANIZATION> as ill-informed, provocative and ill-advised,'' said <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Freeman </PERSON>, executive vice president of <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Express </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Shearson </ORGANIZATION>'s parent. He said it was ill-informed because of the `` continued erroneous assertion that somehow <ORGANIZATION> Shearson </ORGANIZATION>, rather than <ORGANIZATION> Beazer </ORGANIZATION>, is trying to acquire <ORGANIZATION> Koppers </ORGANIZATION>, which is simply not true and strikes the management of <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Express </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> as a bizarre allegation.'' <ORGANIZATION> Beazer </ORGANIZATION>'s offer has been extended until April 15 while courts consider legal challenges by <ORGANIZATION> Koppers </ORGANIZATION> that have slowed the takeover bid.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880412-0027 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-12-88 0149EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     04-12 0987</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,1022</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in The News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Will </PERSON> <PERSON> Cornelia </PERSON> `` Super Deb'' Guest and <PERSON> Sylvester </PERSON> `` Rambo'' <PERSON> Stallone </PERSON> unite in matrimony, creating a gossip columnist's dream couple? Corny says no; her mom and Sly's mom say they would n't mind. `` We are not getting married. I'm only 24 years old. And I do not have a crystal ball,'' said Miss Guest, the goddaughter of <PERSON> Winston </PERSON> <PERSON> Churchill </PERSON> who is trying to parlay her social glitter into an acting career. The romance between Miss Guest and <PERSON> Stallone </PERSON> has been fodder for gossip columnists for months. Miss Guest's mother, socialite C.Z. Guest, says she thinks a marriage would be `` wonderful. He's terrific, a big achiever, and he works very hard _ well, he's obviously quite a guy In Vanity Fair's May issue, <PERSON> Stallone </PERSON>'s mother, <PERSON> Jackie </PERSON>, said she would n't object to a marriage either, after witnessing her son's two broken marriages `` I've seen worse, with my daughter-in-laws.''
</TEXT>
<NOTE>Eds: A version of the following item moved on sports wires.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>TRENTON, N.J. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Abel </PERSON> <PERSON> Kiviat </PERSON>, the world's oldest Olympic champion, has outlasted the gold and silver medals he won in the 1912 <LOCATION> Stockholm </LOCATION> games. In fact, he says, he has n't seen them since they were lost nearly 60 years ago. So on Thursday, King <PERSON> Carl </PERSON> <PERSON> XVI </PERSON> <PERSON> Gustaf </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Sweden </LOCATION>, the grandson of the man who originally awarded <PERSON> Kiviat </PERSON> his medals, will present the 95-year-old former runner with specially crafted duplicates during a visit to <LOCATION> Trenton </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON> <PERSON> Kasper </PERSON>, a member of the Governor's <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> on </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Physical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fitness </ORGANIZATION>, came up with the idea of replacing the original medals after taking <PERSON> Kiviat </PERSON> home from an Olympic fund-raising event in February. `` I knew the king and queen were coming here and I thought, ` Would n't it be great if we could get replacement medals to give to <PERSON> Abel </PERSON>?''' <PERSON> Kasper </PERSON> asked. In the 1912 Olympics, when he was a roommate of Decathlon champion <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Thorpe </PERSON>, <PERSON> Kiviat </PERSON> won the silver medal in the 1,500-meter run and the gold medal in the 3,000-meter cross-country event.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
