<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880315-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-15-88 2336EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p AM-WashingtonCaucuses     03-15 0192</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Washington Caucuses,160</SECOND>
<HEAD>Dukakis Keeps Strong Lead over Jackson in Washington Democratic
Caucuses</HEAD>
<DATELINE>OLYMPIA, Wash. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> held a strong lead over <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> as <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> state party officials released results Tuesday from last week's Democratic presidential precinct caucuses. With about 68 percent of the precincts reporting the results of last Tuesday's balloting, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> had 45 percent, <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> 35 percent, and 14 percent were uncommitted. All the other candidates were well off the pace, with <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> Sen. <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> a weak fourth at 4 percent, <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> Sen. <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> Jr. 2 percent and Rep. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION> 1 percent. The Democratic Party made no effort to collect results statewide on caucus night, gathering precinct returns slowly by mail instead. Republicans say it will be at least another week before county chairmen submit the names of <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> delegates elected in last week's precinct caucuses The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Election </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> reported last week that, with 71 percent of the Republican precincts reporting, former television evangelist <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> led with 39 percent. Sen. <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> finished second with 26 percent and Vice President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> got 24 percent.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880315-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-15-88 0502EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--CarKids     03-15 0175</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Car Kids,0182</SECOND>
<HEAD>Father Pleads Guilty In Children's Deaths</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LEWISTOWN, Pa. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A 24-year-old man has pleaded guilty to involuntary manslaughter in the death of his two children, who died last summer hours after he locked them inside his car. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Shields </PERSON> of <LOCATION> White </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Township </LOCATION> entered the plea Monday, and faces a maximum 10-year prison term and $ 20,000 fine. Judge <PERSON> Francis </PERSON> <PERSON> Searer </PERSON> deferred sentencing pending an investigation by probation officials. <PERSON> Shields </PERSON> testified at his wife's trial two weeks ago that he agreed to watch their children, <PERSON> Kristle </PERSON>, 3, and <PERSON> Calvin </PERSON>, 1, on the morning of Aug. 22, but instead locked them in the car and closed the windows. The children were discovered in the afternoon, when the temperature reached the mid-80s, authorities said. <PERSON> Lisa </PERSON> <PERSON> Shields </PERSON> pleaded guilty to reduced charges and also is awaiting sentencing. Both parents were charged with two counts of involuntary manslaughter and endangering the welfare of children. The more severe counts against Mrs. <PERSON> Shields </PERSON> were dropped. The two endangerment counts were incorporated in Shields' guilty plea, court officials said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880315-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-15-88 0000EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-BoxOffice     03-15 0520</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Box Office,0540</SECOND>
<HEAD>`Good Morning, Vietnam' Ties Box Office Record</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JEFF WILSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>HOLLYWOOD (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 `` Good Morning, <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>'' was moviegoers' favorite for the the ninth-straight weekend, tying it with `` Crocodile Dundee'' for the longest consecutive time at the top Second in last weekend's box office survey was `` Vice Versa,'' featuring a Judge <PERSON> Reinhold </PERSON> transformation into a prepubescent kid, followed by `` Masquerade'' in third and `` Off Limits'' fourth. All 10 top grossing films combined took in about $ 30 million, with `` Good Morning, <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>'' ringing up a mere $ 4.36 million during the pre-Easter vacation box office doldrums. `` It's another down week,'' said <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Krier </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> Exhibitor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Relations </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, which surveys the studios' weekly performance at the box office. `` It looks like we're marking time until Easter.'' For the Easter break, the studios are releasing the animated feature `` The Fox and the Hounds,'' <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Alda </PERSON>'s `` A New Life,'' <PERSON> Matthew </PERSON> <PERSON> Broderick </PERSON>'s `` Biloxi Blues'' and <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON> <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Hall </PERSON>'s `` Johnny B <PERSON> Goode </PERSON>.'' In addition to `` Good Morning, <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>,'' the <ORGANIZATION> Disney </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Studios </ORGANIZATION> had two other pictures in the top 10. `` Three Men and a Baby'' was seventh 7 after 15 weeks in release and `` Shoot to Kill'' ninth. The lure of romance between <PERSON> Rob </PERSON> <PERSON> Lowe </PERSON> and <PERSON> Meg </PERSON> <PERSON> Tilly </PERSON> gave `` Masquerade'' a debut weekend gross of $ 3.5 million while the <PERSON> Willem </PERSON> <PERSON> Dafoe-Gregory </PERSON> <PERSON> Hines </PERSON> cop thriller `` Off Limits'' earned $ 2.8 million. In fifth was <PERSON> Cher </PERSON>'s critically-acclaimed `` Moonstruck,'' which won her a <ORGANIZATION> Golden </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Globe </ORGANIZATION> trophy and an Oscar nomination, followed by <PERSON> Harrison </PERSON> <PERSON> Ford </PERSON>'s `` Frantic'' in sixth and `` Three Men and a Baby'' in seventh. `` Moving,'' starring <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Pryor </PERSON> as a <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> engineer forced to relocate his family to <LOCATION> Boise </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION>, earned more than $ 2.4 million to place eighth, followed by `` Shoot to Kill.'' In 10th place was `` Switching Channels,'' a broadcast version of the venerable newsroom comedy `` The Front Page.'' It earned $ 1.9 million in its second week. Here are the top films for the weekend as tallied by <ORGANIZATION> Exhibitor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Relations </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, with distributor, weekend gross, number of theater screens, average per screen, total gross, number of weeks in release and estimated production costs. 1. `` Good Morning, <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>,'' Disney-Touchstone, $ 4.36 million, 1,579 screens, $ 2,767 per screen, $ 91.5 million, 11 weeks, $ 21 million. 2. `` Vice Versa,'' <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION>, $ 4.05 million, 1,225 screens, $ 3,306 per screen, $ 4.05 million, one week, n-a. 3. `` Masquerade,'' <ORGANIZATION> MGM-UA </ORGANIZATION>, $ 3.5 million, 1,030 screens, $ 3,398 per screen, $ 3.5 million, one week, n-a. 4. `` Off Limits,'' 20th Century <PERSON> Fox </PERSON>, $ 2.79 million, 1,366 screens, $ 2,047 per screen, $ 2.79 million, one week, n-a. 5. `` Moonstruck,'' <ORGANIZATION> MGM-UA </ORGANIZATION>, $ 2.66 million, 1,155 screens, $ 2,309 per screen, $ 49.37 million, 12 weeks, $ 17 million. 6. `` Frantic,'' <ORGANIZATION> Warner </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bros. </ORGANIZATION>, $ 2.60 million, 1,054 screens, $ 2,469 per screen, $ 13.2 million, two weeks, $ 20 million. 7. `` Three Men And A Baby,'' Disney-Touchstone, $ 2.55 million, 1,348 screens, $ 1,893 per screen, $ 147.6 million, 15 weeks, $ 18 million. 8. `` Moving,'' <ORGANIZATION> Warner </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bros. </ORGANIZATION>, $ 2.4 million, 1,404 screens, $ 1,732 per screen, $ 7.49 million, two weeks, n-a. 9. `` Shoot to Kill,'' Disney-Touchstone, $ 2 million, 1,037 screens, $ 1,956 per screen, $ 24.2 million, four weeks, $ 18 million. 10. `` Switching Channels,'' Tri-Star, $ 1.94 million, 971 screens, $ 2,002 per screen, $ 5.8 million, two weeks, n-a.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880315-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-15-88 0001EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Networks-Primary     03-15 0190</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Networks-Primary,0197</SECOND>
<HEAD>Networks Plan Election Specials</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 CBS and <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> said they will broadcast half-hour news specials on <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> primary election returns tonight at 11:30 p.m. EST. <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> planned no full-length election special but will devote the first six minutes of its `` Nightline'' program at 11:30 p.m. to election returns, <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> said. <ORGANIZATION> Cable </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Network </ORGANIZATION> said it will provide periodic reports and a half-hour program on election returns at 1 a.m. Wednesday. <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> also were broadcasting brief special reports on voting results. <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> planned five-minute news briefs at 8:55 p.m. and 9:55 p.m. and its half-hour special at 11:30 p.m., with `` NBC Nightly News'' anchorman <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Brokaw </PERSON> as host, said spokeswoman <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Lou </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Callaghan </PERSON>. CBS planned one prime-time news brief, with the time yet to be set, and an 11:30 p.m. special program, with `` CBS Evening News'' anchorman <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Rather </PERSON> as host, said <PERSON> Donna </PERSON> <PERSON> Dees </PERSON>, spokeswoman for the network. <ORGANIZATION> CNN </ORGANIZATION> will air five - to seven-minute reports at every half hour from 8 p.m. to 10:30 p.m. and will devote its `` Inside Politics'' program at 1 a.m. to election returns, said spokeswoman <PERSON> Kitsie </PERSON> <PERSON> Bassett </PERSON>
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880315-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-15-88 0002EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Korea-Cartoons     03-15 0729</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Korea-Cartoons,0756</SECOND>
<HEAD>South Korean Cartoonists Inject A Little Political Humor</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</NOTE>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BARRY RENFREW</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SEOUL, South Korea (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 What <PERSON> Shim </PERSON> <PERSON> Min-sop </PERSON> is doing now conceivably could have landed him in jail not so long ago. He's drawing cartoons that poke gentle fun at <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korean </LOCATION> political leaders And people are getting a laugh out of them, without worrying that something could happen to them as well. <PERSON> Shim </PERSON>'s cartoons seem tame by most standards. Politicians and political parties are parodied as rival baseball teams and the jibes are never too strong. Nevertheless, <PERSON> Shim </PERSON> says, it is a remarkable change. `` In the past it was a taboo to caricature the big political names in this country,'' he said. Ridiculing the president or making jokes about him, for example, were seen as anti-state acts. <PERSON> Shim </PERSON> and other cartoonists have been able to take advantage of recent political liberalization in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> to start injecting a little laughter and ridicule into politics. The cartoonists contend that political caricature is healthy and Korean politics can benefit from it. `` Cartoons and caricatures will bring the political leaders closer to the people,'' <PERSON> Shim </PERSON> maintained. Political cartoons have proliferated in newspapers and magazines and command large, enthusiastic audiences eager for a regular flow of material ranging from traditional editorial cartoons to long stories. Literacy is very high in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> but people prize cartoons for their humor. Newspaper cartoons so far are low-key and ironic. Some recent ones showed caricatures of the main political parties chasing each other in an unending circle, to symbolize ineffectiveness. Another showed top leaders as squabbling babies. A favorite of cartoonists is to have bemused Koreans staring at politicians battling for power and asking what is happening to the country. `` It is refreshing to see the taboos broken about the myths surrounding the political bigwigs,'' said <PERSON> Han </PERSON> <PERSON> Kye-su </PERSON>, a political analyst who has followed the growth of political cartooning. Many cartoonists say they have always seen their work as a way of calling for reform and liberalization. `` Korean cartoonists have been struggling for political change for a long time,'' <PERSON> Shim </PERSON> said. Cartoons are a valuable teaching tool that can vividly explain the meaning of an issue as well as amuse readers, <PERSON> Shim </PERSON> added. `` The political cartoonist can present the issues in a more amusing, but understandable manner to the public.'' The newly installed President <PERSON> Roh </PERSON> <PERSON> Tae-woo </PERSON>, who pledged freedom of speech and expression after years of authoritarian rule, personally encouraged cartoonists to take up political subjects by saying he did not mind being caricatured. <PERSON> Shim </PERSON> and other cartoonists say their work is still very gentle and restrained for fear of angering authorities and losing what freedom they have. But they say they expect to make their humor more biting as time goes on and liberalization expands. Cartoonists are also restrained by fear of offending a politician's supporters, <PERSON> Shim </PERSON> said. <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>'s factional politics stress loyalty and supporters tend to resent any joke at their leader's expense, he said. `` The reaction can be terrible from the supporters,'' <PERSON> Shim </PERSON> said. `` People should learn to accept both positive and negative.'' Anti-government students and dissident groups, which have long used cartoons in their political literature, also are making greater use of caricatures, but usually not in a humorous way. The cartoons distributed at anti-government rallies and meetings are biting and bitter. Government and mainline opposition politicians are depicted as vicious tyrants suppressing the people with tear gas and clubs. Some are more subtle, depicting the divided opposition leaders as crying infants quarreling over a toy. `` They are not jokes,'' said one dissident. `` They show the people the reality of the government and why there is no democracy in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>.'' Anti-government cartoons are distributed in pamphlets on college campuses or posted on trees and sidewalks at anti-government rallies. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, represented by a fiendish-looking Uncle <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> or a swaggering and bullying <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> soldier, is a fixture in the underground cartoons. Dissidents claim the country's successive authoritarian governments have survived because of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> backing. One recent cartoon showed a tough-looking Statue of Liberty with a boxing glove on her upraised hand. <PERSON> Shim </PERSON> and other cartoonists reject their underground competition and the radical politics behind it. They say change must be moderate. `` It's too early to expose politicians to a more revealing fashion,'' <PERSON> Shim </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880315-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-15-88 0028EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Colombia-Elections     03-15 0777</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Colombia-Elections,0806</SECOND>
<HEAD>Rich Still Run Colombia, But Left Makes Tiny Inroads</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</NOTE>
<HEAD>An AP News Analysis</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TOM WELLS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BOGOTA, Colombia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Mayoral elections in <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION> have left a small crack in the political fortress of the upper class, the power behind this Latin American country since it won independence from <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION> in 1819. The elections on Sunday marked the first time that mayors had been elected in <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION>. Previously, they were appointed by governors, who were appointed by the president. And the president always came from the <ORGANIZATION> Liberal </ORGANIZATION> or the Conservative parties that are manipulated by the rich. But a leftist coalition, the <ORGANIZATION> Patriotic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> party </ORGANIZATION>, won at least 14 of l ,008 mayoral posts in Sunday's election, which in some cases brought people from the poorer classes closer to the seat of power in local politics The money and power of the traditional parties ruled out in most cases, such as in <LOCATION> Bogota </LOCATION> where <PERSON> Andres </PERSON> <PERSON> Pastrana </PERSON>, the son of former president <PERSON> Misael </PERSON> <PERSON> Pastrana </PERSON>, was elected mayor on the Conservative ticket. The <ORGANIZATION> Liberal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> President </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Virgilio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Barco </ORGANIZATION> won 430 of the mayoral races, and the Conservative party won 402 mayoral posts. Coalition candidates won 24 of the mayoral elections. Other results may not be known for a week because of the remoteness of many towns. The showing by the new Patriotic Union was small. But the results were surprising given that the party was organized just three years ago. The leftist coalition also had to survive a wave of assassinations by right-wing death squads that killed 520 of the members of the party, including its president, <PERSON> Jaime </PERSON> <PERSON> Pardo </PERSON>. The <ORGANIZATION> Patriotic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION> also had to confront a colonial attitude of patronage. Entire towns and areas traditionally adhere to one of the two traditional parties. Until recently, people did not join political parties. They were born into them. It is common knowledge that failure of a peasant to support the party controlling an area means virtual economic suicide. A loan application at the local bank for buying seed will be rejected. A worker will be turned away when looking for a job at a big hacienda. Colombians still call the rich <PERSON> La </PERSON> <PERSON> Rosca </PERSON>, a kind of intertwined pastry. The term refers to a loose intertwining of influential people _ politicians, businessmen, landowners, doctors and lawyers _ who control the lives of the poor. Nowhere are the poor more aware of <LOCATION> La </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rosca </LOCATION> than in small towns, where the wealthy own most of the rural land. A 1970 government study showed that 4.3 percent of the people in <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION> owned 68 percent of the land. Ten percent of the farms held 80 percent of total farmland. Those figures probably have not changed much. The government's concession to hold mayoral elections is an indication that <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION> may be heading toward true democracy. The country has a long history of violence, perpetuated largely by a political elite that refused to reform partisan traditions. For example, elements of the Liberal party resisted social changes in 1948. A charasmatic Liberal leader, <PERSON> Jorge </PERSON> <PERSON> Elicer </PERSON> <PERSON> Gaitan </PERSON>, broke away from the party and ran as an independent. <PERSON> Gaitan </PERSON> was assassinated shortly afterward. People saw their only hope of bettering their lives cut down, and the frustration exploded into the worst disturbances ever seen in <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION>. That period, known simply as The Violence, has had an impact upon Colombian politics ever since. So when former president <PERSON> Belisario </PERSON> <PERSON> Betancur </PERSON> offered peace talks to the country's leftist guerrillas in 1984, most people approved. Perhaps they recognized that the need for social changes were again putting pressure on the system. The guerrillas said in 1985 they wanted a government more responsive to the poor people. For starters, they said they wanted the election of mayors. <PERSON> Betancur </PERSON> agreed, and the congress approved a constitutional amendement to allow the first election in 1988. The peace talks collapsed last year, but the government went ahead with the elections. The army says there are about 5,000 leftist guerrillas in <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION>. The rebels claim they have close to 20,000 combatants. Whatever the number, their forces are growing each year. Ten years ago the army said there were only about 2,500 guerrillas. The growth of guerrilla forces and the possibility of another upheaval probably will depend greatly on whether the wealthy will concede to such programs as land reform, housing programs and building more schools and hospitals in rural areas. The government's attitude toward social change continues to be cautious. The election of mayors is a beginning, but not a solution.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Wells </PERSON> is bureau chief for <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880315-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-15-88 0111EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-SovietEmigre     03-15 0525</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Soviet Emigre,0540</SECOND>
<HEAD>Svoiet Writer Finds New Home</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WOONSOCKET, R.I. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A Soviet dissident whose pleas for an exit visa were ignored until he stepped up his reporting of human rights abuses has found a new home in the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Theodore </PERSON> <PERSON> Kizelov </PERSON>, 43, arrived in <LOCATION> Rhode </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> last Tuesday after a journey that led from <LOCATION> Sverdlovsk </LOCATION>, a town in the <LOCATION> Ural </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mountains </LOCATION>, through <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION> to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> Tolstoy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION>, an international, non-profit organization that helps resettle political refugees, found him an apartment and gave him enough money to live on for a month, said <PERSON> Maureen </PERSON> <PERSON> Dalpe </PERSON> of the Woonsocket chapter. <PERSON> Kizelov </PERSON>, who had never been outside the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> before his expulsion, learned English by listening to British radio broadcasts and should have little trouble finding a job, Ms. <PERSON> Dalpe </PERSON> said. `` I will start with any job available,'' said <PERSON> Kizelov </PERSON>, `` even washing dishes in a restaurant.'' <PERSON> Kizelov </PERSON> had been a dissident since the late 1970s, when he wrote what he calls his first `` open letter'' opposing the government _ a statement against the Soviet invasion of <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>. He sent the letter to the <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> Monitor and <ORGANIZATION> Helsinki </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Group </ORGANIZATION>, which published it outside the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. `` I did n't begin to hide until 1983,'' <PERSON> Kizelov </PERSON> said, because in general, it is safe to risk criticizing the Soviet government without reprisals for three years or so. But the <ORGANIZATION> KGB </ORGANIZATION> patrols that began following him that year did not deter him. To make himself a difficult target, <PERSON> Kizelov </PERSON> began moving from city to city. He held odd jobs, and friends helped with money. Meanwhile, he continued to gather information about Soviet human rights violations, sending the information to groups interested in publishing it. Last fall, <PERSON> Kizelov </PERSON> found himself working as a theater decorator in <LOCATION> Sverdlovsk </LOCATION>, a town whose former political boss, <PERSON> Boris </PERSON> <PERSON> Yeltsin </PERSON>, had been promoted to serve as the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>'s first secretary of <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Yeltsin </PERSON> was drummed out of office by party officials last November after delivering a speech that reportedly rankled powerful officials in the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, including General Secretary <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>. Officials in <LOCATION> Sverdlovsk </LOCATION>, however, took a dim view of one of their favorite sons being kicked out of office, and began demonstrating in public. <PERSON> Kizelov </PERSON> wrote about it. He sent his 3,000-word report on the demonstrations and a cover letter to <PERSON> Sergei </PERSON> <PERSON> Grigoryants </PERSON>, editor of a Moscow-based underground magazine called Glasnost. The sporadically-published magazine takes its cue from <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s policy of `` openness'' in public affairs. But <PERSON> Grigoryants </PERSON> never received the report. <PERSON> Kizelov </PERSON> assumes it was intercepted by Soviet police. A short while after sending it, he received an `` invitation'' to report to the emigration office to talk about his desire to leave the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. `` They say nothing until I was involved in the demonstrations,'' said <PERSON> Kizelov </PERSON>. While Americans seem to be cautiously optimistic about the policy of glasnost, <PERSON> Kizelov </PERSON> calls it a `` mask.'' He says Soviet society is intolerant of anything but the official line and there is no such thing as freedom of speech. `` I do n't like the socialist way of life in principle,'' said <PERSON> Kizelov </PERSON>. `` In my opinion, it is the wrong way of development.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880315-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-15-88 0013EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Ireland-IRA 3dLd-Writethru a0789 03-15 0910</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Ireland-IRA, 3d Ld - Writethru, a0789,0934</SECOND>
<HEAD>URGENT</HEAD>
<HEAD>Procession Accompanies Bodies of IRA Members to Northern Ireland</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: UPDATES with arrival in Belfast, gunman killed near home of
one of slain guerrillas, Protestants pelt funeral procession with
stones. Pick up 6th graf pvs: Police, relatives of...</NOTE>
<HEAD>PRECEDE Carrickaron</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BELFAST, Northern Ireland (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A funeral procession bearing the bodies of three <ORGANIZATION> IRA </ORGANIZATION> guerrillas slain in <LOCATION> Gibraltar </LOCATION> was met by thousands of people when it arrived early Tuesday under heavy rain at <ORGANIZATION> Roman </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> west <LOCATION> Belfast </LOCATION>. Jeering Protestants waving <LOCATION> British </LOCATION> flags had hurled stones and bottles at the cortege in <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION> as it made its way by road to <LOCATION> Belfast </LOCATION> from <LOCATION> Dublin </LOCATION> in the Irish Rep0ublic. <PERSON> Mairead </PERSON> <PERSON> Farrell </PERSON>, 31; <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> McCann </PERSON>, 30, and <PERSON> Sean </PERSON> <PERSON> Savage </PERSON>, 24, were unarmed and walking toward the Gibraltar-Spanish border when <LOCATION> British </LOCATION> commandos in civilian clothes shot them March 6. British officials said the three had planned to detonate a car bomb at a public military ceremony in <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s fortress colony at the southern tip of <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION> two days later. Monday night British troops fatally shot a gunman near <LOCATION> Savage </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Belfast </LOCATION> home Police identified the slain man as <PERSON> Kevin </PERSON> <PERSON> McCracken </PERSON>, 33. A statement by <LOCATION> Belfast </LOCATION> police headquarters said <PERSON> McCracken </PERSON> fired at an army patrol and the soldiers shot back. It said <PERSON> McCracken </PERSON> was jailed in 1978 for membership in the outlawed <ORGANIZATION> Irish </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> and illegal possession of guns. The report said <PERSON> McCracken </PERSON> was released on parole in 1985. The coffins of the three slain guerrillas were carried into the homes of their families in west <LOCATION> Belfast </LOCATION>. Hundreds of police and soldiers, many in riot gear, were on duty as the funeral procession arrived in <LOCATION> Belfast </LOCATION>. At <LOCATION> Newry </LOCATION>, five miles north of the border town of <LOCATION> Carrickaron </LOCATION> in the <LOCATION> Irish </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Republic </LOCATION>, the hearses with the bodies drove qround the predominantly <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> town for two hours Monday night and were cheered by crowds of <ORGANIZATION> IRA </ORGANIZATION> supporters. But on the outskirts of <LOCATION> Newry </LOCATION>, 35 miles south of <LOCATION> Belfast </LOCATION>, Protestants threw bricks, bottles and stones at the vehicles, breaking some windows. Farther north at <LOCATION> Loughbrickland </LOCATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Banbridge </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protestant </ORGANIZATION> crowds again pelted the cortege with stones and shouted abuse as police moved forward to disperse them. The hearses were escorted by police vehicles and followed by dozens of cars containing <ORGANIZATION> IRA </ORGANIZATION> supporters. Press Association, <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s domestic news agency, said about 1,000 people met the coffins Monday when they arrived from <LOCATION> Gibraltar </LOCATION> at <LOCATION> Dublin </LOCATION>'s airport, many of them members of <ORGANIZATION> Sinn </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fein </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> IRA </ORGANIZATION>'s legal political arm. The cortege stopped briefly at the border at <LOCATION> Carrickaron </LOCATION> when two senior officers of <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION>'s police force, the <ORGANIZATION> Royal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ulster </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Constabulary </ORGANIZATION>, ordered the Irish tricolors removed from the coffins. Police, relatives of the slain guerrillas and <ORGANIZATION> Sinn </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fein </ORGANIZATION> members reached a compromise after a 30-minute argument and the flags were folded up and left atop the coffins, covered with funeral wreaths. The <ORGANIZATION> IRA </ORGANIZATION> is waging a guerrilla campaign to drive the British from <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION> and unite the Protestant-dominated province with the overwhelmingly <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> <LOCATION> Irish </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Republic </LOCATION>. At least 2,628 people have been killed since sectarian violence began in <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION> in August 1969. <ORGANIZATION> Sinn </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fein </ORGANIZATION> president <PERSON> Gerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Adams </PERSON> and other senior party figures led the airport reception. The coffins were draped in the green, orange and white Irish flag and a priest recited prayers in Irish and English. Four women in black jackets and trousers formed an honor guard. A lone bagpiper played a lament. In the heavy mist, the coffins were transferred to three hearses. A cortege led by police, which grew to more than 100 cars, made its way along the 100-mile route to the border. About 20 cars continued from the border to <LOCATION> Belfast </LOCATION>, capital of <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION>, where the three will be buried Wednesday or Thursday. Thousands of people lined the roads. Scores of teen-agers held black flags at waist level as the convoy passed through the Catholic town of <LOCATION> Drogheda </LOCATION>. Many drivers threw black flags from their car windows. On both sides of the border, black flags hung from lampposts along the route. The procession took three hours to cover the 60 miles to <LOCATION> Dundalk </LOCATION> on the border, where 5,000 people turned out. Another lone piper escorted the hearses through the town. An honor guard of four men and two women dressed in black marched beside them. <ORGANIZATION> Royal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> soldiers loaded the coffins onto the jet in <LOCATION> Gibraltar </LOCATION> because baggage workers would not handle them, British television networks reported. In <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> IRA </ORGANIZATION> said it fired a three-volley rifle salute at a shrine in <LOCATION> Belfast </LOCATION> to coincide with the bodies' arrival on Irish soil. An <ORGANIZATION> IRA </ORGANIZATION> statement circulated by <ORGANIZATION> Sinn </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fein </ORGANIZATION> said the guerrillas wished the bereaved families `` peaceful and dignified funerals,'' which was seen as a possible hint that the funerals would be allowed to take place without demonstrations. In the past, funerals have been disrupted by hooded <ORGANIZATION> IRA </ORGANIZATION> members firing salutes over the coffins and the police moving in to arrest them. Police in the <LOCATION> Irish </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Republic </LOCATION> and British-ruled <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION> were expected to mount a huge security operation to prevent such displays this time. <ORGANIZATION> Sinn </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fein </ORGANIZATION> said the three guerrillas would be buried at <LOCATION> Milltown </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Cemetery </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Belfast </LOCATION> on Wednesday or on Thursday, Saint <PERSON> Patrick </PERSON>'s Day Relatives of the dead appealed for calm and a Roman Catholic bishop asked police and mourners to avoid violence. The <ORGANIZATION> Royal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ulster </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Constabulary </ORGANIZATION> said it would intervene if necessary to stop armed displays at the funerals.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880315-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-15-88 0124EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Afghanistan 2ndLd-Writethru a0688 03-15 0774</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Afghanistan, 2nd Ld - Writethru, a0688,0790</SECOND>
<HEAD>Pressure Mounts on Pakistan To Sign Peace Pact</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: INSERT 2 grafs after 4th graf pvs, Both sides ... UPDATING
with latest Soviet comment. Picks up 5th graf pvs, Pakistan has ..
. editing 11th graf pvs, In Belgrade ... to conform.
^By MOHAMMAD AFTAB</NOTE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>GENEVA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Pressure mounted Monday on <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> to sign an Afghan settlement aimed at securing the withdrawal of an estimated 115,000 Soviet troops and end nine years of fighting in <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>. Sources close to the talks said the Pakistani chief representative, acting Foreign Minister <PERSON> Zain </PERSON> <PERSON> Noorani </PERSON>, received a message from the Kremlin calling upon him to sign the documents without further delay. The chief Afghan negotiator, Foreign Minister <PERSON> Abdul </PERSON> <PERSON> Wakil </PERSON>, scheduled a news conference for Tuesday, the day Soviet leader <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> named as a target date for the conclusion of the nearly 6-year-old talks. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> said <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> will bring home its troops starting May 15 if the settlement is signed Tuesday. Both sides have said they do not consider March 15 a rigid deadline. Sources close to the talks, who declined to be identified, said that apart from pressing for the formation of an interim government, <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> also felt that there are still some loose ends to be sorted out in the agreements that make up the peace package. The Soviet deputy foreign minister, <PERSON> Vadim </PERSON> <PERSON> Loginov </PERSON>, told a news conference in <LOCATION> Belgrade </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Yugoslavia </LOCATION>, on Monday that <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> is still `` optimistic'' it can pull its troops out, but he acknowledged the <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> talks are encountering difficulties. `` Nobody has set a definite deadline,'' he said. `` All that has been said is that if by the 15th -LRB- of March -RRB-, the last of the four agreements has been signed, then we will begin to withdraw our forces.'' <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> has been insisting that the formation of a transitional government in <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> be linked to the settlement. Both <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> have adamantly rejected that condition. <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> argues that only a broad-based government can guarantee implementation of the peace accords and the safe return of five million Afghan refugees in <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>. `` We are ready to sign the moment our concerns are removed,'' <PERSON> Noorani </PERSON> told reporters as his delegation left an afternoon meeting with <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> mediator <PERSON> Diego </PERSON> <PERSON> Cordovez </PERSON>. Before an earlier meeting in the morning, <PERSON> Noorani </PERSON> had said, without elaborating, <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> would `` announce something today.'' But there was no such announcement as the talks were adjourned until Tuesday. In <LOCATION> Belgrade </LOCATION>, where he was on a state visit, <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> was asked by a reporter if there was progress at the <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> talks. With a smile, he said, `` There is,'' and `` There will be,'' but did not elaborate. <PERSON> Najib </PERSON>, president of <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>'s pro-Soviet government, accused <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> Monday of using tricks to block the final agreement. `` It can be said candidly that that people who resort to ruses and who do n't want the document of the <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> talks to be signed are actually enemies of the refugees,'' <PERSON> Najib </PERSON> was quoted as saying in an interview with the Afghan news agency <ORGANIZATION> Bakhtar </ORGANIZATION> excerpted by <ORGANIZATION> Tass </ORGANIZATION>, the official Soviet news agency. <PERSON> Najib </PERSON> noted that <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> once said the only issue between the two countries was an acceptable timetable for Soviet withdrawal. He charged that <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> raised questions about an interim government to delay the agreement. <PERSON> Najib </PERSON> said the rebels are interested in the millions of Afghan refugees only as a `` reserve of military force to be used as cannon fodder.'' <PERSON> Noorani </PERSON>, meanwhile, was reported to be in constant touch with his capital, <LOCATION> Islamabad </LOCATION>, where the cabinet held its third lengthy meeting in two days, presumably to weigh its next step. The Swiss Radio reported earlier that Prime Minister <PERSON> Mohammad </PERSON> <PERSON> Khan </PERSON> <PERSON> Junejo </PERSON> had said a decision on whether <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> would sign the settlement would be made Monday. In another development, a spokesman for the fragile seven-party alliance of the anti-Soviet guerrillas, revealed that <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> had rejected again any direct negotiations with the insurgents. The spokesman, <PERSON> Gulbadin </PERSON> <PERSON> Hekmatyar </PERSON>, who also leads the largest and most radical group in the alliance, said that no guerrilla delegation would be sent to <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> unless the Soviets drop their opposition. <PERSON> Hekmatyar </PERSON>, the leader of the Hezb-i-islami group, is widely believed to be the next chief of the seven-party alliance following the resignation of <PERSON> Yunis </PERSON> <PERSON> Khalis </PERSON> for health reasons. Unconfirmed reports indicated the 69-year-old <LOCATION> Khalis </LOCATION> quit in protest over plans to send a guerrilla delegation to the <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> talks. <PERSON> Hekmatyar </PERSON> said his appointment as leader of the alliance may be announced Tuesday. `` But if there is a majority opposing my leadership, then I will not be chosen,'' he added, speaking in <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880315-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-15-88 0135EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Dole'sProblems     03-15 0926</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Dole's Problems,920</SECOND>
<HEAD>Dole's Troubles Began Back In New Hampshire</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By EVANS WITT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Political Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Only a month ago, <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> looked ready to wrest the Republican presidential nomination from <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. Now, he is desperately looking for ways to keep his <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> hopes from being wiped out by <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> in today's <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> primary. In mid-February, everything was looking up for <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>. He had scored an upset win in the <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> caucuses, and as the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION> primary approached, polls were suggesting he could overtake the vice president in the state. But in one 48-hour stretch _ the final two days before the voting in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION> _ the <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> campaign derailed, and has never gotten back on track. A combination of body blows _ weak organization, poor planning, a mean image and just bad luck _ has reduced the formidable minority leader of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> to a battered, struggling candidate. With the vice president leading 2-to-1 in the Illinois polls, the question <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> faces over and over is when _ not if _ he will withdraw. <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> said it will not be today or Wednesday: `` I've made a judgment that <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION>, whatever happens, we're going to keep going.'' From the start, <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> was judged a tough contender for the 1988 nomination. A seasoned politician with national stature, the <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> senator was one Republican who could match <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> in fund-raising, name recognition and experience. But there were doubts about <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> as well, doubts that all came to the surface the weekend before the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION> primary Feb. 16 _ `` the 48 hours that cost them the campaign'' is how one Republican professional described those days. `` He was ready to put <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> away,'' said <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> pollster <PERSON> Lance </PERSON> <PERSON> Tarrance </PERSON>, who worked for former candidate <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON>. <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> was riding the wave out of his big early win _ a triumph in the <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> caucuses on Feb. 8. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was a disappointing third behind former television evangelist <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON>. That should have meant a big boost for <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> for the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION> primary the next week. `` You need some luck ... and <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> did n't get much good luck out of <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>,'' Tarrance said. `` The news of <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> beating out <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> ... was the big story.'' <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> did start picking up strength in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was down, and changing his style as his campaign struggled to recover. But by Thursday of that week, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was on the counterattack, readying ads accusing <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> of `` straddling'' major issues. And the <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> campaign could not get its act together to respond. One television commercial attacking <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> _ called `` Footsteps'' inside the campaign _ was ready Thursday. But top aides viewed it and judged it `` unusable'' because of poor production and problems with the script, said two sources who spoke on the condition they not be named. <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> tried twice that week to make a new spot, promising to veto any tax increases, but once again aides judged it not usable, a top <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> adviser said, speaking on the condition of anonymity. When the new ads were ready late Friday, the <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> campaign could n't get them on the air. The television stations were closing for the weekend, making it harder to switch the tapes at the stations. `` They could n't get the old ads off the air and the new ones on,'' said the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> professional, who is not working for any campaign. `` That's what the campaign is supposed to be able to do. They did n't.'' Then it was on to the <LOCATION> South </LOCATION>, where <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> rode President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s popularity and his own solid organization to a wipeout win over <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> on Super Tuesday Organizational problems have been a trademark of <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> campaigns from the start. The wily <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> operator was loath to delegate authority and had a penchant for snarling lines of authority, several <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> aides said. Former Labor Secretary <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Brock </PERSON> was brought into run the campaign on Nov. 1, but that was probably too late. `` The <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> campaign has been working on strategy for years,'' said the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> pro. For example, the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> campaign had prepared long and hard for the possibility of an <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> loss. In contrast, the <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> campaign found itself pumping up expectations of a victory in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION>, when even aides said the preferable course would have been to talk of how tough it would be to beat <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> in his own backyard. And after the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION> loss, the image of a mean <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> came back to haunt him. He snapped at <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> in a television interview that <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s ads were lying about <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>'s record. The chaos in the final days of the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION> campaign was eerily echoed in <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> went into the state saying he had to win, then backed off on that contention. He made deep cutbacks in his staff, and let the word leak out before he made an explanation. He abruptly moved to pull ads off the air, giving rise to rumors he was throwing in the towel. To top it all off, his half-hour address to the voters of <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> on Saturday night was hit by technical problems. `` He did it to himself,'' said <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> consultant <PERSON> Eddie </PERSON> <PERSON> Mahe </PERSON> of <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>. `` The voters ca n't see any big differences between them on the issues. What they did is make their decisions on personality and style.'' <PERSON> Mahe </PERSON> said the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> voters saw each man face defeat in a key early contest _ <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hamsphire </LOCATION>. And they liked what they saw in <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> more.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880315-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-15-88 0019EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Israel Bjt   03-15 0683</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Israel, Bjt,0700</SECOND>
<HEAD>Israel Imposes Curfew On 600,000 Palestinians In Gaza Strip</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By SERGEI SHARGORODSKY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>JERUSALEM (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> imposed a nightly curfew on more than 600,000 Arabs in the entire <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strip </LOCATION> and reportedly sealed off entrances to the occupied territory after about 300 Arab policemen in <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> said they would resign. The army on Monday also closed one of the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION>'s largest fruit and vegetable markets as <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> tightened economic sanctions in the occupied lands. Elsewhere in the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> soldiers on Monday shot and wounded 11 Palestinians, hospital officials said. A 3-year-old girl was shot in the eye with a rubber bullet, and five Israelis were injured by stones thrown by Arabs. <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> radio said the 300 Arab policemen in the <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strip </LOCATION> announced Monday they would resign. They joined 450 officers in the occupied lands who turned in their badges earlier following orders of PLO-inspired underground leaflets. The curfew in <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION>, announced Monday, was a reaction to the resignations, the radio said. The 10 p.m. to 3 a.m. curfew also was designed to prevent `` the entrance of violent instigators ... and of written instigation material,'' it said. The army said the curfew was to prevent late night demonstrations. The curfew over the entire <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strip </LOCATION> was imposed for the first time since Arab unrest started on Dec. 8. It forces the residents to stay in their homes while entrances to <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> are sealed off by the army, the radio said. An army spokesman said the curfew would be imposed until further notice. At the <LOCATION> Erez </LOCATION> checkpoint at the entrance to <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> photographer <PERSON> Max </PERSON> <PERSON> Nash </PERSON> on Monday saw 15 to 20 Arab trucks and taxis prevented by the army from entering. He said soldiers would let in army vehicles and cars belonging to Jewish settlers who live in <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION>. Other Israelis and journalists were not permitted to drive in. `` Where would we sleep? We want to enter, all our families are inside,'' an Arab worker stopped at <ORGANIZATION> Erez </ORGANIZATION> told <ORGANIZATION> Israel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> radio </ORGANIZATION>. The situation in <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION>'s refugee camps was not immediately clear. On Sunday night, the army cut electricity and telephone lines to 41,000 people in the Beach Camp, an Arab reporter said. <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> authorities acknowledged that some policemen in the <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strip </LOCATION> quit but gave no figures. About 850 Arab policemen work in the occupied territories. The police control crime and direct traffic, but they are not used to quell <PERSON> Arab </PERSON> rioting in the occupied lands. `` It is clear their resignations were not handed in freely but because they fear for their lives,'' <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> police commander <PERSON> Shimon </PERSON> <PERSON> Levy </PERSON> said on <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> radio. Graffiti on the walls in <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> called for the resignation of the Israeli-appointed mayor and city council, <ORGANIZATION> Israel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Television </ORGANIZATION> said. In response to the PLO-backed unrest, <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> stepped up economic sanctions. Shipment of gasoline and other fuel to service stations in the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> was banned as of Sunday, and a regional fruit and vegetable market was closed on Monday in <LOCATION> Jericho </LOCATION>, 20 miles northwest of <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION>. Arab merchants said 70 trucks carrying produce were turned away Monday. In addition, the army ordered <LOCATION> Jericho </LOCATION> shop owners to close during the morning hours when <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> leaflets said shops should be open. <ORGANIZATION> Israel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Television </ORGANIZATION> said the Arab merchants responded with a total commercial strike. The economic test of wills continued on Monday in <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, where slogans painted in the red, green, white and black colors of the outlawed <LOCATION> Palestinian </LOCATION> flag called for a two-day general strike starting today. Protests were reported on Monday in <LOCATION> Jenin </LOCATION> and the nearby <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> village of <LOCATION> Yamoun </LOCATION>, where troops using live ammunition shot and wounded 11 people, hospital officials said. According to <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> figures, at least 91 Palestinians have been killed since anti-Israeli rioting began Dec. 8. Witnesses said Jewish settlers on Monday drove through the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> town of <LOCATION> Ramallah </LOCATION> and nearby <LOCATION> Al </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Amari </LOCATION> refugee camp, honking their horns. Witnesses said Palestinians then held a similar car demonstration, during which soldiers shot 3-year-old <PERSON> Rasha </PERSON> <PERSON> Yussef </PERSON> <PERSON> Said </PERSON> in the eye with a rubber bullet.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880315-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-15-88 0139EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-ATVSettlement     03-15 0672</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-ATV Settlement,660</SECOND>
<HEAD>New ATV Settlement Stresses Advertising, Safety Programs</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RANDOLPH E. SCHMID</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Advertising for all-terrain vehicles will begin stressing safety under a new agreement that also calls on makers of the off-road vehicles to set up new training programs and limit ATV sales. The government on Monday disclosed the new settlement, which could replace a preliminary agreement announced in December. The recreational vehicles have grown sharply in popularity in recent years, with more than 2 million currently believed to be in use. At the same time accidents have increased markedly, with more than 900 fatalities reported in the last five years, as well as 300,000 injuries, according to information collected by the Consumer Product <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION>. That led to a government safety investigation and the new agreement by the commission, the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, and the five manufacturers of the machines: <ORGANIZATION> Honda </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Yamaha </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Kawasaki </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Suzuki </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> Polaris </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Industries </ORGANIZATION>. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> Gerhard </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gesell </PERSON> will hold a hearing on the settlement April 18 and could order it into effect immediately. It would replace the preliminary agreement between the government and the manufacturers announced on Dec. 30. <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Terrence </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Scanlon </PERSON> said through a spokesman that the settlement is the biggest safety accomplishment in the history of his agency. Commission general counsel <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> V. </PERSON> <PERSON> Lacy </PERSON> said the settlement will continue the ban on sales of new three-wheeled ATVs and that manufacturers have agreed to buy back any of the three-wheel versions remaining in dealer inventories. The more stable four-wheel ATVs will still be sold, he said, but marketing of the full-size versions with engines of 90 cubic centimeters and over will be limited to riders aged 16 and over. Smaller machines will be allowed to be sold for riders ages 12 to 16, he said. The commission vote was 2-1, with <PERSON> Scanlon </PERSON> and commissioner <PERSON> Carol </PERSON> <PERSON> Dawson </PERSON> in favor and commissioner <PERSON> Anne </PERSON> <PERSON> Graham </PERSON> dissenting. <PERSON> Graham </PERSON>, who also voted against the preliminary settlement in December, said in a statement that the settlement should have allowed <ORGANIZATION> ATV </ORGANIZATION> owners to obtain refunds. `` Without the refund, consumers are not obtaining the remedies necessary given the nature and severity of the hazards presented by ATVs,'' she said. The new 150-page settlement is much more detailed than the one announced in December, which drew criticism from <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and consumer groups as not being extensive enough. Some consumer groups have said all the vehicles should be recalled because of safety problems. <PERSON> Lacy </PERSON> said the settlement calls for the manufacturers to spend between $ 8.4 million and $ 8.6 million on advertising starting in the fall. The ads will stress the inherent safety risks of the vehicles, <PERSON> Lacy </PERSON> said, and will be placed in a variety of media. Included, he said, would be advertising on such broadcasts as the World Series, CBS Evening News and Monday Night Football. In addition the manufacturers have agreed to set up a national headquarters to develop safety and training programs for riders, and to provide hands-on training for all new purchasers and for all consumers who bought the machines since Dec. 30, 1986. Buyers will be offered incentives such as $ 50 in cash, a $ 100 savings bond or merchandise certificates to induce them to take the training programs, <PERSON> Lacy </PERSON> said. Other provisions of the agreement, he said, include: _ New warning labels on the machines being sold, plus mailings providing these labels for all current owners for whom the manufacturers have addresses _ The hands-on training programs for new buyers will include their immediate families also _ Development of new owners manuals with added safety information _ Establishment of a safety hotline for consumers to get information and development of safety-related videos to be made available at dealer showrooms _ Elimination of the safety verification form that had been required as part of the earlier settlement This form, in which a buyer acknowledges knowing of the hazards of the machines, had been criticized by consumer groups, who said it could be used to protect the manufacturers in case of lawsuits stemming from accidents.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880315-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-15-88 0140EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-FatigueSyndrome     03-15 0680</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Fatigue Syndrome,0699</SECOND>
<HEAD>Doctors Should Rule Out Look-Alike Diseases in Mysterious Fatigue
Syndrome</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DANIEL Q. HANEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Science Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BOSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Doctors should rule out a long list of ills, such as AIDS and alcoholism, before they decide patients are afflicted with a baffling, newly recognized ailment called chronic fatigue syndrome, researchers say. In the past, the illness has been referred to as the yuppie disease, because some of its victims are young professionals, or more formally, Epstein-Barr virus syndrome or chronic mononucleosis. In a report published in the March issue of the Annals of <ORGANIZATION> Internal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medicine </ORGANIZATION>, 16 top researchers in this field agreed to call it chronic fatigue syndrome, and settled on a definition for the afflication. The definition largely involves ruling out other illnesses that can cause similar symptoms, including the hallmark of the syndrome, extreme fatigue. `` It's a diagnosis of exclusion, and it has to be considered as such even after you've ruled everything else out,'' said Dr. <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Holmes </PERSON>, of the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Centers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Disease </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Control </ORGANIZATION> and chief author of the report. `` You have to continue to be concerned that there is something else going on,'' he added. `` You have to keep an open mind and not simply close the books.'' Another co-author, Dr. <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Komaroff </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> Brigham </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Women </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>, said the new definition should help researchers as well as doctors who are faced with patients who have heard of the illness and think they have it. `` Many of them have other physical illnesses, or they are depressed or anxious,'' he said. `` Doctors need an anchor to help distinguish patients with chronic fatigue syndrome from patients who have other kinds of fatigue.'' According to the definition, people with the syndrome must have suffered debilitating fatigue for at least six months. It must be bad enough to reduce daily activity by at least half. Doctors also must rule out a long list of diseases that can mimic the symptoms of the syndrome. These include cancer, tuberculosis, AIDS, depression, diabetes, alcoholism, poisoning and kidney disease, among many other disorders. In addition, patients must show signs of at least eight of 11 other possible conditions. These are mild fever, sore throat, painful lymph nodes, generalized muscle weakness, muscle discomfort, headaches, painful joints, sleep problems, sudden onset of the symptoms, such neurological problems as trouble concentrating, confusion or forgetfulness and general fatigue lasting at least 24 hours after exercise that the patient easily could have withstood when healthy. When the disease first received widespread attention three years ago, doctors believed it was somehow linked with the Epstein-Barr virus, because some victims showed signs of activation of that common virus. However, many experts now say that Epstein-Barr virus is not associated with the illness, since victims are just as likely to show exposure to the viruses that cause measles, genital herpes and cold sores, among other things. Although the <ORGANIZATION> CDC </ORGANIZATION> has received thousands of questions about the illness from patients and doctors, no one knows how many people have it. Its cause also is a mystery. Some believe it can be triggered by persistant infections with a variety of viruses. Among the suspects are a group of microbes called the enteroviruses as well as a newly discovered virus known as human herpes virus 6. Researchers suggest it's a reaction to these lingering infections rather than the mischief of the viruses themselves that makes people feel poorly. `` My theory is that certain viruses are able to escape ever being fully eradicated by the body,'' said <PERSON> Komaroff </PERSON>. `` They come back to fight again. You have a constant Iran-Iraq war where the battles are continual. The process of doing battle and mobilizing the body's immune system causes some of the symptoms of feeling ill.'' <PERSON> Holmes </PERSON> noted that the symptoms of chronic fatigue syndrome are similar to those experienced by people treated with the natural hormone interferon `` Interferon is the body's normal response to a viral infection,'' <PERSON> Holmes </PERSON> said. `` It may be that something like overproduction of interferon for a prolonged period may be causing the illness.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880315-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-15-88 0033EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Israel-Economy     03-15 0710</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Israel-Economy,0734</SECOND>
<HEAD>Revolt Shifts Gears: A New Emphasis on Economy</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Israel, Bjt</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By NICOLAS B. TATRO</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>JERUSALEM (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The confrontation in the occupied <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strip </LOCATION> has increasingly become an economic test of wills between <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> occupation authorities and Palestinians. Underground Palestinian leaders have persuaded many merchants and ordinary citizens to stop paying taxes and have enforced repeated strikes, keeping at home a large part of the 110,000 laborers who work in <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>. The measures are designed to make <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> bear more of the economic burden for occupation, which <PERSON> Arab </PERSON> activists say will give impetus to <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s withdrawal. <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> has adopted increasingly tough economic sanctions, some of which are designed to put the squeeze on the Arab middle class. The army imposed an indefinite ban on trucks taking gasoline to the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION>'s 50 service stations. The move crippled public and private transport. <LOCATION> Qabatiyeh </LOCATION>, a <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> village of several thousand people, was banned from exporting its quarried rock to <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION> and visitors from abroad will not be allowed to visit the village, <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> officials said. The move was punishment for the lynching of an alleged collaborator who was hung from an electricty pole after he fired into a crowd advancing on his home and fatally wounded a child. In <LOCATION> Jericho </LOCATION>, the army closed a regional produce market and ordered shops to close during morning hours, when <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> leaflets said the shops should be open. `` The military government is trying to tell the people here who is boss. They want to hurt the people economically. I think they intend to try to break the strike this way,'' said <PERSON> Saeb </PERSON> <PERSON> Erakat </PERSON>, a political science professor at <ORGANIZATION> Al </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Najah </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. Israeli authorities have selectively used other measures as well, such as cutting off electricity to areas placed under curfew. <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> officials say they hope such steps will encourage moderates to put pressure on Palestinian militants, although there is no sign that such measures are having the desired effect. `` Agitators on the Arab side want to disconnect the population as much as possible from any connection with <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>,'' said a senior official in the military administration of the occupied territories. He said the tax rebellion had minimal impact in January and February, leading to a 10 percent decline in revenues, or about $ 200,000 a month. But he said collections were expected to be far lower in March and that road repairs, garbage collection and other services in the occupied territories could suffer if there was not enough income to fund the $ 239 million budget of the army-run <ORGANIZATION> Civil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>. To counter the tax boycott, authorities required Arabs to obtain a certificate saying they paid their taxes before getting import-export licenses, driver's permits and other documents. <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> also lowered the amount of money Palestinians could bring from abroad without permission from $ 5,000 to $ 1,200. The official, who spoke on condition of anonymity, said more economic sanctions were being considered to quell the revolt, which began Dec. 8. and has resulted in the death of more than 90 Arabs He declined to elaborate. But <PERSON> Arieh </PERSON> <PERSON> Shalev </PERSON>, former head of the army-run military government in 1974-76, said it might be necessary to stop Arabs from working in <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> or using the bridges to trade with <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION>. `` Violence has peaked, in my opinion, but it will continue and it's doubtful whether it will stop without taking brutal -LRB- economic -RRB- measures,'' <PERSON> Shalev </PERSON> said on <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> radio. <PERSON> Ephraim </PERSON> <PERSON> Kleiman </PERSON>, an economics professor at <ORGANIZATION> Hebrew </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, said <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> was better positioned to endure a showdown than the Palestinians. `` The occupied territories are dependent for income on three things: work in <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>, the export of agricultural goods and quarried stone to <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION>, and financial support from Arab countries,'' he said in an interview. He said <PERSON> Arab </PERSON> job boycotts would deal a `` serious blow'' to the construction industry, textile factories, restaurants and garbage collection. But overall, he said, the `` economic impact on <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> is much smaller.'' Arab economists disputed the contention. `` We are prepared to suffer more than the Israelis,'' said <PERSON> Samir </PERSON> <PERSON> Hazboun </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Bir </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Zeit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> economist. He said the tax rebellion had added to <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s cost of continuing the occupation and that bad publicity abroad had affected investment and tourism.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880315-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-15-88 0142EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Koch-Austria     03-15 0274</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Koch-Austria,0281</SECOND>
<HEAD>Koch Greets New Austrian Ambassador With Waldheim Blast</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The new Austrian ambassador to the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> came bearing gifts to Mayor <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> I. </PERSON> <PERSON> Koch </PERSON>, but the mayor greeted him with a diatribe against <LOCATION> Austria </LOCATION>'s president, <PERSON> Kurt </PERSON> <PERSON> Waldheim </PERSON>. `` I think he's a bad guy. He was just one of those obsequious guys when he was here, before I knew he was a war criminal. And I had dinner with him a couple of times,'' <PERSON> Koch </PERSON> on Monday told <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Hohenfellner </PERSON>, who became the permanent Austrian representative at the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> in February. `` You'll forgive me if I'm honest, OK, and it's not intended as anything but honesty because I have the highest regard for your chancellor.'' <PERSON> Waldheim </PERSON>, who was secretary-general of the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION>, has come under fire since files were uncovered that suggest he had a greater role than he has admitted as an officer in the Nazi army during World War II. There are reports that <PERSON> Waldheim </PERSON> knew about atrocities being committed against partisans and villagers where he was stationed. <PERSON> Waldheim </PERSON> has stood fast against the accusations and refused to resign as president. He has been banned as an undesireable from <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Koch </PERSON> told <PERSON> Hohenfellner </PERSON> that Austrian Chancellor <PERSON> Franz </PERSON> <PERSON> Vranitzky </PERSON> was invited to dinner the next time he comes to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. `` I'd like him to stay at <LOCATION> Gracie </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mansion </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Koch </PERSON> said of the mayor's residence. `` I would n't do that for the president. ... For the president, this city is off limits.'' The mayor gave <PERSON> Hohenfellner </PERSON> a tie and the ambassador gave him a 19th century goblet <PERSON> Koch </PERSON> said he would use at Passover.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880315-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-15-88 0147EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     03-15 0695</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0722</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names In The News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MITCHELL, S.D. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Country singer <PERSON> Johnny </PERSON> <PERSON> Cash </PERSON> ended a three-city <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION> tour here with an unwelcome non-musical sidekick _ the hiccups. `` This is an all-time first for me,'' Cash told his audience in the Corn Palace. `` It's the first time I've done a show with the hiccups.'' Cash, who also had a recent bout with the flu, sipped water during Sunday afternoon's performance. He even left the stage for a short time to try unsuccessfully to get rid of his hiccups. He and his wife, June Carter Cash, performed to the audience of 2,000 for about two hours.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>SANTA MONICA, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Doctors removed singer <PERSON> Dennis </PERSON> <PERSON> Day </PERSON> from the critical list after he responded to treatment for a head injury he suffered last week in a fall at home. His condition was upgraded to serious Monday after surgery Saturday relieved swelling of the brain, said <PERSON> Armen </PERSON> <PERSON> Markarian </PERSON>, spokesman for <PERSON> St. </PERSON> <PERSON> John </PERSON>'s Hospital. Day, 71, was diagnosed last July as suffering from amyotropic lateral sclerosis, or <PERSON> Lou </PERSON> <PERSON> Gehrig </PERSON>'s disease, a progressive nerve disorder that causes loss of muscle control. Day became famous by performing with comedian <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Benny </PERSON> starting in 1939. An accomplished Irish tenor, Day also was known for playing the innocent foil to <PERSON> Benny </PERSON>'s irascible character on television and radio.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Rev. <PERSON> Allan </PERSON> <PERSON> Boesak </PERSON>, an anti-apartheid leader, says productions such as the movie `` Cry Freedom'' and the musical `` Sarafina'' play important roles in publicizing the struggle of blacks in his native <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>. `` You can not reach everybody by making a speech, or even by saying something on television,'' <PERSON> Boesak </PERSON> said in an interview in April's Essence magazine. `` Some other people are more convinced by reading a book, by meeting someone face to face, by seeing a play, by seeing a movie. I believe that if you get all these different audiences, and you speak to them in a medium that they can understand, then so much the better.'' <PERSON> Boesak </PERSON>, 41, is a minister in the <ORGANIZATION> Dutch </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reformed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> and president of the <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Alliance </ORGANIZATION> of Reformed Churches. Under <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>'s racially restrictive laws, which reserve most power for the white minority, he is considered of mixed race. The magazine said writer and former Black Panther leader <PERSON> Elaine </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> interviewed <PERSON> Boesak </PERSON> when he and his wife, <PERSON> Dorothy </PERSON>, and four children were in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> recently.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WESTLAKE VILLAGE, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Having a newborn baby wo n't keep three-time Grammy-winner <PERSON> Deniece </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> from the recording studio, her publicist says. Miss <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>, 35, who gave birth Saturday, is planning to record an album next month, press agent <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Angelotti </PERSON> says. `` Mother and child are doing fine'' but will remain in the hospital for several days, he said. <PERSON> Forrest </PERSON> <PERSON> Matthew </PERSON> <PERSON> Westering </PERSON>, who weighed 9 pounds, 3 ounces at birth, is the first child for the singer and her husband, <PERSON> Brad </PERSON> <PERSON> Westering </PERSON>, who were married in 1986. Miss <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> has two children from a previous marriage. Miss <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> began her career as a backup singer for <PERSON> Stevie </PERSON> <PERSON> Wonder </PERSON>. In 1978, she recorded a No. 1 single, `` Too Much, Too Little, Too Late,'' with <PERSON> Johnny </PERSON> <PERSON> Mathis </PERSON>. She recently won her third Grammy, best female gospel performance, for `` I Believe in You'' on the album `` Water Under the Bridge.''
</TEXT>
<NOTE>Eds: A version of this item moved on sports wires.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>INDIANAPOLIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Retired Brig. Gen. <PERSON> Chuck </PERSON> <PERSON> Yeager </PERSON>, the first man to fly faster than the speed of sound, will drive the pace car in the 1988 <LOCATION> Indianapolis </LOCATION> 500, race officials say. The announcement was made Monday at a ceremony in which <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Motors </ORGANIZATION> officials presented the keys for 66 black 1988 <ORGANIZATION> Cutlass </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supremes </ORGANIZATION> to Speedway president <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Cloutier </PERSON>. The cars are replicas of the open-top Cutlass that will pace the 72nd <LOCATION> Indianapolis </LOCATION> 500 on May 29. <PERSON> Yeager </PERSON>, who retired from active duty in the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> in 1975, set his flight speed record on Oct. 14, 1947. He works as a consultant test-pilot for <ORGANIZATION> Northrop </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> McDonnell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Douglas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> and the flight test center at <ORGANIZATION> Edwards </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Base </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Yeager </PERSON> also drove the pace car in the 1986 Indy 500.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880315-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-15-88 0042EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-Minister-Attack     03-15 0298</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Minister-Attack,0307</SECOND>
<HEAD>Railey Misses Deadline in Lawsuit, Attorney Says</HEAD>
<DATELINE>DALLAS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Former minister <PERSON> Walker </PERSON> <PERSON> Railey </PERSON> has decided not to contest a civil suit accusing him of choking his wife nearly to death, <PERSON> Railey </PERSON>'s attorney said Monday. <PERSON> Doug </PERSON> <PERSON> Mulder </PERSON> told the <ORGANIZATION> Dallas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Morning </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> that <PERSON> Railey </PERSON>'s decision was based on estimates that it would cost nearly $ 100,000 in legal fees to dispute the lawsuit filed Feb. 2 by <PERSON> Railey </PERSON>'s mother-in-law, <PERSON> Billie </PERSON> <PERSON> Jo </PERSON> <PERSON> Nicolai </PERSON>. `` He told me that he had decided his assets would be best used in the support and maintenance of his children,'' said <PERSON> Mulder </PERSON>, who represented <PERSON> Railey </PERSON> before a <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> grand jury investigating the attack. <PERSON> Railey </PERSON>, 40, missed a Monday deadline for answering the suit, which seeks unspecified damages, said <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Arnold </PERSON>, an attorney for Mrs. <PERSON> Nicolai </PERSON>. In absence of a response, a judge could rule against the former senior minister of the <ORGANIZATION> First </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Methodist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dallas </ORGANIZATION> and award damages. <PERSON> Peggy </PERSON> <PERSON> Railey </PERSON>, 39, has been in a coma since she was found unconscious on the floor of her garage last April. She had been choked. <PERSON> Railey </PERSON> was not charged, but both his attorney and Assistant District Attorney <PERSON> Norm </PERSON> <PERSON> Kinne </PERSON> identified the former minister as the prime suspect. <PERSON> Railey </PERSON> denied any involvement but refused to cooperate with police, invoking his Fifth Amendment right against self-incrimination 43 times when questioned by a grand jury. Mrs. <PERSON> Railey </PERSON> remains in a Tyler nursing home. <PERSON> Railey </PERSON>, who now lives in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION>, has assigned her guardianship to her parents, and that of his two children to family friends. `` The question now is when do I want to go to court and ask for a default judgment,'' <ORGANIZATION> Arnold </ORGANIZATION> said Monday. `` It could be tomorrow or it could be a couple of months. It depends on <PERSON> Peggy </PERSON>'s best interests.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880315-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-15-88 0152EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Byrne-Vrdolyak Bjt   03-15 0630</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Byrne-Vrdolyak, Bjt,0652</SECOND>
<HEAD>Byrne, Vrdolyak _ Once Allies _ Now Adversaries On Comeback Trail</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Political Rdp, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ED WHITE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CHICAGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Jane </PERSON> <PERSON> Byrne </PERSON> and <PERSON> Ed </PERSON> <PERSON> Vrdolyak </PERSON>, once on the same team pulling the levers of city government, are on the comeback trail, this time by trying to throw a monkey wrench into each other's plans Mrs. <PERSON> Byrne </PERSON>, the former mayor, says her last attempt at office will be today when she runs in the Democratic primary for clerk of the nation's largest local court system. <PERSON> Vrdolyak </PERSON>, a former alderman and former chairman of the powerful <ORGANIZATION> Cook </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, wants the same office. But he's now a Republican running unopposed in the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> primary. A victory by either candidate in November's general election could give a jump start to his or her political future. But a loss could be politically fatal. `` It's a position that has some patronage, it has jobs,'' said <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Kleppner </PERSON>, a social scientist at <ORGANIZATION> Northern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Illinois </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> and analyst of <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> politics. `` More important than the number of jobs, if you're an office-holder, you can grab the media. As <PERSON> Jane </PERSON> <PERSON> Byrne </PERSON> once said, the new precinct captain in this age is television,'' <PERSON> Kleppner </PERSON> said Monday. Mrs. <PERSON> Byrne </PERSON> was in a tough primary race with <PERSON> Aurelia </PERSON> <PERSON> Pucinski </PERSON>, the county <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>'s endorsed candidate and daughter of fiery <PERSON> Alderman </PERSON> <PERSON> Roman </PERSON> <PERSON> Pucinski </PERSON>. Mrs. <PERSON> Byrne </PERSON>, mayor from 1979 to 1983, was ousted by <PERSON> Harold </PERSON> <PERSON> Washington </PERSON>, who became the city's first black chief executive and then withstood an election challenge from her last year. Besides announcing proposals to streamline the court system's bureaucracy and broaden services for county residents outside <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>, Mrs. <PERSON> Byrne </PERSON> and Mrs. <PERSON> Pucinski </PERSON> have mostly haggled over who had the late mayor's affection <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> supported Mrs. <PERSON> Pucinski </PERSON> and the party's slate of endorsed candidates just a few days before he died Nov. 23. But in Mrs. <PERSON> Byrne </PERSON>'s effort to appeal to <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>'s powerful black voting bloc, she points to a unity breakfast she had with <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> after he won the primary last February. Mrs. <PERSON> Byrne </PERSON> also pulls out a newspaper article that quotes Mrs. <PERSON> Pucinski </PERSON> as saying she was n't <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>'s first choice for the clerk's job. Mrs. <PERSON> Pucinski </PERSON> has countered with a radio blitz featuring prominent black politicians and even <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>'s half brother, <PERSON> Ramon </PERSON> <PERSON> Price </PERSON>. `` <PERSON> Harold </PERSON> believed we had come too far to go back to the days of the bosses. ... That's why <PERSON> Harold </PERSON> chose <PERSON> Aurelia </PERSON> <PERSON> Pucinski </PERSON>,'' Price says on the ad, broadcast on black-oriented radio stations. But Mrs. <PERSON> Pucinski </PERSON>'s alderman father was viewed among blacks as an obstructionist during <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>'s reign as mayor. `` I would expect <PERSON> Byrne </PERSON> to get the black vote,'' <PERSON> Kleppner </PERSON> said. `` The question is how much.'' <PERSON> Vrdolyak </PERSON>, an alderman for 15 years, lost power to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> in the <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> and waged an unsuccessful bid against him on a third-party ticket last April. <PERSON> Vrdolyak </PERSON> subsequently resigned from the chairmanship of the county Democratic organization to become a Republican. With no primary opponent, <PERSON> Vrdolyak </PERSON> has spent most of his time talking about demanding integrity and honesty from the court system's 2,000 employees. He's also portraying Democrats as big taxers and spenders, hoping to get conservative Democratic voters to join his cause in November. At a rally Sunday for Vice President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, <PERSON> Vrdolyak </PERSON> said `` they do n't represent you.'' `` They do n't hardly represent anybody any more,'' he said. If Mrs. <PERSON> Byrne </PERSON> survives the primary and meets <PERSON> Vrdolyak </PERSON> in November, the clerk's race will feature two former allies. <PERSON> Vrdolyak </PERSON> was her floor leader in the <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>, and she once helped install him as chairman of the county <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>. Today, the affection is lost. `` He's devious. He's a wheeler-dealer,'' she told a newspaper last week. `` It's distasteful. ... I do n't like him. He's not my cup of tea.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880315-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-15-88 0125EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-NukeProtest 1stLd-Writethru a0665 03-15 0374</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Nuke Protest, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0665,0381</SECOND>
<HEAD>200 Arrested in Continuing Action at Test Site</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: INSERTS 4 grafs after 3rd graf pvs, `The majority...', to
UPDATE with later protest at booking site, picking up 4th graf pvs,
`Monday's arrests ...'</NOTE>
<DATELINE>MERCURY, Nev. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Two hundred arrests were reported Monday as anti-nuclear protesters tried to block buses carrying thousands of workers to the nation's nuclear testing grounds. The protesters slowed traffic into the <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION> Test Site, 65 miles northwest of <LOCATION> Las </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vegas </LOCATION>, but failed to halt work, said <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Chris </PERSON> <PERSON> West </PERSON>. The majority of those arrested were carried away by officers after lying down on the main road leading into the sprawling desert site. Later, many of those arrested had to be dragged by police off buses in <LOCATION> Tonopah </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Nev. </LOCATION>, about 135 miles away, where they were taken to be booked before being released. `` They were n't going to stand for being driven 135 miles away and being let loose,'' said protest spokeswoman <PERSON> Trudy </PERSON> <PERSON> Mason </PERSON>. The <ORGANIZATION> Nye </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sheriff </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> said officers decided to remove the protesters from three buses and from the <LOCATION> Tonopah </LOCATION> convention center, which was serving as a booking facility, after they refused for several hours to be released. `` They just sat down and went limp and we dragged them out of there,'' said Capt. <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Gumbmann </PERSON>. <PERSON> Mason </PERSON> claimed some of the protesters were injured, but <PERSON> Gumbmann </PERSON> said he knew of no injuries. Monday's arrests followed a demonstration Saturday by up to 5,000 people, the largest in more than seven years of protests at the site. Police arrested 1,240 people that day, mostly on misdemeanor trespass citations. A spokesman for the American Peace Test, which is sponsoring the demonstrations, said 50 protesters had infiltrated the 1,350-square-mile site, which is the size of <LOCATION> Rhode </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION>. <PERSON> West </PERSON> said he was unaware of any such incidents, but said any infiltrators would not be able to reach sensitive areas. American Peace Test estimated there were 200 protesters at the site Monday, but <PERSON> West </PERSON> said the number was closer to 400. He said 300 personnel from the <ORGANIZATION> Nye </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sheriff </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Nevada </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Highway </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Patrol </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Wackenhut </ORGANIZATION> Security remained on duty or on standby. The protests are scheduled to continue through Sunday.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880315-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-15-88 0043EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-Scotus-Darden     03-15 0117</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Scotus-Darden,110</SECOND>
<HEAD>URGENT</HEAD>
<HEAD>Court Denies Darden Stay</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> by a vote of 6-3 refused early Tuesday to postpone the execution of <PERSON> Willie </PERSON> <PERSON> Jasper </PERSON> <PERSON> Darden </PERSON>, scheduled to die later in the morning in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>'s electric chair. <PERSON> Darden </PERSON>, who was scheduled to be electrocuted at 7 a.m. at <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> State Prison, has maintained his innocence in the 1973 fatal shooting of a <LOCATION> Lakeland </LOCATION> furniture store owner during a robbery. His case has been the focus of an international campaign against capital punishment. Pope <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> II and Soviet dissident <PERSON> Andrei </PERSON> <PERSON> Sakharov </PERSON> had made appeals on his behalf. The dissenting votes were cast by justices <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Brennan </PERSON>, <PERSON> Thurgood </PERSON> <PERSON> Marshall </PERSON>, and <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Blackmun </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880315-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-15-88 0054EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Shamir-Peres     03-15 0718</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Shamir-Peres,0739</SECOND>
<HEAD>Shamir Speaks For Half His Government in Washington</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-US-Israel, Bjt</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAN IZENBERG</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>JERUSALEM (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
