<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880616-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-16-88 2340EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Pakistan-islam     06-16 0436</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Pakistan-islam,0450</SECOND>
<BYLINE>Opposition Leader Balks At Decree On Islamic Law</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ISLAMABAD, Pakistan (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Opposition leader <PERSON> Benazir </PERSON> <PERSON> Bhutto </PERSON> assailed President <PERSON> Mohammad </PERSON> <PERSON> Zia </PERSON> <PERSON> ul-Haq </PERSON> for his decree making Islam the law of the land and accusing him of doing it to stay in power, newspapers reported Thursday. <PERSON> Zia </PERSON> put the so-called Shariah Law into effect Wednesday night in a televised address to the nation. He said his decree makes Islam `` the supreme law of <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>'' but will not affect the rights of non-Moslems or <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>'s business contracts with other nations. The official <ORGANIZATION> Pakistan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> newspaper trumpeted `` Shariat At Last'' on page one. A report in the English-language <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Muslim </ORGANIZATION>, however, quoted Ms. <PERSON> Bhutto </PERSON> as telling Pakistani journalists at a Wednesday reception that her archfoe <PERSON> Zia </PERSON> had `` no right to impose his will on the people of <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>.'' Other newspapers carried similar accounts. Ms. <PERSON> Bhutto </PERSON>, leader of the <ORGANIZATION> Pakistan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, was quoted as saying: `` It has been the <ORGANIZATION> PPP </ORGANIZATION>'s stand that <ORGANIZATION> Islam </ORGANIZATION>, like in the past, is again being used to perpetuate oppressive rule.'' Gen. <PERSON> Zia </PERSON>, who also is chief of the army, surprised the nation on May 29 by firing his entire civilian government and dissolving the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION>. He claimed that in three years in power, they failed to enact the Islamic code and to battle deteriorating law and order. <PERSON> Zia </PERSON> hinted that elections would be announced within 90 days but he has yet to set a date. <PERSON> Zia </PERSON> ousted Ms. <PERSON> Bhutto </PERSON>'s father, Prime Minister <PERSON> Zulfikar </PERSON> <PERSON> Ali </PERSON> bhutto, in a 1977 military coup and had him hanged two years later for complicity in a murder plot. After ruling eight years with martial law, <PERSON> Zia </PERSON> allowed creation of a civilian government in 1985. The opposition press dubbed his firing of that government `` <PERSON> Zia </PERSON>'s second coup d'etat.'' Ms. <PERSON> Bhutto </PERSON> had cautiously welcomed the prospect of new elections after having boycotted the 1985 voting, but she lashed out at <PERSON> Zia </PERSON>'s latest move as an abuse of power `` We believe it is not the business of a caretaker government or an individual to impose their views on the nation,'' she was quoted as saying. `` As in the past, we will resist any such move.'' She repeated her call for free elections and denied reports that her advancing pregnancy would keep her from preaching the party's platform of popular socialism She married <LOCATION> Karachi </LOCATION> businessman <PERSON> Asif </PERSON> <PERSON> Zardari </PERSON> last December and at 35, is expecting her first child this December. `` We would like constitutional continuity which calls for elections within 90 days. If you break this continuity, it would amount to opening a Pandora's box,'' Ms. <PERSON> Bhutto </PERSON> was quoted as saying.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880616-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-16-88 2336EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-ComputerBreak-in 1stLd-Writethru a0754 06-16 0830</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Computer Break-in, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0754,0849</SECOND>
<HEAD>Defense-NASA Computer Network Penetrated By Hackers</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: UPDATES throughout with a third computer and possibly others
entered, no damage, other nations also on network, network name,
third JPL computer break-in last summer, details on how hacker
gained access, Pentagon comment; No pickup</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By LEE SIEGEL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Science Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PASADENA, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Hackers penetrated a non-classified <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> computer network last month, rummaging through data at a <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> base, <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Jet </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Propulsion </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Laboratory </ORGANIZATION>, and at least one other center, the space agency said Thursday. The break-in occurred the night of May 16 and lasted into the early morning hours of May 17, but no damage was done, said <PERSON> Haskell </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Brien </PERSON>, the laboratory's manager of communications and computing network services. `` <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> security people are working with the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> investigating the details of this,'' <PERSON> O'Brien </PERSON> told a news conference. It was unknown whether more than one person was involved or if the break-in was achieved from inside or outside the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, <PERSON> O'Brien </PERSON> said. Unauthorized computer access is illegal, he added. Thousands of computers are linked to the network at hundreds of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and foreign universities and research centers, including military research centers and other <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aeronautics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Space </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> offices, he said. <PERSON> O'Brien </PERSON> described it as a non-classified network for sharing scientific information. The network, named ARPANET, is operated by the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Advanced </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Projects </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION>. He said he considered the incident serious because programs used to design microcircuits could have been damaged and because `` if someone burglarizes my house, I'm offended. If someone accesses my computer, I'm equally offended.'' `` The <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> regards as serious any attempt to gain unauthorized access to its computer systems,'' <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman <PERSON> Susan </PERSON> <PERSON> Hansen </PERSON> said in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. `` Let me assure you, however, that there is no indication that any classified information has been obtained by such hacker activity.'' The break-in was the third known violation of computer security at the Jet Propulsion Laboratory in two years, <PERSON> O'Brien </PERSON> said. He cited a previously publicized August 1986 break-in by a West German hacker, or computer buff, and another last summer, in which the perpetrator was caught but not prosecuted. <PERSON> O'Brien </PERSON> said the hacker in last month's incident first gained access to the Pentagon network through another computer at an undisclosed location. Once inside, the hacker guessed a password _ the name of a <ORGANIZATION> JPL </ORGANIZATION> employee _ to enter the lab's computer, he added. The hacker then used the <ORGANIZATION> JPL </ORGANIZATION> computer as a conduit to enter another ARPANET computer at <LOCATION> Patuxent </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Naval </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Air </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Station </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION>, where authorities noticed something was amiss and notified the Jet Propulsion Laboratory, <PERSON> O'Brien </PERSON> said. He added that he did n't know how many other computers also were penetrated. The lab's chief spokesman, <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON>, initially said members of the <ORGANIZATION> Chaos </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Computer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Club </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Hamburg </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, broke into the <ORGANIZATION> Digital </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Equipment </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> computer at the laboratory, but he later retracted the statement. `` We do n't know for a fact that it was Chaos. ... There are things that make us suspicious, but the bottom line fact is we do n't know,'' <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON> said. `` They're not kids,'' <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON> said of the club's members. `` They're adults. They are a worrisome group to American computer experts. They're not just hackers doing pranks. They are group whose motives and aims are not entirely clear.'' A spokesman for the club told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Bonn </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, that he was unaware of the break-in, but would check into the matter further. `` One thing I can tell you with absolute certainty is they -LRB- the hackers -RRB- did n't get into any classified data banks nor did they get into any sensitive information in the lab,'' <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON> said that as soon as the break-in was discovered, `` we pulled <ORGANIZATION> JPL </ORGANIZATION> out of the network.'' Several days after the break-in, <ORGANIZATION> Digital </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Equipment </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> JPL </ORGANIZATION> officials `` rebuilt the system to make sure that if they -LRB- hackers -RRB- planted any viruses, we were not going to continue using the operating system they had been mucking around with,'' he said. A computer virus is a program surreptitiously inserted into a computer to disrupt its normal program. In April, a West German prosecutor revealed that a 24-year-old West German hacker linked his home computer to about 50 <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military computers by telephone. The electronic break-ins were detected in August 1986. Targets included computers at <ORGANIZATION> JPL </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Systems </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Command </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Segundo </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, and at the <ORGANIZATION> Lawrence </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Berkeley </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Laboratory </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Berkeley </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif </LOCATION>. In September, members of <ORGANIZATION> Chaos </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Computer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Club </ORGANIZATION> announced that youths who were n't club members used home computers to break into a <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> computer information network used by at least nine nations, and that they obtained secrets about the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> space program. The club said the hackers gained regular access to at least 20 <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> computers between May and September 1987 through a flaw in the security system. At the time, <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> officials in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> denied that secret information had been obtained through its computer network.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880616-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-PX-06-16-88 0033EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Obit-Velasquez     06-16 0271</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Obit-Velasquez,0279</SECOND>
<HEAD>Hispanic Organizer Dead Of Cancer</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID SEDENO</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SAN ANTONIO, Texas (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Willie </PERSON> <PERSON> Velasquez </PERSON>, who dedicated his career to increasing Hispanic political power, died Wednesday after a bout with cancer, officials said. He was 44. <PERSON> Velasquez </PERSON>, 44, president of the non-profit <ORGANIZATION> Southwest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Voter </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Registration </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Education </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Project </ORGANIZATION> he helped found in 1972, died at 12:55 a.m. at <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rosa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION>, said spokeswoman <PERSON> Terrie </PERSON> <PERSON> Carter </PERSON>. SVREP initially focused on voter registration and later, with other organizations, sued local governments to convert from at-large voting systems to single-member districts to assure equal Hispanic representation. <PERSON> Velasquez </PERSON>, who was diagnosed with a cancerous left kidney, was admitted to the hospital Monday. He had received treatment at M.D. <LOCATION> Anderson </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION> last month and was to begin chemotherapy within weeks. <PERSON> Velasquez </PERSON>' nonpartisan efforts helped to increase Hispanic voter registration, which has increased from 2.5 million in 1976 to an expected 5 million for the general election in November. <PERSON> Velasquez </PERSON> was a founder of the activist <ORGANIZATION> Mexican-American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Youth </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> and later became a coordinator of <ORGANIZATION> El </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Movimiento </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Social </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> de </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> la </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Raza </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Unida </ORGANIZATION>, before it became the Chicano political party. While in his last semester of graduate school of economics at <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mary </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> in 1968, <PERSON> Velasquez </PERSON> was recruited by the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Farm </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Workers </ORGANIZATION> to organize a strike in the <LOCATION> Rio </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Grande </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION>. After the strike, he became director of the <ORGANIZATION> Mexican-American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Unity </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Antonio </LOCATION> and in June 1970, field director in <LOCATION> Phoenix </LOCATION> of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> La </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Raza </ORGANIZATION>, parent organization of the <ORGANIZATION> Mexican-American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Unity </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Velasquez </PERSON> is survived by his wife, <PERSON> Jane </PERSON>; two daughters and a son.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880616-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-16-88 2349EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-BoatRescue     06-16 0305</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Boat Rescue,0313</SECOND>
<HEAD>Five Costa Rican Fisherman Rescued After Five Months Adrift</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By STEVE ELLIOTT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>HONOLULU (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Five Costa Rican fishermen drifted 3,600 miles in five months after their boat ran out of fuel, surviving on rainwater and fish until their rescue 700 miles southeast of <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> said Thursday. `` We ate anything that came near our boat, such as fish, turtles and sharks,'' <PERSON> Joel </PERSON> <PERSON> Omar </PERSON> <PERSON> Gonzalez </PERSON>, one of the fishermen, told the <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION>. `` We got water because it rained a few days and we managed to fill a lot of empty cans we had on board our boat.'' The Kinei Maru 128, a Japanese tuna boat, spotted the 30-foot Cadiro 3 adrift 700 miles southeast of <LOCATION> Honolulu </LOCATION> on Wednesday. The tuna boat rescued the men and left the Cadiro 3 drifting, said <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Jeff </PERSON> <PERSON> Crawley </PERSON>. The Cadiro 3 set out Jan. 19 from <LOCATION> Puntarenas </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Costa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rica </LOCATION>, for an eight-day fishing trip, he said. `` A storm came upon us so we started heading for shore, but the winds were too strong and they pulled us out to sea,'' <PERSON> Gonzalez </PERSON> said. `` We ran out of deisel and have been adrift ever since then.'' <PERSON> Crawley </PERSON> said as the boat drifted across the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ocean </LOCATION>, the men ate anything they could catch. `` We survived by throwing over bait which we had for our fishing trip,'' <PERSON> Gonzalez </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Crawley </PERSON> said the fishermen communicated with the <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> via the tuna boat's radio. All five were reported in good conditon. <PERSON> Crawley </PERSON> identified the other sailors as captain <PERSON> Gerardo </PERSON> <PERSON> Obregon </PERSON> <PERSON> Orando </PERSON>, <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Fernandez </PERSON> <PERSON> Castillo </PERSON>, Pastor <PERSON> Lopez </PERSON> <PERSON> Rojas </PERSON> and <PERSON> Juan </PERSON> <PERSON> Cernas </PERSON> <PERSON> Bolivar </PERSON>. The <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> did not have the men's ages. The Kinei Maru 128, which sails out of <LOCATION> Iwate </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, was scheduled to arrive in <LOCATION> Honolulu </LOCATION> on Friday morning, <PERSON> Crawley </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880616-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-PX-06-16-88 0039EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Deaths 1stLd-Writethru a0852 06-16 0518</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Deaths, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0852,0532</SECOND>
<NOTE>Eds: ADDS Beach Palmer and Billings; Separates moved for AMs as
a0404 on Velasquez and as a0839 on Hoyman.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Willie Velasquez</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SAN ANTONIO, Texas (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Willie </PERSON> <PERSON> Velasquez </PERSON>, whose 16-year effort to increase Hispanic voter registration led to the ethnic group becoming a viable political force, died Wednesday of cancer. He was 44. In 1972, <PERSON> Velasquez </PERSON> helped found the SVREP, a non-profit organization that initially sought to register Hispanic voters and later, with other organizations, sued local governments to convert from at-large voting systems to single-member districts to assure equal Hispanic representation. He gained politicians' respect for his unpartisan effort to increase Hispanic voter registration, which has increased from 2.5 million in 1976 to an expected 5 million for the general election in November.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>Vincent Hoyman</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BELLEVUE, Wash. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Vincent </PERSON> <PERSON> Hoyman </PERSON>, a veteran <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> newsman who retired in 1968 after 38 years with the news service, died Thursday at age 83. <PERSON> Hoyman </PERSON> worked at the <LOCATION> Des </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Moines </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>., <ORGANIZATION> Tribune </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Capital </ORGANIZATION> before joining the AP in <PERSON> Pierre </PERSON> He transferred to the <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION> bureau in 1937. <PERSON> Hoyman </PERSON> was named news editor in <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION> in 1939, a post he held until his retirement. After his retirement he was manager of the <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Election </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> for <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> state for several years.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>Frank Beach</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BERKELEY, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Frank A. Beach, a pioneer in animal behavior research and a emeritus professor of psychology at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> California-Berkeley </ORGANIZATION>, died Wednesday. He was 77. Beach was a highly acclaimed researcher in the fields of behavorial endocrinology and animal behavior for more than four decades. He was a member of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sciences </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Philosophical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION>. Beach joined the UC faculty in 1958, attaining emeritus status in 1978. His major research had concentrated on the neural and endocrinological controls of sexual behavior, resulting in a crucial body of research results, books and articles.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>Fred Palmer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PENSACOLA, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> Palmer </PERSON>, managing editor of the <ORGANIZATION> Pensacola </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Journal </ORGANIZATION> since 1986, died Wednesday at age 38. <PERSON> Palmer </PERSON> was a reporter for the <LOCATION> Johnson </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Tenn. </LOCATION>, Press-Chronicle from 1969 to 1971. He left to work at <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Roanoke </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> for two years, then returned to the Press-Chronicle. <PERSON> Palmer </PERSON> was Press-Chronicle wire editor for a year, then was promoted to managing editor, a position he held for 10 years. In 1983 he joined the <LOCATION> Rockford </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ill. </LOCATION>, Register Star, first as city editor, then as assistant managing editor-news. He left the Register Star for the position at the <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Journal </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>James Billings</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SPRINGFIELD, Mo. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Hopkins </PERSON> <PERSON> Billings </PERSON>, whose career as a journalist for <LOCATION> Springfield </LOCATION> newspapers spanned nearly five decades, died Tuesday. He was 78. Billings worked for the <ORGANIZATION> Springfield </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Memphis </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Tenn. </LOCATION>, before becoming a page editor with the <ORGANIZATION> Springfield </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Leader </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>. Over the years he worked in public relations and for a local weekly news magazine, The Bias. Billings was news editor of The <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Journal </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Coffeyville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Kan. </LOCATION>, for two years before returning to the Leader & amp; Press in 1957.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880616-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-PX-06-16-88 0010EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-AIDSRdp Bjt   06-16 0873</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AIDS Rdp, Bjt,0897</SECOND>
<HEAD>Study: AIDS Carriers Show No Mental Problems Until Symptoms
Develop</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: LEAD expected about 8 a.m. EDT</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By PAUL RAEBURN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Science Editor</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>STOCKHOLM, Sweden (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 People infected with the AIDS virus show no sign of mental problems until they develop physical symptoms associated with the deadly disease, a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government study shows. `` We're not seeing any difference whatsoever in terms of a number of psychological measures known to be sensitive to virtually any form of brain damage,'' said one of the study's authors, Dr. <PERSON> Ola </PERSON> <PERSON> Selnes </PERSON>, a psychologist at the <ORGANIZATION> Johns </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hopkins </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institutions </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Baltimore </LOCATION>. He presented the findings Wednesday at the <ORGANIZATION> Fourth </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conference </ORGANIZATION> on AIDS. Also at the meeting, Dr. <PERSON> Jonas </PERSON> <PERSON> Salk </PERSON>, the polio vaccine pioneer, described his first efforts toward an AIDS vaccine. In a separate report, Dr. <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Zagury </PERSON>, the daring French scientist who in 1986 injected himself with an experimental AIDS vaccine of his own devising, said that with booster shots he has developed antibodies that might be capable of destroying the AIDS virus. And in a study of the distribution of clean needles and syringes to drug addicts in <LOCATION> Amsterdam </LOCATION>, researchers said they found that such a program does not encourage drug abuse and may well reduce the transmission of acquired immune deficiency syndrome. The AIDS virus attacks the body's immune system, leaving victims susceptible to a wide variety of infections and cancers. AIDS is most often transmitted through sexual contact. Other means of transmission include transfusions of tainted blood or blood products, and the sharing of contaminated hypodermic needles or syringes by drug abusers. AIDS can also be passed from mother to child at or before birth. The study by <PERSON> Selnes </PERSON> and Dr. <PERSON> Justin </PERSON> <PERSON> McArthur </PERSON>, also of <PERSON> Hopkins </PERSON>, was intended to resolve questions raised by earlier studies that had found distinct mental problems, such as loss of memory and mental slowness, in people infected with the AIDS virus. Those changes sometimes seemed to appear before any other signs of AIDS infection. As a result, concern was expressed that people in sensitive jobs, such as airline pilots, nuclear reactor operators or operators of heavy industrial equipment, should be removed from their positions if they become infected with the AIDS virus, even if they are not outwardly sick. `` Based on our results, we do not feel there is any cause for alarm or concern,'' <PERSON> Selnes </PERSON> said. The study was sponsored by the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Allergy </ORGANIZATION> and Infectious Diseases. The debate involves whether mental problems appear early in the course of infection, before other diseases strike. There is general agreement that about 70 percent of those who die of AIDS have significant mental and neurological problems after other symptoms develop, according to a report released in March by the <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION>. That report concluded that there was no evidence for mental or neurological problems in otherwise healthy people infected with the AIDS virus. <PERSON> Selnes </PERSON> and <PERSON> McArthur </PERSON> followed 201 people for two years. Eighty-two were uninfected with the AIDS virus, 88 had been infected for a long time and 31 had been infected for a relatively brief period. The patients were examined every six months with a variety of psychological tests, and no differences were seen between the infected and uninfected subjects, <PERSON> Selnes </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Salk </PERSON> said in a report on his vaccine research that he has completed the first human trials of an unusual vaccine intended to keep infected people from developing AIDS. He said he had given the vaccine to nine men with ARC, or AIDS-related complex, an AIDS-like disease that can progress to AIDS. The vaccine appears safe, he said. It also appears to raise levels of immune system cells, and in one of the subjects the virus seemed to disappear completely. That has persuaded <PERSON> Salk </PERSON> to continue trials with 54 AIDS-infected people who have not yet developed AIDS or ARC. In a separate report, Zagury, a <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Paris </ORGANIZATION> scientist, said his administration of an experimental vaccine to himself in 1986 had enhanced his body's production of antibodies against the AIDS virus. The vaccine consisted of a specially modified smallpox virus containing a portion of the AIDS virus. He gave himself booster shots of his own blood cells, which he had extracted and infected with the same type of modified virus before reinjecting them. He said his body has produced high levels of AIDS antibodies, some of which may be capable of neutralizing the AIDS virus. <PERSON> Ernest </PERSON> <PERSON> Buning </PERSON>, a psychologist with the <ORGANIZATION> Amsterdam </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Municipal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>, said that four years of providing clean syringes and needles to drug addicts in the Dutch city has produced a significant drop in needle sharing and may have helped curb AIDS spread. The needle exchange program gave health workers an opportunity to tell addicts how to lower their AIDS risk, and that counselling was a critical component of the exchange program, said <PERSON> Buning </PERSON>. `` Our conclusion is that the needle and syringe exchange helps addicts to use drugs safely,'' he said. Furthermore, he said, the program did not lead to increased drug use, as critics of such programs had feared. The first <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> needle exchange program will begin soon in <LOCATION> Portland </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ore. </LOCATION>, under the sponsorship of the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION> for AIDS Research.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880616-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-PX-06-16-88 0046EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-APArts:Fridaythe13th     06-16 0926</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AP Arts: Friday the 13th,0945</SECOND>
<HEAD>`Friday the 13th': There's Gold In Them Thar Killings</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By BOB THOMAS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Amid all the hoopla over <PERSON> Mick </PERSON> <PERSON> Dundee </PERSON>, <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Rambo </PERSON>, <PERSON> Willow </PERSON> <PERSON> Ufgood </PERSON> and other heroes of the new film season, the infamous <PERSON> Jason </PERSON> might be overlooked. Not by <ORGANIZATION> Paramount </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pictures </ORGANIZATION>. `` ` Friday the 13th' is a gold mine that keeps on rolling along,'' declares <PERSON> Sidney </PERSON> <PERSON> Ganis </PERSON>, president of worldwide marketing for Paramount. The studio reports that the first six films in the series have grossed over $ 172 million, not to mention the big videocassette sales, cable TV, syndication and a TV series. In its first 18 days, `` Friday the 13th Part VII _ The New Blood'' sold almost $ 16 million worth of tickets in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>. Since the film cost $ 3.5 million _ about 1\18th the budget of `` Rambo III'' _ it should already be solidly in the black. `` Part VII'' profited by premiering on Friday the 13th of May; the series always does better business when released on that fateful day. `` <PERSON> Jason </PERSON> has become part of the vernacular,'' <PERSON> Ganis </PERSON> said. `` Why? I think because he is genuinely frightening, and teen-agers genuinely love to be frightened. My own daughter loved ` Friday the 13th III.' Now she has seen ` VII' and then she goes to see -LRB- the more arty -RRB- ` The Moderns.' A whole generation has grown up on <PERSON> Jason </PERSON> and keeps going back.'' <PERSON> Jason </PERSON> began his rampageous career quite modestly in 1980, in a low-budget thriller created by producer-director <PERSON> Sean </PERSON> <PERSON> Cunningham </PERSON>. Ironically, <PERSON> Cunningham </PERSON> devised the title when he was planning a children's television show. He figured it might work for the title of a feature film, and he was right. `` Friday the 13th'' grossed an amazing $ 40 million. <PERSON> Cunningham </PERSON>, who is now filming another horror film, `` Deep Six,'' signed over his rights to <ORGANIZATION> Paramount </ORGANIZATION>, and the series has had five other directors. The formula remains the same as in the original, which starred <PERSON> Kevin </PERSON> <PERSON> Bacon </PERSON>, later of `` Footloose'' fame, <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> Crosby </PERSON>, son of <PERSON> Bing </PERSON>, and <PERSON> Betsy </PERSON> <PERSON> Palmer </PERSON> as <PERSON> Jason </PERSON>'s mother. The action _ lots of it _ always takes place at <LOCATION> Camp </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Crystal </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Jason </PERSON> returns from the dead, wearing a hockey mask and wielding an ax to pay back a grudge. Many years ago when he was a camper he drowned in the lake because his inattentive counselors were making love in the bushes. <PERSON> Jason </PERSON>'s vengeance is wreaked upon the human race in general, with special emphasis on oversexed counselors. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Carl </PERSON> <PERSON> Buechler </PERSON>, a special effects expert who became a director -LRB- `` Troll,'' `` Cellar Dweller'' -RRB-, directed `` Friday the 13th VII'' from a script by <PERSON> Daryl </PERSON> <PERSON> Haney </PERSON>. <PERSON> Buechler </PERSON> -LRB- pronounced Beekler -RRB- says he saw possibilities of applying two new twists to the same saga. `` One, I thought it would be good to have a main character in the story, someone the audience could cry and cheer for, and follow her through the nightmare world,'' he said. `` She is the teen-ager -LRB- <LOCATION> Lar </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Park </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lincoln </LOCATION> -RRB- whose special powers release <PERSON> Jason </PERSON> from his grave at the bottom of the lake. Telling the story from one person's viewpoint had only been done once before -LRB- in Part V -RRB-. `` Two, I added a substantial element of the supernatural. Before Part VII, <PERSON> Jason </PERSON> was a mindless man who jumped out of closets and killed people. Since he was resurrected by electricity in Part VI, he was now, practically speaking, a ghost. That made him a virtually unstoppable humanoid. `` So I thought it would be fun to fill the last two reels with false endings. I wanted the audience to say, ` Oh, he's up, now he's down, he's dead No, he's up again!' My aim was more fantasy than reality.'' Even with the innovations, <PERSON> Buechler </PERSON> was careful not to tamper too much with the `` Friday the 13th'' formula. `` I was hired to satisfy the producers; if I was hired to do a <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Bond </PERSON> picture, I would certainly follow the Bond formula,'' he said. `` Friday the 13th VII'' inevitably found disfavor with the ratings board of the <ORGANIZATION> Motion </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Picture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION>, which immediately branded the film with an X for extreme <PERSON> gore </PERSON>. This would have made the movie unsalable since a film rated X prevents anyone under age 17 from being admitted to the theater. Like <PERSON> Jason </PERSON>, though, the filmmakers kept coming back again and again with new cuts. `` They gave us an X six times until we finally got an R,'' <PERSON> Buechler </PERSON> said. `` I understand ` Robocop' holds the record at eight.'' Stunt man <PERSON> Kane </PERSON> <PERSON> Hodder </PERSON> is the seventh portrayer of <PERSON> Jason </PERSON>, which might seem a thankless acting job since he does n't speak and is hidden behind a mask. <PERSON> Hodder </PERSON> does n't agree. `` I've always wanted to play that character ever since the first film,'' says <PERSON> Hodder </PERSON>, who has coordinated stunts for `` House,'' `` Ghost Town'' and other thrillers. `` I've always believed that he should be played by a stunt man. `` I think <PERSON> Jason </PERSON> is more of a challenge because he has no dialogue. I tried to get across the feeling of menace just by using certain head movements and body movements.'' If the `` Friday the 13th'' films are stiumlating to teen-agers, they are an ordeal for reviewers, whose vituperation has no apparent effect on the audience. `` Critics hate the movies,'' <PERSON> Buechler </PERSON> said, `` but surprisingly, we've had mixed reviews on VII. The common pattern is for the reviewer to comment that <PERSON> Jason </PERSON> is here to stay, then to review the previous one in the series and conclude, ` If you liked them, you'll like this one.'
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880616-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-PX-06-16-88 0049EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-APArts:JasonPlots     06-16 1051</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AP Arts: Jason Plots,1071</SECOND>
<HEAD>You Can't Keep a Good Man Down</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</NOTE>
<HEAD>With PM-AP Arts: Friday the 13th</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DOLORES BARCLAY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Arts Editor</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 What a groovy guy that <PERSON> Jason </PERSON> <PERSON> Voorhees </PERSON> is _ ahead of his time with that goalie mask fashion look, and ever so creative with axes, knives and spears. He's a real human slice-and-dice machine, but not not too many people like him. Still, they flock to see his movies _ seven so far _ and he does n't even have a speaking part. Here's a look at <PERSON> Jason </PERSON>'s life and death and life and death in the `` Friday the 13th'' sagas:
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 _ `` Friday the 13th'' -LRB- 1980 -RRB-: Six frisky camp counselors reopen <ORGANIZATION> Camp </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Crystal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lake </ORGANIZATION>, which has been closed for over two decades after a rash of unsolved murders. A seventh, who hitchhikes to the camp, never quite makes it: She's turned into a forest pizza The other college-age dimwits romp about until they, too, are carved into human kindling. <PERSON> Alice </PERSON>, the last of the lot, runs into Mrs. <PERSON> Voorhees </PERSON> who lives nearby. She promises to drive the hysterical girl to safety but instead talks about her son, <PERSON> Jason </PERSON>, who drowned years ago while his counselors made love in the woods. She turns on <PERSON> Alice </PERSON> with a hatchet; <PERSON> Alice </PERSON> finally decapitates the madwoman and makes her way to a canoe which drifts to the middle of the lake. In a blink, the drowned <PERSON> Jason </PERSON> reaches up from his watery hell and grabs her. <PERSON> Alice </PERSON> abruptly awakens in a hospital room to be told by police that <PERSON> Jason </PERSON>'s body was never found. <PERSON> Alice </PERSON> says: `` Then he's still there.''
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 _ `` Friday the 13th Part 2'' -LRB- 1981 -RRB-: A new batch of hot-blooded morons begin counselor training at <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Region </LOCATION>, near <LOCATION> Camp </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Crystal </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION>. The camp leader, <PERSON> Paul </PERSON>, talks about <PERSON> Jason </PERSON> _ an icon by now _ and says he's really alive, living off wild animals and waiting to avenge his mother's death. One by one, and two by two the randy counselors-to-be encounter <PERSON> Jason </PERSON>, who enthusiastically dispatches his victims with a curved machete, a spear thrust through two bodies, a hammer. Finally, only <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> and his girlfriend, <PERSON> Ginny </PERSON>, are left. Thinking <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> dead, <PERSON> Ginny </PERSON> tries to flee. She ends up at <PERSON> Jason </PERSON>'s cabin where she finds a shrine to his dead mother containing her decapitated head. <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> shows up, struggles with <PERSON> Jason </PERSON>, and <PERSON> Ginny </PERSON> slices up the `` dead'' boy's body with the machete. <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> and <PERSON> Ginny </PERSON> return to the cabin, and <PERSON> Jason </PERSON> crashes through the window. <PERSON> Ginny </PERSON> wakes up in an ambulance. `` Where's <PERSON> Paul </PERSON>?'' she asks.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 _ `` Friday the 13th Part 3 _ 3-D'' -LRB- 1982 -RRB-: Yet another group of idiots heads for the lake, amid newscasts of mass murders. Three bikers show up to taunt them and are promptly dispatched by our <PERSON> Jason </PERSON>, who picks off the vacationing college kids with his usual finesse: He shoots an arrow through a head, cleaves a body, electrocutes one guy, slits a neck, thrusts a hot fireplace poker through a chest. As usual, one hysterical female is left, <PERSON> Chris </PERSON>. After a struggle, she imbeds an ax in <PERSON> Jason </PERSON>'s head, runs to the lake and paddles a canoe to the center _ silly girl. When she awakens in the morning, Mrs. <PERSON> Vorhees </PERSON>' body, dripping with rotted flesh, explodes from the water and pulls <PERSON> Chris </PERSON> under. Police take a deranged <PERSON> Chris </PERSON> away and we catch one last -LRB-? -RRB- glimpse of <PERSON> Jason </PERSON>, the ax still rooted in his skull, his fingers twitching.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 _ `` Friday the 13th _ The Final Chapter'' -LRB- 1984 -RRB-: Ten people have been slaughtered at <ORGANIZATION> Crystal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lake </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Jason </PERSON> also lies dead. The bodies are taken to the morgue where <PERSON> Jason </PERSON>, perky as ever, rises up, slits the throat of an attendant and guts a nurse. Back at the lake, Mrs. <PERSON> Jarvis </PERSON> and her two children, <PERSON> Trish </PERSON> and <PERSON> Tommy </PERSON>, are in their summer home. A group of teen-agers has moved in next door. The party's soon over, though, as they're harpooned, crucified, hacksawed and otherwise minced. But <PERSON> Tommy </PERSON> is a horror freak who has a makeup collection, masks and clippings about <PERSON> Jason </PERSON>. He saves his sister and himself by putting on a hockey mask, confusing <PERSON> Jason </PERSON> and grabbing the machete. <PERSON> Tommy </PERSON> whacks his personal hero again, and again and again.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 _ `` Friday the 13th _ A New Beginning'' -LRB- 1985 -RRB-: <PERSON> Tommy </PERSON> <PERSON> Jarvis </PERSON> is now 18 and has nightmares about <PERSON> Jason </PERSON>. He lives at a halfway house after being released from a mental institution. Then the murders begin with axes, hunting knives and hedge shears as the weapons du jour. Finally, <PERSON> Tommy </PERSON> comes face to face with <PERSON> Jason </PERSON> who falls from a hayloft onto the steel spike teeth of a tractor harrow. Rain washes away makeup from the corpse's face and reveals the killer as a paramedic pretending to be <PERSON> Jason </PERSON>. <PERSON> Tommy </PERSON>, who still has nightmares, is back in the hospital. He smiles knowingly, pulls a hockey mask from his bureau, hides behind the door and waits.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 _ `` Friday the 13th Part VI _ Jason Lives'' -LRB- 1986 -RRB-: <ORGANIZATION> Crystal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lake </ORGANIZATION> has changed its name to <LOCATION> Forest </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Green </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Tommy </PERSON> <PERSON> Jarvis </PERSON> is now an adult and still haunted. He believes that the only way he ever have a normal life is to make sure <PERSON> Jason </PERSON> is REALLY dead. So he returns to <ORGANIZATION> Crystal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lake </ORGANIZATION> to see <PERSON> Jason </PERSON>'s grave. He pries open the coffin during a storm, and a bolt of lightning hits the crowbar he's used, sending a charge through the decayed corpse. The rejuvenated <PERSON> Jason </PERSON> works his way back to the lake leaving a trail of blood and guts. <PERSON> Tommy </PERSON> follows him, lures him to the lake and somehow traps <PERSON> Jason </PERSON> in chains and rocks so that he sinks to his original watery grave.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 _ `` Friday the 13th Part VII _ The New Blood'' -LRB- 1988 -RRB-: <PERSON> Tina </PERSON> <PERSON> Shepard </PERSON> is telekinetic. While at <ORGANIZATION> Crystal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lake </ORGANIZATION>, her father dies and she tries to bring him back. Instead, she accidentally brings back <PERSON> Jason </PERSON>, who sets about doing what he does best. Ultimately, <PERSON> Jason </PERSON> and <PERSON> Tina </PERSON> face off. Only this time when she does some fancy brain work, she brings back her dead father, who struggles with <PERSON> Jason </PERSON> and pulls him back to the depths of the lake, where they set up housekeeping together until the next time?
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880616-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-PX-06-16-88 0050EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-APArts:JasonActors     06-16 0450</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AP Arts: Jason Actors,0457</SECOND>
<HEAD>Seven Jasons Have Donned the Hockey Mask</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</NOTE>
<HEAD>With PM-AP Arts: Friday the 13th</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DOLORES BARCLAY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Arts Editor</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 It's not exactly a role actors would kill for, but kill indeed they do. Seven men have portrayed <PERSON> Jason </PERSON> <PERSON> Voorhees </PERSON>, the masked and multilated corpse who refuses to stay dead in the seven `` Friday the 13th'' movies. The Jasons have ranged from a professional trapeze artist to a nightclub manager who had no acting experience: 1. <PERSON> Ari </PERSON> <PERSON> Lehman </PERSON> was 14 when he launched <PERSON> Jason </PERSON>'s blood binge in `` Friday the 13th.'' In the movie that made sequels a thriving business, he's only seen in two scenes: a flashback when <PERSON> Jason </PERSON> drowns as a child in <ORGANIZATION> Crystal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lake </ORGANIZATION>, and at the end of the film when his rotting corpse rises from the lake to grab the lone survivor of his mother's murder rampage. Now in his 20s, <PERSON> Lehman </PERSON> has left acting and plays with a funk-rock band. 2. <ORGANIZATION> Warrington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Gillette </ORGANIZATION>, the evil killer in `` Part 2,'' majored in economics at <ORGANIZATION> Villanova </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. He studied acting with <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Strasberg </PERSON> in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> before going to <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> where he joined the <ORGANIZATION> Hollywood </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Stunt </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Man </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>. He's worked in comedy workshops, did a movie documentary on <LOCATION> Saratoga </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION>, and has appeared on the TV soap opera, `` General Hospital.'' 3. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Brooker </PERSON>, <PERSON> Jason </PERSON> in the 3D version, is a professional trapeze artist who has appeared in cirucuses throughout the world. He also does high wire, juggles and works on the trampoline. He studied acting at such theater companies as The Stage and <LOCATION> Riverside </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Studio </LOCATION> and has appeared in commercials. 4. <PERSON> Ted </PERSON> <PERSON> White </PERSON>, a stunt man and actor who played <PERSON> Jason </PERSON> in `` Part IV,'' had never seen a `` Friday the 13th'' movie. His credits include `` The Creature From the Black Lagoon.'' 5. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Wieand </PERSON>, who plays a paramedic posing as <PERSON> Jason </PERSON> in `` Part V,'' does soap operas and commercials. In an interview with <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> magazine </ORGANIZATION>, he talked about his audition for the part: `` The director told me to stare at an empty desk and react as if I saw my son laying there hacked to bits.'' 6. <PERSON> C.J </PERSON>. <PERSON> Graham </PERSON>, who managed a nightclub, was the sixth <PERSON> Jason </PERSON>. He got the part after portraying <PERSON> Jason </PERSON> for a club performance by an illusionist who was a friend of the company that did special effects for the `` Friday the 13th'' movies. He suggested <PERSON> Graham </PERSON>, who had no acting experience, as the next <PERSON> Jason </PERSON>. 7. <PERSON> Kane </PERSON> <PERSON> Hodder </PERSON>, a stunt coordinator, stunt man and actor, has performed stunts in over 25 movies and more than 40 TV shows. He might be the last <PERSON> Jason </PERSON>, but who knows?
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880616-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-PX-06-16-88 0053EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Bakker'sBack     06-16 0844</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bakker's Back,0868</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bakker: I'm Staying Until I Get PTL Back</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By PAUL NOWELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>FORT MILL, S.C. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Sitting in his tiny store-front office just down the street from the sprawling grounds of <ORGANIZATION> Heritage </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> USA </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON> predicted he would soon regain control of the <ORGANIZATION> PTL </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION>. `` God does n't take you halfway and dump you,'' said <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON>, who resigned from the television ministry last year in the wake of a sex scandal and is under investigation by a federal grand jury. `` I've been building this place for 15 years. I'm staying until I get it back.'' Even the ever-optimistic <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON> admitted it will be an uphill climb for him and his wife, <PERSON> Tammy </PERSON> <PERSON> Faye </PERSON>, to get back PTL. They intend to present a reorganization plan for the Christian retreat in <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bankruptcy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> S.C. </LOCATION>, before June 29. `` We are also placing an advertisement in a local newspaper asking all former employees who are interested in being a part of the <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> and <PERSON> Tammy </PERSON> ministry to come to the office and fill out a form,'' he said Wednesday. `` These are not job applications; it's just a survey to see how many are interested. Bankruptcy Judge <PERSON> Rufus </PERSON> <PERSON> Reynolds </PERSON> has already told <ORGANIZATION> PTL </ORGANIZATION> officials to sell land, buildings and other assets to raise enough money to settle claims against the ministry that could reach $ 130 million. Last month, <ORGANIZATION> PTL </ORGANIZATION> officials worked out a deal with businessman <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Shinn </PERSON> calling for <PERSON> Shinn </PERSON> to buy all or most of <ORGANIZATION> PTL </ORGANIZATION>'s property at <ORGANIZATION> Heritage </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> USA </ORGANIZATION> and lease parts of the ministry to a new church. <PERSON> Shinn </PERSON>, who owns <ORGANIZATION> Charlotte </ORGANIZATION>'s new <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Basketball </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> franchise and a minor league baseball team, has declined to say how much he will offer for the complex. Estimates have ranged from $ 75 million to $ 100 million. M.C. `` Red'' <PERSON> Benton </PERSON>, the court-appointed trustee at <ORGANIZATION> PTL </ORGANIZATION>, has said there are several other offers and vowed to treat any proposal from <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON> fairly. `` I'm more convinced at this moment that we will be back at <LOCATION> Heritage </LOCATION> <LOCATION> USA </LOCATION> than at any time in nearly a year and a half,'' said <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON>, adding that he hopes to buy some television time to promote his plan. <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON> returned to <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> in early June and opened an office in a shopping mall next door to the headquarters of the `` Bring Back Bakkers'' club. `` I've yet to meet a negative person,'' <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON> said in an interview Monday in his office decorated with photographs of him and <PERSON> Tammy </PERSON>. `` We came here psychologically prepared for battle. But people have been coming up to us in the restaurants and on the street to give us their support.'' Since his return, <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON> said, a car dealer gave him a new car and other offers have been made. `` They told me they only have one question, ` What can we do to get <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> and <PERSON> Tammy </PERSON> back?''' he said. `` Never before have I had such an outward expression of support from local business people.'' Not all business owners share that sentiment. `` There's still too much of a bad taste in people's mouths,'' said <PERSON> Sharon </PERSON> <PERSON> Haney </PERSON>, who owns a small leather shop across the street from <LOCATION> Heritage </LOCATION> <LOCATION> USA </LOCATION>. Several blocks away, <PERSON> Marge </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON>, who operates a craft shop, said, `` I do n't think <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> can make it work. So many people are so disgusted. I'm the first to forgive, but ...'' At <ORGANIZATION> Heritage </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> USA </ORGANIZATION>, the impact of the <ORGANIZATION> Bakkers </ORGANIZATION>' departure is apparent. The water slide is closed. Shuttle buses that transport visitors to the various attractions are nearly empty. Main Street, a collection of shops and restaurants, looks like a ghost town. The park's nearly 1,500 employees of a year ago have been cut by nearly two-thirds, to just over 500. `` The mood around here used to be a three-ring circus. Now it's like a cemetery,'' said <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Crisp </PERSON>, who has been coming to <ORGANIZATION> Heritage </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> USA </ORGANIZATION> from <LOCATION> Lenoir </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.C. </LOCATION>, with her husband for six years Still, she does n't know if she wants the <ORGANIZATION> Bakkers </ORGANIZATION> back. `` Everyone is deserving of a second chance, but they have to come back truly repentant,'' she said. `` The thing that disturbs me is when <PERSON> Tammy </PERSON> said, ` What did we do wrong?' That boggles my mind. What about the credit cards and selling Heritage three times over?'' The <ORGANIZATION> Bakkers </ORGANIZATION> also have their fervent supporters. `` No one can run this place like <PERSON> Jim </PERSON>,'' said <PERSON> Loretta </PERSON> <PERSON> Graves </PERSON>, of <LOCATION> Charlotte </LOCATION>, who stopped by during a break from job hunting. `` If God can forgive him, I can.'' <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON> declined to give details of his reorganization plan, and he wo n't identify any financial backers. `` We'll present a conservative plan without any pie-in-the-sky deals,'' he said. `` It's built on our track record of the past. I plan to restore it to where I left it and go beyond. `` I think we can help people because of what we've been through,'' <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON> said. `` They want to know, ` Does the Bible really work?' We've been through one of the most devastating times of just about any public figures in history.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880616-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-PX-06-16-88 0053EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Athens-Pollution     06-16 0720</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Athens-Pollution,0743</SECOND>
<HEAD>Athenians Fear Another Smog-Filled Summer</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in report for Thursday PMs.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By PATRICK QUINN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ATHENS, Greece (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The government says its campaign to reduce atmospheric pollution is working, but some among <LOCATION> Athen </LOCATION>'s 3.5 million people are not so sure. For years, the capital has been plagued by a brown layer of noxious smoke, exhaust fumes and factory emissions that Athenians call the `` nefos,'' Greek for cloud. On a warm windless day, the `` nefos'' sends an average of 300 Athenians to hospitals complaining of headaches, chest pains, nausea and stinging eyes. `` I drive around <LOCATION> Athens </LOCATION> all day and when I get home my nose is clogged and my hair is oily from the fumes,'' said <PERSON> Michalis </PERSON> <PERSON> Leontsakos </PERSON>, one of the city's 15,000 taxi drivers. `` And when summer hits, it's much worse.'' Last July a 10-day heatwave compounded the smog problem and more than 1,200 mostly poor and elderly Athenians died of heatstroke or breathing problems. Officials in Prime Minister <PERSON> Andreas </PERSON> <PERSON> Papandreou </PERSON>'s Socialist government maintain, however, that a new package of anti-smog measures is producing results and that last summer's high temperatures are unlikely to recur. `` The recent package has been particularly productive,'' Environment Minister <PERSON> Evangelos </PERSON> <PERSON> Kouloumbis </PERSON> said. `` We have had a 15 to 25 percent reduction in overall pollution levels.'' The smog forms over the mountain-ringed <LOCATION> Athens </LOCATION> basin on warm, still days. The sun heats up a layer of cold night air close to the ground and the air then rises into the lower atmosphere where it acts as a barrier that traps the warmer pollutants under it. The problem is aggravated by the lack of parks and green spaces in <LOCATION> Athens </LOCATION>' concrete sprawl. The city has just 23 square feet of greenery per resident, compared to 107 square feet in <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION>, 215 in <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Austria </LOCATION>, and 290 in <LOCATION> Amsterdam </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Netherlands </LOCATION>. Environmental scientists blame the city's 750,000 cars, diesel-powered taxis, buses and trucks for 75 percent of the smog. `` If you take away half the cars, you'd only have half the problem,'' said <PERSON> Dimitris </PERSON> <PERSON> Hadzidakis </PERSON>, a chemical engineer with the state-run pollution control program. `` Traffic would move faster and you'd have few engines idling.'' To cut down on traffic the government abolished <LOCATION> Greece </LOCATION>'s traditional split working day with its three-hour midday break Stores now stay open from 9 a.m. to 7 p.m. and the change eliminated two of the city's four rush hours. The new measures also ban half the city's taxis from the five-square mile city center on alternate days and have closed a two-square mile central commercial district to traffic. But despite the government claims, some people who work in the city center say they ca n't see much improvement. `` The nefos seems to be the same and fewer people shop in the afternoon hours because of the heat and smog,'' said <PERSON> Michalis </PERSON> <PERSON> Vitos </PERSON>, a shoe store clerk. `` The summer looks like its going to be worse and will definitely cut business.'' Half the city's private cars have been banned from the center on alternate days since 1984. Cars with license plates ending in even numbers drive on even-numbered days and vice versa. `` We think that updated cars burning unleaded gas must gradually replace <LOCATION> Athens </LOCATION>' current fleet of private automobiles,'' said Environment Minister <PERSON> Kouloumbis </PERSON>. But Greeks complain they ca n't afford to buy new cars because of import taxes that triple the basic price. <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> statistics indicate the average private car in <LOCATION> Athens </LOCATION> is 10 years old. The government's 1985 target of a 27 percent pollution reduction by 1990 is still on track, but it may take 20 more years to fully solve the problem, environment officials say. `` The trouble is the city's spreading faster that we can reduce the pollution ... and there are 30,000 more cars on the streets every year,'' said <PERSON> Hadzidakis </PERSON>, the chemical engineer. The government has banned low quality heating fuel and insists that filters be installed on <LOCATION> Athens </LOCATION>' 120 main industrial plants by the end of this year. But independent environmental researchers say the measures still are n't radical enough. `` To solve the pollution problem, you'd have to remove all industry from <LOCATION> Athens </LOCATION> ... and find some way to make at least 1 million Athenians move at least 30 kilometers -LRB- 19 miles -RRB- out of the city,'' said <PERSON> Panayiotis </PERSON> <PERSON> Christodoulakis </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> Panhellenic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ecological </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Studies </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880616-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-PX-06-16-88 0128EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-UN-MotherTeresa 1stLd-Writethru a0882 06-16 0406</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-UN-Mother Teresa, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0882,0409</SECOND>
<HEAD>Mother Teresa Tells U.N. Abortion Is Greatest Threat To Peace</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: SUBS 3rd graf, `Mother Teresa ...,' to CORRECT Mother
Teresa's title. PICKS up 4th graf, `The small ...'</NOTE>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY49</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PETER JAMES SPIELMANN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>UNITED NATIONS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Mother </PERSON> <PERSON> Teresa </PERSON> on Wednesday gave her best wishes to the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> conference on disarmament and gave delegates a new issue to ponder by saying `` abortion has become the greatest destroyer of peace.'' `` I think the world has never needed so much tender love as today,'' she told reporters after she met Secretary-General <PERSON> Javier </PERSON> <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Cuellar </PERSON> for a courtesy call. <PERSON> Mother </PERSON> <PERSON> Teresa </PERSON>, 77, works with and is the founder of the international <ORGANIZATION> Missionaries </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Charity </ORGANIZATION>, a religious order in <LOCATION> Calcutta </LOCATION>. She received the Nobel Peace Prize in 1979 for her work to ease the suffering of dying slum dwellers, and is known there as the `` saint of the gutters.'' The small, frail-looking woman, wearing a white cotton shawl and blue-trimmed robe, spoke fiercely against `` the evil of abortion, of destroying children, of neglecting children.'' `` We're fighting abortion by adoption, and we have saved thousands of children from being destroyed, because as you know abortion has become the greatest destroyer of peace because it destroys the child, the gift of God. And it destroys the conscience of the mother, it is actually a double killing.'' When asked if she discussed with <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Cuellar </PERSON> the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> population control programs, she said she had not. Many anti-abortion activists have criticized the programs, saying them promote abortion as a possible option. `` I think we talked of other things, that we did n't say,'' she replied. Another reporter asked her why the concept of non-violence does not seem to work in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>, where <PERSON> Mohandas </PERSON> <PERSON> K. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gandhi </PERSON> lived for 21 years and where Anglican Archbishop <PERSON> Desmond </PERSON> <PERSON> Tutu </PERSON>, the 1984 Nobel Peace Prize winner, carries on the tradition of peaceful civil disobedience today. <PERSON> Mother </PERSON> <PERSON> Teresa </PERSON> said `` non-violence begins at home,'' adding, `` Our government in <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> and the government of <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> have given us full permission to go to <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>. And we have a mixture of all nationalities, and I am going to take take with me different nationalities, different colors, and bring there with me the joy of loving.'' She said she was in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> to try to open a center to care for children infected with AIDS.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880616-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-PX-06-16-88 0131EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Bush-Drought     06-16 0704</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bush-Drought,680</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush Gets Much-Ballyhooed Drought Briefing; Says Rain Needed to
End It</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP News Analysis</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDS: stands for PM-Farm Scene</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By DON KENDALL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Farm Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 In the end, Vice President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s appearance at the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> for a drought briefing was outshone by a career federal meteorologist's description of the trouble spots and how they could worsen Reporters who had been herded into a room to look at the vice president, then herded out, ended up only with a written statement in which <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> declared that rain is needed to end the drought plaguing large portions of the country. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, accompanied by <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Minority Leader <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> and a White House entourage, met Wednesday for about half an hour in the office of <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Lyng </PERSON>. For a while, the placid atmosphere of the old <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> administration building was charged by the swarming of security forces assigned to protect the vice president, who is expected to be the Republican presidential nominee. The main elevators were stopped, and employees were routed far around the sensitized area where <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was to enter and walk within the building. The department's flock of public affairs specialists scurried and fluttered about. It was an exciting time for almost everyone _ except for reporters looking for news. Reporters, photographers and television technicians were herded into a conference room, or a holding pen, where they were required to put all tape recorders and cameras on the floor and then move outside to a hallway. Dozens of <ORGANIZATION> Secret </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> security people hovered close while a large German Shepherd was taken into the abandoned holding area to sniff the equipment for bombs or weapons. None was found. After more waiting, the two dozen or so news people were allowed to walk up one flight to <PERSON> Lyng </PERSON>'s outer office. The group was allowed to enter for a `` photo opportunity'' at which the subjects are often asked questions over the clicks and whirrs of cameras. But <PERSON> Norton </PERSON> <PERSON> Strommen </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION>'s chief meteorologist, was explaining a set of yellow-and-red charts to his audience, including <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>, who were seated on a couch, and <PERSON> Lyng </PERSON> and others in the official party. No questions were shouted by reporters while <PERSON> Strommen </PERSON> talked. After a few minutes, all news people were sternly ordered out of <PERSON> Lyng </PERSON>'s office. Those who tried to tarry in the area were finally herded downstairs again and lodged behind a yellow tape that represented a security boundary. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> then zipped out <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION>'s front door without enduring a single question from reporters about drought or anything else. In his wake, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> left a single-page statement noting that if relief does n't come soon, the corn crop could be in jeopardy. `` Without rain there is the potential for this to be a catastrophe,'' he said, echoing <PERSON> Lyng </PERSON>'s congressional testimony of the day before. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said farmers in 21 states are receiving some form of emergency relief, `` but sad to say, nothing will take the place of rainfall, and we have to be concerned about the plight of the nation's farmers.'' <PERSON> Strommen </PERSON> filled in the gaps later, gathering up his charts and leading reporters back into the conference room where he summarized his presentation to <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>. <PERSON> Strommen </PERSON> said the West is severely lacking in moisture from reduced snowpack during the winter, which resulted in `` well-below-normal'' reservoir levels in much of the region, including <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION>. Another major problem area is in the <LOCATION> northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Great </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Plains </LOCATION>, notably in <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Dakotas </LOCATION>, he said. And dry areas still persist in the Southeast, which has not yet fully recovered from the 1986 drought. `` The best areas in terms of moisture are the <ORGANIZATION> Southwest </ORGANIZATION>, up into the central <LOCATION> Great </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Plains </LOCATION> ... in <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Strommen </PERSON> said. Just in the last two weeks, the drought has expanded into the eastern Corn Belt states of the <LOCATION> Midwest </LOCATION>, and `` this is a major concern for us,'' he said. Without substantial rains soon, <PERSON> Strommen </PERSON> said the Corn Belt drought has a `` potential for deterioration'' of crops. However, he said, `` it simply is too early in the growing season to try to define what that potential is.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880616-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-PX-06-16-88 0135EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Reagan'sFarewell Bjt   06-16 0771</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Reagan's Farewell, Bjt,720</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHINGTON WIRE: Toronto Summit is Reagan's Final Bow</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By W. DALE NELSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> will be bidding farewell to summitry next week in <LOCATION> Toronto </LOCATION>. Eight years ago, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> went to his first economic summit in <LOCATION> Montebello </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Quebec </LOCATION>, as an untried figure on the world scene, a former movie actor reading his remarks from cue cards, on the defensive about a huge budget deficit, and espousing economic beliefs that some of his colleagues found dubious if not ridiculous. On Sunday, he leaves <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> for his last economic summit. Once again, it will be in <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> will still be reading from cue cards. He still has the same conservative beliefs. The <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> budget deficit has zoomed from $ 78.9 billion in 1981 to an estimated $ 146.7 billion. But this time, it's different. For one thing, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> has been in office longer than any of the other summit leaders except his staunch ally from <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON>. She and <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>'s <PERSON> Francois </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitterrand </PERSON> will be the only leaders there who were on board in 1981. For another, the president's aides are confident this time of the kind of reception <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> will get from his colleagues as he makes what will almost surely be his final bow on the global stage. `` I think they have learned what the rest of the world learned, which was not to underestimate <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>,'' the president's chief spokesman, <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON>, said `` I'm told that at the first summit, he was regarded as a sort of quaint, amusing character from the past, when he talked about markets and private enterprise and entrepreneurship,'' said Undersecretary of State <PERSON> Allen </PERSON> <PERSON> Wallis </PERSON>. `` Now, at the summits that's all they do _ everybody talks in that framework. `` I hope and believe that there is going to be a recognition on the part of all of the countries there that reliance on free markets and reliance on open societies is the best way to foster economic growth and sound economic development,'' said Secretary of the Treasury <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>. `` This is the message, if I may say so, that President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> took to the first economic summit in 1981, a message at the time that was greeted with a certain skepticism and perhaps even some derision,'' <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> said. `` And now, it is not so greeted, and everybody is pretty much in sync and on board with that concept and I think, hope and believe there will be a further endorsement of that at this summit.'' A European official in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, speaking on condition he not be identified, said there is still some skepticism abroad, however, about such things as <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s tax reduction programs and the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> budget and trade deficits. `` I am sure President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> has, since 1981, marked cornerstones on a number of things, but I am also sure we could not afford the kind of policies which President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> affords in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>,'' the official said. As <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> headed for Montebello eight years ago, one <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> aide, asking that he not be further identified, said, `` There is a push that we project him as leader of the free world.'' But the aide also indicated a fear that other participants would snipe at the president's economic programs and challenge his influence. A Canadian Press writer said then that the new American chief executive would have to rely on `` his good humor and charm'' to cope with `` the greater international experience and intellect'' of such leaders as <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>'s <PERSON> Pierre </PERSON> <PERSON> Trudeau </PERSON> and <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>'s <PERSON> Helmut </PERSON> <PERSON> Schmidt </PERSON>. Now, as <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> prepares to go to <LOCATION> Toronto </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said: `` I think they will see that the man they see in 1988 is the same man they saw in 1980. The difference is what he's done, that he's changed the face of the world In terms of military strength, certainly the strength of focus and purpose of <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> has been strengthened by the president's commitment to it.'' <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> added: `` East-West relations have changed dramatically under the president's leadership. The world economy is so much stronger now than it was in 1980 and 1981. Those three elements of achievement have given <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> a whole new stature. `` Because <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> is leaving office after so many years, undoubtedly there will be a tribute to him of some kind,'' <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said. `` I do n't know any specifics planned in terms of organization, but I am sure the discussions and the statements will in some way recognize the leadership that the president has given to the economic summits.''
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880616-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-PX-06-16-88 0136EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Congress-Drugs Bjt   06-16 0744</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Congress-Drugs, Bjt,730</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush Says He Would Take Income, Assets of Drug Users</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LARRY MARGASAK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Vice President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> says he endorses a House Republican plan to confiscate 25 percent of the adjusted gross income and net assets of anyone caught possessing illegal substances. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> took center stage Wednesday at a House Republican news conference, as he combined his support for the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> plan with a blistering partisan attack that was cheered by dozens of his supporters attending the event. `` I'm sick and tired ... in hearing the Democrats do nothing but tear down and criticize'' the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration's attempts to halt drug abuse, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said. `` I'm talking about <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> and <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> the last two months.'' The Republican plan also calls for the death penalty for drug kingpins, and it would require that states suspend the driver's license of anyone convicted of using drugs, or face loss of federal highway funding <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, in <LOCATION> Framingham </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mass. </LOCATION>, hit back on the drug issue, criticizing the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration for permitting <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> budget cuts that have idled drug interdiction patrols. `` How can we possibly be serious about fighting a war on drugs when we're cutting <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> patrols by 55 percent? It's that kind of thing _ one of the reasons I'm running for the presidency,'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> said. In addition to the vice president, administration officials appeared all over the Capitol complex Wednesday to testify on the drug problem. The top <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> officer discussed the cuts in his agency's drug patrols. The administration's chief budget official and the <ORGANIZATION> defense </ORGANIZATION> secretary testified on the need for drug-free workplaces. <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Carlucci </PERSON> told lawmakers that <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s defense contractors will soon be ordered to provide a drug-free workplace environment for their 3.2 million employees. The hundreds of defense contractors would be required to develop extensive education programs about the dangers of drugs; employees with security clearances could also be required to undergo mandatory drug testing, <PERSON> Carlucci </PERSON> said. An estimated 3 million workers on Pentagon contracts have security clearances of various types. <PERSON> Carlucci </PERSON> did not say if the testing would be required of all employees with clearances or just those with the more sensitive access clearances. <PERSON> Carlucci </PERSON> testified before an unusual joint meeting of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Armed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committees </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Miller </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>, director of the <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Management </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Budget </ORGANIZATION>, also said the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration supports efforts to create drug-free workplaces. But he expressed reservations before a House Government Operations subcommittee about legislation designed to bring about that goal. A bill sponsored by committee Chairman <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Brooks </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Texas </LOCATION>, would require federal contractors and grantees to establish drug-free workplace policies. Employees would have to observe the policies, and sanctions could be imposed if drug use still occurred in the workplace. The sanctions, which would be applied under due process requirements, include future disbarment of contractors who are frequent violators. <PERSON> Miller </PERSON> said the bill, which in part calls for employers and employees to certify that they are complying with the law, would require `` extensive new paperwork burdens.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, standing with some 50 <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Republicans at their news conference, declared the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> package `` better than anything the Democrats are going to dream up.'' Democrats control both houses of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, however, and majority <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> task forces are at work developing their own drug proposals. Answering reporters' questions, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> also said he supports the administration's `` zero tolerance'' policy of seizing property when even a small amount of illegal drugs is found. He said, `` If some yacht owner is inconvenienced, it's too damn bad.'' Adm. <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Yost </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, commandant of the <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION>, told a <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Merchant </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> subcommittee that his budget shortfall is $ 103 million. He said the money problem `` is proving to be a serious blow to our operations'' against drug smugglers. `` There is a great hue and cry from members getting on the bandwagon for new omnibus drug legislation to win the war against drugs, and <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> is now considering a package of drug legislation costing $ 2 billion,'' said Rep. <PERSON> Earl </PERSON> <PERSON> Hutto </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Fla </LOCATION>., chairman of the panel `` I wonder where some of those same people were earlier this year when this subcommittee was trying to get <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to find the $ 103 million necessary just to keep the Coast Guard ... afloat.'' <PERSON> Yost </PERSON> said last week that the amount of drugs seized by the <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> has been reduced by about one half since the cutbacks.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880616-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-PX-06-16-88 0136EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Dukakis-WomanVeep Bjt   06-16 0586</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Dukakis-Woman Veep, Bjt,580</SECOND>
<HEAD>Prospects Of Female Running Mate For Dukakis Appear Dim</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DONALD M. ROTHBERG</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Political Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 As <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> begins the process of selecting a <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> vice presidential nominee, the surest bet in politics is that his choice will be a man. Not even the women who worked so hard four years ago to get <PERSON> Geraldine </PERSON> <PERSON> Ferraro </PERSON> on the Democratic ticket expect <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> to follow <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Mondale </PERSON>'s history-making example. `` It certainly is n't the top-of-line discussion it was in 1984,'' said <PERSON> Joanne </PERSON> <PERSON> Howes </PERSON>, a political consultant and director of the non-partisan Women's Vote Project. `` Is that a priority in his campaign this year, or in the party?'' said <PERSON> Irene </PERSON> <PERSON> Natividad </PERSON>, director of the National Women's Political Caucus `` It does n't seem like it.'' So when <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Brountas </PERSON>, the <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> lawyer who is heading the <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> search for a running mate came to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> to talk vice presidential politics, the big names on his calling list were all male, names like <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON>, <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> <PERSON> Nunn </PERSON>, and <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON>. He did pay a call on Sen. <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Mikulski </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION>. But now in her second year as a senator, she is on no one's list of vice presidential prospects. Missing from <PERSON> Brountas </PERSON>' list was Rep. <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Schroeder </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION>, who came close to running for president and is the most credible vice presidential prospect among Democratic women. Three women often are mentioned as potential running mates for Republican <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> _ former <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>, Sen. <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> <PERSON> Kassebaum </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> and former U.N. Ambassador <PERSON> Jeane </PERSON> <PERSON> Kirkpatrick </PERSON>. This is the party that turned its back on the Equal Rights Amendment and demands that its national candidates take strong stands against abortion. Analysts talk of a `` gender gap'' that favors Democrats, the fact that a far higher percentage of women than men support Democratic candidates. Yet, this election year, the likely women vice presidential candidates are Republicans, not Democrats. `` I think the major reason is obvious,'' said <PERSON> Celinda </PERSON> <PERSON> Lake </PERSON>, a senior associated with <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Analysis </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Group </ORGANIZATION>, a Democratic polling organization. `` There are lots of ways in which the Democrats are turning away from the'84 experience. `` And one of the ways, which I think is incorrect, is they think they would not benefit from nominating a woman as the vice president.'' The ``'84 experience,'' of course, was the fact the Mondale-Ferraro ticket was beaten in 49 of 50 states as President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> received an estimated 55 percent of the women's vote. `` I also think,'' said <PERSON> Lake </PERSON> `` there is somewhat of a shortage of women who are both ready and willing. ... Because the Democrats have been out of office for eight years, we do n't have the women in the administrative pipeline.'' That view was echoed by others, including <PERSON> Joanne </PERSON> <PERSON> Symons </PERSON>, a political consultant who worked on Rep. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON>'s presidential campaign `` There are not enough -LRB- Democratic -RRB- women in the pool,'' she said, because a <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> president has been filling Cabinet positions the past seven and a half years. <PERSON> Lake </PERSON> also cited an ambition factor. She listed Gov. <PERSON> Madeleine </PERSON> <PERSON> Kunin </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Vermont </LOCATION>, along with <PERSON> Schroeder </PERSON> and <PERSON> Mikulski </PERSON> as Democratic women who have the stature to be vice presidential candidates and said, `` I do n't think they want it. They want to be No. 1, not No. 2.'' <PERSON> Howes </PERSON> said, `` The real goal is to be prepared in the 1990s for a woman to be ready to be president of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and to run for president of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and to win.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880616-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-PX-06-16-88 0140EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-ScotusRdp     06-16 0434</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Scotus Rdp,420</SECOND>
<HEAD>Court Rules Homosexual Agent May Sue CIA Over Dismissal</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RICHARD CARELLI</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> has suffered its first-ever defeat in the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> and as a result must explain in federal court its 1982 firing of a homosexual spy. <PERSON> Morton </PERSON> <PERSON> Halperin </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Civil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberties </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION> here called Wednesday's ruling by the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> a `` major victory'' in limiting what the <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> can do in the name of national security and `` a modest step forward'' for gay rights. `` At the very least, it gives us the opportunity to contend that constitutional rights have been violated,'' <PERSON> Halperin </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Steven </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Reich </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> lawyer who is helping represent the fired spy, called the ruling `` a terrific victory.'' `` The <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> is subject to the rule of law and not above the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Constitution,'' <PERSON> Reich </PERSON> said. The court's 6-2 ruling flatly rejected the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration's arguments that the 1947 law creating the <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> gave the spy agency's director virtually absolute authority to fire employees. A homosexual identified in court documents only by the fictitious name <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Doe </PERSON> was fired by then-CIA Director <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Casey </PERSON> in 1982. The agency claimed <PERSON> Doe </PERSON>'s homosexuality was a security threat. <PERSON> Doe </PERSON> had joined the <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> as a clerk-typist in 1973 and worked his way up to a covert job as an electronics technician, in which he was rated an excellent agent. In January 1982, he voluntarily told an agency security officer that he was gay. <PERSON> Doe </PERSON> was placed on paid leave pending an investigation, and that May he was told he was being fired `` in the interests of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>.'' <PERSON> Doe </PERSON> told agency officials that his family, neighbors and friends knew he was a homosexual, and that he had never revealed classified information to any unauthorized person. <PERSON> Doe </PERSON>'s suit demands that he be reinstated. In other decisions, the court: _ Barred police, by a 6-2 vote in an <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION> case, from questioning criminal suspects who already have invoked their right to remain silent or get a lawyer's help _ even if the questions center on some other crime _ Provided a victory for the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration and free-trade advocates by ruling unanimously that the government does not have to place restrictions on imported uranium to help protect <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> producers of the nuclear fuel _ Ruled, 7-1, in a case from <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> that business promoters sometimes must share the liability of deals gone sour _ Said <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> courts may apply that state's laws in a natural gas royalties dispute between <ORGANIZATION> Sun </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Oil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> and mineral rights owners from <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION>
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880616-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-PX-06-16-88 0141EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-SatelliteTV     06-16 0577</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Satellite TV,560</SECOND>
<HEAD>Pirates Said Using Modern Business Techniques To Sell Illegal
Electronics</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DEBORAH MESCE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A pirate underworld that holds seminars in the <LOCATION> Bahamas </LOCATION> and advertises openly in publications is thriving on sales of illegal decoders to backyard satellite dish owners, according to industry officials. Pirates are using modern business techniques, including the distribution of `` how to'' video tapes, to establish a sales network for the illegal electronics, <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> <PERSON> Dunham </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Instrument </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> executive, said in testimony submitted Wednesday to the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> telecommunications subcommittee. General Instrument makes the VideoCipher II decoder, whose electronics have become the de facto industry standard. Each of the three dozen or so cable programming services that have scrambled their signals can be decoded by the VideoCipher. Industry leaders estimate that as many as half of the nearly 1 million decoders on the market have been illegally modified. With the illegal decoders, backyard dish owners can avoid subscribing to scrambled programming services like <ORGANIZATION> HBO </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Showtime </ORGANIZATION> and other popular cable channels. Instead, they can pick up virtually all channels free. <PERSON> Dunham </PERSON> said General Instrument has responded to the piracy with changes in the circuitry of the decoder, a public relations campaign to let dish owners know the penalties for dealing with the illegal electronics and an amnesty program that allowed dish owners to trade in modified units at no cost or legal risk. `` In spite of these efforts, piracy has continued,'' <PERSON> Dunham </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Dunham </PERSON> said decoder pirates have held seminars in the <LOCATION> Bahamas </LOCATION> to exchange information, run technology centers to develop new ways to break the system and have tried to buy General Instrument's proprietary chips from suppliers <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Phillips </PERSON>, chief executive officer of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Telecommunications </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cooperative </ORGANIZATION>, said pirates are offering full services to the dealers and telling them the risk of getting caught is low. And pirates are even making house calls, going `` door to door where they see the satellite dishes and offer their services. They will sell entire modified descramblers or modify your own unit at home,'' he said. `` Pirates are so competitive, they have even developed programs and systems to prevent other pirates from pirating from them,'' he said. <PERSON> Sid </PERSON> <PERSON> Swartz </PERSON>, president of <ORGANIZATION> West </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, a satellite TV retailer based in <LOCATION> Mount </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vernon </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wash. </LOCATION>, said illegal decoders are costing him business. Dealers can make a $ 1,000 profit on the sale of an illegal decoder, and buyers get a sky full of permanent free programming. Legal decoders retail for $ 395, and users then must buy a program package, which for a variety of cable channels and a couple of premium channels costs about $ 250, he said. `` The consumer perceives no real value in complying with the law when all of his neighbors are apparently violating it with impunity,'' he said in testimony to the the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> panel. Witnesses called for swift prosecution and punishment of pirates and tougher penalties. Currently, a first offense nets up to one year in prison and a fine of up to $ 25,000. <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Hewitt </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> Satellite </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Broadcasting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Communications </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, said that should be increased to two years and $ 50,000 and five years and $ 100,000 for a second offense, he said. The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cable </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Television </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> says penalties are already stiff enough and that what's needed is more vigorous enforcement coupled with technological innovations and `` a better understanding by the public that piracy is a serious crime.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880616-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-PX-06-16-88 0141EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Nuclear-Drugs     06-16 0845</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nuclear-Drugs,820</SECOND>
<HEAD>Security Threat Posed By Drug Trafficking At Nuclear Lab, Probers
Say</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT M. ANDREWS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
