<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880314-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-14-88 2328EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-SouthAfrica-Hangings 1stLd-Writethru a0721 03-14 0499</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-South Africa-Hangings, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0721,0513</SECOND>
<HEAD>`Sharpeville Six' To Be Executed Friday, Lawyer Says</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: INSERT 5 grafs after 7th graf pvs, Theresa Ramashamola ...
UPDATING with British government, Amnesty asking hangings be called
off. Pick up 8th graf pvs, Dlamini's killing ...</NOTE>
<DATELINE>JOHANNESBURG, South Africa (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The `` Sharpeville Six,'' a group of blacks whose murder convictions have drawn protest at home and abroad, are scheduled to be hanged Friday, one of their lawyers said Monday. Attorney <PERSON> Prakash </PERSON> <PERSON> Diar </PERSON> said an appeal for clemency was denied and the five men and one woman were notified they will be executed Friday morning. The six were convicted in connection with the killing of black township councilor <PERSON> Jacob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dlamini </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Sharpeville </LOCATION>, about 40 miles south of <LOCATION> Johannesburg </LOCATION>, on Sept. 3, 1984. Evidence at their trial showed the six were not among those who actually hacked and burned <PERSON> Dlamini </PERSON> to death. They were convicted under the doctrine of `` common purpose,'' which holds they were responsible for the killing by being part of the mob that gathered outside <PERSON> Dlamini </PERSON>'s home with the intent to kill him. Human rights groups and government officials, both in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> and internationally, have called for clemency. <PERSON> Theresa </PERSON> <PERSON> Ramashamola </PERSON>, 26, is the only woman on death row in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> for what activists consider a politically motivated offense. <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Conservative </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> government expressed hope Monday night that <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> will call off the hangings. <PERSON> Lynda </PERSON> <PERSON> Chalker </PERSON>, minister of state at the <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION>, told the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commons </ORGANIZATION>, `` Even at this late stage we sincerely and earnestly hope that the South African government will heed the united call of everyone for clemency in these cases.'' She said <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> backed a <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> call for the sentences to be commuted. About 100 lawmakers of <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s opposition <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> signed a statement expressing `` total condemnation'' of the planned executions. <ORGANIZATION> Amnesty </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION>, the London-based human rights organization, appealed to South African President P.W. <PERSON> Botha </PERSON> to spare the lives of the six. <PERSON> Dlamini </PERSON>'s killing came during riots which began a two-year outbreak of nationwide anti-apartheid protests that left more than 2,000 blacks dead. Black activists frequently targeted black township councilors, considering them collaborators with the white-led government. The <ORGANIZATION> Media </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Workers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> appealed to the government Monday to `` demonstrate good will to the people of <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> in particular and mankind at large by sparing the lives of the Sharpeville Six.'' The scheduled execution date is three days before the anniversary of the <LOCATION> Sharpeville </LOCATION> riots of March 21, 1960. Sixty-nine blacks were killed when police fired on peaceful protesters demonstrating against the pass laws, which required blacks to carry identification documents while in white areas. The laws have since been repealed. The 1960 shootings raised an international storm of protest. By law and custom, apartheid establishes a racially segregated society in which the 26 million blacks have no vote in national affairs. The 5 million whites control the economy and maintain separate districts, schools and health services.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880314-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-14-88 2335EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p AM-PoliticalRdp 3rdLd-Writethru a0787 03-14 1044</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Political Rdp, 3rd Ld-Writethru, a0787,970</SECOND>
<HEAD>Dole, Simon Fighting to Survive in Illinois Primary</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDs: SUBS 7th graf pvs, bgng, ``The whole, with quote from Kirk,
sted spokeswoman; SUBS 25th graf pvs, An ABC, with tracking poll in
Tuesday's Washington Post</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By EVANS WITT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Political Writer</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> declared Monday `` it's not over'' for his Republican presidential campaign despite indications of a big <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> victory for <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, but Democrat <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> admitted `` I have no plans beyond tomorrow'' and the home-state primary he needs to win. With five presidential candidates racing around the state in a final day of campaigning, <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> was buoyed by a poll suggesting he may have pulled even with fellow favorite son <PERSON> Simon </PERSON>. `` On the eve of a significant breakthrough ... with your help, we the people can win <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> told a cheering crowd of about 1,800 in <LOCATION> Carbondale </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ill. </LOCATION> `` I tell you, we the people will win.'' <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, lying third, sought a good enough showing to keep up some momentum from Super Tuesday. Over and over on Monday, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> hammered at <PERSON> Simon </PERSON>'s contention that the Democratic convention will be deadlocked. It `` would be a disaster'' for the Democrats to end the primary process without a nominee-to-be, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> said, with `` negotiating, dealing, people behind closed doors trying to decide who the nominee ought to be.'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> apparently was n't the only Democrat wanting to avoid a brokered convention. Democratic Chairman <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Kirk </PERSON> suggested Monday he would try to rally uncommitted delegates behind whichever candidate is leading the field at the end of the primary season, if none has a lock on the nomination. <PERSON> Kirk </PERSON> said in a telephone interview from <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> that he did n't want to `` leave the impression that <PERSON> Kirk </PERSON>'s going to be the broker'' but said he would be `` in the middle'' of efforts to avoid hurting the nominee with a battle just before or during the convention The problem for <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> was much more immediate than the conventions, months away in the summer. The <ORGANIZATION> Kansas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> was looking for a way to keep his campaign alive in the face of a string of <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> victories. `` It's not over for <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>,'' he told the Executives Club of <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>. Later, at a news conference, <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> repeated his determination to continue beyond Tuesday: `` I've made a judgment that <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION>, whatever happens, we're going to keep going.'' The <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> senator said he had `` made some inroads'' against <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION>, but that there had not been enough time to stop <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s surge after a 16-state win last Tuesday. `` You want to elect momentum or elect the better candidate?'' he asked the Executives Club audience. `` Maybe it's going to take a couple of weeks for everything to sort of slow down.'' But the <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> outlook for <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> was not good. A <ORGANIZATION> Chicago </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tribune </ORGANIZATION> poll said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was the choice of 62 percent of the likely <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> voters in <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION>, with only 28 percent for <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>. Such a strong showing could give <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> a big chunk of the 82 Republican delegates at stake in <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION>. Added to his current total of 705 delegates, it could give him more than 60 percent of the 1,139 needed to win the nomination at the GOP National Convention in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION> in August. <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> has 165. Despite the numbers, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> told a reporter that suggestions he has locked up the nomination are premature. `` I feel the speculation has gotten ahead of the story,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said as he flew on Air Force Two from <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Springfield </LOCATION>, Ill. However, when asked if he were surprised that <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> was staying in the race, he replied: `` I'm not sure I understand what he's doing.'' On the Democratic side, <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> was facing the reality that he has to win the <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> primary to keep even his stripped-down campaign alive until the Democratic National Convention in July. `` I have no plans beyond tomorrow,'' he said in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>. `` I have to win and I will win. But obviously <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION> come next.'' And second place is n't good enough. `` A strong second is n't very strong,'' <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> told a reporter. If he does end up in second place in either delegates or the popular vote in <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION>, he said, `` I'd have to reevaluate.'' One poll published Monday in the <ORGANIZATION> Chicago </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tribune </ORGANIZATION> suggested <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> faces the possibility of a second-place finish. The survey, conducted Friday and Saturday, said 32 percent of likely Democratic voters supported <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, 29 percent backed <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> and 20 percent said they would vote for <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>. Rep. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION> was the choice of 5 percent and Sen. <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> had the backing of 4 percent. The poll, conducted by <ORGANIZATION> Peter </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hart </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associates </ORGANIZATION>, interviewed 500 people and had a potential margin of error of 5 percentage points. An <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News-Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> tracking poll published in Tuesday's editions of the <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> gave <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> the lead with 39 percent support to <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s 34 percent among very likely Democratic voters <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> had 17 percent with <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> and <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> far behind. The potential sampling error in the survey, conducted Saturday and Sunday, was plus or minus 6 percentage points. Going into the <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> primary, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> held the lead in the <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> delegate count, with 463 to 424 for <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>. <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> had 353 and <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> just 36. A total of 173 delegates are at stake on the Democratic side in <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION>. One <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> goal is to win some of those delegates, a difficult task given the complicated nature of the state's ballot. Voters not only cast ballots for presidential candidates, they also vote directly for delegate candidates. Thus, a vote for <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> in the `` beauty contest'' portion does not necessarily mean a vote for him in the delegate selection process. Another goal, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> aides said privately, is to narrow the Democratic field. Mentioning the polls showing <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> drawing his last-minute support from <PERSON> Simon </PERSON>'s voters, the governor's aides said they would be delighted to see <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> beat <PERSON> Simon </PERSON>, believing it would drive the senator from the race. Republican <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> was to be in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> on primary day, where he planned to meet with the visiting <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> prime minister, <PERSON> Yitzhak </PERSON> <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON>. The <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> campaign characterized it as a meeting of `` two old friends.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880314-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-14-88 2344EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-People-Hepburn 1stLd-Writethru a0654 03-14 0418</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-People-Hepburn, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0654,0426</SECOND>
<HEAD>Planned Parenthood Honors Katharine Hepburn and Mother</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: LEADS with 4 grafs to UPDATE with affair under way; PICKS UP
3rd graf pvs, `She felt ...'</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By CATHERINE CROCKER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Katharine </PERSON> <PERSON> Hepburn </PERSON>, whose outspoken suppport of women's reproductive rights is a family tradition, made a rare public appearance Monday night when Planned Parenthood honored her and her late mother at a gala affair. The 79-year-old Miss <PERSON> Hepburn </PERSON> received a standing ovation from 1,100 guests at the Waldorf-Astoria Hotel for the black-tie event, titled `` Celebrating Two Generations of Individual Courage. `` It's a frightfully important subject,'' the actress said of women's rights to abortion and birth control. `` And I'm damn lucky to have had a mother who waked me up at an early age'' to the importance of `` doing things for other people.'' Attired in a black pantsuit, Miss <PERSON> Hepburn </PERSON> said, `` ` When a girl becomes pregnant should she be forced by law to have this baby? She's 13. She does n't want it. She ca n't support it. Her family does n't want it. It would seem to me that she should be allowed to have an abortion.'' Miss <PERSON> Hepburn </PERSON> was `` enthusiastic'' about the party, said <PERSON> Winston </PERSON> <PERSON> Forrest </PERSON>, vice president of <ORGANIZATION> Planned </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Parenthood </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION>. `` She felt her mother deserved the honoring,'' he said. The black-tie event is to benefit a Planned Parenthood fund to honor Miss <PERSON> Hepburn </PERSON>'s mother, <PERSON> Katharine </PERSON> <PERSON> Houghton </PERSON> <PERSON> Hepburn </PERSON>. Proceeds from the dinner, priced at $ 500 to $ 1,000 a ticket, will be dedicated to Miss <PERSON> Hepburn </PERSON>'s three priorities: keeping abortion safe and legal, preventing teen-age pregnancies and preserving family planning for the poor. Her mother, an early supporter of birth control, worked alongside Planned Parenthood founder <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Sanger </PERSON> more than 70 years ago. Mrs. <PERSON> Hepburn </PERSON>, a member of the <PERSON> Houghton </PERSON> family that founded Corning Glass, testified before the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> in the 1930s on the need for birth control, particularly for poor women, <PERSON> Forrest </PERSON> said. She maintained that `` a rich woman could get the information and access to birth control but the poor woman could not,'' he said. She died in 1951 at the age of 73. Miss <PERSON> Hepburn </PERSON> became involved in Planned Parenthood in 1981. The group's president, <PERSON> Faye </PERSON> <PERSON> Wattleton </PERSON>, recruited the actress `` to take on the legacy her mother had established by volunteering to write letters and be spokesperson for reproductive rights and abortion rights for women,'' <PERSON> Forrest </PERSON> said. He said her involvement has brought the organization an additonal 200,000 donors and supporters.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880314-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-14-88 2351EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-WheelchairProtest     03-14 0270</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Wheelchair Protest,250</SECOND>
<HEAD>Handicapped People Protest DOT Transportation Policies</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 More than 50 handicapped people demonstrated outside the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> on Monday to protest what they said are federal policies that result in inadequate mass transit services for disabled people. Some protestors chained themselves to the doors of the DOT headquarters and vowed to stay until officials agree to improve bus service for handicapped people. Members of Americans Disabled For Accessible Transportation -LRB- ADAPT -RRB- gathered from around the country to protest the department's decision to appeal a January ruling that transit agencies must provide services to the handicapped regardless of cost. In the ruling, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> Marvin </PERSON> <PERSON> Katz </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION> struck down a <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> regulation requiring the nation's transit authorities to spend no more than 3 percent of their budgets on the disabled. The demonstrators timed their protest to coincide with a three-day meeting of the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, which represents local agencies that provide bus and subway service. <PERSON> Timothy </PERSON> <PERSON> Cook </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION> attorney who represented ADAPT in the lawsuit, said the present system of allowing transit agencies to decide what services to provide to the handicapped `` gives individual states the option to discriminate.'' <PERSON> Cook </PERSON> said that in <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION>, handicapped residents must phone five to seven days in advance to get an accessible bus to pick them up. `` They should be able to use the next bus coming along,'' <PERSON> Cook </PERSON> said. `` Many transit authorities simply do n't want funny-looking people on the bus with normal people.'' Transportation Secretary <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Burnley </PERSON> said Monday the department is `` fully committed to providing mass transportation to people with disabilities.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880314-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-14-88 2355EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Panama-Canal     03-14 0630</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Panama-Canal,0648</SECOND>
<HEAD>Canal Operated Despite Unrest</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</NOTE>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DOUGLAS GRANT MINE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BALBOA, Panama (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Canal </LOCATION>, still one of the hemisphere's most important pieces of real estate, has allowed ships to move between the <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> without interruption through nine months of political unrest. Nearly 13,000 vessels a year avoid the long voyage around <LOCATION> Cape </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Horn </LOCATION>, the southern tip of <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, by traveling 50 miles from sea to sea through the `` Big Ditch'' that opened in 1914. More than 140 million tons of cargo move through it every year. The <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> Canal Treaties signed in 1977 commit the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> to turn over complete control of the canal and military installations to <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> by midnight Dec. 31, 1999. Gen. <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>, commander of the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forces </ORGANIZATION> and the man in charge in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>, claims <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> wants to renege on the treaties and continue `` occupying'' the canal indefinitely. He says the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration is waging a smear campaign to try to replace him with an administration it can manipulate. <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> was indicted in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> last month on charges of involvement in smuggling Colombian cocaine into the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. Although the canal remains an emotional topic of debate, its strategic importance has declined in the past 30 years. <PERSON> Dennis </PERSON> <PERSON> McAuliffe </PERSON>, administrator of the <ORGANIZATION> Panama </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Canal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION>, says that is because the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has improved and extended its military forces. `` During and after World War II, through the 1950s, the major port system was <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> and sealift through the canal was about the only way to reinforce presence in the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION>, but now there are major <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> naval forces in both oceans and major ports on the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Coast </LOCATION>,'' he said. `` There is less of a need to transport capital ships through the canal, and airlift capacity has increased tremendously.'' Traffic through the canal brings the commission about $ 320 million a year in tolls. Supertankers and the largest bulk carriers are too big for the three sets of locks that raise and lower vessels 85 feet, but 93 percent of the world's ships can get through, said <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Wainio </PERSON>, chief of the commission's Economic and Marketing Division. `` The Panamax is still the world's most popular cargo shipbuilding design,'' he said, referring to the largest vessel the canal can handle. A Panamax vessel has a beam width of 106 feet. The locks are 110 feet wide. Nor is the canal concept outdated. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> began a study last year of the feasibility of building another. Its conclusions are expected in 1992 at the earliest. For the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, the strategic value of what used to be the <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> Canal Zone is enhanced by the presence of the <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Command </ORGANIZATION>, involving about 10,000 American soldiers and 20,000 dependents, which is responsible for <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military operations in <LOCATION> Latin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>. It operates half a dozen bases along the canal and has its headquarters in <LOCATION> Quarry </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Heights </LOCATION>, adjacent to <LOCATION> Balboa </LOCATION>. During their long tenure, the Americans built replicas of their own towns. Communities of white wooden houses on tree-lined streets named in English still can be found in the 10-mile-wide area that had been the Canal Zone. <PERSON> McAuliffe </PERSON> said this week that day-to-day coordination between his commission and <LOCATION> Panamanian </LOCATION> port authorities is `` easy, fluid and very effective.'' This month, there had been several bomb threats, which he called `` an irritant,'' and the commision flew in large quantities of cash because of <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s banking crisis to cover the paychecks of canal employees. The latest checks were handed out Monday. Under sanctions imposed last week, the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration is withholding monthly payments to <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> of about $ 6.6 million for canal operations and putting the money in escrow.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880314-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-14-88 2357EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-APArts:JewishExhibit     03-14 0598</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AP Arts: Jewish Exhibit,0613</SECOND>
<HEAD>Most Important Private Collection of Jewish Art in Europe</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By VIOREL URMA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>VIENNA, Austria (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Fifty years after the <ORGANIZATION> Nazis </ORGANIZATION> closed the world's first museum of Jewish art in <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION>, a private exhibit of Jewish ritual objects has been drawing large crowds of visitors. Some 800 items displayed at the `` Judentum in <LOCATION> Wien </LOCATION>'' -LRB- `` Jews in <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION>'' -RRB- exhibit housed by the Museum of the History of <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION> are all loans from a private Judaica collection, regarded by art historians as one the most important private collections of Jewish life. According to <PERSON> Max </PERSON> <PERSON> Berger </PERSON>, owner of the collection, most of the drawings, paintings, sculptures, medals, coins, manuscripts and handicraft on show were in danger of being destroyed or lost after <LOCATION> Austria </LOCATION>'s annexation by <ORGANIZATION> Nazi </ORGANIZATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> in 1938. <PERSON> Berger </PERSON>, a Viennese businessman who survived a Nazi concentration camp, pieced together his collection over years and this is the first time it has been shown in public. The exhibit displays mementoes of Jewish life from the early 18th century until present, focusing on <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION> as an important center in the history of European Jewry. Museum officials said it is the first step toward opening a permanent Jewish museum here in the next two or three years. About 6,000 Jews live in <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION> today, compared with 200,000 who helped make this city a capital of science, culture and the arts before World War II. They included <PERSON> Sigmund </PERSON> <PERSON> Freud </PERSON>, <PERSON> Gustav </PERSON> <PERSON> Mahler </PERSON>, <PERSON> Stefan </PERSON> <PERSON> Zweig </PERSON>, <PERSON> Arnold </PERSON> <PERSON> Schoenberg </PERSON> and hundreds of others. Some 65,000 Austrian Jews perished in Nazi concentration and death camps during the war. The exhibit is divided into eight sections, including ritual objects and Hebrew writings, the Jewish year and life, the history of the Viennese Jews, Zionism, anti-semitism and persecution and Jewish contributions to art and culture. `` It's the first time that the most important private <ORGANIZATION> Judaica </ORGANIZATION> collection in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> is displayed for the Austrian public after the war,'' <PERSON> Karl-Albrecht </PERSON> <PERSON> Weinberger </PERSON>, a curator who helped set up the display, said in an interview. By March 3, the exhibit had been visited by some 30,000 people. `` On Saturdays and Sundays we have up to 500 visitors a day,'' <PERSON> Weinberger </PERSON> said, adding that recently Austrian school authorities advised schools to come and see the exhibit as part of their history classes. More young Austrians gradually have been educated about the <ORGANIZATION> Nazi </ORGANIZATION> past and the Holocaust in the two years since the first disclosures that President <PERSON> Kurt </PERSON> <PERSON> Waldheim </PERSON> had covered up his wartime past as a German army lieutenant in the <LOCATION> Balkans </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Weinberger </PERSON> said the exhibit was planned before <PERSON> Waldheim </PERSON> became president. The most valuable objects displayed are a silver-and-gold torah crown made in <LOCATION> Austria </LOCATION> in 1810 and a torah plaque made in 1806 of gold-covered silver. The oldest display is a torah curtain made around 1700 of red velvet laced with silver threads. <PERSON> Weinberger </PERSON> said the first Jewish Museum in the world opened in <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION> in 1895, with a very big collection of Jewish art. The <ORGANIZATION> Nazis </ORGANIZATION> dismantled it in 1938. While some items were lost or destroyed, others were taken by the Germans to <LOCATION> Prague </LOCATION> where they planned to open a big anti-semitic Jewish museum. The museum never materialized but some objects have remained in the <LOCATION> Prague </LOCATION> Jewish Museum which opened after the war. Asked if the Austrians ever asked the Czechs to return the items held by the <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Museum </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Weinberger </PERSON> said they never did. `` It's difficult to prove what objects belonged to the Jewish <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Museum </LOCATION> as all catalog were destroyed during the war,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880314-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-14-88 2357EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-HondaShip     03-14 0238</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Honda Ship,0243</SECOND>
<HEAD>Ship Carrying Japan-Bound Hondas Returns To U.S.</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PORTLAND, Ore. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A cracked fuel line threw a metric wrench into a plan by <ORGANIZATION> Honda </ORGANIZATION> to become the first Japanese automaker to transport its U.S.-built cars back to <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> for sale. The auto carrier <ORGANIZATION> Green </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bay </ORGANIZATION>, built in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> last year, was examined by repair crews Monday, a day after it slipped quietly back into port here with its cargo of 540 U.S.-built Accords and 100 <ORGANIZATION> Honda </ORGANIZATION> motorcyles. The ship's owner, <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Gulf </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lines </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Orleans </ORGANIZATION>, declined to comment, but <ORGANIZATION> Honda </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Shin </PERSON> <PERSON> Tanaka </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION> said a fuel line crack forced the ship's return. He said <ORGANIZATION> Honda </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Motor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Ltd. </ORGANIZATION> was postponing from March 22 to April 8 a gala reception to welcome the vessel at <LOCATION> Narashino </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Port </LOCATION>, east of <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION> If necessary, he said, the cargo will be moved to another ship from the <LOCATION> Green </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION>, which has made several successful trips for <ORGANIZATION> Honda </ORGANIZATION> since it was completed Oct. 29 by <ORGANIZATION> Mitsui </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Engineering </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <ORGANIZATION> Shipbuilding </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ltd </ORGANIZATION>. The ship departed March 7 with much fanfare, after <PERSON> Tetsuo </PERSON> <PERSON> Chino </PERSON>, president of <ORGANIZATION> Honda </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> North </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, drove the first car on board and held a news conference with Sen. <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Packwood </PERSON>, R-Ore. <PERSON> Francois </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Elmealeh </PERSON> of the Port of <LOCATION> Portland </LOCATION>'s marine marketing department said the problems with the ship did n't threaten the cargo or crew `` I think it's an embarrassment more than anything,'' <PERSON> Elmealeh </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880314-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-14-88 0008EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p AM-Simon 1stLd-Writethru a0794 03-14 0556</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Simon, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0794,490</SECOND>
<HEAD>Simon Shrugs Off Poll Suggesting He's Losing Ground In Illinois</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDS: SUBS grafs 8-9 pvs, `Simon still ... he said,' with 3 grafs
to UPDATE with Washington Post-ABC News poll showing Simon with
strong lead; PICKS UP 10th graf pvs bgng, `I would'</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By WILLIAM C. HIDLAY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CHICAGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Sen. <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> shrugged off new poll results suggesting his lead in his home state had diminished to a tie with <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, but conceded Sunday that his <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> campaign was hampered by not having the money to buy television ads in <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION>. `` Obviously, not to have paid media hampers me in <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> said as he campaigned in the city's <LOCATION> Chinatown </LOCATION> neighborhood. `` But the only way I could have paid media would be to use up the resources and obligate the matching funds that are coming.'' That would have left <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> unable to afford television advertising in <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> and other states with contests upcoming, he said. `` Frankly, I'm not in it just for <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> _ otherwise I'd go on paid media. ... I want to win the nomination _ not buy the nomination,'' he added. But the results of a <ORGANIZATION> Chicago </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tribune </ORGANIZATION> poll to be published in Monday's editions suggested <PERSON> Simon </PERSON>'s campaign was faltering in <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION>, despite his record as a state representative and <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> senator. The poll of 500 registered Democrats indicated 32 percent supported <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, 29 percent backed <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> and 20 percent favored <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>. However, the poll, taken for the <ORGANIZATION> Tribune </ORGANIZATION> by <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Hart </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> Associates </ORGANIZATION>, has a margin of error of plus or minus five percentage points, making the race a dead heat. The poll, taken Friday and Saturday, updates one taken earlier last week that showed <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> leading with 35 percent, followed by <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> with 30 percent and <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> with 18 percent. <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> still insisted he would carry his home state on Tuesday, saying, `` I think the people of <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> are going to make a sound decision.'' And his optimism appeared to be supported by a poll for <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> which was published in Monday's editions of the newspaper That poll showed <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> holding a strong lead with 42 percent, <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> 33 percent, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> 14 percent, Sen. <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> Tennessee </ORGANIZATION> 4 percent, Rep. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> Missouri </ORGANIZATION> 3 percent and others and undecided, 4 percent. The poll was based on telephone interviews Friday night and Saturday with 287 <ORGANIZATION> Illinois </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> voters who were likely to cast ballots. The margin of error was 6 percent. `` I would add that four years ago there was n't a single poll that showed me ahead and I won,'' <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> said, referring to his upset victory in a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Senate race against <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> incumbent <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Percy </PERSON>. Meanwhile, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, who has assaulted <PERSON> Simon </PERSON>'s campaign with a blitz of last-minute television advertising, accused <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> of `` doing a disservice to the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>'' by talking up the likelihood of a brokered presidential convention in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>. `` I think the notion of a brokered convention would be an absolute disaster,'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> said Sunday. `` The reality is we're not going to have a first-ballot nominee,'' <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> countered. `` And those brokered conventions have produced candidates ... like <PERSON> Franklin </PERSON> <PERSON> Roosevelt </PERSON>, <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> Truman </PERSON> and <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, and it turned out quite well for the <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> people.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880314-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-14-88 0021EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-ChildSexAbuse     03-14 0569</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Child Sex Abuse,0587</SECOND>
<HEAD>Trial Of Former Day Care Teacher Nearing End</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Note contents.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By JULIA DOLAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEWARK, N.J. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 It's been nearly three years since a toddler's visit to a doctor sparked what has become the marathon trial of <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Kelly </PERSON> <PERSON> Michaels </PERSON>, a former day-care teacher accused of sexually abusing her students. Ms. <PERSON> Michaels </PERSON>, 26, resigned from the Wee Care Day Nursery in <LOCATION> Maplewood </LOCATION> in April 1985 after working for six months. A few days later, a boy, now 7, told a nurse taking his temperature rectally that Ms. <PERSON> Michaels </PERSON> did the same to him. The school was closed soon afterward, and by December 1985, Ms. <PERSON> Michaels </PERSON> had been indicted on 235 counts of sexually abusing 31 3-to 5-year-old students. The charges have since been reduced to 20 students. Closing arguments in the trial, which began nine months ago in <ORGANIZATION> Superior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Newark </LOCATION>, are expected to begin Tuesday. The prosecution contends Ms. <PERSON> Michaels </PERSON> performed sexual acts on the children, forced them to perform sexual acts on her, engaged them in nude sex play and threatened further harm if they told of the abuse. Ms. <PERSON> Michaels </PERSON>, who once aspired to be an actress, has been free on $ 25,000 bail and living with her family in <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION> since January 1986. All but 128 charges of abuse have been dropped because of lack of evidence and recent higher court rulings that clarified what testimony is admissible in child sex abuse cases. `` We'll all be glad when it's over,'' Ms. <PERSON> Michaels </PERSON>' attorney, <PERSON> Harvey </PERSON> <PERSON> Meltzer </PERSON>, said last week. `` We are very, very optimistic she'll be acquitted on all charges.'' Assistant Prosecutor <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Goldberg </PERSON> said, `` We feel there is no reason to disbelieve the children's testimony about what happened.'' The boy who went to the doctor three years ago testified via closed-circuit television last June that Ms. <PERSON> Michaels </PERSON> once took his temperature and that of two friends using a rectal thermometer. The boy's mother testified earlier he told her in April 1985 that Ms. <PERSON> Michaels </PERSON> used a rectal thermometer daily on children. The mother and son were among about 120 prosecution witnesses. In all, 19 children testified via closed-circuit television from Judge <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Harth </PERSON>'s chambers. Ms. <PERSON> Michaels </PERSON> took the stand earlier this month, and was one of 22 defense witnesses. The defense has argued there was not `` the time, space or opportunity'' in the bustling environment of the school for Ms. <PERSON> Michaels </PERSON> to commit the alleged offenses. But the prosecution said Ms. <PERSON> Michaels </PERSON>, whose duties included supervising napping children, created opportunities. They contend she sometimes took children, without permission, to a remote music room and played the piano during sex games. The defense also says the children were prompted in their allegations by investigators, psychologists and prosecutors. Experts for the prosecution testified children can not be `` brainwashed'' and could not have made up the stories. The prosecution also said Ms. <PERSON> Michaels </PERSON>' presented a false image of herself. `` As a four-year drama student, a lot of what she was doing on the witness stand was an attempt to appear spontaneous when in fact it was not spontaneous,'' <PERSON> Goldberg </PERSON> said. But <PERSON> Metzler </PERSON> said: `` What we have is a very, very large jigsaw puzzle that the jury must complete. ... We are going to show there are pieces missing from the puzzle. Then it's up to the jury to determine if the missing pieces amount to a reasonable doubt.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880314-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-14-88 0031EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     03-14 0879</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names ,0910</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in the News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 After 15 years of entertaining readers around the world, humorist <PERSON> Russell </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> says he has written his last `` Sunday Observer'' column. `` I did it for 15 years. That's a long time to write a column with three weeks' lead time,'' <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> said Sunday. `` Columnists tend to hang on too long. I wanted to call it quits before that.'' <PERSON> Baker </PERSON>, who announced his decision in a farewell column in <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Magazine </ORGANIZATION>, plans to continue his weekday column for the <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> and work on a book. <PERSON> Baker </PERSON>'s daily and Sunday columns are distributed to about 400 newspapers across the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and about 100 foreign papers, according to <PERSON> Kevin </PERSON> <PERSON> Delaney </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>. The weekday column appears twice a week. `` I'll still be doing the daily column, probably longer than I should,'' <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> said. `` I'm 62 years old. You begin to run out of steam.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Courtney </PERSON> <PERSON> Gibbs </PERSON>, the newly crowned Miss <LOCATION> USA </LOCATION>, says she's tone deaf and ca n't dance, which is one reason why she entered the pageant: It has no talent requirement. `` The Miss America Pageant has a talent division, and I really do n't have a talent that fits into any category,'' the 21-year-old Ms. <PERSON> Gibbs </PERSON> was quoted as saying in this week's People magazine. Ms. <PERSON> Gibbs </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>' fourth-consecutive winner of the pageant, said she hopes her talent is `` speaking, because I want to go into broadcasting, but you ca n't do that for three minutes in front of the judges. `` I mean, I was a model for seven years, but I do n't think they'd understand me modeling clothes for three minutes.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>EVERETT, Pa. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Officials in this small, south-central <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> community are waiting for actor <PERSON> Clint </PERSON> <PERSON> Eastwood </PERSON> to make their day by paying a 10 -LCB- - year-old speeding ticket <PERSON> Eastwood </PERSON>, who is also mayor of <LOCATION> Carmel </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, was driving west along the <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Turnpike </LOCATION> in a frend's new black Ferrari on Oct. 23, 1977, when he was clocked going 69 mph in a 55 mph zone, police say. District Justice <PERSON> Marion </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Morgret </PERSON> of <PERSON> Everett </PERSON> said recently he stopped sending <PERSON> Eastwood </PERSON> collection letters and warnings eight years ago. He had the citation placed in his `` dead'' file. <PERSON> Eastwood </PERSON>, known for his tough-guy roles in such films as `` Dirty Harry'' and `` Sudden Impact,'' was fined $ 53 and ordered to pay $ 10 in costs. The actor's agent, <PERSON> Lenny </PERSON> <PERSON> Hirshan </PERSON>, said <PERSON> Eastwood </PERSON> was on location in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> shooting a movie and could not be contacted.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LAGOS, Nigeria (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Jimmy </PERSON> <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> has vowed to support <LOCATION> Nigeria </LOCATION>'s drive to eradicate guinea worm, a debilitating parasite that permanently disables 12,000 Nigerians annually. The former <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> president, who arrived Sunday on an overnight visit to this West African nation, pledged the support of Global 2000, a private, non-profit institution founded during his 1977-81 presidency. The Atlanta-based organization funds health and agriculture projects in the developing world. `` <LOCATION> Nigeria </LOCATION> is the most heavily afflicted country in <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>. If we can succeed here we can reach our goal to totally eradicate guinea worm'' by 1995, <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> said during a meeting with the nation's health minister, Dr. <PERSON> Olikoye </PERSON> <PERSON> Ransome-Kuti </PERSON> It is estimated that 2.5 million Nigerians contract the disease each year through contaminated drinking water.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>SOUTH BEND, Ind. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Eunice </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> <PERSON> Shriver </PERSON> has been selected to receive the 1988 Laetare Medal, one of the most prestigious awards given to American Catholics, the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Notre </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dame </ORGANIZATION> announced. The university's president, the Rev. <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Malloy </PERSON>, said recently Mrs. <PERSON> Shriver </PERSON> will be honored for her work as founder and chairwoman of Special Olympics International. `` Inscribed on each Laetare Medal is the slogan, ` Truth is mighty and will prevail,' `` <PERSON> Malloy </PERSON> said. `` Last summer, while hosting the International Special Olympics Games, the Notre Dame community saw anew an ancient Christian truth: <PERSON> Christ </PERSON> comes most often in the stranger's guise.'' Mrs. <PERSON> Shriver </PERSON>, a native of <LOCATION> Brookline </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mass. </LOCATION>, is the fifth of the nine children of <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> and <PERSON> Rose </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzgerald </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, and the sister of the late President <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>BEVERLY HILLS, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Directors Guild of <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> has honored <PERSON> Bernardo </PERSON> <PERSON> Bertolucci </PERSON> with his second directing award for `` The Last Emperor,'' in what could bode a triple-crown award season for the Italian movie director. <PERSON> Bertolucci </PERSON>, who in January won a <ORGANIZATION> Golden </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Globe </ORGANIZATION> for directing `` The Last Emperor,'' picked up the <ORGANIZATION> DGA </ORGANIZATION> award Saturday night in ceremonies held jointly at the <LOCATION> Beverly </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hilton </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hotel </LOCATION> and in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>. An Academy Award next month would make it a <PERSON> Bertolucci </PERSON> sweep. Only three times in the 40-year history of the <ORGANIZATION> DGA </ORGANIZATION> award has it failed to coincide with the Academy Award winner for best director. The last time was in 1985, when <PERSON> Steven </PERSON> <PERSON> Spielberg </PERSON>'s directorial colleagues gave him the nod for `` The Color Purple,'' while the <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Motion </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Picture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Arts </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sciences </ORGANIZATION> did n't even nominate him. The Oscar went instead to <PERSON> Sydney </PERSON> <PERSON> Pollack </PERSON> for `` Out of <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>.'' Other top <ORGANIZATION> DGA </ORGANIZATION> winners Saturday were <PERSON> Will </PERSON> <PERSON> MacKenzie </PERSON>, who received the TV comedy directing award for an episode of <ORGANIZATION> NBC-TV </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Family Ties'' called `` ` A' My Name is Alex''; and <PERSON> Marshall </PERSON> <PERSON> Herskovitz </PERSON>, who won the nighttime dramatic series award for his pilot for <ORGANIZATION> ABC-TV </ORGANIZATION>'s `` thirtysomething.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880314-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-14-88 0032EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Obit-Rudofsky     03-14 0290</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Obit-Rudofsky,0302</SECOND>
<HEAD>Rudofsky, Architect and Social Commentator, Dies</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Bernard </PERSON> <PERSON> Rudofsky </PERSON>, an architect and social commentator, has died at age 82. <PERSON> Rudofsky </PERSON> died of cancer Saturday at <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> University </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION>. He wrote on a variety of subjects, ranging from the relationship between the body and clothes to how streets are used in cities. <PERSON> Rudofsky </PERSON>'s books and museum exhibitions influenced not only architecture but fashion, interior design, urban planning and food. `` He was our most perceptive and outspoken critic of human habits and habitations,'' said the chief editor of <ORGANIZATION> Interior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Design </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> magazine </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Stanley </PERSON> <PERSON> Abercrombie </PERSON>. <PERSON> Rudofsky </PERSON> first made waves in 1944 with an exhibition at the Museum of Modern Art entitled `` Are Clothes Modern?'' The exhibition, which examined the incompatibility of the human body and clothing, showed one of his contributions to fashion, the `` <PERSON> Bernardo </PERSON> <PERSON> Sandal </PERSON>,'' a curved piece of leather with straps. Twenty years later, <PERSON> Rudofsky </PERSON> had an exhibit at the Museum of Modern Art called `` Architecture Without Architects'' on vernacular architecture _ the design of buildings built in societies, sometimes ancient or primitive, that he believed were without pretensions. <PERSON> Rudofsky </PERSON>, who was born and educated in <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION>, received a master's degree in architecture and engineering and a doctorate in technical sciences at the <ORGANIZATION> Technical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. He practiced architecture for several years in <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>. He has lived in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> since 1935. His books included `` Streets for People,'' in which he examined how streets are used in cities around the world, and `` The Unfashionable Human Body,'' which looked at the relationship between the body and clothing. <PERSON> Rudofsky </PERSON> taught at <ORGANIZATION> Yale </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Massachusetts </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Technology </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Royal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Arts </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Copenhagen </LOCATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Waseda </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION>. He is survived by his wife, <PERSON> Berta </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880314-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-14-88 0053EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-AIDSBenefit 2ndLd-Writethru a0412 03-14 0632</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-AIDS Benefit, 2nd Ld - Writethru, a0412,0641</SECOND>
<HEAD>AIDS Benefit With Elizabeth Taylor Raises $2 Million</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: INSERTS 1 graf after 4th graf pvs to add background on
Taylor's role in evening's events, picking up 5th graf pvs, `As
the...'.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By SANDRA WALEWSKI</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MIAMI BEACH, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Amid the glitter and glamour of <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON> and a parade of other celebrities, a gala benefit Sunday raised $ 2 million for AIDS, which organizers said made it the largest private fund-raiser for the disease ever. `` That's so much money ... I mean that's so incredibly much money, and the things that money will do!'' said Ms. <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON>. `` We're talking about living or dying. And it's getting closer and closer to all of us. ... We want to do something about it. `` The government can help to a certain point. Dollars can help to a certain point,'' she said. The evening's total was about $ 2 million, said <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Figetakis </PERSON>, an associate of Ms. <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON>'s publicist, <PERSON> Chen </PERSON> <PERSON> Sam </PERSON>. Ms. <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON> chairs the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> AIDS </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION>, which will receive part of the funds. She served as hostess and chief drawing card at the gala. As the finale swung into full force Sunday night, a steady stream of stars in sparkling jewels and dresses began arriving at the Fontainebleau Hilton Hotel here. They expressed gratitude they could contribute in the battle against AIDS. `` It's really an honor for me to be here,'' actor <PERSON> Matt </PERSON> <PERSON> Dillon </PERSON> said. `` It's a real problem everywhere, not just in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, but all over the world. Anything I can do to help is why I'm here.'' `` I think it's about time <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> got involved in the fight against AIDS,'' said <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> Vice star <PERSON> Saundra </PERSON> <PERSON> Santiago </PERSON>. `` I'm very happy to be here to support this. Other stars on hand included <PERSON> Lauren </PERSON> <PERSON> Hutton </PERSON>, <PERSON> Cheryl </PERSON> <PERSON> Tiegs </PERSON>, <PERSON> Ben </PERSON> <PERSON> Vereen </PERSON>, <PERSON> Marlee </PERSON> <PERSON> Matlin </PERSON>, <PERSON> Donna </PERSON> <PERSON> Summers </PERSON>, <PERSON> Grace </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>, <PERSON> Margaux </PERSON> <PERSON> Hemingway </PERSON>, <PERSON> Eddie </PERSON> <PERSON> Albert </PERSON>, <PERSON> Susan </PERSON> <PERSON> Anton </PERSON> and <PERSON> Van </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>. Organizers say they hope the benefit will serve as a model for similar fund-raising efforts elsewhere. `` We've had the most private funds raised -LRB- for acquired immune deficiency syndrome -RRB- at this one function than any other place in the country,'' said event spokesman <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Cinnamon </PERSON>. `` We want it to be the prototype for the rest of the country.'' Despite a lack of corporate sponsorships, which had been expected to raise some $ 500,000 of the initial $ 3 million goal, tickets to the `` grand finale'' at the hotel here sold out and private donations were giving the fund drive an added boost, organizers said. Stars and guests were invited Sunday to attend about a dozen black-tie parties from <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Palm </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION>, being held at the homes of local celebrities and prominent community leaders for $ 2,500 a plate, before converging in <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION> for the finale. The AIDS benefit was spearheaded by the <ORGANIZATION> Community </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Alliance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Against </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> AIDS </ORGANIZATION>, a fund-raising arm of the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Miami </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medicine </ORGANIZATION>. Proceeds from the event were being split between the university's AIDS programs and the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> AIDS </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION>, a non-profit group chaired by Ms. <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON>, which supports research and education. In <LOCATION> Palm </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Celia </PERSON> <PERSON> Lipton </PERSON> <PERSON> Farris </PERSON> raised at least $ 137,000 in advance ticket sales for a private party being held in her home with Ms. <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON> and some 300 guests. During the event, Ms. <PERSON> Farris </PERSON>, a former child star and widow of a wealthy industrialist, announced she was giving an additional $ 1.1 million, <PERSON> Figetakis </PERSON> said. Funds raised in <LOCATION> Palm </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION> will go toward the Comprehensive AIDS Program, an organization in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Palm </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Belle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Glade </LOCATION> that cares for AIDS victims. Other private dinner parties were being held in the homes of singer <PERSON> Julio </PERSON> <PERSON> Iglesias </PERSON>, theatrical producer <PERSON> Zev </PERSON> <PERSON> Bufman </PERSON> and <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON>, chief executive officer of <ORGANIZATION> Centrust </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION>, among others.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880314-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-14-88 0057EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-FinalTuesday Bjt   03-14 0530</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Final Tuesday, Bjt,500</SECOND>
<HEAD>Super Tuesday's Over, But `Final Tuesday' Lies Ahead</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BOB McHUGH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 With Super Tuesday behind them, the presidential candidates are looking toward the next big Tuesday on the calendar _ June 7, when the <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> primaries offer the last big bloc of delegates to be allocated before the national conventions. There are other big primaries in coming months, including <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>. But none offers a larger one-day delegate total than Final Tuesday, as it's been dubbed. <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> also will hold primaries June 7. For Democrats, with <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> and <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> Sen. <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> bunched in the lead, the late primaries on opposite sides of the country now loom as potentially decisive. On the Republican side, where a big Super Tuesday victory last week made Vice President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> his party's likely choice, the June 7 primaries are expected to be much less crucial. A day after Super Tuesday, both <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> and <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> announced they would soon make campaign stops in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, too, is building organizations in both states. <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Kelly </PERSON> says the Super Tuesday result `` almost guarantees that the race will come down to <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, and <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> will have a say in picking the nominee.'' In <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION>, Democratic Sen. <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON> said, `` <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> takes on real importance. We are, with <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, the final two tests.'' <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> voters will select 205 Democratic delegates in the primary, and 109 more will be chosen in post-primary meetings. Along with 22 pre-selected `` super delegates,'' the state will send the largest single delegation to the convention with 336 members. <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> Democrats will select 71 delegates in primary voting. They'll join with 38 more picked by party leaders, and nine super delegates for a total of 118. To win the nomination, a <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> candidate will need 2,082 delegates. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> now leads the field with 460, followed by <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> with 424 and <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> with 353. Missouri Rep. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> totals 145 delegates, followed by <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> Sen. <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> with 36. Some party leaders say it will be nearly impossible for any of the three leaders to gather enough wins between now and June to win the nomination on the convention's first ballot. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, the front-runner, would need to win more than 60 percent of the delegates remaining available. But Final Tuesday wins could give any candidate an unchallengable advantage in the final stretch. `` If you can go into the convention just coming off of -LRB- a win in -RRB- <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION>, it's momentum,'' said Rep. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Florio </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.J. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> independent pollster <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Teichner </PERSON> said results from the two primaries also have the potential to sway several hundred uncommitted super delegates from around the nation. Those delegates, members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and other party leaders, will go to the national convention legally unpledged. In 1984, <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> Mondale </PERSON> and <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Hart </PERSON> battled for the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> nomination right up until the <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> primaries. <PERSON> Hart </PERSON> won in <LOCATION> Calfornia </LOCATION>, but <PERSON> Mondale </PERSON> _ who took <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> and several smaller states that day _ emerged the overall victor.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880314-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-14-88 0058EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Bush Bjt   03-14 0576</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bush, Bjt,580</SECOND>
<HEAD>Riding High In Illinois, Bush Ignores Dole, Makes Democrats His
Target</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ED WHITE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>GALESBURG, Ill. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Red lights do n't stop <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. The vice president's limousine glides along under state police escort, with cars pulling over to make way. Traffic signals are ignored; the curious crane their necks. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> is hoping Tuesday's <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> primary will be just as smooth a ride. Although heavily favored to win the state's <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> contest, with 82 delegates at stake, the vice president nonetheless has been spending 12-hour days on the campaign trail. But on the stump his targets are no longer Republican rivals like <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>, the <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> senator he crushed in the primaries of Super Tuesday. Instead, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> is aiming his rhetoric at Democrats. `` I've never seen such a gloomy bunch,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said of the Democrats, as he spoke to 500 people at a <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> dinner here. `` Everything they said about our country is negative _ midnight in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, by contrast, is upbeat. He ought to be _ he's so far ahead of <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> that the <ORGANIZATION> Chicago </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tribune </ORGANIZATION> has quit polling on the Republican side. At a stop in a campaign office in <LOCATION> Libertyville </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and Gov. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON>, who has been accompanying him around the state, made phone calls to try to round up votes. `` We're putting the hard sell on,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said into the telephone. `` We're at the grass-roots stage now.'' At stop after stop, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> delivers his message _ along with a series of one-liners. He said his success on Super Tuesday `` gave new meaning to the words Southern Comfort.'' He tells crowds he's got the support of the `` <ORGANIZATION> James </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Gang </ORGANIZATION>'' _ <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> Secretary of State <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Edgar </PERSON> and <LOCATION> Cook </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> Sheriff <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Grady </PERSON>. His standard speech includes pledges to trim the deficit in four years through tight spending, and to be tough with the Soviets. He says he expects criticism from the Democrats over the Iran-Contra affair _ he got some Sunday, from <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, who said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> had never fully explained his role in the matter. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, who says he has answered all questions about the matter except his private advice to the president on secret arms sales, said he was n't worried about Democrats harping on Iran-Contra. `` They'll raise it,'' he said. `` Of course they will. So what?'' The Democrats, he said, lack knowledge of foreign affairs. `` I ca n't wait to debate any one of those Democrats on foreign policy. None of them have had any experience except when they had breakfast at the <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pancakes </ORGANIZATION>,'' he said. He touches on the matter indirectly, perhaps, when he warns voters to expect to find a few warts. `` I might make a mistake here and there,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said, `` but I've had enough experience I would n't do it like <PERSON> Yogi </PERSON> <PERSON> Berra </PERSON> did They asked <PERSON> Yogi </PERSON> what went wrong when the <ORGANIZATION> Mets </ORGANIZATION> lost a few ball games. He said ` We made the wrong mistakes.''' `` You've got to think about it,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said. `` Anybody's going to make mistakes.'' In the bleachers at <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Viator </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> High </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Arlington </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Heights </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Scott </PERSON> <PERSON> Bieda </PERSON>, 30, held his 1 -LCB- - year-old daughter and nodded in agreement `` I like what I hear,'' he said. `` Those are the issues that are important to me: bargaining from strength and tackling the deficit. But you can say anything now. The proof is in the pudding. We'll see what happens if he gets in.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880314-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-14-88 0059EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Israel-ArabPolice Bjt   03-14 0722</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Israel-Arab Police, Bjt,0749</SECOND>
<HEAD>Policemen's Resignations Shake Occupied Territories</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN RICE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BETHLEHEM, Occupied West Bank (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A mass resignation of Arab policemen has displayed the muscle of the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> and posed a security dilemma for <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> and Palestinians alike in the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strip </LOCATION>. A national police spokesman, <PERSON> Yehoshua </PERSON> <PERSON> Goldapfel </PERSON>, on Sunday said that 450 of the 850 Arab police in the occupied territories `` have asked to leave the force.'' He left open the possibility more would depart. The police control crime and direct traffic, but they are not used to quell <PERSON> Arab </PERSON> rioting in the occupied lands, now in its fourth month. Arab officers in <LOCATION> Bethlehem </LOCATION> said all 70 Arab policemen would be off the job today at the city's headquarters office for the southern half of the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION>. As a shift ended at noon Sunday, newly retired officers drifted from the station in jeans and jackets into the central Manger Square. A dozen <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> soldiers in riot gear stood watch beside a phalanx of huge tour buses. `` I will be left without a job, without income,'' said traffic officer <PERSON> Mohammed </PERSON> <PERSON> Abu </PERSON> <PERSON> Ghayada </PERSON>, who spent 12 of his 36 years on the force. He said he might try driving a taxi. `` The people have decided, and we go with the decision of the Palestinian people,'' said policeman <PERSON> Fadl </PERSON> <PERSON> Najajri </PERSON>, a 15-year veteran and a father of nine. The walkout was triggered by a communique issued March 10 by the <ORGANIZATION> Palestine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> and clandestine local leaders of the violent protests against Israeli rule of the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strip </LOCATION>. The message was driven home for some officers by the March 8 stabbing death of a Palestinian policeman in <LOCATION> Jericho </LOCATION> accused of cooperating too closely with Israeli authorities. `` The killing in <LOCATION> Jericho </LOCATION> made me decide very quickly,'' said a 33-year-old policeman who gave his name only as <PERSON> Ramis </PERSON>. The National Police Commissioner, <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Krauss </PERSON>, told <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> radio on Sunday: `` There's pressure on them from the outside and a system of threats. But each one of them is organizing his friends, and we'll deal with them.'' He did not specify how. The resignations threaten to open wider cracks in <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s territorial administration, which employs 18,000 Arabs and is an important buffer between Israelis and the already rebellious Palestinians `` It is a precedent for many more civil servants to resign,'' said <LOCATION> Bethlehem </LOCATION> Mayor <PERSON> Elias </PERSON> <PERSON> Freij </PERSON>. Forty tax collectors in the <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strip </LOCATION> quit last week under pressure from underground organizers. Rioters in the village of <LOCATION> Qabatiyeh </LOCATION> on Feb. 24 lynched an alleged <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> collaborator who opened fire on a crowd nearing his house and killed a child. Authorities punished Qatabiyeh by banning visits of family members from abroad and forbidding the town's major export of stone to <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION>. Authorities also demolished houses of people accused of involvement in attacks on alleged collaborators. `` Such methods will be used against villages and groups we know are involved in attacks on people who are considered to be collaborators or people who are cooperating with authorities,'' said a senior military spokesman. But he also admitted on Sunday that <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> `` can not provide 100 percent security'' to all people who work with authorities. Police spokesman <PERSON> Nahum </PERSON> <PERSON> Mendel </PERSON> on Sunday termed the police resignations `` a big problem,'' and said authorities discussed offering pay raises to keep veteran officers. Several Arab officers said <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> superiors had offered to double their pay, now $ 400 to $ 500 a month, if they would stay. All said they refused. Arab businessmen also are worried by the disappearance of local protectors. `` The authorities will not bring any <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> police to this area. There will be no law here,'' said <PERSON> Rabah </PERSON> <PERSON> Abdeen </PERSON>, owner of a plastics factory and a gasoline station in <LOCATION> Bethlehem </LOCATION>. An <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> spokesman in the <LOCATION> Bethlehem </LOCATION> head office said police in <LOCATION> Ramallah </LOCATION>, 10 miles north of <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION>, were unable to respond to a major traffic accident on Sunday. `` I feel abandoned when out of 80 people at the station, only six of us were left,'' the <LOCATION> Ramallah </LOCATION> district commander, <PERSON> Miko </PERSON> <PERSON> Bachar </PERSON>, said on <ORGANIZATION> Israel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Television </ORGANIZATION>. He said all six were Israeli officers. <PERSON> Freij </PERSON> also said the resignations `` will vastly affect the process of the courts in the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION>,'' which together with those in the <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strip </LOCATION> handle about 200,000 cases a year, mostly traffic-related.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880314-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-14-88 0126EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Bechtel-Pipeline Bjt   03-14 0807</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bechtel-Pipeline, Bjt,830</SECOND>
<HEAD>Giant Overseas Building Company Caught up in Pipeline Case</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BRYAN BRUMLEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Bechtel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Group </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> , </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, a giant construction company which for years quietly built billion-dollar projects in the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION>, is receiving unwanted attention from a grand jury investigation of Attorney General <PERSON> Edwin </PERSON> <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>'s role in a failed <LOCATION> Mideast </LOCATION> pipeline deal. The aborted deal, to build a pipeline from Iraqi oilfields to the <LOCATION> Jordanian </LOCATION> port of <LOCATION> Aqaba </LOCATION>, was part of what <ORGANIZATION> Bechtel </ORGANIZATION> president <PERSON> Alden </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Yates </PERSON> called a `` project development scheme'' to boost business in a bad market. Falling oil prices were devastating the international construction business in 1984 when <ORGANIZATION> Bechtel </ORGANIZATION> began to draw up engineering and financing plans for the $ 1 billion pipeline. `` It did n't work for geopolitical reasons,'' <PERSON> Yates </PERSON> said in a telephone interview from <ORGANIZATION> Bechtel </ORGANIZATION> headquarters in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION>. Independent counsel <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> McKay </PERSON> is focusing on a possible bribery conspiracy involving <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> officials, <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Rappaport </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Swiss </LOCATION> businessman involved with <ORGANIZATION> Bechtel </ORGANIZATION> in the deal, <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> and <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Wallach </PERSON>, a close friend of <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> hired by <PERSON> Rappaport </PERSON> to garner administration backing for the project. Secretary of State <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON>, who was president of <ORGANIZATION> Bechtel </ORGANIZATION> before joining the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration in 1982, recused himself from any role in the pipeline negotiations, opening the way for <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> to become the pivotal Cabinet official in the deal. Former <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Caspar </PERSON> <PERSON> Weinberger </PERSON>, who served as <ORGANIZATION> Bechtel </ORGANIZATION>'s general counsel under <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON>, appears to have played no role in the deal In addition to the unwelcome publicity over the pipeline deal, <ORGANIZATION> Bechtel </ORGANIZATION> continues to have problems of a different nature, the same ones that drove it into the politically risky <LOCATION> Aqaba </LOCATION> pipeline deal. Lower oil prices, the dearth of nuclear projects and debt in the developing world have curtailed <ORGANIZATION> Bechtel </ORGANIZATION>'s trademark leviathan deals. `` People characterize us as not willing to take on little projects, but that's not true any more,'' said <PERSON> Yates </PERSON>. <ORGANIZATION> Bechtel </ORGANIZATION>'s business jumped from $ 7.6 billion in 1980 to an average of $ 13 billion annually 1981-83, and back down to $ 8.6 billion in 1984. It has fallen more gradually since then, forcing the company to seek new markets. <ORGANIZATION> Bechtel </ORGANIZATION>'s `` mega projects,'' those costing above $ 50 million, have dropped from 96 in 1983 to 73 in 1986. <PERSON> Yates </PERSON> declined to discuss the specifics of the pipeline case because it is under investigation, but he said it fit into a larger pattern under which <ORGANIZATION> Bechtel </ORGANIZATION> officials sought to spot potential jobs, prepare engineering reports and arrange financing for prospective clients. Along these lines, <ORGANIZATION> Bechtel </ORGANIZATION> since 1985 has been studying the possibility of building a second <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Canal </LOCATION>, said <PERSON> Yates </PERSON>. `` The Iraq-Jordan pipeline was a ` project development scheme,''' said <PERSON> Yates </PERSON>. `` In the old days, an oil company would send out a request for a project, and we would do it. Now we doing project development, looking at the stuff way upstream.'' In the pipeline deal, <ORGANIZATION> Bechtel </ORGANIZATION> sought out a partner in <LOCATION> Rappaport </LOCATION>, who owns oil refineries and tankers, and asked him to secure promises from <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> officials that they would not attack the pipeline, said company spokesman <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> Donner </PERSON>. <PERSON> Wallach </PERSON>, hired by <PERSON> Rappaport </PERSON>, wrote a memo to <LOCATION> Meese </LOCATION> on Sept. 25, 1985, saying that <PERSON> Rappaport </PERSON> had confirmed an arrangement with <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s then-prime minister <PERSON> Shimon </PERSON> <PERSON> Peres </PERSON> that `` <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> will receive somewhere between $ 65 - $ 70 million a year for 10 years out of the conclusion of the project `` What is also indicated to me, and which would be denied everywhere, is that a portion of those funds will go directly to Labor,'' wrote <PERSON> Wallach </PERSON>, in an apparent reference to <PERSON> Peres </PERSON>' Labor Party. <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> and his lawyers deny that the wording referred to a bribe _ the allegation the special prosecutor is investigating. Iraqi officials informed <ORGANIZATION> Bechtel </ORGANIZATION> in a letter dated Dec. 31, 1985, that they were dissatisfied with security arrangements and that the deal was off, said <PERSON> Donner </PERSON>. Other deals have gone bad for <ORGANIZATION> Bechtel </ORGANIZATION>. New orders fell from $ 13 billion in 1980 to $ 3.5 billion in 1986, the most recent year for which full statistics are available. And the payroll is down from a high of 45,000 to fewer than 18,000, according to company officials. They declined to provide profit figures. The company still prefers massive projects, but has expanded into such new areas as computerized factories, space and weapons technology and toxic waste cleanup, said <PERSON> Yates </PERSON>. `` If you can do a $ 1 billion job, it is easier than doing ten $ 100 million jobs,'' he said in a succinct statement of the Bechtel credo. <ORGANIZATION> Bechtel </ORGANIZATION> still pulls down its share of big jobs worldwide. Its engineers are involved in the $ 9.6 billion project to build the Eurotunnel under the English channel. <ORGANIZATION> Bechtel </ORGANIZATION> also is building a $ 3.3 billion tunnel project in <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> and a $ 2.7 billion project to develop a new central terminal at <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Kennedy </LOCATION> <LOCATION> International </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880314-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-14-88 0127EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-AIDS-Children Bjt   03-14 0659</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AIDS-Children, Bjt,0678</SECOND>
<HEAD>Kids With AIDS: A Life Nasty, Brutish And Short</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LARRY McSHANE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Nine-year-old <PERSON> Celeste </PERSON> has big brown eyes and long brown hair. She also has no mother, no father, no little brother and almost no hope. `` All in all, she's been one of the lucky ones,'' says <PERSON> Anita </PERSON> <PERSON> Septimus </PERSON>, head of social services at the <ORGANIZATION> Albert </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Einstein </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medicine </ORGANIZATION>, which runs the nation's largest pediatric AIDS clinic. <PERSON> Celeste </PERSON> is among a growing number of children who are victims of congenital AIDS. They must pay with their future for a parent's past _ a problem that becomes more common as the disease enters the heterosexual population Both of <PERSON> Celeste </PERSON>'s parents were intravenous drug users who contracted AIDS; her mother died in 1983, her father died last year. <PERSON> Celeste </PERSON> and her brother were infected in the uterus. He died Christmas Eve. Every two weeks, to assist and extend her fragile life, <PERSON> Celeste </PERSON> is given treatments of gamma globulin, blood serum that contains a high concentration of antibodies. She is the oldest youngster of more than a dozen treated there. Some, less than a year old, are born to die; others face years of battling the disease and the cruel ostracism that often surrounds it. In either case, the prognosis for such children remains invariably pessimistic, specialists say. `` We have never seen anybody who has beaten the disease,'' <PERSON> Einstein </PERSON>'s Dr. <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Bernstein </PERSON> said recently. `` I think you get to a certain point and hope you can stay there, not deteriorate further.'' Recent state Health Department figures indicate the potential number of AIDS-infected newborns is growing at a startling rate. One in every 61 babies born in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> last November carried antibodies to the AIDS virus, which means they had been exposed to the virus. About 40 percent of these children will develop acquired immune deficiency syndrome in some form; 25 percent to 30 percent of those children will be dead before their second birthday. Most of them were born to mothers who used drugs intravenously. Dr. <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON>, the city health commissioner, put the number of children born in the city with AIDS antibodies last year at about 600; for 1988 the projection is 1,000. Between 1980 and 1986, the total was only about 250 children. In fact, AIDS babies were cited as the reason for the first increase in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>'s infant mortality rate since 1974. One reason for the spurt is the large number of addicts in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. Intravenous drug abusers make up almost half the city's AIDS population while in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> and most other cities with large AIDS populations, most sufferers are homosexual But even in <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION>, a state not known for large outbreaks of AIDS, one in 476 child-bearing women tested positive for AIDS antibodies, according to a study reported recently in the New England Journal of Medicine. Nationwide, there were 865 cases of pediatric AIDS reported as of Feb. 29, with 111 diagnosed in just the first two months of the year. Altogether, 518 children are known to have died of AIDS. The Bronx Municipal Hospital Day Care Center, the nation's first day care facility for AIDS-infected children, opened in June 1986 to help out; <PERSON> Septimus </PERSON> said another is planned for <PERSON> Einstein </PERSON>. Sixty-five percent of the <PERSON> Einstein </PERSON> kids live in foster homes, she said. But some have spent so much time in hospitals, in broken homes or at arm's length from a terrified society that social skills like speaking have not been properly developed. In fact, they say the children remain innocent victims to the end, never realizing they were born without much of a chance. `` Some of the older kids have a sense of it, but even the ones who are older have physical delays _ an 8-year-old with the intelligence of a 5-year-old,'' said <PERSON> Bernstein </PERSON>. `` But we do n't have that many older kids, so we do n't know.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880314-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-14-88 0115EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i BC-Japan-Stocks     03-14 0029</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Japan-Stocks,0029</SECOND>
<HEAD>Stocks Close Lower In Japan</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Nikkei Stock Average closed at 25,433.51 points, down 110.22 points, on the <ORGANIZATION> Tokyo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Stock </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Exchange </ORGANIZATION> on Monday.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880314-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-14-88 0140EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lites     03-14 0426</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lites,0439</SECOND>
<HEAD>On The Light Side</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MIAMI (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 `` Come on everybody _ let's do the conga!'' was the rallying cry for more than 120,000 people who lined up at <LOCATION> Little </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Havana </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Calle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ocho </LOCATION> festival and danced into the record books. About 1.5 million people were jammed along 23 blocks of Eighth Street -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> Calle </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ocho </ORGANIZATION> in Spanish -RRB- on Sunday when <PERSON> Gloria </PERSON> <PERSON> Estefan </PERSON> and the <ORGANIZATION> Miami </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sound </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Machine </ORGANIZATION> set about forming a conga line. `` Is everybody ready? Let's conga,'' said Ms. <PERSON> Estefan </PERSON> as her band began playing their hit `` Conga.'' People began to grab the shoulders in front of them and sidestep to the Latin beat. `` There's no way it could fail. As soon as the music plays, we just grab on to somebody and hang on,'' said <PERSON> Nuvia </PERSON> <PERSON> Valdez </PERSON>, who showed up early to take part in the historic strut. When it was over, <PERSON> Anna </PERSON> <PERSON> Nicholas </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Guinness </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Book </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Records </ORGANIZATION> confirmed a record line of 119,986 dancers, shattering the old mark of a 10,442-person chain formed last August in <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>. The computer-assisted count was made by volunteers at 30 observation posts. `` It may seem like a conga line is an inane thing, but it represents a lot more,'' Ms. <PERSON> Estefan </PERSON> said. `` Because this community is so diverse, getting along and having a street party of this magnitude really says a lot about our city.'' The festival began as a block party 11 years ago to showcase <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION>'s Cuban culture.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>CHICAGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 There are gadget lovers. There are cat lovers. There are people who love home improvement projects. If enough people fall into all three categories, the maker of the electronic cat door is in luck. <ORGANIZATION> Reilor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Horsham </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION> is showing off its product here at the annual National Home Center Show, which started Sunday. The cat door comes with a coded collar key so only the owner's cat can enter The door can be programmed to open from only the inside or only the outside, or from both sides. It's available at pet stores for $ 120 - $ 150, said <PERSON> Shelley </PERSON> <PERSON> Daniels </PERSON>, a spokeswoman for the show An estimated 36,000 retailers are expected to attend the show, sponsored by Home Center Magazine of <LOCATION> Lincolnshire </LOCATION>. The magazine says it did a recent survey of 1,561 homeowners across the country that found 93 percent of those households undertook at least one home improvement project last year. `` <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> homeowners seem willing to tackle almost any type of home improvement imaginable,'' said <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Berry </PERSON>, an official of <ORGANIZATION> Vance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Publishing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, the company producing the show.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880314-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-14-88 0143EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-AndersonAnniversary Bjt   03-14 0722</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Anderson Anniversary, Bjt,730</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHINGTON WIRE: Our Man in Lebanon: 1,094 Days As Hostage</HEAD>
<BYLINE>An AP News Analysis</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>By JONATHAN WOLMAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The reigning drama of 1980 was not so much the <PERSON> Carter-Reagan </PERSON> campaign but the interminable hostage crisis in <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION>. The two became intertwined, and as <PERSON> Jimmy </PERSON> <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> gave up his presidency, 52 Americans were being returned to freedom. `` The pain's gone; the weight's lifted,'' <PERSON> Dorothea </PERSON> <PERSON> Morefield </PERSON> exulted as her husband ended 444 days of nerve-wracking captivity. `` We can all drink to this one,'' <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said. Cut to 1988. Another presidential campaign is in high gear and a new set of Americans is held captive in the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION>. This time around, the hostages are bound and blindfolded far from the political limelight; the hope is that obscurity will diminish their value. For <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON>, Tuesday will mark three full years as hostage. It has been 1,094 days since <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON>, returning from a tennis game, was shoved at gunpoint into a waiting car. <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> is an old friend, your basic boy-next-door, off to see the world in a foreign correspondent's trench coat. He has an enviable talent for finding the story and telling it straight, whether in <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION> or <LOCATION> Johannesburg </LOCATION> or <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>. We spent our salad days together in <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION>'s <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION> bureau; he filed the state broadcast wire and lived out towards <PERSON> Ann </PERSON> <PERSON> Arbor </PERSON> with his family and a wonderful collection of Japanese etchings. From <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION>, he became <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION>'s chief <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> correspondent by way of tours in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>. In 1984, <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> and I had lunch in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> and he caught me up on the dangers and satisfaction of reporting the complex story of <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>. I told him we called it `` wartornLebanon'' as if it were one long word. He laughed. Now he is a part of the wartornLebanon story, longest held of some two dozen Westerners missing in the sad city of <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>. I was out pricing washing machines on Saturday, March 16, 1985, when a radio newscast said an <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> reporter had been kidnapped in <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>. I figured it might be <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON>, and it was. I figured he might be free by Monday, and he was n't. Who would have thought a year would go by, or two, let alone three? That his baby would be born and he would n't know? She would turn one, learn to walk, learn to talk, and he would n't know. Last spring she turned two. Is she a terrible two? Is she eating her vegetables? He would n't know. The washing machine is three years old and <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> is still the property of Shiite kidnappers, currency in a geopolitical ordeal that has killed two American hostages and threatens the remaining eight. <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> <PERSON> Waite </PERSON>, who negotiated tirelessly for all the Western hostages, now shares their fate. In March 1986, we marked the first <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> anniversary in a church on <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Avenue </LOCATION>. It was an optimistic gathering; perhaps freedom was just around the corner. Rarely had a hostage been held so long; we hoped he was holding up. <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, who knew <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> celebrity-to-reporter, delivered a call for peace and brotherhood and deliverance. Hostage relatives expressed frustration, and more. `` There have been so many times that I was frightened they would do something to them,'' <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON>'s sister, <PERSON> Peggy </PERSON> <PERSON> Say </PERSON>, said of the six Americans then in captivity. Another hostage relative, <PERSON> Sue </PERSON> <PERSON> Franceschini </PERSON>, said, `` I'm on automatic pilot most of the time, but we made it through the holidays.'' Her brother, Rev. <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Jenco </PERSON>, would be released in 1986, but for others, more holidays would pass and more Americans would be taken. The second <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> anniversary was marked at a second church, up 16th St. from the White House. The Iran-Contra story was out and it was clear that the hostages were key pawns in a multi-level `` arms for hostages'' intrigue. Optimism? Not so you could notice. The third <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> anniversary is upon us and Wednesday we gather in a third church, this time for a candlelight and olive branch ceremony in <LOCATION> Georgetown </LOCATION>. The pain, not gone. The weight, not lifted. No one knows how <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> will mark the day. He was last heard from in a videotape on Christmas Eve, day 1,012.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Jonathan </PERSON> <PERSON> Wolman </PERSON> is <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION>'s assistant bureau chief in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880314-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-14-88 0146EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-CandidateGore Bjt   03-14 0830</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Candidate Gore, Bjt,830</SECOND>
<HEAD>Gore Draws On Disparate Background To Appeal To Different Groups</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By WILLIAM M. WELCH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
