<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880703-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-03-88 0047EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-VesselSeized 1stLd-Writethru a0680 07-03 0260</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Vessel Seized, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0680,0264</SECOND>
<HEAD>Eighteen Arrested After Coast Guard Opens Fire On Vessel With
Drugs On Board</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: ADDS ``supply vessel'' to last graf pvs, `DeLong said...,' to
clarify type of ship.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>SEATTLE (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Panamanian officials granted the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> permission to seize a drug-carrying, Panamania-registered vessel before the <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> fired 60 rounds into its engine room, officials said Saturday. The Encounter Bay, with a cargo of more than 50 tons of marijuana and 18 crewmen were being taken to <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION>, where they are expected to arrive Wednesday, <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> spokesman Lt. <PERSON> Eldo </PERSON> <PERSON> DeLong </PERSON> said. The incident took place Thursday night, several hundred miles off the <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> coast in international waters, after a patrolling <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> C-130 aircraft reported a suspicious vessel, and after permission to board the ship was granted by Panamanian Embassy authorities. The Coast Guard cutter <PERSON> Boutwell </PERSON> opened fire with a .50 - caliber machine gun after repeated and varied efforts failed to stop the 180-foot vessel, said another <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> spokesman, Petty Officer 1st Class <PERSON> Craig </PERSON> There were no reports of injuries. Authorities boarded the vessel and arrested the crew, <PERSON> DeLong </PERSON> said. He said Guardsmen did n't know the marijuana was on board when they tried to stop the vessel. The 18 crewmen were being held aboard the <PERSON> Boutwell </PERSON>, said <PERSON> Herlihy </PERSON>. The marijuana has an estimated street value of $ 220 million. <PERSON> DeLong </PERSON> said damage was minimal to the Encounter Bay, a converted off-shore oil rig supply vessel, but it was being towed to <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION> where it will be taken into <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Customs custody.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880703-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-03-88 0414EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i BC-Israel     07-03 0217</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Israel,0224</SECOND>
<HEAD>Police Fire Tear Gas on Rioters in Old Walled Jerusalem</HEAD>
<DATELINE>JERUSALEM (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Police fired tear gas grenades and rubber bullets Sunday to disperse hundreds of stone-throwing Arabs on the biblical Via <LOCATION> Dolorosa </LOCATION> in the walled Old City of <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION>. At least eight people were injured, witnesses said. Massive police reinforcements were rushed to the <LOCATION> Old </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. Police closed its gates and major streets leading into it, witnesses said. The riot was one of the most serious in Arab east <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION> since the Palestinian uprising against Israeli rule started nearly seven months ago. In the uprising, 215 Palestinians and four Israelis have died. Sunday's violence began with a protest over an archaeological excavation close to the Western Wall and the Temple Mount in the <LOCATION> Old </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, according to <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> officials and police reports. <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Bahat </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION> district archaeologist, told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> that the dig began Sunday to clean part of the ancient <LOCATION> Hasmonean </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Tunnel </LOCATION>, a 300-yard cave. But an Arab prayer leader called on Arabs to gather, claiming authorities actually intended to dig a tunnel, <PERSON> Bahat </PERSON> and <PERSON> Arab </PERSON> reports said. <PERSON> Bahat </PERSON> said the tunnel links the wall, the last remnant of the ancient Jewish Temple, with the <LOCATION> Via </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dolorosa </LOCATION>, which according to Christian tradition was <PERSON> Jesus </PERSON>' route from <ORGANIZATION> Pilate </ORGANIZATION>'s judgement hall to <LOCATION> Golgotha </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880703-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-03-88 0451EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a BC-SovietInspections-Sites     07-03 0254</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Soviet Inspections-Sites,0262</SECOND>
<HEAD>Three INF Treaty Verification Inspection Sites Named</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TRAVIS AIR FORCE BASE, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Officials named three additional sites where Soviet inspectors will monitor compliance with the treaty to eliminate medium-range nuclear missiles. One group was to leave <PERSON> Travis </PERSON> early Sunday for a cruise missile testing and training facility at <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Huachuca </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ariz. </LOCATION>, about 60 miles south of <LOCATION> Tucson </LOCATION>, said Master Sgt. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Castillo </PERSON>, a spokesman at <LOCATION> Travis </LOCATION>. Another group will visit <ORGANIZATION> Davis-Monthan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Base </ORGANIZATION> near <LOCATION> Tucson </LOCATION>, a missile training center that later will be an elimination site where Soviets can monitor missile destruction, <PERSON> Castillio </PERSON> said. A third team will inspect the <ORGANIZATION> Pebulo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Depot </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Pebulo </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Colo. </LOCATION>, where Pershing II missiles are stored and repaired, he said. The Soviet teams are part of a contingent of 70 missile specialists who arrived at <LOCATION> Travis </LOCATION> on Friday night. A group of 22 Soviet on-site inspectors was welcomed Saturday to <LOCATION> Salt </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> to begin its spot check at the <ORGANIZATION> Hercules </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aerospace </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> missile plant in <LOCATION> Magna </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION>, where Pershing II missiles banned under the Intermediate-range Nuclear Forces Treaty were produced. A group of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> inspectors arrived in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> on Friday under the treaty signed by President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and Soviet leader <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> in December. The INF pact, the first to allow such on-site inspection, is viewed as a trial for the proposed <ORGANIZATION> Strategic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Arms </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reduction </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Treaty </ORGANIZATION>, which would slash arsenals of long-range superpower nuclear weapons by 30 percent to 50 percent, and involve much more complicated verification procedures.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880703-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-03-88 0600EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i BC-Taiwan-Earthquake     07-03 0178</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Taiwan-Earthquake,0184</SECOND>
<HEAD>Earthquake Injures 13 in Taiwan</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TAIPEI, Taiwan (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A strong earthquake shook northern <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION> on Sunday. Police said it unleashed rockslides that injured 13 people. They said the injured people were hit by falling rocks at three waterfall tourist sites in suburban <LOCATION> Taipei </LOCATION>. The quake, measuring 5.5 on the <PERSON> Richter </PERSON> scale, set off rock avalanches in an area covering 1,200 square yards, authorities said. The injured, who were all Taiwanese, were taken to a hospital, police said. One was reported to be in serious condition, and the others suffered only minor injuries. The Central Weather Bureau placed the epicenter of the early-afternoon earthquake in <LOCATION> Sanchi </LOCATION>, a coastal village about 10 miles north of <LOCATION> Taipei </LOCATION>. The earthquake was felt in the capital, where residents reported their houses shook violently, the bureau said. The Richter scale measures ground motion as recorded on seismographs. Every increase of one number means a ten-fold increase in intensity. An earthquake of magnitude 5 can cause serious damage in a populated area, and one of magnitude 6 can cause severe damage.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880703-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-03-88 0616EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a BC-BombThreat     07-03 0151</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Bomb Threat,0155</SECOND>
<HEAD>Pakistan Airlines Jet Returns To Kennedy After Bomb Threat</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A <ORGANIZATION> Pakistan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> jetliner with 274 people on board returned to <LOCATION> Kennedy </LOCATION> <LOCATION> International </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION> early Sunday after police received a threat of a bomb aboard the <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> 747, officials said. No bomb was found, and there were no reported injuries. The anonymous threat was called into the 911 police emergency number at 10:58 p.m. Saturday. The plane, Flight No. 712, a 10:15 p.m. departure to <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Karachi </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>, was already airborne, said <ORGANIZATION> Port </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Authority </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION> Officer <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Palermo </PERSON>. The airline was notified and the pilot decided to return to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Palermo </PERSON> said. The plane touched down just before 2:30 a.m., he said. The passengers were taken off the plane while the craft and the luggage were searched. Passengers were expected to reboard and resume their flight later Sunday morning, <PERSON> Palermo </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880703-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-03-88 0729EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i BC-Japan-Explosion     07-03 0154</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Japan-Explosion,0161</SECOND>
<HEAD>Four Killed, 30 Injured in Japanese Mill Explosion</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An explosion rocked a steel mill in western <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> on Sunday, killing four workers and injuring 30 others, police reported. They said six of the injured were severely poisoned with carbon monoxide gas. A police official, who spoke on condition of anonymity, said the blast occurred at the <LOCATION> Kure </LOCATION> plant of <ORGANIZATION> Nisshin </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Steel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, a blast-furnace steel producer. The cause of the explosion, which destroyed a fuel pipe, was under investigation. The carbon monoxide gas dispersed without affecting residents of <LOCATION> Kure </LOCATION>, which is about a half mile from the plant, the official said. <PERSON> Toshiaki </PERSON> <PERSON> Kawatoko </PERSON>, a spokesman for <ORGANIZATION> Nisshin </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Steel </ORGANIZATION>, told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> that 34 employees, including engineers, were working at a new furnace when the explosion occurred. The blast did not start a fire, he said. <ORGANIZATION> Nisshin </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Steel </ORGANIZATION> makes about 3 million tons of steel products a year.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880703-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-03-88 0847EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i BC-Germany-HelicopterCrash     07-03 0182</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Germany-Helicopter Crash,0186</SECOND>
<HEAD>Up to Eight People Feared Dead in Helicopter Crash</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> GARMISCH-PARTENKIRCHEN </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> -RRB- _ A <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> German </LOCATION> army helicopter slammed into a cliff and crashed in a wooded area Sunday. As many as eight people were feared dead, police said. Hesse state radio in <LOCATION> Frankfurt </LOCATION> reported that 13 people were on board the helicopter and that all were probably dead. The number of people actually aboard the aircraft could not be immediately determined. Rescue teams were on their way to the crash scene near the Bavarian resort community of <LOCATION> Garmisch-Partenkirchen </LOCATION>, police said. A spokesman for the West German army in <LOCATION> Mittenwald </LOCATION>, 12 miles east of <LOCATION> Garmisch-Partenkirchen </LOCATION>, said the helicopter had exploded. The weather was rainy and foggy when the accident occurred in the mountainous area, the army spokesman said. The helicopter took off at about 10 a.m. from army barracks near <LOCATION> Mittenwald </LOCATION>. Hikers in the area saw the helicopter explode, a <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> spokesman said in <LOCATION> Bonn </LOCATION>. The aircraft, identified as a Bell UH-1-D, apparently slammed into a cliff, said the spokesman, who asked not to be identified.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880703-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-03-88 1111EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-NotDead     07-03 0157</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Not Dead,0159</SECOND>
<HEAD>Dead Man Not Dead, Three Arrested</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW DELHI, India (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A policeman who was supposed to be dead turned up alive and was arrested along with his wife and son after they tried to collect $ 5,400 in benefits, the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> India </ORGANIZATION> said Sunday. The news agency reported that Constable <PERSON> Ganesh </PERSON> <PERSON> Singh </PERSON>, from the town of <LOCATION> Balaghat </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Madhya </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Pradesh </LOCATION> state, went on leave two weeks before his retirement June 1. A few days later, his son told authorities <PERSON> Singh </PERSON> had died of a heart attack. A sum of 70,000 rupees, about $ 5,400, was granted to the constable's family because the man died in service. But before his family was able to cash in, a police officer spotted <PERSON> Singh </PERSON> strolling around the Balaghat railway station. The constable confessed he, his wife and son had plotted his `` death'' because benefits for a policeman dying in service were higher than normal retirement pensions.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880703-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-03-88 1112EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-China-Rocket     07-03 0367</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-China-Rocket,0379</SECOND>
<HEAD>China Announces Debut Of More Powerful Rocket</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> announced it has developed a new, more powerful rocket in its successful Long March series and said it soon will launch a meteorological satellite into space. The new Long March 4 has a propelling power of 300 tons and the capability of putting a 2.5-ton payload into orbit, the official <ORGANIZATION> Xinhua </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> said late Saturday. Aeronautics officials hope the new rocket will help attract more foreign customers for <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s nearly 3-year-old satellite launch service, which despite cut-rate prices has only one customer under contract. <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> has launched 22 of its own satellites in the past 18 years using the Long March 1, 2 and 3 rockets. Most recently, the Long March 3 sent a communications satellite into orbit that <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> said would double domestic communications capacity. The Long March 3 was introduced in April 1984. It can put up to 1.4-ton load in long-distance orbit and up to 3 tons in low-altitude orbit. The <ORGANIZATION> Xinhua </ORGANIZATION> report quoted <PERSON> Chen </PERSON> <PERSON> Shouchun </PERSON>, chief engineer of the <ORGANIZATION> Great </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wall </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Industrial </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s launch company, as saying the No. 3 rocket uses advanced low-temperature technology applied in only a few other countries. He did not give any details about the new Long March 4. <ORGANIZATION> Xinhua </ORGANIZATION> said in November that scientists had modified the Long March 3 to nearly double its launch capabilities. It was not clear if that modified version was the same as the Long March 4. <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> announced its international launch service in October 1985, hoping to take advantage of the halt in the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> space shuttle and European launching programs caused by accidents. The <ORGANIZATION> Great </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wall </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Industrial </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> has reported numerous inquiries from potential foreign customers, but only one, <ORGANIZATION> Sweden </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Space </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, has signed a formal contract. <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> agreed in December to launch a scientific and telecommunications satellite for <LOCATION> Sweden </LOCATION> using the Long March 2. No date has been set. Last month, <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> signed a tentative agreement with a consortium of three Chinese, British and <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> companies to launch a communications satellite to serve <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION>. Similar non-binding launch agreements with two <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> companies, <ORGANIZATION> Teresat </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>. And <ORGANIZATION> Pan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pacific </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, subsequently fell through
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880703-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-03-88 1112EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-LangeHospitalized     07-03 0172</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Lange Hospitalized,0174</SECOND>
<HEAD>New Zealand Prime Minister Admitted To Hospital</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WELLINGTON, New Zealand (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Prime Minister <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Lange </PERSON> was admitted to a hospital after suffering chest pains, according to a statement issued by his office Sunday. Doctors at <ORGANIZATION> Green </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lane </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Auckland </LOCATION> said Sunday that <PERSON> Lange </PERSON>'s condition was comfortable but that he was likely to remain in the hospital for several days. A hospital spokesman said <PERSON> Lange </PERSON> did not suffer a heart attack. <PERSON> Lange </PERSON>, 45, was suffering from a heavy bout of influenza last week and experienced associated chest pains later, <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Wicksteed </PERSON>, <PERSON> Lange </PERSON>'s press officer, said. Deputy Prime Minister <PERSON> Geoffrey </PERSON> <PERSON> Palmer </PERSON> cut short a trip and returned home at <PERSON> Lange </PERSON>'s request. <PERSON> Palmer </PERSON> went directly to the hospital to visit <PERSON> Lange </PERSON> after flying into <LOCATION> Auckland </LOCATION> on Sunday and told reporters the prime minister was in good spirits. `` The prime minister is expected to remain in hospital for several days and return to work in one or two weeks with no limitations imposed on his activities,'' the hospital spokesman said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880703-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-03-88 1113EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Plane-BombScare     07-03 0142</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Plane-Bomb Scare,0143</SECOND>
<HEAD>TWA Flight Bound for New York Delayed by Bomb Scare</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CAIRO, Egypt (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A <ORGANIZATION> TWA </ORGANIZATION> jetliner bound for <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> returned to <LOCATION> Cairo </LOCATION> <LOCATION> International </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION> after taking off Sunday because a telephone caller claimed there was a bomb on board, an airport official said. The official, speaking on condition of anonymity, said the jet returned to the air at 1 p.m. -LRB- 6 a.m. EDT -RRB-, 5 -LCB- hours later, after the plane was evacuated and its passengers and luggage searched. No bomb was found. He said someone called minutes after the plane took off for <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> en route to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>. The anonymous caller said there was a bomb on the plane and hung up. The official said 156 passengers of various nationalities were aboard the plane. He said one American woman refused to get back on the plane.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880703-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-03-88 1114EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Soviet-JulyFourth     07-03 0210</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Soviet-July Fourth,0215</SECOND>
<HEAD>Soviets Wish Americans Peace On Fourth Of July</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MOSCOW (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The legislature of the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> sent July Fourth greetings Sunday to President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and Americans and said the world looks forward to improved relations between the superpowers. Also Sunday, the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> newspaper Pravda accused Vice President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> of favoring Cold War policies toward the <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION>. The Presidium, or executive committee, of the Supreme Soviet, sent <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> a telegram extending `` congratulations and wishes of peace and well-being to the <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> people.'' The <ORGANIZATION> Tass </ORGANIZATION> news agency reported that the message referred to `` important and fruitful results'' of the December summit between <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and Soviet leader <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> and their meeting in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> in late May and early June. The message cited the new treaty eliminating superpower shorter-and medium-range nuclear missiles and progress on efforts to cut strategic nuclear weapons as fruits of `` the constructive Soviet-American dialogue whose continuation and deepening are being awaited by the entire world.'' But commentator <PERSON> Vladislav </PERSON> <PERSON> Drobkov </PERSON> wrote in Pravda that presidental candidate <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> still believed in Cold War policies between the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. Pravda said it could not understand why <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> would `` draw such gloomy perspectives of further development of ties between our two countries.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880703-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-03-88 1132EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-SlovakPilgrimage     07-03 0392</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Slovak Pilgrimage,0406</SECOND>
<HEAD>Slovak Pilgrimage Testifies to Religious Revival</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ROLAND PRINZ</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LEVOCA, Czechoslovakia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 At least 100,000 Slovak Roman Catholics converged on a remote hillside Sunday in a show of religious strength 40 years after the Communist takeover. The pilgrims thronged the <ORGANIZATION> Virgin </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Levoca </LOCATION>, an eastern Slovak town of 11,000 about 25 miles from the Polish border. Some said they walked up to 125 miles. Pilgrims and some independent observers said that up to 200,000 people may have attended the pilgrimage, which began Friday and is an annual event started more than 200 years ago. `` Interest in religion before our very eyes is growing,'' <PERSON> Stefan </PERSON> <PERSON> Garaj </PERSON>, the apostolic administrator of <LOCATION> Spiss </LOCATION> diocese, told the crowd at an open air Mass. Thousands arrived Friday and stayed through Sunday for 20 hours of Masses, prayer sessions and singing that climaxed with Sunday's open air Mass <LOCATION> Czechoslovakia </LOCATION>'s Catholics have been buoyed by the recent consecration of two auxiliary bishops in <LOCATION> Prague </LOCATION> and bishop <PERSON> Jan </PERSON> <PERSON> Sokol </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Trnava </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Slovakia </LOCATION>'s largest diocese. The church has also been strengthened by a petition signed by about 600,000 people calling for religious freedom and the appointment of new bishops. About 60 percent of the 15.5 million residents of <LOCATION> Czechoslovakia </LOCATION> are Roman Catholics, according to church officials. Most of them are Slovaks. <PERSON> Garaj </PERSON> hailed Pope <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> II </PERSON> as `` the greatest pilgrim of our century.'' The pope was not at the pilgrimage. Many worshipers spent the night in tents. Elderly Slovak women knelt in the mud hours after a downpour had soaked the ground. Groups of young people trekked up and down the hill led by youths carrying wooden crosses. Attendance at the <LOCATION> Levoca </LOCATION> pilgrimage dropped during the 1950s but began to pick up again in 1968 during a brief liberalization attempt in <LOCATION> Czechoslovakia </LOCATION>. It was crushed when Soviet tanks intervened. Attendance has been growing since then. Police watched the crowd climb the hill on three different treks but did not interfere. An unspecified number of plainclothes police were said to be observing the rites. The recent appointment of bishops came after 15 years in which the <LOCATION> Prague </LOCATION> government and the <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION> failed to agree on candidates acceptable to both sides. None of the three new bishops is a member of Pacem in <LOCATION> Terris </LOCATION>, a pro-government clergymen's organization banned by the <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880703-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-03-88 1134EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-China-SoccerBrawl     07-03 0201</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-China-Soccer Brawl,0204</SECOND>
<HEAD>Soccer Players Attack Referee After Teammate Penalized</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Shanghai </LOCATION> soccer players punched and shoved a referee who penalized a teammate, and police had to break up the brawl, an official newspaper reported. Authorities have not decided what penalty to impose on the players, the <LOCATION> Shanghai </LOCATION> newspaper <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> said in its Saturday edition, seen Sunday in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>. It did not say if any were arrested. The report said the fight broke out June 29 during a game between the <ORGANIZATION> Shanghai </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Diesel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Engine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Factory </ORGANIZATION> team and a military team. The game was tied 1-1 when referee <PERSON> Tang </PERSON> <PERSON> Jaikang </PERSON> penalized a member of the factory team for rushing at the legs of an opponent and knocking him down as he tried to score. A teammate of the penalized man punched <PERSON> Tang </PERSON>, and other teammates joined in, the paper said. When <PERSON> Tang </PERSON> broke away, one player chased the referee and knocked him in the stomach and injured him. Game officials expelled those who attacked <PERSON> Tang </PERSON> and tried to resume play but the penalized players seized the ball and began running with it, the paper said. Police finally arrived and ended the mayhem, and the game was called off.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880703-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-03-88 1136EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p AM-Democrats-Unity Bjt   07-03 0914</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Democrats-Unity, Bjt,910</SECOND>
<HEAD>Democrats Unusually Unified Heading Into Convention</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID ESPO</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Political Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Think of recent Democratic National Conventions. Sweet harmony does n't exactly spring to mind. More like bitter divisions that spilled over into street battles in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> 20 years ago. Or the last-ditch floor fight that Sen. <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> waged against President <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> in 1980. Or a nasty little firefight over selection of a new party chairman four years ago that weakened <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Mondale </PERSON> almost on the eve of his nomination. But this time officials in <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' campaign and other Democrats, pointing to quick work on platform, rules and credentials issues, say they expect to present a unified front to their four-day prime-time television audience beginning on July 18. Barring an unexpected disruption by <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> or his supporters over the selection of a vice presidential running mate, of course. `` The party is as unified as it has been since 1964, and that was when you had an incumbent president,'' says <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Kirk </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> party </ORGANIZATION> chairman _ and the man who managed <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>'s unsuccessful campaign in 1980 <PERSON> Kirk </PERSON>'s view is semi-shared by <PERSON> Eddie </PERSON> <PERSON> Mahe </PERSON>, a Republican political consultant. `` They are willing to subordinate any and all personal and interest group agendas in the interests of victory,'' he says of this year's Democrats. But <PERSON> Mahe </PERSON> added that Democratic unity is likely to prove short-lived and that special interests will reassert themselves if <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> wins the White House in the fall. `` The day they win, <PERSON> Katie </PERSON> bar the door,'' he said. That's a problem Democrats will worry about if and when the time comes. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> has made a number of largely symbolic concessions to <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> since the primary season ended, and party officials are crowing about the relatively smooth transition between the primary campaign and the convention. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, who will have the support of more 1,100 delegates at the convention, has said repeatedly that he deserves a vice presidential offer, and that he has decided whether he would accept one but wo n't say what his decision is. He and his wife will have dinner at the <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> home on Monday, and the topic of the vice presidency is expected to come up. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> is widely expected by his aides to select a different running mate, and the <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> governor frequently quotes <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s earlier statements that a nominee is entitled to make his own pick. Other Democrats say they doubt <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> will raise a furor if he is passed over, although there has been no clue about what might happen if <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> chooses a political partner whom <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> finds offensive. `` I think he has been and will be very positive no matter what happens,'' said Rep. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON>, the <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION> congressman who challenged for the presidential nomination last winter. With the exception of the vice presidential nomination, this year's <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> campaign has been remarkably free of the types of disputes that produced divisions in earlier conventions. This year: _ <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> wrapped up the nomination on the final day of the primaries, and unlike in 1980 and 1984 no one has questioned his control over a majority of delegates. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> has continued to campaign publicly, occasionally sniping at the <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> governor, but thus far has never suggested summoning his forces for an all-out fight such as the one Kennedy waged in 1980. The other, losing contenders generally have endorsed <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> warmly and most of them are expected to speak at the convention, although <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Hart </PERSON> will be in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> writing a newspaper column and offering commentary for an Italian television audience. _ Democratic draftsmen came up with the shortest platform in decades, in keeping with <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' desires and <PERSON> Kirk </PERSON>'s hope of avoiding a `` litany of social, cultural or ideological buzzwords.'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> yielded to <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> on some issues, notably his desire to brand <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> a terrorist state and his call for periodic increases in the federal minimum wage to keep pace with inflation. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> has described the platform as bland, and his aides have filed a dozen minority planks for possible votes at the convention. But <PERSON> Kirk </PERSON> says, `` If there are planks that will be discussed and debated it will be a civil agreement to disagree.'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> aides sound almost like they welcome a floor vote to demonstrate their stand against higher taxes and a <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> freeze, two key <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> demands. `` There may be some fights and that's a normal part of the process and <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> will stick to his position,'' says <PERSON> Leslie </PERSON> <PERSON> Dach </PERSON>, the campaign's communications director. _ <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> agreed to several concessions sought by <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> on party rules covering the 1992 campaign. That mollified <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> without costing this year's winner anything. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> will not care about the selection of delegates in 1992 if he loses this year _ and wo n't have to worry about it if he wins and is running for re-election. Thus, he agreed to a sharp reduction in the number of automatic super delegates who will attend the 1992 convention, the party officials who have overwhelmingly favored <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> this year. He also consented to <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s demand to award all other delegates in 1992 in proportion to the vote received in primaries. _ All potential credentials challenges were ironed out between the <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> forces, averting a floor fight. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> picked up eight new delegates in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION>; six in <LOCATION> Puerto </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rico </LOCATION> and three in <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> in the process. Most of them came from <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, who has more than he needs.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880703-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-03-88 1137EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p AM-BushSpending Bjt   07-03 0810</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Bush Spending, Bjt,800</SECOND>
<HEAD>As Spending Limit Looms, Bush `Party Builds' and GOP Picks Up the
Tab</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RITA BEAMISH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was talking about crime and politics and Democrats versus Republicans, sounding for all the world like the presidential candidate he is. But something was missing _ there was no specific mention of his Democratic rival, <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>. The reason _ this <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> speech was not a campaign trip, it was a `` party building'' mission paid for by the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION>. The semantic distinction _ in which <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> attacks liberals or Democrats but not <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> by name _ has allowed the vice president to take several trips on the <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> tab at a time when his own campaign funds are virtually gone. Since the primaries ended June 7, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has taken nine out-of-state swings, five of them at least partially financed by the <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>. The practice is legal under <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Election </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> guidelines, but demonstrates a loophole the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> camp has found to keep his campaign in the public eye. Democrats accuse <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> of sleight of checkbook to circumvent the law that places a $ 23 million ceiling on primary campaign spending. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> is pushing the limit, having spent $ 21.3 million by the beginning of June. He severely cut back on campaign spending to avoid surpassing the cap before the Republican National Convention Aug. 15-18. The <ORGANIZATION> RNC </ORGANIZATION> will be pitching in to help with expenses once the convention declares <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> the nominee, but can give him no more than $ 5,000 while he is still technically a primary candidate. That's where party building has come in handy. The <ORGANIZATION> RNC </ORGANIZATION> can spend whatever it wants to help its <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> candidates and state party organizations around the country. Such spending logically includes sending a sitting vice president on speech-making tours to help promote the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> cause, says <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> spokeswoman Ede Holiday. `` He's got a proven track record as one of the best fund-raisers in the <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>,'' she said, adding that the party would utilize <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> even if he was not a presidential candidate. It's not so much his dual role, however, as the financial arrangements that explain why sometimes his talks are peppered with criticism of <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, his certain opponent in November, and other times laced only with general attacks on Democrats. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> told the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> fund-raising luncheon on Thursday: `` I am under these constraints because this is a party-building event. That means I can not put in perspective the differences between me and the man I'll be running against.'' He then proceeded with a lively attack on liberals in a clearly coded reference to <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>. `` You can call it party building, but it's campaigning,'' said <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman <PERSON> Julie </PERSON> <PERSON> Anbender </PERSON>. `` When the vice president is the certain presidential nominee and is traveling around the country, it is fairly evident that ... his primary purpose is to promote his candidacy.'' `` If he does n't talk about his opponent, it's not a campaign trip,'' countered <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> campaign attorney <PERSON> Trevor </PERSON> <PERSON> Potter </PERSON>. `` The Republicans are being very careful not to do this one wrong. If there's any question they allocate it to the campaign.'' Once the Republican convention nominates him in August, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> will get an infusion of $ 46 million from the federal Treasury for his campaign and the Democratic nominee will get the same amount. In addition, the national parties are allowed to spend $ 8.3 million each on their nominees. Even trips to raise the $ 8.3 million are not necessarily considered campaign-related by the Republicans because the $ 8.3 million _ while designated to help elect <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> _ is party money rather than campaign money, <PERSON> Potter </PERSON> said. Any RNC spending on <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> before the convention is not counted against the $ 8.3 million because he is not the nominee yet. Despite Democratic frustration, the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> practice `` is totally within the statutes and the regulations,'' said <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Election </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman <PERSON> Sharon </PERSON> <PERSON> Snyder </PERSON>. She said the law `` recognizes the double or triple functions and double or triple hats a that a candidate may wear.'' The <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> forces are quick to point out that they are not charging any of <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s travel in this post-primary period to the taxpayers, even when he is invited to speak in his vice presidential capacity. In those cases, the campaign has scheduled fund-raising events in the same state so the <ORGANIZATION> RNC </ORGANIZATION> can pick up the tab. Even his <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> Two plane expenses are charged to the campaign to avoid charges of using his office. The campaign is particularly sensitive on the issue, <PERSON> Potter </PERSON> said, in light of a complaint filed against President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s campaign when he charged a Veterans of Foreign Wars speech to the White House budget rather than the campaign The <ORGANIZATION> FEC </ORGANIZATION> decision that there was no violation in that case is the subject of an ongoing federal court case.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880703-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-03-88 1138EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p AM-GOPReady     07-03 0713</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-GOP Ready,730</SECOND>
<HEAD>New Orleans: Not Just A Great Place To Party</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARY FOSTER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW ORLEANS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Six weeks before the Republican National Convention, officials here are doing everything they can to avoid the problems that have been reported in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>, convention city of the Democrats. City officials desperately want to show the world that <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION> is a good place to do business, not just a great place to party. `` We have never had this kind of opportunity before and I think the people have basically responded,'' said Mayor <PERSON> Sidney </PERSON> <PERSON> Barthelemy </PERSON>. After a rocky start, the civic machinery is humming along for the Aug. 15-18 convention. In <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>, by contrast, persistent reports of poor planning and confusion are marring the road to the July 18-21 Democratic gathering. `` Not Ready For Prime Time'' barked the headline about <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> in one national newsmagazine last week. It's the kind of spotlight <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION> officials have been working all year to avoid. The city is no stranger to Big Events: annual Mardi Gras street parties, six Super Bowls, a papal visit and the 1984 World's Fair. But this is different. The convention comes at a time when the city is reeling from an economic depression caused by a slump in the oil industry. <PERSON> Ron </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>, a local businessman and vice chairman of the host committee, sees the convention as a major step toward helping the city and state recover from the oil slump, which sent unemployment rates in <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION> soaring to the highest in the nation. `` We have an opportunity with this convention to change how the people of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> perceive the city of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION> and the state of <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION>,'' said <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>. <PERSON> Barthelemy </PERSON> and others are hoping the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> meeting will rid the city once and for all of any negative feelings left over from the 1984 World's Fair. Although the fair was a great party, it was a financial flop that drew mostly negative publicity. Bad press started the day before it opened, and stories of its financial problems and lawsuits followed. `` There were never any logistical problems with the World's Fair,'' <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> said `` The problem was not enough good publicity, and not enough people came to it.'' When the national media shows up this time, organizers will have 10,000 volunteer workers to make sure delegates, reporters and convention guests find everything in place. `` We want to see that everything is ready from hotels and night spots, down to the little man in his house who's being asked to hang a flag out,'' Councilwoman <PERSON> Peggy </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> said. A $ 280,000 message center will be set up in the Superdome, <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> said. Computer terminals in the major hotels will allow delegates and reporters to check messages from various points in the city. Two fund-raising groups are raising the $ 5.5 million <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION> agreed to put up when it signed the contract to host the convention. `` We ca n't afford another tax,'' <PERSON> Barthelemy </PERSON> said. `` We had to go another route so we're asking for contributions.'' Collections got off to a slow start, but by the third week of June, 60 percent of the money had been raised, according to <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON>, head of <ORGANIZATION> Taylor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Oil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> and head fund-raiser. Convention Manager <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Phillips </PERSON> says he's not worried about the city's ability to pay. `` I'm not concerned about the city living up to its obligations, they have met every one of them on time,'' he said. <PERSON> Phillips </PERSON> also said he sees no reason to worry yet about another possible snag, a police organization's demands that the city enter into a collective bargaining agreement. `` In <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION> in 1984 the police and the taxi drivers both said they were going to strike if something was n't agreed upon and neither did,'' said <PERSON> Phillips </PERSON>. `` The city has said they're talking with the police association and it's coming along. It's a wait and see.'' A <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Orleans </ORGANIZATION> study says the convention will have a $ 137 million impact on the local economy, but local officials think the long-range impact is far more important. `` This is a wonderful chance to show the city off,'' <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> said. `` We want to make sure we take full advantage of it. `` We're paying very close attention to all the details.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880703-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-03-88 1146EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a AM-BRF--RecordStriptease     07-03 0188</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Record Striptease,0192</SECOND>
<HEAD>Couple Tries to Strip Their Way Into Record Book</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Delane </PERSON> <PERSON> Balliot </PERSON> and <PERSON> Newcomb </PERSON> <PERSON> Munt </PERSON> ended a 72-hour marathon strip act in a store window after stripping to their underwear 432 times. They began their quest to enter the Guinness Book of World Records Wednesday afternoon. If nobody else breaks their record, they hope the 1989 Guinness book will list them as the first record holders for consecutive stripping. `` My feet are twice the size of my shoes right now,'' <PERSON> Balliot </PERSON> said Saturday as she took off her high heels. `` I want to go home, take a shower, go to sleep for days.'' `` We are the pioneers,'' said <PERSON> Munt </PERSON>, 28. He works as a stripper for a singing telegram company, as does <PERSON> Balliot </PERSON>, 22. The professional strippers were allowed to rest for five minutes every hour during their bump and grind-a-thon, but they often danced several straight hours to accumulate time for catnaps. For establishing the record their employer is giving each of them $ 500, a new set of clothes and a free trip to either <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> or <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880703-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-03-88 1153EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a AM-SackOfMoney     07-03 0263</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Sack Of Money,0268</SECOND>
<HEAD>Man Asks Court To Keep 1,602 Hundred-Dollar Bills During Court
Fight</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NASHVILLE, Tenn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A man has asked a court whether he can keep $ 160,200 in $ 100 bills that his aunt wrapped as a Christmas gift and gave to him before killing herself. <PERSON> Benton </PERSON> <PERSON> Vincent </PERSON> <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>'s aunt had been accused of defrauding <ORGANIZATION> South </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Telephone </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> of about $ 180,000, police said. <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> took a brown grocery sack of money to <ORGANIZATION> Chancery </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> on Friday and turned it over until a judge rules on its ownership. In a complaint filed by his lawyers, <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> said <PERSON> Kathleen </PERSON> <PERSON> DePierri </PERSON>, 49, gave him packages of money, plus assets worth about $ 20,000, a few days before she killed herself in December 1986. <PERSON> Davis </PERSON>, a 21-year-old senior at <ORGANIZATION> Vanderbilt </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> at the time, said he put the wrapped packages in his car trunk and did not open them until several weeks after Ms. <PERSON> DePierri </PERSON>'s suicide. He is seeking a ruling on whether he can keep the money or whether it should go to <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bell </LOCATION>. The company has charged that Ms. <PERSON> DePierri </PERSON>, a social worker, defrauded its employee health plan by billing for treatment she was not qualified to provide. Ms. <PERSON> DePierri </PERSON> was found dead of a gunshot wound in her office Dec. 16, 1986, by federal investigators she was to have met to discuss a possible deal in which she would repay South Central Bell and avoid criminal prosecution. <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> refused Friday to talk about the money or why he kept it for 18 months before turning it over.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880703-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-03-88 1157EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w AM-Congress-StockMarket Bjt   07-03 0823</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Congress-Stock Market, Bjt,790</SECOND>
<HEAD>Despite Market Crash, Congress Stalled on Stock Legislation</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ALAN FRAM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> are drifting into the waning days of this year's session gridlocked in a struggle to pass legislation addressing the continuing woes of the securities industry. News from the stock market over the last several months raises the kinds of issues <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> usually pounces on quickly: One trillion dollars in equity values vanish overnight in history's worst stock market crash. Billions of dollars go up for grabs in an endless series of corporate takeover battles. Insider trading scams net millions of dollars in illegal profits. Yet, no bills are even close to passage. Congressional offices have files fat with testimony they've collected at hearings on Wall Street's problems But most lawmakers and lobbyists seem convinced that the chances of any major legislation being enacted in 1988 are increasingly remote. `` I'm unhappy about it,'' said <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Banking </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Proxmire </PERSON>, D-Wis., who is retiring from <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> next year and has made stock market legislation a priority in his final months in office `` But there's not much I can do.'' Turf fights have slowed the proposals, as regulatory agencies, securities exchanges and even congressional committees with market jurisdiction struggle to expand or retain powers they now have. Deeper divisions exist, however, over the very need for new laws. The growing influence of the futures markets, increasingly common dramatic price swings and hostile takeovers are villains to some. But others say they are little more than inevitable changes that do more good than harm and that legislation could not control anyway. `` No one is for the crash,'' said executive director <PERSON> Sarah </PERSON> <PERSON> Teslik </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institutional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Investors </ORGANIZATION>, which represents large pension funds. `` It would be lovely to say, ` Here are the problems.' But is there a problem?'' The measures that have been introduced are ambitious attempts to stifle what their sponsors say is abusive, unbridled behavior that threatens the nation's economy. One <PERSON> Proxmire </PERSON> bill, a response to last October's stock market collapse, would tighten federal regulation of the stock, futures and options exchanges. An <ORGANIZATION> Intermarket </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coordination </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> would be formed, consisting of the chiefs of the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reserve </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Securities </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Exchange </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Commodity </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Futures </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Trading </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION>. The committee would create `` circuit breakers'' to automatically shut down trading if wild price swings occur, and make a range of changes designed to dampen speculation and enhance information gathering by the exchanges. A second Proxmire measure attempts to clamp down on corporate raiders by forcing them to make their takeover efforts more public. A third bill, introduced last Thursday by Rep. <PERSON> Rick </PERSON> <PERSON> Boucher </PERSON>, D-Va., would require brokerage firms to set up systems to weed out insider trading, and offer bounties to people who tell the authorities about the leaking of privileged information All three proposals face imposing hurdles in a year in which <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> has only about 50 work days left, and in which lawmakers are becoming increasingly distracted by the political campaigns. The market regulation legislation has yet to make it out of <PERSON> Proxmire </PERSON>'s own committee and has still not been introduced in the House. It has run into opposition from the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration, many lawmakers, federal regulators and market officials, who question whether any changes are needed. And its supporters have lost momentum as the crash recedes further into the past. `` It's a case of everyone sort of stumbling around and in the meantime the problem seems to be going away,'' says <PERSON> A.A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Sommer </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, a lawyer who monitors Capitol Hill for business groups. <PERSON> Proxmire </PERSON> brought his corporate raider bill to the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> floor last month, only to see his colleagues vote to attach what he calls killer amendments, provisions that would help raiders by limiting the defenses corporate managers could use. The surprised lawmaker pulled the bill off the floor and says he still has n't decided what he'll do next. The insider trading legislation may have the best chance of passage, especially with last week's new charges against an investor and a trader accused of earning $ 19 million in illegal profits. Rep. <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Markey </PERSON>, D-Mass., chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> telecommunications and finance subcommittee and a co-sponsor of <PERSON> Boucher </PERSON>'s bill, says the insider trading measure is his `` best bet'' for action As <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Heard </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> consultant to financial institutions, argues, `` There's nobody who's against stronger enforcement or tightening up insider trading laws.'' But <PERSON> Boucher </PERSON> and his allies still need to sell their proposal to their colleagues, who will have numerous measure competing for their attention as the 100th <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> winds down. Even if the securities bills are not approved in 1988, lawmakers pressing the legislation are succeeding in keeping the stock market issue in the news and getting public reaction to their ideas. `` We may not be able to get everything passed this year, but we'll set the stage for next year,'' <PERSON> Markey </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880703-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-03-88 1158EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Jazz     07-03 0427</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Jazz,0439</SECOND>
<HEAD>JVC Latin Jazz Concert A Fitting Tribute To Machito</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PAUL RAEBURN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The great Cuban jazz musician <PERSON> Machito </PERSON> died in 1986, but the <ORGANIZATION> JVC </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Jazz </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Festival </ORGANIZATION>'s tribute to him provided ample evidence that the Afro-Cuban jazz tradition <PERSON> Machito </PERSON> fathered is strong and well. On Saturday night, <PERSON> Carnegie </PERSON> <PERSON> Hall </PERSON> resounded with the salsa and jazz of <PERSON> Mongo </PERSON> <PERSON> Santamaria </PERSON>, <PERSON> Paquito </PERSON> <PERSON> D'Rivera </PERSON>, <PERSON> Tito </PERSON> <PERSON> Puente </PERSON> and <PERSON> Celia </PERSON> <PERSON> Cruz </PERSON> in a concert that underscored the continuing vibrancy of <PERSON> Machito </PERSON>'s legacy. <PERSON> Machito </PERSON> came from <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> in the late 1930s and is generally credited with being the first to combine Cuban rhythms with jazz melodies and harmonies. Among the members of <PERSON> Machito </PERSON>'s early orchestras was a young drummer named <PERSON> Tito </PERSON> <PERSON> Puente </PERSON>, who ultimately launched his own big band after World War II and has become one of the biggest names in Latin music. <PERSON> Puente </PERSON> appeared with his big band Saturday night at the <ORGANIZATION> Machito </ORGANIZATION> tribute, where he performed with all the vigor of the young man who once worked for <ORGANIZATION> Machito </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Puente </PERSON>'s music is a true salsa-jazz fusion, seamlessly mixing jazz-inflected horn arrangements with a churning Latin rhythm section. While the Latin rhythmic groove was paramount in everything <PERSON> Puente </PERSON> played, he also revealed an introspective side with a silky, mysterious performance of `` Autumn Leaves,'' which he played on vibraphone. <PERSON> Puente </PERSON> followed a rousing opening set by <PERSON> Mongo </PERSON> <PERSON> Santamaria </PERSON>, whose smaller band revealed crisp, clean rhythms and taught arrangements. <PERSON> Santamaria </PERSON> was followed, in turn, by the Cuban-American alto saxophonist <PERSON> Paquito </PERSON> <PERSON> D'Rivera </PERSON>, who has brought Latin music to a wider audience of jazz afficionados. <PERSON> D'Rivera </PERSON>'s quartet opened with a deft interpretation of `` All The Things You Are,'' and later welcomed <PERSON> Dave </PERSON> <PERSON> Valentin </PERSON>, the Puerto Rican flute player, for a guest spot. In one of the few apparent instances of poor planning during the concert, <PERSON> Valentin </PERSON> was ushered off the stage after only one selection, just as he was warming to the sound of the concert hall. <PERSON> D'Rivera </PERSON> also introduced to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> a young Brazilian singer and guitarist named <PERSON> Anna </PERSON> <PERSON> Caram </PERSON>, who performed two breezy numbers that revealed a supple if slightly hyperkinetic vocal style and a considerable talent as a guitarist. The high point of the evening came with the appearance of <PERSON> Celiz </PERSON> <PERSON> Cruz </PERSON>, the great salsa singer whose 35 years in the business earned her a standing ovation before she began to sing. She delivered several selections in a deep, powerful voice before all of the evening's musicians gathered on stage for a freewheeling performance of `` Machito Forever,'' a Puente composition.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880703-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-03-88 1209EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w AM-Congress'Record Bjt   07-03 0898</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Congress' Record, Bjt,890</SECOND>
<HEAD>Congress Posts Unusually Productive Session</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By STEVEN KOMAROW</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Democratic-controlled <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> is bragging about a session of unusual productivity, although the circumstances that have helped make that possible may soon be gone. `` We think it is probably the most productive <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> in recent history,'' House Speaker <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Texas </LOCATION>, said. The record backs up that statement. _ For the first time in years, the House has passed all 13 of the annual spending bills on time When the final two measures were voted on Wednesday, it was the earliest that had been done in 28 years. _ The catastrophic health insurance bill, signed into law Friday by President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, is the biggest change in the Medicare system since the program began 23 years ago _ The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> ratified the Intermediate-Range Nuclear Forces treaty with the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> _ After a seemingly endless partisan battle over aid to <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>'s Contra rebels through most of the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration, lawmakers on both sides of the aisle approved a non-weapons aid package _ Both the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> have approved bills to overhaul the nation's welfare laws, and an agreement between the two chambers is being negotiated _ The housing aid programs have been renewed, and after years of stalemate, a compromise has been struck on toughening the nation's laws against discrimination in `` Those are some pretty significant things done in this <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>,'' conceded Rep. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Michel </PERSON>, the House Republican leader. <PERSON> Michel </PERSON> was also quick to point out that Republicans `` played a meaningful role'' in those accomplishments. Still on the agenda are <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> completion of the spending bills, a pre-election anti-drug bill, and another veto fight with President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> over trade and a companion plant-closing notification bill. And lawmakers are talking optimistically about finishing the session on time in the first week of October. `` The reason we have been productive is because we have a <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and a <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>,'' <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> said. After six years of <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> control, Democrats won back the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> in the 1986 election. But crediting a unified <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> as the main reason for the legislative success would be misleading. Last year, when both chambers were <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION>, not one of the annual spending bills was finished on time. The most important reason <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> was able to move speedily this year was last fall's deficit-reduction pact with <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, which set in advance the overall spending levels Another reason for this year's success has been just-departed White House chief of staff <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON>. The former senator's non-confrontational style, and his work directly with <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to iron out wrinkles, helped keep the process moving on several occasions `` This illustrates that there is nothing wrong with the budget process that a cooperative president can not fix,'' said Rep. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gray </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>, D-Pa., chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Budget </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> himself, of course, is in his final months in office. Like other presidents after a long tenure, he has been concentrating on foreign policy initiatives, including the summits with Soviet leader <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>. Meanwhile, domestic programs have regained some of the attractiveness in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> that was tarnished in <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s early years of anti-big-government rhetoric. `` It's in large measure due to the fact that it's an election year,'' said Rep. <PERSON> Leon </PERSON> <PERSON> Panetta </PERSON>, D-Calif. Republicans, too, are voting for measures that `` members can point to as establishing their credibility on a broad range of domestic issues. <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>'s chief vote-counter, Rep. <PERSON> Tony </PERSON> <PERSON> Coelho </PERSON>, D-Calif., said that while Republicans have complained about the sometimes strong-arm tactics of the Democrats to keep the schedule moving, members of both parties were tired of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>' traditionally chaotic approach `` You have an atmosphere for strong leadership,'' he said. `` But if the leadership was n't willing to take advantage of that, it would n't happen. ... We are always working the system _ It's hands-on. The test of whether <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> is running better will come next year. Although most observers expect <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> will remain in Democratic control, there will be a new president ambitiously pursuing an agenda that may not jive with that of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, and the budget summit with <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> will be a memory. `` I'm not so naive as to think we wo n't fall back into the same old syndrome,'' <PERSON> Michel </PERSON> said. If <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> wins, <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> will again have a <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> opponent _ and one with more vigor. If <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> wins, there could be a clash of the expectations that <ORGANIZATION> Democrats </ORGANIZATION> have pent up in the past eight years and the huge national debt that has built up. `` We have begun to reverse the trend that was eroding and beginning to do away with our domestic infrastructure,'' <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> said. A <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> victory would also take away <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>'s much-enjoyed role as the top elected Democrat in the country, an adjustment some associates say might be difficult for him. Another adjustment will come by next year when the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> ethics investigation against <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>, who is accused of using his elective office for financial gains, should be completed. If <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> is found to have done wrong, it could shake up the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> leadership. <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> has declared his innocence, and has called the current probe wearying. But the ethics case is also a useful distraction for the right-wing opposition in the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, which is spending more time attacking the speaker and less time sabotaging the legislative schedule. `` I do n't think I intended it that way,'' chuckled <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880703-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-03-88 1237EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w AM-WhyIt'sDry Bjt   07-03 0754</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Why It's Dry, Bjt,750</SECOND>
<HEAD>Why a Drought?</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RANDOLPH E. SCHMID</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Meteorologists know that a stalled high pressure system and a split jet stream are causing the drought in <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, but they are at a loss to explain why the phenomena occurred and when they might end. In a high-pressure system, also known as an anticyclone, dry air gradually descends toward the ground and moves in a clockwise pattern around the center. It is the opposite of a cyclone, where rising, moist, counterclockwise winds promote the development of clouds, and thus rain. As followers of newspaper weather maps and broadcast reports know, <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s changing weather pattern generally consists of a series of highs and lows _ anticyclones and cyclones _ marching across the country from west to east. That pattern is stalled, has been for a month or more, and is likely to stay stalled, according to <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gilman </PERSON>, head of the <ORGANIZATION> Long-Range </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Predictions </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Group </ORGANIZATION> at the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Weather </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>. In normal times, the highs and lows, and their accompanying weather fronts, are steered across the nation by strong, high-altitude winds known as the jet stream. Tearing across the nation's middle and southern sections in winter, these winds pull along the major storms that many people dread. When warm summer weather comes, the jet stream usually edges to the north. There, it brings in moisture from the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Northwest </LOCATION>, while at the same time helping pull storms north into the nation's middle from the <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> Not so this year, <PERSON> Gilman </PERSON> said. The jet stream has split in two. One stream is sweeping to the north in <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>, steering <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> storms north of the Farm Belt. The second is moving across just south of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, blocking gulf storms from coming north. And trapped in the middle is that dismally warm and sunny anticyclone. This split is `` not a rare event, if you define rare as something that almost never happens. But it's not frequent either,'' said <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Livezey </PERSON>, an associate of <PERSON> Gilman </PERSON>'s at the federal Climate Analysis Center. Can he say why it occurs? `` Unfortunately not. The processes which lead to this sort of event are n't well understood right now,'' <PERSON> Livezey </PERSON> said. It may simply be part of the natural variability of the atmosphere, he said. At any rate, the meteorologists are n't ready to attribute it to any specific cause. `` That's one of the problems in dynamic meteorology that we're still working on Figuring out how -LRB- these patterns occur -RRB- is one of the keys to long-range forecasting,'' said <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Sabol </PERSON> of the Climate Analysis Center. Even determining whether the high caused the jet stream to split, or the split jet stream trapped the high, is difficult, <PERSON> Livezey </PERSON> said. At any rate, the two work together. The high blocks the movement of storms into the Farm Belt while the jet stream guides them around it. Once that pattern starts, the hot, dry weather tends to worsen and reinforce itself, said <PERSON> Vernon </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kousky </PERSON>, also of the Climate Analysis Center. `` Everybody has felt the cooling sensation when water evaporates after they get out of the ocean or a pool,'' he explained. In the same way, `` If you have wet ground, some of the solar radiation is used to evaporate water, the area is kept cooler and this is good for man and plants as well.'' The drought, however, has reduced ground moisture. Without the cooling of evaporation, and the clouds that the evaporated water might eventually form, the weather can get hotter and hotter. `` You might call it a drought feedback mechanism, it tends to perpetuate on itself,'' <PERSON> Kousky </PERSON> said. When it will end, no one was willing to say. `` There is no normal lifetime of a drought. They can last from several months to years,'' the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Weather </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> noted in a statement on the drought. `` Unfortunately, reliable predictions of the drought's end, its geographic spread, or changes in severity, can not be made today,'' the service said. In his long-range forecast, <PERSON> Gilman </PERSON> called for the current weather pattern to continue, at least through July. The most intense focus of the drought may drift to the east and south in the next three months, he said. But the pattern of rainfall behind it will be spotty, he said, with only the western parts of the <LOCATION> Great </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Plains </LOCATION> likely to see much increase in rain through the end of September. Whether that will be in time to save threatened crops remains to be seen.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880703-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-03-88 1239EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-BridgeOpening     07-03 0377</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Bridge Opening,0390</SECOND>
<HEAD>Ozal Inaugurates Second Bridge Over Bosporus</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By VEDAT ERDAMAR</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ISTANBUL, Turkey (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Premier <PERSON> Turgut </PERSON> <PERSON> Ozal </PERSON> on Sunday inaugurated the second bridge linking <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION> and was the first to cross it after a ritual sheep sacrifice opened the ceremony. <PERSON> Ozal </PERSON> called the eight-lane suspension bridge across the Bosporus strait `` a monument symbolizing friendship and cooperation between <LOCATION> Turkey </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>.'' The bridge was built by a consortium of Japanese, Italian and Turkish companies. The Turkish premier then drove his car 14 miles from Levent on the European side to <LOCATION> Kozyatagi </LOCATION> on the <ORGANIZATION> Anatolian </ORGANIZATION> side, followed by hundreds of vehicles. The bridge's main span reaches 3,597 feet and is about 192 feet above the strait. It is the sixth longest suspension bridge in the world. Thousands of people crowded nearby hills to watch the inauguration ceremony, which opened after the sheep sacrifice, an Islamic ritual. Dozens of helicopters hovered and thousands of police and soldiers enforced tight security measures following reports of sabotage threats by Japanese <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> terrorists. The $ 123 million bridge was built in 2 -LCB- years by <ORGANIZATION> Ishikawajima </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Heavy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Industries </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Company </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Mitsubishi </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Heavy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Industries </ORGANIZATION> and <LOCATION> Nippon </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kokan </LOCATION> <LOCATION> K.K </LOCATION>. of <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Impregilo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> S.P.A. </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION> and the <PERSON> Sezai </PERSON> <PERSON> Turkes </PERSON> and <PERSON> Fevzi </PERSON> <PERSON> Akkaya </PERSON> Turkish construction company. In addition to the bridge, 111 miles of highways will be constructed, starting from <LOCATION> Kinali </LOCATION> near the Greek border in the west, passing through <LOCATION> Istanbul </LOCATION> and ending in <LOCATION> Sakarya </LOCATION> in the east. An additional 24 miles of peripheral roads will be built. The total cost of the project, including the bridge, is estimated at $ 551 million. The new bridge is three miles north of the first bridge over the Bosporus, which stretches from <LOCATION> Hisarustu </LOCATION> on the European side to <LOCATION> Kavacik </LOCATION> on the Anatolian side. The new bridge was built because of increased traffic over the strait. between the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>. But the traffic will not be significantly eased until the peripheral roads are completed by the end of this year, officials said. The daily traffic volume over the first bridge, which opened in 1973, reached more than 130,000 vehicles in 1987, according to a Highways Directorate report. The report said 426 million vehicles had crossed the bridge by November 1987.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880703-0025 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-03-88 1245EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Soviet-Scorecard 1stLd-Writethru   07-03 0819</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Soviet-Scorecard, 1st Ld-Writethru,a0736,0844</SECOND>
<HEAD>Gorbachev Leads Winners in National Conference</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: SUBS 13th graf pvs, ``Yeltsin was ...'' to correct Yeltsin
stripped of Politburo position in February. Pickup 14th pvs,
``Gorbachev says ...</NOTE>
<HEAD>AP News Analysis</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN-THOR DAHLBURG</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MOSCOW (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> emerged from the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>'s first national conference in nearly 50 years with political reforms he championed, but he also endured hostility toward his drive for more openness. Such was the mixed scorecard of the four-day conference that ended Friday. The 5,000 delegates met in the party's first conference since <PERSON> Josef </PERSON> <PERSON> Stalin </PERSON> convened one in 1941. At <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s urging, they ordered an overhaul of the late dictator's system that vested the nation's power and prestige in the party's bureaucrats. By charting the path of political reform, <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> said, the <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION> conclave pointed the way to a new `` democratic image of socialism'' that would enable his economic and social reforms to proceed. Resolutions adopted at the conference _ on topics including political reform, the openness policy known as `` glasnost,'' and inter-ethnic relations _ were not immediately made public. But a preliminary scorecard can be drawn based on delegates' speeches, reports in the state-run media and officials' comments to reporters. _ <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> himself looks like a winner He gained his mandate for political change and led the kind of frank, often searing debate he espouses. The disputes starkly contrasted with the polite, well-ordered ceremonial conferences of past <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION> rulers. Among their political reforms, the delegates approved creating a new, more powerful presidency with powers to draft legislation and oversee foreign policy and defense _ a post apparently tailor-made for <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>. However, some delegates to the conference said they were awaiting proof that <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s economic reform program, in its third year, will improve life. Until the fine print of the resolutions is made public, it would be premature to call the conference an unqualified triumph for the 57-year-old <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> chief. _ <PERSON> Yegor </PERSON> <PERSON> K. </PERSON> <PERSON> Ligachev </PERSON>, the No 2 Kremlin leader often rumored to be at odds with <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>, also appeared to have gained ground. <PERSON> Ligachev </PERSON>'s extraordinary speech, in which he disavowed any ideological differences with <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>, amounted to a ringing defense of the party's Old Guard and a stinging blow to his would-be rival, <PERSON> Boris </PERSON> <PERSON> N. </PERSON> <PERSON> Yeltsin </PERSON>. _ <PERSON> Yeltsin </PERSON>, the one-time protege of <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> and former <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> party boss, came away from the conference a loser He asked delegates for `` political rehabilitation'' and instead culled attacks from a succession of speakers, including <PERSON> Ligachev </PERSON> and <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> himself. <PERSON> Yeltsin </PERSON> was stripped of his <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> party post last year and an alternate seat on the ruling Politburo in February after complaining that entrenched bureaucrats were blocking <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s reforms <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> says <PERSON> Yeltsin </PERSON> has some good ideas and is energetic but that he lacks tact and has been rude. Segments from <PERSON> Yeltsin </PERSON>'s speech and from the frequently acidic attacks on him were shown on national television, apparently to nip any vestiges of popular support for him. _ President <PERSON> Andrei </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gromyko </PERSON> and fellow long-time Politburo member <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Solomentsev </PERSON>, both in their 70s, may have also come away losers In a rare public attack, one delegate called them and two other senior party figures holdovers from the `` period of stagnation,'' as the era of <PERSON> Leonid </PERSON> <PERSON> I. </PERSON> <PERSON> Brezhnev </PERSON> is now known. <PERSON> Yeltsin </PERSON> also attacked <PERSON> Solomentsev </PERSON> by name, accusing him of protecting corrupt party officials. <PERSON> Ligachev </PERSON>, however, defended his Politburo colleagues, saying they helped engineer the election of <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> as party chief in March 1985. In addition, the conference raised questions about the future of some groups affected by its decisions: _ The journalists known as the `` glasnost gang,'' the most outspoken advocates of <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s openness campaign, may have suffered a setback <PERSON> Vitaly </PERSON> <PERSON> Korotich </PERSON>, editor of the weekly magazine <ORGANIZATION> Ogonyok </ORGANIZATION>, and <PERSON> Grigory </PERSON> <PERSON> Baklanov </PERSON>, editor of the <LOCATION> Znamya </LOCATION> literary monthly, met a chilly, sometimes hostile reception. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> had to intervene twice to silence delegates so <PERSON> Baklanov </PERSON> could finish speaking. The editor of the government daily newspaper <ORGANIZATION> Izvestia </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Ivan </PERSON> <PERSON> Laptev </PERSON>, was also jeered from the floor. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> proclaimed that `` openness has been the hero of the conference.'' But <PERSON> Ligachev </PERSON> specifically endorsed some sentiments in a speech by a conservative writer who denounced recent daring press forays into the Soviet past and present. _ Party bureaucrats, from the countryside to the senior leadership, suffered All party officeholders will now be limited to two five-year terms. Before, they could serve for life. It was also clear that local party leaders will lose their jobs if they can not muster enough support to be chosen as chairmen of the country's 50,000 local governing councils. _ Finally, the 20 million members of the party rank and file, whose qualifications will be reviewed this year, face uncertainty A reevaluation of their standing could be used to blunt conservative opposition to <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s reforms.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> John-Thor </PERSON> <PERSON> Dahlburg </PERSON>, an <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> correspondent based in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> since November 1986, specializes in <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> politics and internal affairs.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880703-0026 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-03-88 1246EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Israel-Strike     07-03 0268</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Israel-Strike,0277</SECOND>
<HEAD>Israeli Medical Workers Go On Strike</HEAD>
<DATELINE>JERUSALEM (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 About 3,000 nurses walked off the job Sunday to protest a government health plan they say will increase the burden on already understaffed hospitals. Also Sunday, 900 workers of Magen <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Adom </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s version of the <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION>, shut down services after failing to receive June paychecks. And physicians who have been staging short strikes for several months closed out-patient clinics and performed only emergency surgery. The doctors also oppose the government's health proposal, which calls for shortening the waiting list for operations by introducing a second daily surgery shift. <PERSON> Ilana </PERSON> <PERSON> Cohen </PERSON>, head of the nurses' union, said the government should first substantially increase the number of public hospital nurses. There are now about 12,000. `` It's inconceivable that they should talk about a second shift when the nurses can hardly cope with the first shift,'' she said. She said the 12,000 nurses will take turns striking. Groups of 3,000 nurses will rotate taking two-week `` vacations.'' <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s debt-ridden hospital system has been plagued for the past two years by strikes and walkouts. The government says more than 22,000 people have been waiting months for elective surgery, and medical unions say the number is 50,000. The new health plan calls for medical staff to do 15,000 operations in the next nine months. A committee consisting of Prime Minister <PERSON> Yitzhak </PERSON> <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON>, Deputy Premier <PERSON> Shimon </PERSON> <PERSON> Peres </PERSON>, Finance Minister <PERSON> Moshe </PERSON> <PERSON> Nissim </PERSON> and Health Minister <PERSON> Shoshana </PERSON> <PERSON> Arbeli-Almoslino </PERSON> has been named to propose a solution to the health crisis. Ms. <PERSON> Cohen </PERSON> called on the committee to include the professional workers in their deliberations.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880703-0027 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-03-88 1254EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-US-Iran     07-03 0517</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-US-Iran,540</SECOND>
<HEAD>URGENT</HEAD>
<HEAD>Sources Say it is ``Doubtful'' Fighter Was Shot Down</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BRYAN BRUMLEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Administration sources said it was `` doubtful'' that the plane shot down by <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> forces Sunday was an Iranian F-14 fighter, and that the <ORGANIZATION> Joint </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chiefs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Staff </ORGANIZATION> were trying to determine whether it was a civilian airliner, as claimed by <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>. `` It is doubtful that an F-14 was up there at all,'' said an administration source, speaking on condition of anonymity. Earlier, <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> spokesmen said that <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> forces had shot down an Iranian fighter jet over the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> and that officials were `` checking out'' an Iranian report that an American-fired missile had downed an <ORGANIZATION> Iran </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> jetliner carrying 290 passengers. The chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Joint </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chiefs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Staff </ORGANIZATION>, Adm. <PERSON> Wiliam </PERSON> <PERSON> Crowe </PERSON>, was to brief reporters on the matter early this afternoon. Lt. Col. <PERSON> Arnold </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> said <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials are ` aware of the Iranian claim, of the press reports of it, and we're checking it out.'' At the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, a spokesman said the president had been kept informed of `` the incidents in the Gulf.'' The <ORGANIZATION> Islamic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> said the <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> Air jetliner took off from <PERSON> Bandar </PERSON> <PERSON> Abbas </PERSON> at 10:15 a.m. -LRB- 2:45 a.m. EDT -RRB- and was last tracked 7 minutes later. The agency said 100 bodies had been recovered and all aboard the jetliner were feared killed when two <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> missiles hit it. Major <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Stepp </PERSON> said hostilities began in the gulf Sunday when an Iranian gunboat fired at a helicopter at 2:10 a.m. EDT. He said the helicopter was not hit and that the <LOCATION> USS </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vincennes </LOCATION> and the frigate USS Montgomery returned fire, sinking two Iranian boats and downing a F-14 fighter plane that apparently joined the battle. The spokesman gave no exact time for the shooting down of the F-14. No American casualties were reported. The incident was the first such hostility between the two nations since the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> destroyed two oil platforms in April. `` Our reports indicate that two small Iranian patrol boats were sunk and one was damaged. The <ORGANIZATION> USS </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Vincennes </ORGANIZATION> also reported that it downed an Iranian F-14 aircraft that was approaching in a hostile manner,'' the spokesman said. Lt. Col. <PERSON> Keith </PERSON> <PERSON> Schneider </PERSON> said the fighter jet was approaching the <LOCATION> Vincennes </LOCATION> `` at a high rate of speed'' in the <LOCATION> Strait </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hormuz </LOCATION> and that `` warnings were issued.'' `` It was clearly identified as an F-14; it ignored warnings and was approaching in a hostile manner,'' <PERSON> Schneider </PERSON> said. He said <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> officials had not determined whether the F-14 was in sight at the time it was shot down. He said that after the incident, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> forces watched an Iranian helicopter search the area where he said the fighter jet was downed and that the American forces were `` standing clear and allowing them to continue their operations.'' <PERSON> Phyllis </PERSON> <PERSON> Oakley </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman, said seven hours after the airliner went down, `` We are certainly very much in touch with this, but the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> is handling everything. At the moment, there is not anything for the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> to say.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880703-0028 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-03-88 1319EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-People     07-03 0568</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-People,0589</SECOND>
<HEAD>People In The News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY44</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PONTIAC, Mich. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The 15-year-old son of Polish labor leader and Nobel Peace Prize winner <PERSON> Lech </PERSON> <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> has visited a local school as part of a three-month tour of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> to improve his English. During the visit to the Orchard Lake Schools, <PERSON> Slawek </PERSON> <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> attended a workshop on Polish heritage. <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON>, son of the founder of the banned Solidarity labor movement, arrived from <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> on Tuesday for a tour of the country with <PERSON> Jan </PERSON> <PERSON> Wydro </PERSON>, a <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> family friend who lives in <LOCATION> Oil </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pa </LOCATION>. Stops on <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON>'s itinerary include <ORGANIZATION> Disney </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Orlando </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, and <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION>, before returning home on Aug. 29. `` He just wants to see <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Wydro </PERSON> said. The large number of automobiles and computers in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has made the biggest impression on young <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON>, he said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>DELHI, N.Y. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Former pop singer <PERSON> Cat </PERSON> <PERSON> Stevens </PERSON> told delegates to the weekend annual convention of the <ORGANIZATION> Islamic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Circle </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> North </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION> that he's glad he got out of the music business. <PERSON> Stevens </PERSON>, now known as <ORGANIZATION> Yousuf </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Islam </ORGANIZATION>, converted to <ORGANIZATION> Islam </ORGANIZATION> nine years ago after a successful career that included such hits as `` Wild World,'' ` Peace Train,'' `` Morning Has Broken,'' `` Oh Very Young'' and `` Another Saturday Night.'' In a lecture Saturday, the 40-year-old former singer-songwriter condemned the music industry, calling it corrupt, particularly in the business area. He said he was happy to have `` extracted'' himself from `` that business.'' The convention at the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Technology </ORGANIZATION> at <LOCATION> Delhi </LOCATION> ran Friday through Monday.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>SAN FRANCISCO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Famed `` King of Torts'' lawyer <PERSON> Melvin </PERSON> <PERSON> Belli </PERSON> says he ca n't talk about his wife's filing for legal separation, but says he's written a book about marriage and divorce. <PERSON> Lia </PERSON> <PERSON> Belli </PERSON>, 39, said Friday she had filed for the separation after 16 years of marriage and wanted <PERSON> Belli </PERSON> barred from their home. She contends the 80-year-old man beat her and falsely accused her of having affairs. She is <PERSON> Belli </PERSON>'s fifth wife. He said his book about marriage will be out in about three weeks. Interviewed Saturday by a <ORGANIZATION> KCBS </ORGANIZATION> radio reporter outside the couple's mansion, <PERSON> Belli </PERSON> said one thing he's learned about marital disputes is that `` you do n't talk about divorce when children are involved.'' The <PERSON> Bellis </PERSON> have one daughter, <PERSON> Melia </PERSON>, born in 1973. <PERSON> Belli </PERSON> cut short a tour of the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> after <PERSON> Lia </PERSON> reported to police Tuesday that an intruder fired two shots at her in her bedroom at 5 a.m.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LEBANON, Tenn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Gilligan </PERSON>, the Skipper and the rest of the gang wo n't be there, but <PERSON> Dawn </PERSON> <PERSON> Wells </PERSON>, better known as <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Ann </PERSON>, will be in town Saturday as honorary queen of a `` Back to the'50s'' parade. `` I think it's a hoot,'' said <PERSON> Wells </PERSON>, who played <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Ann </PERSON> on `` <PERSON> Gilligan </PERSON>'s <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION>,'' the saga of seven castaways shipwrecked on a tropical island. Ms. <PERSON> Wells </PERSON> said she does n't mind being remembered as the shy, innocent girl-next-door she played on the 1960s sitcom that is still seen in reruns. `` People ask me trivia questions I ca n't answer,'' she said. `` I got on a plane recently and the whole plane broke out in the <PERSON> Gilligan </PERSON>'s song. It's really nice to be recognized.'' Since the series, she has worked in television and on stage and appeared in the movies `` The Town That Dreaded Sundown'' and `` Winterhawk.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880703-0029 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-03-88 1404EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p AM-MerkleCampaign Bjt   07-03 0730</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Merkle Campaign, Bjt,0754</SECOND>
<HEAD>Controversial Top Federal Prosecutor Now Underdog In Senate Race</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PAT LEISNER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CLEARWATER, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
