<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880920-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-20-88 2340EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Rio-Bankruptcy     09-20 0323</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Rio-Bankruptcy,0331</SECOND>
<HEAD>Rio Seeks Federal Aid to Avoid Bankruptcy</HEAD>
<DATELINE>RIO DE JANEIRO, Brazil (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Rio </LOCATION> <LOCATION> de </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Janeiro </LOCATION> wants $ 54 million from the federal government to avoid bankruptcy, but federal officials said Tuesday that bailing out this celebrated tourist mecca would set a bad precedent. Presidential press spokesman <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Henrique </PERSON> <PERSON> Santos </PERSON> told reporters that if President <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Sarney </PERSON> helps <LOCATION> Rio </LOCATION>, `` the next day there will be a line of 4,000 mayors knocking on the door of the presidential palace.'' Rio Mayor <PERSON> Roberto </PERSON> <PERSON> Saturnino </PERSON> <PERSON> Braga </PERSON> said last week that his city of 5 million people was broke and could not pay its debts or the salaries of 100,000 municipal employees unless <PERSON> Rio </PERSON> received federal aid. <LOCATION> Rio </LOCATION> is <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION>'s second-largest city and a major tourist attraction. But Finance Minister <PERSON> Mailson </PERSON> <PERSON> da </PERSON> <PERSON> Nobrega </PERSON> has refused the city's request to issue $ 54 million in emergency bonds. <PERSON> Rio </PERSON> has been hurt in the last few decades by the transfer of the federal capital to <LOCATION> Brasilia </LOCATION> and the flight of industry to <LOCATION> Sao </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Paulo </LOCATION>, the nation's largest city. Today, <PERSON> Rio </PERSON> owes about $ 150 million to Brazilian creditors and another $ 150 million in foreign debts. The city has projected a budget deficit of close to $ 180 million this year. <PERSON> Saturnino </PERSON> <PERSON> Braga </PERSON> warned that the city may have to cut off school lunches and medical supplies to city hospitals unless its credit is extended. The mayor, a former economist who belongs to the fledgling Brazilian <ORGANIZATION> Socialist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, also said the city was considering selling the <ORGANIZATION> Nelson </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Piquet </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Autodrome </ORGANIZATION>, named for its famous race car driver and the site of the annual Brazilian Formula 1 Grand Prix. He predicted financial chaos unless the city received aid. `` There could be a deterioration of the city. Chaos. General strikes, deterioration of public services and the conservation of the city. But we'll do everything possible to avoid bankruptcy'' he said in an interview over the weekend with the Jornal do Brasil newspaper of <LOCATION> Rio </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880920-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-20-88 0000EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-Homeless 2ndLd-Writethru a0727 09-19 1319</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Homeless, 2nd Ld-Writethru, a0727,1,290</SECOND>
<HEAD>100,000 U.S. Children Homeless On Any One Night, Study Finds</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDs: SUBS 14th graf pvs bgng, `Dr. Frank,' to restore Press' title</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By DAVID BRISCOE</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Associated Press Writer = <LOCATION> WASHINGTON </LOCATION> -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> -RRB- _ At least 100,000 of <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s children are homeless on any given night and that does n't include those who have run away from home or been kicked out by their parents, the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sciences </ORGANIZATION> estimated Monday While male alcoholics and former mental patients still make up a large portion of the homeless, the fastest growing group of people with no place to live are children under 18, said the academy's <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medicine </ORGANIZATION> `` The committee feels strongly that the growing phenomenon of homeless children is nothing short of a national disgrace that must be treated with the urgency that such a situation demands,'' said the report. One recommendation aimed directly at helping children: Federal support for enriched day care and Head Start programs should be expanded and coupled with outreach efforts to make homeless parents aware of help available for their children. A recommendation for the homeless in general: Permit the use of food stamps at restaurants so prepared meals will be available to people who do n't have kitchens. A controversy has erupted over the report, triggered by a majority of the committee formed by the institute to do the study, which was ordered by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. Ten of the 13 members of that panel, chaired by <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Vladeck </PERSON>, the president of <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fund </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, endorsed a supplemental statement that the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sciences </ORGANIZATION> refused to publish in the report. The only mention of it appears in a footnote on page 136 of the 242-page book. It says, in part, that the committee members `` unanimously wish to express their strong feeling that the recommendations are too limited in addressing the broader issues of homelessness _ especially the supply of low-income housing, income maintenance, the availability of support services, and access to health care for the poor and uninsured.'' <PERSON> Vladeck </PERSON>, interviewed Monday night by telephone, said he supports the supplemental statement because the report as published, which focuses on health and human needs of the homeless, `` does n't adequately convey our sense of outrage and dismay at the phenomenon of homelessness. He said the supplementary statement calls for three specifics: `` First, an expansion of federal support of low-income housing to at least the 1981 budget levels from which they've been cut 70 percent since; `` Second, for development of a range of community-based residential treatment services for the mentally ill and substance abusers, and `` Third, for increasing the minimum wage to a level that makes adequate housing affordable.'' Dr. <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Press </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sciences </ORGANIZATION>, blocked publication of the statement. He was quoted in Tuesday's editions of <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> as saying he did so because `` the language was charged and polemical and emotional. `` The academy has a certain credibility to maintain and must assure <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and the executive branch that it will stick to the data and minimize the intrusion of values as much as possible,'' Press said. `` This panel was so repelled by what they saw that they wanted to go beyond their charge and give their views. We told them that was not our process. If they wanted to do it, they had to do it independently.'' He said he was glad the members were issuing their statement but said the main report was `` terrific as it stands.'' In the report, the committee applauded changes that allow use of food stamps at shelters and soup kitchens. But it said operators of those facilities need to be educated in the principles of sound nutrition and the special nutritional needs of the homeless. The committee also sought to dismiss fears of city government officials who might conclude that increasing their efforts to help the homeless would only draw more homeless people to their cities. The great majority of homeless people are long-term residents of the city where they live, the committee said. What's more, it said, what causes homeless people to move to another city is the prospect for work, not the prospect for welfare. If jobs are n't available, they tend not to stay long. As for homeless children, the report said there are no national studies pinning down the numbers, but using `` even the most conservative estimates'' would mean that: _ On any given night, 735,000 people in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> have no home in which to sleep and must resort to streets, shelters, institutions or other makeshift quarters Citing research by the <ORGANIZATION> Alliance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Housing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>, a homeless advocacy group, the committee concluded that 1.3 million to 2 million people will be homeless for one night or more in the course of a year. _ Most of the 735,000 homeless on any given night are alone, but at least a quarter of them are members of families and 55 percent of the family members are children Thus, the report concludes, `` a minimum of 100,000 children are homeless on any given night of the year'' and that figure counts only children in intact families and leaves out `` runaway, throwaway or abandoned children.'' The study did not detail how it concluded that `` children under the age of 18, usually as part of a family headed by a mother, are the fastest growing group among the many subpopulations of the homeless.'' All statistics on the homeless are difficult to come up with, the report acknowledged. In that connection, the <ORGANIZATION> Census </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> announced Monday that it will make a special effort in 1990 to count the homeless. On March 20 of that year, census takers will visit emergency shelters from 6 p.m. to midnight and street locations where the homeless often congregate between 2 a.m. and 4 a.m. The report said most homeless children are in families headed by the mother and it found that homeless mothers frequently have no one to call on even in severe emergencies. It cited one <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> study in which 43 percent of the mothers could not name any one person to depend upon in a time of stress `` and almost a quarter named their minor child as their principal source of emotional support.'' During 10 months of research, the committee and its staff visited agencies serving the homeless in 11 cities _ <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Lexington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ky. </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Milwaukee </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Nashville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Diego </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Louis </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> _ and rural areas in <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION>. `` Those who stay in rural areas remain hidden until some event causes them to lose their housing, at which point they can be found living in, for example, cars, abandoned buildings, and woods,'' the report said. The study says the major causes of homelessness are: _ A decrease in the number of housing units for low-income people _ 2.5 million fewer than in 1980 _ while the number of people who can only affod such units has increased because of skyrocketing housing costs _ A tightening of eligibility for public assistance programs as well as a decline in the value of such assistance _ Policies of state mental hospitals, general hospitals, rehabilitation facilities and some jails and prisons that have fewer people admitted and free some who were previously held `` One result of these factors is that the system for providing temporary shelter for people who are homeless has been burdened beyond its capacity,'' with people staying for months rather than days, the report says. The study says health problems both cause and result from homelessness. Alcoholism, drug abuse, mental illness and the fatal disease AIDS, or acquired immune deficiency syndrome, often results in people losing jobs and homes, it noted. Many diseases are complicated by homelessness and illnesses such as exposure, hypothermia, skin disorders. In addition, accidents, muggings and rapes are often the result of the victim having no home, the study says.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880920-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-20-88 0002EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Nicaragua-Talks 1stLd-Writethru   09-20 0685</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Nicaragua-Talks, 1st Ld-Writethru,a0647,0704</SECOND>
<HEAD>Sandinista-Contra Talks Begin in Guatemala</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: LEADS with 14 grafs to UPDATE with talks breaking off; PICKS
up 9th graf pvs: The agreement...
^By ALFONSO ANZUETO LOPEZ</NOTE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>GUATEMALA CITY (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Representatives of the Nicaraguan government and rebel leaders met for the first time in three months Monday but broke off talks after failing to agree on a new location for resuming peace negotiations. The rebel delegation rejected the government's demand that future talks to end the 7-year-old civil war take place in the Nicaraguan capital of <LOCATION> Managua </LOCATION>, rebel leader <PERSON> Roberto </PERSON> <PERSON> Ferrey </PERSON> said after the meeting. The rebels proposed <LOCATION> Guatemala </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Costa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rica </LOCATION> or the <LOCATION> Dominican </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Republic </LOCATION> as alternative sites for high-level negotiations, <PERSON> Ferrey </PERSON> said. Monday's meeting had been called as a preliminary step to resuming the peace talks that collapsed June 9. The four-hour session was the first meeting between the leftist government and the U.S.-backed rebels since talks collapsed. A possible second day of talks on Tuesday was ruled out, and no date for another meeting was announced. <PERSON> Ferrey </PERSON> said rebels were open to considering new proposals on a location for the talks, and the government has said it would keep trying to persuade the rebels to bargain in <LOCATION> Managua </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Ferrey </PERSON> said he reiterated a rebel proposal that high-level talks be held Sept. 26-28, but not in <LOCATION> Managua </LOCATION>. The proposal was contained in a letter he submitted to Nicaraguan Deputy Foreign Minister <PERSON> Victor </PERSON> <PERSON> Hugo </PERSON> <PERSON> Tinoco </PERSON>, head of the government delegation, and was made available to reporters. The rebels, known as Contras, also demanded the government release more than 40 opposition demonstrators arrested in July and guarantee freedom of expression as a precondition to further talks. <PERSON> Ferrey </PERSON> said that during previous talks in <LOCATION> Managua </LOCATION>, rebel leaders `` felt like prisoners in their own country'' and added, `` our telephone conversations were listened to.'' He did not elaborate. In a separate press conference, <PERSON> Tinoco </PERSON> said the government was sticking by its position that the talks be held in <LOCATION> Managua </LOCATION>. A fragile March 21 cease-fire remains in effect in <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>, but each side accuses the other of violating the truce. <PERSON> Tinoco </PERSON> had said before the meeting Monday he expected it to result in `` a cease-fire for 30 or 60 days that could be extended indefinitely.'' There was no announcement on extending the cease-fire. Both sides had agreed on March 23 to seek a negotiated settlement to the conflict the government says has claimed the lives of 28,000 Nicaraguans. <PERSON> Tinoco </PERSON> said Monday that that agreement called for <LOCATION> Managua </LOCATION> as the site of peace negotiations. The agreement called on the rebels to lay down their arms in exchange for democratic reforms. Shortly before peace talks broke off in June, the <ORGANIZATION> Sandinistas </ORGANIZATION> proposed a timetable for disarmament and political reforms. But the Contras rejected the plan, saying it did not go far enough. They demanded freedom for political prisoners and democratic reforms in <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> before disarming. <PERSON> Tinoco </PERSON> said the <ORGANIZATION> Sandinistas </ORGANIZATION> will urge that a cease-fire verification commission funded by $ 10 million from congress be put into operation. Commission members would include the secretary-general of the <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> States </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Joao </PERSON> <PERSON> Baena </PERSON> <PERSON> Soares </PERSON>, and Nicaraguan Cardinal <PERSON> Miguel </PERSON> <PERSON> Obando </PERSON> y Bravo. <PERSON> Tinoco </PERSON> also reiterated the government's demand that the Contras free 66 prisoners of war being held in <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION>. He blamed the Contras for ending peace talks on June 9. `` The Contras broke them off to seek military aid in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>,'' he said. Direct <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military aid to the rebels ended Feb. 29, and the Contras have few bargaining chips left. Non-lethal <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> aid to the Contras is distributed only in <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION>. During the past four months, most of the rebel forces fled back to base camps inside <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION> to receive new supplies of uniforms and food. Contra sources say only 2,000 fighters remain inside <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> while more than 9,000 are holed up in isolated camps in eastern <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION>. The cease-fire pact in March caused deep divisions within the rebel ranks. Militant Contras, led by <PERSON> Enrique </PERSON> <PERSON> Bermudez </PERSON>, a former colonel under the deposed <PERSON> Anastasio </PERSON> <PERSON> Somoza </PERSON> dictatorship, said the agreement was tantamount to surrender.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880920-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-20-88 0125EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Deaths 1stLd-Writethru a0696 09-20 0377</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Deaths, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0696,0385</SECOND>
<NOTE>Eds: ADDS Staley; No separates moved for the AMs cycle.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Bill Kennedy</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>FORT SMITH, Ark. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, a Pulitzer Prize-winning journalist and former <ORGANIZATION> Southwest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Record </ORGANIZATION> editor, died Friday from complications of a heart attack. He was 64. As a reporter for the <LOCATION> Watsonville </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION> -RRB- Register-Pajaronian, <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> was named co-winner of the 1955 Pulitzer Prize for public service for exposing corruption in government. His coverage of that story brought him one of his two <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Broadcasting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>. Big Story Award awards The stories were made into television dramas. <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> was editor of the <ORGANIZATION> Southwest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Record </ORGANIZATION> between 1971 and 1975 after heading the national news bureau of the <ORGANIZATION> Donrey </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Media </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Group </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> D.C </ORGANIZATION>. Between 1975 and 1977, he was editor of the Donrey newspaper in <LOCATION> Hilo </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>Garaldine Price</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>FAIRFAX, Va. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Garaldine </PERSON> `` Garry'' Price, the widow of longtime <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> congressman <PERSON> Melvin </PERSON> <PERSON> Price </PERSON>, died Sunday of lung cancer at the age of 66. Mrs. Price and Price, a veteran Democrat lawmaker from <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Louis </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ill. </LOCATION>, married in 1952 while she was a field representative for the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cancer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>Tom Siler</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>KNOXVILLE, Tenn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Siler </PERSON>, a former <LOCATION> Knoxville </LOCATION> sports editor and author of four books, died Sunday after a long illness at age 78. <PERSON> Siler </PERSON>'s career began in 1931 and included stints with The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Nashville </LOCATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Chicago </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sun </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION>. He was <ORGANIZATION> Knoxville </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News-Sentinel </ORGANIZATION> sports editor from 1957-1979.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>Oren Staley</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>KANSAS CITY, Kan. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Oren </PERSON> <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Staley </PERSON>, former president of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Farmers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> for 20 years and an unsuccessful candidate for <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION> in 1986, died Monday. He was 65. <PERSON> Staley </PERSON> owned <ORGANIZATION> Oren </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Staley </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Realty </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, which has offices in <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Joseph </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mo </LOCATION>. As president of <ORGANIZATION> NFO </ORGANIZATION>, a Denver-based organization which represents more than 250,000 farm families, <PERSON> Staley </PERSON> often lobbied <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> on farm legislation and related issues. In 1986 <PERSON> Staley </PERSON> finished third in the Democratic primary for the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION>. In November 1986 he filed for Chapter 11 bankruptcy, saying his 956-acre farm was unprofitable and that personal loans he took out to cover costs of his <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> bid had worsened his financial problems.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880920-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-20-88 0010EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Iraq-Iran     09-20 0316</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Iraq-Iran,0323</SECOND>
<HEAD>Iraqi Foreign Minister Says Shatt Must Remain Iraqi</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NICOSIA, Cyprus (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The crucial <PERSON> Shatt </PERSON> <PERSON> al-Arab </PERSON> waterway must remain under Iraqi control and can not be used by <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> as a negotiating tool in peace talks to end their 8-year-old war, <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>'s foreign minister was quoted as saying Monday Foreign Minister <PERSON> Tariq </PERSON> <PERSON> Aziz </PERSON> said the waterway, the delta of the <LOCATION> Tigris </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Euphrates </LOCATION> rivers and <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>'s sole outlet to the sea, should remain under Iraqi control as `` a historical, logical, legal and a just matter,'' according to the official <ORGANIZATION> Iraqi </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Aziz </PERSON>, speaking at a press conference, said <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> rejects what he said was <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'s use of the waterway as a means to pressure <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> in the U.N.-mediated peace talks that started in <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> on Aug. 25, the agency reported. <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> is demanding sovereignty over the <LOCATION> Shatt-al-Arab </LOCATION> estuary and that the outlet be cleared of sunken ships and silt. <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'s first wants to negotiate the withdrawal of both side's troops to internationally recognized borders, the exchange of war prisoners and a <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> investigation to determine who started the war. The talks broke off Sept. 13 and are scheduled to resume in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> in the first week of October. <PERSON> Aziz </PERSON> said that <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> is committed to peace and that `` <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> would bear the consequences for its insistence on its current position.'' After the press conference, <PERSON> Aziz </PERSON> left <LOCATION> Baghdad </LOCATION> for <LOCATION> Riyadh </LOCATION> and consultations with King Fahd of <LOCATION> Saudi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arabia </LOCATION> about the negotiations and other `` issues of common interest,'' the news agency said. In a related development, the agency reported that President <PERSON> Saddam </PERSON> <PERSON> Hussein </PERSON> met with his military field commanders Monday and one item on the agenda was the possibility of changing the course of the Shatt <PERSON> al-Arab </PERSON>. Press reports in the region have said <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> is considering the project to change the path of the waterway in case its talks with <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> deadlock completely.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880920-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-20-88 0311EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-SATScores-Questions     09-20 0225</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-SAT Scores-Questions,0266</SECOND>
<HEAD>SAT Sample Questions</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 How hard are SAT questions? Here are questions from a test administered on May 2, 1987, reprinted by permission of the <ORGANIZATION> Educational </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Testing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>, which is the copyright owner of the questions. Included is the percentage of test-takers correctly answering each. MATH: `` If a, b, and c are integers, the expression a -LRB- b + c -RRB- is always equal to each of the following EXCEPT -LRB- A -RRB- -LRB- a + b -RRB- c -LRB- B -RRB- a -LRB- c + b -RRB- -LRB- C -RRB- -LRB- c + b -RRB- a -LRB- D -RRB- ab + ac
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 Answer is -LRB- A -RRB-; correctly answered by 79 percent of test-takers. `` If the average -LRB- arithmetic mean -RRB- of six numbers is -6, and the sum of four of the numbers is 20, what is the average of the other two numbers? -LRB- A -RRB- 7 -LRB- B -RRB- 8 -LRB- C -RRB- -8 -LRB- D -RRB- -28 -LRB- E -RRB- -32
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 Answer is -LRB- D -RRB-; correctly answered by 16 percent of test-takers. VERBAL: Directions: Choose the word most nearly the OPPOSITE in meaning to the words in capital letters. `` UNCORK'' -LRB- A -RRB- reform -LRB- B -RRB- empty -LRB- C -RRB- seal -LRB- D -RRB- dry out -LRB- E -RRB- blend in
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 Answer is -LRB- C -RRB-; correctly answered by 95 percent of test-takers. `` MAGNANIMOUS'' -LRB- A -RRB- dainty -LRB- B -RRB- latent -LRB- C -RRB- vengeful -LRB- D -RRB- conspicuous -LRB- E -RRB- compatible
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 Answer is -LRB- C -RRB-; correctly answered by 11 percent of test-takers.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880920-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-20-88 0312EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Chile-FarmPolitics     09-20 0770</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Chile-Farm Politics,0791</SECOND>
<HEAD>In Chilean Farm Country, Political Question Is Tinged by Fear</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By KEVIN NOBLET</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SAN FERNANDO, Chile (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 In the country's agricultural heartland, old ingrained fears tinge the debate over the referendum next month on Gen. <PERSON> Augusto </PERSON> <PERSON> Pinochet </PERSON>'s presidency. For prosperous landowners, frightening memories of farm seizures by leftist peasants in the early 1970s has helped push them solidly into the pro-Pinochet camp. `` This is the fear we have, of returning to the past,'' said <PERSON> Francisco </PERSON> <PERSON> Olea </PERSON>, owner of a 100-acre spread here in the country's fertile <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION> But for struggling farm workers, the prospect of reprisal by their bosses or local officials is keeping many from openly voicing dissent. Some say resentment with <PERSON> Pinochet </PERSON>'s authoritarian rule, and with a hand-to-mouth existence, will find expression in the ballot box. `` At least before there was work, and the worker had the right to express his opinion,'' said laborer <PERSON> Ramon </PERSON> <PERSON> Arias </PERSON>, as he painted a tractor by the roadside. Two farmhands with him made similar comments, but refused to give their names. Chileans will decide Oct. 5 in a yes or no ballot on a new term for <PERSON> Pinochet </PERSON>, the right-wing army commander who seized power in a bloody 1973 coup and has already ruled longer than any previous president. If a majority vote for him, he will remain as president until 1997, but the military junta that he has headed as the governing body since 1973 will be disbanded. If he loses, open elections will be held in a year and he must hand over power in 1990, when a new <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, two-thirds elected and one-third appointed, will go into place. <PERSON> Farmowner </PERSON> <PERSON> Olea </PERSON> and others like him have benefited from an export-oriented, free-market economic program carried out by <PERSON> Pinochet </PERSON>'s administration. Foreign sales of grapes and other fruit, much of it grown in the <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION>, have been booming. With government credits and technological assistance, many farm owners are expanding production and making solid profits. But they have not forgotten the chaotic, radical reform programs launched by President <PERSON> Salvador </PERSON> <PERSON> Allende </PERSON>, a self-declared Marxist elected in 1970 and toppled in the coup led by <PERSON> Pinochet </PERSON> three years later. <PERSON> Olea </PERSON>'s home and land were illegally seized by peasants. He negotiated with them so he could live in his house, which also had been taken over, while they worked his land as they liked. `` We lived through a savage lack of order,'' said <PERSON> Luis </PERSON> <PERSON> Aullet </PERSON>, who is partner with his brother <PERSON> Cesar </PERSON> in a 70-acre farm. `` There was no respect for your home, your land.'' <PERSON> Cesar </PERSON> <PERSON> Aullet </PERSON> said the Allende government sent `` experts'' with no knowledge of agriculture to supervise land reform programs. `` What we fear is -LRB- that kind of -RRB- ignorance,'' he said. The landowners said that, with the production boom, conditions for farm workers were improving significantly. `` Manpower is becoming scarce, and there's competition in salaries to attract workers,'' <PERSON> Cesar </PERSON> <PERSON> Aullet </PERSON> said. `` Anyone who wants work can find it.'' The Aullets said that at the height of the harvesting season, workers could not be found for less than 1,000 pesos, about twice the minimum legal daily wage and equivalent to about $ 4. Their positive vision of rural <LOCATION> Chile </LOCATION> is shared by <PERSON> Pinochet </PERSON>'s campaign strategists, who predict overwhelming voter support from the heartland Opposition leaders contend that the countryside's poor majority are suffering economically and are eager for a change but wo n't say so publicly because they fear losing their jobs or government benefits, such as pensions and housing subsidies. The opposition's political campaign is aimed at overcoming such fears, while recognizing them as legitimate. One prominent campaign slogan in the countryside is `` Say yes, but vote no.'' Several farm workers said harvesting jobs paid an average 700 pesos, or less than $ 3 a day, and lasted only a few months a year. `` You ca n't live on that,'' <PERSON> Arias </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Jorge </PERSON> <PERSON> Contreras </PERSON>, who sells bread from the back of his small, battered truck in the countryside around <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Fernando </LOCATION>, said most of his customers opposed <PERSON> Pinochet </PERSON>'s continued rule. `` I travel 50 kilometers -LRB- 30 miles -RRB- a day, and I can tell you there are a lot more people for the ` no' vote than the ` yes' vote,'' he said But he added: `` Lots of people may vote ` yes' because they're afraid. He said that in one remote town on his bread route, <LOCATION> Tinguiririca </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Alto </LOCATION>, `` people are telling each other that if you vote ` no,' you'll be arrested.'' The government has said the vote will be secret, and the opposition has publicized its plans to have representatives at each polling place to prevent intimidation.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880920-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-20-88 0313EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-YankeePanky     09-20 0641</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Yankee Panky,0658</SECOND>
<HEAD>Musical by Philippine Foreign Minister Gets New York Debut</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By DAVID BEARD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Teddy </PERSON> <PERSON> Roosevelt </PERSON> skips across the stage, bullying subordinates and singing his joy at another war. Commodore <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Dewey </PERSON> orders the beginning of the Battle of <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION> to a Latin jazz accompaniment. `` Manifest Destiny: An Evening of Yankee Panky,'' opening Wednesday in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> for a five-show run, is the unlikeliest of musicals _ a bittersweet history of <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s 1898 takeover of the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION>, written by that nation's foreign secretary, <PERSON> Raul </PERSON> <PERSON> Manglapus </PERSON>. Inspired by the musical `` 1776,'' which ran on Broadway from 1969 to 1971, <PERSON> Manglapus </PERSON> wrote `` Yankee Panky'' 14 years ago, while on a self-imposed exile from the authoritarian rule of President <PERSON> Ferdinand </PERSON> <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON>. `` He thought a musical would be a painless way to show a neglected part of our nation's history,'' said his son <PERSON> Francis </PERSON>, who is producing the play. `` He really researched it. The information that he gained for the play he's really using right now.'' `` Right now'' refers to <PERSON> Manglapus </PERSON>' protracted negotiations with <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> over the future of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military bases in the islands. He was appointed foreign secretary last year by President <PERSON> Corazon </PERSON> <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON>. As a negotiator, <PERSON> Manglapus </PERSON> has demanded a steep increase in the amount of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> aid in exchange for continued use of the bases, the largest <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military complex on foreign soil. As a playwright, he provides an insight into why some Filipinos consider the military outposts an odious vestige of American rule. In `` Yankee Panky,'' <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> diplomats beguile Philippine rebels, promising them arms, support and independence if they defeat the Spanish colonialists, but offering no written guarantees. Straw-hatted American businessmen plot to wean Filipinos from fruit juices to soft drinks and create new <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> export markets. The garrulous Roosevelt is portrayed nearly to satiric excess, smoking cigars, grinning and barking: `` I say you ca n't civilize without the use of force.'' With a score that ranges from Tin Pan Alley to bossa nova, `` Yankee Panky'' explores the broken promises, the bloody suppression of a Philippine war of independence in 1899-1901 and the battle for the <LOCATION> Philippine </LOCATION> mind that ensued. The nation finally gained independence in 1946. `` The goal of this play is to destroy certain myths that people still cling to,'' <PERSON> Francis </PERSON> <PERSON> Manglapus </PERSON> said during a rehearsal. `` There's this myth that the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has a ` special relationship' with the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION>. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> is not looking out for our interests; it is looking out for its interests.'' <PERSON> Manglapus </PERSON> wrote the play while on a <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fellowship </ORGANIZATION> to study Philippine-American relations from 1898 to 1902. A musical was a natural vehicle for the 69-year-old <PERSON> Manglapus </PERSON>. At home on the piano, xylophone and drums, he had written songs to cheer fellow prisoners of the Japanese in World War II. Later he led a <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION> Dixieland band _ The Executives _ that jammed with <PERSON> Lionel </PERSON> <PERSON> Hampton </PERSON> and <PERSON> Prince </PERSON> <PERSON> Sihanouk </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION>, a part-time jazz clarinetist. <PERSON> Francis </PERSON> <PERSON> Manglapus </PERSON> and director <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Pudenz </PERSON> tried to stage `` Yankee Panky'' in 1980, `` but the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION> was n't front-page news then,'' the younger <PERSON> Manglapus </PERSON> said. After <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> was toppled, `` Yankee Panky'' became a success in <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION>, and a recent crop of political plays on <LOCATION> Broadway </LOCATION> encouraged <PERSON> Manglapus </PERSON> and <LOCATION> Pudenz </LOCATION> to take a plunge in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>. Its 35-member cast performs traditional Philippine dances and sings lyrics that range from superficial -LRB- `` To spread civilization; To improve sanitation'' -RRB- to savage -LRB- `` They like to play the democrat; And never teach the little brown brat.'' -RRB- <PERSON> Pudenz </PERSON> hopes its run at the <ORGANIZATION> Episcopal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cathedral </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> John </ORGANIZATION> the Divine in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> is a prelude for another presentation in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. `` We would love to do it in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, so that the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> could see it, and understand a little bit more,'' <PERSON> Pudenz </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880920-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-20-88 0007EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-OLY--Newspage-Diving     09-20 0206</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-OLY--Newspage-Diving,0211</SECOND>
<HEAD>U.S. Diver Louganis Wins Gold Medal A Day After Accident</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SEOUL, South Korea (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 American <PERSON> Greg </PERSON> <PERSON> Louganis </PERSON> won his second consecutive Olympic gold medal in men's springboard diving Tuesday just a day after he hit the back of his head on the board. Sporting a bare spot on his head, <PERSON> Louganis </PERSON> gave a picturesque performance and knocked off two Chinese challengers. He finished with 730.80. Tan Liangde of <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, runner-up to <PERSON> Louganis </PERSON> at the 1984 Summer Games, had 704.88 to win the silver medal and <PERSON> Li </PERSON> <PERSON> Deliang </PERSON> of <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> finished with 665.28 to take the bronze. The other American, <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Bradshaw </PERSON>, came in fifth with 652.99, behind <PERSON> Albin </PERSON> <PERSON> Killat </PERSON> of <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> who had 661.47 points. The dive that marred <PERSON> Louganis </PERSON>' performance in Monday's preliminaries caused him no problem Tuesday The reverse 2 -LCB- - somersault in the pike position earned three 9s, three 8.5 s and one In the preliminaries, he received two zeros, one .5, three 1s, one 1.5 and five stitches. <PERSON> Louganis </PERSON>, 28, is seeking to become the first man to win both the springboard and platform events in consecutive Olympics. He captured his first Olympic medal in 1976 when, at the age of 16, he finished second in the platform competition.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880920-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-20-88 0314EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-NebraskaSenate     09-20 0753</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nebraska Senate,0769</SECOND>
<HEAD>New Alliance Candidate Enters Nebraska Race, Kerrey Drops Debates</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By JIM NOLAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>OMAHA, Neb. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The race for <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> between <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> incumbent <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Karnes </PERSON> and Democratic challenger <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Kerrey </PERSON> has been disrupted by a third-party candidate, a maverick legislator who was nominated at a convention held in a fast-food restaurant. <PERSON> Kerrey </PERSON>, a former one-term governor who is leading in the polls, boycotted Sunday what was to have been the second of eight campaign debates after organizers agreed to include state Sen. <PERSON> Ernie </PERSON> <PERSON> Chambers </PERSON>, candidate of the left-wing <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Alliance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Kerrey </PERSON> said Monday he would engage in future debates with <PERSON> Karnes </PERSON> only if the incumbent barred Chambers and renounced the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Alliance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, which <PERSON> Kerrey </PERSON> characterized as a fringe group bent on disrupting the political process. `` The issue is whether the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Alliance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> deserves to be in our debates,'' <PERSON> Kerrey </PERSON> said. `` I have said no. I have said that a party of 14 members, that holds its nominating convention in Booth No. 2 at <PERSON> Denny </PERSON>'s Restaurant should not be included.'' <PERSON> Karnes </PERSON> called Chambers a legitimate candidate who had a right to participate in the debates. But on Monday, <PERSON> Karnes </PERSON> said he would `` not be debating any further'' and blamed <PERSON> Kerrey </PERSON> for the breakdown. `` <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Kerrey </PERSON> is the debate-buster in this campaign,'' he said. `` I believe <PERSON> Kerrey </PERSON> has accomplished his goal of destroying the debate process. I do not believe it will do me any good to continue.'' The first debate certainly did <PERSON> Karnes </PERSON> little good. Speaking at the State Fair in <LOCATION> Lincoln </LOCATION> on Sept. 5, he was booed when he said `` we need fewer farmers.'' <PERSON> Karnes </PERSON>, who in one of his commercials picks up a bale of hay and is described as the farmer-senator, said the remark was a slip of the tongue. <PERSON> Karnes </PERSON>, a lawyer for an <LOCATION> Omaha </LOCATION> grain company, was plucked from political obscurity in 1986 when newly elected GOP Gov. <PERSON> Kay </PERSON> <PERSON> Orr </PERSON> chose him to succeed Democratic Sen. <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Zorinsky </PERSON>, who died of a heart attack. Analysts believe <PERSON> Karnes </PERSON> stands to gain from Chambers' candidacy. <PERSON> Chambers </PERSON>, who is black, is very popular in the predominantly low-income, Democratic-voting <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Omaha </LOCATION> district he has represented in the Legislature for 18 years. Blacks make up about 12 percent of <LOCATION> Omaha </LOCATION>'s population and there are few blacks in the state outside its largest city. Chambers, a barber, has a long history of controversy in <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION> politics. While most state senators wear suits on the floor of the <ORGANIZATION> Legislature </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Chambers </PERSON> wears a sweat shirt and blue jeans. He once called <LOCATION> Libyan </LOCATION> leader <PERSON> Moammar </PERSON> <PERSON> Gadhafi </PERSON> a `` great man'' and said President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> was `` a Rambo-esque character in the last stages of senility.'' Chambers acknowledged that his candidacy could hurt <PERSON> Kerrey </PERSON>, but added, `` It would be a mistake, it would diminish me as a person and the significance of what I'm about, to say I'm running this race to stop <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Kerrey </PERSON>,'' <PERSON> Chambers </PERSON> said. `` I want to stop both of them _ I want to win.'' But stopping the Democrats nationally is an avowed goal of the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Alliance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, a black-led organization that describes itself as multiracial, leftist, opposed to <LOCATION> Contra </LOCATION> aid and nuclear weapons and favoring more rights for women and homosexuals. In <LOCATION> Omaha </LOCATION> last week, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Alliance </LOCATION> presidential candidate <PERSON> Lenora </PERSON> <PERSON> Fulani </PERSON> said her campaign sought to `` dump <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>.'' `` It would give me great joy to spoil for a party that has come into the Afro-American community and other communities in this county and taken our vote, taken our hope, taken our desire and turned it into a Dukakis-Lloyd <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> ticket,'' Ms. <PERSON> Fulani </PERSON> said. An <ORGANIZATION> Omaha </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> World-Herald </ORGANIZATION> poll released Sunday showed <PERSON> Kerrey </PERSON> favored by 51 percent of the 755 registered voters questioned by telephone statewide Sept. 14-16. <PERSON> Karnes </PERSON> was favored by 33 percent and <PERSON> Chambers </PERSON> had 4 percent. Eleven percent said they were undecided. The poll had a margin of error of 3.6 percent. Ironically, <PERSON> Kerrey </PERSON> was the original <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Alliance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> nominee. In the May 10 primary, the former governor received 20 <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Alliance </ORGANIZATION> write-in votes and <PERSON> Chambers </PERSON> finished fourth with five votes. <PERSON> Kerrey </PERSON> declined the nomination, and <PERSON> Chambers </PERSON> was chosen in July at a state convention held at a <PERSON> Denny </PERSON>'s Restaurant. <PERSON> Chambers </PERSON>, who also was running unopposed for re-election to his seat in the <ORGANIZATION> Legislature </ORGANIZATION>, accepted the nomination. After the courts ruled he could not run for two offices simultaneously, Chambers elected to remain on the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> ballot and said he would mount a write-in legislative campaign.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880920-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-20-88 0019EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Pope-Africa Bjt   09-20 0726</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Pope-Africa, Bjt,0745</SECOND>
<HEAD>Trip Serves to Prepare South Africa Voyage</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP News Analysis</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DENNIS REDMONT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>VATICAN CITY (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Pope <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> II </PERSON>'s 10-day swing through <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> has paradoxically served to reduce the stigma of any future visit to <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>, while firmly including the <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION> as a player in efforts to solve the region's conflicts. An unexpected touchdown in <LOCATION> Johannesburg </LOCATION>, involvement in a hostage drama in <LOCATION> Lesotho </LOCATION>, and quiet diplomacy to nudge <LOCATION> Mozambique </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> away from confrontation marked a trip which initially had only the trappings of the fourth papal pastoral visit to the continent. `` You could say it was an act of grace,'' commented <ORGANIZATION> Vatican </ORGANIZATION> Secretary of State <PERSON> Agostino </PERSON> <PERSON> Casaroli </PERSON>, pondering the consequences after bad weather forced a landing in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>, the very country whose racial policies the <PERSON> pope </PERSON> excoriated at his first touchdown in <LOCATION> Zimbabwe </LOCATION>. Before <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON>'s visit to <LOCATION> Zimbabwe </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Botswana </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Lesotho </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Swaziland </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Mozambique </LOCATION>, some bishops and African leaders urged him to strike the nation of apartheid from any future travel, but by the time the pope landed in <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION> Monday night, few voices against a future stopover had been raised. Even the Rev. <PERSON> Allan </PERSON> <PERSON> Boesak </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> Protestant </ORGANIZATION> anti-apartheid leader who attended a papal ecumenical papal meeting in <LOCATION> Maputo </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mozambique </LOCATION>, stopped short of discouraging a trip, despite his charges that the pope had been too soft on the white minority government. <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION> prelates confirmed the pope would fly to <LOCATION> Madagascar </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Tanzania </LOCATION> in 1989, and that he was considering a visit to rigidly Marxist <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION>. A customary Vatican procedure is to include countries of the same region on one trip, making the prospect of a <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> trip in the near future a distinct possibility. After all, the pope had now landed at Jan Smuts airport, sipped tea with Foreign Minister <PERSON> Pik </PERSON> <PERSON> Botha </PERSON>, ridden 190 miles in a bulletproof government sedan, stopped for refreshments at an Afrikaner gas station and visited people injured in the storming in <LOCATION> Lesotho </LOCATION> of a hijacked bus, during which six people were killed by South African commandos. The pope, who has rarely held back from sensitive subjects on his foreign tours, continued to speak out: _ He lectured the 20-year-old king of <LOCATION> Swaziland </LOCATION> and his four wives about polygamy _ He repeatedly nudged <LOCATION> Mozambique </LOCATION>'s Marxist government, overwhelmed by 6 million people on the edge of famine and by the ravages of a civil war, to sit down at the negotiating table with rebels, offering the church's help if needed The latter subject was all the more delicate since President <PERSON> Joaquim </PERSON> <PERSON> Chissano </PERSON>'s government until recently held on to confiscated church property, while the <ORGANIZATION> Mozambique </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Resistance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Movement </ORGANIZATION> _ a shadowy group holding much of the country _ tried to depict itself to the <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION> and the outside world as anti-communist, and thus in favor of religious freedom. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> set his own agenda in some of the most graphic speeches of any papal trip, exclaming: `` Yes, my beloved brothers, I have felt the heart of this country bleed ... I am taking home images of suffering ... the worried gaze of many children, the look of uncertainty of so many youths, the tired eyes of so many adults and the sad look of the aged.'' Becoming unusually specific, he has permitted Mozambican bishops to encourage negotiations between the government and rebels, while backing a government program of amnesty which has already convinced 2,000 rebels to lay down their weapons. `` The pope's trip was like rain on scorched earth,'' commented <PERSON> Nampula </PERSON> <PERSON> Bishop </PERSON> <PERSON> Dom </PERSON> <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Vieira </PERSON> <PERSON> Pinto </PERSON>, saying it marked a turning point in church-state relations. On the government side, <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Luis </PERSON> <PERSON> Cabaco </PERSON>, head of the ruling <ORGANIZATION> FRELIMO </ORGANIZATION> party's foreign relations department, said <LOCATION> Mozambique </LOCATION> could endorse practically everything the pope had recommended. <PERSON> Cabaco </PERSON> added that the government also felt encouraged by the <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Mozambique </LOCATION>'s efforts to revive a non-aggression pact and economic cooperation with <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> and by the <PERSON> pope </PERSON>'s worldwide appeal for aid. According to diplomats, who spoke on condition of anonymity, the <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION> _ as it has done in the case of <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> and other countries _ is dangling the prospect of formal diplomatic relations with <LOCATION> Mozambique </LOCATION> as an incentive for it to continue supporting the regional peace process and the thaw in religious freedom.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>___</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Rome </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> Chief <PERSON> Dennis </PERSON> <PERSON> Redmont </PERSON> has covered the papacy since 1975.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880920-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-20-88 0315EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Salvador     09-20 0359</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Salvador,0371</SECOND>
<HEAD>Rebel-Ordered Transport Ban Largely Heeded</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DOUGLAS GRANT MINE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SAN SALVADOR, El Salvador (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A vast majority of bus and truck drivers heeded a nationwide transportation ban called by leftist rebels despite assurances from the military that traffic would be protected. Only a handful of mass transit buses circulated Monday in this capital of 1 million inhabitants, forcing workers to walk to their jobs or pay inflated fares to pickup truck and van owners. More than 70 percent of urban bus traffic was halted and inter-city service was even more severely curtailed, an official of the bus owners' association told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>. A dispatcher at one of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>'s two terminals said 90 percent of the bus service between provinces was stopped. The indefinite ban on bus and truck traffic was the fifth called this year by Marxist-led guerrillas waging a nearly 9-year-old war against the U.S.-backed government. Previous rebel bans lasted three days each. The government urged citizens to ignore Monday's ban, saying the military would protect vehicles. Col. <PERSON> Mauricio </PERSON> <PERSON> Vargas </PERSON>, the army chief of operations, told <ORGANIZATION> YSU </ORGANIZATION> radio that about 13,000 soldiers were providing and protecting transport. `` We refuse to allow a violent minority to impose its will on us,'' he said. Soldiers rode shotgun aboard several state-owned buses circulating in the capital and some army trucks carried passengers to and from the city outskirts. <PERSON> Lorgio </PERSON> <PERSON> DeLeon </PERSON>, a 48-year-old father of six, was stranded at the eastern bus terminal with no way to get to his tailor's job in <LOCATION> Zacatecoluca </LOCATION>, 35 miles southeast of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>. `` This hurts the poor worker more than anyone. We do n't work today, we get our pay docked,'' he said. Rebels of the <ORGANIZATION> Farabundo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Marti </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION> said the ban was in response to the actions of riot troops who broke up a Sept. 13 demonstration by leftist university students. The troops used tear gas and clubs and fired shots in the air to disperse nearly 3,000 students at that protest. About 250 demonstrators were arrested. All but 14 were subsequently released, with the remainder charged with what the government called `` terrorist acts.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880920-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-20-88 0254EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Gilbert-Reporter'sNotebook     09-20 0432</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Gilbert-Reporter's Notebook,0445</SECOND>
<HEAD>Sketches Drawn From the Aftermath of Hurricane Gilbert</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT GLASS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>KINGSTON, Jamaica (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Some notes gathered in the aftermath of Hurricane Gilbert, which struck <LOCATION> Jamaica </LOCATION> on Sept. 12:
</TEXT>
<HEAD>___</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 The 17 members of a <ORGANIZATION> British </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airways </ORGANIZATION> crew got caught up in the hurricane at <LOCATION> Kingston </LOCATION>'s Pegasus Hotel. The morning after, they took over the duties of hotel staffers, most of whom were unable to get to work. In return for free meals, flight attendants and cockpit crew waited tables, washed dishes, tended bar and lugged suitcases up to guests' rooms for a full day. For burser <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Evans </PERSON>, the toughest part was washing dishes, pots and pans `` piled to the ceiling'' with no hot water. The answer was to use a little lime juice.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>___</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Power failure knocked out traffic lights in <LOCATION> Kingston </LOCATION>, and driving in the city of 750,000 inhabitants became a risky business. You nose into the road and hope oncoming cars stop and let you in. If they do n't, you just wait. At one especially busy intersection, a fellow wearing a bright red shirt and flowered bermuda shorts directed traffic with the flair of a seasoned cop.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>___</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 An insurance company's billboard that greets visitors to the northern coast resort of <PERSON> Ocho </PERSON> <PERSON> Rios </PERSON> could cause a shrug. The sign, a quarter of which was ripped away, carries the message: `` ` S YOUR HOME INSURED? If so, relax and enjoy the scenery.''
</TEXT>
<HEAD>___</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Along with winds reaching 145 mph, Hurricane <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON> dumped up to 10 inches of rain on <LOCATION> Jamaica </LOCATION>, swelling rivers and reservoirs. But a week after the storm, water was in dangerously short supply because electricity had not been restored to most pumping and filtration stations. In <LOCATION> Kingston </LOCATION>, people gathered at burst water mains and open hydrants. In the countryside, roads were lined with people trudging behind wooden carts loaded with jugs and buckets filled with water. Women balanced plastic containers on their heads. Health officials warned against taking water from rivers and streams that could be contaminated by the carcasses of animals. Millions of water-purification tablets were being airlifted into the country.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>___</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Twelve families were sheltering at <LOCATION> Woodbourne </LOCATION> Seventh-day Adventist Church in <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Thomas </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Parish </LOCATION>, one of the four eastern Jamaican districts hardest hit by the hurricane. They told how the winds demolished their homes and furniture and and wiped out their meager farms. A slightly built teen-age boy was asked if he had anything to say. `` I feel frightened, sir,'' he said. `` We do n't have anyplace to live. It seemed cruel to ask him anything else.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880920-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-20-88 0258EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FarmScene     09-20 0958</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Farm Scene,950</SECOND>
<HEAD>Tighter Controls Needed on Dairy Promotion Program, Audit Says</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DON KENDALL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Farm Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A national dairy promotion program financed by dairy farmers should be tightened to eliminate slipshod accounting methods, waste and unauthorized use of funds, an Agriculture Department audit says. The report by the <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION>'s office of inspector general criticized the <ORGANIZATION> Agricultural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Marketing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>, which administers the program, for not providing adequate guidelines and controls over those sharing in the funds, and for submitting incomplete information to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. `` AMS' annual report to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> did not include information relating to approximately 60 percent of the activities of the program,'' the auditors said. `` <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> had not been informed as to the accountability of approximately $ 374.4 million of $ 619.7 million of the Dairy Promotion Program assessments for the three-year period ending April 30, 1987.'' The inspector general's office said it was looking into at least one case of possible fraud. However, it declined to provide details and said only that a report on the investigation would be issued later. The program was created by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> in a 1983 law that imposes a mandatory assessment of 15 cents for each 100 pounds of milk produced and marketed in the 48 contiguous states. Producers may assign up to 10 cents of the assessment to regional or state qualified programs, or QPs, that have similar promotional projects. But at least 5 cents of the assessment must be sent to the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dairy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Promotion </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION>, or <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dairy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION>, which consists of 36 dairy farmers appointed by the secretary of agriculture. The board finances national promotional programs, including television commercials, to help sell more milk and other dairy products, all subject to review by AMS officials. According to the report, which has been circulating recently within the dairy industry and the department, auditors looked into the use of program funds during the period of May 1985 through May 1987 and `` other periods as deemed necessary.'' During that period, approximately 291 billion pounds of milk were marketed, with an assessment of around $ 436.9 million, of which almost $ 168.2 million was remitted to the national board and $ 268.7 million credited to the QPs. The audit report said: _ Five of the 18 QPs reviewed passed $ 14.7 million of $ 15.6 million in assessment funds collected to other QPs and incurred approximately $ 235,000 in administrative costs _ Two other QPs improperly used $ 106,500 for activities such as school activity funds, athletic tournaments, support of veterinary services, the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Future </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Farmers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION> and other miscellaneous accounts _ Five QPs with assessments funds totaling about $ 20.5 million had internal control weaknesses such as separation of duties, management of promotional materials and procurement systems _ Four QPs incurred $ 2.4 million in administrative costs in excess of the 5 percent limit set by the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dairy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> `` In the absence of guidelines concerning the use of the assessment funds, the QPs and an affiliated organization, the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dairy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Industry </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> -LRB- of <LOCATION> Rosemont </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ill. </LOCATION> -RRB-, had only their discretion to follow,'' the report said. Auditors said they questioned the association's classification of `` about $ 5.8 million of administrative costs as program costs, $ 1,500 in monthly per diem to the <ORGANIZATION> UDIA </ORGANIZATION>'s chairman of the board of directors and $ 85 per diem per day in excess of travel-related expenses to members of the <ORGANIZATION> UDIA </ORGANIZATION> board.'' The report recommended a general tightening up of procedures, including accounting by the QPs on how the money is spent. Also, the department's <ORGANIZATION> Agricultural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Marketing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> should `` devise and implement guidelines'' that organizations must follow before getting any funds. In its comments, the AMS agreed to some of the audit report's recommendation but said its authority on others was limited and that action by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> may be required `` If the department concludes that such additional oversight is desirable, AMS would be willing to discuss'' with <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> the purpose and legislative intent of the law authorizing the dairy promotion program, the marketing service said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 When it comes to curbing the cotton boll weevil, it's a matter of timing and tillage rather than how much pesticide is used, the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> says. A seven-year study in the lower <LOCATION> Rio </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Grande </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION> of <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> led to a new state law last year that requires farmers to destroy cotton stalks by Sept. 15. By shredding the stalks and then following up with deep plowing, the destructive weevils are deprived of winter shelter and food when they are dormant. Entomologist <PERSON> Kenneth </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Summy </PERSON> of the department's <ORGANIZATION> Agricultural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> says in a report that the <LOCATION> Rio </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Grande </LOCATION> study showed that farmers applied pesticides 15 times to 18 times a year in 1980 and 1981. But in 1984, following a year of `` moderate'' stalk destruction, chemicals only had to be applied three or four times, he said. From 1985 to 1987, pesticide use rose again, sometimes equaling 1981 levels, because farmers did n't destroy the cotton stalks. Last year the <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> legislature passed the law requiring cotton growers to destroy stalks annually by Sept. 15 in the <LOCATION> Rio </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Grande </LOCATION> zone, later in other parts of the state. To help state officials enforce stalk destruction, <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> scientists worked out a surveillance system for cotton fields by using infrared aerial photos to detect which fields are not plowed by the deadline, <PERSON> Summy </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>'s 65th annual outlook conference has been scheduled for Nov. 29 through Dec. 1. Analysts from government and the private sector participate in the annual meetings to talk about the national and global economies, agriculture and trade in the coming year. Sessions will include forecasts for major farm commodities, including wheat, corn, soybeans, cotton and meat. Other meetings will focus on food prices, water quality, conservation aquaculture and transportation.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880920-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-20-88 0318EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Haiti-Analysis     09-20 0856</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Haiti-Analysis,0884</SECOND>
<HEAD>Atrocities Linked To Namphy Regime Seen As Key Factor In Coup</HEAD>
<HEAD>AP News Analysis</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By MICHAEL NORTON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> PORT-AU-PRINCE </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Haiti </LOCATION> -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> -RRB- _ An upsurge in atrocities not seen in <LOCATION> Haiti </LOCATION> since the terror of the 29-year <PERSON> Duvalier </PERSON> dynasty appears to have triggered an army revolt that toppled the government of Lt. Gen. <PERSON> Henri </PERSON> <PERSON> Namphy </PERSON>. Some see an opening for democratic reforms under <LOCATION> Haiti </LOCATION>'s new leader, Lt. Gen. <PERSON> Prosper </PERSON> <PERSON> Avril </PERSON>, who announced on nationwide television Sunday that he was assuming the presidency `` to save the country from anarchy and chaos.'' But a Haitian government official said privately that <PERSON> Avril </PERSON> may be thwarted by the military high command, which the official said `` is not favorable to an opening toward the civilian sector and wants to maintain its privileges.'' Before the coup, <PERSON> Avril </PERSON> was the army's adjutant general. Soldiers of the elite, 1,000-man Presidential Guard ousted <PERSON> Namphy </PERSON> and sent him to neighboring <LOCATION> Dominican </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Republic </LOCATION> early Sunday after several hours of sporadic gunfire that apparently caused no casualties. At least six people were reported killed, however, in what were described as reprisals against alleged Tonton Moucoutes thugs blamed for recent atrocities. In justifying the coup, Sgt. <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Heubreux </PERSON> said the noncommissioned officers who led it wanted to restore honor to the army and `` raise the prestige of the Haitian people degraded by so many acts which have revolted the conscience of the Haitian people and the world.'' It was <PERSON> Heubreux </PERSON> who appeared on television here to introduce <PERSON> Avril </PERSON> as the new president of this impoverished <LOCATION> Caribbean </LOCATION> island nation. Under <PERSON> Namphy </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Haiti </LOCATION> experienced increased random killings and intimidation of groups advocating democratic reform. In the worst recent outrage, about 20 hoodlums brandishing machetes, handguns and steel pikes burst into a Roman Catholic church during <LOCATION> Mass </LOCATION> on Sept. 11 and slaughtered 13 people. Seventy-seven others were wounded. The toughs were identified as City Hall workers, and <PERSON> Namphy </PERSON> and <LOCATION> Port-au-Prince </LOCATION> Mayor <PERSON> Franck </PERSON> <PERSON> Romain </PERSON> were widely blamed for the attack. <PERSON> Romain </PERSON> is thought to be a leader of a Macoutes faction. He reportedly was arrested at the presidential palace shortly before the coup, then taken to the <ORGANIZATION> Dominican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION>. He remained there Monday, seeking political asylum and awaiting an exit visa. A Western diplomat, speaking on condition of anonymity, said the church massacre was the apparent trigger for dissident noncomissioned officers who felt they were not getting proper pay and recognition. <PERSON> Avril </PERSON> had helped <PERSON> Namphy </PERSON> overthrow the 4-month-old civilian government of President <PERSON> Leslie </PERSON> <PERSON> Manigat </PERSON> in a bloodless coup on June 19. The diplomat said of the dissident sergeants: `` Under <PERSON> Manigat </PERSON> they felt slighted and snubbed. Under <PERSON> Namphy </PERSON>, they did not receive the material signs of recognition they expected. And on top of that, the atrocity ... -LRB- Sept. 11 -RRB- must have affected them as men-of-the-people.'' Among 19 demands the <ORGANIZATION> Presidential </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> presented to the military high command on Sunday was a call for democracy, with free elections. It was uncertain whether the high command would agree to any democratic reforms. <PERSON> Avril </PERSON>'s pledge to take part in a dialogue with opposition parties was generally welcomed, but popular politician <PERSON> Sylvio </PERSON> <PERSON> Claude </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> leader, remained skeptical. According to <PERSON> Claude </PERSON>, <PERSON> Avril </PERSON> `` is known as a Duvalierist, and all Duvalierists are criminals.'' <PERSON> Avril </PERSON> has been closely identified with the Duvalier regimes since the early 1960s, when he took part in the struggle against anti-Duvalierist guerrillas. <PERSON> Francois </PERSON> `` Papa Doc'' <PERSON> Duvalier </PERSON> destroyed the political power of the army in the 1960s with his private militia of thugs, popularly known as <ORGANIZATION> Tonton </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Macoutes </ORGANIZATION>. Upon his death his son, <PERSON> Jean-Claude </PERSON> `` Baby Doc'' <PERSON> Duvalier </PERSON>, succeeded him in 1971. After the fall of <PERSON> Jean-Claude </PERSON> <PERSON> Duvalier </PERSON> in February 1986, <PERSON> Avril </PERSON> was briefly an adviser to the junta headed by <PERSON> Namphy </PERSON>. <PERSON> Avril </PERSON> was dismissed in March 1986 after popular protest demonstrations against him. <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Birns </PERSON>, director of the Washington-based <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hemispheric </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Affairs </ORGANIZATION>, said the key to the future course of Haitian politics lies with Col. <PERSON> Jean-Claude </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON>, commander of the feared 700-man <ORGANIZATION> Dessalines </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Barracks </ORGANIZATION>. The military high command was said to be resisting efforts by the <ORGANIZATION> Presidential </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> to elevate <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> to armed forces commander in chief. <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> has been indicated on drug trafficking charges by a federal court in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>. White House spokesman <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> on Monday that making <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> army commander `` would certainly give us an indication of the difficulties we will have with this government if he is appointed.'' <PERSON> Birns </PERSON> said, `` Although skeptical that democracy is near in <LOCATION> Haiti </LOCATION>, I think it -LRB- the coup -RRB- is a hopeful sign. <PERSON> Namphy </PERSON>'s rule had degenerated into a highly eccentric and dangerous mode and something had to be done to get rid of him.'' `` Curiously enough, in recent weeks, <PERSON> Jean-Claude </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> ... has established close working relations with some democratic figures in <LOCATION> Haiti </LOCATION>'' and soldiers from the <ORGANIZATION> Dessalines </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Barracks </ORGANIZATION> had been sent to guard <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> churches recently. `` Of course, all these people -LRB- jockeying for authoritarian power -RRB- are thugs,'' <PERSON> Birns </PERSON> said. `` It's a question of relativity.''
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Norton </PERSON> is based in <LOCATION> Port-au-Prince </LOCATION> as correspondent for <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> and has lived in <LOCATION> Haiti </LOCATION> for the past two years.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880920-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-20-88 0319EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Poland-Media     09-20 0586</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Poland-Media,0600</SECOND>
<HEAD>Walesa Making Remarkable Comeback In Official Media</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By JOHN DANISZEWSKI</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WARSAW, Poland (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Solidarity leader <PERSON> Lech </PERSON> <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON>, who was virtually ignored by Polish newspapers and television for the past seven years, is suddenly staging a remarkable comeback in the state-controlled media. Two official publications last week ran interviews of <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON>, a newspaper printed a detailed profile of him, <PERSON> Radio </PERSON> <PERSON> Polonia </PERSON> broadcast his words to its foreign audiences, and most state-run newspapers had front-page headlines last week such as, `` Kiszczak -LRB- the interior minister -RRB- Meets <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON>.'' While <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> is not quite yet a media celebrity in <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>, his name is getting into print again for the first time since martial law was imposed in 1981. The change comes as the official press has begun to push the line that greater dialogue is needed to solve the country's problems. Publication of the first interview Thursday, in the September issue of the monthly Confrontations, followed <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON>'s agreement to end a wave of August strikes in return for the promise of a meeting with government officials that could lead to restoring his union's legal status <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON>, in the interview, called for legalization of Solidarity and for loosening central controls on the economy, politics and society. `` There must be Solidarity'' he said of the union which was suppressed under the martial-law crackdown of Dec. 13, 1981 and outlawed the following year. He added that Solidarity could not function solely as a trade union until `` social and political pluralism also gets into the act in earnest.'' Asked about the recent negotiations with Interior Minister <PERSON> Czeslaw </PERSON> <PERSON> Kiszczak </PERSON>, he said: `` It is either a big game in which you try to outmaneuver <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> once again, or it is really the opening of a new chapter in Polish history. I hope the latter is right.'' He called on <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> to abandon centralized economic planning and embrace a system to `` create possibilities.'' He added: `` Only in pluralism can I see a chance for progress and better living. As responsible people we should discuss how to leave behind a model which has not stood the test.'' <PERSON> Adam </PERSON> <PERSON> Kowalski </PERSON>, deputy editor of Confrontations, said the editors felt `` satisfaction, joy'' when they submitted the interview and got approval from the <ORGANIZATION> Censorship </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> to publish it. <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> spoke to the two reporters at his home on Sept. 1, the same day he ended a strike at the Lenin shipyard in <LOCATION> Gdansk </LOCATION>. The two journalists also published a version of the interview in another magazine, Reporter. State-owned Radio Polonia, which beams official propaganda in 10 languages to other countries around the world, devoted six minutes Friday of its daily half-hour broadcasts to a <LOCATION> Walesa </LOCATION> interview, a station spokesman said. In the broadcast, <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> said both he and the government had learned something during the past seven years. `` You are the first Polish journalists of the officially published press since December 13, 1981, to ask me for an interview,'' <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> was quoted in the opening line of the Confrontations piece. The sudden attention to <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> does not suit all Poles. After all, for years <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> was referred to _ when at all _ only negatively, as a private person, as a former leader of a former union or as a tool of foreign powers. `` I think that Gen. <PERSON> Kiszczak </PERSON> should not talk to Mr. <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> because Mr. <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> is just the same kind of citizen as all of us,'' said one man interviewed on the street by state television Saturday.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880920-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-20-88 0323EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Long-termCare     09-20 0580</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Long-term Care,570</SECOND>
<NOTE>For release 10 a.m. EDT; time set by source</NOTE>
<HEAD>Study Says Many People Can't Collect On Nursing Insurance</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JILL LAWRENCE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Six out of 10 people with private nursing home insurance are likely to receive no benefits because of restrictions on their policies, says a study released today by the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Seniors </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cooperative </ORGANIZATION>. The study by the consumer advocacy group concludes `` many of the policies now being offered for sale ... are not likely to pay adequate benefits if and when people need them.'' While there may be a role for the private insurance industry in filling the national need for long-term care protection, `` this role should not include selling bad policies to unsuspecting consumers,'' the study said. <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Firman </PERSON>, president of the Washington-based group, and <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Weissert </PERSON>, director of the program on aging at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> North </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Carolina </ORGANIZATION>, conducted the study. They based their findings on an analysis of 77 typical private long-term health care insurance plans offered by 21 companies. The most common restriction, found in 77 percent of the plans, was that a person must first be hospitalized for his or her condition before being allowed to collect benefits for subsequent nursing home care. `` Fifty-four percent of nursing home admissions do not come directly from a hospital and will not qualify for coverage under a plan with this restriction,'' the report said. The other major limitation, included in 40 percent of the plans, said people must first receive skilled-level nursing home care before they can qualify for lower levels of long-term care. Such a requirement excludes 46 percent of nursing home residents, the study said. `` The effect of these exclusions is even more dramatic and troubling'' when combined with waiting periods and other restrictions, the report said. `` The average probability of not collecting benefits ... was 61 percent, if you are admitted to a nursing home.'' Although 95 percent of the plans studied said they cover patients with Alzheimer's disease, the researchers said 81 percent of the plans contain the two major restrictions regarding hospitalization and skilled care. `` Given the long duration and deteriorating characteristics of Alzheimer's disease, it is likely that for much of the patient's period of illness, these restrictions would preclude eligibility for coverage,'' they said The study said the most common type of nursing home coverage is a $ 50-a-day indemnity benefit _ an amount it labeled `` grossly inadequate'' to meet the expected costs of care. If someone purchased such a plan now and entered a nursing home in 20 years, the study said, out-of-pocket costs could reach up to $ 130,000 if the plan had no inflation protection. Two-thirds of the companies studied did not offer inflation protection. `` For most people who are in a nursing home for a long period of time, the effect of most of the plans we studied will be to delay but not to prevent eventual impoverishment,'' the researchers said. Fifty-six of the plans studied offered home health care coverage, but substantial restrictions `` make it unlikely that most persons in need of home care will collect significant benefits,'' the study said. The most common restriction is requiring a prior covered nursing home confinement before a policy-holder can tap into home care benefits. Other plans require only prior hospitalization, according to the report. Several lawmakers have introduced long-term care insurance schemes involving the federal government or joint public-private efforts; <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> is expected to consider the matter seriously next year.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880920-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-20-88 0252EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Census-Homeless     09-20 0290</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Census-Homeless,290</SECOND>
<HEAD>Census Planning Special Homeless Count</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A special effort to count the nation's homeless will be conducted as part of the 1990 Census <PERSON> Cynthia </PERSON> <PERSON> Taeuber </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Census </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> said Monday that officials have decided to hold a separate count, a few days before the regular national census, in an effort to count those living on the streets and in shelters. The homeless have become an increasingly visible part of <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> society, but there are no concrete estimates of their numbers. On March 20, 1990, Census takers will visit emergency shelters, both public and private, and will go to various street locations which have been identified as places the homeless congregate, said <PERSON> Taeuber </PERSON>. The street search for the homeless will be conducted from 2 a.m. to 4 a.m., and shelters will be visited from 6 p.m. to midnight, she said. Census officials will be working with various groups and agencies that serve as advocates for the homeless, explained <PERSON> Taeuber </PERSON>, in order to determine in advance where to look for these people. In addition, the agency will encourage people with those groups, and the homeless themselves, to work as enumerators in the count. However, these workers will have to pass the same written exams and other criteria as all Census workers. Census day for most of the nation is April 1, 1990. The count of the homeless is being taken a few days early, however, because many shelters close at the end of March or beginning of April, <PERSON> Taeuber </PERSON> said. She added that the <ORGANIZATION> Census </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> will not try to define who constitutes a homeless person. Instead it will merely issue counts of people living on the streets and those staying in various types of shelters.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880920-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-20-88 0253EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-SenatorialHaircuts     09-20 0465</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Senatorial Haircuts,460</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHINGTON TODAY: Senate Barbers Shaved Senators _ and Taxpayers</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LAWRENCE L. KNUTSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A shave and a haircut used to cost nothing, if you were a <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> senator and were shaved and trimmed in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> barber shop. And when one reform-minded senator tried to eliminate free senatorial shaving and hair cutting 37 years ago, his shaved-for-free colleagues rebelled. The senator was the late <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION>, and his experience was recalled in a recent <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> speech by <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Republican leader <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON> had gone to the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> barber shop for a haircut. `` After the barber had done his work,'' said <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>, `` <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON> began to think that his income was ample enough to pay for his own haircut _ which then cost a dollar and a quarter _ and not charge it to the taxpayer.'' So <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON> introduced an amendment to the annual legislative appropriations act to cut off funds for the barber shop unless it began charging senators for its services. The counterattack was not long coming. At a <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> hearing, Sen. <PERSON> Carl </PERSON> <PERSON> Hayden </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION> complimented <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON> on his haircut, then recalled that the haircut issue was one that flared from time to time. <PERSON> Hayden </PERSON> said that when he first came to the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> he became disturbed at newspaper articles complaining about free senatorial haircuts and discussed the matter with <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> veteran <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Borah </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION>. `` Senator <PERSON> Borah </PERSON> said, ` You tell that reporter to go to the devil. I want the same service that was received here by <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> Clay </PERSON> and <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> C </PERSON>. <PERSON> Calhoun </PERSON>.''' <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> picked up the story, saying, `` After a good laugh, the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> shouted down Senator <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON>' amendment, and the free haircut survived.'' But only for the monent. `` I want to assure taxpayers that today senators pay their own way when they have their hair cut, as Senator <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON> tried and failed to accomplish 37 years ago,'' <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> said. While they pay more than a dollar and a quarter, the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> barbering charges may be a bit gentler than those of most commercial barbershops. The current charge for a haircut in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> barbershop is $ 4.50. More elaborate cuts are $ 6.50. Hair styling costs $ 9.00. A shave costs $ 4.00.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 During debate on a major drug bill earlier this month, Rep. <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Rangel </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.Y. </LOCATION>, resorted to a ruffle of rhetorical flourishes to introduce the next speaker, Rep. <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Rostenkowski </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Ill </LOCATION>. `` At this time I would would like to recognize for eight minutes the chairman of the awesome and powerful <ORGANIZATION> Ways </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Means </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, one of the most distinguished leaders that we have in this <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, Mr. <PERSON> Rostenkowski </PERSON> from <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION>. `` The awesome chairman is recognized,'' said Rep. <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Carr </PERSON>, D-Mich., who was presiding
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880920-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-20-88 0252EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-US-MissileProjects Bjt   09-20 0770</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-US-Missile Projects, Bjt,750</SECOND>
<HEAD>US, Allies Try To Slow Argentine, Brazilian, North Korean Missiles</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BARRY SCHWEID</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Diplomatic Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and its industrial allies are trying to slow the development of missiles in <LOCATION> Argentina </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> and hope to have the cooperation of the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> in the global campaign against proliferation. The <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> confirmed on Monday that the seven allies, meeting in <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION> Sept. 8-9, exchanged expressions of concern about missile proliferation and technology transfers that might enhance <LOCATION> Argentina </LOCATION>'s capability. Afterward, a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> official told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> the same group registered concern in its deliberations about programs in <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>. The official, who spoke on condition of anonymity, said Secretary of State <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> may pursue the problem with Soviet Foreign Minister <PERSON> Eduard </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shevardnadze </PERSON> during their talks in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> on Thursday and Friday. In any event, the official said, Assistant Secretary of <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Allen </PERSON> <PERSON> Holmes </PERSON> will take up the issue at talks in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> next week with <PERSON> Viktor </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Karpov </PERSON>, senior Soviet arms control negotiator. <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>'s attempt to extend the range of its Scud B missile should demonstrate to the Soviets the proliferation problem extends to their region, the official said. <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION>'s attempt to develop the Sonda IV missile is the other program the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> discussed with representatives of <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, the official said. `` It was an attempt to keep everybody up to date in the area,'' the official said. `` They did not adopt any special program. That's not the way it works. Meanwhile, spokesman <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Redman </PERSON>, referring to the medium-range Condor II that <LOCATION> Argentina </LOCATION> reportedly is developing with the help of <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>, said `` the basic concern is that we do what we can to limit this kind of technology because it is the kind of technology that produces missiles that would be nuclear-capable.'' He said they also would exceed `` the range of parameters we established,'' meaning a range beyond 180 miles and a payload in excess of 1,100 pounds. The seven countries agreed last year that they would not export missiles or technology for them that went beyond these limits. Meanwhile, an <ORGANIZATION> Arab </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> League </ORGANIZATION> representative voiced concern about <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s launch Monday of a test satellite into orbit and said it meant the Arabs would have to strengthen their defenses. <PERSON> Clovis </PERSON> <PERSON> Maksoud </PERSON>, who represents the <ORGANIZATION> Arab </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> League </ORGANIZATION> in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, said the satellite gave <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> `` a serious strategic leverage'' since the country already had the capability to fire long-range missiles. <PERSON> Maksoud </PERSON>, in an interview, stressed steps taken jointly by <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> to strengthen their strategic ties. He cited <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> inclusion of <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> in the program to develop a space-based defense against ballistic missiles and `` <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s record, which is replete with disclaiming nuclear capability. As a result, <PERSON> Maksoud </PERSON> said, the launching of a test satellite `` warrants enhancing Arab defensive capabilities'' so that any <LOCATION> Mideast </LOCATION> negotiations produce a peaceful outcome `` rather than ratifying Israeli hegemony.'' The satellite is designed for communications purposes, but the <ORGANIZATION> Arab </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> League </ORGANIZATION> official said it could be used to monitor <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s foes. `` We are deeply concerned that such a communications satellite can be modified into a spy system and, therefore, further enhance the strategic imbalance which the <LOCATION> American-Israeli </LOCATION> strategic agreement has introduced,'' <PERSON> Maksoud </PERSON> said. <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Redman </PERSON> said the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> was not involved in any way with the Israeli program. `` We do n't have any details of the launch beyond what was reported by the Israelis,'' he said. A spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Space </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Command </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION>, Cmdr. <PERSON> Dugald </PERSON> <PERSON> Gillies </PERSON>, said American radars and sensors picked up the <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> satellite shortly after launch. Its orbit has been calculated to have a high point of 716 miles and a low point of 155 miles, he said. `` It was launched early Monday Eastern Daylight Time and is in a near polar orbit,'' <PERSON> Gillies </PERSON> said. Defense officials at the Pentagon said they were unsure exactly what the satellite's payload included. `` But we're leaning toward more of an experimental communications package as opposed to a true spy satellite,'' said one source who spoke on condition of anonymity. `` This launch is impressive because it's a first, but I do n't think this particular satellite is going to offer much more ability to keep tabs on their neighbors,'' the source said <PERSON> Redman </PERSON> stressed that <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> leaders had given public assurances that their goal was `` peaceful purposes of space research and technological advancement.'' <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> is the eighth nation to place a satellite into space. The country is generally believed to have nuclear capability.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880920-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-20-88 0251EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-RuralHealth     09-20 0320</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Rural Health,320</SECOND>
<HEAD>Grants Awarded For Rural Health Research Centers</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CRISPIN Y. CAMPBELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
