<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881006-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-06-88 2350EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p AM-Reagan-Quayle     10-06 0344</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Reagan-Quayle,330</SECOND>
<HEAD>Reagan Says Quayle's Debate Effort `Headed Off Picking On'
Candidate</HEAD>
<HEAD>With AM-Political Rdp Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By W. DALE NELSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said Thursday he believes Republican <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>'s performance in the vice presidential debate `` headed off, or should have headed off, all this picking on him that has been going on.'' `` I think he handled himself very well,'' <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> told reporters who questioned him at a state dinner for President <PERSON> Moussa </PERSON> <PERSON> Traore </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Mali </LOCATION>. `` I really think that <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> actually, just by the whole nature of the event, headed off, or should have headed off, all this picking on him that has been going on,'' the president said. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> also said that some of the points that the Democrats were claiming were made by <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> in the debate were based on `` things that were not factually true, such as who is responsible for the deficit and so forth.'' <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, who is making a campaign trip to <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION> on Friday, said he will be picking up the pace of his involvement in the campaign between now and Election Day. Asked whether he thought the issues were being addressed in the campaign, he said, `` Yes, I do. At least by our side.'' Earlier, posing for photographers before a private meeting with <PERSON> Traore </PERSON>, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> was asked whether he thought <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> would be damaged by the exchange in which Democrat <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> criticized him for comparing himself with the late President <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>. `` No,'' he said. `` I thought that remark was a cheap shot and unbecoming a senator of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>.'' When asked if it was a mistake for <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> to make the comparison in the first place, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said, `` No. The only comparison he was making was that he was being attacked, I think unfairly, on the basis of his age and his experience in government and he was pointing out that <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, who sought the highest office and won it, had actually less experience in government than he had and was the same age.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881006-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-06-88 2358EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-BRF--Philippines-Travel     10-06 0145</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Philippines-Travel,0149</SECOND>
<HEAD>President Bans Frequent Flyers</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MANILA, Philippines (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Corazon </PERSON> <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON> has banned foreign trips by administration officials except in urgent cases approved by her, according to a presidential order published today. Mrs. <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON>, who has visited eight countries, <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION> since she came to power in 1986, said the limit to foreign travel was necessary to conserve money and compel officials to perform their chores at home. `` These officials should be on hand to efficiently and effectively manage their respective offices and be available to respond immediately and decisively to matters that require their attention,'' she said. <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION> newspapers said Mrs. <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON> issued the order because many officials were traveling abroad too frequently. During the last two years, Mrs. <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON> has traveled to <LOCATION> Singapore </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Indonesia </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Switzerland </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Brunei </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881006-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-06-88 2359EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Lebanon-Hostages 2ndLd-Writethru a0748 10-06 0747</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Lebanon-Hostages, 2nd Ld-Writethru, a0748,0766</SECOND>
<HEAD>American Hostages Threatened</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Leads with 3 grafs to UPDATE with Christian militia leader
also calling for U.N. troops in Beirut. Pickup 3rd graf pvs ``We
shall...''; ADDS 4 grafs at bottom with details.</NOTE>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto BEI2</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DONNA ABU-NASR</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BEIRUT, Lebanon (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Kidnappers holding two Americans threatened the hostages' safety Thursday in venting their anger over proposals to send <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> troops to police <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>'s stalled presidential elections. A Christian militia leader on Thursday called for <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> troops in <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>, a day after <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> suggested the idea. The kidnappers' warning came in a typewritten statement in Arabic from the <ORGANIZATION> Revolutionary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION>. The statement was delivered to the <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> independent newspaper An-Nahar along with a <ORGANIZATION> Polaroid </ORGANIZATION> picture of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> hostage <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Cicippio </PERSON>. `` We shall use all the cards to thwart these conspiracies, including the card of the safety of the hostages, which we shall make the backbone of our confrontation,'' the statement said. The photograph showed <PERSON> Cicippio </PERSON>, 58, of <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Forge </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION>, in a navy blue track suit with red stripes sitting on a blanket-covered bed. His hands were clasped in his lap and he was smiling as he faced the camera, but he looked considerably thinner than in previous pictures released by his captors. <PERSON> Cicippio </PERSON> was acting comptroller at the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Beirut </ORGANIZATION> when he was kidnapped on the school's campus on Sept. 12, 1986. Revolutionary Justice, believed linked to <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>, also claims to hold <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Austin </PERSON> <PERSON> Tracy </PERSON>, 57, of <LOCATION> Burlington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Vt. </LOCATION>, an author, who was kidnapped Oct. 21, 1986 in Moslem west <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>. The note came three days after another group, Islamic Jihad for the <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Palestine </ORGANIZATION>, freed <PERSON> Mithileshwar </PERSON> <PERSON> Singh </PERSON> after 20 months of captivity. <PERSON> Singh </PERSON>, an Indian professor, is a legal resident of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Singh </PERSON> was kidnapped in <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> with three <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> colleagues, who are still captives. A <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> team is debriefing <PERSON> Singh </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Wiesbaden </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, and an official close to the team said <PERSON> Singh </PERSON> was providing `` a lot of raw information'' that could be helpful in learning about Americans still held in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>. The official spoke on condition of anonymity. The Americans held with <PERSON> Singh </PERSON> are <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Turner </PERSON>, 41, a native of <LOCATION> Boise </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION>; <PERSON> Alann </PERSON> <PERSON> Steen </PERSON>, 49, of <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>; and <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Polhill </PERSON>, 54, of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. Sixteen foreigners, including nine Americans, are missing in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> and believed held hostage. The longest held is <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON>, chief <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> correspondent for <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>, who was kidnapped March 16, 1985. Thursday's statement from <PERSON> Cicippio </PERSON>'s kidnappers denounced `` the rude call for imperialist intervention under the slogan of internationalization by a colonial power whose black history is mothering our present tragedies.'' This appeared to be a reference to <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>, which proposed this week dispatching a <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> peacekeeping force to <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> to oversee election of a new president in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>, a former French colony. Two rival Moslem and <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> governments emerged in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> after <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION> failed to elect a new head of state to succeed President <PERSON> Amin </PERSON> <PERSON> Gemayel </PERSON> when his six-year term expired Sept. 22. The communique accused right-wing <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> militants of collaborating with <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> North </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Atlantic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Treaty </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> to partition <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> as a first step to turning it into `` an <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> satellite and a <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> base for intrigues against the people of the region.'' It called the Christian militants `` the grandsons of the crusaders'' and warned: `` We shall mete out the just punishment to the conspirators.'' It was the first communique from <ORGANIZATION> Revolutionary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> since July 7, when the group threatened to `` punish'' hostages for the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> downing of an Iranian jetliner over the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION>. Moslems, who make up 55 percent of <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>'s 4 million people, have been fighting for an equal share of power in the nation's 13-year-old civil war Christian militia commander <PERSON> Samir </PERSON> <PERSON> Geagea </PERSON> on Thursday echoed <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>'s call for <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> peacekeepers in <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>'s Christian and Moslem sectors to oversee presidential elections. `` I propose the formation of a <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> force to deploy in the greater <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> to oversee the presidential election,'' <PERSON> Geagea </PERSON> said in an interview with The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Geagea </PERSON> said the plan should include withdrawal of his Lebanese Forces militia from Christian east <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>, and of Syrian troops and allied leftist and Moslem militiamen from the city's western sector. Asked whether the proposed <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> force should remain after <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION> elects a new president, <PERSON> Geagea </PERSON> said: `` It is for the new president and the new Cabinet he forms to decide that.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881006-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-06-88 0025EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-MortuaryStress     10-06 0957</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Mortuary Stress,0986</SECOND>
<HEAD>Military Mortuary Volunteers Get Stress Counseling</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By THERESA HUMPHREY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>DOVER AIR FORCE BASE, Del. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 In December 1985, when 248 soldiers and eight crewmen died in a plane crash in <LOCATION> Gander </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Newfoundland </LOCATION>, the remains were dug out of the ice and snow and transferred here to be identified and prepared for burial. Nearly 400 servicemen stationed at <ORGANIZATION> Dover </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Base </ORGANIZATION> volunteered to work around the clock at the gruesome task, cleaning the building, running errands, putting together uniforms _ all to see that the bodies were returned to their families before Christmas. The long hours in which the tragic became the mundane inevitably led to a special kind of stress, and that in turn led to a special kind of counseling at this base, which serves as the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military's morgue and mortuary. The counseling program for the volunteers is called `` critical incident stress debriefing.'' `` The debriefing process is basically designed to help normal people ... deal with exposure to overwhelming and traumatic events in terms of dealing with it personally, emotionally and professionally,'' said <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON>, director of the base Family Support Center. `` What ended up happening,'' <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> said, recalling the aftermath of the Gander crash, `` was that early on, probably about four days into the operation, people began to notice that people were having a lot of trouble coping, dealing, functioning. `` And a lot of the behavior we saw people dealing with were situations that you find in battle fatigue-like situations, combat stress situations.'' It was n't the first time for <ORGANIZATION> Dover </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Base </ORGANIZATION>. Inside the main door of the mortuary is a simple wooden plaque, headed `` Significant Events,'' listing numbers and faraway place names that evoke memories of flag-draped coffins. The places _ Gander, <LOCATION> Jonestown </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> _ are reminders of the thousands of dead <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> servicemen and the civilians whose remains have come home through the base. A nondescript, 30,000-square-foot building houses the largest mortuary operated by the armed services. `` It's really the largest mortuary in the country,'' said <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Carson </PERSON>, a civilian government employee who started in the funeral business in 1950 and who has been in charge of the facility for 17 years. The mortuary can handle up to 100 bodies per day, and there is storage space for up to 1,000. The average workload is 55 to 60 bodies per month, but the average workload is not what the mortuary is noted for. War, disasters and terrorist acts _ the `` significant events'' _ have sent 23,722 bodies through the mortuary, 21,693 of them during the <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> war. The <LOCATION> Jonestown </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Guyana </LOCATION>, catastrophe where followers of cult leader <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> committed suicide, resulted in 913 deaths in November 1978. The base received the remains of the seven astronauts from the space shuttle Challenger. When a major tragedy occurs, there is an outpouring of volunteers from among the ranks of servicemen stationed at <LOCATION> Dover </LOCATION>, as in the case of the Gander crash. `` The troops on this base, they really rallied to this thing. They really wanted to help,'' <PERSON> Carson </PERSON> said. Before the remains arrive, <PERSON> Carson </PERSON> briefs volunteers in an effort to determine how they perceive death and whether they `` have hang-ups about dead bodies.'' Nearly 200 volunteers were on hand when the bodies of 237 <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> servicemen were returned from <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>, victims of the terrorist bombing of a Marine barracks in October 1983. As is most often the case, the bodies from <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> were identified and embalmed before arriving. At <LOCATION> Dover </LOCATION>, they were given cosmetic work and dressed for burial. <PERSON> Gander </PERSON> was significant because the remains came directly from the crash site, <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> said. Volunteers, working 10 to 14 hours at a stretch, `` were exposed to some things the average person has a great deal of trouble dealing with.'' `` There were some people who had real physical discomfort, people who were nauseous. We had some people who were coping extremely well, able to do the job and keep going,'' <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> said. To help alleviate the stress, a mass debriefing was held and psychological counseling was offered. Since the Gander disaster, the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> and all branches of the military have begun to explore the implications of the exposure to and the handling of dead bodies. <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> and four others at the base have taken training courses designed mainly to help firefighters, police officers and emergency medical personnel learn to cope with the intimacy with death that they find in their jobs. <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> hopes to have at least eight or nine people trained at all times. During the Gander disaster, base personnel reacted intuitively and from knowledge of post traumatic stress disorder, <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> said, adding that officials learned ways to `` shelter people from some of the factors that would increase the likelihood of showing longterm effects from post traumatic stress disorder.'' During a stress debriefing, he said, small groups discuss what they experienced _ `` what it was like for them, what was the hardest part about that, because what we know is that if someone talks about exposure to that type of event, the likelihood of them ending up with longterm post traumatic stress disorder symptoms is going to be markedly decreased.'' According to <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON>, volunteers' time in the mortuary will be reduced in the future. `` Once you go past the third and into the fourth day, you can predict a lot of the things that are going to be happening to people emotionally and physically in terms of wearing down,'' he said. As groups are rotated in and out they will probably be debriefed and given two days off before being allowed to return. `` We know what we need to know now,'' <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881006-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-06-88 0030EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-APArts:BaseballMovies     10-06 1074</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AP Arts: Baseball Movies,1101</SECOND>
<HEAD>The Diamond Is A Studio's Best Friend, At Long Last</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By BOB THOMAS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>HOLLYWOOD (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The success of this summer's `` Bull Durham'' has helped lead the way to an outpouring of movies about baseball, once considered box-office poison by the moguls who ran the <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION> studios. During its first month of release, `` Bull Durham,'' a funny, sexy account of minor-league baseball starring <PERSON> Kevin </PERSON> <PERSON> Costner </PERSON> and <PERSON> Susan </PERSON> <PERSON> Sarandon </PERSON>, scored $ 26 million in ticket sales in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>. The Orion release, written and directed by former <PERSON> bush </PERSON> league player <PERSON> Ron </PERSON> <PERSON> Shelton </PERSON>, has been followed by `` Eight Men Out'' and `` Stealing Home.'' `` Eight Men Out,'' <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Sayles </PERSON>' drama about baseball's greatest scandal, the sellout by members of the 1919 <ORGANIZATION> Chicago </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sox </ORGANIZATION>, received a warm welcome from critics. Stars include <PERSON> Charlie </PERSON> <PERSON> Sheen </PERSON>, D.B. <PERSON> Sweeney </PERSON>, <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Cusack </PERSON> and <PERSON> Christopher </PERSON> <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON>. <PERSON> Jodie </PERSON> <PERSON> Foster </PERSON> won raves for her performance in `` Stealing Home,'' the story of a minor league ballplayer seeking a comeback after years on the skids. TV's <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Harmon </PERSON> co-stars. Upcoming baseball movies include: _ `` <ORGANIZATION> Major </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> League </ORGANIZATION>,'' with <PERSON> Charlie </PERSON> <PERSON> Sheen </PERSON> and <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Berenger </PERSON> as members of a hapless team who suddenly become winners, Rocky-style. _ `` The Scout,'' <PERSON> Anson </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> directing <PERSON> Rodney </PERSON> <PERSON> Dangerfield </PERSON> as a baseball scout who uncovers a potential superstar. It is filming this fall. _ `` Shoeless <PERSON> Joe </PERSON>,'' filming in <LOCATION> Dubuque </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>, with <PERSON> Kevin </PERSON> <PERSON> Costner </PERSON>, <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Earl </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>, <PERSON> Amy </PERSON> <PERSON> Madigan </PERSON> and <PERSON> Burt </PERSON> <PERSON> Lancaster </PERSON>. According to writer-director <PERSON> Phil </PERSON> <PERSON> Alden </PERSON> <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON>, it is not really a baseball movie. Based on a novel by W.P. <PERSON> Kinsella </PERSON>, it concerns a farmer -LRB- <PERSON> Costner </PERSON> -RRB- who is told by a spirit that <PERSON> Shoeless </PERSON> <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> Black </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sox </ORGANIZATION> fame will come back to life if he builds a diamond in a cornfield. _ `` Trading Hearts,'' already playing in a few regions, a romance about a pitcher -LRB- <PERSON> Raul </PERSON> <PERSON> Julia </PERSON> -RRB-, who is cut from spring training. Producer <PERSON> Herb </PERSON> <PERSON> Jaffe </PERSON> said `` Trading Hearts'' also is not a baseball picture. That's a hangover from the long-held belief that baseball strikes out in theaters. The arguments most often heard over the years are that baseball is incomprehensible to foreign audiences, and that women, who make up a large part of movie audiences, will not want to see films about baseball. <PERSON> Thom </PERSON> <PERSON> Mount </PERSON>, producer of `` Bull Durham'' and part owner of the minor league <LOCATION> Durham </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.C. </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Bulls </ORGANIZATION>, encountered such prejudice when he sought a releasing company. `` Five studios turned us down before <ORGANIZATION> Orion </ORGANIZATION> picked up ` <ORGANIZATION> Bull </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Durham </ORGANIZATION>,''' he said. `` We were told simply that baseball pictures do n't make money.'' He attributed the film's success to the appeal of <PERSON> Costner </PERSON>. `` Also, young women are impressed with the role <PERSON> Susan </PERSON> <PERSON> Sarandon </PERSON> plays _ a strong, vital, liberated character.'' By attracting the female audience, `` Bull Durham'' appears to have solved one of <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION>'s prejudices. It remains to be seen whether it can also appeal to foreign moviegoers; there is hope in baseball-crazy <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, and the game has been spreading to other countries as well. Given the reasonable cost _ $ 9 million _ `` <ORGANIZATION> Bull </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Durham </ORGANIZATION>'' is assured of a profit in the domestic market alone. A survey of baseball movies over the years indicates that the studios' anti-baseball attitude may have been justified. Even the box-office luster of <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Redford </PERSON> could n't convert the allegorical `` The Natural'' into a winner. The best-remembered of baseball movies, `` The Pride of the <ORGANIZATION> Yankees </ORGANIZATION>,'' with <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Cooper </PERSON> as <PERSON> Lou </PERSON> <PERSON> Gehrig </PERSON>, was another commercial disappointment. Many other biographical films have failed to excite the movie-going public, especially women: `` The Winning Team,'' with <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> as <PERSON> Grover </PERSON> <PERSON> Cleveland </PERSON> <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON>; `` The Babe <PERSON> Ruth </PERSON> <PERSON> Story </PERSON>,'' <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Bendix </PERSON> as the great Bambino; `` The <PERSON> Stratton </PERSON> <PERSON> Story </PERSON>,'' <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Stewart </PERSON> as <PERSON> Monty </PERSON> <PERSON> Stratton </PERSON>, who staged a comeback after losing a leg; `` The Pride of <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Louis </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Dailey </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> as <PERSON> Dizzy </PERSON> <PERSON> Dean </PERSON>; `` The <PERSON> Jackie </PERSON> <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> <PERSON> Story </PERSON>,'' in which the black pioneer in the major leagues played himself; `` Fear Strikes Out,'' <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON> <PERSON> Perkins </PERSON> as <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Piersall </PERSON>, victim of mental illness. Baseball musicals have proved to be only middling hits: `` Damn Yankees'' with <PERSON> Tab </PERSON> <PERSON> Hunter </PERSON> and <PERSON> Gwen </PERSON> <PERSON> Verdon </PERSON>; `` Take Me Out to the Ballgame,'' with <PERSON> Gene </PERSON> <PERSON> Kelly </PERSON>, <PERSON> Esther </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> and <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Sinatra </PERSON>. The same with comedies: `` Alibi Ike'' -LRB- <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> -RRB-; `` Rhubarb'' -LRB- <PERSON> Ray </PERSON> <PERSON> Milland </PERSON> -RRB-; `` It Happens Every Spring'' -LRB- <PERSON> Ray </PERSON> <PERSON> Milland </PERSON> -RRB-. The difficulty of selling a baseball movie to the studios is illustrated with `` Eight Men Out,'' produced, oddly enough, by three women: <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Boyle </PERSON>, <PERSON> Midge </PERSON> <PERSON> Sanford </PERSON> and <PERSON> Sara </PERSON> <PERSON> Pillsbury </PERSON>. A book about the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sox </ORGANIZATION> scandal was optioned in 1980, but the film was not made until this year. `` We could n't get a development deal anywhere,'' <ORGANIZATION> Pillsbury </ORGANIZATION> said. `` The story had three strikes against it: The subject was undeniably baseball; it was an ensemble piece; it was period and hence expensive. We were told that baseball pictures had never been successful, especially overseas.'' The producers finally made a deal with <ORGANIZATION> Orion </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pictures </ORGANIZATION>, which also sponsored `` Bull Durham'' and `` The Scout.'' <ORGANIZATION> Pillsbury </ORGANIZATION> thinks `` Eight Men Out'' will appeal to women. `` Baseball is simply the arena that the story takes place in,'' she said. `` It's more of a human story which is all the more exciting because it is true.'' `` The Scout'' also had a tortuous route to the screen. The film actually went into production in 1982 with <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Falk </PERSON> as star, then was suspended. Earlier this year <ORGANIZATION> Orion </ORGANIZATION> sent it to <PERSON> Kathy </PERSON> <PERSON> Lymberopoulos </PERSON>, producer and associate of <PERSON> Rodney </PERSON> <PERSON> Dangerfield </PERSON>. The story, she said, centers mainly on a baseball scout's life and less on the game itself. As to any feminine prejudice against baseball, she added, `` I love baseball, and so do a lot of women. You look around a ballpark today and you'll see about half-and-half, men and women.'' What do the players themselves think of baseball movies? Here's <PERSON> Lou </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>, 53, star of the <ORGANIZATION> Los </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Angeles </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dodgers </ORGANIZATION> in the 1960s and now doing community service, lecturing against alcohol and drug abuse: `` I've liked some of them, like the <PERSON> Lou </PERSON> <PERSON> Gehrig </PERSON> story, <PERSON> Roy </PERSON> <PERSON> Campanella </PERSON> -LRB- TV movie -RRB- and <PERSON> Jackie </PERSON> <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON>, ` Bingo Long' and ` The Natural. But you're not going to get an accurate picture of baseball out of movies. There's got to be a lot of fantasizing. They give you what the public wants, not what is real. `` I especially liked ` Bingo Long' because it was about the <ORGANIZATION> Negro </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> League </ORGANIZATION>, and I could identify with it. It captured the particular social life and lifestyle that we all went through,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881006-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-06-88 0036EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-APArts:BaseballMovies-List     10-06 0216</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AP Arts: Baseball Movies-List,0240</SECOND>
<HEAD>Hollywood Baseball Movies</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-AP Arts: Baseball Movies</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here is a list of the more notable films about baseball over the years: `` <PERSON> Casey </PERSON> at the Bat'' 1899. `` Casey at the Bat,'' -LRB- <PERSON> Wallace </PERSON> <PERSON> Beery </PERSON> -RRB-, 1927. `` College'' -LRB- <PERSON> Buster </PERSON> <PERSON> Keaton </PERSON> -RRB-, 1927. `` Babe Comes Home'' -LRB- Babe <PERSON> Ruth </PERSON> -RRB-, 1927. `` Speedy'' -LRB- <PERSON> Harold </PERSON> <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> -RRB-, 1928. `` Elmer the Great'' -LRB- <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> -RRB-, 1933. `` Alibi Ike'' -LRB- <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> -RRB-, 1935. `` The Pride of the <ORGANIZATION> Yankees </ORGANIZATION>'' -LRB- <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Cooper </PERSON> -RRB-, 1942. `` The Babe Ruth Story'' -LRB- <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Bendix </PERSON> -RRB-, 1948. `` The Stratton Story'' -LRB- <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Stewart </PERSON> -RRB-, 1949. `` Take Me out to the Ballgame'' -LRB- <PERSON> Gene </PERSON> <PERSON> Kelly </PERSON>, <PERSON> Esther </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> -RRB-, 1949. `` It Happens Every Spring'' -LRB- <PERSON> Ray </PERSON> <PERSON> Milland </PERSON>, <PERSON> Jean </PERSON> <PERSON> Peters </PERSON> -RRB-, 1949. `` Kill the Umpire'' -LRB- <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Bendix </PERSON> -RRB-, 1950. `` The <PERSON> Jackie </PERSON> <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> Story'' -LRB- <PERSON> Jackie </PERSON> <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> -RRB-, 1950. `` Angels in Outfield'' -LRB- <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON> -RRB-, 1951. `` Rhubarb'' -LRB- <PERSON> Ray </PERSON> <PERSON> Milland </PERSON> -RRB-, 1951. `` The Winning Team'' -LRB- <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> -RRB-, 1952. `` The Pride of <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Louis </LOCATION>'' -LRB- <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Dailey </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> -RRB-, 1952. `` The Big Leaguer'' -LRB- <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> -RRB-, 1953. `` Fear Strikes Out'' -LRB- <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON> <PERSON> Perkins </PERSON> -RRB-, 1957. `` Damn Yankees'' -LRB- Tab Hunter -RRB-, 1958. `` Safe at Home'' -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> Mickey </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mantle </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> Maris </PERSON> -RRB-, 1961. `` Bang the Drum Slowly'' -LRB- <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Moriarity </PERSON>, <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Niro </PERSON> -RRB-, 1973. `` The Bad News Bears'' -LRB- <PERSON> Tatum </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Neal </PERSON>, <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> Matthau </PERSON> -RRB-, 1976. `` The Bingo Long Traveling All-Stars and <ORGANIZATION> Motor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Kings </ORGANIZATION>'' -LRB- <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Earl </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>, <PERSON> Billy </PERSON> <PERSON> Dee </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> -RRB-, 1976. `` The Natural'' -LRB- <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Redford </PERSON> -RRB-, 1984.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881006-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-06-88 0040EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-APArts:Sweeney     10-06 0836</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AP Arts: Sweeney,0859</SECOND>
<HEAD>Acting Is Like Baseball: Just Do It</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By HILLEL ITALIE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 D.B. <PERSON> Sweeney </PERSON> approaches acting the way Shoeless <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> played baseball: Just do it. `` The best theory I ever heard about acting was from -LRB- <PERSON> James </PERSON> -RRB- <PERSON> Cagney </PERSON>,'' said <PERSON> Sweeney </PERSON>, 26, who plays <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> in <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Sayles </PERSON>' `` Eight Men Out,'' the story of the 1919 <ORGANIZATION> Chicago </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sox </ORGANIZATION> scandal `` You walk in. Plant your feet. Stare the other fellow in the eyes and tell the truth. All the acting theories I've heard, all the books I've read ... you ca n't get it any simpler or purer than that.'' `` Eight Men Out'' tells the story of the biggest scandal in baseball. The 1919 White Sox were widely regarded as the best team of their time. With such pitchers as <PERSON> Ed </PERSON> <PERSON> Cicotte </PERSON> and <PERSON> Lefty </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>, and a lineup featuring future Hall of Famers <PERSON> Eddie </PERSON> <PERSON> Collins </PERSON> and <PERSON> Ray </PERSON> <PERSON> Schalk </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> won the American League pennant and were heavy favorites against the <ORGANIZATION> Cincinnati </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reds </ORGANIZATION> in the World Series. No one, however, could play ball like <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, a lifetime .356 hitter and outstanding left fielder. Once a mill worker in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>, he had little education and could not read or write, but was peerless on the field. `` He was very passive,'' <PERSON> Sweeney </PERSON> noted. `` He took the path of least resistance in everything he could. Everything he did was from a defensive mode, except on the field, where he attacks.'' <PERSON> Sweeney </PERSON> wanted to contrast <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s athletic grace with his awkwardness in private life. `` On the field, I wanted him to be like -LRB- ballet superstar <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> -RRB- <PERSON> Baryshnikov </PERSON>. I wanted every move he made to be beautiful,'' <PERSON> Sweeney </PERSON> said. `` Off the field, I wanted him to be tentative.'' Players earned little money in <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s era and were often tempted by gamblers to throw games. Eight members of the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sox </ORGANIZATION>, including <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, agreed to, or were aware of, an effort to deliberately throw the series against <LOCATION> Cincinnati </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> Reds </ORGANIZATION> won the series and the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sox </ORGANIZATION>' poor play aroused widespread suspicion. The following year, Commissioner <PERSON> Kenesaw </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Landis </PERSON> permanently banned <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> and his seven teammates from baseball. No one could ever prove that <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, who batted .375 in the World Series, ever tried to throw a game. More likely, he was punished for being aware of the fix and not trying to stop it. `` They do n't kick you out of the Pentagon for knowing about fraud,'' <PERSON> Sweeney </PERSON> said, adding that <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, who died in 1951, should have his name cleared and be inducted into the Baseball Hall of Fame. <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Bernard </PERSON> <PERSON> Sweeney </PERSON> was born and raised in <LOCATION> Shoreham </LOCATION>, N.Y. He attended <ORGANIZATION> Tulane </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> and hoped to play major league baseball until tearing ligaments in his right knee. The injury convinced <PERSON> Sweeney </PERSON> to pursue a career in acting, and he transferred to the performing arts division of <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. After graduating in 1984, he appeared in the Broadway revival of `` The Caine Mutiny.'' He made his film debut in <PERSON> Sidney </PERSON> <PERSON> Lumet </PERSON>'s `` Power,'' and has since appeared in <PERSON> Francis </PERSON> <PERSON> Ford </PERSON> <PERSON> Coppola </PERSON>'s `` Gardens of Stone'' and `` No Man's Land.'' Although <PERSON> Sweeney </PERSON> has not appeared on stage in two years, he still prefers the working atmosphere of the theater. `` On ` No Man's Land,' there were about four producers, one director to start the film and one to end it. We had five different writers. And by the way, we also have these actors,'' he said. `` In a play, even if it's a <PERSON> Neil </PERSON> <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> play on <LOCATION> Broadway </LOCATION>, it's going to have to be about the actors or nobody's going to come I enjoy acting on stage better because there are less people with walkie-talkie's in your face.'' <PERSON> Sweeney </PERSON> felt an immediate rapport with <PERSON> Sayles </PERSON> -LRB- `` Brother From Another Planet,'' `` Matewan'' -RRB-, and enjoyed working with him on the set. `` We met in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> and talked for about an hour. We talked about <PERSON> Roberto </PERSON> <PERSON> Clemente </PERSON> -LRB- the late <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION> Pirates star -RRB-. <PERSON> John </PERSON> likes the <ORGANIZATION> Pirates </ORGANIZATION>. He's a real blue-collar man. Those are the right reasons to like a baseball team,'' he said. `` I had access to <PERSON> John </PERSON> all the time. We had a great relationship. We would just check in with each other to gauge each other's continued enthusiasm.'' To prepare for the film, <PERSON> Sweeney </PERSON> traveled to <LOCATION> Kenosha </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wis. </LOCATION>, and worked out with the local minor league team. `` <LOCATION> Kenosha </LOCATION> is a good town for <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>. A real blue-collar town. Everybody there works for one of those corporations. I think there's a similar ethic about work that <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> might have grown up with. `` That's the world where <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> came from.'' Playing <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> boiled down to forgetting about everything except baseball. `` I tried to stand there and clear my mind,'' <PERSON> Sweeney </PERSON> said. `` He would just stand and take his three swings and more often than not, hit it, and hit it well. In my daily life, I have to deal with bank statements, acting, associates and friends and things. It's often like a juggling act.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881006-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-06-88 0048EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-APArts:BaseballFan     10-06 0514</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AP Arts: Baseball Fan,0523</SECOND>
<HEAD>Take Me Out To The Tenplex: A Baseball Fan Goes To The Movies</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</NOTE>
<HEAD>With PM-AP Arts: Baseball Movies</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LARRY McSHANE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 It's so, <PERSON> Joe </PERSON>. The baseball movie, long relegated to <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION>'s minor leagues, is the winner of 1988's cinematic comeback of the year award. From summer smash `` Bull Durham'' to critical rave `` Eight Men Out,'' baseball movies are back. And so what if `` Stealing Home,'' the Mark Harmon-Jodie Foster entry in the baseball movie race, was almost universally panned? Two out of three means <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION> is batting .667 this year. The bounce back of baseball has prompted musings on the subject in <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION>, The <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Newsweek </ORGANIZATION>. Actor <PERSON> Kevin </PERSON> <PERSON> Costner </PERSON> delivered the Most Valuable Performance in `` Durham'' as veteran minor league catcher <PERSON> Crash </PERSON> <PERSON> Davis </PERSON>, but an assortment of stars suited up this year: <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Harmon </PERSON>, <PERSON> Charlie </PERSON> <PERSON> Sheen </PERSON> and D.B. <PERSON> Sweeney </PERSON>, to name a few. <PERSON> Costner </PERSON> and <PERSON> Sheen </PERSON> will do it again for movies coming out next year. The switch-hitting <PERSON> Costner </PERSON> will appear in `` Shoeless <PERSON> Joe </PERSON>,'' playing a farmer under the sway of `` Black Sox'' star <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s ghost, while <PERSON> Sheen </PERSON> will be joined by `` <LOCATION> L.A. </LOCATION> Law'' star <PERSON> Corbin </PERSON> <PERSON> Bernsen </PERSON> in `` Major League. But why this return of the ballplayer as movie star after years without any horsehide hits? _ The ` R' rating. <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Cooper </PERSON> as <PERSON> Lou </PERSON> <PERSON> Gehrig </PERSON>, who was married in `` Pride of the <ORGANIZATION> Yankees </ORGANIZATION>,'' never enjoyed the off-field activities of <ORGANIZATION> Durham </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bulls </ORGANIZATION> rookie righthander Nuke LaLoosh. And if <PERSON> Susan </PERSON> <PERSON> Sarandon </PERSON> had played Mrs. <PERSON> Gehrig </PERSON>, <PERSON> Lou </PERSON> might have been the luckiest man on the face of the <LOCATION> Earth </LOCATION>. _ The popularity of baseball. Virtually everybody has played or watched the American Pastime. Major league attendance increases every year _ in fact, you can expect that announcement from outgoing commissioner <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Ueberroth </PERSON> within weeks of the season's finish this year _ The `` I-Can-Do-That'' Syndrome. This factor is best described by <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lampoon </ORGANIZATION> editor <PERSON> Matty </PERSON> <PERSON> Simmons </PERSON>: `` Any 5-foot-3, 270-pound slob can watch <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bell </PERSON> blast a <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> Clemens </PERSON> 95-mph fastball into northern <LOCATION> Quebec </LOCATION> and say to himself, ` I can do that.' Why? Because baseball players look like human beings. They look like they belong behind a 7-Eleven counter.'' Think about it. Ca n't you picture <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mets </ORGANIZATION> phenom <PERSON> Gregg </PERSON> <PERSON> Jefferies </PERSON> serving up a cold Slurpee and a Big Gulp? Now try to imagine <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Giants </ORGANIZATION> rookie <PERSON> Jumbo </PERSON> <PERSON> Elliot </PERSON>, 6-foot-6, 305 pounds, doing the same thing. As <PERSON> Simmons </PERSON> points out, <PERSON> Elliot </PERSON> could BE a 7-Eleven counter. There's one more big reason: the movies are better. In the past, most baseball movies focused on one player, one star. There was <PERSON> Jimmy </PERSON> <PERSON> Stewart </PERSON> as one-legged pitcher <PERSON> Monty </PERSON> <PERSON> Stratton </PERSON>. And <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON> `` Psycho'' <PERSON> Perkins </PERSON> as outfielder <PERSON> Jimmy </PERSON> <PERSON> Piersall </PERSON>. Or <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> playing hurler <PERSON> Grover </PERSON> <PERSON> Cleveland </PERSON> <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON> before his career really took off. `` Bull Durham'' was the product of writer-director <PERSON> Ron </PERSON> <PERSON> Shelton </PERSON>, who spent five years kicking around the minor leagues in the <ORGANIZATION> Baltimore </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Orioles </ORGANIZATION> organization. `` Eight Men Out'' was done by <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Sayles </PERSON>, a die-hard baseball fan.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881006-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-06-88 0222EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lottery     10-06 0049</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lottery,0051</SECOND>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the winning weekly state lottery numbers picked Wednesday:
</TEXT>
<HEAD>MASSACHUSETTS</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Wednesday Megabucks: 05; 14; 17; 24; 26; 30.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>NEW YORK</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Wednesday Lotto 54 Game: 01; 11; 14; 22; 51; 52. Supplementary 02.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>RHODE ISLAND</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Grand Lot Game: 5-0-9; 2-8-0-3; 3-5-4-6-9; 1-4-1-8-1-1.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881006-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-06-88 0056EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-ChineseShip     10-06 0230</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Chinese Ship,0235</SECOND>
<HEAD>Detained Ship Departs</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MANILA, Philippines (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Military authorities allowed a Chinese research ship to sail away today after they were convinced the vessel had simply sought shelter from a typhoon and was not smuggling guns to local communist rebels, officials said. The 3,324-ton Science Research Vessel No. 1 had steamed into northern <LOCATION> Luzon </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION>'s Casiguran Sound late Monday and <LOCATION> Philippine </LOCATION> Constabulary troops seized it early the next day after a boarding party found guns and ammunition aboard. The <ORGANIZATION> Chinese </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> said the ship was seeking shelter from Typhoon <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON>, which skirted northern <LOCATION> Luzon </LOCATION> Wednesday, and the arms aboard were for protection of the ship's 56 scientists and 45 crew from pirates. The arms included three machine guns, eight assault rifles, two semi-automatic rifles, two hand guns and 4,850 rounds of ammunition. Maj. <PERSON> Julius </PERSON> <PERSON> Yarcia </PERSON>, a constabulary intelligence officer inspected the vessel for a second time Wednesday, and told reporters today he found no signs the ship or the people aboard had violated any Philippine law. The ship's scientists were reportedly aboard to conduct underwater research. Military officials are wary of ships with arms because of frequent reports of smuggling to communist rebels waging a 19-year insurgency. Casiguran is in an area known for years as a rebel stronghold. <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> maintains diplomatic relations with the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION> and has consistently denied giving the rebels any material aid.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881006-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-06-88 0057EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Imelda'sShoes     10-06 0553</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Imelda's Shoes,0570</SECOND>
<HEAD>Imelda's Shoe-Shine Man Never Short Of Work</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By TERESA ALBOR</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MANILA, Philippines (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Bonifacio </PERSON> <PERSON> Santos </PERSON>, whose mother never owned more than one pair of shoes at a time, may be one of the country's foremost experts on footwear. His job: he shines <PERSON> Imelda </PERSON> <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON>' shoes. <PERSON> Santos </PERSON> says it's a full-time job to polish and buff the 2,400 pairs of shoes that <PERSON> Imelda </PERSON> left behind when she and her husband, <PERSON> Ferdinand </PERSON> <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON>, fled to <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION> after the February 1986 uprising that toppled his administration. For maintaining the thousands of dollars worth of shoes, about half of which are on display at the Malacanang Palace museum, <PERSON> Santos </PERSON> earns 2,300 pesos, or $ 115, per month. `` I know my salary is not enough to buy even one pair of imported shoes like these,'' said <PERSON> Santos </PERSON>, 29. Soon after the <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> administration collapsed, President <PERSON> Corazon </PERSON> <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON>'s government announced that the former first lady had left behind 3,000 pairs of shoes, most of them imported. <PERSON> Eva </PERSON> <PERSON> Toledo </PERSON>, curator of the museum, said later inventories reduced the figure to `` only'' 2,400 pairs, some of which were found in Marcos residences throughout the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION>. `` I was shocked when I first saw them,'' said <PERSON> Santos </PERSON>, one of 16 children. `` When my mother's shoes wore a hole in the bottom, she'd get a new pair That's the way it is with most of us Filipinos.'' <PERSON> Santos </PERSON> said he spends every Friday brushing the dust from the shoes. The rest of the week is devoted to polishing and buffing. By the time he finishes polishing every pair, it's time to start all over again. `` I clean the shoes with shoe polish,'' he said. `` I have to use so many colors to match the shoes. We've had to wrap some of them in plastic now, just to protect them.'' The collection includes elegant high heels, slippers with giant pompons and one pair with battery-operated, five-inch heels that glow. Most are imported. <PERSON> Imelda </PERSON>'s size, 8 -LCB-, is hard to find in a country where the average woman wears a size 6 shoe. <PERSON> Santos </PERSON> says proudly that his own brown shoes are strictly `` locally made.'' <PERSON> Toledo </PERSON> said the government can not get rid of the shoes until a court decides who owns them. The shoes, along with millions of dollars worth of property, businesses and other possessions, were seized by the government when <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> fled the country. `` We will have to continue taking care of them,'' she said. <PERSON> Toledo </PERSON> said the shoes must be continually polished to prevent deterioration because of high humidity and poor storage facilities. About half the collection is stored in the basement of <LOCATION> Malacanang </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Palace </LOCATION>, beneath <PERSON> Imelda </PERSON>'s former bedroom. The palace is on the banks of the <LOCATION> Pasig </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION>, and water is seeping up from the basement floor. <PERSON> Toledo </PERSON> said that although the <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> family spent a fortune acquiring personal possessions, they appear to have made little effort to provide for care and maintenance. `` Water oozes up through here and there's nothing we can do about it,'' she said, tapping her feet on the tiled basement floor. <PERSON> Santos </PERSON> said that despite his shock at the <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON>' excesses, he's proud of his job, which he considers a `` service to the Filipino people. `` And besides, without a job, I'd go hungry,'' he added.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881006-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-06-88 0058EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-PlasticBullets     10-06 0714</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Plastic Bullets,0735</SECOND>
<HEAD>New Ammunition Draws Outcry As Casualties Mount</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By EILEEN ALT POWELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>GAZA CITY, Occupied Gaza Strip (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Israeli army's use of plastic bullets to break up Palestinian demonstrations is filling hospital wards with casualties and prompting calls for tighter controls. Victims of the new ammunition, including two teen-agers treated for plastic bullet wounds at <LOCATION> Ahli </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arab </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, complain that stones thrown by protesters do not warrant the penalty. `` It's unreasonable punishment,'' said <PERSON> Mazul </PERSON> <PERSON> Abu </PERSON> <PERSON> Lail </PERSON>, 19, a tailor who was shot in the ankle. In a nearby bed, 16-year-old <PERSON> Rifaat </PERSON> <PERSON> Massoud </PERSON>, a construction worker, nodded in agreement. `` It is n't right and it is n't fair for the soldiers to shoot innocent people,'' <PERSON> Massoud </PERSON> said, shifting uncomfortably with a bullet wound in his left side. The plastic bullet was introduced in August to supplement rubber bullets, water cannons, tear gas and clubs in dealing with the uprising in the Israeli-occupied <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strip </LOCATION>. Defense Minister <PERSON> Yitzhak </PERSON> <PERSON> Rabin </PERSON> said the other weapons `` proved to be insufficient to cope with stone throwing'' and that the army needed something less lethal than lead bullets. The aim, <PERSON> Rabin </PERSON> said, is to reduce anti-Israeli violence in the territories with a minimum of fatalities. Since the uprising began Dec. 8, at least 280 Palestinians have been killed and hundreds injured. Six Israelis have died. But <PERSON> Rabin </PERSON> has acknowledged that the introduction of the plastic bullets may lead to more injuries. In the past three weeks, more than 325 Palestinians have been wounded in clashes with <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> troops, many by plastic bullets, hospital officials and <PERSON> Arab </PERSON> sources say. The army says plastic bullets can penetrate the body, but they are not supposed to be lethal if fired from at least 70 yards. However, at least four deaths from plastic bullets have been reported at <LOCATION> Shifa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. Last week, Dr. <PERSON> Rustum </PERSON> <PERSON> Namari </PERSON>, director of the <LOCATION> Mukassad </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION>, showed reporters fragments of a plastic bullet removed from the brain of a critically injured <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> youth. <PERSON> Namari </PERSON> said the bullet appeared to have been fired at close range. `` If a plastic bullet enters the throat, chest or abdomen, it has the potential to cause death,'' said a surgeon at <ORGANIZATION> Shifa </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION> who spoke on condition of anonymnity. `` Remember, too, that bullets respect no age,'' he added. Victims, he said, have ranged in age from 7 to 90. The bullets, developed after <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> officials studied use of plastic ammunition in <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>, are produced in <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>. Similar plastic rounds have been used in <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION> for riot control since 1970, and at least 13 deaths have been attributed to them there. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION> have objected to the use of plastic ammunition against <LOCATION> Palestinian </LOCATION> demonstrators, and opposition has been mounting in <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>. A senior official of the U.N. Relief and <ORGANIZATION> Works </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION>, which provides humanitarian services to Palestinian refugees, filed a complaint with Israeli military officials after casualties in <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> jumped from 19 in July to more than 130 in September. Last week, the <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Civil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rights </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> filed a petition with Israeli Attorney General <PERSON> Yosef </PERSON> <PERSON> Harish </PERSON>, urging him to issue legal guidelines on the use of the new bullets. The group contended that `` opening fire for purposes of deterrence is an illegal act'' and called on <PERSON> Harish </PERSON> to block use of the bullet for riot control. Until recently, <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> soldiers were instructed to fire lead or plastic bullets only if their lives were in imminent danger. In recent weeks, however, firing rules have been changed so troops may use the plastic rounds to break up demonstrations. The army chief of staff, Lt. Gen. <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Shomron </PERSON>, told a parliament committee Tuesday that the army needed to stop riots before they get out of hand. `` Arabs who deliberately choose to go out and demonstrate are getting injured,'' <PERSON> Shomron </PERSON> was quoted as saying in <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION> newspapers. `` Eventually they will realize that it is not in their interest to get involved in riots.'' But he insisted strict orders had been issued against misusing the new weapon. In addition to a firing range of 70 yards, the bullets are to be aimed only at legs, <PERSON> Shomron </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881006-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-06-88 0100EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-China-Relations     10-06 0673</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-China-Relations,0690</SECOND>
<HEAD>China Talking Summits And Trade With Old Rivals</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By JIM ABRAMS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> has set a course toward reconciliation with old adversaries, talking summitry with the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> and making economic deals with <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>. In what appear to be breakthroughs after years of talks, <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> is sending Foreign Minister <PERSON> Qian </PERSON> <PERSON> Qichen </PERSON> to <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> and preparing for a visit by Prime Minister <PERSON> Rajiv </PERSON> <PERSON> Gandhi </PERSON> of <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>. Both events could occur before year's end. <PERSON> Qian </PERSON>, the first Chinese foreign minister to make a working visit to the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> since <PERSON> Chou </PERSON> <PERSON> En-lai </PERSON> in 1956, is expected to lay the groundwork for the first Chinese-Soviet summit since <PERSON> Nikita </PERSON> <PERSON> Khrushchev </PERSON> visited <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> in 1959. A summit would effectively normalize relations, which have been difficult since <PERSON> Nikita </PERSON> <PERSON> Khrushchev </PERSON> and <PERSON> Mao </PERSON> <PERSON> Tse-tung </PERSON> split in 1960 over ideological differences and leadership of the Communist world. Relations reached bottom with border fighting in 1969. <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s diplomatic impasse with <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> is just as old. Heads of government met last when <PERSON> Chou </PERSON>, as premier, visited <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Delhi </LOCATION> in 1960, and the last Indian prime minister who traveled to <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> was <PERSON> Jawaharlal </PERSON> <PERSON> Nehru </PERSON> in 1954. The two most populous nations in the world have been at odds because of <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>'s pro-Soviet stance, close <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> ties with <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> and a border feud that led to fighting in 1962. <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> also is forging new ties with another former enemy in war, <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>. Direct and indirect trade could double to the equivalent of $ 3 billion this year and <LOCATION> Shandong </LOCATION> province, facing <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> across the <LOCATION> Yellow </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sea </LOCATION>, recently agreed to an exchange of trade offices with <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>. South Korean auto and electronics makers plan to invest in Chinese plants, and tourists from <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> are being welcomed to <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>. Formal diplomatic ties are unlikely soon, however, because <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> remains close to <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>, its economically moribund ally in the Korean War of 1950-53. Qian, the foreign minister, said in a recent interview that economic ties with <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> were `` only natural'' as <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> opened up its coastal areas. The mood of detente also extends to <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, a frequent object of Chinese criticism despite its role as a major trading partner and chief source of financial aid. Japanese officials in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> note a marked reduction over the past year in Chinese warnings about a resurgence in Japanese militarism or <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s tendency to forget crimes it committed in World War II. Both nations called the visit by Prime Minister <PERSON> Noboru </PERSON> <PERSON> Takeshita </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> in August the beginning of a `` new era'' in relations. Senior leader <PERSON> Deng </PERSON> <PERSON> Xiaoping </PERSON> has said since gaining power a decade ago that <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> needs peace on its borders to achieve economic development. <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> began border talks with <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> in 1981 and negotiations with <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> in 1982. Little progress has been made in either forum. The possibility of <PERSON> Gandhi </PERSON> and <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> standing on the Great Wall owes more to the more relaxed state of the world. U.S.-Soviet disarmament agreements, moves to settle wars in <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION>, and prospects for peace in <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION> and other areas appear to have given <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> more room to maneuver. `` Dialogue is taking the place of confrontation and the tendency to seek peaceful settlement of international disputes is growing,'' <PERSON> Qian </PERSON> said in a recent address to the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION>. A Western diplomat said: `` The Chinese may see the world as less dangerous to their interests. If you do n't have to use a lot of energy to protect yourself, it gives you more flexibility.'' Younger leaders who have emerged in the past year are edging away from a foreign policy based mainly on the restating of formulas and principles. One of them, Premier <PERSON> Li </PERSON> <PERSON> Peng </PERSON>, noted recently that <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> share a 4,300-mile border and declared: `` Strain on relations between the two countries is not in the interest of <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> because we need to modernize our country in a peaceful environment.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881006-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-06-88 0103EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-AmericanForecaster     10-06 0584</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-American Forecaster,0601</SECOND>
<HEAD>Romance, Big Shoes For Men, Turkey Hunting Hot In '89</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By JOE WHEELAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>DENVER (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Romance, clodhopper shoes for men and lullaby tapes for yuppie babies will be hot in 1989, but it will be a ho-hum year for fashions and a bad year for fat kids, according to The American Forecaster 1989. Other'89 trends identified by the Forecaster: gutterless bowling alleys, fighting dogs on steroids and <LOCATION> turkey </LOCATION> hunting. New Age religion channeling will become passe in 1989, along with teddy bears and soft cookies, said <PERSON> Kim </PERSON> <PERSON> Long </PERSON>, author of the sixth annual 192-page Forecaster, which went on sale this week. Long said 1989 could be a boring year trend-wise. The problem, he said, is that baby boomers _ the one-third of the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> population born between the years 1946 and 1964 _ are concentrating on their careers and families, and college students have grown serious. The rise of romance and a growing de-emphasis on sex in advertising, movies and television are directly linked to the aging baby boomers, <PERSON> Long </PERSON> said. `` More of them are having their first kids, and that tends to slow you down and keep you close to home,'' he said. Long was surprised by the growing popularity of lullaby tapes for the babies of baby-boomer moms. `` Baby boomer mothers who do n't have time or do n't know how to sing lullabies are buying tapes from the professionals,'' he said Clothing styles are becoming conservative and utilitarian, <PERSON> Long </PERSON> said. `` There is nothing in men's or women's fashions that is a jump ahead _ pretty boring,'' he said. In men's footwear, this means the return of big shoes _ expensive, leather wingtips and brogues. `` The big shoe thing has been building slowly and is part of the gradual return to traditional clothing,'' <PERSON> Long </PERSON> said. Long, a <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION> free-lance writer, has been writing The American Forecaster since 1983. His predictions have gained such respectability that the Old Farmer's Almanac gave Long space in the 1988 and 1989 editions. Long said the New Age practice of channeling, popularized by actress <PERSON> Shirley </PERSON> <PERSON> MacLain </PERSON>, will fade in 1989 because of skepticism and ridicule. But astrology will remain hot in 1989, <ORGANIZATION> Long </ORGANIZATION> said, mainly because of President and <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s reliance on astrological interpretations and the subsequent efforts by astrologers to legitimize the practice as a science. Out-of-shape youngsters will be put in fitness programs as the preoccupation with health trickles down from adults to their offspring, Long predicted. Some curiosities among the trends that will take hold in 1989: steroid use to make fighting dogs meaner and stronger, gutterless bowling alleys and a surge in <LOCATION> turkey </LOCATION> hunting, which <PERSON> Long </PERSON> said was becoming popular because the birds are tough to shoot. Gutterless bowling alleys are for novices and the hopelessly uncoordinated, <PERSON> Long </PERSON> said. Inflatable tubes are placed in the gutters between the lanes. Long said in an interview last week that of his 1988 forecasts, he is proudest of his prediction that girdle sales would increase and of his identification of biodegradable plastics as an important development. On the down side, he was off the mark in predicting the end of the TV shows `` <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION>'' and `` Dynasty'' and in saying that Pee Wee <PERSON> Herman </PERSON> would go prime time. Long wrote in the'89 Forecaster that <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> will be the next president, but last week he hedged. `` According to every single indicator from the common to the bizarre, it's too close to call.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881006-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-06-88 0104EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Italy-Fashion     10-06 0477</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Italy-Fashion,0492</SECOND>
<HEAD>Sexy Milan Gets Cute, Dainty And Debutante</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>BY DANIELA PETROFF</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Fashion Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MILAN, Italy (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 In just six months, Italian fashion has experienced a radical mood swing from aggressive and sexy to subdued and demure. Leaving the miniskirted, spike-heeled woman behind, the Italian designers presenting their spring-summer 1989 collections in <LOCATION> Milan </LOCATION> this week are courting a younger, at least outwardly more innocent woman who loves pants, long skirts and flat shoes. Her favorite colors are tender shades of cream and pink or the classic combination of white with navy blue or black. Her taste in fabrics ranges from diaphanous georgette and chiffon to batiste and linen. Crisp white blouses, always a sign of good clean living, pop up throughout the collections. Some are man-tailored, others daintily lace-collared, still others a feminine version of the bowling shirt. <PERSON> Gianfranco </PERSON> <PERSON> Ferre </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>'s `` numero uno'' shirtmaker, opts for a wide collared, man-tailored silk shirt embellished by a giant nautical motif. The entire Ferre collection, presented in <LOCATION> Milan </LOCATION> Tuesday, was an ode to the sea, with navy blue and white stripes the dominant pattern and anchors, compasses and life preservers printed everywhere. At the height of the miniskirt mania last year, <PERSON> Ferre </PERSON>, known for his staid fashion, shocked the fashion crowd with the shortest, tightest look on the <LOCATION> Milan </LOCATION> runway. In keeping with the current search for lost innocence, his spring-summer collection brings hemlines right down to the ankle and softens the silhouette with wide tops and loose-fitting pants. Extra feminine touches were offered by the high sailor suit waistline on skirts and pants, and enticing see-through, star-sequined T-shirts. Evening at <PERSON> Ferre </PERSON> was all stars and stripes in long shimmery evening gowns, the tightest seen thus far on this week's Italian ready-to-wear runway. On Wednesday, the fourth day of the five day showings, <PERSON> Basile </PERSON> and <PERSON> Ferragamo </PERSON> continued the trend toward calmer, more feminine styles. <PERSON> Luciano </PERSON> <PERSON> Soprani </PERSON>, for <PERSON> Basile </PERSON>, picked dainty floral prints for his super-soft long skirts worn under a neat tight waisted blazer or a belted Safari jacket. Evening wear turned the fashion page back to the heyday of the debutante ball. Dressed in their empire-waisted full-skirted strapless evening gowns, they looked as innocent as a busload of college freshmenn at their first mixer. Even when the rest of <LOCATION> Milan </LOCATION> was vying for the shortest look, <PERSON> Ferragamo </PERSON> persevered in its classic tailored style, with a discreet knee-skimming hemline. It took the sedate Florentine tailors little effort to lengthen this look to mid-calf in slim unfussy skirts worn under a simple short-sleeved linen blazer. The classic look continued in the Chanel-inspired little black day suits with gold buttons worn with a Ferragamo logo T-shirt. <PERSON> Ferragamo </PERSON>, famous for its shoes, capitalized on its own classics by dotting the collection with little golden shoes as lapel pins and charms on a bracelet.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881006-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-06-88 0107EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     10-06 0926</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0973</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names In The News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SANTA MONICA, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Comedian <PERSON> Whoopi </PERSON> <PERSON> Goldberg </PERSON> wants to end her two-year marriage to Dutch cinematographer <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Claessen </PERSON>, citing irreconcilable differences. Details of the divorce petition Miss <PERSON> Goldberg </PERSON> filed Tuesday were n't disclosed by her spokeswoman, <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Solters </PERSON>. <PERSON> Claessen </PERSON>, 29, and <PERSON> Miss </PERSON> <PERSON> Goldberg </PERSON>, 38, met during the filming of a documentary on the homeless. The couple have no children. <PERSON> Solters </PERSON> said Wednesday that they `` have been separated for some time'' and that Miss <PERSON> Goldberg </PERSON> has been living with cameraman <PERSON> Eddie </PERSON> <PERSON> Gold </PERSON>. Miss <PERSON> Goldberg </PERSON>, who won an Oscar nomination for her performance in <PERSON> Steven </PERSON> <PERSON> Spielberg </PERSON>'s `` The Color Purple,'' stars in <ORGANIZATION> Warner </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bros. </ORGANIZATION>'s forthcoming movie `` Clara's Heart. She will soon be seen on the TV series `` Star Trek: The Next Generation.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The photographer whose car and camera were damaged by <PERSON> Cher </PERSON>'s boyfriend, 24-year-old <PERSON> Rob </PERSON> <PERSON> Camilletti </PERSON>, says <PERSON> Camilletti </PERSON> is getting off the hook. `` I think he should have been charged with assault with a deadly weapon. No, I'm not pleased with these charges,'' <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Brandt </PERSON>, a photographer for the entertainment tabloid Star, said Wednesday. <PERSON> Camilletti </PERSON> was charged Wednesday with reckless driving and malicious mischief. The misdemeanor offenses are less serious than the felony charge of assault with a deadly weapon for which <PERSON> Camilletti </PERSON> was booked after the June 27 confrontation. Camilletti was released on $ 2,000 bail. <PERSON> Camilletti </PERSON> had said he lost control of <PERSON> Cher </PERSON>'s black Ferrari while swerving to avoid photographers outside the home he shares with the Oscar-winning actress. He said he hit <PERSON> Brandt </PERSON>'s car and then smashed his camera and telephone. <PERSON> Brandt </PERSON> accused <PERSON> Camilletti </PERSON> of trying to kill him, and sued the couple for unspecified damages. Reckless driving carries up to 90 days in jail and a $ 1,000 fine; the two counts of malicious mischief could bring up to 18 months in jail and a $ 6,000 fine.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WINTER SPRINGS, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Sheelah </PERSON> <PERSON> Ryan </PERSON>, winner of <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>'s record $ 55.1 million Lotto jackpot last month, passed up the chance to claim another prize her extraordinary luck brought her: a blender she won at a raffle Her name was drawn for a door prize at an open house held for a new office of <ORGANIZATION> Prudential </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bowles </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Realty </ORGANIZATION>, where she used to work, said owner <PERSON> Wil </PERSON> <PERSON> Bowles </PERSON>. By the time her name was drawn Friday, Ms. <PERSON> Ryan </PERSON> had left and another name was selected for the prize. `` I do n't think missing it will worry her,'' said <PERSON> Bowles </PERSON>. Her former boss also disclosed that Ms. <PERSON> Ryan </PERSON> has bought a $ 260,000 house through the real estate firm she quit after winning the nation's largest lottery prize. <PERSON> Bowles </PERSON> said Ms. <PERSON> Ryan </PERSON> paid cash for the house, the location of which he would not disclose.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>BALTIMORE (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Gov. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Schaefer </PERSON> disputes <ORGANIZATION> Playboy </ORGANIZATION> magazine's depiction of him as an oddball, saying the publication should stick to pictures of nude women. `` I'm not weird,'' <PERSON> Schaefer </PERSON> declared Tuesday in response to an article in the November issue. <PERSON> Schaefer </PERSON>, whom the magazine identifies as the `` chuckly bachelor gov of the <ORGANIZATION> Orioles </ORGANIZATION>' home state,'' was lumped in the same category as comedian <PERSON> Pee-wee </PERSON> <PERSON> Herman </PERSON>, singer <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> and sexologist Dr. <PERSON> Ruth </PERSON> <PERSON> Westheimer </PERSON>. `` I think they ought to stick to publishing pictures of nude women and not bother people who are trying to do something,'' said <PERSON> Schaefer </PERSON>, who had n't read the story. The article recycles asome old <PERSON> Schaefer </PERSON> adventures, including the day he was delivered in a box to <LOCATION> Annapolis </LOCATION> to become governor. It also recounts <PERSON> Schaefer </PERSON>'s habit of calling male reporters `` girls'' and his insistence on staying in his longtime <LOCATION> Baltimore </LOCATION> rowhouse. Playboy likens him to <PERSON> Norman </PERSON> <PERSON> Bates </PERSON>, the crazed motel owner in the <PERSON> Alfred </PERSON> <PERSON> Hitchcock </PERSON> thriller `` Psycho'' and a sequel, `` Psycho II.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> has been named to receive the 1988 Humanitarian Award from the <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> <PERSON> Wiesenthal </PERSON> <PERSON> Center </PERSON>, and his wife, <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON>, will receive the center's first Museum of Tolerance award, the center said. Nearly 2,000 guests, including <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Walters </PERSON>, <PERSON> Arnold </PERSON> <PERSON> Schwarzenegger </PERSON> and <PERSON> Ben </PERSON> <PERSON> Kingsley </PERSON>, are on the invitation list for the Oct. 30 awards presentation. The ceremony will take place during a gala to celebrate the 80th birthday of <PERSON> Wiesenthal </PERSON>, the Nazi hunter who lives in <LOCATION> Austria </LOCATION>, said center spokeswoman <PERSON> Lydia </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Triantopoulos </PERSON>. The Los Angeles-based center selected <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> as its 1988 recipient in recognition of his efforts to prevent nuclear war, his staunch support of <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> and his efforts on behalf of Soviet refuseniks, said a statement released Wednesday. Previous recipients of the Humanitarian Award included French President <PERSON> Francois </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitterrrand </PERSON> and former Soviet refusenik <PERSON> Natan </PERSON> <PERSON> Sharansky </PERSON>. The center studies the Holocaust and serves as an information-collection center in the hunt for escaped <ORGANIZATION> Nazis </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>Eds: A version moved on sports wire.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>GRAPEVINE, Texas (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The owners of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Football </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> League </ORGANIZATION> teams approved the sale of the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> England </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Patriots </ORGANIZATION> to shaver-maker <PERSON> Victor </PERSON> <PERSON> Kiam </PERSON> and the sale of the <ORGANIZATION> Seattle </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Seahawks </ORGANIZATION> to a group headed by <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> land developer <PERSON> Ken </PERSON> <PERSON> Behring </PERSON>. The transactions were approved unanimously Wednesday pending the reception of documents by the league office within 10 days. Controlling interest in the Patriots was sold by the <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> family, which founded the team, to <PERSON> Kiam </PERSON> for a reported $ 90 million after a 14-hour negotiating session this week. `` I'm gratified,'' said <PERSON> Kiam </PERSON>, chief executive officer of Connecticut-based <ORGANIZATION> Remington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Products </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co </ORGANIZATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> Seahawks </ORGANIZATION> sale already had been completed and league approval was only a formality. The 13-year-old franchise was sold by the Nordstrom family of <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION> department store fame to a group headed by <PERSON> Behring </PERSON> for a reported $ 80 million.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881006-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-06-88 0106EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-ForeignOwnership Bjt   10-06 0476</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Foreign Ownership, Bjt,470</SECOND>
<HEAD>Foreign Investment Disclosure Bill Clears House</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MIKE ROBINSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Foreign investors with a `` significant interest'' in American business or property would have to disclose their holdings to the government under legislation approved by the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>. `` Give us the opportunity to have a basic inventory of ownership of the American economy,'' Rep. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Bryant </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Texas </LOCATION>, the sponsor, said as the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> approved the measure 250-170 on Wednesday. The measure now goes to the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>, where its chances for approval are dim. Those owning more than 5 percent of a business or property valued at more than $ 5 million or that has more than $ 10 million in annual gross sales would have to report their identity and holdings to the <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>. The measure also would apply to investors holding more than 5 percent of a combination of two or more businesses or properties valued at more than $ 20 million or with annual gross sales of more than $ 40 million. Foreigners with `` controlling interests'' in <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> businesses and properties would be required to submit more extensive reports, including balance sheets and the identities of officers and directors. The <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> would establish a registry of foreign interests owning <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> property. Rep. <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Cooper </PERSON>, D-Tenn., described the measure as `` election-year xenophobia'' designed to capitalize on fear of foreigners among voters Supporters retorted that foreign takeover of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> assets should not occur in secret. `` The <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> people have the right to know who holds the mortgage on <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>,'' Rep. <PERSON> Marcy </PERSON> <PERSON> Kaptur </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Ohio </LOCATION>, declared. The bill originally was included in the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>'s version of a wide-ranging trade measure signed by President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> Aug. 23. But sponsors, seeking to build support for the trade bill, dropped the foreign ownership provision before it went to <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>. The foreign ownership disclosure bill is now moving forward as separate legislation. The measure's prospects are dim in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>, where it would be vulnerable to a time-consuming filibuster with only days remaining until lawmakers adjourn to campaign full time. Critics say the bill would bare business secrets that ought to be private, thus scaring off foreigners whose investment helps to finance the budget deficit and fuels the economy, creating jobs for Americans. `` The issue is confidentiality,'' said Rep. <PERSON> Norman </PERSON> <PERSON> Lent </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-N.Y. </LOCATION> `` This bill does n't have adequate safeguards.'' Data on foreign ownership of <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> property already is collected by 17 federal agencies. But the information is often kept secret, even from <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, and in any case the names of the actual owners rarely appear. Complaints persist that even those reports are often incomplete, inaccurate and largely meaningless and that hundreds of billions of dollars in new investment have simply fallen through the cracks in recent years. Opponents also blasted the bill as discriminatory toward foreign investors because Americans would not have to provide the same information.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881006-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-06-88 0110EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FarmScene     10-06 0839</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Farm Scene,830</SECOND>
<HEAD>Study Says Consumers Likely To Feel Effects Of Wheat Price Rise</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DON KENDALL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Farm Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A new Agriculture Department analysis of this summer's drought-induced rise in wheat prices says consumers might feel some effect at grocery stores at least through 1989. `` Past movements suggest that the drought's influence on farm prices of wheat will be felt for about a year at the industrial -LRB- wholesale -RRB- level and for a year and a half or more by consumers,'' the report said. The study was done by <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Babula </PERSON> of the department's <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>, and <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bessler </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> A & amp; <ORGANIZATION> M </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, and reported in the current issue of Agricultural Outlook magazine <PERSON> Babula </PERSON> said Wednesday in a telephone interview that he and <PERSON> Bessler </PERSON> are not forcasting how food prices will behave in the coming months. Prices of various items could decline but still leave some impact from the 1988 drought. `` We're not predicting anything,'' <PERSON> Babula </PERSON> said. `` We're showing how things have moved in the past ... and some of the things that we might expect to see happen in the future.'' A statistical computer model was used to show how prices of wheat at the farm, wholesale prices and retail prices have moved together in the past. The model was then `` shocked'' with an increase in the farm price of wheat to simulate the 7.7 percent average monthly boost during May, June and July, when the effects of the drought were first reflected in the market. `` When the farm price shock occurs, processor -LRB- wholesale -RRB- prices for wheat rise immediately, peaking a month after the rise in the farm price,'' the report said. `` At their highest, processor prices increase less than half of the 7.7 percent increase in the farm price. Processor price increases are felt for about a year, but the impulse generally declines in strength through time.'' On the other hand, the 7.7 percent average increase in the farm price of wheat `` generates gradual, not immediate, increases in consumer prices of wheat-related goods,'' the report said. Delivery, sale and consumption of flour, bread, cake mixes, pasta and other wheat-related foods occur throughout the year and are not as closely tied to the wheat crop cycle as processing, which includes the flour milling and baking industries. `` So, the consumer price effects last more than a year,'' the report said. `` Consumer price rises peak at seven months, but prices stay relatively high until 17 to 20 months after the initiating farm price shock. The increase in consumer prices is smaller but more enduring than the jump in processor prices.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Some promising new biological weapons are being used in the war against marauding grasshoppers, says the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>. In one development, two commercial firms _ <ORGANIZATION> Evans </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> BioControl </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Broomfield </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Colo. </LOCATION>, and <PERSON> Bozeman </PERSON> Bio Tech of <PERSON> Bozeman </PERSON>, <PERSON> Mont </PERSON>. _ have adapted <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> technology for producing and storing a parasite, Nosema lucustae. Department studies show the parasite kills 50 percent to 60 percent of grasshoppers in three to four weeks. The basic tests and development were done by the department's <ORGANIZATION> Agricultural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> at the agency's <ORGANIZATION> Rangeland </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Insect </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Laboratory </ORGANIZATION> in <PERSON> Bozeman </PERSON> by J.E <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> and colleagues. <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> said the parasite is available to homeowners and ranchers through regional agents and on contract to government agencies, which use it on a large scale in the West. <ORGANIZATION> Grasshoppers </ORGANIZATION> cause an estimated $ 400 million in damage to grass and crops each year, he said. Spores of the parasite are put on wheat bran flakes to form a bait. After the insects eat the bait, the organism `` attacks the pest's fat cells and depletes its energy stores,'' <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> said in a report issued here on Wednesday. The parasite remains in the grasshopper population because sick females pass it on to offspring, and survivors eat dead relatives, he said. Meanwhile, another development involves an agreement with <PERSON> Evans </PERSON> <PERSON> Biotechnical </PERSON> to field test another natural killer, grasshopper entomopoxvirus, the agency said. In laboratory tests, the virus kills 20 percent to 30 percent of the grasshoppers right away and stunts the growth of an additional 20 percent to 30 percent. <PERSON> Doug </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Streett </PERSON>, an entomoligist at the agency's <PERSON> Bozeman </PERSON> laboratory, said <ORGANIZATION> Evans </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> BioControl </ORGANIZATION> plans to produce the virus and mix it with the parasite for tests on 1,000 acres in the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Streett </PERSON> said that in combination the two ingredients may work more rapidly to kill the grasshoppers.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Ice cream production in August was estimated by the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> at 87.7 million gallons, up 4 percent from a year earlier. That did n't count 39.4 million gallons of ice milk, a 20 percent increase from August 1987, or 5.21 million gallons of sherbet, up 13 percent. August production figures issued on Wednesday also showed butter output at 74.2 million pounds, up 12 percent from a year earlier. Production of American-type cheese, at 214 million pounds, was up 4 percent. Production of non-fat dry milk was reported at 66.6 million pounds, down 17 percent from August 1987.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881006-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-06-88 0112EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-WaterEnforcement Bjt   10-06 0828</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Water Enforcement, Bjt,790</SECOND>
<NOTE>For Release at 10 a.m. EDT; time set by source</NOTE>
<HEAD>Report: EPA Rarely Enforces Laws on Drinking Water</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GUY DARST</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Federal and state governments took legally required enforcement action for only 2.6 percent of more than 100,000 violations of the Safe Drinking Water Act in fiscal 1987, a conservation group said today. It is the policy of the <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> to permit 23 months to lapse before even considering enforcement actions such as fines, lawsuits or administrative orders, the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wildlife </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federation </ORGANIZATION> said in releasing its findings. The federation said the nation's water systems or states notified customers of only 6 percent of the violations instead of every single one as the law requires. The federation said it examined 15,000 pages of <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> records covering the 1987 fiscal year and found that 36,763 public water systems committed 101,588 violations of the act. The affected water systems serve about 40 million people. <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Cook </PERSON>, deputy director of <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Drinking </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Water </ORGANIZATION>, said he was at a loss to explain how the federation arrived at its figures. He said his office recorded about 2,800 systems with `` significant'' violations in 1987, and 15,500 systems with violations <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> believed minor, a decline from 4,500 and 17,000, respectively, the year before. `` All regulatory agencies must have enforcement discretion,'' <PERSON> Cook </PERSON> said. When <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> finds a violation, `` It is our position that it need not be an enforcement action'' that follows. Sixty-four percent of water systems serve fewer than 500 people, with 73 percent of significant violators and 83 percent of minor violators that small or smaller, <PERSON> Cook </PERSON> said. Small systems may have difficulty raising money for the best equipment, he said. `` It may take some time for this community to float a loan. ... You're talking about years. It does n't make a lot of sense, if you have a cooperative community which is moving ahead, to beat them over the head with penalties that they ca n't afford anyway. Communities may be fined up to $ 25,000 for each day of violation, though fines that large are rare. `` It's important to understand that if enforcement actions are not taken, the states are aggressive in protecting the public health'' through `` boil water'' notices to the public, requirements for provision of bottled water and similar measures, <PERSON> Cook </PERSON> said. He said the agency `` heartily recommends'' to the states fines and other actions against systems it considers `` recalcitrant.'' There are about 201,000 water systems serving the public, of which 59,000 are `` community'' systems serving more than 25 people and the rest `` non-community'' systems serving resorts, campgrounds and other areas used only part of the year or by a transient population. The federation's report did not distinguish between excessive concentrations of a contaminant and failure to monitor or failure to report findings. But <PERSON> Norman </PERSON> <PERSON> Dean </PERSON>, a federation lawyer and principal author of the report, said the records showed 13,224 violations of enforceable contamination standards by community water systems and 4,282 violations by `` non-community'' systems. `` This is not a situation where 99 percent of the violations are paper work violations,'' <PERSON> Dean </PERSON> said. Monitoring and reporting requirements are `` the heart of the law,'' the study said. `` They enable the identification and correction of public health risks before they blossom into crises. `` One <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> official told us that some public water systems stop monitoring when they become aware of a known health standard violation,'' the report said. The only detailed EPA examination of a state program, a review of <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>'s efforts completed in 1984, found a `` significant deficiency'' in reporting by state authorities of all violations to EPA. State agencies took only 2,544 enforcement actions, the federation said. <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> during the year completed only 50 administrative orders, had proposed 57 more and had issued 101 notices of violation, the first step before issuing an order or going to court. <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> told the federation recently it actually had completed 183 or 184 such orders during the 1987 fiscal year, but the federation said it was unable to verify the number or explain the discrepancy with the lower numbers found in its own examination of the records. Requirements that customers are to be notified are aimed at forcing water systems to toe the mark so they will not have to face public criticism, but water systems issued only 5,269 such notices and states only 598 in the year studied, the report said. The law permits states to run drinking water pollution prevention and enforcement programs as long as they are as strict as a federal program would be. A state may opt out, leaving <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> with direct authority. Only <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> District </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION> have chosen to let <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> enforce the federal law in their jurisdictions. But in all states, the law was changed in 1986 to require <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> to act directly against local water systems if state authorities do not act within 30 days of learning of a violation.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881006-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-06-88 0113EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-LatinRulers     10-06 0222</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Latin Rulers,0229</SECOND>
<HEAD>Pinochet One Of Few Authoritarian Leaders Remaining In Latin
America</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Chile Bjt</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>SANTIAGO, Chile (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Gen. <PERSON> Augusto </PERSON> <PERSON> Pinochet </PERSON> is one of the few authoritarian leaders left in <LOCATION> Latin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, where elected civilian government has returned to most countries. The nearest geographically is Gen. <PERSON> Alfredo </PERSON> <PERSON> Stroessner </PERSON>, who has ruled <LOCATION> Paraguay </LOCATION> since seizing power in 1954. President <PERSON> Fidel </PERSON> <PERSON> Castro </PERSON> has governed <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> since leading a successful revolution in 1959 and installing a communist regime. In <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>, Gen. <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> qualifies as an authoritarian leader but is not technically the chief of state. Elected civilian governments have replaced military regimes in the last few years in <LOCATION> Argentina </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Uruguay </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Peru </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ecuador </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Bolivia </LOCATION>. Military governments ruled <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION> for two decades until 1985. Five generals took turns as president, chosen by their peers and sharing power with them. <LOCATION> Argentina </LOCATION>'s armed forces ousted civilian President <PERSON> Isabel </PERSON> <PERSON> Peron </PERSON> in March 1976 and retained power until 1983, leaving in disgrace after defeat in the <LOCATION> Falkland </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Islands </LOCATION> war with <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>. Governing was an act of the military institution in both countries, but the regimes of <PERSON> Pinochet </PERSON>, 72, and <PERSON> Stroessner </PERSON>, 75, are personal. <PERSON> Pinochet </PERSON> declared a few years ago: `` Not a single leaf moves in this country unless I move it,'' and <PERSON> Stroessner </PERSON> probably could say the same.
</TEXT>
