<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880324-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-24-88 0118EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-PuffingMother     03-24 0210</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Puffing Mother,0215</SECOND>
<HEAD>Woman Gains Right to Light Up</HEAD>
<DATELINE>GREAT NECK, N.Y. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A chain-smoker who had been ordered by a judge not to puff in front of her children won the right to light up again. The appeals division of the state <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> granted a stay of the order Tuesday, permitting 41-year-old <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> Roofeh </PERSON> to smoke in the presence of her husband and children pending a hearing scheduled for September. Mrs. <PERSON> Roofeh </PERSON> said Wednesday she already is trying to kick the habit. `` I was only doing it -LRB- smoking -RRB- to annoy my husband,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Roofeh </PERSON>, who is seeking a divorce, said as she left for her first session at a non-smoking clinic. `` I'm coughing like crazy. I do n't think it's good for the kids. Mrs. <PERSON> Roofeh </PERSON>'s husband, <PERSON> Jahanshan </PERSON>, an orthopedic surgeon, went to court last year, arguing that her smoking is harmful to their children, ages 6, 7 and 9. He said he tried unsuccessfully for 12 years to get her to curtail her habit. Last month, Judge <PERSON> Ralph </PERSON> <PERSON> Diamond </PERSON> ordered Mrs. <PERSON> Roofeh </PERSON> to confine her smoking to a small room in the couple's six-bedroom home. Her attorney, <PERSON> Joel </PERSON> <PERSON> Brandes </PERSON>, appealed, contending such an order is unconstitutional. <PERSON> Roofeh </PERSON>'s attorney, <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> Schissell </PERSON>, had no comment on the stay.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880324-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-24-88 0120EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-People-Schroeder     03-24 0223</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-People-Schroeder,190</SECOND>
<HEAD>Jay Schroeder's Restaurant Victim Of Second-String Quarterback
Woes</HEAD>
<DATELINE>FALLS CHURCH, Va. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Being a second-string quarterback can be hard on business, as the <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Redskins </ORGANIZATION>' <PERSON> Jay </PERSON> <PERSON> Schroeder </PERSON> has discovered. <PERSON> Schroeder </PERSON>, backup to starter <PERSON> Doug </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>, says the restaurant operating in this <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> suburb under his name `` was a business venture that did n't work out.'' The owners of <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Schroeder </PERSON>'s All-Pro Restaurant recently decided to close the eatery because of mounting debts. <PERSON> Schroeder </PERSON> allowed his name to be used for the establishment in exchange for a small percentage of its profit and an agreement to appear there several times a week. He declined to discuss the closing, saying the restaurant's problems were `` for me to know.'' <PERSON> Schroeder </PERSON> lost his position as the Skins' starting quarterback in midseason last year. The Skins went on to win the Super Bowl under <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>. `` Having the second-string quarterback's name on the restaurant did not help business,'' said <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Sandground </PERSON>, general manager at the Sign of the Whale, another <LOCATION> Falls </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Church </LOCATION> restaurant. Former <ORGANIZATION> Redskins </ORGANIZATION>' quarterback <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Theismann </PERSON> owns three restaurants in the area that bear his name. But <PERSON> Theismann </PERSON> began his career as a restaurateur just as his career was beginning to take off, while the opening of <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Schroeder </PERSON>'s last year coincided with <PERSON> Schroeder </PERSON>'s slump. <PERSON> Schroeder </PERSON> said he was looking into other business opportunities.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880324-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-24-88 0133EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-TVArrest     03-24 0456</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-TV Arrest,0470</SECOND>
<HEAD>Suspect Arrested On TV Viewer's Tip</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT MIMS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MURRAY, Utah (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> woman who watched a TV show on unsolved crimes supplied the tip that led to the arrest of a man wanted in the poisoning death of a <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> beauty queen, authorities said. <PERSON> Steven </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Mack </PERSON>, 39, was arrested without incident in this <LOCATION> Salt </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> suburb after a dozen squad cars closed in on his car Tuesday, said police Sgt. <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Brusik </PERSON>. <PERSON> Mack </PERSON> was being held at <LOCATION> Salt </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jail </LOCATION> on $ 500,000 bail. Authorities in <LOCATION> Sacramento </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, had been seeking <PERSON> Mack </PERSON>, 39, in the slaying of <PERSON> Karen </PERSON> <PERSON> Grace </PERSON> <PERSON> Winslett </PERSON>, 21, of <LOCATION> Carmichael </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Winslett </PERSON> had won the title of Miss English Leather in <LOCATION> Las </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vegas </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Nev. </LOCATION>, shortly before she disappeared in 1987 Her body was found 12 days later in her car, parked behind a <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sacramento </LOCATION> motel. Detectives said she died of a large dose of Percodan, a pain killer. They said <PERSON> Mack </PERSON> was linked to the crime by physical and other evidence that the detectives would not detail. <LOCATION> Sacramento </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> Sheriff's Sgt. <PERSON> Tennise </PERSON> <PERSON> Allen </PERSON> credited the Sunday night showing of <ORGANIZATION> Fox </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Broadcasting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>'s `` <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s Most Wanted'' with bringing about <PERSON> Mack </PERSON>'s arrest. Following the show, an employee of a country club in <LOCATION> Marion </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, called her local sheriff's department to say she recognized <PERSON> Mack </PERSON> as having once worked at the club. She also recalled having received a telephone call from someone in <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION> in February asking for a man named <PERSON> Sean </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Lanier </PERSON>. A check of club personnel records had showed no one by that name had worked there. <LOCATION> Salt </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> police were alerted, and <PERSON> Mack </PERSON> was arrested after he left a home been purchased by a <PERSON> Sean </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Lanier </PERSON> in November, authorities said. was unarmed and taken by surprise. The arrest is the fourth of an escapee or suspect stemming from the show, according to <PERSON> Fox </PERSON>. <PERSON> Mack </PERSON>, a forger and burglar who served two prison terms and was paroled in 1985, sells novelties and sports and clothing items, authorities said. <LOCATION> Sacramento </LOCATION> police also said <PERSON> Mack </PERSON> is a suspect in a similar slaying of a 19-year-old woman in <LOCATION> Marion </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>. In all, the `` <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s Most Wanted'' episode generated 170 calls on a toll-free number shown on the screen. The show, which premiered earlier this year, has as its host <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Walsh </PERSON>, who has been active in the movement for better police efforts to trace missing children since his son, <PERSON> Adam </PERSON>, was abducted and slain. Another arrest stemming from the show was that of a murderer who had escaped from an <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION> prison in 1986 was found last month working as a supervisor at a homeless shelter in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880324-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-24-88 0139EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-SunriseWind     03-24 0322</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Sunrise Wind,0330</SECOND>
<HEAD>`Sunrise Wind' Bodes Ill For Farming Conditions</HEAD>
<DATELINE>POST, Texas (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A tough year for farmers is in the wind _ that is, if an old Comanche Indian legend holds true. According to the legend, the wind direction at precisely sunrise on the day after the first day of spring will tell what kind of weather and farming conditions the next year will hold for the region. If the wind, called <LOCATION> Taba </LOCATION> ` na <PERSON> Yuna </PERSON>' e in Comanche, comes from the east or northeast, good harvests should follow; if it blows from the north or northwest, conditions will be A west or southwest wind does n't bode well, and a south wind is just plain bad news. Records on the annual ceremony are said to show a 92 percent success rate since 1906, the first year settlers gathered to see what the winds had in store. `` Chief'' <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Runkles </PERSON>, who has been performing the ceremony for 15 years, began his dance Tuesday with supplications to <LOCATION> Wakantanka </LOCATION>, the Father Spirit, and <PERSON> Mikeana </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Mother </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Earth </LOCATION>, as well as the winds. `` The <LOCATION> Mother </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Earth </LOCATION> is revered because she gives us food to eat,'' he said. `` Wakantanka is the Great Father above _ we seek his blessings.'' As he spoke, a southerly wind blew so hard that Indian dancers from an <ORGANIZATION> Amarillo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Boy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Scout </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Explorer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> had to shield a ceremonial fire as it was ignited. The gusts died down as sunrise neared. Seconds before <PERSON> Runkles </PERSON> caught the first glimpse of the sun over the distant horizon, a gust whisked in from the north, then reversed direction at the moment of sunrise, giving an official reading of west-southwest _ bad news for farmers. Despite the <ORGANIZATION> Indians </ORGANIZATION>' claims of predictive accuracy, however, farmers do n't necessarily need to worry. Last year, smoke from Runkles' fire indicated a south wind and poor conditions, but <LOCATION> Southern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Plains </LOCATION> farmers ended up with one of the best cotton harvests on record.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880324-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-24-88 0140EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-APArts:Sing     03-24 0719</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AP Arts: Sing,0738</SECOND>
<HEAD>High School Sing Reaches Screen With Patti LaBelle</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in report for Thursday AMs.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By JEFF BRADLEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>TORONTO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Above a pawn shop in downtown <LOCATION> Toronto </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Patti </PERSON> <PERSON> LaBelle </PERSON> rips into a group of lackadaisical <LOCATION> Brooklyn </LOCATION> high school students. In her first major dramatic role, the pop star is playing an inspirational teacher in a movie musical based on Sing, the annual song-and-dance competition in <LOCATION> Brooklyn </LOCATION>'s schools. The legendary program at such schools as Erasmus Hall gave rise to such talents as Barbra Streisand and <PERSON> Neil </PERSON> <PERSON> Diamond </PERSON>. But with the urban decay of the past decade, only a dozen schools now take part. The struggle to preserve that old <LOCATION> Brooklyn </LOCATION> spirit has inspired the film, `` SING,'' with a plot centered on education board plans to close a beloved high school where generations of immigrants got their start. With songs from the writer of `` Footloose'' and `` Fame'' and a tempestuous love story between a street-smart Italian kid and a Jewish princess, the Tri-Star Pictures production now shooting in <LOCATION> Toronto </LOCATION> is scheduled for release in February 1989. `` I'm hooked on it. I'm one of those people who think about community and pulling together and family,'' said <PERSON> LaBelle </PERSON>, the rhythm and blues artist who first hit the pop charts in the 1960s with the <ORGANIZATION> Blue </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bells </ORGANIZATION> and later in the'70s with the trio <PERSON> LaBelle </PERSON>. She has appeared in two previous films, `` A Soldier's Story'' and the TV movie `` Unnatural Causes.'' In `` SING,'' she plays Mrs. <PERSON> Devere </PERSON>, an adviser who shakes her junior class students out of apathy. `` She's very uplifting to the kids,'' <PERSON> Labelle </PERSON> said between takes of her chart-targeted big number, `` Total Concentration,'' in which she demonstrates how to put over a song. Producer <PERSON> Craig </PERSON> <PERSON> Zadan </PERSON> and screenwriter-lyricist <PERSON> Dean </PERSON> <PERSON> Pitchford </PERSON>, who won an Academy Award for `` Fame,'' said they created the part with <PERSON> LaBelle </PERSON> in mind and waited until she found time to do it. `` There's a real honesty there, nothing phony about her. In her own way she's lived through what this teacher has gone through,'' said <PERSON> Pitchford </PERSON>. <PERSON> LaBelle </PERSON> has charmed the crew by introducing them to her own home cooking _ fried chicken and potato salad. But she's not sure about life as an actress. `` I'm not a Cher. I do n't know if I'd have enough patience to do another movie,'' she said, complaining about the number of retakes. `` It hurts enough some times that you want to cry. I like to perform live.'' However, director <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Baskin </PERSON>, who co-produced Streisand's landmark `` Broadway Album'' and is making his first feature film, said <PERSON> LaBelle </PERSON> looked great in the first rushes Co-stars include <PERSON> Lorraine </PERSON> <PERSON> Bracco </PERSON> who played <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Berenger </PERSON>'s wife in `` Someone to Watch Over Me,'' <PERSON> Louise </PERSON> <PERSON> Lasser </PERSON> of `` <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Hartman </PERSON>, <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Hartman </PERSON>'' fame and <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Dicenzo </PERSON> who was <PERSON> Rob </PERSON> <PERSON> Lowe </PERSON>'s boss in `` About Last Night.'' The young lovers are <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Dobson </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jessica </PERSON> <PERSON> Steen </PERSON>. For co-producer <PERSON> Neil </PERSON> <PERSON> Meron </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Brooklyn </LOCATION> and Sing alumnus, the project is a labor of love. `` In the high school I went to, Sing no longer exists,'' <PERSON> Meron </PERSON> lamented. `` <LOCATION> Brooklyn </LOCATION> is one of the oldest communities in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, and the way those communities found to express themselves was through music and dance.'' To research the film, the production team talked with veteran teachers in <LOCATION> Brooklyn </LOCATION> and attended a Sing performance at <ORGANIZATION> Midwood </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> High </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> where faculty member <PERSON> Bella </PERSON> <PERSON> Tillis </PERSON> launched the program in 1947. Sing competitions involved reviews or skits created and staged by a committee from each class. The musical skits were judged on sing night when freshmen, sophomores, juniors and seniors got to strut their stuff. In the 1950s and'60s, when Sing was at its peak, the competitions were fierce. Lyricist <PERSON> Pitchford </PERSON> also found inspiration in <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>, where he's been working with the <ORGANIZATION> Royal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Shakespeare </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> on the Broadway-bound musical, `` Carrie. `` After ` Fame' the last thing I wanted to do was another high school film set in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> about kids who sing and dance,'' he said. `` But <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> has tradition and history we can only approximate in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>. The closest thing to that kind of longevity is in <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Coast </LOCATION> settlements like <LOCATION> Brooklyn </LOCATION>. Sing became a metaphor for that tradition. `` I developed an enormous affection for Sing and the neighborhoods of <LOCATION> Brooklyn </LOCATION> and a real despair for the passing of this tradition.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880324-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-24-88 0142EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Cyprus-Archaeology     03-24 0816</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Cyprus-Archaeology,0845</SECOND>
<HEAD>Cyprus' Civilization May Be 1,500 Years Older Than Believed</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</NOTE>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DONNA ABU-NASR</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>AKROTIRI, Cyprus (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 New discoveries by American archaeologists indicate that humans could have settled on <LOCATION> Cyprus </LOCATION> around 9000 B.C., 1,500 years earlier than previously thought. The finds also indicate that some species of ancient animals survived here at least 1,000 years after they were believed to have become extinct. If proven correct, the discoveries mean that <LOCATION> Cyprus </LOCATION> was one of the earliest human settlements north of <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>, along with the island of <LOCATION> Corsica </LOCATION>, also in the <LOCATION> Mediterranean </LOCATION>. `` If these dates are corroborated, the site will have provided by far the earliest archaeological evidence for island colonization anywhere in the <LOCATION> Mediterranean </LOCATION>,'' Dr. <PERSON> Stuart </PERSON> <PERSON> Swiny </PERSON>, director of the <ORGANIZATION> Cyprus </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Archaeological </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION>, reported in a recent lecture. Scientists had previously dated man's arrival on <LOCATION> Cyprus </LOCATION> around 7500 B.C. But archaelogists digging on a slope near the sprawling British air base at <LOCATION> Akrotiri </LOCATION> on <LOCATION> Cyprus </LOCATION>' south coast recently found pygmy hippopotamus and dwarf elephant bones, some mixed with shells, flint and ash. Archaelogists believe the flint, an early cutting tool, was used to slice meat from the animals. The ash indicated cooking fires. Carbon dating placed the remains at around 9000 B.C., a millenium after those species of animals were believed to have died out. <PERSON> Swiny </PERSON> said that the animals, common to many <LOCATION> Mediterranean </LOCATION> islands thousands of years ago, were wiped out by climatic changes during the last Ice Age that ended around 12,000 years ago. `` We thought ... these animals died out because of natural causes _ they could n't get enough food or enough water,'' <PERSON> Swiny </PERSON> said in an interview after the lecture. `` But now it looks as if man was also responsible for wiping them out.'' The <LOCATION> Akrotiri </LOCATION> excavation is sponsored by the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nevada </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Schools </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Oriental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION>, which sponsors the <LOCATION> Cyprus </LOCATION> <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> institute. The dig is under the direction of Dr. <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Simmons </PERSON>, who currently is in <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION>. The original discovery was made in 1980 by a <LOCATION> British </LOCATION> security officer at <LOCATION> Akrotiri </LOCATION>, Maj. <PERSON> Brian </PERSON> <PERSON> Pile </PERSON>, then a lieutenant, while he was training his men to seek out unusual objects. Underground excavation at the site, eight miles south of the port city of <LOCATION> Limassol </LOCATION>, started last July and will continue this summer. <PERSON> Swiny </PERSON> said the actual age of the site will remain questionable until results of further tests are obtained. The finds are only some of the important discoveries unearthed by American archaeologists in the last few years on <LOCATION> Cyprus </LOCATION>, the center of trade routes between <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> for centuries. The island is studded with relics of a history that spans more than 10,000 years, during which more than a dozen civilizations, including Achaean Greeks, Egyptians, Romans, Armenians, Venetians and Ottoman Turks left their imprint. Americans are involved in six of the 20 digs currently being made in the Greek-controlled southern part of <LOCATION> Cyprus </LOCATION>. The Cyprus American institute provides logistical help at one sponsored by <ORGANIZATION> Brandeis </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, of <LOCATION> Waltham </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mass. </LOCATION>, at the Late Bronze Age town of <LOCATION> Kalavasos-Ayios </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dhimitrios </LOCATION>, 18 miles northeast of <LOCATION> Limassol </LOCATION>. It was one of the biggest Bronze Age settlements on <LOCATION> Cyprus </LOCATION> and a center for the island's ancient copper trade. <LOCATION> Cyprus </LOCATION> is the Phoenician word for copper. Last summer archaelogists uncovered the remains of a 13th century B.C. building, covering more than 10,764 square feet and once at least two stories high, that was apparently destroyed by fire. `` It's the biggest and most important building at the site and one of the biggest of that period in <LOCATION> Cyprus </LOCATION>,'' said Dr. <PERSON> Alison </PERSON> <PERSON> South </PERSON> <PERSON> Todd </PERSON>, the dig's co-director. `` We also found some inscriptions which are very rare to the period in Cypro-Minoan script,'' she added. Cypro-Minoan, which resembles the script used in <LOCATION> Minoan </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Crete </LOCATION> 4,000 years ago, has never been deciphered. The presence of these inscriptions and the huge storage capacity of the building, known as Building X, suggest it was either a palace or a town hall. The storage room, more than 60 feet long and 24 feet wide, consists of an outer wall and six stone pillars that once supported the roof. The shards of at least 47 jars, some once as tall as six feet, have been found. All apparently had been smashed in the fire. But six intact jars were later discovered in pits below the floor. <PERSON> Todd </PERSON> discovered a tomb, considered one of the richest and best preserved ever found on <LOCATION> Cyprus </LOCATION>, while digging an exploratory trench out from the building. The oval-shaped tomb contained the skeletons of three young women, a child about 3 years old and three infants. They apparently had social status and wealth. The women had been buried with gold and silver jewelry, bronze and bone artifacts, containers of wine with small cups inside and cylindrical ivory cosmetic boxes.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880324-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-24-88 0143EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-ProstateTreatment     03-24 0609</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Prostate Treatment,0629</SECOND>
<HEAD>Enlarged Prostates Treated Without Hospital Stay, Researcher
Reports</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By MALCOLM RITTER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Science Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An experimental treatment for enlarged prostate glands shows promise as an outpatient alternative to surgery that hospitalizes about 400,000 American men a year, researchers say. An enlarged prostate makes urination difficult by constricting the urinary tract, and the experimental procedure widens the narrowed portion by inflating a balloon, said <PERSON> Flavio </PERSON> <PERSON> Castaneda </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Minnesota </ORGANIZATION>. Test results show complete or significant resolution of the urination problem in about 80 percent of patients with the most common type of enlargement, he said. The half-hour procedure is done with only a local anesthetic and without an overnight stay in the hospital, he said. Standard surgery requires general anesthesia or a spinal injection that numbs the lower part of the body, and a hospital stay of several days. The prostate is a walnut-sized gland that surrounds the urine-carrying urethra. In older men, it frequently enlarges and puts pressure on the urethra, making urination more difficult. The experimental technique is to be described Thursday by <PERSON> Castaneda </PERSON>'s colleague, <PERSON> Wilfrido </PERSON> <PERSON> Castaneda-Zuniga </PERSON>, at a meeting of the <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cardiovascular </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Interventional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Radiology </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Orlando </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>. More than 60 patients have been treated with the experimental procedure, called balloon urethroplasty, at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Minnesota </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Castaneda </PERSON> said in a recent telephone interview The patient takes a tranquilizer and the urethra is numbed with local anesthetic. A thin, flexible tube with the balloon on its tip is inserted into the urethra and guided to the narrowed portion, where the balloon is inflated. For the <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION> patients, the urination problem was erased or significantly eased in almost 80 percent of cases in which most enlargement was from the side lobes of the prostate, rather than the middle lobe, <PERSON> Castanada </PERSON> said. Most patients have predominant enlargement of side lobes, he said. When the main problem was the middle lobe, the success rate dropped to about 30 percent to 40 percent, he said. No recurrence of symptoms has been seen in any patient helped by the procedure, he said. Forty-eight have been followed for more than six months after the procedure, including one followed for three years, he said. `` We're at this point unable to know how long it -LRB- symptom relief -RRB- will last on the average,'' <PERSON> Castaneda </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Abraham </PERSON> <PERSON> Cockett </PERSON>, professor and chairman of the urology department at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rochester </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, called the concept interesting. But he said more patients must be studied, and for periods longer than at least a year following the procedure, to better assess its effectiveness. Removing prostate tissue with standard surgery relieves symptoms for some 15 years, said <PERSON> Cockett </PERSON>, who is secretary of the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Urological </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>. In another presentation at the meeting Thursday, participants are to discuss an experimental alternative to removing gallbladders. About 500,000 gallbladders are removed in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> annually. Gallstones are the most frequent reason, said <PERSON> Eric </PERSON> <PERSON> Martin </PERSON>, director of cardiovascular and interventional radiology at the <ORGANIZATION> Columbia-Presbyterian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>. In two patients, Italian scientists have instead guided a flexible tube through the skin and into the gallbladder, used it to remove gallstones and injected a solution to turn the gallbladder into scar tissue. `` I still think it needs a lot of work, but it's exciting,'' said <PERSON> Martin </PERSON>. He noted that machines called lithotripters, now used to pulverize kidney stones, are also being studied for destroying gallstones. It is too early to tell how lithotripters and the surgical technique tried in <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION> will fit in to future management of gallbladder disease, he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880324-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-24-88 0939EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--OstrichFlap     03-24 0180</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Ostrich Flap,0190</SECOND>
<HEAD>Ostrich Farmer Sqwaks At Ruling</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LEBANON, Ohio (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A ostrich farmer thinks county commissioners may have their heads in the sand for failing to agree that an ostrich has as much value as a turkey. The dispute is over an <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> law that allows farmers to be reimbursed by the county if dogs kill their farm animals. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Erwin </PERSON> of <PERSON> Morrow </PERSON> filed a $ 600 claim for two ostriches killed by dogs. But <ORGANIZATION> Warren </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commissioners </ORGANIZATION> said Tuesday damages can be collected only on animals that provide meat, eggs, or feathers, and ostriches did n't. `` No one could think of any -LRB- agricultural value of the ostrich -RRB-,'' said commission President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Terwilleger </PERSON>. He invited <PERSON> Erwin </PERSON> to appeal, and <PERSON> Erwin </PERSON> said he would. `` I think that ostrich farming has as much credibility as cattle farming or sheep farming,'' said <PERSON> Erwin </PERSON>, 32. He said ostrich hides and feathers are sold in <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, and he plans to breed ostriches for meat. He said the meat is more of a bargain than turkey. `` You get a lot more bird for your money.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880324-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-24-88 0939EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--Zaccaro-Drugs     03-24 0146</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Zaccaro-Drugs,0150</SECOND>
<HEAD>One Charge Dropped</HEAD>
<DATELINE>RUTLAND, Vt. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 One of two drug charges against <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Zaccaro </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, the son of 1984 vice presidential candidate <PERSON> Geraldine </PERSON> <PERSON> Ferraro </PERSON>, has been dismissed for lack of evidence. District Judge <PERSON> Francis </PERSON> <PERSON> McCaffrey </PERSON> on Monday threw out a charge of possession of cocaine with intent to sell. After <PERSON> Zaccaro </PERSON>'s 1986 arrest, <PERSON> McCaffrey </PERSON> ruled inadmissible eight grams of cocaine and records of drug transactions seized by police from <PERSON> Zaccaro </PERSON>'s car. The judge said at the time that the search warrant was based on insufficient evidence. <PERSON> Zaccaro </PERSON> still faces an April 4 trial on a charge of selling a quarter-gram of cocaine to a state trooper while <PERSON> Zaccaro </PERSON> was a student at <ORGANIZATION> Middlebury </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> McCaffrey </PERSON> also said defense attorneys can not claim at the trial that <PERSON> Zaccaro </PERSON> was a victim of selective prosecution because the issue does not relate to guilt or innocence.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880324-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-24-88 0207EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lites     03-24 0578</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lites,0598</SECOND>
<HEAD>On The Light Side</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CAMDEN, N.J. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Oscar the Grouch, the guru of garbage on television's `` Sesame Street,'' has been asked to remove all recyclables from his trash can home. The famous character on the long-running PBS-TV children's show recently received a letter from <PERSON> Paula </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Barnabie </PERSON>, who works for the <ORGANIZATION> Camden </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Solid </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Waste </ORGANIZATION>. Every day, Ms. <PERSON> Barnabie </PERSON> wrote, the clank of aluminum, the crunch of newspapers and the tinkle of glass can be heard as <PERSON> Oscar </PERSON> fights his way to the surface of his trash can to snarl at Sesame Street residents. `` I watch the program every day with my nephew and I just could n't take it any more,'' she said. `` It would be so much nicer and environmentally sound for you to have a recycling bucket near your trash can.'' <LOCATION> Camden </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> will even give the tetchy titan of trash one of its brand new recycling buckets, she informed <PERSON> Oscar </PERSON>. The bright yellow buckets `` can be dirtied up in no time flat'' to match the rest of his dirty, dented decor, she said. The producers of Sesame Street are considering Ms. <PERSON> Barnabie </PERSON>'s suggestions, said <PERSON> Gail </PERSON> <PERSON> Y. </PERSON> <PERSON> Miyasaki </PERSON>, a spokeswoman for Children's Television Workshop, the show's Ms. <PERSON> Barnabie </PERSON> said she has not heard from Oscar, however. `` If he recycled, he'd be able to find a pen and paper in that can to write back to me,'' she said. `` I hope he does n't tell me to go ` scram.'''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>MIRAMAR, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Bailey </PERSON>'s face and <PERSON> Burt </PERSON> <PERSON> Reynolds </PERSON>' body have been sprawled across the side of a warehouse for 10 years, but City Commissioner <PERSON> Vicki </PERSON> <PERSON> Coceano </PERSON> says she wants to beautify the area _ starting with <PERSON> Bailey </PERSON>. The 19-foot wide mural on <PERSON> Bailey </PERSON>'s carpet store has <PERSON> Bailey </PERSON>'s head superimposed on <PERSON> Reynolds </PERSON>' body _ a takeoff on the actor's centerfold pose in Cosmopolitan magazine several years The body reclining on a shag rug is nude except for flesh-tone bikini trunks. `` He needs to be dressed or he needs to get off the rug,'' Ms. <PERSON> Coceano </PERSON> said Tuesday. The issue arose when the commission rejected <PERSON> Bailey </PERSON>'s request for a variance to expand his store. Ms. <PERSON> Coceano </PERSON> said the city has chosen to start its beautification program with him. `` People know me for this sign,'' <PERSON> Bailey </PERSON> said. `` I'll put a dark swimsuit on this next time, but skimpier.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>TELLURIDE, Colo. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Suzanne </PERSON> <PERSON> Carrell </PERSON> beat a filing deadline by 10 minutes to become a candidate for town moderator, a job most residents had forgotten existed and which rarely has any duties. The unpaid job calls for her to moderate at town meetings, if they ever are called under <ORGANIZATION> Telluride </ORGANIZATION>'s custom-made home-rule charter, which gives either the town council or residents the right to call a town meeting twice a year. There have been only three such town meetings in the last nine years, although there was an attempt to call one last year. That failed for lack of a quorum. `` It is not a job with a lot of use,'' confirmed Town Clerk <PERSON> Leslie </PERSON> <PERSON> Sherlock </PERSON>, who admitted forgetting about the opening until someone brought it to her attention for this year's election. <PERSON> Carrell </PERSON>, who works in a liquor store and a bookstore, said she decided to file for the post on Tuesday because she did n't have the time to serve on the town council. But she said she was surprised to learn she may not have any work to do.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880324-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-24-88 0209EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Burnley-FAA     03-24 0510</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Burnley-FAA,500</SECOND>
<HEAD>Burnley Says FAA Can Be Slow in Improving Air Safety Rules</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ALAN FRAM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Transportation Secretary <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Burnley </PERSON> <PERSON> IV </PERSON> says the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aviation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> sometimes needs `` the bureaucratic equivalent of a cattle prod'' to move on safety issues. In an unusual condemnation of an agency by the Cabinet officer who oversees it, <ORGANIZATION> Burnley </ORGANIZATION> accused the <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> of frequently harboring `` institutional resistance'' when the time comes to move harshly against the nation's aviation industry. At times, he said, `` it has been necessary to use the bureaucratic equivalent of a cattle prod to get the <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> to take needed safety actions.'' <ORGANIZATION> Burnley </ORGANIZATION> blamed the problem on the agency's structure and not its employees. The <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> is charged with writing and enforcing safety regulations for <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> aviation, running the nation's air traffic control system and promoting American air commerce. `` Because the <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> is charged with promoting and protecting the industry's commercial interests, it is sometimes reluctant to take safety and enforcement actions that impose significant costs and burdens on that industry,'' <ORGANIZATION> Burnley </ORGANIZATION> told the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> aviation subcommittee. As an example, <ORGANIZATION> Burnley </ORGANIZATION> said <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> officials and industry representatives opposed a 1986 proposal that airline and airport employees be screened by security devices, arguing that the plan was `` too burdensome.'' Even when the proposal was changed, the <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> delayed implementing the proposal for a year, he said. Two weeks ago, <ORGANIZATION> Burnley </ORGANIZATION> told reporters the <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> was not being strict enough in punishing airlines whose employees did not effectively screen passengers for weapons. He sent <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> Administrator <PERSON> Allan </PERSON> <PERSON> McArtor </PERSON> a memo March 8 asking him `` to give his personal attention to this matter.'' <PERSON> McArtor </PERSON> agreed, <ORGANIZATION> Burnley </ORGANIZATION> said Wednesday. `` Often it takes someone from outside the organization to insist that there may be ways to enhance safety that are being overlooked,'' he said. <ORGANIZATION> Burnley </ORGANIZATION> said the <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> `` is filled with competent, dedicated professionals'' who are placed in `` an inherently untenable position'' by the agency's structure. Asked after the hearing if he believed <PERSON> McArtor </PERSON> was responsible for any of the agency's problems, he said, `` <PERSON> Allan </PERSON>'s doing a fine job, doing an outstanding job.'' In a statement, <PERSON> McArtor </PERSON> said the <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> is taking steps to improve its efficiency. `` The current system for dealing with aviation issues is too slow and cumbersome,'' he said. The <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> has been criticized by some lawmakers in recent years for failing to move quickly enough to expand the number of air traffic controllers and for a lack of aggressiveness in making other safety improvements. Sen. <PERSON> Wendell </PERSON> <PERSON> Ford </PERSON>, D-Ky., chairman of the aviation panel, has introduced legislation that would make the <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> an independent agency in hopes of giving it the ability to respond more quickly to problems <ORGANIZATION> Burnley </ORGANIZATION> said the <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> could do a better job if its promotional duties and the air traffic control system were removed from its responsibilities. The agency should continue overseeing safety as a part of the <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, he said, so, `` If you do n't get what you want out of an administrator, there's a secretary you can collar.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880324-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-24-88 0214EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-US-Africa     03-24 0451</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-US-Africa,450</SECOND>
<HEAD>Officials Warn That U.S. Losing Ground Africa</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RUTH SINAI</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> is losing influence in <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> by letting its military aid to the continent drop to an unprecedented low while the Soviets provide 17 times as much assistance, administration officials say. <LOCATION> Sudan </LOCATION> has asked the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> to remove its emergency military stockpiles and facilities, and <LOCATION> Somalia </LOCATION> has rejected the visit of a top-level military delegation, the officials say. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military aid levels to <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> this year have dropped to an unprecedented low of $ 25.2 million, said Deputy Assistant Secretary of Defense <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Woods </PERSON>. `` We have since last year lost our prepositioning rights in one important African country, and have had important military'' negotiations canceled in another, <PERSON> Woods </PERSON> told the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> subcommittee on foreign operations Wednesday. Although he declined to name either country, another official who spoke only on condition he not be named identified the first country as <LOCATION> Sudan </LOCATION>. He said the non-aligned government of <PERSON> Sadiq </PERSON> <PERSON> Mahdi </PERSON> was unwilling to honor political arrangements made by his predecessor <PERSON> Gaafar </PERSON> <PERSON> Nimeiri </PERSON>, who was deposed in April 1985. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> relations with <LOCATION> Sudan </LOCATION>, strategically placed in eastern <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> on the <LOCATION> Red </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sea </LOCATION> coast, have been strained by <LOCATION> Sudan </LOCATION>'s warming ties with <LOCATION> Libya </LOCATION>. As a result of congressional budget cuts, as well as the less cordial ties with the <LOCATION> Khartoum </LOCATION> government, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military aid to <LOCATION> Sudan </LOCATION> was canceled in fiscal 1988, along with six other African countries. The administration will seek a renewal of the aid for fiscal 1989, said the official. <LOCATION> Somalia </LOCATION>, upset with a drop of its military aid to $ 5 million from some $ 20 million in 1986, rejected a visit by a high-level <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military delegation, the official said. But the visit will probably be rescheduled, he added. <PERSON> Woods </PERSON> warned that if the military aid for <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> remains at the current level, `` we can no longer operate a meaningful aid program to <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>.'' The administration has asked for $ 740 million in economic and development aid for <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> next year and $ 83.7 million in military assistance. Assistant Secretary of State <PERSON> Chester </PERSON> <PERSON> Crocker </PERSON> told the panel that `` the perception in <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> is that we're opting out. And that creates strains.'' <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military aid to <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> accounts for only 3 percent of the total military assistance to the continent, <PERSON> Crocker </PERSON> said. In contrast, the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> has poured $ 15 billion into African states since 1980, more than 17 times the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> input, he said. In addition, the Soviets maintain 6,500 military advisers in <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>, and <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> has some 45,000 troops there, most of them in <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION>. `` Properly funded, the -LRB- <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military aid -RRB- program reduces reliance on Soviet bloc hardware and advisers,'' <PERSON> Woods </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880324-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-24-88 2340EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Israel Bjt   03-24 0769</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Israel, Bjt,0791</SECOND>
<HEAD>Sharon Warns of War, Threatens Expulsions; Two Palestinians Killed</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAN IZENBERG</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>JERUSALEM (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Trade Minister <PERSON> Ariel </PERSON> <PERSON> Sharon </PERSON> warned that <LOCATION> Palestinian </LOCATION> violence could lead to war with neighboring <PERSON> Arab </PERSON> states, in which case <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> might expel Palestinians from its occupied lands and from <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> itself. He made the comment Thursday, when Israeli security forces shot and killed another two Palestinians and seven were reported wounded in clashes throughout the occupied <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION>. Israeli troops also rounded up hundreds of Arabs in an attempt to silence the leaders of the four-month uprising, <PERSON> Arab </PERSON> sources said. In <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> warplanes divebombed <LOCATION> Palestinian </LOCATION> guerrilla bases on the outskirts of <LOCATION> Sidon </LOCATION> for almost an hour, the second air raid in two days. <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> radio quoted Lebanese sources as saying 30 people were killed in the attack. Also Thursday, The Labor Party re-elected Foreign Minister <PERSON> Shimon </PERSON> <PERSON> Peres </PERSON> as its leader and candidate for the premiership. He said he would appeal to the nation to support the U.S.-initiated peace process _ in essence an exchange of land for peace with the Arabs. In the <LOCATION> Balata </LOCATION> refugee camp near <LOCATION> Nablus </LOCATION>, border policemen opened fire on demonstrators throwing rocks, concrete blocks and iron bars at them. Two protesters were killed, the army and the Israeli news agency <ORGANIZATION> Itim </ORGANIZATION> reported. A Palestinian was shot in the leg and three border policemen were injured by rocks in the clash, <ORGANIZATION> Itim </ORGANIZATION> reported. Thursday's fatalities raised the Palestinian death toll to 109 by <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> count since violence broke out in the occupied territories Dec. 8. One Israeli soldier has been killed. <PERSON> Sharon </PERSON> told journalists in <LOCATION> Tel </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Aviv </LOCATION> that, by failing to halt the disturbances at their onset, <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> had lost its deterrent capability. As a result, he said, <PERSON> Arab </PERSON> states could launch a surprise attack against <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>. The hawkish former general, a leader of the right-wing <ORGANIZATION> Likud </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bloc </ORGANIZATION>, hinted that in such a war, <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> might expel Palestinians and Israeli Arabs. <PERSON> Sharon </PERSON> referred to <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s first prime minister, <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Ben </PERSON> <PERSON> Gurion </PERSON>, saying <PERSON> Ben </PERSON> <PERSON> Gurion </PERSON> refused to allow Arabs who fled the country during the 1948 <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> war to return to their homes. `` The rule that <PERSON> Ben </PERSON> <PERSON> Gurion </PERSON> determined then applies now too,'' <PERSON> Sharon </PERSON> said. `` Those who began the war in December 1987 must remember that they are fully responsible for its results ... Remember this well, not just the residents of -LRB- the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> towns of -RRB- <LOCATION> Halhoul </LOCATION> and Qalqilyeh but also those of <LOCATION> Jaffa </LOCATION> -LRB- in <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> -RRB- and -LRB- Israeli-annexed Arab east -RRB- <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION>.'' <PERSON> Peres </PERSON>, who was re-elected by an overwhelming majority of the <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>'s 1,250-member <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, accused the <ORGANIZATION> Likud </ORGANIZATION> of frightening the nation into believing yielding occupied territories would threaten <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s existence. `` We will opt for a political solution,'' he said. `` The camp of intimidation rejects any political solution. The camp of hope believes in such a solution.'' Speaking at the same party gathering, Defense Minister <PERSON> Yitzhak </PERSON> <PERSON> Rabin </PERSON> said: `` Peace is a more central element of security than -LRB- occupied -RRB- territories.'' In other developments Thursday, <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> troops converted <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> schools into detention centers as they continued a campaign of mass arrests in the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strip </LOCATION>, which <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> seized in the 1967 <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> war. Among those detained in the overnight roundups Thursday were several Palestinians allegedly responsible for drafting and publishing the latest underground leaflets, police ministry spokesman <PERSON> Nahum </PERSON> <PERSON> Mendel </PERSON> said. He declined to say how many suspects were arrested. In the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> city of <LOCATION> Hebron </LOCATION>, an Islamic official said <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> troops detained about 200 Imams, or Moslem relgious leaders, in nighttime roundups this week. The official, who spoke on condition of anonymity, said most of those held were members of the fundamentalist Islamic Jihad movment. In <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> officials rounded up at least 15 Palestinians Wednesday night, bringing to more than 110 the number of Arabs arrested there in the last four days, the <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> lawyers' association said. Meanwhile, the Roman Catholic Patriarch of <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION> decided to suspend the Palm Sunday procession because of the possibility of violence along its narrow, winding route through <LOCATION> Arab </LOCATION> <LOCATION> east </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION>, said the Rev. <PERSON> Caudio </PERSON> <PERSON> Baratto </PERSON>, director of the <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Information </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>. In another development, the government temporarily banned publication of <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> daily, <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> Ittihad </PERSON>. <PERSON> Amos </PERSON> <PERSON> Gilboa </PERSON>, Prime Minister <PERSON> Yitzhak </PERSON> <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON>'s adviser on Arab affairs, said the 40-year-old newpaper's `` statements had become far more extreme ... and completely changed in character,'' since the anti-occupation unrest began. The <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> has four representatives in parliament. It has organized demonstrations and protests against <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s handling of the unrest and in favor of a <LOCATION> Palestinian </LOCATION> state to replace the occupied territories' military government.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880324-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-24-88 2341EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-China-Train     03-24 0420</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-China-Train,0434</SECOND>
<HEAD>Trains Collide In China; 27 Dead</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Two passenger trains collided Thursday in a <LOCATION> Shanghai </LOCATION> suburb, killing 27 Japanese students on a school trip, the Japanese Embassy said. Other reports said more than 100 other people were injured. <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s official <ORGANIZATION> Xinhua </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> said one of the trains had ignored a stop signal when it left <LOCATION> Shanghai </LOCATION> station. There were discrepancies in death and injury reports. Foreign Ministry officials in <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION>, citing reports from the Japanese Consulate in <LOCATION> Shanghai </LOCATION>, said the death toll of 27 included a victim that was possibly Chinese. A total of 47 Japanese and 57 Chinese passengers were injured in the crash, government officials in <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION> said. <PERSON> Shigekazu </PERSON> <PERSON> Sato </PERSON>, an official with the <ORGANIZATION> Japanese </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>, said the injured included 36 people from <ORGANIZATION> Gakugei </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> High </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> in southern <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Kochi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Prefecture </LOCATION>. The crash, in the <LOCATION> Shanghai </LOCATION> suburb of <LOCATION> Fengbang </LOCATION>, occurred at 2 p.m. when a northbound train leaving <LOCATION> Shanghai </LOCATION> for <LOCATION> Hangzhou </LOCATION> collided with a southbound train arriving from <LOCATION> Changsha </LOCATION>, said <PERSON> Fu </PERSON> <PERSON> Fenghao </PERSON>, spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> Shanghai </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Affairs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Fu </PERSON> said it had not been determined if there were other foreigners on the train. The departing train's first two cars and the luggage car of the other train were knocked off the tracks. Most of the victims appeared to be in the first cars of the departing train, <PERSON> Fu </PERSON> said. <ORGANIZATION> Xinhua </ORGANIZATION> said the departing train `` rolled out of the <LOCATION> Kuangxiang </LOCATION> station, ignoring the prohibiting signal, and collided with the train that was entering the station.'' <PERSON> Kazuyoshi </PERSON> <PERSON> Shoji </PERSON> at the Japanese Consulate in <LOCATION> Shanghai </LOCATION> said one of the dead Japanese was <PERSON> Hideo </PERSON> <PERSON> Shimomura </PERSON>, identified by television stations in <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION> as a 16-year-old student. The 193-member <ORGANIZATION> Gakugei </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> High </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> group was traveling on the Hangzhou-bound train. <PERSON> Shoji </PERSON> said the group was in the car immediately behind the engine. `` We were playing cards and suddenly there was a loud bang, and things went flying all over the floor,'' said an unidentified male student interviewed in <LOCATION> Shanghai </LOCATION> by the <ORGANIZATION> Japan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Broadcasting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> `` There was a huge bump, and then one of our teachers came into the car and told us to get out,'' said another student. `` We broke the windows and climbed out.'' The train tracks were blocked seven hours after the accident, <PERSON> Fu </PERSON> said. He said soldiers, police and medical workers took the dead and injured to nearby hospitals and that investigators were at the scene. It was <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s fourth fatal train accident this year. Three train accidents killed 141 people in January.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880324-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-24-88 0714EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Budget Bjt   03-24 0677</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Budget, Bjt,680</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bipartisan House Sends Senate $1.1 Trillion Budget</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ALAN FRAM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Lawmakers are crediting the budget summit accord between congressional leaders and the White House for the bipartisan ease with which the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> sent a $ 1.1 trillion budget for fiscal 1989 to the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>. The spending plan, which alters some of the domestic priorities President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> had included in his own proposed package last month, was approved 319-102 on Wednesday by the Democratic-controlled House. In contrast to last year, when budget writers toiled several weeks longer amid staunch opposition by Republicans, <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> lawmakers this time voted 92-78 for the resolution. `` I think it would have been impossible without the summit,'' Rep. <PERSON> Delbert </PERSON> <PERSON> Latta </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, ranking Republican on the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Budget </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, said afterward. `` Democrats and Republicans in the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> are trying to work together,'' said Rep. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gray </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>, D-Pa., chairman of the budget panel The spending plan would produce a deficit of $ 134 billion. It would thus avoid spending cuts that would be required under the Gramm-Rudman balanced-budget law should the deficit miss the 1989 deficit target of $ 136 billion by more than $ 10 billion. To achieve that $ 134 billion figure, however, lawmakers agreed to use economic forecasts made by the administration. Had the legislators used the more pessimistic projections from their own <ORGANIZATION> Congressional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Budget </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION>, there would be $ 35 billion more in red ink, triggering spending slashes that are considered particularly untidy in an election year. Shortly after the Dow Jones Industrial Average plunged 508 points last Oct. 19, administration officials and congressional leaders held four weeks of closed-door bargaining aimed at slashing the federal deficit. The pact they emerged with last Nov. 20 set broad outlines for federal budgets for fiscal 1988, which ends Sept. 30, and for fiscal 1989. Their agreement settled in advance many of the disputes that typically spawn bitter, long-running debates among lawmakers, such as over how much money the government should spend for defense, domestic and foreign assistance programs, and whether new taxes are necessary. The 1989 budget resolution approved by the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> precisely met those summit targets, according to budget committee numbers. Thus, the package provides $ 299.5 billion for the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> in budget authority, the amount up to which the military can commit itself in new contracts, and $ 294 billion in outlays, or money to actually be spent next year. In addition, it provides $ 148.1 billion in budget authority and $ 169.2 billion in outlays for domestic programs that are not controlled by automatic formulas. And it allows $ 18.1 billion in budget authority and $ 16.1 billion in outlays for foreign aid. The $ 14 billion in new 1989 taxes called for by the summit have already been enacted into law. Lawmakers envision no additional taxes for the year. The budget would grant a hefty increase to space and science programs, although only about half as much as <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> wanted. It would also grant major increases in spending for education, the homeless, battling drugs and research and testing for AIDS. The legislators ignored <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s proposals to end federal assistance to <ORGANIZATION> Amtrak </ORGANIZATION>, the Northeast passenger railroad, and to some development programs, and his effort to dramatically slash aid to mass transit programs. Most federal agencies would be given a bit less money than they would need to keep up with inflation. But many urban and rural aid programs such as the Farmers Home Administration's rural development grants and loans, which <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> had slated for substantial cuts, would receive the same amounts of money as this year. And many programs geared toward helping low-income people, such as job training, would receive enough money to keep up with the rising cost of living. Military and civilian federal employees would be granted 3 percent pay raises. The budget resolution does not require presidential approval and sets spending targets. The actual money will have to be provided in later legislation. <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Majority Leader <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON>, D-W. <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, said Wednesday he did not expect full <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> action on the budget before the second week of
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880324-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-24-88 0233EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-SuperCollider     03-24 0325</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Super Collider,320</SECOND>
<HEAD>Backers Scaling Back Super Collider Funding Request</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TIM BOVEE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Representatives of states vying for the superconducting super collider are seeking only about one-third of the funding initially planned for the project next year, in what they describe as a bow to political reality. Rep. <PERSON> Carl </PERSON> <PERSON> Pursell </PERSON>, R-Mich., said Wednesday that lawmakers from six of the seven states still in the running for the $ 4.4 billion physics research complex agreed to press for around one-third of the $ 363 million requested by President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> in his 1989 budget Representatives from the seven states formed a task force last week to support the project, which has been attacked by congressional critics as likely to siphon away money needed for research in other areas. The dispute comes as both <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and the White House are trying to reduce the federal budget deficit. During a private meeting, the representatives discussed funding `` somewhere around the bottom of $ 100 million plus,'' <PERSON> Pursell </PERSON> said. `` We have not fixed on exact figures.'' They also discussed target dates in their drive to ensure that the project survives congressional budget cuts, <PERSON> Pursell </PERSON> said. `` As long as we've got good support from the leadership, we're sure we can get through the budget process,'' <PERSON> Pursell </PERSON> said The representatives will meet soon with <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Speaker <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> and <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Minority Leader <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Michel </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> to discuss appropriations, <PERSON> Pursell </PERSON> said. Officials have predicted that the super collider, centered on a 53-mile-round particle accelerator, will produce 4,000 jobs and have an annual operating budget of about $ 280 million. Physicists at the center will study subatomic particles and the physical nature of the universe. States that remain in the running for the project are <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION> was unrepresented at Wednesday's meeting, <PERSON> Pursell </PERSON> said. The <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> has said it plans to decide in November where to build the super collider.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880324-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-24-88 0233EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Vietnam-Congress     03-24 0406</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Vietnam-Congress,420</SECOND>
<HEAD>Administration Opposes Greater Contact with Vietnam</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JEFF BARKER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration is resisting calls to raise the level of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> diplomatic contact with <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>, saying it wants to maintain pressure on the Vietnamese to withdraw their troops from <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION>. Sen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> McCain </PERSON>, R-Ariz., and Rep. <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Ridge </PERSON>, R-Pa., on Wednesday called for the establishment of a `` working <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> presence'' in They said little progress has been made on numerous issues which remain as the `` legacy'' of the Vietnam War, despite numerous visits to <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> by congressional and administration delegations. The administration, however, said it opposed the lawmakers' call for the creation of `` interest sections,'' which are typically established between nations that do n't recognize each other but acknowledge mutual concerns. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION>, for example, have interest section personnel stationed in third-party embassies in each others' nations `` We continue to believe that political and economic isolation is the most effective way of pressing <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> to end its occupation of <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION>,'' the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> said in a statement released Wednedsay. `` We are prepared to discuss normalization with <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>, therefore, only in the context of an acceptable settlement in <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION> which includes the withdrawal of Vietnamese troops,'' it said. <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>'s military occupation of <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION> is in its ninth year. <PERSON> McCain </PERSON> and Ridge are both <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> veterans and <PERSON> McCain </PERSON> is a former prisoner of war. They issued their call for greater diplomatic contact with <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> on the 15th anniversary of <PERSON> McCain </PERSON>'s release after five years of captivity <PERSON> McCain </PERSON> said establishment of interest sections `` falls far short of diplomatic recognition, and certainly implies no approval of a nation's policies.'' He said that if no progress is made on issues such as Americans still listed as missing from the Southeast Asian conflict, then `` the option of further normalization'' could always be set aside. <PERSON> McCain </PERSON> said several members of the administration had indicated privately that they supported better communication between the nations, but that he expected that the administration's `` official'' position on <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> would remain the same <PERSON> McCain </PERSON> and <PERSON> Ridge </PERSON> said greater contact also is needed to administer a two-year program to bring 8,000 to 12,000 children of <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> soldiers to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. `` There is a tremendous logistical problem and barrier to progress, just by the fact that all of our technical people must travel in and out of <LOCATION> Bangkok </LOCATION> every time there is to be communication,'' <PERSON> Ridge </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880324-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-24-88 0235EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-TongassForest     03-24 0550</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Tongass Forest,540</SECOND>
<HEAD>Congress Moving to Cut Timbering in Alaska Rain Forest</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID GOELLER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Interior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> is chopping away at the huge timber harvests in <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Tongass </ORGANIZATION> rain forest, the nation's largest national forest and the timber cutting programs's biggest money loser The panel gave voice vote approval Wednesday to legislation pushed by hard-lobbying conservation groups to scrap the 1980 law guaranteeing that the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> gets at least $ 40 million a year to spend on Tongass timber sales. The money, much of it for logging roads to ancient stands of huge trees, was mandated as part of the compromise that apportioned public lands in <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> for various uses, including commercial development and wilderness. The compromise gave protected wilderness status to 5.4 million acres of the 17.9 million acre <ORGANIZATION> Tongass </ORGANIZATION>, which has the nation's largest populations of bald eagles and grizzly bears The 1980 law, in what backers said represented economic guarantees for southeast <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>, set a goal of commercially harvesting 450 billion board feet of Tongass trees every 10 years from non-wilderness sections. No other national forest has a congressionally mandated harvest goal or gets its appropriations without the year-by-year review <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> gives to spending requests for other federal forests. Rep. <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Vento </PERSON>, D-Minn., said that because of low demand and falling prices for wood pulp from <ORGANIZATION> Tongass </ORGANIZATION>, taxpayers have lost 99 cents for each $ 1 in sales, with some old trees going for $ 2 apiece <PERSON> Vento </PERSON> called the 1980 law `` a mandate to overcut ... one of the world's only temperate rain forests.'' `` We're changing the entire environment when we cut 400 - and 500-year-old trees,'' he said Approved by the committee was a package put together by Rep. <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Miller </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Calif </LOCATION>., to scrap the 1980 timbering guarantees and assure that the Tongass is subject to the same timber-harvest planning practices applied to all other national forests The bill would put a five-year moratorium on commercial logging in about 1.7 million acres considered by the <ORGANIZATION> Southeast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Alaska </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conservation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> to be prime fish and wildlife habitat threatened by timbering. <PERSON> Miller </PERSON>'s plan also would require the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> to renegotiate its long-term contracts to supply Tongass timber to two large mills owned by <ORGANIZATION> Louisiana </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pacific-Ketchikan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Alaska </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pulp </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>. About two-thirds of the Tongass production goes to these mills, which convert it to pulp, principally for export to <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> Critics say the 50-year contracts, executed in the 1950s, give the companies a regional monopoly and too large a voice in <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> management decisions for the Tongass. <PERSON> Miller </PERSON> said the Tongass now is `` almost a scandalous operation.'' `` We have a process that is not driven by rational forest management,'' he said. `` We have cuttings driven by a political bargain.'' <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Young </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>'s only <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> member and the ranking Republican on <ORGANIZATION> Interior </ORGANIZATION>, opposed <PERSON> Miller </PERSON>'s plan because `` it basically shuts down the mills. ... We're talking about 6,000 jobs.'' <PERSON> Young </PERSON> said the committee was being unduly influenced by conservation groups such as the <ORGANIZATION> Wilderness </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Sierra </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Club </ORGANIZATION>, which have made the <ORGANIZATION> Tongass </ORGANIZATION> and a proposal to drill for oil in the <ORGANIZATION> Arctic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wildlife </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Refuge </ORGANIZATION> their major Capitol Hill battlegrounds in 1988. Young called the environmental groups `` special interests'' and said, `` The national environmental community is jerking our string.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880324-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-24-88 0236EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Koop-Aging     03-24 0416</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Koop-Aging,400</SECOND>
<HEAD>Surgeon General Says Old Age Should No Longer Mean Poor Health</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JERRY ESTILL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Surgeon General <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Everett </PERSON> <PERSON> Koop </PERSON> says old people do n't have to suffer poor health just because they're old. `` The whole theme of this meeting is it's never too late to start prevention,'' <PERSON> Koop </PERSON> said Wednesday at the close of a three-day workshop on health promotion and aging. How do older people maximize their health? The same way younger people do, said <PERSON> Koop </PERSON>: do n't smoke, do n't drink too much, rest, eat right and exercise. `` Old age is not a disease and there are many oldsters who are disease free,'' said <PERSON> Koop </PERSON>. `` You do n't necessarily have to have your kidneys fail, you do n't necessarily have to have dementia. ... My plea would be to separate old age and disease. They do n't necessarily go together. Smoking is a prime example of the never-too-late approach, said <PERSON> Koop </PERSON>. `` There is a tremendous tendency on the part of physicians to say, ` Well he's over 65, he has n't got many vices, has n't got many years left, why bother the poor old fellow?''' he said. `` But if they would just look him straight in the eye and say, ` You're not going to live as long or have as good a quality of life as if you stop smoking,' if he stops he will note an immediate benefit.'' <PERSON> Koop </PERSON>, 71, said he is convinced older people will shift to healthier diets and exercise more if properly counseled by their doctors. `` I do think you can change a person's behavior,'' he said. `` If somebody is willing to look at him from a bird's - eye view and try to rearrange his life and point out how he could do these things and what the benefits would be, people listen and they Even though the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> population is aging, he said, it is not becoming less healthy. `` As we see people who are now in middle-age come along into the graying years they are going to be far healthier than this generation was when it entered the 65-and-older group,'' he said. `` These are the people who are jogging and swimming and hiking. These are the people who are snacking on salad and yogurt. These are the people who are wearing sensible shoes. They have stopped smoking. They have given up hard liquor. They wear seat belts. They understand the things they can do to preserve the quality of life and the function they already have.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880324-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-24-88 0236EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Orchestra-Baseball     03-24 0340</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Orchestra-Baseball,330</SECOND>
<HEAD>European Symphony to Play at Baseball Game</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CARL HARTMAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Brahms </PERSON> and <PERSON> Berlioz </PERSON> will be featured in the concert halls, but the <ORGANIZATION> European </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Community </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Youth </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Orchestra </ORGANIZATION> has also been asked to belt out the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and Canadian anthems at a baseball game between the <ORGANIZATION> Atlanta </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Braves </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Montreal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Expos </ORGANIZATION>. The orchestra's brass ensemble is scheduled to play at an exhibition game March 31 at Municipal Stadium in <LOCATION> Palm </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla </LOCATION>. The orchestra's 140 musicians, aged 14 to 23, come from all 12 countries of the European Community: <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Denmark </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Belgium </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Holland </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Luxembourg </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Portugal </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Greece </LOCATION>. For the orchestra's 10th anniversary, it is making its first tour of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, arriving from <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Palm </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION> on Monday. `` They've asked us to send the brass ensemble for the game,'' explained Boston-born <PERSON> Joy </PERSON> <PERSON> Bryer </PERSON>, the orchestra's secretary general. She has lived in <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> for 31 years. `` We've mailed the scores to them all around <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>. They do n't know anything about <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> but what they see on television Now they'll be finding out more for themselves.'' The brass section consists of 20 instruments _ trumpets, French horns and others that furnish a maximum of volume. Mrs. <PERSON> Bryer </PERSON> gave reporters details about the trip on Wednesday in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. During its stay in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>, the orchestra will also send groups to schools, hospitals and a community center at <LOCATION> Belle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Glade </LOCATION> on <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Okeechobee </LOCATION>, where the audience will be mostly migrant farm workers. Its first formal concert will be on April 10 in the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Palm </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Auditorium </LOCATION>. Later concerts will be at <LOCATION> Clearwater </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>, April 11; <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>'s <PERSON> Avery </PERSON> <PERSON> Fisher </PERSON> <PERSON> Hall </PERSON> on April 13; <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>'s Symphony Hall on April 15; and a final performance at the <ORGANIZATION> Kennedy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Concert </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hall </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> on April 17. The conductor will be <PERSON> Erich </PERSON> <PERSON> Leinsdorf </PERSON>. Part of the proceeds will go to anti-drug efforts and to Very Special Arts, the fund set up by violinist <PERSON> Itzhak </PERSON> <PERSON> Perlman </PERSON> to help handicapped musical students.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880324-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-24-88 0237EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-NorthRetire     03-24 0519</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-North Retire,520</SECOND>
<HEAD>North to Receive Full Military Retirement Benefits</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Iran-Contra Arraignment Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By NORMAN BLACK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Lt. Col. <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> <PERSON> North </PERSON> is beginning his retirement with more notoriety than most officers, but he is still entitled to the same benefits as any of the other more than 1.5 million men and women drawing military pensions. North, the former national security aide who was indicted last week in the Iran-Contra affair, announced two days later he had decided to retire on May 1 from the <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corps </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> North </PERSON> said he was taking the step because he would probably have to subpoena high-ranking government officials to mount his legal defense and did n't want to do so as a military officer. By specifying a May 1 retirement _ a request that has been approved _ North will have completed the minimum 20 years of active duty required to retire with a pension. Unless an officer has served 20 years, he is not eligible to receive any type of pension. Starting at 20 years of service, the size of the pension for officers of <LOCATION> North </LOCATION>'s age is computed on a rising scale _ going from 50 percent of basic pay up to 75 percent of basic pay after 30 years' service. In North's case, the lieutenant colonel is drawing $ 3,693.60 in basic pay a month, or $ 44,323.20 a year. With exactly 20 years of service, he will be entitled to 50 percent of that as a pension payment. North's former boss, Rear Adm. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Poindexter </PERSON>, retired in December with more than 29 years of service and is drawing a pension of more than $ 52,700 a year. North will have to pay federal income tax on his pension payments. But unless he goes back to work for the federal government, he's free to collect his military pension without limit for the rest of his life. Like his other former brothers in arms, <PERSON> North </PERSON> also will be eligible for a number of other benefits to help ease his entry into private life. For example, if he wants to continue shopping at a military commissary or exchange, he'll have that right. The former <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> will also be able to relax at military officer clubs, use military recreation facilities and read books at military libraries. If he wants to shop for liquor at a military package store or take in a movie at a theater on base, he can do that, too. And he can also drop off his laundry at a base dry cleaning store or buy new clothing. As a retired officer, <PERSON> North </PERSON> also is provided the right to medical care at a military hospital, but only on a space-available basis. Active-duty servicemen are given first priority. If he ca n't gain admission to a military hospital, <PERSON> North </PERSON> will be covered by the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> CHAMPUS </ORGANIZATION> health insurance plan. When he uses a private hospital and CHAMPUS, however, he'll have to pay an annual deductible and 25 percent of his bill. As a retired officer drawing a pension, <PERSON> North </PERSON> also will be eligible for burial in a national cemetery.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880324-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-24-88 0239EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Scotus-FoodStamps     03-24 0468</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Scotus-Food Stamps,460</SECOND>
<BYLINE>UAW Says Ruling Allows ``Economic Warfare Against Working People.''
^By RICHARD CARELLI</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Auto </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Workers </ORGANIZATION> President <PERSON> Owen </PERSON> <PERSON> Bieber </PERSON> says the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> dealt a `` blow to working families throughout <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'' by upholding a law limiting food-stamp eligibility for striking workers. The high court said Wednesday a 1981 federal law imposing food stamp limits on strikers' families does not violate any constitutional rights. The 1981 law, amending the Food Stamp Act, generally bars a family from becoming eligible for food stamps at a time when one of its members is on strike. Families already receiving food stamps when a member goes on strike are not dropped from the program but are barred from receiving additional food stamps despite the loss of income. The law was challenged by the <ORGANIZATION> UAW </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Workers </ORGANIZATION>, and some of the unions' members. They said the law violated strikers' freedom of association and speech, and denied equal protection to strikers' families. The court, by a 5-3 vote, disagreed. <PERSON> Bieber </PERSON> said Wednesday's ruling `` serves only the interest of those who wage economic warfare against working people.'' He added, `` In a democracy which affords its citizens the legal right to form trade unions and engage in peaceful strikes, it is hypocritcal and inconsistent to punish the family members of those who choose to exercise that right.'' Writing for the court, Justice <PERSON> Byron </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> White </PERSON> said: `` Union strike funds should be responsible for providing support and benefits to strikers during labor-management disputes. It was no part of the purposes of the Food Stamp Act to establish a program that would serve as a weapon in labor disputes.'' But Justice <PERSON> Thurgood </PERSON> <PERSON> Marshall </PERSON> contended in a dissenting opinion that the 1981 law amounted to such a `` weapon'' for management. `` No other purpose can adequately explain the especially harsh treatment reserved for strikers and their families by the 1981 enactment,'' <PERSON> Marshall </PERSON> said. The Food Stamp Act generally excludes benefits for people, and the households of people, unwilling to work. But <PERSON> Marshall </PERSON> noted that people who can prove they quit their jobs for `` good cause'' may collect food stamps if otherwise eligible _ while strikers may not. White was joined in upholding the law by Chief Justice <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Rehnquist </PERSON> and Justices <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Stevens </PERSON>, <PERSON> Sandra </PERSON> <PERSON> Day </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Connor </PERSON> and <PERSON> Antonin </PERSON> <PERSON> Scalia </PERSON>. Justices <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Brennan </PERSON> and <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Blackmun </PERSON> joined <PERSON> Marshall </PERSON>'s dissenting opinion. Justice <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> did not participate in the decision. The nation's food stamp program, paid for by the federal government and administered by the states, has supplemented the food-buying power of millions of low-income families since 1964. Participating households receive food stamp coupons that can be used for food purchases at retail stores. Eligibility for food stamps is based on income and several other factors.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880324-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-24-88 0240EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FarmScene     03-24 0698</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Farm Scene,690</SECOND>
<HEAD>Soviet Grain Harvest Up, But Quality Poor, U.S. Officials Say</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DON KENDALL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Farm Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Two <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> economists say the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>'s agriculture is still in trouble, despite a couple of back-to-back bumper grain harvests. At the request of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, the Soviets opened talks here last weekend on a new long-term grain agreement to replace the current pact which expires on Sept. 30. The agreement commits <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> to buy at least a specified minimum amount of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> grain each year. The preliminary one-day session was adjourned without anything conclusive announced or any indication as to when and where the negotiations would be resumed. But <PERSON> Chris </PERSON> <PERSON> Foster </PERSON> and <PERSON> Ed </PERSON> <PERSON> Cook </PERSON> of the department's <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> note that the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> `` does n't always meet the provisions of the agreement'' by failing to buy the specified minimum amounts. Last year's total Soviet grain harvest was 211.3 million metric tons, up slightly from 210.1 million tons in 1986, the first time that two consecutive grain crops of more than 200 million tons have been produced by the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. However, <PERSON> Foster </PERSON> noted that last year's Soviet harvest was of `` poor quality and contained above-average amounts of moisture.'' <PERSON> Cook </PERSON> said <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> agriculture still has many basic inefficiencies and that Soviet leader <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> has had only slight success so far in his efforts to reform his country's agriculture. `` <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> seems now to be taking a less radical approach to agricultural reform than was anticipated a year ago,'' <PERSON> Cook </PERSON> said. There has not been a dramatic shift toward a `` market economy'' and the promised increases in local autonomy for farm managers has been slow to materialize. Rather, <PERSON> Cook </PERSON> added, `` The focus now seems to be on making adjustments to the traditional system.'' <PERSON> Cook </PERSON>, whose comments appear with <PERSON> Foster </PERSON>'s in a forthcoming issue of <LOCATION> Farmline </LOCATION> magazine, said the Soviet system historically has been hampered by a lack of incentives and authority for farm workers and managers. Policies have been decreed from above, with little reward for greater efficiency. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s reforms `` have succeeded somewhat in reducing paperwork associated with agriculture, but incentives and autonomy remain inadequate by our standards,'' <PERSON> Cook </PERSON> said. In the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, money is still taken from profitable farms and given to unprofitable farms, in part to even out differences in farm wages, he said. Large disparities in income are avoided, but there is little incentive to make a farm more profitable.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Agriculture Department on-site reviews of <ORGANIZATION> Farmers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Home </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> operations in <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> have turned up sex discrimination and severe shortcomings in the hiring of blacks and Hispanics in agency offices. `` The prevailing view expressed by female employees during interviews is that sex discimination often enters into employment decisions,'' the report said Wednesday. `` This perception is corroborated by the number of sex discrimination complaints lodged and by the lack of women in higher graded positions.'' The review was made last year under the <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION>'s Equal Employment Opportunity -LRB- EEO -RRB- program, which calls for compliance checks of several department agencies in various states, including <ORGANIZATION> FmHA </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Soil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conservation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Agricultural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Stabilization </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conservation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>. Reports on the reviews have been released periodically by the department's <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Advocacy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Enterprise </ORGANIZATION>. In addition, the <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> office released a number of reports on civil rights compliance by the agencies in <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION>. In each case, the on-site review found the operations `` generally in compliance'' with civil rights requirments and regulations. However, most of the civil rights reports noted numerous deficiencies in the employment of women and minorities, and shortcomings in outreach programs.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A study of last year's wheat quality showed that 76 percent of the hard red winter wheat samples graded No. 1 or No. 2, compared with 70 percent in 1986, the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> says. For hard red spring wheat, 75 percent graded No. 1, compared with 70 percent in 1986, the department's <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Grain </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inspection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> said Wednesday. The annual survey involved 12,739 wheat samples from the 1987 crop, said <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kirk </PERSON> <PERSON> Miller </PERSON>, administrator of the agency. The samples were taken during the first four weeks following local harvests around the country.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880324-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-24-88 0714EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-TreasuryAuction     03-24 0101</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Treasury Auction,110</SECOND>
<HEAD>Yields Up on Two-Year Treasury Notes</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Yields on two-year <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> notes have risen in the government's latest auction to the highest level in two months. The average yield in Wednesday's auction was 7.39 percent, up from 7.16 percent at the last auction on Feb. 24. It was the highest rate since two-year notes averaged 7.4 percent on Jan. 27. The notes will carry a coupon interest rate of 7 -RRB- percent, with each $ 10,000 in face value selling for $ 9,997.30. A total of $ 8.53 billion in notes were sold out of bids totaling $ 25.08 billion.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880324-0025 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-24-88 0241EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Scotus-Workers     03-24 0503</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Scotus-Workers,490</SECOND>
<HEAD>Court Reviews Federal-State Roles in Protecting Fired Workers</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID FOX</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
