<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880902-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-02-88 2337EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-ForestFiresRdp 3rdLd-Writethru a0773 09-02 1027</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Forest Fires Rdp, 3rd Ld - Writethru, a0773,1045</SECOND>
<HEAD>Firefighters Work To Protect Montana Town</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Leads with 15 grafs with fire kept out of West Yellowstone,
picking up 15th graf pvs, `I'm packed ...;' SUBS 24th and 25th
graf, `By Friday...' to UPDATE with all California fires under
control or contained and changes evacuated houses in Utah to some
sted 15.
^LaserPhotos CKCX1, XYS3</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By ROGER PETTERSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Firefighters declared a temporary victory Friday in their battle to keep a forest fire out of a small <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION> town, and forest officials warned that more lightning and dry, hot weather were forecast this weekend. `` It's like sitting on a time bomb,'' said <PERSON> Scott </PERSON> <PERSON> Phillips </PERSON>, recreation officer for the <ORGANIZATION> Sawtooth </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Recreation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Area </ORGANIZATION> in central <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION>. `` If we can get through this weekend without a conflagration, it will be a miracle.'' Forests and rangeland burned Friday in parts of <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION>, especially in <ORGANIZATION> Yellowstone </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Park </ORGANIZATION>, and in <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> Boise </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Interagency </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fire </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>, the logistics command for the national battle against forest fires, reported more than 25,000 firefighters, military and support personnel on the lines of more than three dozen major fires in the West. Fire Center spokesman <PERSON> Arnold </PERSON> <PERSON> Hartigan </PERSON> called it `` the most severe fire season in almost 30 years.'' More than 3.5 million acres have burned, two-thirds of that in <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>, and suppression costs already exceed $ 250 million. `` The fire season is anything but over. ... The 30-day weather forecast calls for continued unseasonably hot and dry weather for the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Northwest </LOCATION> and northern Rockies,'' <PERSON> Hartigan </PERSON> said. Record highs were forecast during the weekend in <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, with a threat of lightning. <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> officials asked people to stay out of forests in central <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION> and restrictions on such things as open campfires were tightened in <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. Many forests in <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION> were closed to recreational use. Logging activity was shut down statewide in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, on public and private land, because of fire concern. The <ORGANIZATION> Weyerhaeuser </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> closed all its timberlands to public access until further notice. The focus of attention Friday in and around <LOCATION> Yellowstone </LOCATION>, where some 550,000 acres have been charred, was the small town of <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Yellowstone </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mont. </LOCATION>, just outside the park's west entrance. It was threatened by flames just over a mile away that were spreading from the 118,000-acre North Fork fire inside the park that had grown by nearly 10,000 acres since Thursday morning. Bulldozers, helicopters and back fires stalled the advance of the fire Friday. But gusty winds swept a swath of flame south of the town and a wind change predicted for Monday raised concerns the blaze could move back toward the community. `` In my judgment this community is very defensible,'' <PERSON> Denny </PERSON> <PERSON> Bungartz </PERSON>, the North Fork fire's incident commander, told about 60 townspeople. He said firetrucks had pumped 5,000 gallons of water into dry brush around a warehouse at the park boundary, and 50 fire engines would be in town during the night to hose down buildings if necessary. To the east and north of town, the <LOCATION> Madison </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> formed a natural fire break. Firefighters improved on that barrier by bulldozing fire lines and lighting backfires, exhausting the forest's fuel before the main fire could reach the river, as helicopters dropped water on the area. Residents of the small town, with a year-round population of 750, prepared to evacuate but most stayed put Friday. Most of the people leaving town were tourists who decided to spend their Labor Day weekend somewhere less smoky. Curious onlookers filled the streets Friday as afternoon winds blew away the smoky haze. `` I'm packed up and ready to go,'' said <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Powell </PERSON>, owner of a hamburger stand downtown. `` I left <LOCATION> L.A </LOCATION> because I could n't stand the smog. I do n't like this stuff.'' Some people were driving in the other direction, because West Yellowstone will play host to hundreds of square dancers this weekend for the Knothead Jamboree. Resident dance caller <PERSON> Orvile </PERSON> <PERSON> Pittam </PERSON> says it's been sponsored by square dance groups in <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION> every Labor Day weekend for 37 years and attracts up to 800 people. <PERSON> Ken </PERSON> <PERSON> Takata </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> West </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Yellowstone </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chamber </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> president, said that while there have been some cancellations because of the fires, it's too early to tell what the overall effect will be. `` We want people to know that right now conditions are pretty good,'' he said Friday. `` We've had some bad press that <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Yellowstone </LOCATION> is being evacuated, and that's just not the case. We hope it will be business as usual.'' Elsewhere in <LOCATION> Yellowstone </LOCATION>, the Clover Mist fire had covered 232,400 acres after growing 1,000 acres in 24 hours, the <LOCATION> Snake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> complex of fires was stable at about 156,500 acres and the <LOCATION> Wolf </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> fire grew slightly to 40,500 acres, said fire information officer <PERSON> Brian </PERSON> <PERSON> Morris </PERSON>. North of <LOCATION> Yellowstone </LOCATION> in south-central <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION>, firefighters in the Absaroka-Beartooth Wilderness changed their tactics Friday on a 49,800-acre wilderness fire that jumped fire lines four days in a row. Fire information officer <PERSON> Chris </PERSON> <PERSON> Comstock </PERSON> said Friday that officals changed their strategy from building fire lines to setting backfires because `` our method of approach right now has n't been effective in catching this fire.'' Fire bosses in <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION> used a second day of light wind to gain more ground against the worst of <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION>'s 17 wildfires, with more than 3,000 firefighter and support personnel still battling fires that had burned more than 75,000 acres. Only the 40,300-acre Tepee Butte fire remained out of control in <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION>, in the <ORGANIZATION> Wallowa-Whitman </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> and the Hell's <ORGANIZATION> Canyon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Recreation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Area </ORGANIZATION> It was 25 percent contained Friday, officials said. By Friday, fires that raged through tinder-dry <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> forests were dying down, with all reported contained or under control. A new forest fire near <LOCATION> Salt </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> forced the evacuation of a few homes on Friday. The state's largest fire was a 2,000-acre blaze fanned by ridgetop winds near northern <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION>'s Pineview Reservoir. The fire was initially declared under control late Tuesday at 525 acres but roared to life again late Wednesday when gusts fanned hot spots and pushed flames over fire lines.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880902-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-02-88 2344EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-GovernmentWhistleblower     09-02 0369</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Government Whistleblower,320</SECOND>
<HEAD>Ex-Government Whistleblower Awarded $560,000 in Settlement</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The federal government has agreed to pay $ 560,000 to settle its dispute with a senior employee who was fired five years ago after warning of hazardous conditions in major government buildings, his attorney said late Friday. The <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> agreed to the payment to settle its dispute with <PERSON> Bertrand </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Berube </PERSON>, with the bulk of the money representing back pay and interest, said <PERSON> Louis </PERSON> <PERSON> Clark </PERSON>, an attorney for <PERSON> Berube </PERSON> and director of the Government Accountability Project. The <ORGANIZATION> GSA </ORGANIZATION> in July had been ordered by the <ORGANIZATION> Merit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Systems </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> to reinstate <PERSON> Berube </PERSON> to his former post as the <ORGANIZATION> GSA </ORGANIZATION>'s <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> area regional director and to pay him back wages and legal fees Under terms of the settlement, <PERSON> Berube </PERSON> will receive $ 530,000, of which $ 181,000 will go for attorney's fees. In addition, the <ORGANIZATION> GSA </ORGANIZATION> will pay $ 24,000 into his retirement account, and $ 6,000 for unemployment compensation <PERSON> Berube </PERSON> otherwise would have to repay, <PERSON> Clark </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Berube </PERSON> also was offered a position as deputy administrator in the <ORGANIZATION> GSA </ORGANIZATION>'s <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION> area office, but opted to retire now, at age 55. He will be allowed to begin drawing a full pension of $ 32,500 a year immediately. <PERSON> Clark </PERSON> said was <PERSON> Berube </PERSON> was pleased with the settlement, but would rather have had his job back in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. Someone else has the job now, and <PERSON> Berube </PERSON> opted to settle rather than go through additional years of litigation for <PERSON> Berube </PERSON> to regain the position, <PERSON> Clark </PERSON> said. <ORGANIZATION> GSA </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Costello </PERSON> confirmed that the agency has agreed to five the Government Accounting Project, which championed <PERSON> Berube </PERSON>'s case, a check for $ 530,000 to settle the dispute, <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> reported in Saturday's editions. Overall, <PERSON> Berube </PERSON> can be expected to receive $ 440,000 in back pay and benefits over his lifetime that he would not have received without the settlement. At the time of his firing, <PERSON> Berube </PERSON> oversaw 7,000 employees in the <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> area and a budget of $ 2 billion. He was in charge of maintaining virtually every government building in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Berube </PERSON> was dismissed after he alleged that many federal buildings in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> posed serious fire and health hazards and that maintenance was deferred to save money.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880902-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-02-88 2354EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Mexico-Hurricane 3rdLd-Writethru   09-02 0640</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Mexico-Hurricane, 3rd Ld - Writethru,a0794,0654</SECOND>
<HEAD>Hurricane Debby Hits Mexican Coast</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDS: SUBS grafs 8-11, `Dozens of ... were affected' with 8 grafs
to update with evacuations, details. Pick up 12th pvs, `Although
the...</NOTE>
<DATELINE>TUXPAN, Mexico (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Hurricane Debby lashed this Gulf of <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> port city Friday with heavy rain and winds gusting up to 74 mph, knocking out power, flooding streets and forcing some people to flee their homes. But the first hurricane of the 1988 <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> season began weakening shortly after hitting the coast and was downgraded to a tropical storm. The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Weather </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> said <PERSON> Debby </PERSON> moved inland at <LOCATION> Tuxpan </LOCATION>, a city of 120,000 about 165 miles northeast of <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, at 4 p.m. -LRB- 6 p.m. EDT -RRB-. It said at that time the storm was carrying winds up to 74 mph, the minimum strength to be classified as a hurricane. The service downgraded <PERSON> Debby </PERSON> to tropical-storm status after its center stalled on reaching the eastern <LOCATION> Sierra </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Madre </LOCATION> mountain range 50 miles inland about 7:30 p.m., with maximum winds of 49 mph. Heavy rains were falling in parts of <LOCATION> Veracruz </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Tamaulipas </LOCATION> states. `` We can say the storm is becoming disorganized,'' a weather service spokesman said. `` By morning maximum winds should be around 30 mph and the storm should disappear by Saturday night.'' The storm caused power outages in <LOCATION> Tuxpan </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Poza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rica </LOCATION>, about 20 miles to the south, and dozens of people were evacuated from low-lying areas in the two cities and near the <LOCATION> Tuxpan </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Tecolutla </LOCATION> rivers. `` The rains have calmed somewhat, but the winds are strong,'' said <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION> worker <PERSON> Francisco </PERSON> <PERSON> Javier </PERSON> <PERSON> Cruz </PERSON> <PERSON> Balderas </PERSON>. `` Many streets are inundated, and the rivers are rising fast.'' Hundreds of people sought refuge in schools and municipal offices in <LOCATION> Alamo </LOCATION>, a coffee-producing town about 20 miles west of <LOCATION> Tuxpan </LOCATION>, said <PERSON> Roberto </PERSON> <PERSON> Martinez </PERSON>, editor of the newspaper <ORGANIZATION> El </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mundo </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Tampico </LOCATION>. Dozens of residents had to be rescued from cars and flooded homes in <LOCATION> Poza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rica </LOCATION>, a city of 300,000. Authorities closed streets in some sections of the city because of flooding. `` The situation is bad enough, but not desperate,'' said <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Garcia </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Poza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rica </LOCATION>. `` A lot of trash in the streets and tree trunks are blocking runoff,'' he said. `` Even we ca n't get out _ we're trapped.'' He said several dozen residents of low-lying areas in the city were evacuated to higher ground but he could n't give a figure as to how many people were affected. <PERSON> Martinez </PERSON> said there were power outages throughout the northern <LOCATION> Veracruz </LOCATION> coastline and that some local roads were cut off by flooding. Residents of <LOCATION> Tampico </LOCATION> and other cities in southern <LOCATION> Tamaulipas </LOCATION> state were bracing for heavy rains, he said. `` There was a lot of panic buying in supermarkets here, but so far there have n't been any problems,'' <PERSON> Martinez </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Guadalupe </PERSON> <PERSON> Lopez </PERSON>, a spokeswoman with the <LOCATION> Veracruz </LOCATION> state government in <LOCATION> Jalapa </LOCATION>, said she could provide no figures on how many people were affected by the storm and that officials had no estimate of damages. There were no reports of deaths or injuries, she said. Although the national weather services in <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> said <PERSON> Debby </PERSON> was carrying winds of 74 mph, the <LOCATION> Mexican </LOCATION> navy station and port authority in <LOCATION> Tuxpan </LOCATION> said it did not have hurricane strength. <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> Capt. <PERSON> Domingo </PERSON> <PERSON> Rojas </PERSON> <PERSON> Cadenas </PERSON> said his reports showed <PERSON> Debby </PERSON> carrying winds of 50 mph and gusts of up to 62 mph when it reached <LOCATION> Tuxpan </LOCATION>. `` There is heavy rain now'' he said late Friday, but the storm had not caused any major problems. <PERSON> Debby </PERSON> grew from a depression into a tropical storm early Friday and then quickly gathered strength, becoming a hurricane by afternoon when it was just off the coast. It was the first hurricane of the 1988 Atlantic hurricane season and the fourth named storm.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880902-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-02-88 0011EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-SculptureGarden     09-02 0604</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Sculpture Garden,0621</SECOND>
<HEAD>Sculpture Garden Gives Public Hands-On Art Experience</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By KARREN MILLS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MINNEAPOLIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A sculpture garden where visitors touch, climb on and lie down in statues worth millions of dollars attracts those who rarely visit museums. The <LOCATION> Minneapolis </LOCATION> Sculpture Garden, being formally dedicated Saturday, is on 7 -LCB- acres of downtown city parkland and is the largest urban sculpture garden in the country, city and museum officials say. It features a giant cherry in a spoon by <PERSON> Claes </PERSON> <PERSON> Oldenburg </PERSON>, and sculptures by other such masters as <PERSON> Isamu </PERSON> <PERSON> Noguchi </PERSON> and <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> Moore </PERSON>. `` I see children playing around and among the sculptures. They become active participants like you probably could n't have in a museum,'' said <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Fisher </PERSON>, superintendent of the <LOCATION> Minneapolis </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Park </LOCATION> and Recreation Board. The $ 12.8 million joint project of <ORGANIZATION> Walker </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Art </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>, the park board and the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Minnesota </ORGANIZATION>'s Landscape Arboretum provides hands-on experience for adults, too, with its 40 sculptures. Visitors, who have been allowed in during the two years the project has been in development, can swing on a platform suspended from the large, steel-beamed sculpture `` Arikidea'' by <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> di </PERSON> <PERSON> Suvero </PERSON>, watching the beams overhead shift slowly from the motion of the swing. They can lie on their backs in the aluminum human form that faces the sky and become part of <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Shelton </PERSON>'s `` BLACKVAULTfalloffstone. Or they can step inside <PERSON> Meg </PERSON> <PERSON> Webster </PERSON>'s `` Glen,'' a plant-filled earthen crater, and enjoy the scents and colors of perennial plants and wildflowers. `` The interaction has been one of the bigger things that we've pulled off,'' <PERSON> Fisher </PERSON> said `` To watch the pure joy of some people in their interactions has been a real delight to me.'' The sculptures date from early in the century to the present, and range in style from classical realism to elemental abstractism. They were created by artists working in a variety of media, including bronze, stone and wood. Permanent installations represent such acknowledged masters as <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> Moore </PERSON>, <PERSON> Reuben </PERSON> <PERSON> Nakian </PERSON> and <PERSON> Isamu </PERSON> <PERSON> Noguchi </PERSON>, as well as leading contemporaries such as <PERSON> Deborah </PERSON> <PERSON> Butterfield </PERSON>, <PERSON> Ellsworth </PERSON> <PERSON> Kelly </PERSON> and <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Segal </PERSON>. The garden, designed by <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Larrabee </PERSON> <PERSON> Barnes </PERSON> in association with landscape architect <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Rotschild </PERSON>, is largely symmetrical. Four 100-foot-square plazas are separated by walkways lined with linden trees. The more traditional sculptures are placed among the trees along the walkways, with the larger constructions inside the plazas. The garden's focal point is the $ 500,000 fountain sculpture `` <LOCATION> Spoonbridge </LOCATION> and Cherry'' by <PERSON> Claes </PERSON> <PERSON> Oldenburg </PERSON> and Coosje <PERSON> van </PERSON> <PERSON> Brugggen </PERSON>. The giant gray aluminum spoon holding a deep red bing cherry with a black stem arches from the reed and iris-lined shore to an island in a free-form pond, giving off a glistening mist and adding a touch of fantasy to the garden. The Sage and <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Cowles </PERSON> <PERSON> Conservatory </PERSON> is a series of three connected glass houses that feature permanent and seasonal horticultural displays. One exhibit contains a dozen palm trees that rise nearly 60 feet high looming over <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Gehry </PERSON>'s 22-foot-high sculpture `` Standing Glass Fish'' which rises from a pool of white water lilies. A footbridge designed by artist <PERSON> Siah </PERSON> <PERSON> Armajani </PERSON> spans city traffic to link the garden to <LOCATION> Loring </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Park </LOCATION> and the downtown area. One of the major goals of the sculpture garden, said <ORGANIZATION> Walker </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Art </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> director <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Friedman </PERSON>, is to develop an appreciative audience by making as much good work available as possible. The garden is meant to attract art lovers as well as people who do n't normally frequent museums. <PERSON> Friedman </PERSON> said he hopes it will help dispell the perception that a museum is `` a somewhat remote presence, even a fortress of art.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880902-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-02-88 0014EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Camel     09-02 0644</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Camel,0663</SECOND>
<HEAD>The Saga Of Jimmy Carter's Camel: Southern (Egypt) Hospitality</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By NEJLA SAMMAKIA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CAIRO, Egypt (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The guards at the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION>, on alert for suicide car bombers and other terrorists, were perplexed this week when a pickup truck approached the iron gate with a pink-ribboned camel peering from the rear. They stopped the driver and shouted at him in Arabic: `` It's forbidden It's forbidden!'' After a few minutes of negotiations, the heavy gate swung open and in came <PERSON> Jimmy </PERSON> <PERSON> Carter </PERSON>'s camel _ an example of southern -LRB- <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION> -RRB- hospitality. The saga began the weekend of Aug. 17, when Egyptian officials telephoned wealthy camel trader <PERSON> Abdel-Wahab </PERSON> <PERSON> Waguih </PERSON> and told him the former <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> president and his wife, <PERSON> Rosalynn </PERSON>, would be visiting suburban <LOCATION> Cairo </LOCATION>'s sprawling camel market. The Carters and seven relatives arrived Aug. 18 for a two-day private visit to cap an African tour. A <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> spokesman said Mrs. <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> specifically selected the camel market for sightseeing along with the <LOCATION> Giza </LOCATION> pyramids and the Sphinx. At the market, in the suburb of <LOCATION> Imbaba </LOCATION>, traders noisily bargain to sell camels earlier bought from Sudanese owners, who trek with the animals for about 40 days across <LOCATION> Sudan </LOCATION>'s desert before bringing them by train from southern <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Imbaba </LOCATION>. Once sold, the animals are used as a beasts of burden or are slaughtered for meat. <PERSON> Waguih </PERSON> was instructed to show the <ORGANIZATION> Carters </ORGANIZATION> around and give them a flavor of Egyptian business. But he also gave the <ORGANIZATION> Carters </ORGANIZATION> two silver daggers, a bunch of genuine Sudanese camel whips _ and the 6-year-old camel, a pink ribbon tied around his neck, worth between $ 560 and $ 740. He said his gift-giving was typical of `` Saeedi'' _ the hospitality shown by people from southern <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION>. His generosity went so far as wanting to honor his guests by slaughtering a sheep at <PERSON> Carter </PERSON>'s feet, a traditional Moslem act of welcome, `` but the American Embassy people told me not to,'' he said. `` <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> would n't like it.'' Although he accepted the huge animal, <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> told the embassy he could n't take it home to <LOCATION> Plains </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ga. </LOCATION>, and instead wanted to give it to Sister <PERSON> Emmanuelle </PERSON>, a French nun who works with <LOCATION> Cairo </LOCATION>'s garbage collectors, the zabaleen. Nobody came to pick up the beast for 10 days, and <PERSON> Waguih </PERSON> said he became impatient. `` I took it to the embassy in a van. There were guards at the door, but I do n't care, I'm not afraid,'' he said, recounting the Monday incident at the embassy as he sat outside his office at the market with 10 relatives. An embassy official signed a receipt for the camel and dispatched an Egyptian employee with <PERSON> Wagih </PERSON> to deliver it to al-Muqattam mountain, where thousands of zabaleen live and where Sister <PERSON> Emmanuelle </PERSON> has set up a school, a health center and a veterinary clinic. `` The camel is now out of our hands,'' said the embassy spokesman, speaking on condition of anonymity. `` It's up to Sister <PERSON> Emmanuelle </PERSON> to decide what to do with it, to sell it or have it slaughtered for meat.'' The Roman Catholic nun had no comment except `` I still do n't know'' the camel's fate For the zabaleen, accustomed to donkeys, pigs and sheep, the camel provided a spectacle but not much enthusiasm _ or appetite. `` We are n't used to eating camel meat in this area,'' said <PERSON> Yanni </PERSON> <PERSON> Rizk </PERSON>, a worker at the nearby <LOCATION> Cairo </LOCATION> slaughterhouse, explaining it is an area without camel butchers. `` It's a joke,'' said Sister <PERSON> Juliana </PERSON>, an Egyptian nun who helps Sister <PERSON> Emmanuelle </PERSON> at her health center. `` They'll probably sell it and put the money into the vet center. Otherwise, the camel requires money for food and care, and we have no place to keep it.'' The beast, meanwhile, stands waiting in the vet center courtyard, the pink ribbon still around its neck.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880902-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-02-88 0016EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--Britain-Tourism     09-02 0119</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Britain-Tourism,0122</SECOND>
<HEAD>Record Number of Tourists Visit Britain in 1987</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A record 15.4 million foreign tourists visited <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> last year, including many more Japanese, Europeans and North Americans, the <ORGANIZATION> British </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tourist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Authority </ORGANIZATION> said. The figure marked an 11 percent increase from 1986, and the visitors spent $ 10.4 billion, the authority said Thursday. The authority said 1987 visits by Japanese increased 45 percent from 1986 while those by Greeks and Italians increased 38 percent. North American tourists in 1987 increased by 19 percent from the year before, said the government-funded authority. The tourist authority said <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> was fifth in tourism earnings for a second consecutive year last year, after the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880902-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-02-88 0019EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Burma-Opposition     09-02 0787</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Burma-Opposition,0808</SECOND>
<HEAD>Burmese Opposition Unites In Name Of Assassinated Hero</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By DENIS D. GRAY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BANGKOK, Thailand (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The expatriate daughter of a near legendary hero assassinated 40 years ago is helping to unify vast but potentially chaotic anti-government forces in <LOCATION> Burma </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Aung </PERSON> <PERSON> San </PERSON>, leader of <LOCATION> Burma </LOCATION>'s independence struggle, was gunned down at the age of 32 _ before, as many have suggested, the world of workaday politicking he was about to enter could mar his image. Some media reports have compared his daughter, <PERSON> Aung </PERSON> <PERSON> San </PERSON> <PERSON> Suu </PERSON> <PERSON> Kyi </PERSON>, with <LOCATION> Philippine </LOCATION> President <PERSON> Corazon </PERSON> <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON> and <PERSON> Benazir </PERSON> <PERSON> Bhutto </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> _ women from nationally prominent families who led or lead opposition forces. The 43-year-old daughter last week drew crowds of up to 400,000 to hear her call for democracy after 26 years of authoritarian rule. Some diplomats and Burmese analysts believe she will be only a transitional figure, but one who could help unify disparate groups and prevent a plunge into anarchy. <PERSON> Aung </PERSON> <PERSON> San </PERSON>'s daughter was thrust unwittingly into the political arena after coming to <LOCATION> Rangoon </LOCATION> from her home in <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> in April to care for her ailing mother. `` She saw all the commotion and turmoil, the rioting and demonstrators getting killed,'' said Burmese emigre spokesman <PERSON> Max </PERSON> <PERSON> McGrath </PERSON> in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>. `` She must have been affected emotionally, especially when demonstrators carried pictures of her father at the head of the procession.'' In an interview with a British television network last week, she said she had no plans for a new political party or an immediate blueprint for a future <LOCATION> Burma </LOCATION> beyond an interim <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Consultative </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> leading to democracy If her program sounded vague, her presence stirred strong emotions. `` It's like if <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Washington </PERSON>'s son had come along in 1830 and said, ` I'd like to be president of the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Stats </ORGANIZATION>.' It would have a certain ring to it,'' says British <LOCATION> Burma </LOCATION> expert <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON>. Like <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, whose name <PERSON> Aung </PERSON> <PERSON> San </PERSON> used to invoke, the <LOCATION> Burmese </LOCATION> leader fought for independence from <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>. Sealing their vow to liberate <LOCATION> Burma </LOCATION> in blood, he and the so-called `` Thirty Comrades'' marched into their homeland during World War II, attacking first the Allies and then the Japanese. Contemporaries recall <PERSON> Aung </PERSON> <PERSON> San </PERSON> as a compelling personality, a sincere, highly principled and simple-living man who could mix easily with colleagues and then lapse into periods of brooding silence. After the war he negotiated successfully with the British government for independence. But months before it was granted, the youthful, handsome <PERSON> Aung </PERSON> <PERSON> San </PERSON> and half a dozen other leaders were killed when assassins of a political opponent burst into a Cabinet meeting with automatic rifles blazing. His death on July 19, 1947, is still commemorated as Martyr's Day. <PERSON> Aung </PERSON> <PERSON> San </PERSON> <PERSON> Suu </PERSON> <PERSON> Kyi </PERSON> was barely 2 years old when her father died. She was educated in <LOCATION> Burma </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>, where he mother served as ambassador from 1960 to 1967. She obtained a Bachelor of Arts degree from <ORGANIZATION> Oxford </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> in 1967, worked at the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> headquarters in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> and in 1972 married <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Aris </PERSON>, an <ORGANIZATION> Oxford </ORGANIZATION> professor and expert on Tibetan culture and the Himalayan region. Although she accompanied her husband on long research stints to <LOCATION> Bhutan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Nepal </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> and other <LOCATION> Asian </LOCATION> countries, acquaintances say she did not pursue a career after marriage. The demonstrations against a quarter century of oppressive rule ended the calm of her private life. Some Burmese also called for the return of her brother, <PERSON> Aung </PERSON> <PERSON> San </PERSON> <PERSON> Oo </PERSON>, a 45-year-old American citizen living in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. Despite the rousing welcome for <PERSON> Aung </PERSON> <PERSON> San </PERSON> <PERSON> Suu </PERSON> <PERSON> Kyi </PERSON>, `` I think people are beginning to have some questions about her,'' said a <LOCATION> Western </LOCATION> diplomat in <LOCATION> Rangoon </LOCATION>. `` She's really an expatriate with no political experience.'' But in a <ORGANIZATION> BBC </ORGANIZATION> interview she countered this by saying, `` I have never been away. ... In my thoughts, I have never been away from my country and my people. In my heart, also i have never been seperated from them.'' She and her husband, who is with her in <LOCATION> Rangoon </LOCATION> along with their two sons, regularly visited <LOCATION> Burma </LOCATION> during the Ne Win period. Rather than an emigre opposition figure, she was allowed to return home at the price of keeping an apolitical silence about conditions in her country, <LOCATION> Burmese </LOCATION> emigres say. Some Burmese believe her marriage to a foreigner would not be well accepted by many in the inward-looking nation. It also is unclear whether she has any formal political ambitions, although last week she appeared to be thinking about a future in <LOCATION> Burma </LOCATION>. `` The Burmese people love my father very much and I think they are ready to support me because I'm my father's daughter,'' she said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880902-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-02-88 0022EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Israel-Children     09-02 0880</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Israel-Children,0904</SECOND>
<HEAD>More Than 50 Children Killed In Palestinian Uprising</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By RONI RABIN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>RAMALLAH, Occupied West Bank (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Days before he was shot to death in January, 16-year-old <PERSON> Rabeh </PERSON> <PERSON> Mahmoud </PERSON> told his family he wanted to give his life for the Palestinian cause, his sister, <PERSON> Sabah </PERSON>, recalls. <PERSON> Mahmoud </PERSON> is one of 53 youths under age 18 who have been kille during the 8-month-old Palestinian uprising in the occupied <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strip </LOCATION>. They comprise about a fourth of the deaths from Israeli army gunfire. Thousands of other youths have been wounded. TV viewers worldwide have seen the young Palestinian boys in kafiyeh headdresses throwing rocks at troops, then running as soldiers respond with tear gas and bullets. Israeli military officials allege the youths are placed in the front lines of protests to generate world sympathy and portray <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> occupation troops as ruthless soldiers who do not hesitate to shoot children. `` Children are weapons in this war. It is very sinister,'' said Col. <PERSON> Renaan </PERSON> <PERSON> Gissin </PERSON>, the army's deputy spokesman. `` With children up front, they -LRB- Palestinian leaders -RRB- win either way _ whether our soldiers refrain from shooting because of strict orders to avoid hurting children, or if they open fire, the <LOCATION> Palestinians </LOCATION> win the war for the media,'' <PERSON> Gissin </PERSON> said. `` They make sure the picture of the dead child makes it to the papers.'' But the youngsters, encountered in refugee camps throwing rocks at soldiers not much older than themselves, say they are the leaders of the revolt. They have become known as the `` children of the stones'' after a poem by Syrian writer <PERSON> Nizar </PERSON> <PERSON> Qabani </PERSON>. The <ORGANIZATION> Palestine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> has made posters of youngsters holding firebombs. Palestinians call children who are killed `` martyrs,'' not `` victims.'' <PERSON> Sabah </PERSON> <PERSON> Mahmoud </PERSON>, the sister of slain 16-year-old <PERSON> Rabeh </PERSON>, says her father now is worried about about his 13-year-old son, who is often out in the streets with friends. The father cries whenever soldiers pass their house, she said. `` When <PERSON> Rabeh </PERSON> told my father he wanted to die for Palestine, we thought he was joking,'' <PERSON> Sabah </PERSON> said, sitting below a gold-framed portrait of her dead brother, the only picture on the walls of the <LOCATION> Beitin </LOCATION> village farmhouse not far from <LOCATION> Ramallah </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> casualty lists, updated as of Aug. 12, show 202 Palestinians killed by Israeli army gunfire. Of these 53 are 18 or younger, with 18 under 16 years old and six who were below 14. The youngest casualty listed by the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> was a 9-year-old girl, but the army said she was killed by a rock thrown by a Palestinian. The army, whose death figures differ only slightly from <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> ones, does not give breakdowns by age. The <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> count shows three other Arab youths under 18, including a 12-year-old, were shot to death by Jewish settlers. A 14 - and 17-year-old were beaten to death by troops, the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> says An official of an international relief organization, speaking on conditoin of anonymity, estimated at least 8,000 youngster have been wounded by bullets, beatings, tear gas or rubber bullets. Israeli youths are n't directly involved in the protests, but they are among civilians injured by rocks and firebombs hurled at cars. The army lists 312 such casualties but has no breakdown by age. A Jewish girl, 15-year-old <PERSON> Tirza </PERSON> <PERSON> Porat </PERSON>, was shot to death accidentally by an armed escort in the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> in April when a group of Jewish hikers clashed with <PERSON> Arab </PERSON> villagers. Police are investigating whether an 8-year-old boy slain August 27 near <LOCATION> Haifa </LOCATION> was killed by Palestinians. One reason Palestinian youngsters are so involved in protests is demographic: Almost 50 percent of the population of the occupied territories is 17 or younger, according to the <ORGANIZATION> West </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Data </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Project </ORGANIZATION> research foundation. These are youngsters raised under the military rule <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> has maintained over the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strip </LOCATION> since the territories were captured from <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION> in 1967. Analysts say the young have become radicalized and are rebelling against <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> and the traditional leadership of their elders, which failed to secure an independent state. `` It's a schoolyard revolution,'' said <PERSON> Bernard </PERSON> <PERSON> Mills </PERSON>, a U.N. Relief Works Agency official in the occupied <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strip </LOCATION>. `` Even before the uprising, by March of 1987, if you were over 14 years old and had n't been arrested by the Israelis, you had n't got your school letter, to put it in American terms.'' Young people 18 to 25 are emerging as the new generation of leaders, and their younger siblings are followers and would-be successors, military sources said. `` Like the Americans of the 1960s who said, ` Do n't trust anyone over 30,' they are saying ` Do n't trust anyone over 25,''' <PERSON> Gissin </PERSON> said. The Israeli army recently introduced plastic bullets in a move it says is intended to cut casualties. The army says its soldiers have orders not to open fire at children, but occupation rules consider those over age 14 accountable for their actions. <PERSON> Chris </PERSON> <PERSON> George </PERSON>, an official of Save The Children, an <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> relief organization, said the army should respect children's status as minors. `` Even if a kid is involved in a confrontation _ throwing a rock for example _ there is no justification for a well-equipped army to use lethal force,'' <PERSON> George </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880902-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-02-88 0027EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-BRF--StarkReturn     09-02 0174</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Stark Return,0178</SECOND>
<HEAD>Stark Returning To Home Base Saturday</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MAYPORT NAVAL STATION, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> is planning a low-key welcome for the refitted USS Stark when it returns home Saturday, ready for duty almost 16 months after being heavily damaged by <LOCATION> Iraqi </LOCATION> missiles. Lt. Cmdr. <PERSON> Tim </PERSON> <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> spokesman, said the Stark will be greeted by family members of the crew and local <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> officials `` but there will be no formal ceremonies.'' `` It is planned as the routine return of a ship from an overhaul period,'' said <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON>. The guided-missile frigate has been in Ingalls Shipbuilding yard in <LOCATION> Pascagoula </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Miss. </LOCATION>, for the past nine months to repair the missile damage that left 37 crew members dead in May 1987. The job was completed on time and was $ 52 million less than the estimate, <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> officials said. The government of <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> has promised to pay the costs of repairing the ship and to compensate the families of those killed during the attack. It will be presented a bill for the repairs.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880902-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-02-88 0032EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Greece-Smog     09-02 0174</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Greece-Smog,0178</SECOND>
<HEAD>Scores Hospitalized After Second Day Of Smog</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ATHENS, Greece (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Half the city's taxis and privately owned cars were banned from the <LOCATION> Athens </LOCATION> area for a second straight day in an effort to dispel record levels of smog. The government said emergency measures would be dropped today because of a substantive drop in pollution levels. The state-run <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Emergency </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aid </ORGANIZATION> said 92 people with pollution-caused heart and respiratory problems sought treatment Thursday at clinics in the Greek capital. Another 24 were hospitalized, the center said. The <ORGANIZATION> Panhellenic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ecological </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Studies </ORGANIZATION>, a private pollution monitoring organization, said 436 people required hospital treatment. `` There was a temperature inversion that got really bad Wednesday. It was like having a lid over <LOCATION> Athens </LOCATION> that kept the pollution trapped underneath,'' said <PERSON> Dimitris </PERSON> <PERSON> Hadjidakis </PERSON> of the Government Program for Pollution Control. About 15,000 taxis and half the city's 730,000 private cars were banned from a 155-square-mile area, and <LOCATION> Athens </LOCATION>' 120 biggest factories were told to reduce output by 30 percent during the emergency.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880902-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-02-88 0033EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-SlayingMovie     09-02 0314</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Slaying Movie,0322</SECOND>
<HEAD>Parents of 15-year-old Murderer Decide Not to Assist in Film of
Slaying</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CANTON, Mass. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The parents of a high school student convicted of murdering his classmate have decided not to take part in a movie about the slaying, spurning a $ 35,000 offer that will go to the victim's mother, a newspaper reported. The movie will be dedicated to the memory of <PERSON> Shaun </PERSON> <PERSON> Ouillette </PERSON>, who was a 15-year-old freshman at <ORGANIZATION> Canton </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> High </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> when he was beaten to death with a baseball bat in 1986, said <PERSON> Dennis </PERSON> <PERSON> Bogorad </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> Dave </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associates </ORGANIZATION>, a Hollywood-based production company. <PERSON> Rod </PERSON> <PERSON> Matthews </PERSON>, also 15, was convicted in March of second-degree murder in the slaying of his classmate. `` They -LRB- <PERSON> Matthew </PERSON>'s parents -RRB- have no interest in the movie,'' a family friend, <PERSON> Mel </PERSON> <PERSON> Ginsberg </PERSON>, told The Patriot Ledger of <PERSON> Quincy </PERSON>. `` They're not going to make it. They did n't sign anything. Mr. and Mrs. <PERSON> Matthews </PERSON> are not out to capitalize on this.'' `` They're just an average family and they do n't want any more damage done,'' <PERSON> Ginsberg </PERSON> said. He said the <PERSON> Matthews </PERSON> were upset when <PERSON> Ouillette </PERSON>'s mother, <PERSON> Jeanne </PERSON> <PERSON> Quinn </PERSON>, accused them on <PERSON> Geraldo </PERSON> <PERSON> Rivera </PERSON>'s national television talk show of accepting `` blood money'' and trying to capitalize on the crime. <PERSON> Kenneth </PERSON> and <PERSON> Janice </PERSON> <PERSON> Matthews </PERSON> had planned to donate a $ 35,000 payment from the movie production company plus a share of the profits to a psychiatric clinic where their son was held prior to his trial in March, the newspaper reported Thursday. The family decided to forego the fee when it learned that <PERSON> Ouillette </PERSON>'s estate could sue to obtain the profits within three years. <PERSON> Quinn </PERSON> said she has agreed to help make the movie and will receive the $ 35,000 payment. She has said she is participating to guarantee events surrounding her son's death are accurately portrayed. <PERSON> Matthews </PERSON> was sentenced to life in prison and is eligible for parole in 2001.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880902-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-02-88 0455EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--MahaliaJackson     09-02 0149</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Mahalia Jackson,0152</SECOND>
<HEAD>Gospel Singer Mahalia Jackson Gets Posthumous Walk of Fame Star</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The late gospel singer <PERSON> Mahalia </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> was honored with the dedication of a star on the Hollywood Walk of Fame. About 200 people, including the singer's brother, <PERSON> Johnny </PERSON>, attended the unveiling Thursday of the walk's 1,876 th star, said <ORGANIZATION> Hollywood </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chamber </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman <PERSON> Ana </PERSON> <PERSON> Martinez </PERSON> <PERSON> Gwendolyn </PERSON> <PERSON> Lightner </PERSON>, <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s pianist for the last six years of her life, also came to the ceremony on <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Boulevard </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, who died in 1972 at age 60, sold millions of records during a recording career that began in 1934 and included such songs as `` Move On Up A Little Higher'' and `` He's Got The Whole World In His Hands.'' Stars are awarded by the <ORGANIZATION> Chamber </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> through an application process and for a fee of $ 3,500. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s estate paid the fee, Ms. <PERSON> Martinez </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880902-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-02-88 0052EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-LotteryRdp     09-02 0075</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lottery Rdp,0079</SECOND>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the winning weekly state lottery numbers picked so far this week:
</TEXT>
<HEAD>DELAWARE</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Play 4: 0-5-3-5.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>MASSACHUSETTS</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Wednesday Megabucks: 01; 04; 06; 24; 32; 33.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>NEW JERSEY</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Pick 6 Lotto: 05; 12; 27; 31; 36; 39. Bonus: 53076.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>NEW YORK</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Wednesday Lotto 54 Game: 05; 08; 29; 37; 41; 47. Supplementary 14.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>PENNSYLVANIA</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Big 4 Lottery: 8-1-8-7.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>RHODE ISLAND</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Grand Lot Game: 5-9-6; 5-4-7-3; 2-5-3-7-8; 3-9-8-3-8-7.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880902-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-02-88 0058EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Boisjoly-Thiokol     09-02 0506</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Boisjoly-Thiokol,0522</SECOND>
<HEAD>Judge Reportedly Dismisses Engineer's Suits Against Morton Thiokol</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SALT LAKE CITY (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A federal judge has dismissed two multibillion-dollar lawsuits filed against <PERSON> Morton </PERSON> <PERSON> Thiokol </PERSON> by a former engineer who warned against the disastrous launch of the space shuttle Challenger, a lawyer said Thursday. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Levin </PERSON>, attorney for former rocket engineer <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> Boisjoly </PERSON>, told KSL-TV that he learned Thursday afternoon that <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> K. </PERSON> <PERSON> Winder </PERSON> had dismissed the $ 3 billion suits with prejudice, meaning they can not be refiled. Court documents were expected to be made public Friday morning. The judge had taken the matter under advisement in February following a hearing on the company's motion to quash the suits. One of <PERSON> Boisjoly </PERSON>'s suits had sought $ 1 billion for the deaths of the seven Challenger crew members on Jan. 28, 1986, and $ 1 million in compensatory damages for his own health and career. <PERSON> Boisjoly </PERSON>, who this year won the Scientific Freedom and Responsibility Award from the American Association for the Advancement of Science, contended <PERSON> Morton </PERSON> <PERSON> Thiokol </PERSON> impugned his professional reputation after he and other engineers testified before a presidential commission investigating the Challenger explosion. The engineers testified that they had warned against launching the shuttle in the unusually cool weather. His other lawsuit, filed under the False Claims Act on behalf of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> taxpayers, sought $ 2.075 billion and alleged that <PERSON> Morton </PERSON> <PERSON> Thiokol </PERSON> knowingly provided the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aeronautics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Space </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> with defective solid rocket motors. <ORGANIZATION> Morton </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Thiokol </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Rocky </PERSON> <PERSON> Raab </PERSON> said the company had received no official notification of the decision. `` But if, in fact, it does prove to be true, it does vindicate what we've said all along. It repudiates what the claims were about Challenger that he -LRB- <PERSON> Boisjoly </PERSON> -RRB- made,'' he said. `` Most of all, we're just glad to see that it's over with,'' <PERSON> Raab </PERSON> said. Company attorneys had said <PERSON> Boisjoly </PERSON>'s assertion that he was defamed was based on office chatter. `` It is just workplace-related talk that goes on all the time,'' attorney <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Jordan </PERSON> told the judge during February's hearing. However, <PERSON> Levin </PERSON> accused company officials of having launched a campaign to defame the engineer through pamphlets and interviews, `` not coffee-shop stuff.'' In a May interview, <PERSON> Boisjoly </PERSON> said only after two years of therapy and `` the positive catharsis'' of giving lectures on the disaster was he able to stop blaming himself for the destruction of the shuttle and deaths of the astronauts. <PERSON> Boisjoly </PERSON> and several other <ORGANIZATION> Morton </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Thiokol </ORGANIZATION> engineers had argued the night before the launch that temperatures of 53 degrees Fahrenheit or less could result in a failure of a rocket joint seal. But after a second caucus with <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> officials, <PERSON> Boisjoly </PERSON> said, company managers `` perceived pressure from <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> ... there was no other justification for the launch. I felt the pressure, others felt the pressure.'' He took disability leave July 21, 1986, and left the company for good two months later. The <ORGANIZATION> Rogers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> investigating the explosion later blamed the disaster on a leaking joint seal that allowed superhot gases to escape and ignite the shuttle's external fuel tank.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880902-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-02-88 0058EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lottery     09-02 0039</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lottery,0044</SECOND>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the winning weekly state lottery numbers picked Thursday:
</TEXT>
<HEAD>DELAWARE</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Play 4: 0-5-3-5.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>NEW JERSEY</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Pick 6 Lotto: 05; 12; 27; 31; 36; 39. Bonus: 53076.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>PENNSYLVANIA</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Big 4 Lottery: 8-1-8-7.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880902-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-02-88 0455EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a BC-Theater     09-02 0366</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Theater,0377</SECOND>
<HEAD>Girl Quartet Sings the '50s off-Broadway</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: No PMs Planned</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By MARY CAMPBELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Chiffons and the Orlons were female quartets, organized in 1960 to sing pop songs. The Taffetas are four women organized in 1988 to sing 1950s pop songs at the off-Broadway Cherry Lane Theater. The Taffetas, who pretend to be sisters, remind one most closely of the Lennon Sisters, of <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> <PERSON> Welk </PERSON> reknown. Bubbles even stream up behind the Taffetas during their encore. It's an evening for smiling in the theater. In their pastel-colored gowns, with matching microphone cords and shoes, the Taffetas look like they're going to make fun of the'50s. They do n't. They do n't comment on the songs or update arrangements. They're going for nostalgia, in which the audience can look back with gentle, bemused affection. Those who do n't remember the'50s can view it like their parents' antiquated photo album. Those who do can try to recall who originally sang the songs. The Taffetas stress naivete, talking a lot about Mom and their home town of <LOCATION> Muncie </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ind </LOCATION>. They sing like crystalized sugar, only once digging with gusto into a lyric, `` Where the Boys Are.'' That song was sung originally by <PERSON> Connie </PERSON> <PERSON> Francis </PERSON>. The Taffetas also draw extensively from <PERSON> Patti </PERSON> <PERSON> Page </PERSON> and <PERSON> Teresa </PERSON> <PERSON> Brewer </PERSON>. `` Mr. <PERSON> Sandman </PERSON>'' _ that was by the Chordettes. `` Dedicated to the One I Love'' _ the <LOCATION> Shirelles </LOCATION>. They do n't choose only from female soloists and quartets. `` Cry'' was a <PERSON> Johnnie </PERSON> <PERSON> Ray </PERSON> hit and the <ORGANIZATION> Ames </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Brothers </ORGANIZATION> first enlightened the world about `` Rag Mop,'' which the Taffetas take at a stately tempo. The singers are <PERSON> Jody </PERSON> <PERSON> Abrahams </PERSON>, <PERSON> Karen </PERSON> <PERSON> Curlee </PERSON>, <PERSON> Melanie </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON> and <PERSON> Tia </PERSON> <PERSON> Speros </PERSON>. Pianist <PERSON> Rick </PERSON> <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON>, drummer <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Osrowitz </PERSON> and bassist <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Rubin </PERSON> accompany. The show was conceived by <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON> and staged and choreographed by <PERSON> Tina </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON>. Like the mixed quartet in off-Broadway's `` Oil City Symphony,'' the Taffetas take time to talk about their hobbies. They are n't as clever as the `` Oil City'' four and their music is n't nearly as varied. Still, an evening with `` The Taffetas'' is a pleasant way, as they used to say on `` Your Hit Parade,'' to stroll down memory lane.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880902-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-02-88 0014EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Colombia-Guerrillas     09-02 0389</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Colombia-Guerrillas,0404</SECOND>
<HEAD>President Delivers Peace Plan; Rebels Kill 12 Peasants</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TOM WELLS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BOGOTA, Colombia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Virgilio </PERSON> <PERSON> Barco </PERSON> offered Thursday to initiate peace talks with leftist guerrillas, who launched their second big attack in a week in northern <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Barco </PERSON> introduced his peace plan on national television. He said the talks should conclude with the dissolution of guerrilla organizations. Guerrillas must stop their terrorist acts, human rights violations, kidnappings and extortions before talks begin, <PERSON> Barco </PERSON> said. He said a peace agreement should be reached by the time of the next presidential and parliamentary elections, in March 1990. Guerrillas firing automatic assault rifles, throwing hand grenades and setting fire to houses killed 12 peasants Tuesday night, Gov. <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Gabriel </PERSON> <PERSON> Amin </PERSON> of the state of <LOCATION> Cordoba </LOCATION> said Thursday. The guerrilla attacks appear to be an effort by the rebels to force the government to open peace talks and make concessions. An estimated 30 guerrillas of the <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> set fire to a ranch, killed 10 peasants and wounded 15 Tuesday near the town of <LOCATION> Canalete </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Amin </PERSON> said. Canalete is about 320 miles north of the capital of <LOCATION> Bogota </LOCATION>. The insurgents then attacked the nearby village of <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Tomate </LOCATION>, setting fire to 26 huts and killing two people, the governor said in a broadcast interview with the Colombian radio chain <ORGANIZATION> RCN </ORGANIZATION>. In <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Tomate </LOCATION>, a village of 600 people, the attackers left messages painted on walls declaring, `` Death to the toads and paramilitaries,'' survivors said in interviews with RCN. Guerrillas call army informants toads. Peasants in <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION> have long claimed that they are caught between the army and the guerrillas. In dozens of interviews with The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>, peasants have told of being forced to sell food and other necessities to guerrillas. Often the army hears of this and through threats or torture, soldiers force the peasants to tell of guerrilla movements, the peasants say. The guerrillas then return and kill the peasants, accusing them of being army informants, the peasants have said. The <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> and another guerrilla group known as the <ORGANIZATION> Colombian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Revolutionary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Armed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forces </ORGANIZATION> attacked the town of <LOCATION> Saisa </LOCATION> in the state of <LOCATION> Cordoba </LOCATION> on Aug. 23 and killed 12 civilians, 10 soldiers and two policemen, the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> said earlier. Twenty-two soldiers and policemen were taken prisoner, the ministry said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880902-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-02-88 0103EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Deaths 1stLd-Writethru a0808 09-02 0427</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Deaths, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0808,0436</SECOND>
<NOTE>Eds: ADDS Mohler; AMs separates moved as a0809 on Alvarez, a0744
on Sullivan and a0640 on Weiser.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Luis Alvarez</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BERKELEY, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Luis </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Alvarez </PERSON>, 77, a Nobel Prize winner and physicist who helped develop the atomic bomb and a controversial theory that asteroids wiped out the dinosaurs, died Wednesday of cancer. <PERSON> Alvarez </PERSON> was noted not only for physics, but for his work in other, widely varied fields that included archeology, paleontology and astronomy. During World War II, he was credited with inventing a number of radar systems and an effective bomb sight. <PERSON> Alvarez </PERSON> also played a significant role in developing the atomic bomb during the <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION> Project, invented several types of atom smashers and did a personal analysis of evidence in the 1963 assassination of President <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>. He was awarded the Nobel Prize in physics in 1968 for his development of the liquid-hydrogen bubble chamber and for the numerous elementary particles of matter that his team discovered using the device. But in the last decade, he was catapulted into headlines by the dinosaur extinction theory he developed with his son, <ORGANIZATION> UC-Berkeley </ORGANIZATION> geologist <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Alvarez </PERSON>, and <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> <PERSON> Berkeley </PERSON> chemists <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Asaro </PERSON> and <PERSON> Helen </PERSON> <PERSON> Michel </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>Leonor Sullivan</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ST. LOUIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Leonor </PERSON> <PERSON> K. </PERSON> <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON>, a 12-term member of the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and the only woman ever elected to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> from <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION>, died Thursday of heart failure at age 86. Mrs. <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON> began her political career after she married <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Rep. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON> in 1941. In 1952 she was elected to her husband's former <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> House seat a year after his death. <PERSON> Mrs </PERSON> <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON> stepped down in 1976. While in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, Mrs. <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON> became a noted environmentalist and consumer advocate. She pushed for preservation of environmental resources and improved employment conditions, as well as consumer protection laws for foods, drugs and cosmetics. In 1954, Mrs. <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON> was an author of legislation creating the food-stamp program.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>Martin Weiser</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Weiser </PERSON>, a film publicist who once transformed a <LOCATION> Sunset </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Boulevard </LOCATION> theater into a giant Easter bonnet to promote the opening of `` Mame,'' died Sunday. He was 76.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>Harold Mohler</HEAD>
<DATELINE>HERSHEY, Pa. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Harold </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Mohler </PERSON>, 69, retired chairman of <ORGANIZATION> Hershey </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foods </ORGANIZATION>, died Wednesday of a heart attack. <PERSON> Mohler </PERSON> joined <ORGANIZATION> Hershey </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foods </ORGANIZATION> after his graduation from <ORGANIZATION> Lehigh </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> in 1948. He was promoted from industrial engineer to assistant to the president and later became director, vice president and president before being named chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Hershey </ORGANIZATION> board in 1974.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880902-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-02-88 0025EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-Crash-List 1stLd-Writethru a0779 09-02 0713</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Crash-List, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0779,0846</SECOND>
<HEAD>With AM-Delta Crash Bjt</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: UPDATES fatals list with cause of death</NOTE>
<DATELINE>GRAPEVINE, Texas (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here is a list of fatalities and survivors of the crash of <ORGANIZATION> Delta </ORGANIZATION> Flight 1141. The names of people who died and the cause of death were provided by <LOCATION> Tarrant </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> Medical Examiner <PERSON> Nizam </PERSON> <PERSON> Peerwani </PERSON>. <ORGANIZATION> Delta </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lines </ORGANIZATION> provided the names of survivors; hometowns and ages are listed as provided by hospital officials Thursday.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>FATALITIES</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Patrick </PERSON> <PERSON> Scott </PERSON> <PERSON> Morgan </PERSON>, 28, <PERSON> Richardson </PERSON>, smoke inhalation. <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Kay </PERSON> <PERSON> Morgan </PERSON>, 29, <PERSON> Richardson </PERSON>, smoke inhalation. <PERSON> Tiffany </PERSON> <PERSON> Lynn </PERSON> <PERSON> Morgan </PERSON>, 14 months, <PERSON> Richardson </PERSON>, smoke inhalation. <PERSON> Millar </PERSON> <PERSON> Browne </PERSON>, 55, <PERSON> Richardson </PERSON>, smoke inhalation. <PERSON> Glen </PERSON> <PERSON> Harvey </PERSON> <PERSON> Campbell </PERSON>, 53, <PERSON> Joshua </PERSON>, smoke inhalation. <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Scott </PERSON> <PERSON> Owen </PERSON>, 29, <PERSON> Sanger </PERSON>, smoke inhalation. <PERSON> Philip </PERSON> <PERSON> Vogel </PERSON>, 69, <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION>, smoke inhalation. <PERSON> Thelma </PERSON> <PERSON> Vogel </PERSON>, 67, <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION>, smoke inhalation. <PERSON> Dixie </PERSON> <PERSON> Dunn </PERSON>, 56, <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION>, smoke inhalation, burns. <PERSON> Rosilyn </PERSON> <PERSON> Marr </PERSON>, 43, <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION>, smoke inhalation. <PERSON> Jennifer </PERSON> <PERSON> Campbell </PERSON>, 44, <PERSON> Joshua </PERSON>, smoke inhalation. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Speer </PERSON>, 25, <PERSON> Rosebud </PERSON>, smoke and carbon monoxide inhalation, burns. <PERSON> Marian </PERSON> <PERSON> Fadal </PERSON>, 65, <LOCATION> Waco </LOCATION>, smoke inhalation.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>SURVIVORS</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Treated and released from <ORGANIZATION> Harris </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Methodist </ORGANIZATION> H.E.B. Hospital <PERSON> Keith </PERSON> <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON>, 44, <ORGANIZATION> Dallas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Buddy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Smith </ORGANIZATION>, 55, <PERSON> Benton </PERSON>, <LOCATION> La </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Phillip </PERSON> <PERSON> Zetzman </PERSON>, 25, <PERSON> Dallas </PERSON> <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Stewart </PERSON>, 44, <PERSON> Monroe </PERSON>, <LOCATION> La </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Michelle </PERSON> <PERSON> Christensen </PERSON>, 25, <PERSON> Dallas </PERSON> <PERSON> Geoff </PERSON> <PERSON> Parkes </PERSON>, 37, <PERSON> Dallas </PERSON> <PERSON> Majorie </PERSON> <PERSON> DeWitte </PERSON>, 56, <LOCATION> Shreveport </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> La </LOCATION>. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Carmichael </PERSON>, 35, <LOCATION> Monticello </LOCATION>, Ark. <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON>, 59, <LOCATION> Euless </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Mona </PERSON> <PERSON> Thomason </PERSON>, 36, <PERSON> Dickerson </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> James </PERSON>, 35, <LOCATION> Anchorage </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ak </LOCATION>. L.E. <PERSON> Bettes </PERSON>, 53, <LOCATION> Great </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Falls </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Mont </PERSON>. W.T. Glass, 60, <PERSON> Bastag </PERSON>, <LOCATION> La </LOCATION>. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Sarvis </PERSON>, 33, <LOCATION> Euless </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> <PERSON> Norma </PERSON> <PERSON> Sarvis </PERSON>, 32, <LOCATION> Euless </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> <PERSON> Allen </PERSON> <PERSON> Sarvis </PERSON>, 7 months, <LOCATION> Euless </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> <PERSON> Christopher </PERSON> <PERSON> Sarvis </PERSON>, 3, <LOCATION> Euless </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>, 37, <PERSON> Dallas </PERSON> <PERSON> Jeff </PERSON> <PERSON> Sham </PERSON>, 27, <PERSON> Maude </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> <PERSON> Kay </PERSON> <PERSON> Koop </PERSON>, 30, <PERSON> Irving </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Hammock </PERSON>, 29, <LOCATION> Garland </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Mauney </PERSON>, 37, Norphlet, Ark. <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Verheyden </PERSON>, 33, <LOCATION> Duncanville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> <PERSON> Damon </PERSON> <PERSON> Berry </PERSON>, 37, Oth, <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION> <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Walker </PERSON>, 40, <PERSON> Dallas </PERSON> <PERSON> Sarah </PERSON> <PERSON> Robert </PERSON>, 2, <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Monroe </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> La </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Dale </PERSON> <PERSON> Patterson </PERSON>, 36, <PERSON> Dano </PERSON>, state not available <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Hanson </PERSON>, 58, <PERSON> Shangaloo </PERSON>, <LOCATION> La </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Vera </PERSON> <PERSON> Kirkland </PERSON>, 59, <PERSON> Whitman </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Mosal </PERSON>, <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, Miss. <PERSON> Alicia </PERSON> <PERSON> Haynes </PERSON>, 32, <PERSON> Dallas </PERSON> <PERSON> Elsie </PERSON> <PERSON> Martin </PERSON>, 73, <LOCATION> Springhill </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> La </LOCATION>. <PERSON> A.A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Frymark </PERSON>, 71, <PERSON> Hurst </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> <PERSON> Wilbur </PERSON> <PERSON> Hill </PERSON>, 64, <PERSON> Buhl </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION> <PERSON> Ben </PERSON> <PERSON> Diamond </PERSON>, 77, <LOCATION> Shelby </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.C. </LOCATION> <PERSON> Jane </PERSON> <PERSON> Wood </PERSON>, 26, <LOCATION> Garland </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> <PERSON> Evan </PERSON> <PERSON> Wood </PERSON>, 5, <LOCATION> Garland </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> <PERSON> Adam </PERSON> <PERSON> Wood </PERSON>, 3, <LOCATION> Garland </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> <PERSON> Walt </PERSON> <PERSON> Allen </PERSON>, 42, <PERSON> Dallas </PERSON> <PERSON> Penn </PERSON> <PERSON> Waugh </PERSON>, 38, <PERSON> Dallas </PERSON> <PERSON> Audrey </PERSON> <PERSON> Mattson </PERSON> 32, <PERSON> Webster </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> <PERSON> Marlla </PERSON> <PERSON> McMahan </PERSON>, 31, Mather, <LOCATION> Calif </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Troy </PERSON> <PERSON> Prater </PERSON>, 57, <PERSON> Dallas </PERSON> <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> King </PERSON>, 38, <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospitalized </LOCATION> at <ORGANIZATION> Harris </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Methodist </ORGANIZATION>: <PERSON> Collette </PERSON> <PERSON> Callow </PERSON>, 25, <LOCATION> Arlington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bernyce </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION>, 71, <PERSON> Buhl </PERSON>, <PERSON> Idaho </PERSON> <PERSON> Stella </PERSON> <PERSON> Grigg </PERSON>, 59, <PERSON> Troup </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Judd </PERSON>, 31, <PERSON> Dallas </PERSON> <PERSON> Edith </PERSON> <PERSON> Coleman </PERSON>, 72, Casper, <LOCATION> Wyo </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Dyer </PERSON>, 38, <PERSON> Pearcy </PERSON>, Ark. <PERSON> Tammy </PERSON> <PERSON> Robert </PERSON>, 37, <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Monroe </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> La </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Reinholt </PERSON>, 53, <LOCATION> Yakima </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wash. </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Neill </PERSON> or <PERSON> O'Neal </PERSON> <PERSON> Randall </PERSON> <PERSON> Foreman </PERSON>, 38, <PERSON> Keller </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> <PERSON> Dana </PERSON> <PERSON> Dieson </PERSON>, 80, <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Worth </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Martin </PERSON>, 74, <LOCATION> Springhill </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> La </LOCATION> <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, 24, <PERSON> Benton </PERSON>, <LOCATION> La </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Sandra </PERSON> <PERSON> Safier </PERSON>, 32, <LOCATION> Sugarland </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Fuchs </PERSON>, 54, <LOCATION> Farmington </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Utah </PERSON> <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> De </PERSON> <PERSON> Witte </PERSON>, 50, <LOCATION> Shreveport </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> La </LOCATION>. Released from <ORGANIZATION> Methodist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Brian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Griggers </ORGANIZATION>, 25, <LOCATION> Demopolis </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ala. </LOCATION>. Hospitalized at <ORGANIZATION> Methodist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> <PERSON> Brad </PERSON> <PERSON> McClarey </PERSON>, 34, <PERSON> Sandy </PERSON>, <PERSON> Utah </PERSON> <PERSON> Gregory </PERSON> <PERSON> Griggers </PERSON>, 22, <PERSON> Jefferson </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Ala. </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Brian </PERSON> <PERSON> Griggers </PERSON>, 25, <LOCATION> Demopolis </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ala. </LOCATION>. Hospitalized at <LOCATION> Harris </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION> <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Nix </PERSON>, 66, <LOCATION> Waco </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> <PERSON> Jean </PERSON> <PERSON> Nix </PERSON>, 54, <LOCATION> Waco </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> Released from <ORGANIZATION> Irving </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Community </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Care </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> System </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Edana </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Robnett </ORGANIZATION>, 28, <LOCATION> Greenwood </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Springs </LOCATION> <PERSON> Dale </PERSON> <PERSON> Owens </PERSON>, 59, <LOCATION> Bentonville </LOCATION>, Ark. <PERSON> Geraldine </PERSON> <PERSON> Owens </PERSON>, 59, <LOCATION> Bentonville </LOCATION>, Ark. <PERSON> Darlene </PERSON> <PERSON> Owens </PERSON>, 27, <PERSON> Dallas </PERSON> <PERSON> Lori </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, 27, <LOCATION> Cardova </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Tenn. </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Joyce </PERSON> <PERSON> Millard </PERSON>, 61, <PERSON> Fort </PERSON> <PERSON> Allen </PERSON>, <LOCATION> La </LOCATION> <PERSON> Shelly </PERSON> <PERSON> Hughes </PERSON>, 31, <LOCATION> Calgary </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Canada </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospitalized </ORGANIZATION> at <ORGANIZATION> Irving </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Community </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Norman </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Newcity </ORGANIZATION>, 36, <LOCATION> Kennesaw </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ga. </LOCATION>. Hospitalized at Parkland Hospital <PERSON> Edmond </PERSON> <PERSON> Fadal </PERSON>, 63, <LOCATION> Waco </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON>, 51 Capt <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Davis </PERSON>, 48, pilot, <LOCATION> Greenville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> <PERSON> Natalie </PERSON> <PERSON> Glim </PERSON>, 67 <PERSON> Bernard </PERSON> <PERSON> Glim </PERSON>, 69 Released from <ORGANIZATION> Baylor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> <PERSON> Dennis </PERSON> <PERSON> Selvan </PERSON>, 42, <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Utah </PERSON> <PERSON> Russell </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, 37, <LOCATION> Boise </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION> <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Galloway </PERSON>, 27, <LOCATION> Colleyville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> <PERSON> Russell </PERSON> <PERSON> Guttu </PERSON>, 24, <LOCATION> Salt </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Utah </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ronald </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Black </ORGANIZATION>, 30, <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Monroe </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> La </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Melissa </PERSON> <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON>, 24, <LOCATION> Tupelo </LOCATION>, Miss. Released from <ORGANIZATION> Northeast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Community </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION> <PERSON> Danny </PERSON> <PERSON> Ellington </PERSON>, 40, <LOCATION> Tulare </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Karie </PERSON> <PERSON> Solomonson </PERSON>, 22, <LOCATION> Euless </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> Hospitalized at <ORGANIZATION> Northeast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Community </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Robert </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coester </ORGANIZATION>, 38, <LOCATION> Carrollton </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> <PERSON> Diana </PERSON> <PERSON> George </PERSON>, 22, <PERSON> Dallas </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> <PERSON> Kirkland </PERSON>, 37, <PERSON> Monroe </PERSON>, <LOCATION> La </LOCATION> <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> Boynton </PERSON>, 30, <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Colony </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Melba </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> McDonald </ORGANIZATION>, 36, <LOCATION> Texarkana </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> McDonald </PERSON>, 34, <LOCATION> Texarkana </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 Other survivors as provided by <ORGANIZATION> Delta </ORGANIZATION> officials: <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> <PERSON> Belinda </PERSON> <PERSON> Brunenan </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Andre </PERSON>
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880902-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-02-88 0113EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-ShuttleRehearsal     09-02 0425</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Shuttle Rehearsal,0436</SECOND>
<HEAD>Computer Glitch Halts Discovery Astronauts' Simulated Flight</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SPACE CENTER, Houston (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A simulated shuttle mission designed to test the Discovery astronauts' trouble-shooting skills was halted just before a mock landing because of a real-life computer crash, <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> officials said. The five astronauts were preparing to end their 56-hour mission Thursday afternoon by simulating a shuttle landing with a flat tire when the computer shutdown cut the rehearsal short. `` I'm sure they'll be looking at it to see why it went down, but nobody here considers it to be a big problem that the simulation ended early,'' said <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Johnson </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Space </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Hartsfield </PERSON>. <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aeronautics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Space </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> officials stressed that there was no problem with any kind of computer used in actual flight control. In <LOCATION> Huntsville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ala. </LOCATION>, meanwhile, engineers at <ORGANIZATION> Marshall </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Space </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Flight </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> said Thursday's fifth and final test of seals and joints on the space shuttle booster rocket lifted their confidence in parts redesigned after the Challenger disaster. `` Based on all appearances the test was a complete success,'' said <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON>, technical assistant to the manager of the solid rocket motor project. The two-minute static test firing, with the booster segment anchored in a $ 25 million test stand, put launch-style pressure on the redesigned joints. The seals are designed to keep internal hot gases inside the twin rockets that help kick shuttles into earth orbit. The failure of a joint in one of Challenger's two boosters was blamed for the January 1986 explosion that killed all seven crew members. Before the computer crash at <ORGANIZATION> Johnson </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Space </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>, officials said, the Discovery crew handled all the simulated problems posed to them during a dress rehearsal for their flight, which is slated for late September or early October. The 56-hour mock mission began about an hour late Tuesday morning because of an earlier problem with the shuttle simulator. But other glitches faced by the Discovery crew were intentional, as commander <PERSON> Rick </PERSON> <PERSON> Hauck </PERSON>, pilot <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Covey </PERSON> and mission specialists <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Hilmers </PERSON>, <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Lounge </PERSON> and <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON> were placed in situations designed to test their ability to solve a multitude of problems that could encounter on an actual mission. Shortly after launch Tuesday, the astronauts were forced to alter their course and enter a low orbit after <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> trainers staged a main engine failure. On Wednesday, <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON> and <PERSON> Lounge </PERSON> had to go outside the orbiter to fix a stuck tilt-table needed to deploy a $ 100 million communications satellite. That simulation was done in a water tank, spokeswoman <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Selby </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880902-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-02-88 0035EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-DeltaCrash 4thLd-Writethru a0831 09-02 1128</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Delta Crash, 4th Ld-Writethru, a0831,1160</SECOND>
<HEAD>Investigators Find Flap Handle Indicator in Wrong Position</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: INSERTS 4 grafs after 5th graf, `Delta Flight ...,' with
deaths caused by smoke inhalation, survivor's comments.</NOTE>
<HEAD>LaserPhotos SA1, DN9, DN10, DN12</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KELLEY SHANNON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>GRAPEVINE, Texas (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Investigators Thursday found the flap indicator handle on a shattered <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> 727 in the wrong position, but a federal safety official said it could have been jarred that way in the fiery crash, which killed 13 people. The handle, which is located on the console between the pilot and the first officer, indicates the position of the aircraft's wing flaps At a news conference Thursday night, <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> member <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Dickinson </PERSON> said the handle on the <ORGANIZATION> Delta </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lines </ORGANIZATION> jet that crashed Wednesday was found to be in the `` up position,'' opposite where it should have been for a proper takeoff. But he went on to say the handle could have been pushed into the wrong position by the impact or by a crew member during the plane's evacuation <ORGANIZATION> Delta </ORGANIZATION> Flight 1141 went down as it tried to take off from <LOCATION> Dallas-Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Worth </LOCATION> <LOCATION> International </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION> en route to <LOCATION> Salt </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> with more than 100 people aboard. Most were able to escape the burning plane by crawling out of emergency exits or torn-open areas. All 13 deaths were attributed to smoke inhalation, according to the <LOCATION> Tarrant </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> medical examiner's office, with burns also listed in two instances. One of the survivors, <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Coester </PERSON>, 39, of the <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION> suburb of <LOCATION> Carrollton </LOCATION>, said he was most troubled by his unsuccessful efforts to rescue passengers trapped in the back of the burning plane. `` I tried to get the rear door open,'' said <PERSON> Coester </PERSON>, who was hospitalized for smoke inhalation and first -, second - and third-degree `` There was a handle on the outside. I got the door ajar, but not enough for them to get out.'' Investigators found at least five bodies near that door after the flames were extinguished. The same flight Thursday from <LOCATION> Dallas-Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Worth </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Salt </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> was aborted when the pilot detected a problem with his plane. Most of the 102 passengers, including six survivors of the crash Wednesday, left about two hours later on another plane, <ORGANIZATION> Delta </ORGANIZATION> officials said. Federal investigators determined that the flaps and slats aboard a <ORGANIZATION> Northwest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> MD-80 had not been properly set for takeoff when that plane crashed Aug. 16, 1987, at <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION> Metropolitan airport, killing 156 people. <PERSON> Dickinson </PERSON> cautioned that the <ORGANIZATION> NTSB </ORGANIZATION> investigation team had just begun to study positions of the <ORGANIZATION> Delta </ORGANIZATION> aircraft's wings and slats. <ORGANIZATION> NTSB </ORGANIZATION> investigators said none of the witnesses they interviewed who were on nearby planes could tell them the position of the airplane's flaps. <PERSON> Dickinson </PERSON> said investigators have not talked to the crew, but hoped to interview First Officer <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> <PERSON> Kirkland </PERSON> on Friday. The <ORGANIZATION> NTSB </ORGANIZATION> official also said control tower personnel indicated the <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> 727 took off at an angle that was higher than normal. Control tower workers who watched the plane leaving told investigators the plane had a `` nose high attitude of 15 to 20 degrees.'' `` Investigators assume that they meant that was higher than normal,'' <PERSON> Dickinson </PERSON> said. Earlier Thursday, <PERSON> Dickinson </PERSON> told reporters the plane's crew had another indication of trouble during takeoff. A cockpit tape recording recovered from the plane showed that pilots had talked about an engine problem seconds before the jetliner crashed. `` Shortly after takeoff there was a sound, -LRB- apparently a -RRB- warning a stall condition may be approaching,'' <PERSON> Dickinson </PERSON> said. He said the sound came from the shaking of the `` stick,'' a device similar to the steering wheel that automatically makes a sound when a problem develops. `` This indicates the plane may be approaching a point where it wo n't be able to fly,'' he said. `` Shortly after that, there was some conversation about an engine problem.'' But he stressed that the warning sound could have stemmed from something besides an engine problem. He would not elaborate, except to say, `` In this case, we're talking about hydraulics.'' `` Every accident in its own way is unique,'' said <ORGANIZATION> NTSB </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Benson </PERSON>. `` You have to start from the beginning, put together a mosaic and slowly discover what went wrong.'' On Wednesday, the 15-year-old <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> 727 failed to gain sufficient altitude, bounced three times on the runway and burst into flames. At least 95 people aboard miraculously survived by clambering or being pulled through emergency doors or through cracks in the burning fuselage into the hazy sunshine. `` Why? Why did it happen? That's the question we have to answer now,'' <ORGANIZATION> Delta </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Berry </PERSON> said in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Delta </ORGANIZATION>'s headquarters Witnesses said there appeared to have been a fire or explosion in an engine on takeoff, <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aviation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Barker </PERSON> said. `` But that was not confirmed,'' he said. `` This was merely what some witnesses were reporting.'' Thirty to 40 investigators from the <ORGANIZATION> NTSB </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Delta </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Pratt </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <LOCATION> Whitney </LOCATION>, which manufactured the plane's three engines, fanned out over an area about the size of two football fields, examining pieces of the wrecked aircraft. Wearing gloves and carrying bags, some crawled inside the charred hulk, using the same cracks where passengers braved flaming jet fuel 24 hours earlier. They also climbed on the lone remaining attached wing, which had been turned red-hot by the fire, to peer into the cabin through blackened windows. At one point, about 20 of them gathered, peering intently at the left rear engine. They removed the engine shroud and looked inside. The cockpit recording, as well as the plane's flight data recorder, had already been recovered in good condition from the wreckage and taken to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> for analysis. <PERSON> Dickinson </PERSON> said safety board officials had listened to the cockpit tape recording just once, and they and other investigators planned to listen to again. The pilot, Capt. <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Davis </PERSON>, 48, of <LOCATION> Greenville </LOCATION>, was pinned in the wreckage and had to be extricated by rescuers. He was listed in fair condition Thursday at <ORGANIZATION> Parkland </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION>, suffering back injuries and burns. <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> has been a <ORGANIZATION> Delta </ORGANIZATION> pilot since 1965 and a <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> 727 captain for nine years. His co-pilot and engineer also survived the accident, but two <ORGANIZATION> Delta </ORGANIZATION> flight attendants were among the 13 fatalities. All of the dead were from <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>. Ninety-seven passengers and a crew of seven were listed aboard the aircraft, but the exact count was uncertain because babies were not included on passenger lists. Three years ago, a <ORGANIZATION> Delta </ORGANIZATION> L-1011 crashed at the same airport, killing 137 in the worst aviation accident in <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> history. <ORGANIZATION> Delta </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> Conley </PERSON> said none of the airline's other 727s would be pulled from service because of Wednesday's crash. `` We do n't see anything serious enough to pull any planes,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880902-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-02-88 0049EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Chile Bjt   09-02 0604</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Chile, Bjt,0633</SECOND>
<HEAD>Pinochet Lifts Ban on Exiles; Opponents Dismiss Move As
Self-Interest</HEAD>
<BYLINE>BY EDUARDO GALLARDO</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SANTIAGO, Chile (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Right-wing President <PERSON> Augusto </PERSON> <PERSON> Pinochet </PERSON> announced that hundreds of his critics living in exile may return to <LOCATION> Chile </LOCATION>, but opponents said the move, and others like it, are aimed only at winning votes in a presidential referendum. Four hours after Thursday's announcement, <PERSON> Isabel </PERSON> <PERSON> Allende </PERSON>, 44, the daughter of former President <PERSON> Salvador </PERSON> <PERSON> Allende </PERSON>, flew to <LOCATION> Santiago </LOCATION>. She has been living in <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> since her father, a self-proclaimed Marxist, died during a bloody coup led by <PERSON> Pinochet </PERSON> 15 years ago. Asked why she returned, she told reporters at the airport, `` Because it's my legitimate right.'' She said her mother, <PERSON> Hortensia </PERSON> <PERSON> Bussi </PERSON>, the exiled widow of Allende, also plans to return. `` We are going to prepare a grand entrance, through the front door, as we've always said,'' Ms. <PERSON> Allende </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Oyarce </PERSON>, a Communist who was labor minister in the <PERSON> Allende </PERSON> government, returned to his homeland on the same flight as Ms. <PERSON> Allende </PERSON>. <PERSON> Pinochet </PERSON> lifted a ban on the return of 430 Chileans who had opposed him, including some of the fiercest leftist opponents of his military government. `` The prohibitions are lifted. All of them,'' the president told reporters. `` I have spoken this morning with the interior minister and have given instructions with respect to exile that totally solves this problem.'' Opponents said the army general is only trying to lure voters in an Oct. 5 presidential referendum in which <PERSON> Pinochet </PERSON> is the sole candidate. His nomination for the referendum was made Tuesday by <PERSON> Pinochet </PERSON> himself and the commanders of the navy, air force and national police. It sparked nationwide anti-government protests. If the majority of Chileans vote `` no'' in the ballot, an open election is to be held. If they vote `` yes,'' <PERSON> Pinochet </PERSON> would begin an eight-year term as president in March. `` The regime is trying to change -LRB- <PERSON> Pinochet </PERSON>'s -RRB- image on the eve of the referendum,'' said <PERSON> Patricio </PERSON> <PERSON> Aylwin </PERSON>, leader of a 16-party opposition coalition. <PERSON> Aylwin </PERSON> challenged <PERSON> Pinochet </PERSON> to a `` free and open'' debate on national television, `` so he can have the opportunity to contrast his ideas with those of the opposition.'' In another move opponents say was aimed at winning the referendum, <PERSON> Pinochet </PERSON> last week lifted the state of emergency that has suppressed civil liberties since the 1973 coup. The president also ordered a 3 percent reduction in the price of gasoline. On Wednesday, <PERSON> Pinochet </PERSON> made a conciliatory gesture toward his critics, appealing for their support in a nationally televised speech. `` There is a new democracy ahead of us. We must work together to make it efficient,'' the 72-year-old general said. `` Our democracy has a place for everybody.'' The tone of the speech contrasted sharply with <PERSON> Pinochet </PERSON>'s past references to opposition leaders, whom he has called `` traitors'' and `` bandits'' who `` sell out their motherland.'' <PERSON> Pinochet </PERSON> told reporters at the government palace Thursday that he is not shifting his style in an effort to change his authoritarian image. `` What happens is that a person must act according to the circumstances,'' he said. Supporters praised <PERSON> Pinochet </PERSON>'s moves as proof of his intention to hold an honest referendum. `` The decision of ending exile is part of the President's appeal to peace and unity of all Chileans,'' said Interior Minister <PERSON> Sergio </PERSON> <PERSON> Fernandez </PERSON>. <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Cabello </PERSON>, leader of an independent organization supporting <PERSON> Pinochet </PERSON>, said `` the move shows the President's deep democratic conviction.'' But <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Sanfuentes </PERSON>, a spokesman for the outlawed <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, said: `` <PERSON> Pinochet </PERSON> will take other measures to try to buy out the consciences of Chileans, but these measures will not prevent the collapse of his dictatorship.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880902-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-02-88 0053EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Mexico Bjt   09-02 0717</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Mexico, Bjt,0739</SECOND>
<HEAD>Chaotic Scene in Congress Draws Criticism, Praise</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto MO1</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RICHARD HERZFELDER</BYLINE>
