<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880511-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-11-88 2336EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-People-MotleyCrue     05-11 0387</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-People-Motley Crue,0403</SECOND>
<HEAD>Crowds Grow As Heavy Metal Trial Continues</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ATHENS, Ala. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A teen-ager testified Wednesday in a $ 2.6 million lawsuit against the heavy metal rock group <ORGANIZATION> Motley </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Crew </ORGANIZATION> that flying pieces of dry ice from a flaming special-effects pot on stage split his lip during a 1985 show. `` I could feel straight through to my teeth,'' said 19-year-old <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>. On Tuesday, the second plaintiff in the case, 17-year-old <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Miller </PERSON>, said lost an eye to flying debris during the concert in <LOCATION> Huntsville </LOCATION>. Named as defendants in the suit are the band, the city of <LOCATION> Huntsville </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Von </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Braun </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Civic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> and <LOCATION> Nashville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Tenn. </LOCATION>, promoter of the concert. Attorneys for <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> and <PERSON> Miller </PERSON> contend illegal fireworks were used as special effects, and that city and civic center officials were negligent in allowing their use. About 30 teen-agers cut class to catch a glimpse Wednesday of the band's bass player, <PERSON> Nikki </PERSON> <PERSON> Sixx </PERSON>. <PERSON> Sixx </PERSON> needed a police escort to reach his car after testifying Tuesday. Some 300 fans stood outside as he departed that day. <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> testified that he was standing about 20 feet from the stage when the accident took place. He said <PERSON> Motley </PERSON> <PERSON> Crue </PERSON> had just begun the song `` Shout to the Devil'' when he saw flames shoot up on either side of the drummer. Then, he said, `` something come out and hit me,'' splitting his lip before he could cover his face. He said when he looked down, he saw blood and what looked like crushed ice. When he stepped on it, he said, his foot slipped as if the object were melting. <PERSON> Miller </PERSON> testifed Tuesday that he heard a `` big boom'' and saw flames just before something object struck him in the face during the concert. <PERSON> Miller </PERSON>, 14 at the time and attending his first rock concert, said his first thought was that the lights at the arena had been turned off. `` But when I reached up and felt my eye,'' he said, `` there was nothing there.'' <PERSON> Sixx </PERSON> testified Tuesday it was `` impossible'' that the teen-agers were injured by the band's special effects. <PERSON> Sixx </PERSON> said the band continued to use the pyrotechnic displays in concerts after the incident in <LOCATION> Huntsville </LOCATION>. `` I do three to four hundred shows with the stuff right next to me. It has to be safe,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880511-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-11-88 2347EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-CarsonReturns 1stLd-Writethru a0842 05-11 0482</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Carson Returns, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0842,0489</SECOND>
<HEAD>Johnny Carson Back on `Tonight Show'</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: UPDATES throughout with Carson remarks during taping of show.
No pickup.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By JOHN ANTCZAK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BURBANK, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Johnny </PERSON> <PERSON> Carson </PERSON> returned to television Wednesday despite a writers strike, giving a monologue of his own making in which he wisecracked that astrology in the White House finally explains `` the loony tunes things that have been coming out of <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>.'' `` The Tonight Show'' had been in reruns since shortly after the <ORGANIZATION> Writers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guild </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION> struck the film and TV industry March 7. <PERSON> Carson </PERSON> announced last week that reruns of the show would end and he would return to the air, writing his own monologues. <PERSON> Carson </PERSON>, who is not a member of the guild, said at that time possibilities of reaching an agreement with striking writers had been exhausted. On Wednesday, he said the real reason for coming back stemmed from the brouhaha over revelations about the influence of astrology in the White House. `` I just could not stay away any longer from all things that are going on in the country. I was compelled to come back,'' <PERSON> Carson </PERSON> said. `` I'm a Scorpio on the cusp. ... You know, we finally have a clue now as to what the hell -LRB- are -RRB- the loony tunes things that have been coming out of <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>.'' <PERSON> Carson </PERSON> referred to revelations by former White House chief of staff <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Regan </PERSON> that first lady <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> regularly consulted an astrologer to determine the timing of President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s movements <PERSON> Carson </PERSON> said he had not been aware there was a new Cabinet position, Secretary of Health, Education and Soothsaying. He also made brief mention of the strike in both a sincere and joking tone. `` We're glad to be back. As far as the writers strike we're not going to discuss it,'' he said. `` I have a lot of friends who are writers. We hope they join us soon. It is not fun to come to work when you see your friends who you've known for many years standing out on a picket line. Then he quipped, `` And it's a weird picket line. The writers are out there holding up these signs and there's nothing on them.'' <PERSON> Carson </PERSON> explained to out-of-towners that there had been excitement in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> because of persistent rumors that Nostradamus, a 16th century astrologer, forecast an earthquake for a city widely believed to be <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>. `` He was a flim-flam man of the 16th century,'' <PERSON> Carson </PERSON> observed. `` If Nostradamus were alive today he would be <PERSON> Geraldo </PERSON> <PERSON> Rivera </PERSON>,'' he said, referring to the TV personality who opened <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> Capone </PERSON>'s vault to great hype but found next to nothing. <PERSON> Carson </PERSON>'s production company, <ORGANIZATION> Carson </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tonight </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, was rebuffed in efforts to get either a waiver from the guild or reach an independent agreeement that would permit the writers to return to work.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880511-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-11-88 2353EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-US-Kuwait-F18s     05-11 0391</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-US-Kuwait-F18s,380</SECOND>
<HEAD>Administration Wants to Sell F-18 Fighter-Bombers to Kuwait</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration intends to sell advanced F-18 fighter-bombers to <LOCATION> Kuwait </LOCATION>, a deal that would make the tiny <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> state the first <PERSON> Arab </PERSON> country to have them, <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> reported Thursday. Citing unidentified sources in the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> and State departments, the <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> said <LOCATION> Kuwait </LOCATION> wants to buy 40 of the aircraft and the administration will notify <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> soon of its intention to proceed with the sale. The deal could be worth $ 680 million to the manufacturer, <ORGANIZATION> McDonnell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Douglas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, said company spokesman <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Brien </PERSON>. Several <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> officials contacted by The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> on Wednesday night said they were unaware that any decision had been made. One noted that Assistant Secretary of State <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON> had told a congessional panel Tuesday that `` there was a request from <LOCATION> Kuwait </LOCATION> to look at the possibility of selling F-18s.'' Another source, who also spoke on condition that he not be named, said, `` I'm not aware that any decision is imminent.'' `` There's no more than the possibility of a sale,'' he said, adding that he was skeptical that such a decision would have been made so quickly. `` I would doubt it very seriously,'' he said. `` There's interest, but a lot of discussion needs to go on before any decision like that would be considered I think it's awful early. I would be very surprised if it's true.'' The source noted that <LOCATION> Kuwait </LOCATION> has talked to several countries, including <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>, about the possibility of buying advanced aircraft. <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON> had told the congressional panel Tuesday that the administration had alerted <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> that <LOCATION> Kuwait </LOCATION> was interested in the F-18s and might prefer them to the less sophisticated F-16s. <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> could block the sale. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> is selling F-16s to <LOCATION> Bahrain </LOCATION>, but it has n't sold F-18s to any Arab nation, the <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> said The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Kuwait </LOCATION> have created an increasingly close security relationship since last year, when the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> committed naval forces to protect U.S.-flagged ships traveling through the war-torn <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION>. Initially, 11 Kuwaiti ships were re-flagged under this policy and were given protection by the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> recently revised its policy in the gulf, announcing that it would offer help to other ships that were attacked by combatants in the 7 -LCB- - year-old Iran-Iraq war
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880511-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-11-88 0754EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-ChurchUniversal     05-11 1192</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Church Universal,1228</SECOND>
<HEAD>Church Universal and Triumphant: A Threat in Paradise Valley?</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</NOTE>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MIKE DENNISON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CORWIN SPRINGS, Mont. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here in a mile-high valley called Paradise, a religious group is building its home, a retreat for thousands that some local people say threatens the pristine environment bordering Yellowstone National Park. The group is the <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Universal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Triumphant </ORGANIZATION>, a `` New Age'' sect that moved its headquarters in late 1986 from <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> to a 12,000-acre ranch it had bought five years earlier in southwest <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Paradise </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION>. With that move came 200 followers, doubling the number already there, construction plans for a self-sufficient community, and the promise of more church members moving into a valley with a population of about 1,000. Next door is <ORGANIZATION> Yellowstone </ORGANIZATION>, whose wildlife herds often migrate into the valley during the winter. `` This is a place of international significance,'' says <PERSON> Hank </PERSON> <PERSON> Rate </PERSON>, a local resident. `` If they do what they say they want to do, that value is going to be diminished _ not only for our time, but for all time.'' Rate and others fear the group's building plans and its summer conclaves that attract thousands will cause environmental damage in the valley. Some critics say they're uncomfortable with the group's beliefs. The church was founded 30 years ago in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION>, by <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Prophet </PERSON>, who said he received messages from spiritual figures of the past, including <PERSON> Christ </PERSON>, <PERSON> Buddha </PERSON> and Pope <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> XXIII </PERSON>. Upon his death in 1973, his widow, <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> Clare </PERSON> <PERSON> Prophet </PERSON>, became the leader. Church members believe a human soul is continuously reincarnated until people realize the God within themselves. They use praying or chanting to attempt to influence world conditions or personal concerns. Tobacco, alcohol and drugs are forbidden. Ms. <PERSON> Prophet </PERSON>, 47, says her visions suggest a war between the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> before the end of this century. The church supports President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s Strategic Defense Initiative and a nationwide civil defense system. `` We have a lot of down-home, nice type of folks on this ranch who are just like the people that are our neighbors,'' Ms. <PERSON> Prophet </PERSON> says. `` I do n't think that all the hullaballoo that's been made in the press is the reality here.'' Critics draw comparisons between <LOCATION> Paradise </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION> and the tiny town of <LOCATION> Antelope </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ore. </LOCATION>, taken over in the early 1980s and then abandoned by followers of the Baghwan <PERSON> Shree </PERSON> <PERSON> Rajneesh </PERSON>. Church Universal and Triumphant bought some modular housing from the defunct Rajneeshee community, but church leaders say the similarities end there. Since the church bought the ranch in 1981, its leaders have hit the local Rotary and <ORGANIZATION> Kiwanis </ORGANIZATION> club circuit to calm fears that it is a far-out religious cult bent on political control. Church vice president <PERSON> Ed </PERSON> <PERSON> Francis </PERSON>, married to Ms. <PERSON> Prophet </PERSON>, says church members' political persuasion generally resembles that of the area _ conservative and Republican. Not everyone is reassured. `` I'm concerned about the numbers,'' says <PERSON> Leonard </PERSON> <PERSON> Sargent </PERSON>, whose 2,000-acre property borders the church's <ORGANIZATION> Royal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Teton </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ranch </ORGANIZATION>. `` No matter what they happen to believe, it's still an awful lot of people to bring into a fragile area.'' Church officials counter that they chose the valley because of its natural beauty, which they want to preserve. The church bought the <ORGANIZATION> Royal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Teton </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ranch </ORGANIZATION> in 1981 from magazine publisher <PERSON> Malcolm </PERSON> <PERSON> Forbes </PERSON> for a reported $ 7 million. Since then, the church has purchased an additional 21,500 acres in the <LOCATION> Paradise </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION>, including 5,200 acres of hilly prairie near Emigrant intended for settlement by church members, about 25 miles north of the <LOCATION> Royal </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Teton </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ranch </LOCATION>. It also owns a printing shop in <LOCATION> Livingston </LOCATION> that employs 100 people. The church wo n't reveal its income but says it comes from members' donations and various business ventures, largely the sale of religious books and videotapes. It also leases land to members. The church has advertised the ranch to its members as a spiritual retreat offering protection from economic collapse, civil disorder or war. Thousands of followers gather each summer for an annual conclave in a spectacular mountain valley called the `` Heart of the Inner Retreat.'' Ms. <PERSON> Prophet </PERSON> and <PERSON> Francis </PERSON> say the <LOCATION> Royal </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Teton </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ranch </LOCATION> will become a monastic, self-sufficient community for 500 or so church members. With the help of ranch `` staff'' _ church members who receive room, board and small monthly salaries _ the church has installed an extensive irrigation system, grows a wide variety of vegetables and grains, operates a dairy and raises 2,500 head of cattle and sheep. Members also began work in 1986 on the development's central complex. Located near the west bank of the <LOCATION> Yellowstone </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> several miles north of <LOCATION> Yellowstone </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Park </LOCATION>, it would include housing for 260, a church, school, kitchen, dining hall and recreation facilities. But that work halted in November 1986 when the state, prodded by local residents, launched an environmental review. A draft of the review, completed in March, said the project should be able to proceed without damaging wildlife, water quality or aesthetics, as long as the church takes several steps to cushion impact of the development. The state found no threat to the environment that would justify denying sewage and water permits, if the conditions were met. Following a public comment period _ `` We were overwhelmed with comment, both for and against,'' said <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Pilcher </PERSON>, chief of <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Water </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Quality </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> _ the state is completing a final report. The draft said the church should build a bear-proof fence around a tree farm and vegetable fields, monitor groundwater, maintain minimum flows in three creeks crossing ranch property and postpone any use of a geothermal spring near the <LOCATION> Yellowstone </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION>. The church wants to pump water from <LOCATION> LaDuke </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hot </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Springs </LOCATION> for use at its central complex. Park officials are concerned the pumping might affect <LOCATION> Mammoth </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hot </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Springs </LOCATION> nine miles to the south. <PERSON> Francis </PERSON> says the church is willing to accept the recommendations, but a number of groups have suggested the state review is inadequate. Since the 1970s, the church has occupied and later abandoned land in <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> _ `` a series of steps to get here,'' <PERSON> Francis </PERSON> says, adding that the church has no intention of moving again. But critics say the church has not been forthcoming about its plans in the past. `` Basically, <PERSON> Ed </PERSON> <PERSON> Francis </PERSON>' credibility with me is zero,'' says <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Parks </PERSON>, owner of an outdoor equipment shop in nearby <PERSON> Gardiner </PERSON> and a member of the <ORGANIZATION> Bear </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Creek </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>, a local environmental group. `` If he told me it was Thursday, I'd check the calendar.'' When Church Universal and Triumphant bought the ranch, <PERSON> Francis </PERSON> said its rural nature would not be changed. <PERSON> Francis </PERSON> maintains he has been largely consistent: `` I feel that a 1 percent use of property in this area for anything other than open space and wildlife is appropriate and not something that should cause a lot of alarm.'' Parks says the church `` changes the ambience of the whole area,'' bringing the impact of a development but no direct economic benefits. <PERSON> Francis </PERSON> contends that what's really bothering the critics is simpler: They just do n't want others to have a piece of their paradise.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880511-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-11-88 0239EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Tunisia'sNewEra     05-11 0773</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Tunisia's New Era,0799</SECOND>
<HEAD>`New Era' In Tunisia As Pro-Western Bourguiba Slips Into Oblivion</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By ELAINE GANLEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>TUNIS, Tunisia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Habib </PERSON> <PERSON> Bourguiba </PERSON>'s statue still dominates a square in central <LOCATION> Tunis </LOCATION>, but the man who towered over <LOCATION> Tunisia </LOCATION> for 32 years has slipped into oblivion six months after his ouster. His successor as president, <PERSON> Zine </PERSON> <PERSON> El </PERSON> <PERSON> Abidine </PERSON> <PERSON> Ben </PERSON> <PERSON> Ali </PERSON>, has proclaimed a `` new era'' for the North African nation, appealing to the nation's Islamic and Arabic heritage, a stand that has won him immediate widespread support. <PERSON> Bourguiba </PERSON>, who had set the nation on a Western course after he won independence from <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> in 1956, now is 84 years old and confined to a chateau outside <LOCATION> Tunis </LOCATION>. He was declared no longer capable of governing when he was removed from office Nov. 7. <PERSON> Ben </PERSON> <PERSON> Ali </PERSON> took power during a tense crackdown on Islamic fundamentalists and is universally credited, even by political opponents, with sparing the nation from a more serious upheaval. He has sought to make peace with the Islamic fundamentalists and others in the Bourguiba opposition. Newspapers once banned by <PERSON> Bourguiba </PERSON> are back on newsstands. Many people say they no longer fear the police. <ORGANIZATION> Tunis </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, disrupted three days a week last year by demonstrations, is quiet. About 5,000 prisoners, many of them members of an outlawed Islamic fundamentalist group, have been pardoned. The national legislature, dominated by <PERSON> Bourguiba </PERSON>'s ruling party since <LOCATION> Tunisia </LOCATION>'s independence in 1956, has moved toward pluralism with a new law on political parties. In his most risky move, however, <PERSON> Ben </PERSON> <PERSON> Ali </PERSON> has extended a hand to the growing Islamic fundamentalist movement, <PERSON> Bourguiba </PERSON>'s chief target in his waning years. Television and radio now broadcast the five daily calls to Islamic prayer. Islam has alway been the official state religion, but <PERSON> Bourguiba </PERSON> maintained a secular character in government and daily life. <PERSON> Ben </PERSON> <PERSON> Ali </PERSON>, a military man once in charge of the crackdown on fundamentalists, invokes Allah -LRB- God -RRB- at the start of his speeches. `` It's life that's changed, not just politics,'' said <PERSON> Chakib </PERSON> <PERSON> Douss </PERSON>, a brassware merchant in the <LOCATION> Tunis </LOCATION> bazaar. `` Now everyone is free. We feel it every day, every minute. It's not something you read about in the newspaper. It's something you touch.'' Many in the opposition approved of the new climate, if only for now. `` Incontestably, Nov. 7 was a comfort to everyone,'' said a leading member of the <ORGANIZATION> Socialist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democrat </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Movement </ORGANIZATION>, the largest opposition party, speaking on condition of anonymity. `` It's still the honeymoon, so everyone feels obliged to publicly approve him,'' commented <PERSON> M'hamed </PERSON> <PERSON> Jaibi </PERSON>, editor-in-chief of the weekly Maghreb, reopened in September after being shut down four years ago. `` I hope this is a temporary situation,'' he said of <PERSON> Ben </PERSON> <PERSON> Ali </PERSON>'s popularity `` Otherwise, we'll be back in the old system with a president who thinks he is infallible.'' That was an allusion as well to <PERSON> Bourguiba </PERSON>, who had become so dominant that he was declared president-for-life, a benign dictator in charge of a nominal democracy. His Destourian <ORGANIZATION> Socialist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> controlled all seats in the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION>. None of the three legal opposition parties had a meaningful voice. But <PERSON> Ben </PERSON> <PERSON> Ali </PERSON> has promised that his new era would `` open the horizons to a truly democratic and evolved political life.'' Since taking office, he has moved to abolish the lifelong presidency, change the electoral code and press laws, dismantle the feared state security court and given <ORGANIZATION> Amnesty </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION>, the London-based human rights group, a permit to operate here _ its first in the Arab world. <PERSON> Ben </PERSON> <PERSON> Ali </PERSON> has also restored diplomatic relations with neighboring <LOCATION> Libya </LOCATION> and stresses closer ties with the Arab world. While citizens appear won over by the changes, some opposition politicians remain cautious and fundamentalists are reserving full judgment. The final year of <PERSON> Bourguiba </PERSON>'s leadership was marked by a battle against the fundamentalist <ORGANIZATION> Islamic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tendency </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Movement </ORGANIZATION>, culminating in a trial in September of 90 fundamentalists on charges of plotting against the state. `` The Islamic dossier remains the hottest one on <PERSON> Ben </PERSON> <PERSON> Ali </PERSON>'s desk,'' said <PERSON> Hassen </PERSON> <PERSON> Ghodhbani </PERSON>, an Islamic lawyer who defended some of the 90 in the trial He contended the measures taken by <PERSON> Ben </PERSON> <PERSON> Ali </PERSON> remain insufficient. `` Islam is n't just prayer and pilgrimage. It's an entire life system,'' he said. In late April, the legislature quashed any hopes that the <ORGANIZATION> Islamic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tendency </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Movement </ORGANIZATION> might become a legal opposition party _ one of its demands. A new law allowed new political parties but forbade those based on religion, language, race or region. `` The government has adopted a double attitude toward Islam,'' said the opposition politician who spoke anonymously. `` It is a position both clever and dangerous.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880511-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-11-88 0755EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Poland-Chronology     05-11 0471</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Poland-Chronology,0491</SECOND>
<HEAD>Major Events In Recent Polish Labor Turmoil</HEAD>
<HEAD>By The Associated Press</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 The Gdansk shipyard strike that ended Tuesday was the last of the strikes that hit <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> and caused its worst labor crisis since 1981. Here is a chronology of major events in the turmoil: APRIL 25 _ Labor unrest begins with transit workers' 11-hour work stoppage in <LOCATION> Bydgoszcz </LOCATION>. Strikers win 60 percent raise. APRIL 26 _ Strike begins at country's largest steel plant, in <LOCATION> Nowa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Huta </LOCATION>. APRIL 29 _ Employees at <LOCATION> Stalowa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Wola </LOCATION> heavy machinery plant in southeastern <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> stop work. Police detain seven Solidarity leaders, bringing to at least 33 number of opposition activists taken into custody. APRIL 30 _ <ORGANIZATION> Stalowa </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wola </ORGANIZATION> workers win promises of higher pay, end strike. <LOCATION> Krakow </LOCATION> tram drivers ignore strike call. MAY 1 _ Solidarity leader <PERSON> Lech </PERSON> <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> appeals for `` day of action'' to support <PERSON> Nowa </PERSON> <PERSON> Huta </PERSON> strikers. Police arrest demonstrators in at least 19 cities. MAY 2 _ Strike at <LOCATION> Gdansk </LOCATION>'s Lenin shipyard begins. One demand is for local Solidarity chapter to be approved. One-day work stoppage at Dolmel electronics plant in <LOCATION> Wroclaw </LOCATION> ends after workers are promised pay increase. <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> urges <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> to negotiate with unions. MAY 3 _ Government says legalizing Solidarity `` not negotiable.'' <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION> police disperse marchers supporting strikers. Students stage sympathy strikes in <LOCATION> Krakow </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Poznan </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Gdansk </LOCATION>. Brief work stoppages at railroad car plant in <LOCATION> Wroclaw </LOCATION>, copper mine in western <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>. Nine dissidents detained. <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> arrives at <LOCATION> Lenin </LOCATION> shipyard. MAY 4 _ Church mediators win promise of negotations between <LOCATION> Nowa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Huta </LOCATION> strikers, management. <LOCATION> Gdansk </LOCATION> workers back down from May 3 demand that Solidarity be legalized nationwide. MAY 5 _ Police crush <ORGANIZATION> Nowa </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Huta </ORGANIZATION> strike, arrest leaders in pre-dawn raid. Police prevent food deliveries at <LOCATION> Gdansk </LOCATION> shipyard. Threat of force ends 10-hour strike by <LOCATION> Szczecin </LOCATION> bus drivers. Students strike in <LOCATION> Krakow </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Gdansk </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION>. MAY 6 _ <LOCATION> Gdansk </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Solidarity </LOCATION> leader <PERSON> Bogdan </PERSON> <PERSON> Lis </PERSON>, unionist who called <LOCATION> Gdansk </LOCATION> strike each draw three months in prison. Five other activists detained. Government proposes laws to punish organizers of strikes and protests, suspend right to strike. MAY 7 _ Pope <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> II </PERSON> says strikes can be justified, <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> lacks `` true democracy.'' <LOCATION> Gdansk </LOCATION> strike committee, management meet. <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> says its backing for Polish economic program will stay frozen until program wins popular support. <LOCATION> Gdansk </LOCATION> management said to agree generally to increase pay, reinstate fired activists. Police crack down on Solidarity national spokesman for giving interviews. MAY 8 _ <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> and 1,000 workers defy ultimatum to end strike or face prosecution. Talks revive. Cardinal <PERSON> Jozef </PERSON> <PERSON> Glemp </PERSON> supports strikers in sermon. MAY 9 _ Efforts fizzle for sympathy strike at 15,000-employee <ORGANIZATION> Ursus </ORGANIZATION> tractor factory outside <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Gdansk </LOCATION> workers spurn compromise which does not include legally recognized chapter of Solidarity. MAY 10 _ Workers at <LOCATION> Lenin </LOCATION> shipyard in <LOCATION> Gdansk </LOCATION> end eight-day strike without settlement.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880511-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-11-88 0747EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--Korea-Ships     05-11 0137</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Korea-Ships,0140</SECOND>
<HEAD>South Korea's Shipbuilding Orders Decrease 41.3 Percent</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SEOUL, South Korea (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>'s shipbuilding orders decreased more than 40 percent so far this year from the same period in 1987 because of a rapid appreciation in the country's currency, industry officials said today Orders received so far consist of 626,300 gross tons of export ships and 800 gross tons of domestic ships, the officials said. But they added that despite the sluggish orders, local shipmakers still have a combined outstanding order of 6 million tons, enough to keep them busy until the first half of next year. The value of the <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korean </LOCATION> won has risen 7.43 percent against the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> dollar so far this year. A higher won makes South Korean exports more expensive abroad while lowering the prices of foreign imports.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880511-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-11-88 0748EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Nielsens     05-11 0402</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nielsens,0414</SECOND>
<HEAD>Networks Haul Out Original Shows For Sweeps</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JERRY BUCK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Television Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> won back first place in the <ORGANIZATION> A.C. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nielsen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> television ratings from <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> and became the first network in more than seven years to claim the nine top shows. Because of the May sweeps, <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> broadcast mostly original programs for the week that ended Sunday. They face summer reruns and a drought imposed by the scriptwriters' strike. <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> finished more than four ratings points ahead of <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> in gaining its 28th victory in 33 weeks. <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> won the previous week largely on the strength of the final episode of `` Magnum, P.I.'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> also won the top nine places, the first time a network has done that since <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> for the week of Nov. 3, 1980. `` Cheers'' took first place. The only non-NBC show to make the top 10 was <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Who's the Boss?'' Besides regular series, the <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> movie `` The Taking of Flight 847: The <PERSON> Uli </PERSON> <PERSON> Derickson </PERSON> Story'' was seventh and the first half of the miniseries `` Something Is Out There'' was ninth. <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` The Bourne Identity'' was in 11th place with its opening chapter. It teamed up with the <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> Sunday show `` Something Is Out There'' to send the <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> drama `` The Caine Mutiny Court-Martial'' to 58th place. <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s average rating for the week was 15.6; <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>' was 11.5 and <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> 11.2. The rating is a percentage of the nation's estimated 88.6 million households with televisions. In the May sweeps, which helps determine advertising rates for local stations, <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> took over first place from <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>. The ratings in the Nielsen sweeps for April 28-May 8: <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> 14.9, <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> 13.1, <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> 10.4. The Arbitron sweeps for April 27-May 8: <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> 14.8, <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> 12.9, <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> 10.7. `` The Cosby Show'' was the only rerun in the top 10 and, in fact the only one in the top 36 shows last week. More than half the shows in the bottom half of the ratings also were new. Here are the top 10: `` Cheers,'' `` A Different World,'' `` Night Court,'' `` The Cosby Show,'' `` Golden Girls,'' `` <LOCATION> L.A. </LOCATION> Law,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> Monday Movie, `` The Taking of Flight 847: The <PERSON> Uli </PERSON> <PERSON> Derickson </PERSON> <PERSON> Story </PERSON>,'' `` Amen,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> Sunday Movie, `` Something Is Out There,'' Part I, all <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, and <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Who's the Boss?'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> kept its lead among the evening news shows. The ratings: <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> 10.2, <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> 9.3, <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> 8.6.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880511-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-11-88 0241EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-NielsensList     05-11 0697</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nielsens List,0778</SECOND>
<HEAD>List of Week's Top-Rated TV Shows</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Nielsens</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the prime-time television ratings as compiled by the <ORGANIZATION> A.C. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nielsen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> for the week of May 2-8. Top 20 listings include the week's ranking, with full season-to-date ranking in parentheses, rating for the week, and total homes. An `` X'' in parentheses denotes one-time-only presentation. A rating measures the percentage of the nation's 88.6 million TV homes. 1. -LRB- 3 -RRB- `` Cheers,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 22.8 rating, 20.2 million homes. 2. -LRB- 2 -RRB- `` A Different World,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 22.2, 19.7 million homes. 3. -LRB- 7 -RRB- `` Night Court,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 21.7, 19.2 million homes. 4. -LRB- 1 -RRB- `` The Cosby Show,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 21.5, 19.0 million homes. 5. -LRB- 4 -RRB- `` Golden Girls,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 21.2, 18.8 million homes. 6. -LRB- 13 -RRB- `` <LOCATION> L.A. </LOCATION> Law,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 20.2, 17.9 million homes. 7. -LRB- 23 -RRB- `` The Taking of Flight 847: The <ORGANIZATION> Uli </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Derickson </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Story </ORGANIZATION>'' _ `` NBC Monday Night Movies,'' 19.7, 17.4 million homes. 8. -LRB- 15 -RRB- `` Amen,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 19.4, 17.2 million homes. 9. -LRB- 25 -RRB- `` Something Is Out There,'' Part 1, _ `` <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> Sunday Night Movie,'' 19.3, 17.1 million homes. 10. -LRB- 5 -RRB- `` Who's the Boss?'', <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 18.7, 16.6 million homes. 11. -LRB- 38 -RRB- `` The Bourne Identity,'' Part 1, _ `` <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> Sunday Night Movie,'' 18.5, 16.4 million homes. 12. -LRB- 9 -RRB- `` Murder, She Wrote,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 18.3, 16.2 million homes. 13. -LRB- 10 -RRB- `` Just the Ten of Us,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 18.0, 15.9 million homes. 14. -LRB- 8 -RRB- `` 60 Minutes,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 16.3, 14.4 million homes. 14. -LRB- 29 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Hunter </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 16.3, 14.4 million homes. 16. -LRB- 5 -RRB- `` Growing Pains,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 16.2, 14.3 million homes. 17. -LRB- 16 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Matlock </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 16.1, 14.3 million homes. 18. -LRB- 21 -RRB- `` <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION>,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 15.6, 13.8 million homes. 18. -LRB- 31 -RRB- `` Knots Landing,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 15.6, 13.8 million homes. 20. -LRB- 12 -RRB- `` ALF,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 15.5, 13.7 million homes.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 21. -LRB- 23 -RRB- `` Head of the Class,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 15.4. 22. -LRB- 47 -RRB- `` Necessity'' _ `` CBS Tuesday Movie,'' 15.0. 23. -LRB- 48 -RRB- `` <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> Vice,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 14.8. 24. -LRB- 29 -RRB- `` 227,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 14.7. 25. -LRB- 21 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Valerie </PERSON>'s Family,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 14.5. 26. -LRB- 34 -RRB- `` Hooperman,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 14.0. 27. -LRB- 33 -RRB- `` Onassis: The Richest Man in the World,'' Part 2, _ `` <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> Monday Night Movie,'' 13.9. 28. -LRB- 25 -RRB- `` In the Heat of the Night,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.6. 29. -LRB- 27 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Newhart </PERSON>,'' CBS, 13.4. 30. -LRB- 53 -RRB- `` MacGyver,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.3. 31. -LRB- 42 -RRB- `` Facts of Life,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.2. 31. -LRB- 44 -RRB- `` <LOCATION> Falcon </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Crest </LOCATION>,'' CBS, 13.2. 33. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Super Bloopers & amp; Jokes,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.1. 34. -LRB- 51 -RRB- `` St. Elsewhere,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.8. 35. -LRB- 45 -RRB- `` <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION>,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.6. 36. -LRB- 36 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Aaron </PERSON>'s Way,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.3. 37. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Unsolved Mysteries Special,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.9. 37. -LRB- 54 -RRB- `` The Equalizer,'' CBS, 11.9. 37. -LRB- 14 -RRB- `` Moonlighting,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.9. 37. -LRB- 38 -RRB- `` Highway to Heaven,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.9. 41. -LRB- X -RRB- `` <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> Vice Special,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.6. 42. -LRB- 34 -RRB- `` Designing Women,'' CBS, 11.5. 43. -LRB- 69 -RRB- `` Just in Time,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.4. 44. -LRB- 49 -RRB- `` thirtysomething,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.2. 44. -LRB- 38 -RRB- `` Kate & amp; <PERSON> Allie </PERSON>,'' CBS, 11.2. 44. -LRB- 60 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Jake </PERSON> and The Fatman,'' CBS, 11.2. 47. -LRB- 57 -RRB- `` 20-20,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 10.9. 48. -LRB- 62 -RRB- `` <ORGANIZATION> Eisenhower </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> Lutz </PERSON>,'' CBS, 10.8. 49. -LRB- 67 -RRB- `` Mr. <PERSON> Belvedere </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 10.7. 49. -LRB- 62 -RRB- `` Crime Story,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 10.7. 51. -LRB- 71 -RRB- `` Full House,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 10.3. 52. -LRB- 82 -RRB- `` Smothers Bros. Comedy Hour,'' CBS, 10.0. 53. -LRB- 37 -RRB- `` Perfect Strangers,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 9.8. 53. -LRB- 54 -RRB- `` Beauty and the <LOCATION> Beast </LOCATION>,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 9.8. 53. -LRB- 57 -RRB- `` <ORGANIZATION> Simon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> Simon </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 9.8. 56. -LRB- 89 -RRB- `` 48 Hours: Top Dog,'' CBS, 9.4. 56. -LRB- 56 -RRB- `` <ORGANIZATION> Cagney </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> Lacey </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 9.4. 56. -LRB- 18 -RRB- `` The <ORGANIZATION> Caine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mutiny </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Martial </ORGANIZATION>'' _ `` CBS Sunday Movie,'' 9.4. 59. -LRB- 73 -RRB- `` Spenser: For Hire,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 9.3. 60. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Remembering <PERSON> Marilyn </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 8.3. 61. -LRB- 98 -RRB- `` West 57th,'' CBS, 8.2. 62. -LRB- 75 -RRB- `` Tour of Duty,'' CBS, 8.1. 63. -LRB- 73 -RRB- `` Splash, Too,'' Part 2, _ `` Disney Sunday Movie,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 7.2. 63. -LRB- 62 -RRB- `` Dolly!'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 7.2. 63. -LRB- 75 -RRB- `` High Mountain Rangers,'' CBS, 7.2. 66. -LRB- 72 -RRB- `` Our House,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 7.1. 67. -LRB- 57 -RRB- `` The Slap Maxwell Story,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 6.9. 68. -LRB- 83 -RRB- `` Buck <PERSON> James </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 6.8. 69. -LRB- 95 -RRB- `` Hotel,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 6.6. 70. -LRB- 90 -RRB- `` <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION> Knights,'' CBS, 6.5. 71. -LRB- 96 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Ohara </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 6.3. 72. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s Most Wanted,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 6.0. 73. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` 21 Jump Street,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 5.3. 74. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` Married ... With Children,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 5.2. 75. -LRB- 105 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Max </PERSON> <PERSON> Headroom </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 4.8. 76. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` <PERSON> Garry </PERSON> <PERSON> Shandling </PERSON> Show,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 4.3. 77. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` <PERSON> Garry </PERSON> <PERSON> Shandling </PERSON> Show Special,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 3.8. 78. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` <PERSON> Tracey </PERSON> <PERSON> Ullman </PERSON> Show,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 2.8. 79. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` Boys Will Be Boys,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 2.7. 80. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` Family Double Dare,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 2.4.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880511-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-11-88 0259EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--Argentina-US     05-11 0155</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Argentina-US,0160</SECOND>
<HEAD>Argentina To Take Part In U.S. Naval Games</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BUENOS AIRES, Argentina (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Argentina </LOCATION> will take part in naval exercises with the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> for the first time since the 1982 Falklands War. <PERSON> Raul </PERSON> <PERSON> Alconada </PERSON> <PERSON> Sempe </PERSON>, secretary of foreign affairs, said on Tuesday that <LOCATION> Argentina </LOCATION> will participate in `` Operation <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>,'' with <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and several of the Latin countries that once took part in `` Operation Unitas.'' <LOCATION> Argentina </LOCATION> quit the Unitas war games after the <LOCATION> Falklands </LOCATION> conflict to protest what it said was <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> assistance to <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>. The 74-day war over the islands <LOCATION> Argentina </LOCATION> calls the Malvinas killed 712 Argentine and 256 British soldiers. Final details of the exercises next year are to be completed this week in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> while <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> commander Adm. <PERSON> Ramon </PERSON> <PERSON> Arosa </PERSON> is visiting <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Norfolk </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Alconada </PERSON> <PERSON> Sempe </PERSON> said. Naval vessels from the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Argentina </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Chile </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Peru </LOCATION> took part in the Unitas exercises.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880511-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-11-88 0304EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--Italy-Customs     05-11 0115</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Italy-Customs,0116</SECOND>
<HEAD>Customs Dispute Resolved Ending Delays At Italian Border Points</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ROME (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Government and union negotiators settled a labor dispute involving customs officials that had backed up freight at border points. The settlement was reached Tuesday by Finance Minister <PERSON> Emilio </PERSON> <PERSON> Colombo </PERSON> and union leaders. <LOCATION> Colombo </LOCATION> said <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>'s customs administration will be reformed to grant customs officers a pay raise and to redefine their duties. Thousands of trucks were backed up at the crossing points with <LOCATION> Switzerland </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Austria </LOCATION> last week after Italian officers refused to work overtime to clear customs documents. An official at the Italian-Swiss border point of <LOCATION> Chiasso </LOCATION> said the situation was back to normal after the settlement was announced.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880511-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-11-88 0304EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--Italy-Slayings     05-11 0126</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Italy-Slayings,0128</SECOND>
<HEAD>Four People Found Slain In Italian Villa</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SAN ANDREA IN BASANICO, Italy (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Four people were found shot to death in a ransacked villa near the <LOCATION> Adriatic </LOCATION> beach resort of <LOCATION> Rimini </LOCATION>, police said. The victims, whose hands and feet were bound, were killed with a shot through the head, police said. They were identified as <PERSON> Luigi </PERSON> <PERSON> Pagliarani </PERSON>, 60, and his wife, <PERSON> Patricia </PERSON> <PERSON> Schfield </PERSON>, 58, and <PERSON> Sergio </PERSON> <PERSON> Galassi </PERSON>, 66, and his wife <PERSON> Silvana </PERSON> <PERSON> di </PERSON> <PERSON> Vita </PERSON>, 59. Police in the nearby town of <LOCATION> Riccione </LOCATION> said a relative of <LOCATION> Pagliarani </LOCATION> discovered the bodies Tuesday in the living room of the small villa. The safe was empty and the house had been ransacked, police said, adding that it appeared the couples were victims of a robbery.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880511-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-11-88 0748EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a BC-Dance     05-11 0443</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Dance,0454</SECOND>
<HEAD>Agnes de Mille's `The Informer' Ballet Opens in NY</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: No PMs Planned</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By MARY CAMPBELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 `` The Informer,'' a new ballet choreographed by <PERSON> Agnes </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Mille </PERSON> for American Ballet Theater, is a gripping anti-war work certain to become a favorite of audiences for years to come. It's a strong ballet, crisp, clear and deeply felt, with light moments and ominous ones, danced against sets with glowering gray skies. Based on the 1935 movie about strife in <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION> between 1916 and 1921, it is set to Celtic songs, and every wave of the hand, flip or sweep of a scarf and every jig-like jump is identifiably Irish. The <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> premiere Tuesday at the <ORGANIZATION> Metropolitan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Opera </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> was danced with muscular eloquence. <PERSON> Victor </PERSON> <PERSON> Barbee </PERSON> danced the wounded veteran, <PERSON> Johan </PERSON> <PERSON> Renvall </PERSON> the young fighter and red-haired <PERSON> Kathleen </PERSON> <PERSON> Moore </PERSON> the girl. A corps de ballet of 20, as Dubliners, danced superbly. Miss <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Mille </PERSON> had <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Beth </PERSON> <PERSON> Griffith </PERSON> as Irish step-dancing consultant. The choreographer used the timing of quick Irish dance steps, as well as the way feet turn and legs cross each other. The story is crystal clear, almost all of it in dance with very little relying on mime. The young fighter, whose steps are carefree, likes the girl _ and other girls. She likes him but when he leaves with somebody else she flirts with the veteran, who holds one gloved hand, presumably artificial, close to his waist. The veteran is self-conscious, has intense feeling for the girl _ he lifts her with one hand _ and is jealous. So he points out the young fighter to unseen English soldiers. Women mourn the young fighter, heads thrown back then down, mouths silently screaming. In one enormously effective scene, the veteran is alone as dawn comes, revealing silhouettes of men hanged by the English. The veteran tries to strut but is stiff, unable to free his body from his realization of what he did. In the next scene, the girl finds consolation dancing with the veteran. But he confesses to her and she runs in horror to her friends. They shun her at first but take her into their measured line dancing. When the veteran arrives, there is a long silence before two men walk him into the wings. At the end of the half-hour dance Tuesday, <ORGANIZATION> Miss </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> de </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mille </ORGANIZATION>, who suffered a stroke in 1975, walked on stage arm in arm with company artistic director <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> Baryshnikov </PERSON>. The audience, which had watched the ballet in rapt silence, stood to applaud, and bravos rang out. `` The Informer'' was premiered in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> in March.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880511-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-11-88 0309EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--Yugoslavia-Strike     05-11 0131</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Yugoslavia-Strike,0134</SECOND>
<HEAD>1,000 Workers Strike At Contruction Plant In Yugoslavia</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BELGRADE, Yugoslavia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 More than 1,000 employees stopped work at a construction plant in southern <LOCATION> Yugoslavia </LOCATION> and demanded their March wages and a pay increase, the <ORGANIZATION> Tanjug </ORGANIZATION> news agency reported. Three hours after the stoppage began Tuesday at the Ramiz Sadiku plant in <LOCATION> Pristina </LOCATION>, its director, <PERSON> Nijazi </PERSON> <PERSON> Hoxha </PERSON>, and union leaders told the workers that March wages would be paid but they would not receive a pay increase. <ORGANIZATION> Tanjug </ORGANIZATION> said some workers were satisfied with that offer but that others threatened to continue the strike. Officials said a record 365,000 workers took part in more than 1,570 strikes in <LOCATION> Yugoslavia </LOCATION> last year. The government is planning a new economic program to make the centrally run economy more market oriented.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880511-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-11-88 0750EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lites     05-11 0757</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lites,0789</SECOND>
<HEAD>On The Light Side</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BEDFORD, Ind. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A Japanese monkey on the loose for 10 months in southern <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION> is feasting on bananas, peanut butter and cat food this week while authorities try to figure out how to capture the wily fugitive. `` He's been here twice today so far,'' said <PERSON> Janice </PERSON> <PERSON> Rodgers </PERSON>, who spotted the Japanese macaque last week and began feeding it. `` He ate peanut butter sandwiches yesterday because I was out of bananas,'' she said Tuesday. `` He liked them real well, except he got real disgusted when he got peanut butter between his _ I guess you would call them his fingers.'' The Japanese macaque, dubbed `` Jack the Macaque'' by Mrs. <PERSON> Rodgers </PERSON>, stands about 3 -LCB- feet tall, weighs about 30 pounds and has a silky, tan coat. Macaques are generally found in southern <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION> and the East Indies. <PERSON> Jack </PERSON>, a resourceful little primate, survived the winter apparently by foraging. Conservation officers say he runs away as soon as someone in uniform appears. `` He's a pretty smart monkey,'' said <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Ault </PERSON>, conservation officer at <LOCATION> Paynetown </LOCATION>. `` He's kind of allergic to uniforms.'' He escaped about 10 months ago from the Reptile Kingdom in <LOCATION> Brown </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, about 35 miles from Mrs. <PERSON> Rodgers </PERSON>' home here near the Hoosier National Forest. Attempts to recapture the monkey have failed. On Friday, <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> turned up his nose at three tranquilized bananas in favor of a dish of cat food behind the <PERSON> Rodgers </PERSON>' house. `` He had n't done that before,'' said Mrs. <PERSON> Rodgers </PERSON>. `` Then he went out and sat down by the bananas and took a couple of bites and spit them out.'' <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> was a little woozy, but made it back to the woods. When Mrs. <PERSON> Rodgers </PERSON> first saw the monkey last Wednesday she called her husband, <PERSON> Sam </PERSON>, who was at work. While he phoned the sheriff's department, she offered <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> some apples, carrots and bread `` He just kind of looked at me like, ` Oh, please.' I did n't really know what to do,'' she said `` I did n't want to scare him away, so I did what I thought -LRB- ape researcher -RRB- <PERSON> Jane </PERSON> <PERSON> Goodall </PERSON> would do, I squatted down low so that I was about his size.'' When the police car pulled up, the monkey grabbed an apple and carrot and ran for the woods. The animal is n't considered especially dangerous, though Mrs. <PERSON> Rodgers </PERSON> said owner <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Tilton </PERSON> told her the monkey might attack if he felt threatened. `` He's just as cute as he can be,'' said Mrs. <PERSON> Rodgers </PERSON>, adding that she wo n't be too disappointed if future attempts to recapture the monkey also fail. `` I know the owner wants him back,'' she said. `` But I just could n't stand for them to drug him.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>JACKSON, Miss. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Five <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> ninth-graders who beat 200 other teams playing a stock market simulation say they used the strategies and tactics of real investors to reap a $ 110,723 `` paper profit.'' And just like real investors they had a fearful day when the market crashed on Oct. 19. As the stock market plummeted 508 points, they were left holding a handful of cheap stocks that no one wanted to buy. `` We lost $ 34,000,'' said <ORGANIZATION> Auburn </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wessman </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bailey </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Alternative </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION>. `` We wanted to buy some penny stocks because they go up a higher percentage. But the crash came along, and they just went down, down, down.'' The 15-year-old is one of five <PERSON> Bailey </PERSON> ninth-graders who played the stock market in a 10-week game sponsored by <ORGANIZATION> McLarty </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ; </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> and The <ORGANIZATION> Clarion-Ledger-Jackson </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION>. More than 200 <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> teams competed with others across the nation in the game, developed by the <ORGANIZATION> Securities </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Industries </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> and coordinated by the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Enterprise </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>. Each team started with an imaginary $ 100,000 and a $ 100,000 line of credit. They bought and sold stocks according to daily closing prices, and even paid imaginary broker fees. The Bailey group, led by government teacher <PERSON> Johnny </PERSON> <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON>, followed stocks in <ORGANIZATION> USA </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Today </ORGANIZATION> and watched business reports daily. They met for two hours every week to make plans to buy and sell. Their strategy was to short-sell an engineering stock, get rid of two others at a profit, and hold onto the earnings with stable <ORGANIZATION> IBM </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON> wanted his six teams to learn how to take risks and how to recover from mistakes. He offered advice but did n't force the teams to follow it. `` I just told them to ask, ` What companies might make some money?''' <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON> said. `` It's hard to teach the risk, but I told them it's like a big crap game.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880511-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-11-88 0309EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--Bermuda-Plane     05-11 0132</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Bermuda-Plane,0134</SECOND>
<HEAD>American Airlines Jet Makes Emergency Landing In Bermuda</HEAD>
<DATELINE>HAMILTON, Bermuda (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> jetliner carrying 90 people on a flight from <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Puerto </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rico </LOCATION> made an emergency landing in <LOCATION> Bermuda </LOCATION> after the plane's fuel pump manfunctioned, an airline spokesman said. No injuries were reported when the Flight 699 landed on the British island Tuesday, said an official at the Civil Aviation office in <LOCATION> Hamilton </LOCATION>, who spoke with The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> on condition of anonymity. <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> McGregor </PERSON>, an airline spokesman in <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION>, said without elaborating that the pilot decided to land the plane in <LOCATION> Bermuda </LOCATION> after reporting a malfunction of the plane's fuel pump. <PERSON> McGregor </PERSON> said a DC-10 was sent to <LOCATION> Bermuda </LOCATION> from <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> to pickup the stranded passengers and fly them to <LOCATION> Puerto </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rico </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880511-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-11-88 0801EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-WeddingAtLast     05-11 0227</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Wedding At Last,0231</SECOND>
<HEAD>Man Facing Surgery Marries Companion Of 23 Years</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BELLE GLADE, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 After 23 years of living in sin, an 84-year-old cancer patient married his 74-year-old companion in a hospital ceremony arranged and attended by his nurses a day before surgery. <PERSON> Emma </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> stood beside <PERSON> Charlie </PERSON> <PERSON> Vickers </PERSON> in a wheelchair and legally tied the knot Tuesday in a Glades General Hospital lounge as 25 nurses and doctors looked on, hosital spokesman <PERSON> Kerry </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Aunce </PERSON> said. <ORGANIZATION> Palm </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Beach </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Circuit </ORGANIZATION> Judge <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Adams </PERSON> performed the marriage. `` I do n't believe the doctor is going to be able to get me through this, and I want to get my soul ready for the Lord,'' <PERSON> Vickers </PERSON> said of his colon surgery. `` We've been together for 23 years and if something happens, I want us to be married.'' <PERSON> Vickers </PERSON> said he gave up drinking moonshine when he was younger and gave up cigarettes after a colostomy a year ago. `` Smoking is a sin and sleepingwith someone you're not married to is a sin,'' he said. `` It does n't do any good to quit one if you're not going to quit it all, so I wanted to get married and quit it all.'' <PERSON> Vickers </PERSON>, who is scheduled for surgery today, also wanted Ms. <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> to be able to collect his Social Security should he die in surgery, <PERSON> Aunce </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880511-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-11-88 0032EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-MultipleKillings 1stLd-Writethru a0774 05-11 0818</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Multiple Killings, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0774,0838</SECOND>
<HEAD>Witnesses Describe Grinning Gunman; Prosecutor Seeks Death Penalty</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: LEADS with 11 grafs to UPDATE with later testimony, more on
grinning gunman, other shootings, victims showing scars to jury,
identifying Simmons as gunman, picking up 8th graf ``I saw...''</NOTE>
<HEAD>LaserPhotos XOZ1,2</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BILL SIMMONS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>OZARK, Ark. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A man accused of killing 16 people, including 14 family members, grinned as he squeezed off shots during a 45-minute rampage at four businesses, according to people he allegedly shot or tried to shoot. <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gene </PERSON> <PERSON> Simmons </PERSON>, a 47-year-old retired <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> master sergeant, is being tried in the fatal shootings of former co-worker <PERSON> Kathy </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kendrick </PERSON>, 24, and <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Chaffin </PERSON>, 33, Dec. 28 in <LOCATION> Russellville </LOCATION>. Four people were wounded. <PERSON> Simmons </PERSON> is scheduled to face a separate trial July 18 in the slayings of 14 relatives. Prosecutor <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Bynum </PERSON>, who told the jury he would ask for the death penalty, said in his opening statement that <PERSON> Miss </PERSON> <PERSON> Kendrick </PERSON>, a legal secretary, was shot at least four times in the head as she sat at her desk. Officials have said she had spurned <PERSON> Simmons </PERSON>' advances a year earlier. Police have said <PERSON> Chaffin </PERSON> was a chance victim of shooting several minutes later at <ORGANIZATION> Taylor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Oil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, several blocks from the law office. <PERSON> Simmons </PERSON> had once worked at the oil company and had been the boss of <PERSON> Russell </PERSON> <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON>, whom he allegedly wounded there. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Salyer </PERSON>, shot in the forehead at a small market he owned and where <PERSON> Simmons </PERSON> had once worked, said that when <PERSON> Simmons </PERSON> `` squeezed the first shot, he was grinning.'' A witness in the convenience store shooting, <PERSON> Tony </PERSON> <PERSON> Carta </PERSON>, said he saw <PERSON> Simmons </PERSON> lean over a counter of the market and shoot cashier <PERSON> Roberta </PERSON> <PERSON> Woolery </PERSON> in the face. The bullet went in her mouth and out her jaw. Both <PERSON> Salyer </PERSON> and <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON>, who showed their scars to the jury, identified <PERSON> Simmons </PERSON> as the man who shot them. <PERSON> Simmons </PERSON> surrendered after another shooting at a motor freight company, where he allegedly wounded a woman who once had been his boss. Earlier, <PERSON> Juli </PERSON> <PERSON> Money </PERSON>, who worked with <PERSON> Chaffin </PERSON> at the oil company, testified that she saw <PERSON> Chaffin </PERSON> shot on what was her first day at work. She said she heard shots, then saw a door fly open as <PERSON> Chaffin </PERSON> reached for it. `` I saw an arm raise up through a window in the door. It shot and <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> went down,'' she testified. Ms. <PERSON> Money </PERSON> said she was trying to see what was going on and `` wondering whether it was a practical joke'' when `` <PERSON> Simmons </PERSON> stepped over his body, took a stance, and pointed the gun at me. I screamed, ` No,' and dived behind some boxes. `` He was grinning. He had a horrid grin _ it looked like he had false teeth _ and his eyes were wide open.'' She said she grabbed her head because `` I thought I had been shot because I felt the heat from the bullet'' as it whizzed past. She was uninjured. After <PERSON> Simmons </PERSON> surrendered, the bodies of his wife and 13 other relatives were found on his property in <LOCATION> Dover </LOCATION>, 47 miles east of <LOCATION> Ozark </LOCATION>. If convicted of murder, <PERSON> Simmons </PERSON> could be sentenced to death or life in prison without parole. <PERSON> Bynum </PERSON> asked for the maximum penalty on all charges, while <PERSON> Simmons </PERSON>' attorney, <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> `` </PERSON> <PERSON> Doc </PERSON><PERSON> '' </PERSON> <PERSON> Irwin </PERSON>, urged that the jurors `` not be bullied by public opinion, by what the press may say or by what the public may say.'' <PERSON> Irwin </PERSON> asked jurors to consider conflicting statements given by witnesses in describing the gunman. <PERSON> Brenda </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> of <PERSON> Atkins </PERSON> testified Tuesday that she was in the law office on business when <PERSON> Simmons </PERSON> came in and stood in front of Miss <PERSON> Kendrick </PERSON>'s desk. The man had his hands in his pockets but jerked his right arm up and started firing a pistol, she testified. `` He missed her at first,'' she said. `` She just stood there. He kept shooting. Finally, he hit her.'' Mrs. <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> said she was afraid to move and put her head down. When she looked up, <PERSON> Simmons </PERSON> glanced at her and walked out, she said. Asked by <PERSON> Irwin </PERSON> why she had not identified <PERSON> Simmons </PERSON> when she saw him at the police department on Dec. 28, Mrs. <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> said <PERSON> Simmons </PERSON> had kept his head down. She identified <PERSON> Simmons </PERSON> on Jan. 13 from photographs. About 60 spectators were in the courtoom, including relatives of some of <PERSON> Simmons </PERSON>' family members. <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> McNulty </PERSON>, 36, of <PERSON> Bryant </PERSON>, whose brother was among the dead family members, said, `` We've got our grief to deal with and <PERSON> Gene </PERSON> <PERSON> Simmons </PERSON> has got God to deal with.'' <PERSON> Viola </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Shields </PERSON>, 51, sister of <PERSON> Simmons </PERSON>' late wife, <PERSON> Becky </PERSON>, and <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Shields </PERSON>, 53, both of <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Payne </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ala. </LOCATION>, said they sat in the front row because they wanted to make certain that <PERSON> Simmons </PERSON> saw them. `` It's hard for us not to have some hate,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880511-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-11-88 0757EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-DefenseSpending Bjt   05-11 0705</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Defense Spending, Bjt,660</SECOND>
<HEAD>Senate Votes For Panel To Determine Military Closings</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TIM AHERN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> has decided to create a buffer against the political consequences of deciding which of the nation's 3,600 military installationver the proposal that was tacked onto a <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> budget bill. Studies by the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Armed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> have estimated that between $ 1 billion and $ 5 billion a year can be saved if unneeded bases can be closed. Sen. <PERSON> Strom </PERSON> <PERSON> Thurmond </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-S.C. </LOCATION>, summed up the political dilemma Tuesday when he told colleagues: `` The real issue is one that concerns each of us _ and that is the potential loss of jobs in our states and resulting economic dislocations. These are very real concerns.'' Sen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> McCain </PERSON>, R-Ariz., said, `` There is a perception in the country, and I think it's accurate, that <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> can not act to close a single base because of the political ramifications. The Pentagon has not closed any major <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> installations since 1977, when <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> erected a series of stiff legal barriers to the periodic attempts to pare down the nation's military infrastructure. The Pentagon last proposed closing bases in 1985, when it said 22 facilities could be shut down. But that idea ran into a storm of opposition on <LOCATION> Capitol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION> and was later dropped. As it works through the bill, the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> is also trying to answer another politically tricky question of whether to have the military more deeply involved in the anti-drug fight. <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Carlucci </PERSON> said Tuesday he opposes such moves. `` I do not believe law enforcement, making arrests, is appropriate'' for the military, he told a <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> subcommittee. `` I think it is unwise to get the military into the law enforcement question. ... Do we shoot people? Do we shoot down planes?'' The <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> voted 385-23 last week to order President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> to have the military seal <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> borders against drug traffickers and a similar plan is expected to be offered to the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> leaders are searching for a compromise on some type of anti-drug plan, much as the base-closing commission proposal was hammered out among congressional and <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> officials in recent months. Legislators agreed that base closings should be considered in the effort to stretch increasingly scarce dollars in the federal budget, but wanted to be sure they had a say in the process. The original commission plan proposed a nine-member panel, but Sen. <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Dixon </PERSON>, D-Ill., opposed that, saying it would give `` absolute power to the Department of Defense. Sen. <PERSON> Carl </PERSON> <PERSON> Levin </PERSON>, D-Mich., agreed, noting that `` the publics in our communities rely on these bases ... When these bases are closed, it better not look political.'' Senate Minority Leader <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> admitted that closing bases, and the resulting loss of jobs, is politically sensitive. But he added that `` I hope we can close some. ... I know there are some that are unneeded.'' The 15-member commission would include the nine members already announced by <PERSON> Carlucci </PERSON> and six more <PERSON> Carlucci </PERSON> will appoint with the approval of key legislators. The commission is supposed to finish its work by Dec. 31, and if it proposes a list of installations to be closed, <PERSON> Carlucci </PERSON> will have to accept or reject the entire list. His decision can be blocked only by a vote of both the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>. Sen. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Roth </PERSON>, R-Del., said, `` In light of our current budgetary deficit, the need to save $ 2 billion a year is clear and obvious. The commission proposal is not in the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> version of the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> budget measure, but that chamber is expected to consider a separate bill which includes the commission. The competing bills that will be approved in the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> eventually will go to a conference committee to reconcile differences, including the base-closing plan. Both bills authorize $ 299.5 billion in defense spending for the fiscal year beginning Oct. 1.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880511-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-11-88 0246EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-SummitWorries Bjt   05-11 0729</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Summit Worries, Bjt,710</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHINGTON WIRE: Administration Lowering Expectations for Summit</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP News Analysis</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By HENRY GOTTLIEB</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration is adopting a `` What, me worry?'' attitude on whether <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> inaction on the Intermediate-range Nuclear Forces treaty will cloud the <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> summit due to start May 29. And according to several private experts, the stance may be justified. Not more than two weeks ago, summit planners were confident that President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and Soviet leader <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> would be able to crown three years of summitry by exchanging the final, fully ratified documents of the INF treaty the superpowers had been negotiating off and on since 1981. After all, the pact had run the gantlet of hearings, past senators eager to hack away at the treaty, and it emerged with only a few dents. Head counters expected that only a dozen or so senators would vote no on final ratification and that the vote could occcur before the summit. To complete the INF process in time for the <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> meetings seemed doubly important because it had become clear that <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> were still far from reaching their goal of a 30 percent to 50 percent cut in long-range missiles and bombers _ the so-called START agreement. The leaders would be saying, in essence, `` Well, we've stumbled a bit on START, but let's not dwell on it; signing this final, ratified, INF pact will give us a chance to remind the world we can make progress on arms control.'' In the past two weeks, however, glitches have emerged in the INF treaty, mostly over the meaning of verification provisions, and the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> has decided to postpone ratification work indefinitely. The administration is optimistic it will clear away the differences in time for the summit, but that is unlikely to leave the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> time to act. Is the administration worried the failure will hurt the summit? `` Of course not,'' <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Redman </PERSON> said on Tuesday. Like other <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials who spoke on condition of anonymity, <PERSON> Redman </PERSON> said the differences between the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and the Soviets are merely technical and will be resolved. If the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> fails to act in time for the summit, it can do the work afterward and the ratification documents can be exchanged later in the year. The treaty will eliminate ground-launched missiles with ranges between 315 miles and 3,125 miles. Secretary of State <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> was in <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> today to meet Soviet Foreign Minister <PERSON> Eduard </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shevardnadze </PERSON> to try to resolve the INF differences and the administration officials predicted that if <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> and his negotiators are willing to shake hands on a settlement, the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> will go along. <PERSON> Janusz </PERSON> <PERSON> Bugajski </PERSON>, an expert on <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> who works at the <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Strategic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Studies </ORGANIZATION>, believes that with the failure of the superpowers to reach agreement on long-range systems, the spotlight at the summit will be on human rights and regional issues rather than on arms control. Theoretically, <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> could try to win propaganda points by raising the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>'s ratification delay as an alleged example of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> hesitancy to end the arms race, <PERSON> Bugajski </PERSON> said. `` But that's not likely, because <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> wants the summit to be a success for domestic and international reasons,'' <PERSON> Bugajski </PERSON> said. `` We do n't need an INF treaty ratified in time for the summit, we just need it not to be scuttled and that's not going to happen,'' said <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Goldberg </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> RAND </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> consultant and expert on Soviet military affairs. `` Remember, the vast majority of people in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> want to ratify the INF treaty eventually,'' <PERSON> Goldberg </PERSON> said. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> T. </PERSON> <PERSON> Hackett </PERSON>, a foreign policy analyst at the conservative <ORGANIZATION> Heritage </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION>, asserted that the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>'s inaction on the INF treaty reflected members' unease with the treaty despite overwhelming constituent support for approval. The last-minute disagreements over verification `` give them a chance to keep nit-picking so they do n't have to ratify it.'' <PERSON> Hackett </PERSON> added: `` <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> wants the summit to show his nation he is a commanding figure on the world stage. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> wants to put on a show to keep his approval rating high for as long as he can. `` If they ca n't sign an INF treaty they'll find something else to do with some pizazz.''
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> Gottlieb </PERSON> covers the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> for <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880511-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-11-88 0757EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-PlasticGuns Bjt   05-11 0526</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Plastic Guns, Bjt,530</SECOND>
<HEAD>Plastic Handgun Ban Clears House, Prospects Good in Senate</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LARRY MARGASAK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Legislation to ban undetectable plastic firearms could clear the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Judiciary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> this Thursday, just two days after the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> approved a similar bill with a calm that rarely accompanies gun control measures. A smooth ride for the legislation was virtually assured two weeks ago, after Attorney General <PERSON> Edwin </PERSON> <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON> and law enforcement groups agreed to a compromise version _ and the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rifle </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> went along. The <ORGANIZATION> NRA </ORGANIZATION> agreed to avoid a bruising gun control battle in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> when it became clear that no existing handguns would be prohibited under the agreement. Plastic guns are not yet a reality, but chief <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> sponsor <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Hughes </PERSON> said Tuesday the firearms could be a weapon of choice for terrorists in the future. His colleagues agreed, passing the bill 413-4. The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Judiciary subcommittee on the Constitution, meanwhile cleared a similar bill by Sen. <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Metzenbaum </PERSON> for action by the full committee. The full panel meets again on Thursday, and the gun bill is on the agenda. The Hughes bill would make it illegal to manufacture, import, sell, transfer or possess a plastic firearm, defined as a weapon with less than 3.7 ounces of metal. Maximum penalties would be five years in prison, and fines of $ 250,000 for individuals and $ 1 million for organizations. The bill contains a `` sunset'' provision that would repeal the criminal provisions after five years, enabling the law to keep pace with any advances that may occur in firearms detection technology. Voting against the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> measure were Republican Reps. <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Cheney </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION>; <PERSON> Philip </PERSON> <PERSON> Crane </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION>; <PERSON> Norman </PERSON> <PERSON> Shumway </PERSON> of <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Vucanovich </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Hughes </PERSON>' bill was introduced before the administration-police compromise, but embodies the same concept. The more precise language is in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> version, which would establish a detectability standard that would permit detection of the same weapons as the <PERSON> Hughes </PERSON> bill. However, it does not provide for a minimum content of metal in the gun. Both measures would detect all existing hanguns, thus keeping them legal for law-abiding owners. But plastic weapons that failed to meet the same metallic standard would be prohibited. <PERSON> Metzenbaum </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Ohio </LOCATION>, called the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> vote `` a major step in the right direction. I look forward to working with Congressman <PERSON> Hughes </PERSON> to make sure the <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> sends the president the strongest bill possible,'' he said Tuesday. <PERSON> Hughes </PERSON> said he saw no problem in working out a compromise between the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> language. A Winter Park, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>, company that claims to be the leader in plastic firearms technology says it has no plans to produce plastic handguns. <PERSON> Dwight </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Brunoehler </PERSON>, vice president of <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Eye </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Arms </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, said the company was working on a plastic machine gun grenade launcher that it hopes to sell to the Marines. `` We see the military business as where we want to be,'' he said, adding the company will be working on that project for at least the next two years. He said the company also has pledged never to make an undetectable plastic weapon.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880511-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-11-88 0809EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FarmScene     05-11 1068</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Farm Scene,940</SECOND>
<HEAD>Wheat Harvest Forecast Up</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DON KENDALL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Farm Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The 1988 winter wheat harvest could be around 1.62 billion bushels if the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>'s initial forecast is borne out, up 4 percent from last year's production. Based on surveys May 1, the average yield of this year's harvest is expected to be 40.7 bushels per acre, compared with 39.8 bushels per acre in 1987 when winter wheat output was 1.56 billion bushels. Farmers are expected to have about 39.8 million acres for harvest this year, up 1 percent from 39.3 million in 1987. `` As of May 1, over 60 percent of the winter wheat in the major producing states rated in good or better condition,'' said the department's report Tuesday. `` Another 28 percent is rated in fair condition.'' Winter wheat is planted in the fall and harvested the following summer. It makes up about three-fourths of total <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> wheat production. The outlook for wheat prices at the farm also has brightened, reflecting brisk export demand and a reduction in once-awesome <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> wheat stockpiles. In a related supply-and-demand report, the <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> projected total wheat production this year, based on historical trends, at 2.17 billion bushels, up slighly from 2.1 billion bushels in 1987. That would include winter wheat and other kinds planted this spring for harvest later in the year. The report also projected the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> wheat stockpile is expected to decline further to around 796 million bushels by the end of the coming marketing year on May 31, 1989, compared with more than 1.23 billion bushels of old-crop wheat expected to be carried over this June 1. <PERSON> Carl </PERSON> <PERSON> Schwensen </PERSON>, executive vice president of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Asssociation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wheat </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Growers </ORGANIZATION>, said the expected reduction in <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> wheat inventories will mean tighter supplies in the year ahead. Does that mean the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> is running low on wheat after the recent years of huge surpluses? `` That's relatively correct,'' <PERSON> Schwensen </PERSON> said. `` And if we're going to stay in the world market, we're going to have to have adequate supplies for our customers That's why we feel the acreage reserve level can be relaxed and farmers can have the opportunity to market more bushels in the 1989 season.'' <PERSON> Schwensen </PERSON> referred to a farm law provision that limits <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> to no more than a 20 percent land-idling requirement when the wheat stockpile is projected to drop below a billion bushels. At a projected 796 million bushels on May 31, 1989, that would be well below the mark. For the last two years the <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> has required wheat farmers to idle 27.5 percent of their base acreage in order to qualify for supports and other federal benefits. <PERSON> Schwensen </PERSON> said the association wants to see the 1989 requirement reduced to between 10 percent and 20 percent. Wheat market prices were projected for 1988-89 at an average range of $ 2.80 to $ 3.20 per bushel, compared with $ 2.55 estimated for 1987-88. The indicated production of winter wheat, based on May 1, prospects, are listed here. The first numbers show the total production in thousands of bushels. The second numbers are the average yields per acre for the major states.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Arkansas </LOCATION> 41,800 44 <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> 33,440 76 <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION> 91,650 39 <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION> 16,100 35 <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION> 55,300 70 <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> 63,840 57 <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION> 37,100 53 <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> 357,200 38 <ORGANIZATION> Kentucky </ORGANIZATION> 16,380 42 <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION> 31,000 50 <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION> 65,800 47 <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION> 57,200 26 <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION> 86,100 42 <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> 18,900 42 <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> 57,200 55 <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION> 181,300 37 <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION> 40,950 63 <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION> 46,500 30 <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> 15,580 41 <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> 92,800 29 <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> 89,100 54
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> may be headed for another bumper grain harvest, which the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> says could dampen import requirements if wheat quality improves from the last couple of years. In its first forecast of this year's Soviet grain production, the <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> said Tuesday that 1988 production could be 215 million metric tons of grain, up 2 percent from last year's bumper output of 211.4 million tons. The department said the harvests could include 92 million tons of wheat, 109 million tons of coarse grains such as rye, barley, oats and corn, and 14 million tons of miscellaneous grains and pulses, which include peas and beans. Officials said the harvest outlook could mean a cutback in grain imports, particularly wheat. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has been selling the Soviets huge quantities of wheat lately, all of it at subsidized prices under the department's Export Enhancement Program, or EEP. If the 1988 harvest turns out as forecast, it would be the third year in a row that Soviet grain production has exceeded 200 million tons, an unprecedented feat for that country. It also would be the third largest Soviet grain output, exceeded by the record crop of 237.4 million tons in 1978 and the 1976 harvest of 223.8 million tons. However, officials said the 1988 forecast is `` highly tentative'' and that it `` will be modified as the season progresses by both positive and negative factors, including weather developments.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A record catch of 6.9 billion pounds of fish and shellfish was landed by <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> fishermen last year, breaking the previous record of 6.5 billion pounds set in 1980, the government reports. The 1987 catch, valued at $ 3.1 billion, was up 865 million pounds from the 1986 total of 6 billion pounds, worth $ 2.8 billion, the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Oceanic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Atmospheric </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> said Tuesday. <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION> led all states in volume with a catch of 1.8 billion pounds. It was followed by <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>, with 1.7 billion pounds; <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>, 709.6 million pounds; <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, 451.7 million pounds; and <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION>, 436.7 million pounds. By value, <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> was first with a catch of $ 941.7 million, followed by <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION>, $ 315.9 million; <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION>, $ 278.9 million; <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, $ 199.7 million; and <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, $ 173.2 million.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880511-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-11-88 0312EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-SupersonicTransport     05-11 0570</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Supersonic Transport,570</SECOND>
<HEAD>Growth In Transpacific Travel Will Mean Boom In Supersonics</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By HARRY F. ROSENTHAL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 By the end of the century there will be a need for a new civilian transport plane capable of carrying 247 passengers on 5,000-mile trips at two to three times the speed of sound, says a new study. That will open a $ 200 billion-plus market for the country which first manufactures the new generation of supersonic planes for civilian use in the years 2000 to 2010, said the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aeronautics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Space </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>. The agency, however, recommended against building a production transport faster than three times the speed of sound, saying that would involve `` too great a price and with too great a delay in reaching operational service.'' At Mach 2.7, an airplane could fly from <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION> in under four hours. A body traveling at <ORGANIZATION> Mach </ORGANIZATION> 1 would be traveling at the speed of sound, and <ORGANIZATION> Mach </ORGANIZATION> 2 would equal twice the speed of sound. The study said growth in travel across the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> will justify designing and building a supersonic transport. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> had such an effort under way in the 1960s, but abandoned it because of noise-pollution problems and the high cost of fuel. `` Many technologies are much more advanced today,'' the <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> study said. `` Weight reduction and aircraft shaping are the best methods of reducing the sonic boom heard at ground level. New design methods for shaping are just now becoming avialable.'' The aircraft eventually would fly twice as far as the <ORGANIZATION> European </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Concorde </ORGANIZATION>, which has a range of 3,350 miles. The new generation of airplanes would not be the `` Orient Express'' that President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> envisioned in his State of the Union message two years ago when he announced research for a plane capable of flying 25 times the speed of sound and thus able to go into orbit. <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> jointly are now carrying out research for such a hypersonic plane and a decision will be made in 1990 on whether to build it at a cost of $ 3.3 billion. `` <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> program managers believe research for the long-range commercial market should now focus on getting the highest speed possible out of a conventionally fueled, high-speed transport,'' the agency said. Two studies were performed for <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Langley </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> by <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> McDonnell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Douglas </ORGANIZATION>, the only <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> firms building large transports. `` The <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> studies indicate that, by the year 2000, a fleet of 1,200 large, subsonic aircraft would be needed to carry the estimated worldwide, long-range traffic of 315,000 passengers per day,'' <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> said. `` By comparison, less than 800 supersonic transports, each carrying 247 passengers as far as 5,000 nautical miles, could serve the same markets.'' Timeliness in providing a viable and competitive vehicle is important if the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> is to capture a major portion of the high-speed transport market, estimated to be over $ 200 billion, <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> said. It added: `` This market could be an important factor in the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> sustaining a positive balance of trade in the aerospace market.'' The federal government would not be a financial partner in building an SST, but <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> said it has a clear charter to pursue the technologies and reduce the financial risk to aircraft builders. `` It then would be up to industry to build and sell the high-speed, civil transport on their own,'' the agency said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880511-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-11-88 0315EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-MarineMammals     05-11 0534</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Marine Mammals,530</SECOND>
<HEAD>Fisheries, Environmentalists Agree On Truce Over Coastal Fishing</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID GOELLER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
