<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880316-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-16-88 2335EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Honduras-Nicaragua 1stLd-Writethru a0953 03-16 0541</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Honduras-Nicaragua, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0953,0558</SECOND>
<HEAD>URGENT</HEAD>
<HEAD>Honduran Armed Forces Reportedly Surround Sandinista Troops</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: UPDATES thruout with Honduran troops reported surrounding
Nicaraguan soldiers; no pickup.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By FREDDY CUEVAS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>TEGUCIGALPA, Honduras (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Honduran troops on Wednesday surrounded about 2,000 Nicaraguan soldiers who entered the country chasing Contra rebels, military intelligence sources told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>. They said the Sandinista troops had crossed about 3 miles into the Honduran border province of <LOCATION> Olancho </LOCATION>, east of the capital of <LOCATION> Tegucigalpa </LOCATION>, and had remained in the area for 24 hours. One official, who asked not to be identified, said the Nicaraguan troops `` have been surrounded by our army ... and we are only waiting superior orders to enter into action.'' `` There really is tension and there is crisis, however we are acting with prudence but with strength in these affairs, and we hope that everything will stabilize in the next two days,'' he said. The Honduran military went on alert, the sources said, speaking on condition of anonymity. Foreign Minister <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Lopez </PERSON> <PERSON> Contreras </PERSON> said that <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION>' president, <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Azcono </PERSON> <PERSON> Hoyo </PERSON>, contacted Nicaraguan President <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON> to demand the withdrawal of the troops <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON> has not confirmed the presence of Sandinista soldiers in <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION>, and the <ORGANIZATION> Nicaraguan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> has denied any incursion. In <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, presidential spokesman <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> was dispatching 3,200 soldiers to southern <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION> to carry out training exercises and to be `` a signal to the governments and the people of <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>.'' He said they would not enter any combat zones. Earlier, <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said <PERSON> Azcona </PERSON> had asked the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> for help in dealing with an invasion. Intelligence officials said the Sandinista troops apparently entered <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION> to destroy a base camp of the U.S.-backed Contras. `` We have done everything possible to avoid a confrontation that would drastically affect ... both countries,'' one source said. The <ORGANIZATION> Superior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> the </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Armed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forces </ORGANIZATION>, the country's highest military body, was in session most of the day, the officials said. Earlier Wednesday, <PERSON> Azcona </PERSON> met for about six hours behind closed doors to discuss the situation with top officials and the armed forces military chiefs. <PERSON> Lopez </PERSON> <PERSON> Contreras </PERSON> told reporters at a news conference that the military command was reviewing battle plans in case the Sandinista forces continued occupying Honduran territory. In <LOCATION> Managua </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON> refused to confirm or deny that Nicaraguan troops had encroached on Honduran soil. <PERSON> Lopez </PERSON> <PERSON> Contreras </PERSON> did not comment on reports that the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration was dispatching <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> troops to <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION>. `` We do n't want to create a national panic. We only ask our compatriots to have confidence in the government and in the armed forces,'' he said. The foreign minister added that <PERSON> Azcona </PERSON> had demanded that <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON> order the `` withdrawal of the troops because they are raising tensions and producing insecurity in the border.'' <PERSON> Azcona </PERSON> also asked presidents of <LOCATION> Costa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rica </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Guatemala </LOCATION> to appeal to <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON> `` to abstain from bringing about aggressive military actions against <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Lopez </PERSON> <PERSON> Contreras </PERSON> said. `` The government and the army are ready to put into action the right of legitimate defense,'' the foreign minister declared. Military intelligence sources said that at least 2,000 Sandinista troops were inside <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION> and that another 4,500 were near the border in the <LOCATION> Bocay </LOCATION> region.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880316-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-16-88 2350EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-IRAFuneral 3rdLd-Writethru a0975 03-16 0840</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-IRA Funeral, 3rd Ld - Writethru, a0975,0863</SECOND>
<HEAD>3 Killed, Dozens Injured in Attack on IRA Funeral</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: New grafs 1-7 UPDATE with attacker identified, Paisley
denounces attack. Picks up 7th graf pvs, The litle-known ...</NOTE>
<HEAD>LaserPhotos LON14,16</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By EDITH M. LEDERER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BELFAST, Northern Ireland (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A man who fired guns and grenades from behind a tombstone killed three people and wounded 68 at an <ORGANIZATION> IRA </ORGANIZATION> graveside service Wednesday before enraged mourners cornered and beat him. Young Catholics rioted in the streets afterward. <LOCATION> Belfast </LOCATION> police arrested the gunman at the end of a wild chase over graves in the <ORGANIZATION> Milltown </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Roman </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> cemetery during which he hurled grenades at the pursuing mourners and fired until his gun jammed. They identified him as <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Stone </PERSON>, a Protestant, but gave no other information about him. Thousands of mourners screamed and dived for cover when shots shattered the silence of the cemetery in early afternoon, as the coffins of three unarmed <ORGANIZATION> IRA </ORGANIZATION> members killed by British soldiers in <LOCATION> Gibraltar </LOCATION> were being lowered into a single grave. A companion of the attacker fled in a van parked nearby, and police said they captured him in another part of the city. Both men can be held without charge for seven days. Police provided no details on the second man. Mainstream Protestant organizations disavowed the attack. The Rev. <PERSON> Ian </PERSON> <PERSON> Paisley </PERSON>, leader of the <ORGANIZATION> Protestant </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Unionist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, said all `` right-thinking Protestants'' would condemn the attack `` without any ambivalence whatsoever.'' The <ORGANIZATION> British </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Broadcasting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Belfast </LOCATION> said an anonymous caller claimed responsibility Wednesday night on behalf of the <ORGANIZATION> Protestant </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Action </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION>, but gave no recognized codeword to establish authenticity of the claim. The little-known extremist group has claimed responsibility for numerous sectarian assassinations. <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> youths ignored government and church appeals after the attack and rioted through the evening. They burned hijacked buses and other vehicles and blocked streets with flaming barricades. Palls of smoke hung over the Catholic ghettos of <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Belfast </LOCATION>. Police said they fired plastic bullets at rioters who fired a shot and threw stones at a police patrol in the <LOCATION> Ardoyne </LOCATION> district of west <LOCATION> Belfast </LOCATION>. In <LOCATION> Londonderry </LOCATION>, the province's second city, one car was hijacked and set ablaze in the Catholic Bogside district. Police identified the three people killed Wednesday as <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> McErlean </PERSON>, 20; <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Murray </PERSON>, 26; and <PERSON> Kevin </PERSON> <PERSON> Brady </PERSON>, 30. All came from Catholic areas of <LOCATION> Belfast </LOCATION>. One of those wounded at the cemetery was in critical condition and four were in seriously wounded, said a spokesman for <ORGANIZATION> Royal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Victoria </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION>. Most victims were shot or hit by shrapnel while scrambling for cover during the melee, which lasted about five minutes. <ORGANIZATION> Sinn </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fein </ORGANIZATION>, the legal political wing of the outlawed <ORGANIZATION> Irish </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>, blamed <ORGANIZATION> Protestant </ORGANIZATION> paramilitary groups and accused <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> of collusion. In <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>, aides of Prime Minister <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> said she was `` shocked and appalled.'' Her government denounced the attack as `` insane and depraved.'' It appealed for calm, as did <ORGANIZATION> Sinn </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fein </ORGANIZATION>, church leaders and the <LOCATION> Irish </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Republic </LOCATION> government in <LOCATION> Dublin </LOCATION>. Police, the British government and the <ORGANIZATION> Ulster </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, an umbrella organization of <ORGANIZATION> Protestant </ORGANIZATION> vigilante groups, and the outlawed <ORGANIZATION> Ulster </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Freedom </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fighters </ORGANIZATION> denied involvement. The largely <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> IRA </ORGANIZATION> is waging a guerrilla war to drive the British from Protestant-dominated <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION>, and <ORGANIZATION> Protestant </ORGANIZATION> paramilitary groups have grown up to fight it. <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> McGuinness </PERSON>, vice president of <ORGANIZATION> Sinn </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fein </ORGANIZATION>, said: `` It's obvious it was an attack by Loyalist -LRB- Protestant -RRB- movements. <ORGANIZATION> Sinn </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fein </ORGANIZATION> President <PERSON> Gerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Adams </PERSON> said: `` There was collusion between elements with the British Crown forces, probably the Royal Ulster Constabulary -LRB- provincial police -RRB-.'' Police said they deliberately kept away from the funeral because of assurances that the <ORGANIZATION> IRA </ORGANIZATION> would not turn it into a paramilitary display. Commandos in civilian clothes killed the guerrillas, <PERSON> Mairead </PERSON> <PERSON> Farrell </PERSON>, 31; <PERSON> Sean </PERSON> <PERSON> Savage </PERSON>, 24, and <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> McCann </PERSON>, 30, on March 6. British officials said the three were on a mission to bomb a military ceremony at the colony. Mourners were lowering Miss <PERSON> Farrell </PERSON>'s flag-draped coffin into the grave when a bearded man opened fire 15 yards away from behind a gravestone. Young men yelled `` There he is! There he is!'' and the thickset gunman bolted. His cap fell off as he reloaded his pistol, and still dodging and weaving, he fired at the youths and hurled two grenades while taunting the pursuers to keep coming, witnesses said. `` I saw a young man throwing things from the back of the mourners,'' said the Rev. <PERSON> Alec </PERSON> <PERSON> Reid </PERSON>, who was saying prayers beside the open grave. `` I thought they were stones, but it looks as if they were grenades. He was also firing shots into the crowd. There was absolute chaos.'' <PERSON> Adams </PERSON> said the two men involved in the attack entered the cemetery carrying bags and cameras and were mistaken for journalists. The attack occurred after moderate <PERSON> Andy </PERSON> <PERSON> Tyrie </PERSON> was ousted as leader of the <ORGANIZATION> Ulster </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>. Hardliners accused him of weakening the armed fight against the <ORGANIZATION> IRA </ORGANIZATION>. More than 2,600 people have been killed in <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION>'s sectarian violence since August 1969
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880316-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-16-88 0130EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-ChurchWindow     03-16 0379</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Church Window,0391</SECOND>
<HEAD>Window Nearly Mistaken As Trash Identified As A Tiffany</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MEMPHIS, Tenn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A 9-foot-tall stained glass window that was headed for the trash heap after being found in a church garage here was made by <PERSON> Louis </PERSON> <PERSON> Tiffany </PERSON>, an expert says. `` There's no question in my mind whatsoever that it's <PERSON> Tiffany </PERSON>,'' said <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Oppenheimer </PERSON>, who owns a stained glass studio in <LOCATION> Memphis </LOCATION> and is the author of numerous published articles about the craft. `` It's a glorious find.'' The window depicts the figure of <PERSON> Jesus </PERSON> and features examples of drapery glass, a technique unique to <ORGANIZATION> Tiffany </ORGANIZATION> about 1905 when the piece was made, <ORGANIZATION> Oppenheimer </ORGANIZATION> said. He said the window's intricate leading and the plating of glass in multiple layers caused him to suspect right away it was by <PERSON> Tiffany </PERSON>, who lived from 1848 to 1933 and was <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s most famous stained glass artisan. The window, which measures 4 -LCB- - by-9 feet, was found last week in a packing crate in a garage at <ORGANIZATION> Grace </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Luke </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Episcopal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Oppenheimer </ORGANIZATION> said `` The maintenance people were going to throw it out. They thought it was a crate of broken glass,'' he said. Oppenheimer said the value of the window has not been determined, but another <ORGANIZATION> Tiffany </ORGANIZATION> window at the church was appraised 10 years ago at $ 132,000. In 1977, Oppenheimer identified three of the church's windows as <PERSON> Tiffany </PERSON>'s and his findings were confirmed by <PERSON> Sotheby </PERSON> <PERSON> Parke </PERSON> <PERSON> Bernet </PERSON>, the art auction house. <PERSON> Oppenheimer </PERSON> said the crate with the newly discovered window apparently was stored in the church basement in the 1960s but was moved recently to the garage. He said the window is probably one of seven commissioned by the <ORGANIZATION> Grace </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Episcopal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION>, which merged with <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Luke </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> in 1944. <ORGANIZATION> Tiffany </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> records document at least three installations at <ORGANIZATION> Grace </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> and <PERSON> Sotheby </PERSON>'s vouches for three others. All six windows are at <ORGANIZATION> Grace </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Luke </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Oppenheimer </PERSON> said the newly discovered window is apparently the seventh work commissioned from <PERSON> Tiffany </PERSON>. `` There are certain earmarks you look for, including the glass itself,'' he said. `` When you find all of them in one panel and it comes from a church that has a history of commissioning stained glass from <LOCATION> Tiffany </LOCATION>, you just have to take a leap of faith and pronounce it <PERSON> Tiffany </PERSON>.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880316-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-16-88 0701EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--OKVacation     03-16 0157</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--OK Vacation,0162</SECOND>
<HEAD>Oklahomans Trying To Lure Snowbirds</HEAD>
<DATELINE>McALLEN, Texas (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION> officials say a vacation in their state is more than OK, and they hope a road campaign in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> will persuade `` snowbirds'' to stop by on their way back north this spring. State and private tourism supporters opened up a two-day travel show in this lower <LOCATION> Rio </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Grande </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION> city Tuesday, hoping to reach the thousands of retired Midwesterners and Canadians who spend winter in the area. `` You have to try pretty hard coming to <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> not to go through <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION>,'' <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION> Lt. Gov. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kerr </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>, who traveled to <LOCATION> McAllen </LOCATION>. A tourism survey, however, showed that `` <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION> does n't have much of an image,'' <PERSON> Kerr </PERSON> said. The state has launched a $ 1.2 million tourism promotion campaign, said <PERSON> Eugene </PERSON> <PERSON> Dilbeck </PERSON>, director of the <ORGANIZATION> Oklahoma </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tourism </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Recreation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>. State officials project they will get a five-fold return on their promotional investment.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880316-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-16-88 0139EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-People-MissAmerica     03-16 0485</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-People-Miss America,0499</SECOND>
<HEAD>Miss America Addressing Critical Needs Of Nursing Profession</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOYCE A. VENEZIA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ATLANTIC CITY, N.J. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Unlike Miss Americas of recent years, <PERSON> Kaye </PERSON> <PERSON> Lani </PERSON> <PERSON> Rae </PERSON> <PERSON> Rafko </PERSON> is not looking for movie contracts or modeling jobs after her reign ends. Instead, she is anxious to return to her job as a registered nurse at a hospital in <LOCATION> Toledo </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, working with terminally ill cancer and AIDS patients. `` After another six months of this, I'll be ready to hang up the heels and the tiara and head back to work,'' she told nurses Tuesday while visiting hospitals here. The 24-year-old former Miss <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION> is using her reign to maximize the image of her career, however, promoting the nursing profession rather than snipping ribbons to open new shopping malls or shaking hands at state fairs. The first months of Miss Rafko's reign, which began in September, were booked with appearances for the pageant's six sponsors, said pageant executive director <PERSON> Leonard </PERSON> <PERSON> Horn </PERSON>. `` But once people saw that <PERSON> Kaye </PERSON> <PERSON> Lani </PERSON> was a nurse, we cleared her schedule to make room for more public service appearances,'' said <PERSON> Horn </PERSON>, in his first year as head of the pageant. `` This is what I want Miss America to do more of anyway _ less commercial appearances and more living up to the role model that she really is.'' Miss <PERSON> Rafko </PERSON> has visited numerous hospitals and hospices and spoken to many nursing associations and medical groups. She has done a public service announcement for the nursing profession and appeared on the cover of a nursing trade journal. <PERSON> Horn </PERSON> said that <PERSON> Miss </PERSON> <PERSON> Rafko </PERSON>'s career fits in perfectly with public service appearances, acknowledging that future Miss Americas who sing or dance for a living might not have as much expertise in dealing with service-oriented groups. `` But we're going to emphasize the fact that any Miss <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> has a beneficial interest when she speaks to any number of groups, whether it's the Future Farmers of <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> or the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cancer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION>,'' he said. `` You do n't have to be a nurse to speak to those groups and make an impression. Miss <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> can make a difference simply by promoting education.'' But this year, Miss Rafko is intent on hyping her career. `` A main focus of today's <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> people is health, and fortunately I know a lot about that,'' she said. At least one other Miss <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> was inundated with special requests for speaking engagements. Miss America 1984 <PERSON> Vanessa </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>, the first black Miss <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, addressed many black organizations until she relinquished her crown in a scandal over nude photographs. But most recent Miss Americas have followed a fairly routine round of promotional appearances. `` In the past few years, many Miss Americas have concentrated on entertainment careers. There's nothing wrong with that,'' Miss <PERSON> Rafko </PERSON> said. `` Everybody has their own dreams and goals and that's what the Miss <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> pageant is all about.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880316-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-16-88 0146EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-PrisonCharges     03-16 0301</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Prison Charges,0308</SECOND>
<HEAD>Officials Say Could be Hundreds Charges In Operation Ferret</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LEE LINDER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PHILADELPHIA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Saying a special investigation uncovered `` a massive network'' of corruption in city prisons, prosecutors Tuesday announced charges against seven guards and two inmates and said there would be more. District Attorney <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Castille </PERSON> said during a press conference outside the <ORGANIZATION> Philadelphia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Detention </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> that arrests could reach into the hundreds before the 18-month investigation known as `` Operation Ferret'' is completed. Officials said the investigation was prompted by widespread reports of corruption and complaints within the system. `` The investigation will potentially yield the largest number of arrests related to official misconduct by correctional officers in this country's history,'' <PERSON> Castille </PERSON> said. He declined to give specifics. The city has five correctional institutions with between 8,500 and 9,000 inmates. The institutions are run by 1,700 employes, 1,400 of them are guards. The first charges stemmed from two incidents, an escape from <ORGANIZATION> Laurel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hall </ORGANIZATION> minimum security pre-release unit and an aggravated assault against a prisoner at a downtown <ORGANIZATION> YWCA </ORGANIZATION>, another pre-release facility. Those named in a grand jury presentment were charged with crimes ranging from aggravated assault to escape. In the <LOCATION> Laurel </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION> case, guard <PERSON> Dennis </PERSON> <PERSON> Tiest </PERSON>, prison cook <PERSON> Stanley </PERSON> <PERSON> Suder </PERSON>, and inmate <PERSON> Kenneth </PERSON> <PERSON> Lynch </PERSON> were charged with helping inmate <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Longendorfer </PERSON> escape last July. <PERSON> Longendorfer </PERSON> was serving time for terroristic threats and indecent assault. In the other incident, which occurred Feb. 16, six correctional officers were charged with an unprovoked assault on inmate <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>. <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> was hospitalized for four days after the attack, <PERSON> Castille </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Castille </PERSON> said the beating was allegedly in retaliation for <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> reporting a guard asleep at his assigned post. Those charged were officers <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Ricks </PERSON>, <PERSON> Sammie </PERSON> <PERSON> Rogers </PERSON>, <PERSON> Clemon </PERSON> <PERSON> Davis </PERSON>, <PERSON> Christ </PERSON> <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON>, <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Favano </PERSON> and Sgt. <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880316-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-16-88 0200EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-NielsensList     03-16 0655</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nielsens List,0734</SECOND>
<HEAD>List of Week's Top-Rated TV Shows</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Nielsens</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the prime-time television ratings as compiled by the <ORGANIZATION> A.C. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nielsen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> for the week of March 7-13. Top 20 listings include the week's ranking, with full season-to-date ranking in parentheses, rating for the week, and total homes. An `` X'' in parentheses denotes one-time-only presentation. A rating measures the percentage of the nation's 88.6 million TV homes. 1. -LRB- 1 -RRB- `` The Cosby Show,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 25.6 rating, 22.7 million homes. 2. -LRB- 3 -RRB- `` Cheers,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 24.9, 22.1 million homes. 3. -LRB- 2 -RRB- `` A Different World,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 23.9, 21.2 million homes. 4. -LRB- 4 -RRB- `` Night Court,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 22.7, 20.1 million homes. 5. -LRB- 6 -RRB- `` Golden Girls,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 21.4, 19.0 million homes. 6. -LRB- 9 -RRB- `` Murder, She Wrote,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 21.2, 18.8 million homes. 7. -LRB- X -RRB- `` People's Choice Awards,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 20.1, 17.8 million homes. 8. -LRB- 8 -RRB- `` 60 Minutes,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 20.0, 17.7 million homes. 8. -LRB- 5 -RRB- `` Growing Pains,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 20.0, 17.7 million homes. 10. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Aaron's Way Special,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 19.5, 17.3 million homes. 11. -LRB- 22 -RRB- `` Head of the Class,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 19.4, 17.2 million homes. 12. -LRB- 18 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Laura </PERSON> <PERSON> Lansing </PERSON> Slept Here'' _ `` NBC Monday Night Movies,'' 18.9, 16.7 million homes. 13. -LRB- 11 -RRB- `` ALF,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 18.5, 16.4 million homes. 14. -LRB- 31 -RRB- `` Pale Rider'' _ `` <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> Sunday Night Movie,'' 18.4, 16.3 million hhomes. 15. -LRB- 14 -RRB- `` Amen,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 18.2, 16.1 million homes. 16. -LRB- 7 -RRB- `` Who's the Boss?'', <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 17.8, 15.8 million homes. 17. -LRB- 14 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Matlock </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 17.6, 15.6 million homes. 18. -LRB- 26 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Hunter </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 17.4, 15.4 million homes. 19. -LRB- 29 -RRB- `` Knots Landing,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 17.2, 15.2 million homes. 20. -LRB- 19 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Valerie </PERSON>'s Family,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 16.6, 14.7 million homes.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 21. -LRB- 24 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Newhart </PERSON>,'' CBS, 16.3. 22. -LRB- 13 -RRB- `` Family Ties,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 15.9. 23. -LRB- 12 -RRB- `` <LOCATION> L.A. </LOCATION> Law,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 15.7. 24. -LRB- 19 -RRB- `` <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION>,'' CBS, 15.3. 25. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Shattered Innocence'' _ `` CBS Special Movie Presentation,'' 15.2. 26. -LRB- 24 -RRB- `` 227,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 14.4. 26. -LRB- 27 -RRB- `` Day By Day,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 14.4. 28. -LRB- 34 -RRB- `` Probe'' _ `` <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> Monday Night Movie,'' 14.2. 29. -LRB- 41 -RRB- `` <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> Vice,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.6. 30. -LRB- 36 -RRB- `` Facts of Life,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.5. 31. -LRB- 33 -RRB- `` Hooperman,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.2. 31. -LRB- 31 -RRB- `` Designing Women,'' CBS, 13.2. 33. -LRB- 49 -RRB- `` MacGyver,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.0. 34. -LRB- 73 -RRB- `` 48 Hours: Runaway Children,'' CBS, 12.9. 35. -LRB- 35 -RRB- `` Kate & amp; <PERSON> Allie </PERSON>,'' CBS, 12.7. 36. -LRB- 28 -RRB- `` Perfect Strangers,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.6. 37. -LRB- 51 -RRB- `` 20-20,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.5. 38. -LRB- X -RRB- `` <PERSON> Magic-David </PERSON> <PERSON> Copperfield </PERSON>,'' CBS, 12.4. 38. -LRB- 68 -RRB- `` Full House,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.4. 40. -LRB- 40 -RRB- `` Dynasty,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.3. 41. -LRB- 38 -RRB- `` <LOCATION> Falcon </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Crest </LOCATION>,'' CBS, 12.1. 41. -LRB- 41 -RRB- `` Supercarrier,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.1. 43. -LRB- 54 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Frank </PERSON>'s Place,'' CBS, 11.9. 43. -LRB- 23 -RRB- `` The Terminator'' _ `` NBC Sunday Night Movie,'' 11.9. 45. -LRB- 60 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Sonny </PERSON> <PERSON> Spoon </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.7. 45. -LRB- 55 -RRB- `` Highwayman,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.7. 47. -LRB- 46 -RRB- `` <ORGANIZATION> Cagney </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> Lacey </PERSON>,'' CBS, 11.6. 48. -LRB- 49 -RRB- `` The Slap Maxwell Story,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 10.7. 49. -LRB- 63 -RRB- `` Our House,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 10.3. 49. -LRB- 51 -RRB- `` <ORGANIZATION> Simon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> Simon </PERSON>,'' CBS, 10.3. 51. -LRB- 46 -RRB- `` Dolly!'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 9.8. 51. -LRB- 61 -RRB- `` Mr. <PERSON> Belvedere </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 9.8. 53. -LRB- 57 -RRB- `` A Year in the Life,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 9.5. 54. -LRB- 46 -RRB- `` Beauty and the <LOCATION> Beast </LOCATION>,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 9.4. 55. -LRB- 65 -RRB- `` Tour of Duty,'' CBS, 9.0. 56. -LRB- 64 -RRB- `` 14 Going on 30,'' Part 2, _ `` Disney Sunday Movie,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 8.8. 57. -LRB- 65 -RRB- `` Spenser: For Hire,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 8.7. 58. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Decision ` 88: Super Tuesday,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 8.5. 59. -LRB- 67 -RRB- `` Buck <PERSON> James </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 8.2. 59. -LRB- 82 -RRB- `` Probe,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 8.2. 61. -LRB- 79 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Ohara </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 8.1. 62. -LRB- 84 -RRB- `` West 57th,'' CBS, 7.9. 63. -LRB- 76 -RRB- `` Hotel,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 7.5. 64. -LRB- X -RRB- `` ` 88 Vote: Super Tuesday,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 7.2. 64. -LRB- X -RRB- `` <PERSON> Barry </PERSON> <PERSON> Manilow </PERSON>: Swing Street,'' CBS, 7.2. 66. -LRB- 79 -RRB- `` Thorns,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 6.6. 67. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` 21 Jump Street,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 6.0. 68. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Campaign ` 88: Super Tuesday,'' CBS, 5.7. 68. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` Married ... With Children,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 5.7. 70. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` Werewolf,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 4.5. 71. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Redeye Express,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 4.4. 72. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` <PERSON> Garry </PERSON> <PERSON> Shandling </PERSON> Show,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 4.2. 73. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` Duet,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 3.4. 74. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` <PERSON> Tracey </PERSON> <PERSON> Ullman </PERSON> Show,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 3.1. 75. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` Boys Will Be Boys,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 2.6. 76. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` The New Adventures of Beans Baxter,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 2.2. 76. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` Women in Prison,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 2.2. 78. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` Mr. President,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 1.7.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880316-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-16-88 0204EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-ArmedJudge     03-16 0798</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Armed Judge,0820</SECOND>
<HEAD>Honduran Judge Says He Fights To Keep Drugs Off U.S. Streets</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</NOTE>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DOUGLAS GRANT MINE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>TELA, Honduras (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 As he stripped and cleaned the AK-47 assault rifle on his desk, Federal Judge <PERSON> Miguel </PERSON> <PERSON> Angel </PERSON> <PERSON> Izaguirre </PERSON> said he has good reason to try to stop Latin American cocaine from reaching the streets of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. `` In 20 years, the youth that is taking all this cocaine will be running <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> and influencing <LOCATION> Latin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> _ with the mentality of cokeheads,'' he said. `` <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s influence in this region is tremendous. So we Latin Americans have to try to ensure that <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> youth does not take cocaine.'' The 41-year-old <PERSON> Izaguirre </PERSON> is the federal judge in this <LOCATION> Caribbean </LOCATION> coastal town. He also is a weapons buff and student of military history. `` Men, like arms, are proven on the field of battle,'' he said in an interview in his cramped and cluttered office that also contained an Uzi submachine gun. `` And this is my field of battle.'' He has survived two attempts on his life, he said _ one with an incendiary bomb, the other a machine-gun attack on his home during which he returned fire with his Soviet-made AK-47. `` I love the AK,'' he said. His arsenal of weapons, he explained, is `` to defend myself against the <ORGANIZATION> Medellin </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cartel </ORGANIZATION>.'' The <ORGANIZATION> Medellin </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cartel </ORGANIZATION>, named for the city in <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION> where it is based, is believed responsible for more than 80 percent of the cocaine smuggled into the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. `` They have tried to bribe me with money, women, airplanes and yachts,'' he said. Leaning against the wall were five segments of hollowed out <LOCATION> Honduran </LOCATION> redwood ostensibly intended for assembly into rustic doors. They are evidence from the biggest drug bust in <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> history _ the confiscation in November of four tons of cocaine by <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> federal agents in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>. The drug, shipped from the northern Honduran coast, was hidden in the hollows. `` According to our information, the shipment was 8,000 kilos -LRB- almost 9 tons -RRB-. So more than half of it got through,'' he said. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> authorities were greatly concerned when, over the past few years, <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION> became an increasingly important transshipment point for Colombian cocaine. <PERSON> Izaguirre </PERSON> has been cited as a key man in joint U.S.-Honduran efforts to reduce the flow. The judge said <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION>, with its long and relatively unguarded coast and scores of clandestine air strips, provided the ideal midpoint for northbound shipments. `` When I came here in June 1987, I found a series of cases, all of which were being dismissed for lack of evidence. ... Other judges had certain fears, some got sick, some left,'' he said. But within two months, he had handed down the first conviction and prison term for cocaine trafficking in Honduran judicial history. He has convicted 10 others on drug charges, and has nearly three dozen suspected traffickers in jail awaiting judgment. Two major traffickers based here, the <LOCATION> Colombian </LOCATION> <PERSON> Luis </PERSON> <PERSON> Guerrero </PERSON> and the Cuban-American <PERSON> Rafael </PERSON> <PERSON> Gonzalez </PERSON>, were extradited to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> after being arraigned by <PERSON> Izaguirre </PERSON>. They are both serving terms in <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> prisons. <PERSON> Izaguirre </PERSON> said he has given the maximum penalty under Honduran law to all the drug traffickers he has convicted _ five years in prison and a 5,000 lempira -LRB- $ 2,500 -RRB- fine. He complains, however, that the law is too lenient and would like to see penalties increased. He said the law provides the same penalties for cocaine trafficking as it does for marijuana trafficking. The judge _ divorced four times and the father of five children _ carries his weapons with him wherever he goes. `` If it befalls me to die in this post, then I'll die, without the slightest fear,'' he said. He keeps a .357 Magnun revolver on his desk within easy reach. The judge insists he has no political ambitions, but maintains contact with a number of the country's political leaders. `` I tell them it is imperative that we verify the origin of the parties' funds. Because if we do n't, we're running the grave risk that the traffickers get their people elected to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. Then they reform the Constitution in their favor, they gut the anti-narcotics law; they destroy us.'' Though <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> authorities have expressed concern that drug money has corrupted some officers in <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION>' armed forces, <PERSON> Izaguirre </PERSON> said the cooperation given him by the military has been `` total.'' He said his interest in the military began when he was 12 years old, with the reading of <PERSON> Karl </PERSON> <PERSON> von </PERSON> <PERSON> Clausewitz </PERSON>, the 19th century Prussian general and writer of military strategy. `` I was two centimeters -LRB- about an inch -RRB- too short to get into the military academy,'' he said. `` But if I had, I'm sure I would have made general.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880316-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-16-88 0207EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Israel-Battlefield     03-16 0932</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Israel-Battlefield,0960</SECOND>
<HEAD>Nightly Fights Between Jews, Arabs On Roads</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</NOTE>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 The reporter rode on a bus with Jewish settlers who were attacked by Palestinians at night. The stone-throwing assault was one of the nightly incidents that are raising the level of tension in the occupied territories.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>By MASHA HAMILTON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>HALHOUL, Occupied West Bank (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Rocks smashed through windows of Bus No. 60, shattering the quiet murmur of Hebrew as Jewish settlers traveled home on a moonless night. Israelis clutching frightened children in their arms ducked quickly into the aisle. Several men leaped to their feet and fired shots through two broken windows. In the darkness, the voice of a young Israeli boy rang out: `` Get the Arabs! Get them!'' `` Stop the bus!'' shouted another angry Israeli woman. The driver, an Israeli Arab, hesitated and then pulled to a stop. Three Israelis ran from the front of the bus, firing shots, and two others went out the back door. But it was too late. The Palestinian stone-throwers had disappeared into the night. In a 45-minute period Monday night, <PERSON> Arab </PERSON> attackers heaved stones through windows of three buses and five cars near this <PERSON> Arab </PERSON> village on the outskirts of the settlement of <LOCATION> Kiryat </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arba </LOCATION>, about 20 miles south of <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION>. No Arabs were caught. Three Israelis were treated for cuts at a nearby hospital, but there were no serious injuries. Jewish settlers say, however, the assaults show this biblical land is increasingly becoming a battlefield and the Arabs see them as the target. `` Make no mistake. This is war,'' said one woman aboard Bus No. 60, social worker <PERSON> Rachel </PERSON> <PERSON> Klein </PERSON>, 50. About 50 settlers, including a dozen children and three infants, were aboard when the bus was attacked about 9 p.m. Most of the women wore headscarves and the men wore knitted yarmulkes, the head caps of observant Jews. The red-and-white bus, marked with three Hebrew letters denoting the Eged civilian bus cooperative, was on a scheduled hour-long run from <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION> to the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> town of <LOCATION> Hebron </LOCATION>. The trip on the winding narrow road took the settlers past several Arab villages and refugee camps, including the city of <LOCATION> Bethlehem </LOCATION> and the Dheishe refugee camp, which is blocked by a 10-foot-high wire fence to prevent stone-throwing. Settlers retaliated before dawn Tuesday, setting fire to three Arab-owned cars in <LOCATION> Halhoul </LOCATION> and breaking the windows of several others, said <PERSON> Yossi </PERSON> <PERSON> Dayan </PERSON>, president of a newly formed <ORGANIZATION> Kiryat </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Arba </ORGANIZATION> security committee. <PERSON> Dayan </PERSON> said a rising number of settlers who previously were inactive are being driven to fight back by the nearly nightly attacks, even if it means breaking <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> law. The latest leaflet signed by the <ORGANIZATION> Palestine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> and distributed in the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> ordered Arabs to step up their fight against `` the occupation -LRB- and -RRB- its settlers.'' Arabs have not only thrown stones and firebombs at Israeli vehicles, but also defiantly hang the outlawed Palestinian banner from utility poles along roads used by settlers. The nationalist symbol acts like a red flag for many Israelis. `` They do n't have the same rights in this country as we do,'' said the London-born Mrs. <PERSON> Klein </PERSON>, who has lived 13 years in <LOCATION> Kiryat </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arba </LOCATION>. `` How can we let them make us cower in fear on our own buses in our own country? `` Our government is diddling and afraid to take strong action,'' she said. `` But the Arabs only understand a clear message. We should give them one.'' Some settlers already have tried to send a message, damaging Arab-owned cars, carrying out patrols along <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> roads and sometimes firing shots at Palestinians. Settlers are blamed for killing seven of the Arabs who have died during the 14-week uprising. But, <PERSON> Dayan </PERSON> warned: `` If the army does n't move to stop acts of violence against us, we are going to take far more serious steps. We are discussing setting up some kind of _ I do n't want to call them militias _ but some kind of patrols.'' The army maintains an around-the-clock presence in the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION>. But fewer soldiers are in evidence now than a month ago, and the settlers complain that even when troops are on the scene, they are prevented by defense ministry policy from adequately retaliating against the Arabs. `` Many people in <LOCATION> Kiryat </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arba </LOCATION> prefer if the army does n't come, because then they can respond in their own way,'' said <PERSON> Baruch </PERSON> <PERSON> Goldstein </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Brooklyn </LOCATION>, N.Y.-born settler and also a member of the security committee. `` <LOCATION> Kiryat </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arba </LOCATION> is breaking into two groups. One is of people who are frightened, tend to ride the buses less and will eventually leave,'' <PERSON> Goldstein </PERSON> said. `` The other, larger group will stay and, sooner or later, take its own action to stop the violence.'' <PERSON> Goldstein </PERSON>, a 31-year-old doctor who specializes in trauma cases, said about four times as many vehicles traveling between <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Kiryat </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arba </LOCATION> were stoned in the first three months of this year, compared with the first three months of 1987. On Sunday, a 12-year-old girl from <LOCATION> Kiryat </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arba </LOCATION> was struck on the face by a stone as she traveled on a bus to school. Her nose was broken, her teeth chipped and her upper lip cut, said <PERSON> Goldstein </PERSON>, who treated her. `` People know it is against the law for them to act against the Arabs and they will be arrested if they do,'' he said. `` But as the violence against us increases, people are deciding they do n't have too much to lose. They are realizing coexistence with the Arabs is an impossibility.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880316-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-16-88 0208EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Anderson-Chronology     03-16 0577</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Anderson-Chronology,0611</SECOND>
<HEAD>Chronology of Terry Anderson's Captivity</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Lebanon-Kidnap</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON>, chief <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> correspondent for <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>, today began his fourth year as a hostage in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>. Here is a chronology of the 40-year-old American journalist's captivity:
</TEXT>
<HEAD>1985</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 MARCH 16 _ <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> is abducted on <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> street. Telephone caller says Islamic Jihad kidnapped him as part of `` continuing operations against <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> and its agents.'' MAY 16 _ First photo of <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> in captivity is released. Islamic Jihad warns of `` catastrophic consequences'' if <LOCATION> Kuwait </LOCATION> does not free alleged terrorists. SEPT. 9 _ Rev. <PERSON> Benjamin </PERSON> <PERSON> Weir </PERSON> is freed after 16 months in captivity. President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> says he `` will not be satisified'' until remaining Americans also are released. OCT. 29 _ <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> television stations broadcast videotaped birthday message from relatives and friends to <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON>, two days after he turned 38. NOV. 8 _ In open letter, <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> and three other captive Americans call on <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> to `` have mercy'' and negotiate with kidnappers.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>1986</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 FEB. 15 _ <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON>'s father, <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON>, dies of cancer at age 69. JUNE 7 - <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON>'s 46-year-old brother, <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON> <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, dies of cancer four days after making a videotape from his bed appealing to <PERSON> Terry </PERSON>'s captors. JULY 26 _ Rev. <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Jenco </PERSON>, freed after almost 19 months as hostage, says he was held with <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> and two other hostages for a year. OCT. 3 _ In videotaped appeal, <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> and <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Jacobsen </PERSON> call on <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration to work as hard for their release as it did in winning release of journalist <PERSON> Nicholas </PERSON> <PERSON> Daniloff </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>. OCT. 31 _ <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> TV stations broadcast videotape showing <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON>'s 16-month-old daughter, whom he has never seen. NOV. 2 _ <PERSON> Jacobsen </PERSON>, freed after 17 months in captivity, says hostages `` are in hell.'' NOV. 15 _ Islamic Jihad releases new picture of <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON>. DEC. 28 _ Fourth picture of <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> is sent by captors to Western news agency in <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>1987</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 JAN. 16 _ Islamic Jihad distributes another picture of <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON>. JUNE 7 _ <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON>'s daughter is shown on Lebanese TV on her second birthday saying, `` Our hearts are broken. Where is daddy?'' AUG. 2 _ Sixth photo of <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> is released by Islamic Jihad. OCT. 21 _ Islamic Jihad releases another photo of <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON>. OCT. 27 _ As <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> turns 40, friends and family gather at <LOCATION> Jefferson </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Memorial </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> and <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> staff in <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> goes to his vacant office to mark day. NOV. 26 _ <PERSON> Jacobsen </PERSON> says he learned from sources in government and <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> that <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> being held again in chains and blindfolded 24 hours a day. DEC. 10 _ <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> passes his 1,000 th day as hostage in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> DEC. 14 _ <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> newspaper reports Soviet intelligence officials told American officials at summit that foreign hostages were undergoing brutal treatment and drugging. DEC. 24 _ <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON>'s captors release a videotape of <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON>. Appearing to read from a prepared text, <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> criticizes the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration for failing to secure his and fellow prisoners' freedom and warns `` There's a limit to how long we can last.'' DEC. 30 _ <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> newspaper reports <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> analysis of videotape indicates <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> may be held in <LOCATION> Basta </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Prison </LOCATION> in west <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>, along with kidnapped <ORGANIZATION> Anglican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> envoy <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> <PERSON> Waite </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>1988</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 MARCH 10 _ <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON>'s sister <PERSON> Peggy </PERSON> <PERSON> Say </PERSON> and former hostage Jenco accuse presidential candidates of avoiding question of American hostages in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>. MARCH 16 _ <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> begins his fourth year as a hostage.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880316-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-16-88 0209EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Panama-Chronology     03-16 0665</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Panama-Chronology,0684</SECOND>
<HEAD>With PM-Panama</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here is a chronology of events in the Panamanian crisis: THURSDAY, FEB. 25 _ <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s president, <PERSON> Eric </PERSON> <PERSON> Arturo </PERSON> <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON>, announces he is dismissing Gen. <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>, indicted on <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> drug charges, as defense chief and replacing him with Col. <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> <PERSON> Justines </PERSON>, chief of staff. Justines refuses job. FRIDAY, FEB. 26 _ Noriega-dominated <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION> votes to oust <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON>. Education Minister <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Solis </PERSON> <PERSON> Palma </PERSON> named new head of state. <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> opponents call for general strike in protest. Diplomats and economists say customers begin run on domestically owned banks. SATURDAY, FEB. 27 _ <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON> goes into hiding in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>, defying <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>'s order that he leave country. SUNDAY, FEB. 28 _ <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> States </ORGANIZATION> sidesteps <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> issue by refusing to choose between two men claiming to be <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s ambassador. MONDAY, FEB. 29 _ General strike begins with mixed participation. <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s ambassador to <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Juan </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Sosa </PERSON>, refuses to relinquish post to <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> designee. TUESDAY, MARCH 1 _ General strike gains support in second day. Locally owned banks close. International banks limit withdrawals. Plainclothesmen wreck only remaining opposition radio station in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. Security forces crack down on protests amid scattered violence. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government officially denounces <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> as deficient in fighting drug trade. <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON> outlines plans to freeze Panamanian assets outside country. <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, still recognizing <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON> as president, supports action. WEDNESDAY, MARCH 2 _ Doctors join businesses in general strike. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials confirm they will ask <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> banks to freeze <LOCATION> Panamanian </LOCATION> government assets. More violence reported in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. THURSDAY, MARCH 3 _ Organizers end general strike as support fades, saying money crunch will keep pressure on government. President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> indicates he believes <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> must go. Congressmen propose trade, air travel and currency embargo on <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> regime. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> federal courts temporarily block withdrawal of <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> funds from <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> banks. FRIDAY, MARCH 4 _ <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Panama </ORGANIZATION> says it can not meet banks' cash demands because of freeze on bank deposits. International banks fearing a run on deposits close their doors. Local banks remain closed. SUNDAY, MARCH 7 _ Alliance of business and civic groups opposed to <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> calls for `` government of national reconciliation'' and `` authentic democracy.'' Retired people unable to cash pension checks rally in streets. MONDAY, MARCH 8 _ Riot police disperse demonstrators in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> with tear gas and birdshot. TUESDAY, MARCH 9 _ Government says banks can reopen but no one can cash checks or withdraw funds. Few banks respond. Two prominent Panamanian diplomats break with <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>. WEDNESDAY, MARCH 10 _ The <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> votes 367-2 for a non-binding resolution calling on <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> to `` consider seriously'' additional economic and political sanctions. Libyan television reports <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> asked for Libyan backing against `` American military aggression and economic threats.'' FRIDAY, MARCH 11 _ <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> imposes economic sanctions, including eliminating trade preferences for <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> and withholding <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Canal </LOCATION> fees from the <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> government by placing them in escrow. <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> government meets army payroll. <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> federal judge grounds <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Panama </ORGANIZATION>, freezing its assets while he decides which Panamanian officials should control the airline. <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION> tells <LOCATION> Ukkknited </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> it would accept <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> if he asked for asylum. SATURDAY, MARCH 12 _ Panamanian Cabinet meets in emergency session. SUNDAY, MARCH 13 _ <PERSON> Solis </PERSON> <PERSON> Palma </PERSON> calls Cabinet into another emergency session. MONDAY, MARCH 14 _ Public employees stage work stoppages and riot after government is unable to pay wages. Riot police use tear gas and truncheons to disperse hundreds blocking traffic. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration hints it may reassess demand for <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>'s extradition in order to allow him to step down <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> sends 100 additional military personnel to beef up security around canal. TUESDAY, MARCH 15 _ <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> says <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> wants <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> `` out of there.'' At least a dozen are injured in demonstrations as civil servants take to streets to demand paychecks. <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> orders <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Embassy official to leave country, but <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> rejects demand. Government says it will make partial payments to public employees. Employee union leaders reject plan and demand full salaries.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880316-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-16-88 0032EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p AM-Robertson 1stLd-Writethru a0814 03-16 0537</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Robertson, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0814,550</SECOND>
<NOTE>Eds: Top 4 grafs new with Robertson comments; pick up 4th graf pvs
bgng ``I am bumping...</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By RITA BEAMISH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> met with the Republican national chairman Tuesday to discuss his faltering presidential bid and said later he is `` laying the foundation'' for 1992. <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> suffered another disappointing showing in <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION>, collecting just 7 percent in Tuesday's primary. Though he insisted he will remain in the 1988 race, <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> appeared to be looking ahead. `` I am laying the foundation now and definitely talking to people about 1992. I will play a major role in the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION>,'' he told reporters at his headquarters in <LOCATION> Chesapeake </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> also talked with reporters after his meeting with <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Fahrenkopf </PERSON> He said he is approaching the $ 27 million limit that candidates are allowed to spend in the primary season. He said he is laying off staff and will be forced to discontinue the big spending that has characterized his campaign so far. `` I am bumping up against the limit. ... I have enough money to keep in the race through <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> and the convention. But I do n't have enough to do telemarketing and television,'' he said `` My own personal travel will continue but as far as a full-blown media campaign I ca n't afford that any more.'' Election law restricts spending by presidential candidates who accept federal matching funds for their campaigns. The meeting with <PERSON> Fahrenkopf </PERSON> took place at <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON>'s request, a party spokeswoman said. <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> said, `` We were discussing arrangements for the convention in August and also discussing ways where I could help Republicans gain control of key state legislatures, for instance the legislature of <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, so that we could achieve redistricting of a fair basis in the early 1990s and use that as a basis to gain control of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Representatives </ORGANIZATION> and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> for the <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>.'' <ORGANIZATION> RNC </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman <PERSON> Kathryn </PERSON> <PERSON> Murray </PERSON> confirmed the meeting had focused on those two topics at the suggestion of <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON>. She said <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> expressed a wish to campaign on behalf of Republican candidates at all levels. <PERSON> Fahrenkopf </PERSON> `` welcomes his support,'' she said. `` As long as he can continue to bring new voters into the <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, that's a positive,'' <PERSON> Murray </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> also met Tuesday with <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> Prime Minister <PERSON> Yitzhak </PERSON> <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON> who was in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> for talks with <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials. <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> said he and <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON> were `` old friends.'' The <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Broadcasting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Network </ORGANIZATION> that <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> founded broadcasts in the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> endorsed <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON>'s stance against giving up Israeli occupied lands to the Palestinian people until after `` a period of Palestinian self rule.'' `` Any surrender of territory in the near future would seriously imperil the ability of <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> to defend itself,'' he said, adding that he supports negotiations among the Israelis, <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION> and Palestinians. On politics, he was pressed to explain how he could continue campaigning without spending money. <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> said that in <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> he spent only $ 20,000. `` I have tens of thousands of volunteers who are working ceaselessly night and day because they care for a cause, they care for principle,'' he said. `` Its a movement to bring about conservative principles in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880316-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-16-88 0227EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a BC-Dance     03-16 0452</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Dance,0468</SECOND>
<HEAD>Lubovitch Dance Company Looks Fresh</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: No PMs Planned</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By MARY CAMPBELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A viewer never knows exactly what to expect from the <ORGANIZATION> Lar </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lubovitch </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Company </ORGANIZATION> but it's almost certain to be interesting. Tuesday's opening night of a two-week season presented two very different premieres and a masterpiece from 1986, `` Concerto Six Twenty-Two.'' The opening, which attracted a formal-dress audience to the City Center, marks the 20th anniversary of <PERSON> Lubovitch </PERSON>'s founding his own modern dance company to dance his choreography. `` Musette,'' the premiere ending the evening, is set to Poulenc's `` Concerto for Two Pianos.'' <PERSON> Lubovitch </PERSON> has six couples follow the music's moods, which often change. He does n't repeat himself. Early in the dance, though in bare feet, the dancers assume the leg and foot positions of ballet. <PERSON> Lubovitch </PERSON> has, as he usually does, a time for humor. One man's solo ends, to his apparent surprise, when two men pick him up and carry him off stage. At one time, half the dancers stand still, while the rest dance in and out among them like skiers going around poles. When the music becomes lyrical, the men lift and carry the women so their colorful tulle skirts look like big candy canes going by. There is a section that looks like court dancing and one that looks like trained dancers' variations of <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s folk version of court dancing, the reel. A romantic section of music has two men picking up one woman between them and gracefully swinging her. `` Musette'' ends most satisfactorily with a courtly bow. `` Of My Soul,'' to a Bach `` Cantata,'' was danced at Avery Fisher Hall last summer at the Mostly Mozart Festival. The company considers this the `` official'' premiere. <PERSON> Lubovitch </PERSON> incorporated some American sign language into the arm movements. It's an arresting idea which does n't come off brilliantly. Some of the arm movements translate what four people are singing in the orchestra pit. <PERSON> Lubovitch </PERSON> has made them flow in and out of expansive arm reaches. That works but the whole thing does n't seem to arise from the music like the evening's other two dances. `` Concerto Six Twenty-Two,'' premiered at <ORGANIZATION> Carnegie </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hall </ORGANIZATION> in 1986, is danced to <PERSON> Mozart </PERSON>'s `` Concerto for Clarinet and Orchestra.'' The dancers, wearing white, in the first and third movements, looked inspired and fresh. The middle movement, danced by <PERSON> Sylvain </PERSON> <PERSON> Lafortune </PERSON> and <PERSON> Rick </PERSON> <PERSON> Michalek </PERSON>, remains one of dance's most moving and dignified duets. In such simple things as one man leaning back against the other's hand, it shows human support and trust. The <ORGANIZATION> Solisti </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chamber </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Orchestra </ORGANIZATION>, conducted by <PERSON> Ransom </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON>, did a beautiful job with the <PERSON> Mozart </PERSON> and <PERSON> Bach </PERSON> music. The Poulenc music was a recording.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880316-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-16-88 0231EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     03-16 0946</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0986</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names In The News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> J </PERSON>. <PERSON> Fox </PERSON>'s acrobatic quest for a soft drink to satisfy an attractive apartment neighbor won three awards in an international competition for television and radio commercials. The TV commercial for <PERSON> Diet </PERSON> <PERSON> Pepsi </PERSON> was named sweepstakes winner, world's best live action 60-second English-language commercial and best humorous commercial at Tuesday's 28th International Broadcasting Awards dinner. A series of three commercials for Wine World was the radio sweepstakes winner. It also won the series trophy. The annual competition sponsored by the <ORGANIZATION> Hollywood </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Radio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Television </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION> attracted more than 5,000 entries from 60 countries. Radio personalities <PERSON> Casey </PERSON> <PERSON> Kasem </PERSON> and <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Owens </PERSON> were masters of ceremonies at the black-tie presentations at the Century Plaza Hotel attended by an estimated 1,500 advertising and broadcasting executives from around the world. The society also honored <PERSON> Bea </PERSON> <PERSON> Arthur </PERSON>, <PERSON> Rue </PERSON> <PERSON> McClanahan </PERSON>, <PERSON> Betty </PERSON> <PERSON> White </PERSON> and <PERSON> Estelle </PERSON> <PERSON> Getty </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` The Golden Girls'' as international `` Women of the Year.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>BOWLING GREEN, Ohio (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actress <PERSON> Lillian </PERSON> <PERSON> Gish </PERSON> has donated $ 10,000 to <ORGANIZATION> Bowling </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Green </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> to enhance the film theater that bears her family's name. The gift is designated for the <PERSON> Dorothy </PERSON> and <PERSON> Lillian </PERSON> <PERSON> Gish </PERSON> Film Theater endowment fund, which supports activities in the building that commemorates the <PERSON> Gish </PERSON> sisters' contributions to the performing arts. The theater, dedicated in 1976, showcases the art of film by offering regular showings of classic movies. The theater is undergoing a $ 250,000 renovation of its seating, projection facilities, and gallery. The renovation is scheduled to be completed in May 1989. Ms. <PERSON> Gish </PERSON> also donated $ 10,000 in 1986 to advance and support the study of film at Bowling Green. Ms. <PERSON> Gish </PERSON>, 91, was born in <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> and made her acting debut at the turn of the century in the village of <LOCATION> Rising </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sun </LOCATION>, about 20 miles from Bowling Green.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>HAZLETON, Pa. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The TV personality who calls himself The Amazing <PERSON> Kreskin </PERSON> looked into the future of entertainment and predicted that dinner theaters next season will offer more than just musicals. Future dinner theaters will resemble the supper clubs of the 1940s with plush decor, outstanding meals and a wider variety of entertainment, <PERSON> Kreskin </PERSON> said Tuesday in a speech to the annual convention of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dinner </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Theater </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>. Because television is offering a wider choice of entertainment, `` to survive in the next decade, you must offer more than the same old buffet and musical,'' he said. He said concerts, discos and festivals also have changed theatergoers' tastes. `` They want to participate in the entertainment rather than just sitting and watching a production.'' While <PERSON> Kreskin </PERSON> made it clear he was available for such engagements, <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Aikins </PERSON>, theatrical producer and chairman of the convention, said he thought <PERSON> Kreskin </PERSON>'s view was valid. <PERSON> Kreskin </PERSON>, a 53-year-old self-styled `` mentalist,'' has performed extrasensory feats on his own syndicated TV show and in dozens of talk-show appearances.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>MOSCOW (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Musicians from 10 Western countries including <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Bowie </PERSON>, <PERSON> Jennifer </PERSON> <PERSON> Rush </PERSON> and <LOCATION> Irish </LOCATION> rockers U-2 have agreed to perform along with Soviet musicians in benefit concerts next month to fight drug addiction. The official <ORGANIZATION> Novosti </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> said other foreign performers scheduled are Level 42, <PERSON> Supertramp </PERSON>, Foreigner, <ORGANIZATION> Tangerine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dream </ORGANIZATION> and <LOCATION> Bon </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jovi </LOCATION>. Participating Soviet groups are Aquarium, <LOCATION> Bravo </LOCATION>, Brigade S, <ORGANIZATION> Black </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coffee </ORGANIZATION> and others whose music ranges from heavy metal to traditional rock' n' roll, Novosti said. The press agency did not give a date, but said the three six-hour concerts will be held in late April at the 30,000-seat Olympic Stadium in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>. Sources close to the organizers said the concerts were postponed from this month because of bureaucratic red tape. The sources, speaking on condition of anonymity, said former Beatles <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Harrison </PERSON> and <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> McCartney </PERSON>, as well as <PERSON> Julian </PERSON> <PERSON> Lennon </PERSON>, son of the late Beatle <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Lennon </PERSON>, had been invited. It was unclear whether they would participate. The press agency said revenue from tickets costing about $ 16 each will be donated to the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> fund for the struggle against drug addiction and to the Soviet toxicology research center.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Laryngitis caused <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> to cancel a trip today to a <LOCATION> Nashville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Tenn. </LOCATION>, school that a snowstorm had prevented her from visiting once before. `` She ca n't talk. It's a bad case of laryngitis,'' spokeswoman <PERSON> Wendy </PERSON> <PERSON> Weber </PERSON> <PERSON> Toler </PERSON> said Tuesday. `` She started losing her voice last night.'' Mrs. <PERSON> Toler </PERSON> said the White House physician, Dr. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Hutton </PERSON>, had advised the first lady not to travel. It was the second time the first lady had been forced to cancel the visit to <ORGANIZATION> Warner </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Elementary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> and a drug and alcohol abuse prevention program; a snowstorm had prevented Mrs. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> from visiting the city the first time.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>COLUMBUS, Ohio (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Jeb </PERSON> <PERSON> Stuart </PERSON> <PERSON> Magruder </PERSON>, a former <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> aide who served seven months in prison for his role in the Watergate coverup, says he's well prepared to head the mayor's commission on values and ethics `` I talk about these issues to the Kiwanises and the Rotaries around here, as well as deal with these issues through the church, so I would hope that my background would be helpful,'' <PERSON> Magruder </PERSON> said Tuesday. After his release from prison in 1976, <PERSON> Magruder </PERSON> entered a seminary and was ordained in 1981 as a Presbyterian minister. Mayor <PERSON> Dana </PERSON> <PERSON> Rinehart </PERSON> appointed the 15-member volunteer commission, on which he also will sit, as part of the city's response to an incident last year in which passersby made off with bags of money that fell from an armored truck on a freeway <PERSON> Magruder </PERSON>, President <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON>'s deputy director of communications at the time of the 1972 Watergate break-in, pleaded guilty to perjury and conspiracy to obstruct justice.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880316-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-16-88 0230EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Ozone     03-16 0703</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Ozone,700</SECOND>
<HEAD>NASA Panel Says It Can Show CFC Effects On Ozone</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto WX8</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GUY DARST</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aeronautics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Space </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> says the ozone shield is in fact thinning measurably due to chlorofluorocarbon compounds. A <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> panel said the shield thinned out by about 2.3 percent over a 17-year period ending in 1986 in the temperate zones of the Northern Hemisphere. The panel said the shield thinned by 0.5 percent to 1.8 percent over nine years ending in 1987 in the tropics and part of the temperate zones of both hemispheres. This means increased skin cancer around the world, largely unknown effects on fish and wildlife and increased pressure from environmentalists to go beyond the treaty approved by the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> to cut emissions of ozone-destroying chemicals. Chlorofluorocarbons are used as refrigeration fluids, cleaning solvents and plastic foam blowing agents. `` At this point there is no other culprit to blame,'' panel member <PERSON> Sherwood </PERSON> <PERSON> Rowland </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION> at <LOCATION> Irvine </LOCATION> said Tuesday. `` We have taken out all the natural phenomena that are believed to affect ozone.'' A massive 17-month effort by more than 100 scientists convened by <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> went through practically every ozone observation made in recent years, trying to correct for instrument errors and drift and to remove the effects of the 11-year solar cycle and the biennial oscillation of high-altitude winds. Since 1985, there have been several reports of ozone decline worldwide in addition to the well-established ozone `` hole'' over <LOCATION> Antarctica </LOCATION> _ a 50 percent decline in springtime, followed by recovery. <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> Administrator <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> said the report `` will certainly be a part of the 1990 assessment'' called for in the treaty. `` The crucial first step, however, is speedy international ratification,'' he said. But Sen. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> T. </PERSON> <PERSON> Stafford </PERSON>, R-Vt., said, `` The nations of the world should immediately reconvene to consider amendments'' to the treaty, and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> should resume its advocacy of a complete ban `` We've got to make deeper cuts in <ORGANIZATION> CFC </ORGANIZATION> emissions,'' said Sen. <PERSON> Max </PERSON> <PERSON> Baucus </PERSON>, D-Mont. <PERSON> Kevin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fay </PERSON>, executive director of the Alliance for a Responsible CFC Policy, a group of producers and users, said the 1990 schedule `` is the framework to be followed'' because unilateral reductions wo n't help. The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> voted 83-0 on Monday to approve a 31-nation treaty calling for 50 percent cuts by 1998 in production of chlorofluorocarbons. Noting that <ORGANIZATION> CFC </ORGANIZATION> compounds over <LOCATION> Antarctica </LOCATION> now were released at ground level about 10 years ago and that the <LOCATION> Antarctic </LOCATION> hole could last 100 years even if the treaty is followed, <PERSON> Rowland </PERSON> said, `` There's plenty of reason to re-open the ... protocol.'' Ozone at high altitudes makes life on earth possible by blocking the harmful ultraviolet rays. The <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> estimates that each percent decrease in ozone means a 4.8 percent to 7.5 percent increase in non-melanoma skin cancer and a 0.8 percent to 1.5 percent increase in the more deadly melanoma form. Considering the incidence and death rates of both forms, this would mean 280 to 455 deaths per year on top of the 10,000 from skin cancer in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, or 640 to 1,050 deaths if a 2.3 percent decline were uniform across the country. The 2.3 percent is not uniform. <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> presented its 1969-1986 Northern Hemisphere estimates from ground obserations as averages over each of three bands: 30 degrees latitude -LRB- about the latitude of <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Cairo </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Shanghai </LOCATION> -RRB- to 40 degrees -LRB- <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Madrid </LOCATION> -RRB-, down 1.7 percent; 40 degrees to 53 degrees -LRB- <LOCATION> Edmonton </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Alberta </LOCATION>, and <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> -RRB-, down 3.0 percent; and 53 degrees to 64 degrees -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> Fairbanks </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>, and <LOCATION> Reykjavik </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Iceland </LOCATION> -RRB-, down 2.3 percent. No single estimate was presented for all three bands, but <PERSON> Rowland </PERSON> said the average, a 2.3 percent decline, would be close. All the estimates have substantial uncertainty about them. Each of the three band estimates has a 68 percent chance of being plus or minus 1.0 percentage point, at most, away from the number given. Corrected satellite data show an ozone decline of about 2.5 percent in the band running from 53 degrees north to 53 degrees south from 1978 through 1987. But 0.7 percent to 2.0 percent of this results from the solar cycle, the report said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880316-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-16-88 0232EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-SupremacistMarch     03-16 0272</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Supremacist March,0278</SECOND>
<HEAD>Natchez Agrees to Allow White Supremacists To March</HEAD>
<DATELINE>JACKSON, Miss. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Officials in <LOCATION> Natchez </LOCATION> say they'll reluctantly permit a white supremacist protest march against a 14-week-old black boycott of white-owned businesses in exchange for dismissal of a lawsuit against the city <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Barbour </PERSON> announced the settlement Tuesday in dismissing a lawsuit filed by <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> attorney <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Barrett </PERSON> on behalf of The <ORGANIZATION> Nationalist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Movement </ORGANIZATION>. The judge also ordered <LOCATION> Natchez </LOCATION> to pay <PERSON> Barrett </PERSON>'s attorneys' fees in the case. `` The law of the land will prevail in <LOCATION> Natchez </LOCATION>, not the law of the jungle,'' <PERSON> Barrett </PERSON> said after the announcement. `` This is a victory for the red-white-and-blue people _ meaning red-neck, white skin and blue collar.'' <PERSON> Boycott </PERSON> leaders are seeking, among other things, a black school superintendent and more black teachers in the <PERSON> Adams </PERSON> County-Natchez school district. `` I'm opposed to <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Barrett </PERSON> and his movement, but as mayor of the city, you have to abide the by the laws and the courts. We just hope nobody will show up for it,'' <LOCATION> Natchez </LOCATION> Mayor <PERSON> Tony </PERSON> <PERSON> Byrne </PERSON> said of the march. <PERSON> Byrne </PERSON> said officials decided to settle after the <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supervisors </ORGANIZATION> said the city could n't ban the rally scheduled for the county courthouse grounds Saturday afternoon, the day <PERSON> Barrett </PERSON> was seeking permission for the parade through city streets. <PERSON> Barrett </PERSON> had contended in his lawsuit that the city was infringing on the group's constitutional rights by retroactively applying a parade ordinance adopted March 8. `` We'll see to it that Mr. <PERSON> Barrett </PERSON> comes to town, has his parade and rally, and leaves town as expeditiously as possible,'' <PERSON> Byrne </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880316-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-16-88 0232EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-US-OPIC     03-16 0376</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-US-OPIC,370</SECOND>
<HEAD>U.S. Government Agency Would Buy Shares In Business Abroad</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CARL HARTMAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Two years ago the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration proposed selling its <ORGANIZATION> Overseas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Private </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Investment </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> to private interests. Now it's urging that the government agency be allowed to buy shares in private companies. <PERSON> Craig </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Nalen </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> OPIC </ORGANIZATION>'s president for more than seven years, told the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Foreign Affairs subcommittee on economic policy on Tuesday that the agency wants to begin a pilot project that would put $ 10 million over the next five years into black <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Caribbean </LOCATION>. The money would be spent to take up as much as 30 percent of the shares in new American companies there. Government bodies in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Netherlands </LOCATION> already help their private investors in this way. <ORGANIZATION> OPIC </ORGANIZATION>'s main job is to sell insurance to <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> investors overseas, against what are called political risks: war, rebellion, civil strife, confiscation and official freezing of assets. It is one of the few federal agencies that makes money: $ 300 million over the past three years, <PERSON> Nalen </PERSON> said. `` <ORGANIZATION> OPIC </ORGANIZATION>'s strong financial position makes the agency a good candidate for privatization,'' said the president's budget proposal for the year that ended last September. There was considerable opposition to the idea, both inside and outside the agency, on grounds the insurance was sought precisely because it had the power of the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government behind it. After some study, the president's <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Management </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Budget </ORGANIZATION> decided that <ORGANIZATION> OPIC </ORGANIZATION> had better stay part of the government. The privatization plan was quietly dropped. <ORGANIZATION> OPIC </ORGANIZATION> also makes loans to <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> companies setting up business in other countries _ $ 202.8 million worth of loans and guarantees last year. <PERSON> Nalen </PERSON> said Tuesday that buying shares as well as making loans would help small projects get started. It would allow these heavily indebted countries to borrow less for industrial development, he said. Many are unable to borrow because banks have cut back their lending he said. <PERSON> Nalen </PERSON> also argued that direct investment by his agency would help <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> investors. `` <ORGANIZATION> OPIC </ORGANIZATION>'s major ... counterparts all have the ability to invest equity, thus providing their clients with a significant advantage over their <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> competitors,'' he said in his prepared testimony.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880316-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-16-88 0243EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-SimplifiedTaxes Bjt   03-16 0664</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Simplified Taxes, Bjt,640</SECOND>
<HEAD>Students Venture Where the IRS Fears to Tread: Into Simplicity</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JIM LUTHER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Tax Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 If your idea of a good tax form is one with short sentences and short words, take heart. A group of students, venturing where government has been less than successful, vows to come up with a series of tax forms that are understandable even to the high school dropout. And the students say they will finish the job within less than six months. `` I do n't say it's a simple task, but we're going to try,'' Professor <PERSON> Nicholas </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Creme </PERSON>, director of the <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Taxation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Studies </ORGANIZATION> in the <ORGANIZATION> Akron </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Law </ORGANIZATION>, said in an interview Tuesday. He said he wants the students to work with the <ORGANIZATION> Internal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Revenue </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> on the project, although the <ORGANIZATION> IRS </ORGANIZATION> has not yet embraced the idea. The students' interest was piqued by what they learned while representing low-income taxpayers in audits, collections and other actions involving the <ORGANIZATION> IRS </ORGANIZATION>. They learned that on the average, only 11 percent of taxpayers with less than a high school education have the reading skills to comprehend instructions for filling out Forms 1040 or 1040EZ. The students concluded that if taxpayers ca n't understand how to comply with the tax laws, they probably wo n't. Or as <PERSON> Creme </PERSON>, a tax lawyer for 20 years, put it, `` When people ca n't figure out the right answer, they will take the answer that gives them the best break.'' High school dropouts are n't the only people having trouble with this year's tax forms. Even tax professionals shake their heads at some instructions prompted by the more complex provisions of the 1986 tax overhaul, which was initially billed as tax `` simplification.'' This sentence is part of the Form 1040 instructions for determining how much interest is deductible: `` If all of your mortgage debt on your principal home was borrowed before August 17, 1986, -LRB- and you have not borrowed any new amounts on that debt -RRB-; OR, at all times in 1987, the total of your mortgage debts was less than or equal to what you paid for the home plus improvements -LRB- such as adding a room -RRB-, the mortgage interest you paid is fully deductible on line 9a or 9b, whichever applies.'' <PERSON> Creme </PERSON> says that about 20 students training in law, business or education will develop a more-readable W-4 withholding form; W-2 yearend wages-earned statement; 1099 interest-earned form and the basic 1040, 1040A and 1040EZ forms. `` We're not saying we could bring it down to a second-grade level, but we certainly can make it simpler,'' he said. `` If you simplify the forms, people will be a lot less hostile toward the <ORGANIZATION> IRS </ORGANIZATION>. And you'll raise a lot more revenue.'' Creme and some of the students volunteered for the project Monday while testifying before a <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Finance </ORGANIZATION> subcommittee about <ORGANIZATION> IRS </ORGANIZATION> penalties. The chairman, Sen. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Pryor </PERSON>, D-Ark., welcomed the idea Creme and Professor <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Childs </PERSON>, director of the university's <ORGANIZATION> Tax </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Clinic </ORGANIZATION>, said it is not difficult to figure out why the tax forms and instructions are difficult. `` The average sentence length of these publications exceeds 25 words,'' they said in written testimony. `` One-third of the words in these publications are multisyllabled words.'' Creme's solution: `` By reducing the number of syllables and the number of words in a sentence we can make the forms and instructions significantly more readable. And we want to change how the forms look _ change the spacing so things do n't look so crammed in.'' <ORGANIZATION> IRS </ORGANIZATION> forms are developed in consultation with lawyers, accountants and educators. In changing its forms last year to reflect the new tax law, the <ORGANIZATION> IRS </ORGANIZATION> hired a consultant and even went to some shopping malls for instant reaction from random taxpayers. As for the students' project, <ORGANIZATION> IRS </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Pyrek </PERSON> says, `` One-syllable words are nice, but what do you do about ` dependents'?'' The <ORGANIZATION> IRS </ORGANIZATION> estimates nearly half of taxpayers will pay professionals to fill out their returns this year.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880316-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-16-88 0244EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-CovertAction Bjt   03-16 0722</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Covert Action, Bjt,720</SECOND>
<HEAD>Senate Approves Bill Calling For 48-Hour Notification</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TIM AHERN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> approval of a bill requiring the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> to tell <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> about all covert actions within 48 hours after the operations start marks a major step toward avoiding another Iran-Contra affair, say the measure's sponsors. `` This will help immeasurably toward preventing the kind of mistakes that were made'' in the Iran-Contra affair, Sen. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Boren </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Okla </LOCATION>., chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Intelligence </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, said late Tuesday after the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> voted 71-19 in favor of the bill The measure now goes to the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, where `` overwhelming approval'' is likely, according to both <PERSON> Boren </PERSON> and Sen. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Cohen </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Maine </LOCATION>, vice chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Intelligence </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Intelligence </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> is considering a similar bill, but no date has been set for a vote by the panel or for floor action. President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> has threatened to veto the legislation as an unconstitutional restriction on his ability to conduct foreign policy. But <PERSON> Boren </PERSON> said, `` That kind of threat has been heard before and it has n't come true.'' <PERSON> Cohen </PERSON> noted that the 71 votes are four more than the two-thirds which would be required to override any presidential veto. `` And that 71 total is without some of our supporters here,'' he said. The bill arises from the Iran-Contra affair, when <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> weapons were secretly sold to <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> and some of the profits were diverted to the Contra guerrillas in <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> withheld notification about the arms sales from <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> for 10 months. Current laws require only that the White House give Congess `` timely notice'' about covert actions, but they do not define the term. The Intelligence Committees had been operating on the assumption that the phrase meant only a brief delay in notification. `` This bill clarifies what we thought was the procedure all along,'' <PERSON> Cohen </PERSON> said. `` We believed timely meant a couple of days and we were surprised to find out that the administration was working under a different definition.'' The measure does n't give <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> a veto over covert operations, <PERSON> Cohen </PERSON> noted. `` There's no piece of legislation that can weave a web of security around good or bad judgment,'' said <PERSON> Cohen </PERSON>. `` I ca n't say for sure this would have prevented Iran-Contra, but it would mean that we can give the president the benefit of our advice. The function we serve is to have a second opinion outside the administration.'' <PERSON> Boren </PERSON> said if the bill eventually becomes law, `` it will help'' prevent future problems because `` it clears up so many ambiguities that are in the existing law. It makes the notification process so much more clear.'' But he warned that `` you can never prevent absolutely any future Iran-Contras, anymore than a law against bank robberies will prevent bank robberies.'' In the wake of the Iran-Contra affair, <PERSON> Cohen </PERSON> noted, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> has promised to tell <LOCATION> Capitol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION> about all future covert actions and has moved administratively to make many of the changes proposed in the law. `` This only writes into law what the president has already said he would do,'' <PERSON> Cohen </PERSON> said. The bill also requires written `` findings,'' which are the presidential orders authorizing covert operations. Some actions in the Iran-Contra affair were done under an oral finding which was open to misinterpretation, <PERSON> Boren </PERSON> said. Before passing the bill, the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> rejected, 60-32, a proposal by Sen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Chafee </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-R.I. </LOCATION>, to allow notification within 10 days, instead of two days. <PERSON> Chafee </PERSON> said the time period was long enough to permit actions, such as the rescue of hostages, in which lives might be endangered by leaks of information, but short enough to discover situations such as the Iranian arms sale. Earlier, the chamber voted 73-18 to limit debate. That was 13 more votes than needed to invoke cloture and block an attempt by conservative Republicans to pass the measure. One opponent, Sen. <PERSON> Malcolm </PERSON> <PERSON> Wallop </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Wyo </LOCATION>., said: `` This bill is badly drafted, badly conceived, and the worst of its conceptions is that somehow you can legislate intelligence ... it's hard for me to believe that one piece of legislation can obviate stupid activity. <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Carlucci </PERSON> testified last week that <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> believed the bill was an unconstitutional restriction on presidential authority and would veto it. <PERSON> Carlucci </PERSON> took over as <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s national security adviser in the wake of the Iran-Contra affair.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880316-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-16-88 0246EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w BC-SenateCovertActionRollCall     03-16 0245</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Senate Covert Action Roll Call,220</SECOND>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here is the 71-19 roll call Tuesday by which the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> passed a bill requiring the president to tell <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> about all covert actions within 48 hours after they begin. There were 71 votes `` for'' and 19 votes `` against.''
</TEXT>
<HEAD>Democrats voting for (45):</HEAD>
<TEXT>
