<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880520-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-20-88 2336EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-SchoolShootings-Scene 1stLd-Writethru a0</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-School Shootings-Scene, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0832,0650</SECOND>
<HEAD>Posh Suburb Shaken by Violence; It Can Happen Here</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: SUBS 4th graf pvs: `School District... to UPDATE suspect
found dead; SUBS 11th and 12th graf, pvs: `Reporters were... with
DETAILS about discovery of suspect; picks up 13th graf: `Village
residents ...</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By MARIO FOX</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WINNETKA, Ill. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The yellow police tape surrounding the sprawling one-story brick school provided a jarring note on the quiet, tree-lined, sunny street with its comfortable homes. But the tranquility of this affluent <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Shore </LOCATION> community had already been shattered by a shooting rampage that left an 8-year-old boy dead and five other children and an adult critically wounded. The children were shot at <ORGANIZATION> Hubbard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Woods </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Elementary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> in a 15-minute assault by a woman Friday morning in a school restroom and in a second-grade classroom. The woman barricaded herself in a neighboring home and was found dead by police later in the day. Police said she shot herself once in the head with a .32 - caliber School District 36 Superintentent <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Monroe </PERSON>, his shirt stained with blood, tried to reassure anxious parents who gathered outside, and the crowd dispersed quickly. `` There were a lot of mothers trying to get to the school'' immediately afterward, said a resident of the neighborhood, <PERSON> Anne </PERSON> <PERSON> Belmont </PERSON>. `` They're all crying on my front lawn,'' said another resident, <PERSON> Phil </PERSON> <PERSON> Prange </PERSON>. `` These things happen 2,000 miles away. They do n't happen next door to you,'' said a third resident, <PERSON> Susan </PERSON> <PERSON> Bosler </PERSON>. After the classroom shooting, the drama shifted to the nearby home, where a young man was shot and the suspect, identified as 30-year-old <PERSON> Lori </PERSON> <PERSON> Dann </PERSON>, barricaded herself inside. `` I just heard police surrounding the house, calling, ` <PERSON> Lori </PERSON>, let's get it over with.' I did n't hear any response. Then I heard a shot, a blast I would say,'' said <PERSON> Hildegard </PERSON> <PERSON> Oberstoetter </PERSON>, a housekeeper at the home next door. The afternoon dragged into evening. Reporters were kept behind a police line. Trees obscured the houses. Dozens of police officers waited in the street, and squad cars came and went. After eight hours, <ORGANIZATION> Winnetka </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION> Chief <PERSON> Herbert </PERSON> <PERSON> Timm </PERSON> announced Ms. <PERSON> Dann </PERSON> had been found dead in the house. Village residents talked of little else. Teen-agers sitting on cars in a local gas station were discussing the events, and a man sat in his garage listening to developments on a police radio. The boy's death was only the third slaying in his community since 1957, <PERSON> Timm </PERSON> said. `` We never have a drill for something like this. But we do have fire and tornado drills, so the kids were on the floor in the other classrooms'' after the shooting, <PERSON> Monroe </PERSON> said. Standing outside the school at the end of the day, <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Romey </PERSON> said his 7-year-old daughter, <PERSON> Katie </PERSON>, was in another classroom when the shooting occurred. `` I'm relieved to hear our child is safe. It's a tragedy. It's just terrible for the family who lost their child,'' he said `` The kids are calm,'' said his wife, <PERSON> Blanche </PERSON>, adding that school officials `` told us to take them home and let them talk because they've been talked to a lot today.'' `` The school system here is known for being fantastic, and they have handled this whole thing fantastically,'' Ms. <PERSON> Romey </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Hubbard </PERSON> <PERSON> Woods </PERSON> `` is a fabulous school _ one of the best in the country. ... It's a family neighborhood,'' said Ms. <PERSON> Belmont </PERSON>, who lives nearby with two pre-school-age children. The shady suburb north of <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> is nestled on <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION> and marked by large homes and comfortable incomes. <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> Bears president <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> McCaskey </PERSON> lives there, as do numerous <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> realty barons, bankers and industrialists. A survey released last year by a <ORGANIZATION> Roosevelt </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> urbanologist ranked the community of 12,482 the nation's 22nd-wealthiest suburb with an estimated per-capita income of $ 35,406
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880520-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-20-88 2355EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-Mofford-Gifts 2ndLdWritethru a0873 05-20 0978</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Mofford-Gifts, 2nd Ld Writethru, a0873,1000</SECOND>
<HEAD>Officials to Investigate Mofford Gift Purchases While Secretary of
State</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: SUBS 3rd graf, `I have ..., with 2 grafs to UPDATE with
statement from governor's office; picks up 3rd graf: `Mrs. Mofford
...</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By LARRY LOPEZ</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PHOENIX, Ariz. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION>'s attorney general took initial steps Friday toward investigating Gov. Rose Mofford's expenditures of thousands of dollars in state funds on gifts and decorations when she was secretary of state. Some of the spending appears to have lacked legislative authorization, according to records and interviews with officials, although the governor and a close aide said the <ORGANIZATION> Legislature </ORGANIZATION> had approved the funds. Mrs. <PERSON> Mofford </PERSON>'s office issued a statement saying she `` stands behind'' all the expenditures. Press aide <PERSON> Vada </PERSON> <PERSON> Manager </PERSON> said the governor would not hold a news conference on the issue because, `` I do n't think there's anything serious enough to have a press conference over.'' The governor, in a brief interview with radio station <ORGANIZATION> KFYI </ORGANIZATION> said `` I never misspent a penny. It was appropriated for VIP gifts and I used it for that type of purpose. I never used anything for personal gain.'' Mrs. <PERSON> Mofford </PERSON>, 65, became governor April 4 when <PERSON> Evan </PERSON> <PERSON> Mecham </PERSON> was removed from office upon being convicted in a <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> impeachment trial of misusing state funds and obstructing justice. Records examined by The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> showed that Mrs. <PERSON> Mofford </PERSON>'s gift expenditures totaled at least $ 50,000 for her last five years as secretary of state. Mrs. <PERSON> Mofford </PERSON> used state funds to pay for such things as a joke-writing service and diet food as well as paintings, watches, Indian kachina dolls, clocks, flags and knickknacks, typically charging them to `` other operating expenses'' or `` supplies.'' House Speaker <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Lane </PERSON> said he would wait to hear from Attorney General <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Corbin </PERSON> and <LOCATION> Maricopa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> Attorney <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Collins </PERSON> before deciding whether to launch an impeachment probe. Since <PERSON> Corbin </PERSON> is next in line to succeed Mrs. <PERSON> Mofford </PERSON>, he already had turned over to <PERSON> Collins </PERSON> an investigation of her financial disclosure practices. That investigation stemmed from an AP report that while secretary of state she had failed to include a number of her business dealings in the state-required reports. <PERSON> Corbin </PERSON> said Friday that <PERSON> Collins </PERSON> had agreed to investigate the gift expenditures as well. He added that whether any criminal or civil action will be taken will depend on what <PERSON> Collins </PERSON> finds. Mrs. <PERSON> Mofford </PERSON> did not respond to AP queries about the gifts and spoke only briefly to <ORGANIZATION> KFYI </ORGANIZATION>. Earlier this month, she had said that when faced with the need to present gifts to important visitors as secretary of state, she `` took care of it myself.'' `` I've paid for a lot of my dinners and all those artifacts and things that are there,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Mofford </PERSON> continued. `` Only gifts _ we have a fund for VIP gifts that we are permitted to use that was appropriated by the Legislature. Other than that, I pay for it out of my own pocket.'' <PERSON> Karen </PERSON> <PERSON> Osborne </PERSON>, assistant secretary of state, said the expenditures had been authorized by the <ORGANIZATION> Legislature </ORGANIZATION> as early as 1980 when Mrs. <PERSON> Mofford </PERSON> requested permission to spend $ 5,000 to make some kind of presentation to visiting dignitaries `` on behalf of the state.'' The <ORGANIZATION> Legislature </ORGANIZATION>'s official records show $ 2,400 in unspecified `` other'' expenses was approved that year and $ 2,500 in 1981. More recently, the Legislature has provided lump-sum allocations for the secretary of state's office with little direction as to how the funds are divided. The budget this year is $ 1.9 million. <PERSON> Laurie </PERSON> <PERSON> Drobny </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> Joint </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Legislative </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Budget </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>'s staff analyst for the secretary of state's office in 1980, said she did n't believe the $ 2,400 was for gifts but that she could not recall what it was for. <PERSON> Lane </PERSON> also said he did n't know the money was for gifts. He added that he could understand some of the purchases but that buying a joke service or diet food `` blows my mind.'' The state constitution bars the state from giving anything of value to an individual without public benefit, and state law makes unauthorized expenditures of public funds a felony. Mrs. <PERSON> Osborne </PERSON> said she considered that gifts Mrs. <PERSON> Mofford </PERSON> gave as secretary of state did result in a public benefit, because they were aimed at pleasing someone who could bring business to the state, were in recognition of service to the state or were aimed at motivating future conduct. Records for use of state funds the past five years ago show that as secretary of state, Mrs. <PERSON> Mofford </PERSON> spent about $ 9,000 on pens and other novelties with her name on them, about $ 6,400 on 30 watches bearing the state seal, and about $ 5,700 on kachina and other dolls and their display cases. The total also included about $ 11,000 for flags, mostly state and national, some of which were bought from unauthorized vendors at higher prices than those paid to authorized vendors for similar flags. Other expenditures included $ 203.70 for a weight-reduction product shipped to a friend and business partner of Mrs. Mofford, and $ 306 for the five years' annual renewal of a joke service that promises to supply speakers with 120 to 140 new jokes and stories a month. Mrs. <PERSON> Osborne </PERSON> called that `` probably the greatest tool in the world'' since `` nobody wants to hear a dull, totally dry speech.'' As for the diet food, Mrs. <PERSON> Osborne </PERSON> said she did n't know anything about it. A 1978 protocol-fund statute allows the governor, <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> speaker and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> president to make gifts that promote state interests and encourage public service. It does not include the secretary of state. After she became governor, Mrs. <PERSON> Mofford </PERSON> said she wanted <PERSON> Mecham </PERSON>'s privately raised protocol fund _ money he was convicted by the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> of misusing _ placed in the state General Fund that comes from tax revenues `` I would not have a protocol fund, period,'' she said. `` I do n't want one.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880520-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-20-88 0023EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-BRF--ToddlerFalls     05-20 0164</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Toddler Falls,0168</SECOND>
<HEAD>Toddler Survives Fall</HEAD>
<DATELINE>DES MOINES, Iowa (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A 2-year-old boy fell off a third-story balcony, then promptly got up and began walking around after he landed in the grass with only minor injuries, his mother said. `` Owie, Mommy, owie,'' <PERSON> Julie </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> remembered her son, <PERSON> Matthew </PERSON>, saying after falling off the balcony on Wednesday. Ms. <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>, 27, said she had been rushing around Wednesday trying to get her 8-year-old daughter, <PERSON> Nicole </PERSON>, ready for school. When she left the room for a moment, <PERSON> Matthew </PERSON> apparently tumbled off the balcony. `` I do n't know how he landed, but I guess he got up and was walking around the parking lot,'' Ms. <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Matthew </PERSON> was bleeding at the mouth and chin, and he had other scrapes and bruises, but he was listed in good condition at <ORGANIZATION> Iowa </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Methodist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>, a spokesman said. `` It's just a miracle,'' said Ms. <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>. `` You ca n't believe how far it looks from the balcony to the ground.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880520-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-20-88 0026EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Mecham-OtherGovernors     05-20 0606</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Mecham-Other Governors,0615</SECOND>
<HEAD>Several Others Have Faced Criminal Charges For Activities While
Governor</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Evan </PERSON> <PERSON> Mecham </PERSON> is one of several governors or former governors who have faced criminal charges during or in connection with their terms of office. Others include: _ <PERSON> Spiro </PERSON> <PERSON> T. </PERSON> <PERSON> Agnew </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION>: accused of accepting bribes during his tenure as <LOCATION> Baltimore </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> executive from 1962 to 1966 and governor from 1967 to 1969, <PERSON> Agnew </PERSON> pleaded no contest to one count of income tax evasion in 1973 and resigned as vice president of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. _ <PERSON> Ray </PERSON> <PERSON> Blanton </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION>: ousted from office three days before the end of his term in 1979 amid a clemency-for-cash scandal. He was indicted in 1980 with two former aides on charges of extortion, conspiracy, and mail fraud involving the issuance of 12 liquor store licenses to political friends. He was convicted on June 9, 1981, though not on charges related to the clemency scandal, and served a three-year sentence. On Jan. 29, 1988, a federal judge dismissed the mail fraud charges but upheld the extortion and conspiracy charges. _ <PERSON> Edwin </PERSON> <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION>: Indicted in 1985 on federal racketeering charges in connection with nursing home and hospital projects. He was acquitted in a second trial. _ <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Hall </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION>: sentenced to three years for attempting to bribe <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION>'s secretary of state and four counts of extortion. He was convicted after leaving office in 1975. _ <PERSON> Ed </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION>: Tried in 1928 on charges of conspiracy to bribe Gov. <PERSON> McCray </PERSON> while <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> was secretary of state in 1923. He won a directed verdict of acquittal because the statute of limitations had lapsed. _ <PERSON> Otto </PERSON> <PERSON> Kerner </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION>: convicted of income tax evasion, conspiracy and mail fraud stemming from a stock scandal in his second term as governor. <PERSON> Kerner </PERSON> was a federal appeals judge when he was convicted in 1973. _ <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Langer </PERSON> of <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION>: removed from office in 1934 after being convicted of conspiracy to obstruct operation of federal relief activities and soliciting money from federal employees for political purposes. The conviction was overturned, and <PERSON> Langer </PERSON> was cleared of all charges in his fourth trial. He was elected governor in 1936 and later served 19 years as a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> senator. _ <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Leche </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION>: a protege of <PERSON> Huey </PERSON> <PERSON> Long </PERSON>, he was elected governor in 1936 and quickly became wealthy. `` When I took the oath of office, I did n't take any vow of poverty,'' he once said. Leche was indicted on criminal charges including misappropriation of materials to improve his property and gouging the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Highway </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> on truck sales. He resigned in 1939, was convicted in 1940 and was sentenced to prison. He was pardoned by President <PERSON> Truman </PERSON> in 1953. _ <PERSON> Marvin </PERSON> <PERSON> Mandel </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION>: indicted by a federal grand jury on 24 counts on mail fraud, bribery and other charges under the federal racketeering statute. He served 14 months in prison. On Nov. 12, 1987, a federal judge threw out <PERSON> Mandel </PERSON>'s conviction, citing a recent <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> ruling that set up stronger guidelines for mail fraud. _ <PERSON> Warren </PERSON> <PERSON> McCray </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION>: Indicted in 1923 on charges of misrepresenting his holdings in loan applications, and was convicted of mail fraud in 1924. He resigned, served three years in prison and was pardoned by President <PERSON> Hoover </PERSON> in 1930. _ <PERSON> Arch </PERSON> <PERSON> Moore </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> of <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>: indicted by a federal grand jury in 1975 during his second term in office. He and an administrative aide were accused of extorting $ 25,000 from the president of a financial holding company. He was acquitted in 1976.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880520-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-20-88 0037EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-TaughtTooLittle     05-20 0695</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Taught Too Little,0711</SECOND>
<HEAD>Teacher Admits To Being `Part Of Problem' In Beleaguered Public
Schools</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By JAMES LITKE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CHICAGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A whole class of fourth-graders whose teacher failed to make the grade must go to summer school before they can be promoted, says their principal, one of four who tried unsuccessfully to fire the teacher. `` It is really a joke that the system allows this to happen,'' said <PERSON> Dyanne </PERSON> <PERSON> Dandridge-Alexander </PERSON>, principal of <ORGANIZATION> Spencer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Elementary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION>, where <PERSON> Grace </PERSON> <PERSON> Currin </PERSON> teaches. `` Those children deserve a better teacher, a better education.'' <PERSON> Currin </PERSON> `` has not handed in a lesson plan all year,'' <PERSON> Dandridge-Alexander </PERSON> said, `` and when you ask her about it, she says ` I left it at home.' `` The noise level in the class is unbelievable. Kids are fighting. Children are rolling around on the floor. They are throwing chairs across the room. One day I walked into her classroom and said, ` Did you see that chair fly across the room?' and she said, ` I told them not to do that.''' The city's schools are saddled with too many students and too little money, and the result too often is chaos, the <ORGANIZATION> Chicago </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tribune </ORGANIZATION> concluded after a seven-month examination of a system that Secretary of Education <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON> has called the worst in the nation. In addition, a lenient administration, a powerful teachers union and a misguided state law have created an environment that protects incompetent teachers and ignores the children the teachers are supposed to educate, the <ORGANIZATION> Tribune </ORGANIZATION> said Thursday in its weeklong series on the system. The newspaper found that of 139 teachers who, over the last five years, were so lacking in attendance, discipline, teaching ability or relationships with their students that their principals moved to fire them, 99 are still in the classroom. `` I am part of the problem, but remember, you ca n't expect miracles when you have low achievers,'' said <PERSON> Currin </PERSON>, 56, who has taught for 30 years. `` There always will be discipline problems in that class,'' said <PERSON> Currin </PERSON>, whose most recent assignment is at <LOCATION> Spencer </LOCATION>, in an impoverished neighborhood on the city's near <LOCATION> Northwest </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Side </LOCATION>. `` It's the kind of children I teach. During her career, <PERSON> Currin </PERSON> has received at least 12 `` excellent'' ratings and five `` superior'' ratings. But she also has received four unsatisfactory ratings since the 1983-84 school year, the last this March from <LOCATION> Dandridge-Alexander </LOCATION>, the newspaper reported. Since a new state law took effect in January, an unsatisfactory rating is the first step in the termination procedure, which could take a year or longer. The newspaper reported three of <PERSON> Currin </PERSON>'s principals attempted to have her fired under previous guidelines <PERSON> Currin </PERSON> told the <ORGANIZATION> Tribune </ORGANIZATION> her career goal now is retiring `` at full pension.'' She did not return phone messages left for her at the school Thursday. `` Incompetent teachers are a disservice to everyone, especially the teaching profession,'' <ORGANIZATION> Chicago </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Teachers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Chuck </PERSON> <PERSON> Burdeen </PERSON> said Thursday. `` Any principal who says he ca n't get rid of an obviously bad teacher is either lazy or must think assassination is the only answer. `` Secondly, those who are critical of urban school systems are usually the ones like <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON> and the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration, who are taking away the very same resources needed to meet the tremendous needs of these kids,'' he said. <PERSON> Dandridge-Alexander </PERSON> said she is n't concerned as much with blame as she is with correcting the problem. Last month she called parents in to monitor <PERSON> Currin </PERSON>'s classes, and `` they are at a point where they think it is hopeless,'' she said. Because of the new state law giving teachers rated unsatisfactory a year's work before they can be dismissed, <PERSON> Currin </PERSON> will be able to continue teaching until at least March 1989. The new law was part of a 1985 state school reform package, its intent to give school management better tools to weed out weak teachers. But lobbying by teachers unions made the law into yet another measure making it even more difficult to fire teachers, according to the <ORGANIZATION> Tribune </ORGANIZATION>. `` It's a terrible shame,'' said <PERSON> Dandridge-Alexander </PERSON>. `` Those children have suffered because they have a totally inept teacher that no one has been able to fire.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880520-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-20-88 0039EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Chile-Watchers     05-20 0690</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Chile-Watchers,0714</SECOND>
<HEAD>200,000 Volunteer To Watch Presidential Balloting In Chile</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By EDUARDO GALLARDO</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SANTIAGO, Chile (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 With a little financial help from abroad and a lot of enthusiasm from 200,000 volunteers, opponents of <LOCATION> Chile </LOCATION>'s military government have launched a campaign they say will keep fraud out of this year's presidential election. Ten opposition parties, from left to right, have united in the campaign of door-to-door voter education, poll-watching on election day and independent vote counting afterward. Leaders of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Election </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Command </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democracy </ORGANIZATION> maintain that the system is necessary because they believe fraud tipped a 1980 plebiscite to approve a government-drafted constitution. <PERSON> Genaro </PERSON> <PERSON> Arriagada </PERSON>, secretary general of the command, said the 1980 plebiscite, in which the government received 67 percent of the vote, `` lacked the minimal conditions necessary to guarantee any honest election.'' That vote took place without voter registries, because the old ones had been destroyed by the military shortly after they seized power in 1973. Polling stations were manned only by government-appointed officials, without any opposition or independent supervision. <PERSON> Arriagada </PERSON> said a national census taken two years after the vote showed that in several cities the number of people who voted in the plebiscite was higher than the number of residents in the cities. The government has denied accusations of fraud. `` The upcoming presidential plebiscite will be very different,'' <PERSON> Arriagada </PERSON> said. He said voter registries now have reopened, `` and this time we have the capacity to guarantee a clean vote.'' In the plebiscite scheduled for an unspecified date later this year, Chileans will be able to vote `` yes'' or `` no'' on a single, military-appointed candidate for the 1989-97 presidential term. If the candidate is rejected by voters, a competitive election will take place a year later. President <PERSON> Augusto </PERSON> <PERSON> Pinochet </PERSON>, the 73-year-old army commander who has ruled since 1973, is considered the most likely candidate. <PERSON> Ricardo </PERSON> <PERSON> Lagos </PERSON>, leader of the <ORGANIZATION> Socialist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> and a key member of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Election </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Command </ORGANIZATION>, said 700 specialists are training the 200,000 volunteers throughout the country to work as poll-watchers on election day. He added in an interview that the opposition will be able to have three to five monitors at each of the 20,000 or so voting places. `` We can guarantee to every citizen that his vote will be properly accounted for, and that it will remain secret,'' <LOCATION> Lagos </LOCATION> said. Some volunteers have already visited hundreds of thousands of voters in the door-to-door campaign to `` explain to them that this time the vote will be totally clean,'' he said. <LOCATION> Lagos </LOCATION> added that part of the financing for the campaign has come `` from groups abroad interested in the restoration of democracy in <LOCATION> Chile </LOCATION>.'' He said the cost is relatively low, however. He estimated his <ORGANIZATION> Socialist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> will spend the equivalent of around $ 100,000. <LOCATION> Lagos </LOCATION> did no identify the foreign groups sending money, but the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Endowment </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democracy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> the </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> States </ORGANIZATION> and several West European foundations, especially in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Sweden </LOCATION>, have been officially reported in the past as granting financial aid to Chilean democratic dissident groups. The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Election </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Command </ORGANIZATION> also has organized a nationwide computerized vote-counting system to operate independently of the government system. <PERSON> Eduardo </PERSON> <PERSON> Arriagada </PERSON>, an engineer in charge of the Vote Counting Center said `` we will be able to quickly deliver a projection of the vote and complete returns.'' <PERSON> Eric </PERSON> <PERSON> Campana </PERSON>, a leading electoral expert of the <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, the largest in the opposition, said, `` The system we are implementing fully guarantees a clean vote. There will be no fraud this time. Chileans can rest assured of that.'' <PERSON> Campana </PERSON> said volunteers trained as poll-monitors show `` an enormous enthusiasm.'' `` Many of them are paying for their travel and other expenses connected with the campaign out of their own pockets.'' <PERSON> Juan </PERSON> <PERSON> Gabriel </PERSON> <PERSON> Valdes </PERSON>, who works at the Vote Counting Center, said, however, old legislation granting the government emergency powers could still be invoked. `` That legislation, for example, would allow the government to prevent us from announcing the returns we will be gathering,'' <PERSON> Valdes </PERSON> said. That, said <LOCATION> Lagos </LOCATION>, is `` the only fraud possibility that remains open.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880520-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-20-88 0042EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Korea     05-20 0691</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Korea,0712</SECOND>
<HEAD>New Riots Underline Lingering Political Problems</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP News Analysis</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By BARRY RENFREW</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SEOUL, South Korea (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 This week's riots make clear that the militant political opposition remains strong despite substantial democratic reforms. Thousands of students and dissidents opposed to President <PERSON> Roh </PERSON> <PERSON> Tae-woo </PERSON>'s government battled police in the streets. Protest leaders claimed <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> is not a democracy, as they had during the authoritarian regime of <PERSON> Roh </PERSON>'s predecessor and ally, <PERSON> Chun </PERSON> <PERSON> Doo-hwan </PERSON>. Protesters chanted: `` Down with the military dictatorship!'' and `` Destroy the murder regime!'' They hurled firebombs and rocks at riot police during the most violent unrest in months. The scale was much smaller than the huge protests of last summer but the scenes and slogans were the same, demonstrating that <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korean </LOCATION> politics remain turbulent despite the professed desire of all parties to build a stable democratic system. Anti-American sentiment, always present in political protests, seemed particularly evident this time. `` Yankee go home!'' was shouted along with `` Execute <PERSON> Roh </PERSON> Tae-woo!'' Protesters burned a homemade American flag and attacked a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> cultural center. Opposition groups, especially radical students, remain eager to take their causes into the streets. The government still limits some political activity and is quick to use riot police to break up protests. Many South Koreans still distrust <PERSON> Roh </PERSON> because he helped <PERSON> Chun </PERSON> seize power in 1980, when both were army generals, and played a prominent role in <PERSON> Chun </PERSON>'s regime, serving as chairman of the government <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>. That wariness was reflected in <PERSON> Roh </PERSON>'s slender victory in the December presidential election over a divided opposition, and the government party's loss of its majority in parliamentary elections last month. Opposition groups demand an investigation of his role in suppression of the 1980 <LOCATION> Kwangju </LOCATION> uprising, in which at least 191 people were killed. This week's protests marked the eighth anniversary, on Wednesday, of the revolt in the southern city. In addition to being far smaller than those that forced <PERSON> Chun </PERSON> to hold elections, the latest protests have attracted little public support and there is little sign that they will become a threat to the government. The 1987 protests mushroomed into mass demonstrations almost overnight, however, and political observers avoid firm predictions about <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korean </LOCATION> politics. When <PERSON> Roh </PERSON> replaced <PERSON> Chun </PERSON> as president in February, it was the first peaceful transfer of power in the nation's 40-year history. All indications are that both the government and the main opposition parties want to avoid major political unrest before the Olympic Games are held here in September. South Koreans see the games as a national triumph that will give the nation a place on the world stage. <PERSON> Roh </PERSON> has worked hard to build public confidence. He promised to introduce full democracy while ensuring political stability, and has made significant changes. Many curbs on politics imposed by <PERSON> Chun </PERSON> have been removed, creating a sharp contrast to 1987, when riot police took harsh action to disperse even minor peace; ful demonstrations. <PERSON> Roh </PERSON> tries to project himself as a `` common man'' and has discarded much of the presidency's aloofness. Press curbs have been removed, most forms of self-expression are allowed and opposition parties operate freely. Some political controls still apply, however. Street protests against the government still are likely to be broken up and scores of dissidents remain in jail, serving long sentences for political activity. Many South Koreans feel real democracy is not possible until control by the military, government bureaucracy, big business and other powerful factions is ended. People in the streets complain that <PERSON> Roh </PERSON> has yet to deliver on election promises of major social and economic reforms, including doubling pay for industrial workers and the poor. A more fundamental problem lies in the traditional <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korean </LOCATION> belief that compromise is the greatest sign of weakness. Political factions believe only one point of view is right and all others must be defeated or even destroyed. Political leaders on all sides agree such an outlook blocks the road to democracy, but seem unable to change it.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Barry </PERSON> <PERSON> Renfrew </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> bureau chief in <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION>, has covered <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION> for five years.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880520-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-20-88 0043EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-India-Sikhs     05-20 0719</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-India-Sikhs,0742</SECOND>
<HEAD>Ending Temple Siege Doesn't End War</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By EILEEN ALT POWELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW DELHI, India (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The surrender of Sikh extremists in their sacred <ORGANIZATION> Golden </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Temple </ORGANIZATION> did not end the war of terror through which they hope to create a nation called <LOCATION> Khalistan </LOCATION>, the Land of the Pure. During the 10 days Sikh gunmen and their sympathizers spent inside the temple complex, surrounded by about 2,800 policemen and soldiers, their comrades killed 133 people in the holy city of <LOCATION> Amritsar </LOCATION> and other parts of <LOCATION> Punjab </LOCATION> state. Twenty-five more people were reported killed Thursday, the day after the surrender at the temple in <LOCATION> Amritsar </LOCATION>. They included two Hindu priests and a Sikh holy man. It is from <LOCATION> Punjab </LOCATION>, a rich northern agricultural state, that the radicals would create <PERSON> Khalistan </PERSON>. It is the only state where Sikhs, who make up only 2 percent of <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>'s 800 million people, are in the majority. <PERSON> Julio </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Ribeiro </PERSON>, former police chief of <LOCATION> Punjab </LOCATION> and now security adviser to the state government, was asked if the surrender indicated an end to terrorism. He replied: `` No, far from it.'' Bomb disposal squads searched for hidden explosives Thursday in the 400-year-old <ORGANIZATION> Golden </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Temple </ORGANIZATION>, the holiest shrine of <LOCATION> Sikhism </LOCATION>. Police said four more bodies were found inside, bringing the death toll of the siege to 46. A committee of Sikh elders that manages the temple conferred about preparations to reopen the gold-domed shrine. Sikh extremists began fighting for a separate homeland six years ago, accusing the Hindu-dominated federal government of discrimination and of hampering economic development in <LOCATION> Punjab </LOCATION>. Thousands of people have been killed since then. Prime Minister <PERSON> Rajiv </PERSON> <PERSON> Gandhi </PERSON> signed a peace agreement with moderate Sikhs in 1985, but it fell apart within a year. The Sikh extremists, initially blamed for scattered killings, have attacked loaded buses, sleeping villagers and congested markets in recent years. At least 1,088 people have been killed in <LOCATION> Punjab </LOCATION> so far this year, compared to 1,032 for all 1987. Most victims are Hindus, but an increasing number of Sikh moderates are being slain. Police estimate the radicals have more than 3,000 men under arms, with increasingly sophisticated weapons. The greatest fear of <PERSON> Gandhi </PERSON>'s government is that the separatist movement will become a full-scale civil war and encourage insurgencies among other minorities. `` So far, the terrorists are a small section of the population,'' one official said privately. `` We want to keep it that way.'' Support for the extremists within the Sikh community may be waning. After an army raid on the Golden Temple complex in 1984, angry Sikhs held rallies. But hardly any Sikhs objected publicly to the siege of the temple that ended Wednesday, and a gathering of Sikh temple managers in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Delhi </LOCATION> passed a resolution Wednesday praising the government's `` rescue'' of the shrine. Prime Minister <PERSON> Indira </PERSON> <PERSON> Gandhi </PERSON> ordered the 1984 raid to drive out extremists taking shelter in the temple. About 1,200 people were killed. Two of Mrs. <PERSON> Gandhi </PERSON>'s Sikh guards assassinated her five months later. Prominent Sikhs generally believe the violence will continue until the government of <PERSON> Rajiv </PERSON> <PERSON> Gandhi </PERSON>, <PERSON> Indira </PERSON>'s son and successor, reaches a political compromise with the militants. <PERSON> Kushwant </PERSON> <PERSON> Singh </PERSON>, a respected Sikh writer, urged the government recently to abandon its practice of searching for a single moderate Sikh to lead peace efforts. `` What we have to find is not a person or persons to lead the <LOCATION> Punjab </LOCATION>, but -LRB- a way -RRB- to set out principles of conduct and stick to them no matter what the immediate consequences,'' he wrote in <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hindustan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> newspaper. He advocated release of hundreds of Sikhs detained without trial, prosecution of Hindu politicians and others accused of instigating the anti-Sikh riots in 1984, and new investment to stimulate <LOCATION> Punjab </LOCATION>'s faltering economy. <PERSON> Gandhi </PERSON>'s 1985 accord with moderates called for settlement of land and water disputes between <LOCATION> Punjab </LOCATION> and neighboring <LOCATION> Haryana </LOCATION> state, investigation of the 1984 riots and speedy handling of arrest and detention cases. He put <LOCATION> Punjab </LOCATION> under federal rule in May 1987, after the agreement had failed, but in March of this year returned to a softer approach and ordered the release from prison of militant Sikh high priest <PERSON> Jasbir </PERSON> <PERSON> Singh </PERSON> <PERSON> Rode </PERSON>. Rode was arrested last week trying to march on the temple to end the police siege.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880520-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-20-88 0044EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-AnglerWars     05-20 0736</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Angler Wars,0761</SECOND>
<HEAD>Anglers Angered Over Fishing Licenses</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By MARCUS ELIASON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>KILDORRERY, Ireland (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Like the one that got away, the Great Anglers' Strike of'88 is assured of an honorable place in the folklore of Irish fishing. It is a tale of defiance, anger and of farce tinged with menace. It invokes the memory of <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION>'s freedom wars, reflects rural resentment against big-city bureaucrats, and climaxes with an 11th-hour truce mediated by an archbishop. And all because of a fishing license. The trouble began on New Year's Day, when a law took effect requiring anglers, for the first time, to buy licenses. At 15 pounds -LRB- $ 26.50 -RRB- for a year's trout fishing and 10 pounds -LRB- $ 15.60 -RRB- for other fish, the permits are n't exorbitant or unusual for <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>. But the anglers were outraged. They threatened to shut down angling and deal a severe blow to western <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION>'s multimillion dollar tourism industry unless the license law was withdrawn. The government refused, and in mid-April the strike began. Signs popped up along roads and at fishing venues saying `` No Rod License'' and `` Licensed Anglers Not Welcome Here.'' Angling clubs declared their waters off-limits to fishers. Hotels told guests with bookings to stay away. Fishing stores refused to sell the licenses. Dark tales circulated of anglers' car tires being slashed and a fishing boat being sawed in half. True or not, they had the desired effect. By mid-May, as the lakes and rivers swarmed with trout feasting on the newly hatched mayflies, not an angler was in sight, and all angling competitions were canceled. <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Willis </PERSON>, head of the <ORGANIZATION> Munster </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Trout </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fly </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Anglers </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ' </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, says it's not the money, but the principle. `` We believe we have a God-given right to fish,'' said the 54-year-old pub owner, smacking the dashboard of his car. `` I want to hand down to my children and grandchildren what my forefathers gave to me _ the right to fish over these waters for free.'' In the tiny <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Cork </LOCATION> village of <LOCATION> Kildorrery </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Willis </PERSON>' friend <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Collins </PERSON> harked back 70 years to <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION>'s war for independence from <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>. `` My father and <PERSON> Dick </PERSON>'s father put their lives on the line fighting for our freedom, and freedom includes the right to fish,'' he said. `` It's a battle for control,'' <PERSON> Willis </PERSON> said. `` We anglers have developed these waters, cleaned up pollution, restocked them, without one penny in government aid, and we want to keep it that way.'' Commented lawmaker <PERSON> Enda </PERSON> <PERSON> Kenny </PERSON>: `` In the land of Capt. -LRB- Charles -RRB- <PERSON> Boycott </PERSON>, attitudes have become deeply entrenched,'' a reference to the 19th-century land agent who lost his crops to a peasants' boycott and gave his name to the English language The debt-ridden economy urgently needs cash, and the government sees nothing wrong with the angling licenses. But its attitude is under attack. `` It is government by diktat rather than by any sort of consensus,'' charged the <ORGANIZATION> Cork </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Examiner </ORGANIZATION>. `` This whole matter has been handled in a very nonsensical manner.'' Indeed, the law passed so quickly and with so little fanfare that the government tourism agency did n't have time to alter its latest promotional literature, which still says Irish waters are license-free. Meanwhile, the $ 60 million annual tourism industry in western <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION> says hotels catering to anglers have been hit hard by cancellations. `` We are facing ruin at the moment,'' said <PERSON> June </PERSON> <PERSON> Hodgson </PERSON>, who runs a classy anglers' hotel on <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Corrib </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Galway </LOCATION>. `` It's devastating, heartbreaking to look out over an empty lake and see no boats,'' she said Tuesday. Unbeknownst to her, however, higher powers were working to get the anglers and the government off the hook. Late Wednesday, the Archbishop of <LOCATION> Tuam </LOCATION>, Dr. <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Cassidy </PERSON>, announced he had secretly negotiated a deal whereby the licensing law would not be implemented until further discussion. <PERSON> Tommy </PERSON> <PERSON> Tuck </PERSON> of the Anti-Rod-Licensing Campaign saw this as a face-saving compromise and said the boats would return to Corrib later. But <PERSON> Willis </PERSON> remained suspicious. `` I do n't see any government commitment to repeal the law, so for the time being our strike is still on,'' he said. `` This is a tax on our sport,'' he said. `` If they get away with this, next year it'll be the tennis racket, then the golf club, then the hurling stick. You know governments. Once they get one leg in, it's all over. Next year they'll double it, then treble it.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880520-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-20-88 0051EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-LehderProfile     05-20 0808</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lehder Profile,0830</SECOND>
<HEAD>Lehder _ Flamboyant Innovator Of Mass Cocaine Smuggling,
Authorities Say</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Lehder</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By RON WORD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>JACKSONVILLE, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Lehder </PERSON> <PERSON> Rivas </PERSON>, armed with Colombian contacts and a <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> street education, turned a prison cell fantasy into the world's first high-tech cocaine-smuggling ring, authorities say. At the height of his power in the early 1980s, <PERSON> Lehder </PERSON> was a key figure in the <LOCATION> Medellin </LOCATION> cartel, the Colombian drug-trafficking ring responsible for 80 percent of the cocaine brought into this country, according to <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> indictments. He was convicted Thursday on all 11 counts of smuggling lodged against him. `` <PERSON> Lehder </PERSON> was one of the four managers for the multibillion-dollar cartel,'' said <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Hook </PERSON>, spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Drug </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Enforcement </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION>. `` He had hundreds of millions of dollars pass through his bank accounts in a short period of time.'' <PERSON> Lehder </PERSON> owned an island in the <LOCATION> Bahamas </LOCATION>, gave television interviews from a Colombian jungle hideaway, showed a fondness for <PERSON> Adolf </PERSON> <PERSON> Hitler </PERSON> and <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Lennon </PERSON> and even organized his own political party to fight `` <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. imperialism.'' In a 1985 interview from the jungle, where he was a fugitive, <PERSON> Lehder </PERSON> called his nation's stimulants the Achilles' heel of imperialism. `` If coke, coal or marijuana, or gold, or diamonds, or coffee or whatever we have, is going to provide a cornerstone for us to remove imperialism from <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Latin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, well then, so be it,'' he said. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> authorities kept pressing the <LOCATION> Colombian </LOCATION> government, and on Feb. 4, 1987, <PERSON> Lehder </PERSON> was captured for extradition by the <LOCATION> Colombian </LOCATION> government after a short firefight outside a <LOCATION> Medellin </LOCATION> mansion. He wound up in <LOCATION> Jacksonville </LOCATION> facing a federal jury. Trial testimony, drug agents and prosecutors painted <PERSON> Lehder </PERSON> as a pioneer in drug trafficking with a grand design to traffic tons of cocaine through the <LOCATION> Bahamas </LOCATION>. Son of a German father and <LOCATION> Colombian </LOCATION> mother, <PERSON> Lehder </PERSON> grew up in <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION>'s coffee-growing region of <LOCATION> Armenia </LOCATION>, then moved to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> at age 15. His brushes with the law began a few years later. In 1974, he was sentenced to the federal correctional insitution in <LOCATION> Danbury </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Conn. </LOCATION>, for auto theft and marijuana possession. <PERSON> Lehder </PERSON> and a prison mate talked about cocaine as the wave of the future, and pored over an atlas to find a small island they could buy as a waystation, authorities said. After he was deported to <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION> in 1975, <PERSON> Lehder </PERSON> allegedly began smuggling cocaine into the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> in small amounts, concealing it in the lining of suitcases. Soon he was hiring other `` mules,'' and graduated to using large, long-range planes to fly several hundred kilograms at a time out of <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Lehder </PERSON> established his base on <PERSON> Norman </PERSON>'s Cay, a small <LOCATION> Bahamian </LOCATION> island that <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Attorney <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Merkle </PERSON> characterized as `` an aircraft carrier of cocaine.'' His occupation of the island was allegedly blessed by Bahamian Prime Minister <PERSON> Lynden </PERSON> <PERSON> O. </PERSON> <PERSON> Pindling </PERSON> after a series of bribes, according to trial testimony. <PERSON> Pindling </PERSON> has denied the allegation, and has not been charged. Defense attorneys <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shohat </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Quinon </PERSON> contended <PERSON> Lehder </PERSON> was a businessman who wanted to develop the <LOCATION> Bahamian </LOCATION> island as a resort for wealthy Europeans and South Americans. They introduced into evidence a promotional film made by <PERSON> Lehder </PERSON> which extolled the island's virtues. But according to trial testimony, <PERSON> Lehder </PERSON> soon was flying shipments from <PERSON> Norman </PERSON>'s Cay to small airstrips in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION>. `` <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Lehder </PERSON> and <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> Ford </PERSON> had a lot in common,'' <PERSON> Merkle </PERSON> said in his closing arguments. `` <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Lehder </PERSON> was the pioneer of the mass transportation of cocaine for the American consumer.'' Like many pioneers, money was not <PERSON> Lehder </PERSON>'s only objective. <PERSON> Merkle </PERSON> charged that <PERSON> Lehder </PERSON> also viewed cocaine as a revolutionary tool. <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Yakovac </PERSON>, who met <PERSON> Lehder </PERSON> in 1976, said <PERSON> Lehder </PERSON> `` wanted to build a kingdom based on cocaine. ... He pretty much thought he was going to take on the world.'' Outside <PERSON> Lehder </PERSON>'s Bavarian-style resort of <PERSON> Posada </PERSON> <PERSON> Alemana </PERSON> stands a symbolically bullet-pocked nude statue of his hero, slain former Beatle <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Lennon </PERSON>. At his trial, several witnesses testified that <PERSON> Lehder </PERSON> also idolized <PERSON> Hitler </PERSON> and kept swastikas, the symbol of <PERSON> Hitler </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> Nazi </ORGANIZATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, in his home. By 1982, <PERSON> Lehder </PERSON> was spending most of his free time back in <LOCATION> Armenia </LOCATION>, developing a resort, buying ranches, starting a newspaper and forming a political party. He railed against the U.S.-Colombian extradition treaty, since voided by that nation's <ORGANIZATION> supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> court </ORGANIZATION>, calling it an example of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> imperialism. <ORGANIZATION> DEA </ORGANIZATION> agents say <PERSON> Lehder </PERSON> was active in the drug-related violence that swept <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION>, working with guerrilla forces to arrange the assassination of government officials who opposed the drug trade. <PERSON> Lehder </PERSON>'s operation began to unravel when Bahamian forces and the <ORGANIZATION> DEA </ORGANIZATION> began to focus on <PERSON> Norman </PERSON>'s Cay, with the help of marijuana smuggler <PERSON> Ed </PERSON> <PERSON> Ward </PERSON>, who had joined forces with <PERSON> Lehder </PERSON> in 1978 after meeting him on the island.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880520-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-20-88 0052EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-ColaPriceFixing     05-20 0293</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Cola Price Fixing,0300</SECOND>
<HEAD>Soft Drink Execs Convicted Of Price Fixing</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NORFOLK, Va. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The former president of a <ORGANIZATION> Maryland </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coca-Cola </ORGANIZATION> bottler and the chairman of the company that once owned a rival <ORGANIZATION> Pepsi-Cola </ORGANIZATION> bottling operation have been convicted of price fixing by a federal jury. Sentencing for <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Harford </PERSON>, former president of <ORGANIZATION> Mid-Atlantic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coca-Cola </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bottling </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> of Silver Spring, <LOCATION> Md. </LOCATION>, and <PERSON> Morton </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Lapides </PERSON>, chairman of the board of <ORGANIZATION> Allegheny </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Beverage </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Cheverly </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Md. </LOCATION>, has not been set. The two face a maximum of three years in prison. They were convicted Thursday of conspiring to set the wholesale price of their products between February 1983 and the fall of 1985. <ORGANIZATION> Allegheny </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Beverage </ORGANIZATION> was the parent company of <ORGANIZATION> Allegheny </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pepsi-Cola </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bottling </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co </ORGANIZATION>. In the six-week trial, prosecutors sought to show that both companies enjoyed higher profits because of the artifical inflation of their wholesale prices. They provided no estimate of cost to the consumer. `` They did n't want a price war ... and gave a green light to price-fixing,'' said assistant <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Attorney <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Jordan </PERSON> of the defendants. A third executive indicted, <PERSON> Odis </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Allen </PERSON>, vice president of <LOCATION> Mid-Atlantic </LOCATION>, pleaded guilty March 22 to one count of price fixing. Prosecutors said <PERSON> Allen </PERSON> met numerous times with other soft-drink executives to scheme about boosting wholesale prices of both <ORGANIZATION> Coke </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Pepsi </ORGANIZATION>. The defense contended that <PERSON> Harford </PERSON> and <PERSON> Lapides </PERSON> were unaware of what was happening, and were hostile competitors who had fought each other in court and in the marketplace. The indictments came out of a wide-ranging <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> probe of the soft drink industry. In March, <LOCATION> Allegheny </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Mid-Atlantic </LOCATION> agreed to refund $ 45,000 to state and local governments for cola bought by school districts during the time of the alleged price fixing.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880520-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-20-88 0106EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-CopIndicted     05-20 0352</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Cop Indicted,0363</SECOND>
<HEAD>Federal Grand Jury Indicts Former Cop in 1983 Motorcycle Shooting</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW ORLEANS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A white former police officer, acquitted of state charges in the 1983 shooting death of a black man, was indicted Thursday by a federal grand jury for civil rights violations in the same shooting. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Attorney <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Volz </PERSON> said the indictment charges <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Rosiere </PERSON> with shooting <PERSON> Gerard </PERSON> <PERSON> Glover </PERSON>, 18, in the back on Aug. 31, 1983. The federal charges accuse <PERSON> Rosiere </PERSON> of violating <PERSON> Glover </PERSON>'s civil rights. The maximum penalty in the federal case would be life in prison. <PERSON> Rosiere </PERSON>'s attorney, <PERSON> Arthur </PERSON> <PERSON> Lemann </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>, said he would try to get the indictment dismissed on the grounds that it subjects <PERSON> Rosiere </PERSON> to double jeopardy. <PERSON> Volz </PERSON> would not say whether any new evidence was uncovered in the federal investigation. Asked why it took so long to bring the federal charges, <PERSON> Volz </PERSON> would say only that prosecutors had been watching post-trial developments and felt the time finally had come to move on the case. He said federal officials were interested in the case because `` the boy was shot in the back riding on the back of a motorcycle fleeing from what was at worst a traffic arrest.'' Also, <PERSON> Rosiere </PERSON> and his partner admitted that they planted a gun near the scene to make it appear that the shooting was in self-defense, he said. <PERSON> Glover </PERSON>, the son of a policewoman, was a passenger behind the driver of a speeding motocycle that <PERSON> Rosiere </PERSON> and his partner were chasing. <PERSON> Rosiere </PERSON> testified during the trial that he thought he was being fired upon and that his own gun went off when the police car accelerated. His partner, who testified in exchange for immunity, said no one fired from the cycle. <PERSON> Rosiere </PERSON>, a nine-year officer, was suspended from the police force after the shooting and was fired three months later. He was charged in state court and convicted of second-degree murder in 1984. The verdict was overturned by the <ORGANIZATION> Louisiana </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> in 1985 and <PERSON> Rosiere </PERSON> was aquitted in a second trial in 1986. He works as a carpenter in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880520-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-20-88 0119EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-PokerSeries 1stLd-Writethru a0836 05-20 0344</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Poker Series, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0836,0346</SECOND>
<HEAD>Defending Champion Beats New Yorker For $700,000 World Series Of
Poker</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: SUBS graf 2, `Chan, who ..., and graf 7, `Seidel, 28, .. .,
to CORRECT that final losing hand was pair of queens.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By TIM DAHLBERG</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LAS VEGAS, Nev. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Defending champ <PERSON> Johnny </PERSON> <PERSON> Chan </PERSON> capped his comeback fight with a queen-high straight on the final hand Thursday to beat rookie <PERSON> Eric </PERSON> <PERSON> Seidel </PERSON> of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> for the $ 700,000 first prize in the World Series of Poker. <PERSON> Chan </PERSON>, who at one point was down more than $ 1.1 million in chips to <PERSON> Seidel </PERSON>, used the straight to beat <PERSON> Seidel </PERSON>'s two queens and win the final $ 592,000 pot. `` It's not over until it's over,'' said <PERSON> Chan </PERSON>. `` I was n't about to give up.'' It was the second straight World Series win for the 30-year-old <LOCATION> Las </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vegas </LOCATION> restaurateur, who beat a field of 167 players over four days in the <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> Hold ` Em tournament. <PERSON> Chan </PERSON>, who entered the final day's table of six remaining players with $ 529,000 in chips and the lead, had only $ 270,000 in chips to $ 1.4 million for <PERSON> Seidel </PERSON> when head-to-head play among the two finalists began. <PERSON> Chan </PERSON> risked all his chips on the first hand against <PERSON> Seidel </PERSON>, who folded, then steadily mounted a comeback that saw him go ahead with $ 1.2 million in chips to $ 470,000 for <PERSON> Seidel </PERSON>. <PERSON> Seidel </PERSON>, however, came back to win the game's biggest pot _ more than $ 1.2 million _ with a pair of 9s to <PERSON> Chan </PERSON>'s pair of 8s, and the game turned into a marathon with both players betting conservatively. <PERSON> Seidel </PERSON>, 28, playing in his first Series, was down to $ 296,000 when he threw all his chips in on the pair of queens. `` I'm not unhappy with what I did, but it would have been nice to win,'' he said. He wins $ 280,000 for second place. Finishing third and winning $ 140,000 was <PERSON> Ron </PERSON> <PERSON> Graham </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Tacoma </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wash. </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Humberto </PERSON> <PERSON> Bremnes </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Costa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rico </LOCATION> earned $ 77,000 for fourth, while <PERSON> T.J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Cloutier </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION> won $ 63,000 for fifth place
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880520-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-20-88 0123EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     05-20 0870</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0909</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names In The News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ARLINGTON, Texas (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> Baryshnikov </PERSON>, whose stage appearances have been sparing in recent years, will launch a five-week national tour with dancers from the American Ballet Theater with a July 1 performance here. <PERSON> Baryshnikov </PERSON> is expected to dance the title role in <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Balanchine </PERSON>'s `` Apollo,'' the male lead in <PERSON> Balanchine </PERSON>'s jazzy `` Who Cares?'' and in <PERSON> Jerome </PERSON> <PERSON> Robbins </PERSON> `` Other Dances'' at the Six Flags over <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> amusement park. The 40-year-old dancer was forced to cancel a two-day <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION> engagement last August because of an ankle injury. <PERSON> Baryshnikov </PERSON> was a member of the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>'s Kirov Ballet when he defected in 1974 while on tour in <LOCATION> Toronto </LOCATION>. He joined the American Ballet Theater, then danced briefly with the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ballet </LOCATION> before becoming artistic director of the ABT. He also had starring roles in the movies `` The Turning Point,'' `` White Nights'' and `` Dancers.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>FREEHOLD, N.J. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The transcontinental custody dispute over the 5-year-old son of actor <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Toole </PERSON> awaits a decision by an English court, says the attorney for the child's mother. `` We're waiting to see whether <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> has jurisdiction over the child,'' said <PERSON> Raoul </PERSON> <PERSON> Felder </PERSON>, attorney for <PERSON> Karen </PERSON> <PERSON> Somerville </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Toole </PERSON>, <PERSON> O'Toole </PERSON>'s former girlfriend. The decision was expected Monday. <ORGANIZATION> Monmouth </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Superior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> Judge <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Lehrer </PERSON> ordered <PERSON> O'Toole </PERSON> to return the child, <PERSON> Lorcan </PERSON>, to his mother by Tuesday, but <PERSON> O'Toole </PERSON> refused. <PERSON> O'Toole </PERSON>, 55, is in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> with the boy and is being fined $ 1,000 a day by the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> court for failure to comply with the order, his attorney, <PERSON> Jeffrey </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Weinstein </PERSON>, said Thursday. If the English court rules that the child is not within its jurisdiction, <PERSON> Felder </PERSON> said he will seek an arrest warrant for <PERSON> O'Toole </PERSON>. That would prevent the actor from entering the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> without facing arrest, <PERSON> Felder </PERSON> said. The case is being heard in <LOCATION> Monmouth </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> because <PERSON> O'Toole </PERSON> bought a home near here for <PERSON> Lorcan </PERSON> and Ms. <PERSON> O'Toole </PERSON>, 39. The couple never married but Ms. <PERSON> O'Toole </PERSON> took the actor's last name. They broke up shortly after <PERSON> Lorcan </PERSON>'s birth.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Shirley </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>, honored along with fellow actress <PERSON> Connie </PERSON> <PERSON> Stevens </PERSON> for her charitable work with children, says the award means more to her than her Oscar. Childhelp <LOCATION> USA </LOCATION>, an organization devoted to the research, treatment and prevention of child abuse, awarded Miss <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> and Miss <PERSON> Stevens </PERSON> their 24th annual `` Woman of the World'' award Thursday, said spokeswoman <PERSON> Evie </PERSON> <PERSON> Lazzarino </PERSON>. Miss <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>, who won the best supporting actress <PERSON> Oscar </PERSON> in 1960 for her role in `` <PERSON> Elmer </PERSON> <PERSON> Gantry </PERSON>,'' is national chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Leukemia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION>. `` Of all the tributes I have received I'm most grateful and feel strongest about this one, including the Academy Award,'' Miss <PERSON> Lazzarino </PERSON> quoted Miss <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> as saying. Miss <PERSON> Stevens </PERSON>, whose work ranges from movies to television to <LOCATION> Las </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vegas </LOCATION> shows, was honored for her work with `` Windfeather,'' a group devoted to helping native Americans.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actor <PERSON> Sylvester </PERSON> <PERSON> Stallone </PERSON> paid a surprise visit to a young cerebral palsy patient thanks to a little strategic planning by Mayor <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON>. <PERSON> Stallone </PERSON>, star of the `` Rambo'' and `` Rocky'' movies, met Thursday at <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hall </ORGANIZATION> with wheelchair-bound <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON> <PERSON> Byrge </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, who was visiting <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> with his family from <LOCATION> Beckley </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> W. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON> arranged <PERSON> Stallone </PERSON>'s surprise meeting with <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON>, a fourth-grade student who does college-level work and computer `` I'm perhaps a hero in fiction, but he's a hero in reality,'' <PERSON> Stallone </PERSON> said of <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON>. Although he traded jibes with the actor-producer, <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON> admitted later that `` I thought I was going to pass out.'' <PERSON> Stallone </PERSON> later signed a `` Rambo III'' poster for <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON>. The movie opens Memorial Day weekend.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>ATLANTA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actress <PERSON> Victoria </PERSON> <PERSON> Principal </PERSON>, who has been active for several years in the <ORGANIZATION> Arthritis </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION>, will serve as the group's main celebrity advocate in dealings with government agencies. Ms. Principal, a former star of the television series `` <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION>,'' was named the <ORGANIZATION> Arthritis </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION>'s ambassador to government. She has been national campaign chairwoman for the foundation since 1983 and has written three books on beauty, diet and exercise. A foundation announcement credited her efforts with persuading several states to keep drugs used for arthritis on the list of medicines paid for by the Medicaid program. She has been an Arthritis Foundation trustee since 1984. The Atlanta-based foundation says 37 million Americans are affected by arthritis.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NASHVILLE, Tenn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Singer <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Earle </PERSON> is scheduled to stand trial next month in <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION> on charges of assaulting a police officer at a <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION> nightspot New Year's morning. <PERSON> Earle </PERSON>, in turn, has asked that assault charges be filed against the officer, Sgt. L.R. <PERSON> Allen </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Dallas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>. <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION> police said the <LOCATION> Nashville </LOCATION> singer punched and kicked <PERSON> Allen </PERSON> as the officer tried to break up a fight between <PERSON> Earle </PERSON> and his longtime stagehand, <PERSON> Chip </PERSON> <PERSON> Phillips </PERSON>. <PERSON> Earle </PERSON> claims the officer attacked him from behind. A <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION> police spokesman said the department's internal affairs division has investigated <PERSON> Earle </PERSON>'s charges and does n't plan to reprimand <PERSON> Allen </PERSON>. <PERSON> Earle </PERSON> was charged with disorderly conduct, a misdemeanor, and a felony count of aggravated assault. His trial was set for June 6. The singer is known for his country-style albums `` Guitar Town'' and `` Exit O.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880520-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-20-88 0727EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a AM-BRF--GEBlast     05-20 0143</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--GE Blast,0146</SECOND>
<HEAD>1 Killed, 2 Injured In Explosion At General Electric Plant</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ROTTERDAM, N.Y. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An explosion blew a 12-ton metal door off a pressure vessel at <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Electric </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co </ORGANIZATION>'s steam turbine plant Thursday, killing one worker and injuring two others. The explosion took place at about 3:40 a.m. in Building 273, the largest building and main manufacturing plant for steam turbines and generators at the <LOCATION> Schenectady </LOCATION> plant, said <ORGANIZATION> GE </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Stone </PERSON>. Killed in the explosion was 60-year-old <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Dwojakowski </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Schenectady </LOCATION>, a GE worker since 1956, <PERSON> Stone </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Stone </PERSON> said a metal door weighing 12 tons was blown off the pressure vessel, called an autoclave, used in curing insulation applied to a component in the manufacturing of generators. The federal <ORGANIZATION> Occupational </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> is investigating the accident, <PERSON> Stone </PERSON> said, as well as <ORGANIZATION> GE </ORGANIZATION>'s own investigation team.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880520-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-20-88 0157EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--Canada-Thatcher     05-20 0089</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Canada-Thatcher,0091</SECOND>
<HEAD>British Leader To Address Canadian Parliament After Economic
Summit</HEAD>
<DATELINE>OTTAWA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Prime Minister <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> will address a joint session of the Canadian <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION> the day after the world Economic Summit ends in <LOCATION> Toronto </LOCATION> next month. Prime Minister <PERSON> Brian </PERSON> <PERSON> Mulroney </PERSON>'s office announced Thursday that Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON>'s one-day visit to <LOCATION> Ottawa </LOCATION> on June 22 will also include talks on bilateral issues. West German Chancellor <PERSON> Helmut </PERSON> <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON> will pay a four-day visit to <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> prior to the start of the Economic Summit on June 19.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880520-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-20-88 0158EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Belgium     05-20 0144</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Belgium,0149</SECOND>
<HEAD>Government Wins Confidence Vote on Ending Linguistic Strife</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BRUSSELS, Belgium (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Prime Minister <PERSON> Wilfried </PERSON> <PERSON> Martens </PERSON>' new government won a <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> vote of confidence in a step toward advancing its program to end the country's age-old linguistic strife. The vote Thursday endorsed the program of the 10-day-old center-left government that the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Representatives </ORGANIZATION> approved on Sunday. The votes came seven months after <PERSON> Martens </PERSON>' previous center-right alliance government fell apart in a linguistic dispute. <PERSON> Martens </PERSON> now plans to put into effect sweeping constitutional reforms to quell perennial bickering between <LOCATION> Belgium </LOCATION>'s 5.5 million Dutch speakers and 4.5 million French speakers. His new alliance plans to boost the powers of autonomy of northern <LOCATION> Flanders </LOCATION> and southern <LOCATION> Wallonia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Belgium </LOCATION>'s two linguistic regions. The prime minister has said he will send the constitutional changes by August to <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION>, where he will need a two-thirds majority.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880520-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-20-88 0046EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p AM-Bush 2ndLd-Writethru a0834 05-20 0753</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Bush, 2nd Ld-Writethru, a0834,690</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush Wins Reagan Praise, Meets Civil Rights Leaders</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDs: INSERTS 3rd graf with Post report; edits 14th graf pvs to
delete full first reference to Noriega</NOTE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Republican <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> basked on Thursday in the praise of President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> who called him `` an important part of everything we have achieved in this so-called revolution.'' The vice president also received a dispensation of sorts from the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> to disagree with the president's policies. Presidential spokesman <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> told reporters Thursday, `` He has his ideas on how he's going to want to do things, and that's fine.'' Meanwhile, <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION>, quoting sources, reported in Friday's editions that <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> urged at a high-level meeting of administration policymakers that negotiations with <LOCATION> Panamanian </LOCATION> leader <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> be ended. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> campaign spokesman <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Teeley </PERSON> said Thursday night he had no knowledge of any such recommendation by the vice president. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> met held a private evening meeting with civil rights leaders at his official residence. The vice president's chief of staff told reporters that <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> asked the black leaders to `` share open discussion with him.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> called it a `` very good session.'' <PERSON> Benjamin </PERSON> <PERSON> Hooks </PERSON>, head of the <ORGANIZATION> NAACP </ORGANIZATION> and one of the participants, said a wide range of issues was discussed. But Hooks said: `` At this point I'd say the vice president has a long way to go if he actually expects to get a substantial black vote.'' <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Jacob </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Urban </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> League </ORGANIZATION>, who also attended the meeting, said the fact that the meeting had taken place was in itself important. `` This is the first meeting of this type in some eight years, and that is significant,'' he said. <PERSON> Jacob </PERSON> told a recent news conference that the group was trying to set up a similar session with Democrat <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>. <PERSON> Jacob </PERSON>, a supporter of Democrat <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, said, `` Any candidate who wins will have to come to get the black votes. Neither -LRB- <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> nor <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> -RRB- has demonstrated that he has the capacity to get black voters.'' <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, who officially endorsed his vice president two weeks ago, made his comments in an interview with foreign broadcasters. `` I have to say that the vice president has been an important part of everything that we have achieved in this so-called revolution in these seven years or so,'' he said. `` I have always believed that vice presidents in our system of government were relegated to a kind of just standing and waiting position, and I think that's a waste of talent. I have always believed that your vice president should be like a vice president in a private corporation. He should be an executive with duties and functions.'' <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> cited <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s work at the helm of task forces, one on reducing regulations and another on drugs. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s spokesman took pains to make clear that <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was his own man and was free to differ from administration policy. <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> spoke a day after comments by <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and his aides suggested a break with <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> on the question of dismissing drug-trafficking indictments against <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>. `` I wo n't bargain with terrorists and I wo n't bargain with drug dealers either, whether they are on <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> or foreign soil,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said Wednesday. `` I'm saying that he has his ideas on how he's going to want to do things, and that's fine,'' <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said. `` As we go through this campaign, I would expect to see the vice president speaking out on a number of issues in terms of what he would do,'' he said. `` I expect a number of them will be different than existing policies and we will not criticize them in any way. If you want to drive a wedge between the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and the vice president, forget it.'' In the interview with foreign broadcasters, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> was asked about <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s apparent effort to distance himself from White House policy on <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>. `` I can see why the vice president said what he said,'' <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said in the interview. `` Because the impression has been given, based not on information from us, but based on rumors and news leaks and so forth, that we are in negotiations over, with a participant in the drug trade and all. And I think he was making himself plain that you do n't negotiate with people of that kind.'' The president said his talks with <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> were not about his involvement in the drug trade. `` Our goal, what we're trying to achieve, is the restoration of democracy in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880520-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-20-88 0228EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-SpaceShuttle     05-20 0405</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Space Shuttle,400</SECOND>
<HEAD>Nevada Explosion Casts Doubt On Shuttle Schedule After August</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto WX6</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By HARRY F. ROSENTHAL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> still hopes to launch the first post-Challenger space shuttle in August, but the agency is uncertain whether it can meet a goal of nine flights next year, the head of the shuttle program says. The reason for the doubt is the explosion that destroyed the <ORGANIZATION> Pacific </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Engineering </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Production </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> plant in <LOCATION> Henderson </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Nev. </LOCATION>, on May 4. The explosion eliminated the source of half the nation's supply of a chemical used for the shuttle boosters and some other rockets A second plant in <LOCATION> Henderson </LOCATION>, owned by <ORGANIZATION> Kerr-McGee </ORGANIZATION>, has shut down for inspections to see that it is safe. Pacific Engineering and <ORGANIZATION> Kerr-McGee </ORGANIZATION> were the only American companies manufacturing ammonium perchlorate, an oxidizer. The oxidizer makes sure the solid rocket fuel burns evenly. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Truly </PERSON>, associate administrator for space flight of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aeronautics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Space </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>, said Thursday that rocket-maker <ORGANIZATION> Morton </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Thiokol </ORGANIZATION> has enough ammonium perchlorate on hand for four flights and there is enough on hand for a fifth rocket set. The Titan 4 also uses ammonium perchlorate. The chemical, in the form of white crystals, is taken by rail car to <ORGANIZATION> Morton </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Thiokol </ORGANIZATION>'s plant in <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION>, mixed there, and poured into the segments that make the booster rockets. `` The issue will first come up in 1989, but we're not certain there is going to be an impact in 1989 until we get together with the <ORGANIZATION> DOD </ORGANIZATION> -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> -RRB- to match requirements and availability,'' Truly said. He said <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> will have to decide how to divide up the output of <ORGANIZATION> Kerr-McGee </ORGANIZATION>. He said the first post-Challenger flight still is on schedule for launch in late August. He insisted the agency had not set a firm date but is working toward a target of Aug. 22. Pacific Engineering said the explosion, which killed two people and injured 326 was caused by a natural gas leak. Pacific Engineering and <ORGANIZATION> Kerr-McGee </ORGANIZATION> each produced 30 million pounds per year of ammonium perchlorate. <ORGANIZATION> Morton </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Thiokol </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Rocky </PERSON> <PERSON> Raab </PERSON> said the company has n't ruled out buying ammonium perchlorate from foreign firms but added: `` The rest of the world supply is pretty meager I've seen estimates of worldwide production of nine million pounds a year.'' A pair of shuttle booster rockets uses 1.5 million pounds of ammonium perchlorate per flight.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880520-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-20-88 0229EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Reagan-Drugs     05-20 0451</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Reagan-Drugs,440</SECOND>
<HEAD>Administration Wary of Giving Military Drug-Arrest Powers</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MERRILL HARTSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s spokesman says the administration is wary of giving military personnel drug-trafficking arrest powers because `` you cross an enormous bridge when you move them'' to an enforcement role. Spokesman <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> on Thursday did not directly oppose a bill passed overwhelmingly by the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> to allow the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> to make arrests on the high seas, but he said the administration is `` very cautious in that area.'' `` I think the <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> people would want us to be cautious,'' <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said. `` But that does not diminish the idea that there are expanded roles for the military.'' <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Carlucci </PERSON> and Adm. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Crowe </PERSON>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Joint </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chiefs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Staff </ORGANIZATION>, oppose attempts by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to substantially change a military role which now consists primarily of surveillance. <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> was asked about a change <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> made in a speech Wednesday on the subject. The prepared remarks had called for <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> to say he had directed <PERSON> Carlucci </PERSON> to search for `` creative solutions on how we can better use military resources and technologies to detect and interdict drugs coming into this country.'' But when he actually delivered the speech, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> changed that line to say he wanted <PERSON> Carlucci </PERSON> to find better ways for the military `` to detect drugs and support civil law enforcement agencies in interdiction.'' Asked about the significance of the change, <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said, `` There is a very great concern about what it means to make law enforcement officers out of the military.'' `` You cross an enormous bridge when you move them from providing military support and surveillance and physical interdiction efforts to making arrests and legal judgments and so forth,'' he said. `` As I think it was, <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> -RRB- the other day said, ` The first time an F-15 shoots down a dentist because his -LRB- airplane -RRB- radio does n't work, you begin to understand the dimensions of the problem.'' The chamber last Friday voted 83-6 for an amendment outlining a wide-ranging anti-drug role for the military. The proposal calls for more surveillance by <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> planes, increased anti-drug activity by the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> and more <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> helicopters for the <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Customs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>. The most controversial provision would require <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> vessels to track suspected drug boats and would allow <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> officers to arrest suspected drug traffickers in international waters. The officers would be temporarily `` deputized'' by <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> officers who would be aboard for that purpose. <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON>, however, likened the drug trade to `` a 30-foot tidal wave hitting a 25-foot wall'' and said, `` The fact is that interdiction is never going to solve the problem without cutting the demand.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880520-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-20-88 0214EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-ReaganInterview Bjt   05-20 0713</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Reagan Interview, Bjt,710</SECOND>
<HEAD>Reagan Considers Gorbachev a Friend Despite Disagreements</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MERRILL HARTSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> says he considers Soviet leader <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> a friend as well as an adversary and says the West should applaud whatever reforms <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> can achieve. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> also says he believes `` it is evident'' <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> is encountering opposition from forces `` who want to cling to what are more the Stalinist policies'' of yesteryear. Providing a rare insight to the private talks the two have had in recent years, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> told foreign broadcasters Thursday that strains in superpower relations have not harmed their personal relationship. Asked if he considered <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> a friend, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> replied, `` Well, I ca n't help but say yes to that. ... Yes, we can debate and we disagree. But there is never a sense of personal animus when the arguments are over.'' While <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> has challenged <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> to prove that his `` glasnost'' campaign of openness is genuine, he said the West should encourage the move toward change in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. `` If there's any way that outside nations could be helpful in this, they should,'' he said, `` because many of the reforms that he has undertaken are aimed at the things that we have always criticized in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. `` And if there is a way to be helpful in that, certainly, to at least acknowledge our approval of what he is doing, that we should do that.'' <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s obliging tone came on a day in which the president continued to receive briefings in preparation for his May 29-June 2 summit with <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>. The president also made these points in a wide-ranging interview: _ `` I believe there is a desire in the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> to settle once and for all what is still technically a state of war between the Arab nations and <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>.'' He said the purpose of an international peace conference would be to aid the parties but not to `` dictate a settlement'' and said any Soviet role in such a conference would likely have to be preceded by a <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION> decision to resume relations with <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>. _ He hopes that <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> `` has heard some of the things that I have been saying'' about former White House chief of staff <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> T. </PERSON> <PERSON> Regan </PERSON>'s accusation that astrology played a role in official business, saying that `` no decision was ever made by me on the basis of astrology. _ Clandestine sales of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> arms to elements in <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> during parts of 1985 and 1986 were aimed at bringing about the release of hostages held in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> by pro-Iranian extremists, but he claimed that they did not amount to an arms-for-hostages deal `` I've labored under the misapprehension here _ well, worldwide, I guess _ about the so-called Iran-Contra affair,'' he said. `` I've likened it to, if I had a child that was kidnapped, I do n't think that you should pay ransom. But if I found there was another individual that could get that child back for me in return for my doing something for him, that would be all right.'' On superpower relations and arms control, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said he thinks it is possible that a long-range missile treaty can be negotiated before he leaves office because <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> might not want to wait for a new administration. While acknowledging that `` none of us really think'' such a strategic missile deal could be completed at the coming summit in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>, he said he did not think <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> necessarily wants to take his time. He said `` we're working as hard as we can, and it's a far more complex treaty than the INF'' -LRB- Intermediate-range Nuclear Forces -RRB- treaty signed by <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> last December. `` But I think that it is possible that we could have that, yes, while this administration is still here.'' The president said he thinks the atmosphere for arms control has improved in recent years, in part because of the nuclear reactor accident at <LOCATION> Chernobyl </LOCATION> in the <LOCATION> Ukraine </LOCATION>. `` Possibly, in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, it was their tragic experience with <LOCATION> Chernobyl </LOCATION>, and to see that how an area was made unlivable for the people that had lived all their lives there,'' he said. `` And when you stop and think, that that explosion was less than the power of one single warhead.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880520-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-20-88 0218EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Noriega Bjt   05-20 0761</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Noriega, Bjt,770</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHINGTON WIRE: US Vs. Panama _ Which is the Banana Republic?</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP News Analysis</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GEORGE GEDDA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
