<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880525-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-25-88 2359EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Soviet-Cooperatives     05-25 0474</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Soviet-Cooperatives,0489</SECOND>
<HEAD>Heavy List of Amendments Slows Cooperative Law</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MOSCOW (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Soviet Parliament on Wednesday put off voting on a progressive tax on people who work for private cooperatives, a key element of <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s reforms. Such a move by the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Soviet </ORGANIZATION>, which normally approves laws that have been put forward by the ruling <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, is very unusual. It may reflect concern about the contents of the law as well as a greater willingness to speak out under <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s policy of greater openness. The two chambers of the Supreme Soviet, the nominal parliament, met in separate sessions Wednesday to debate the law, scheduled to go into effect on July 1. The law also guarantees that cooperatives' property will not be seized by the government. Officials have said the aim of the progressive tax system on income earned by individuals who work in cooperatives is to get the cooperatives to invest in expanding their businesses rather than paying high salaries to workers. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> has pushed cooperatives as a method of augmenting the state-run economy, which can not provide enough consumer goods and services. Soviet Premier <PERSON> Nikolai </PERSON> <PERSON> Ryzhkov </PERSON> said in a speech to the opening session of the Supreme Soviet on Tuesday that the law was of `` immense social and political significance.'' He said the cooperative system `` in a short time can solve the most severe problems of perestroika -LRB- restructuring -RRB-, the demand of the population for goods and services.'' The cooperative law was to have been brought before a joint meeting of the Supreme Soviet on Wednesday, but officials at the meeting said 22 parliamentarians spoke about the law in meetings of the separate chambers Wednesday morning and that it was delayed while a commission looked at a series of proposed amendments. Officials at the Supreme Soviet meeting gave no details of the issues under debate, but the <ORGANIZATION> Tass </ORGANIZATION> news agency said in a report that `` judging by the deputies' remarks, the new edition of the law has caused no objections of principle, while the amendments suggested are dictated by the desire to protect cooperatives from unfounded interference by local authorities.'' `` Groundless limitations are introduced in many places, often under the pretext of attempts to keep workers from leaving state enterprises,'' <ORGANIZATION> Tass </ORGANIZATION> said. `` Another reason behind the limitations is the bigoted idea that a cooperative is something to be looked down at.'' It said other problems facing cooperatives are the difficulty of obtaining supplies and the system of taxation. <PERSON> Ryzhkov </PERSON> said Tuesday that 6,000 cooperatives had been formed in the previous three months while the new law was being debated, while a total of 14,000 had been formed in 18 months. Restaurants are one of the most popular forms of cooperatives that have opened, and others have formed to make clothing, pump gas, do apartment repairs and provide other services.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880525-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-25-88 0047EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-CaliforniaSenate     05-25 0689</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-California Senate,0707</SECOND>
<HEAD>Pete Wilson Eyes `Jinx'; McCarthy Hoping for Upset</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By JOHN HOWARD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SACRAMENTO, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Democratic Lt. Gov. <PERSON> Leo </PERSON> <PERSON> McCarthy </PERSON> is trailing in the polls and in fund raising, but he has one thing in his favor as he seeks to unseat Republican Sen. <PERSON> Pete </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> this year _ `` The Jinx.'' For more than 30 years, no one has been re-elected to the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> seat <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> holds. Incumbents have died, stepped down or been defeated and descended into political oblivion. By contrast, Democrat <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Cranston </PERSON> is flourishing in his fourth term holding down the state's other seat. `` Everybody talks about ` The Jinx,''' said <PERSON> Craig </PERSON> <PERSON> Schmidt </PERSON>, a <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> aide. `` But this is the year ` The Jinx' will be broken.'' <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON>, not surprisingly, agrees: `` I think it's nonsense, a myth. We're going to prove it's not true.' The question of whether unlucky tradition will prevail may be the most exciting thing about the race, which is generally viewed as a showdown between two competent, conventional and largely colorless politicians. Both men are youthful-looking, clean-cut candidates, with reputations for personal honesty, and are perceived as moderates in their respective parties. <PERSON> McCarthy </PERSON>, 57, a former <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> supervisor who spent 14 years in the <ORGANIZATION> Legislature </ORGANIZATION>, including six years as <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION> speaker, is expected to have no trouble defeating two little-known challengers in the June 7 Democratic primary: <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Banuelos </PERSON>, a communications consultant from <ORGANIZATION> Orange </ORGANIZATION>, and <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Greene </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON>, 54-year-old former mayor of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Diego </LOCATION>, is unopposed for the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> nomination. Since January 1987, <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> has raised $ 4.7 million and spent about $ 4 million, while <PERSON> McCarthy </PERSON> has raised $ 2.4 million and spent $ 1.7 million. Both candidates say about 80 percent of their funds will be used to buy television advertising, a critical resource in this vast state which comprises 10 percent of the nation's population `` We've spent the recesses and the weekends campaigning,'' <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> said in an interview earlier this month, perched on the rear seat of a minivan zipping along Interstate 5. `` We've been out virtually every weekend ... but it's literally impossible for me to meet everybody.'' In one recent campaign swing, <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> hit 13 cities in three days, targeting growers and business groups, while <PERSON> McCarthy </PERSON> has been on the road with a no-frills whistle-stop-style campaign from a motorhome. <PERSON> McCarthy </PERSON> said he has used the lieutenant governor's position to push legislation for health care for the elderly, nursing home improvements and child care programs. `` I think the elderly see me as their No. 1 champion. This is a very significant area of strength for me. This is something everyone concedes. `` But I do n't exaggerate the power inherent in the lieutenant governor's office,'' <PERSON> McCarthy </PERSON> added. `` I received far more media attention when I was Assembly speaker.'' The most recent statewide survey of <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> voters, a May 11 poll by the Gallup Organization, showed <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> with a 21-point lead over <PERSON> McCarthy </PERSON>, 51 percent to 30 percent, with 19 percent undecided. <PERSON> McCarthy </PERSON>, however, dismisses the polls, contending they largely reflect <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON>'s television advertising campaign. Since those polls, <PERSON> McCarthy </PERSON> received more bad news when a phalanx of <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION> film moguls, eight powerful studio chiefs, endorsed <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON>. The studio bosses included several prominent Democrats. <PERSON> McCarthy </PERSON> belittled the significance of the May 2 endorsements, saying that such stars <ORGANIZATION> Morgan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fairchild </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Lemmon </PERSON>, <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Willis </PERSON> and <PERSON> Warren </PERSON> <PERSON> Beatty </PERSON> remained loyal to him. At issue is a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> seat that has traded hands continuously since the 1950s. Moderate Democrat <PERSON> Clair </PERSON> <PERSON> Engle </PERSON>, who won the seat in 1958, died in office, and <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>'s former press secretary, <PERSON> Pierre </PERSON> <PERSON> Salinger </PERSON>, was appointed to complete his term. <PERSON> Salinger </PERSON> lost his 1964 election bid to Hollywood song-and-dance man <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON>, a conservative Republican who in turn was defeated in 1970 by <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Tunney </PERSON>, a Democrat and the son of boxer <PERSON> Gene </PERSON> <PERSON> Tunney </PERSON>. In 1976, <PERSON> Tunney </PERSON> was defeated by former <ORGANIZATION> San </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Francisco </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> President S.I. <PERSON> Hayakawa </PERSON>, an acid-tongued, articulate semanticist known for his hard-line approach to student protesters. In 1982, faced with week standings in the polls, <PERSON> Hayakawa </PERSON> retired and was succeeded by <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880525-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-25-88 0050EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Nielsens     05-25 0464</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nielsens,0475</SECOND>
<HEAD>`Hulk' Wins Ratings Battle with `Baby M'</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KATHRYN BAKER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Television Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> racked up another win in the Nielsens thanks to two ratings `` hulks'' _ one <PERSON> Lou </PERSON> <PERSON> Ferrigno </PERSON> and the other <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Hope </PERSON>. `` The Incredible Hulk Returns,'' a reunion movie starring <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Bixby </PERSON> and <PERSON> Ferrigno </PERSON> as, respectively, a professor and his violent alter ego, ranked fourth in the weekly Nielsens with a rating of 20.2 and a 33 share. Hope's special celebration of 50 years of association with <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> finished in sixth with an 19.0 and 31. And <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> may have solved its Wednesday night ratings with an `` Unsolved Mysteries'' special that was also in the top 10 in the <ORGANIZATION> A.C. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nielsen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> ratings, at ninth, and is due to become a regular weekly fixture in the fall. <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Baby M'' was no match for `` Hulk'' in a three-way made-for-TV movie battle on Sunday. Part one of the two-parter starring <PERSON> JoBeth </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> as <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Beth </PERSON> <PERSON> Whitehead </PERSON> <PERSON> Gould </PERSON> had a 15.0 rating and 24 share and ranked 17th for the week. <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> came in third with `` My Father, My Son,'' starring <PERSON> Karl </PERSON> <PERSON> Malden </PERSON> and <PERSON> Keith </PERSON> <PERSON> Carradine </PERSON> as Adm. <PERSON> Elmo </PERSON> <PERSON> Zumwalt </PERSON> and his son. It had a 13.5 rating and 22 share and ranked 21st. <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> won the week that ended Sunday with an average, prime-time rating of 15.3. <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> was second with 11.6. CBS' 10.7 was its lowest weekly rating this season. Last week was part of the important May sweeps, one of the four months a year when television ratings companies measure viewership in local markets. But with only a few days to go, <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> was second to <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> in sweeps competition. <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s average since the beginning of the season stands at 15.8. <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> has 13.5 and CBS 13.2. The rating is a percentage of the nation's estimated 88.6 million households with televisions. The share is a percentage of sets in use. The top 10-rated shows of the week were: `` The Cosby Show'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, `` A Different World'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, `` Cheers'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, `` The Incredible Hulk Returns'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, `` Night Court'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, `` <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Hope </PERSON>'s Birthday'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, `` Golden Girls'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, `` 60 Minutes'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, `` Unsolved Mysteries'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>,'' and `` The American Comedy Awards'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>. The lowest-rated, prime-time shows were: `` Eisenhower & amp; <PERSON> Lutz </PERSON>'' tied with `` Full House,'' `` Perfect Strangers,'' `` <PERSON> Garfield </PERSON>'s 10th Anniversary,'' `` <PERSON> Beryl </PERSON> <PERSON> Markham </PERSON>, Part 2,'' `` Tour of Duty,'' `` Meet the Munceys,'' `` High Mountain Rangers,'' `` M & amp; W Magazine,'' `` Probe'' and `` Our House.'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> remained third in the news race but closed the gap somewhat. For the week that ended Friday, <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` World News Tonight'' was first for the fourth week in a row, finishing with an average rating of 9.5 and a 20 share. The `` CBS Evening News'' had a 9.2 and a 19 share. `` NBC Nightly News'' had an 8.8 and 19 share.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880525-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-25-88 0050EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Justice-Dennis     05-25 0233</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Justice-Dennis,0238</SECOND>
<HEAD>Justice Department Nominee Known For Diligence</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</NOTE>
<HEAD>With PM-Justice Appointments</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PHILADELPHIA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Attorney <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> S.G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Dennis </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s choice to head the cirminal division of the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, is known for painstaking investigations that have led to his winning convictions in racketeering and official corruption cases. If <PERSON> Dennis </PERSON>, 43, is confirmed by the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> as assistant attorney general, the stint in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> will be his second. He was an assistant <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> attorney in <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION> before becoming head of the narcotics section at the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>'s criminal division in 1980 <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> appointed him <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> attorney in <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION> on May 4, 1983, the first black to hold the post in the Eastern District of <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION>. His office obtained convictions of more than 30 <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION> police officers, including the deputy police commissioner, on extortion and racketeering charges. <PERSON> Dennis </PERSON> also handled the successful prosecution of <PERSON> Nicodemo </PERSON> <PERSON> Scarfo </PERSON>, the reputed head of organized crime in the <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION> area, and City Councilman <PERSON> Leland </PERSON> <PERSON> Beloff </PERSON> for trying to extort $ 1 million from a developer to obtain <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> approval to build a waterfront development. In five years as an assistant <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> attorney in <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Dennis </PERSON> lost only one case. He attributed his record to his methodical style of preparation _ going over evidence again and again, examining and re-examining witnesses until he was able to `` anticipate every conceivable attack.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880525-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-25-88 0249EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Justice-Christensen     05-25 0257</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Justice-Christensen,0265</SECOND>
<HEAD>Choice For Deputy Attorney General Is Known As Manager</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</NOTE>
<HEAD>With PM-Justice Appointments</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SALT LAKE CITY (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Harold </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Christensen </PERSON>, nominated for the post of deputy attorney general, is a civil trial lawyer known for his ability to organize, plan and manage details, colleagues say. If confirmed by the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>, the 61-year-old <PERSON> Christensen </PERSON> would assume the No. 2 spot in the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>. One colleague suggested that <PERSON> Christensen </PERSON>'s qualifications exceed those of Attorney General <PERSON> Edwin </PERSON> <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>. `` I would go so far as to say that as far as being the chief legal enforcement officer in this country, <PERSON> Hal </PERSON> is eminently more qualified than Mr. <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>,'' said attorney <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Campbell </PERSON>. <PERSON> Christensen </PERSON>, a senior partner and chairman of the board of the law firm Snow, <ORGANIZATION> Christensen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> Martineau </PERSON>, was born in <LOCATION> Springville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION>, graduated from the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Utah </ORGANIZATION> and received a law degree from the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Michigan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Law </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> in 1951. `` His ability to reason is unusual,'' said attorney <PERSON> Eugene </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Hansen </PERSON>. `` He has a superior ability to organize, execute plans, manage and delegate.'' Although a Republican, <PERSON> Christensen </PERSON> once organized a Lawyers for <PERSON> Scott </PERSON> <PERSON> Matheson </PERSON> group to campaign for the former <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> governor. He was president of the <ORGANIZATION> Salt </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lake </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bar </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> in 1972, was inducted into the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Trial </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lawyers </ORGANIZATION> in 1974 and was <ORGANIZATION> Utah </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bar </ORGANIZATION> president in 1975-76. <PERSON> Christensen </PERSON> was named the state bar's Lawyer of the Year in 1984 and was appointed chairman of the <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Judicial </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Selection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> that year.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880525-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-25-88 0213EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-NielsensList     05-25 0680</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nielsens List,0755</SECOND>
<HEAD>List of Week's Top-Rated TV Shows</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Nielsens</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the prime-time television ratings as compiled by the <ORGANIZATION> A.C. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nielsen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> for the week of May 16-22. Top 20 listings include the week's ranking, with full season-to-date ranking in parentheses, rating for the week, and total homes. An `` X'' in parentheses denotes one-time-only presentation. A rating measures the percentage of the nation's 88.6 million TV homes. 1. -LRB- 1 -RRB- `` The Cosby Show,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 21.2 rating, 18.8 million homes. 1. -LRB- 2 -RRB- `` A Different World,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 21.2, 18.8 million homes. 3. -LRB- 3 -RRB- `` Cheers,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 20.9, 18.5 million homes. 4. -LRB- 20 -RRB- `` The Incredible Hulk Returns'' _ `` NBC Sunday Night Movie,'' 20.2, 17.9 million homes. 5. -LRB- 6 -RRB- `` Night Court,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 19.9, 17.6 million homes. 6. -LRB- X -RRB- `` <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Hope </PERSON>'s Birthday Special,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 19.0, 16.8 million homes. 7. -LRB- 4 -RRB- `` Golden Girls,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 18.7, 16.6 million homes. 8. -LRB- 8 -RRB- `` 60 Minutes,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 17.3, 15.3 million homes. 9. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Unsolved Mysteries Special,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 17.0, 15.1 million homes. 10. -LRB- X -RRB- `` American Comedy Awards,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 16.8, 14.9 million homes. 11. -LRB- 5 -RRB- `` Who's the Boss?'', <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 16.6, 14.7 million homes. 12. -LRB- 9 -RRB- `` Murder, She Wrote,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 16.3, 14.4 million homes. 13. -LRB- 15 -RRB- `` Amen,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 16.1, 14.3 million homes. 13. -LRB- 13 -RRB- `` Just the Ten of Us,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 16.1, 14.3 million homes. 15. -LRB- 32 -RRB- `` Jagged Edge'' _ `` <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> Tuesday Movie of the Week,'' 15.7, 13.9 million homes. 16. -LRB- 12 -RRB- `` <LOCATION> L.A. </LOCATION> Law,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 15.6, 13.8 million homes. 17. -LRB- 35 -RRB- `` Baby M,'' Part 1, _ `` <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> Sunday Night Movie,'' 15.0, 13.3 million homes. 18. -LRB- 34 -RRB- `` Whisper Kills'' _ `` <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> Monday Night Movie,'' 14.7, 13.0 million homes. 19. -LRB- 50 -RRB- `` St. Elsewhere,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.8, 12.2 million homes. 20. -LRB- 28 -RRB- `` 227,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.6, 12.0 million homes.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 21. -LRB- 18 -RRB- `` My Father, My Son'' _ `` CBS Sunday Movie,'' 13.5. 22. -LRB- 29 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Hunter </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.2. 22. -LRB- 6 -RRB- `` Growing Pains,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.2. 22. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Promised a Miracle'' _ `` CBS Special Movie Presentation,'' 13.2. 25. -LRB- 26 -RRB- `` Head of the Class,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.7. 26. -LRB- 17 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Matlock </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.5. 27. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Rambo: First Blood II'' _ `` <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> Friday Movie of the Week,'' 12.4. 28. -LRB- 48 -RRB- `` <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION>,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.9. 29. -LRB- 39 -RRB- `` Aaron's Way,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.8. 30. -LRB- 55 -RRB- `` 20-20,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.7. 30. -LRB- 24 -RRB- `` Family Ties,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.7. 32. -LRB- X -RRB- `` I Saw What You Did'' _ `` CBS Special Movie Presentation,'' 11.5. 33. -LRB- 54 -RRB- `` The Equalizer,'' CBS, 11.3. 33. -LRB- X -RRB- `` That's Incredible Reunion,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.3. 35. -LRB- 35 -RRB- `` Hooperman,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.1. 35. -LRB- X -RRB- `` 20-20 Special,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.1. 37. -LRB- 43 -RRB- `` Facts of Life,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 10.9. 38. -LRB- 55 -RRB- `` <ORGANIZATION> Cagney </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> Lacey </PERSON>,'' CBS, 10.6. 39. -LRB- 53 -RRB- `` MacGyver,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 10.5. 40. -LRB- 43 -RRB- `` Kate & amp; <PERSON> Allie </PERSON>,'' CBS, 10.2. 40. -LRB- 37 -RRB- `` Designing Women,'' CBS, 10.2. 42. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Best of TV Bloopers and Practical Jokes,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 10.1. 43. -LRB- 60 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Jake </PERSON> and The Fatman,'' CBS, 10.0. 44. -LRB- 73 -RRB- `` Spenser: For Hire,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 9.9. 45. -LRB- 69 -RRB- `` Mr. <PERSON> Belvedere </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 9.7. 45. -LRB- 29 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Newhart </PERSON>,'' CBS, 9.7. 47. -LRB- 79 -RRB- `` I Married Dora,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 9.5. 48. -LRB- 84 -RRB- `` Smothers Bros. Comedy Hour,'' CBS, 9.4. 49. -LRB- 100 -RRB- `` West 57th,'' CBS, 9.0. 49. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Swiss Family Robinson'' _ `` <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> Saturday Movie Special,'' 9.0. 51. -LRB- 70 -RRB- `` Just in Time,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 8.9. 52. -LRB- 55 -RRB- `` Beauty and the <LOCATION> Beast </LOCATION>,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 8.7. 52. -LRB- 91 -RRB- `` 48 Hours,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 8.7. 54. -LRB- 72 -RRB- `` Full House,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 8.6. 54. -LRB- 67 -RRB- `` <ORGANIZATION> Eisenhower </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> Lutz </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 8.6. 56. -LRB- 39 -RRB- `` Perfect Strangers,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 8.4. 57. -LRB- X -RRB- `` <PERSON> Garfield </PERSON>'s 10th Anniversary,'' CBS, 8.3. 58. -LRB- 61 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Beryl </PERSON> <PERSON> Markham </PERSON>: A Shadow on the Sun,'' Part 2, _ `` CBS Tuesday Movie,'' 7.8. 59. -LRB- 77 -RRB- `` Tour of Duty,'' CBS, 7.5. 59. -LRB- 75 -RRB- `` Meet the Munceys'' _ `` Disney Sunday Movie,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 7.5. 61. -LRB- 79 -RRB- `` High Mountain Rangers,'' CBS, 6.8. 62. -LRB- 98 -RRB- `` Probe,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 6.3. 62. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s Most Wanted,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 6.3. 62. -LRB- X -RRB- `` M & amp; W Magazine,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 6.3. 65. -LRB- 74 -RRB- `` Our House,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 6.1. 66. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` 21 Jump Street,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 5.6. 67. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` Married ... With Children,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 5.0. 68. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` <PERSON> Garry </PERSON> <PERSON> Shandling </PERSON> Show,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 4.2. 69. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` Family Double Dare,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 3.5. 70. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` Duet,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 3.1. 71. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` <PERSON> Tracey </PERSON> <PERSON> Ullman </PERSON> Show,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 2.8. 72. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` Boys Will Be Boys,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 2.5. 73. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` Dirty Dozen,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 2.3. 74. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` Werewolf,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 1.4.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880525-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-25-88 0214EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-AncientRoad     05-25 0424</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Ancient Road,0438</SECOND>
<HEAD>Ancient Route to China Is Busy Again</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By SCHEHEREZADE FARAMARZI</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>TASHKARGAN, China (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An ancient road traveled by the likes of <PERSON> Genghis </PERSON> <PERSON> Khan </PERSON>, <PERSON> Marco </PERSON> <PERSON> Polo </PERSON> and <PERSON> Babur </PERSON> has become an active artery of commerce today between <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>. More than 2,000 years ago, silk and spices made their way out of <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> on the route, while gold, silver and wool made their way in. The commerce today is considerably more diverse, if not as exotic. As many as 80 Pakistani merchants travel the road into <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> each day in battered buses to buy silk, porcelain and pearls, and <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> businessmen head in the opposite direction toward the <LOCATION> Khunjerab </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Pass </LOCATION> on the border as part of a barter arrangement between the two countries. The barter enables the Chinese to trade hydroelectric equipment, farm tools, textiles, quilts and porcelain for Pakistani cigarettes, medical herbs, dried fruits, shoes and razor blades. The volume of official barter has increased to the equivalent of $ 3 million in the past year, compared to $ 300,000 in 1986, according to <PERSON> Sadeq </PERSON> <PERSON> Malek </PERSON>, sales officer of <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>'s Northern Areas Traders Cooperatives. The road also is being traveled more and more by tourists. From <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>'s border post of Sost the road follows the <LOCATION> Hunza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION>, then runs along the icy <LOCATION> Khunjerab </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> into <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, crossing numerous glaciers. As it climbs to the <LOCATION> Khunjerab </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Pass </LOCATION>, it goes through a series of narrow chasms and steep declines. At <LOCATION> Tashkargan </LOCATION>, the first Chinese town across the border, workmen are building hotels and inns to accommodate the growing number of travelers passing through. <PERSON> Kamel </PERSON> <PERSON> Tahsin </PERSON>, manager of the government-run <ORGANIZATION> Pamir </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hotel </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Tashkargan </LOCATION>, said the new hotels will be more modern and better equipped. `` Business is getting better,'' he said. `` So we have to add a couple of wings to our hotel.'' <PERSON> Tahsin </PERSON> is one of about 12,000 people in <LOCATION> Tashkargan </LOCATION> who are <ORGANIZATION> Shiite </ORGANIZATION> Moslem Tajiks, the tribe dominant in the area. They are distinguishable by their sharp features and their women by their colorful costume. Across the border in <LOCATION> Sost </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Pakistanis </PERSON> also are building to meet the growing flow of tourists. <PERSON> Assif </PERSON> <PERSON> Khan </PERSON>, a Pakistani government tourist official, said big tour groups now travel to <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> four times a month compared to twice a month a year ago. But it's a tough road to travel, says <PERSON> Amanollah </PERSON> <PERSON> Mogul </PERSON>, the bus driver who makes the journey about once a day back and forth to <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>. The <LOCATION> Khunjerab </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Pass </LOCATION>, he said, makes him dizzy.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880525-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-25-88 0215EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Britain-Gardening     05-25 0730</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Britain-Gardening,0751</SECOND>
<HEAD>A Peak Week For Britain's Passionate Gardeners</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By AUDREY C. WOODS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Horticulturists from <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, garden club members from Biggleswade and window-box farmers from the inner city clutched their coveted tickets Tuesday for the <ORGANIZATION> Chelsea </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Flower </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Show </ORGANIZATION>, which has sprouted along the <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Thames </LOCATION> this week like a promise of summer. On the sun-dappled lawns beside the red-brick <ORGANIZATION> Royal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION> are displayed the very best roses, dahlias, pansies and delphiniums that this nation of gardeners can produce. So great are the crowds at <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s most prestigious annual garden extravaganza that the <ORGANIZATION> Royal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Horticultural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION> limited ticket sales for the four-day trade show to 45,000 per day _ at $ 26 each _ and may have to move to a larger site next year. Last year, 243,000 people crowded onto the 19-acre site, most of them milling under the 3 -LCB- - acre marquee that covers the choicest displays Members of the 84-year-old society, which has sponsored the <ORGANIZATION> Chelsea </ORGANIZATION> show since 1913, have their own viewing days, as does Queen <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> II </PERSON>. Membership in the society is 110,000 and growing, said assistant secretary <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON>. Most are Britons, but there are many American members and a Japanese branch has just begun. More leisure time and income have boosted the growth of gardening, <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON> said. `` But the most important thing is there are no social barriers,'' he said. `` At the show, you'll see dowagers and dustmen -LRB- garbage collectors -RRB- talking about the same thing.'' Gardening in <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> is the closest thing to a universal interest, not counting curiosity about the royal family. Five weekly TV and radio programs are devoted to gardening, and the <ORGANIZATION> British </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Broadcasting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>'s 13-part series, `` The Victorian Kitchen Garden,'' was such a hit last year that it's already being repeated. It is difficult to imagine another country where a half hour of prime time television would be devoted to the growing of tomatoes or methods of repelling slugs; where a person alarmed by clematis wilt can telephone an expert on TV and get immediate help; or where three wry horticulturists could become national celebrities through their radio question-and-answer show. Some city-dwellers nurturing pots of herbs on the windowsill or geraniums on the roof terrace dream of the gardening opportunities in the countryside. But even in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>, most people have access to a bit of grass and soil and just about all of them plant something in it. Because most of central <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>'s dwellings are rowhouses, there are thousands of narrow back gardens, neatly fenced and stretching to meet an identical row of gardens from the houses on the next street. The English rose, honeysuckle, ivy, jasmine and purple wisteria climb the fences and camouflage the garden sheds. Lilacs, plum trees, lavender and foxgloves fill the borders _ often leaving just enough grass to warrant a push mower. Even in the teeming center of the city, there often is a garden in the back and a cat lying in the sun. No upstanding neighborhood pub is without its windowbox of ivy and geraniums. The 18 garden club members on a <LOCATION> Chevron </LOCATION> <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sea </LOCATION> oil platform never have to worry about slugs and aphids, although space is limited in their 10 foot by 8 foot greenhouse bolted to the deck, 100 miles off the <LOCATION> Shetland </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Islands </LOCATION>, northeast of <LOCATION> Scotland </LOCATION>. `` You get a great feeling of satisfaction when you sit down to a fresh tomato sprinkled with chopped basil, knowing you've grown them both,'' rig electrician <PERSON> Malcolm </PERSON> <PERSON> Dobinson </PERSON> told The Daily Mail. Thousands of Londoners work allotments, patches of public land rented for a few pounds a year to families who want to grow their own food. `` We got 60 pounds of strawberries off the allotment last year,'' said <PERSON> Ena </PERSON> <PERSON> Mundy </PERSON>, who's been attending the <ORGANIZATION> Chelsea </ORGANIZATION> show for 30 years. She and her husband travel 18 miles twice a week to their allotment because the soil is `` lovely rich and loamy. Now we're retired, it's our main interest,'' she said Outer <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Barnet </ORGANIZATION> borough has 250 acres in allotments, each 10 yards by 30 yards. Most of these amateur gardeners would probably agree with writer <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Titchmarsh </PERSON> who told an interviewer: `` There's really nowhere else in the world I'd rather be than in my garden. When my time comes I'd be happy to peg out there. An epitaph? Gone to Make Manure.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880525-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-25-88 0215EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-ChristmasCard     05-25 0237</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Christmas Card,0247</SECOND>
<HEAD>Card Mailed 17 Years Ago Returned To Sender</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MACON, Ga. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 More than 17 years after <PERSON> Wilda </PERSON> <PERSON> Richardson </PERSON> mailed a Christmas card to an acquaintance, the post office returned it, unopened. But Mrs. <PERSON> Richardson </PERSON> was n't upset. `` I'm sure that whatever happened was an accident,'' she said. `` I'm sure the post office tries their best not to let this kind of thing happen.'' The card, mailed Dec. 22, 1970, showed up mysteriously last week marked `` return to sender.'' It was intended for <PERSON> Mildred </PERSON> <PERSON> Mealor </PERSON>, a fellow member of the <ORGANIZATION> Pilot </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Club </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION>, who has since died. In 1970, Mrs. <PERSON> Richardson </PERSON> was executive director of the service club for business and professional women. Each year, she mailed hundreds of homemade Christmas cards to friends and club chapters across the country. The card came back with a May 18 postmark from <LOCATION> Gainesville </LOCATION> and a May 19 postmark from <LOCATION> Macon </LOCATION>. It was not delivered postage due, even though it bore a 6-cent stamp. Mrs. <PERSON> Richardson </PERSON>, 84, said she has mailed so many Christmas cards that she had no idea this one never reached its destination. No one knows where the card spent the last 17 -LCB- years. <LOCATION> Gainesville </LOCATION> Postmaster <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Latimer </PERSON> was baffled. `` If it was found in my post office, I'm sure I would have heard about it. Given the size of our office, it's hard to imagine it lying around for 18 years,'' <PERSON> Latimer </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880525-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-25-88 0216EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--Malaysia-Drugs     05-25 0113</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Malaysia-Drugs,0116</SECOND>
<HEAD>Prisoners Smuggling Drugs In Dentures And Bandages</HEAD>
<DATELINE>KUALA LUMPUR, Malaysia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Prisoners who were released to attend court hearings or receive treatment in hospitals have returned with illegal drugs hidden in their dentures and bandages, an official was quoted as saying today. To stop the drug smuggling guards will search all inmates when they return, Prisons Director <PERSON> Zainal </PERSON> <PERSON> Abidin </PERSON> <PERSON> Noor </PERSON> told The Star newspaper. He also said double fencing had been erected around the prison in <LOCATION> Penang </LOCATION>, 180 miles northwest of <LOCATION> Kuala </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lumpur </LOCATION>, to stop people throwing drugs over the wall of the prison to the inmates. He did not say how many prisoners had been caught smuggling drugs.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880525-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-25-88 0204EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lites     05-25 0406</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lites,0421</SECOND>
<HEAD>On The Light Side</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SOUTHBORO, Mass. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Call him persistent, call him tenacious, or call him what co-workers at a computer company dubbed him after a three-year struggle to rid the plant grounds of geese: `` Mr. Goosebuster.'' <PERSON> Norm </PERSON> <PERSON> Heifetz </PERSON>, 52, facilities manager of the <ORGANIZATION> Bytex </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, has become a minor celebrity. Employees presented him with a `` Mr. Goosebuster'' plaque and goosebuster emblems can be spotted throughout the company, <PERSON> Heifetz </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Heifetz </PERSON>' picture even appeared on the front page of a local newspaper. His fame came after he waged war with the pesky geese, which filled the man-made pond at the plant and, even worse, `` strolled all over the grounds.'' `` They come and proliferate and have babies and they make a holy mess of the property,'' he said. `` They like young, fresh grass so they go grazing all day long. It would n't have been so bad if they stayed out back but they came strolling on the sidewalk near the front entrance.'' At first, he banged pots and pans to frighten the geese away. Then, while researching the problem, he learned that geese are `` deathly afraid of swans'' and bought `` a bunch of fake ones.'' Nothing worked. Last year, when the geese returned in late spring, <PERSON> Heifetz </PERSON> began a new plan of attack. He wired up huge speakers and blared distress calls over the pond. Still, the geese remained. Then <PERSON> Heifetz </PERSON> tried a small, remote-controlled boat. Success at last. `` It made a terrible noise and chased them out,'' he said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>SEATTLE (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A man's toothless technique earned him a clam-eating contest victory and possible world record as he downed 397 of the mollusks in eight minutes. <PERSON> Dave </PERSON> <PERSON> Barnes </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Sequim </LOCATION>, a roofer who has been eating the bivalves in competition for 16 years, already holds the record listed in the `` Guinness Book of World Records'' of 424 clams in eight minutes. That record, set in 1975 at <LOCATION> Port </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Townsend </LOCATION>, included a one-minute break in the contest. Tuesday's eating of steamed clams, sponsored by <ORGANIZATION> Ivar </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Acres </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Clams </ORGANIZATION> restaurant on <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION>'s waterfront, was non-stop. Contest spokesman <PERSON> Barry </PERSON> <PERSON> Bartlett </PERSON> said <PERSON> Barnes </PERSON>' performance also will be submitted to the record book. <PERSON> Barnes </PERSON> said he had an advantage over competitors: He took out his false teeth and let the clams slide down unobstructed. In second place was <PERSON> Glen </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Kent </LOCATION>, who ate 306 clams. The 12 contestants downed a total of 2,615 steamed clams.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880525-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-25-88 0216EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--Philippines-Massacre     05-25 0117</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Philippines-Massacre,0120</SECOND>
<HEAD>Wanted Presidential Guard Surrenders In Philippines</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MANILA, Philippines (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A presidential guard who killed 11 people in a <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION> suburb last weekend has surrendered, authorities said today. A spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> Presidential </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Group </ORGANIZATION> said Sgt. <PERSON> Marciano </PERSON> <PERSON> Contaoe </PERSON> surrendered on Tuesday to his commander, Col. <PERSON> Voltaire </PERSON> <PERSON> Gazmin </PERSON>. Police said <PERSON> Contaoe </PERSON> used a .45 - caliber pistol to kill three of his drinking companions on Saturday after a heated argument in the <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION> suburb of After the shooting, <PERSON> Contaoe </PERSON> went to his house and moments later emerged armed with an M-16 assault rifle. He ran to a nearby house and sprayed the occupants with gunfire, killing seven. He killed a taxi driver as he escaped.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880525-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-25-88 0216EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--China-Homework     05-25 0160</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--China-Homework,0164</SECOND>
<HEAD>Chinese Government Limits Homework, Tests</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The government took pity on primary and middle school students who complain of too much homework and testing by setting strict limits on both, an official report said today. The English-language <ORGANIZATION> China </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> said the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Education </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> banned homework for first-grade pupils and set graduated limits for older students. The limits range from 30 minutes a day for second - and third-grade students to an hour daily for sixth-grade pupils, the report said It did not say what the average length of assignments had been. The panel also said pupils `` should not be given the kind of homework that requires heavy monotonous routine work, such as large amounts of copying drills.'' Rote drilling has been the basic method of education in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> for centuries. High schools will be allowed to hold major exams only in key subjects and only at the middle and end of terms, the commission said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880525-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-25-88 0225EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--Angola-Rebels     05-25 0177</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Angola-Rebels,0180</SECOND>
<HEAD>UNITA Reports Killing 17 In Attack On Railroad Station</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LISBON, Portugal (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> UNITA </ORGANIZATION> rebels said they blew up a railroad station and three train loads of arms in the central city of <LOCATION> Huambo </LOCATION> in an attack that killed 14 Angolan and three Cuban soldiers. <ORGANIZATION> UNITA </ORGANIZATION>, the acronym for the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION> for the Total Independence of <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION>, said in statement distributed in <LOCATION> Lisbon </LOCATION> on Tuesday that a group of rebels used explosives on Saturday to destroy the station on the strategic <LOCATION> Benguela </LOCATION> railroad after a one-hour battle with security forces. The official Angolan news agency <ORGANIZATION> ANGOP </ORGANIZATION>, however, said on Saturday that government troops foiled the raid, killing four rebels and wounding several. <ORGANIZATION> ANGOP </ORGANIZATION> said in a report monitored in <LOCATION> Lisbon </LOCATION> that <LOCATION> Huambo </LOCATION> station and other buildings were damaged in the shooting. It said four pounds of explosives were captured from the rebels. It did not mention government casualties. <ORGANIZATION> UNITA </ORGANIZATION>, supported by the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>, has been fighting since 1975 to force the <LOCATION> Cuban </LOCATION> - and Soviet-backed government to share power
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880525-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-25-88 0021EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p AM-PoliticalRdp 1stLd-Writethru a0716 05-25 0786</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Political Rdp, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0716,700</SECOND>
<HEAD>Dukakis Criticizes Trade Bill Veto; Bush Aides Reassure House GOP
Leaders</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDs: SUBS grafs 7-8 pvs with 3 grafs to UPDATE with Idaho results</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By DAVID ESPO</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Political Writer</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democratic front-runner <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> said Tuesday it was `` a very serious mistake'' for President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> to veto trade legislation that requires advance notice of plant closing. <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s aides sought to reassure <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Republicans about the vice president's poor standing in recent polls. `` We have bad polls,'' Rep. <PERSON> Lynn </PERSON> <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> said after attending a closed-door session with <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s top advisers. `` If this were October we'd be suicidal. But it's May.'' <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' sole remaining Democratic rival, campaigned in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> in advance of the state's June 7 primary. He said he would seek government assistance for a farm town where a dozen children have been diagnosed with cancer in recent years. <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> spent most of the day in <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>, where he issued a statement blasting <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> on the trade bill and linking the veto to negotiations with <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>, who faces indictment on drug charges. `` Any administration that is willing to give Gen. <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> 120 days notice and a plea bargain ought to be willing to give the American worker 60 days notice before they are thrown out on the street,'' he said in a statement. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> declared his independence from <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> on the <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> talks last week, saying he opposed negotiations designed to force the <LOCATION> Panamanian </LOCATION> leader to give up his power in exchange for having the drug indictments dropped. The vice president had no official appearances during the day, although he added <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION> to his list of primary state victories. With a quarter of the precincts reporting, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> had 81 percent to 10 percent for <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON>, who suspended his <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> candidacy earlier this month. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was winning 15 delegates in <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION>, to two for <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON>, and one uncommitted. The vice president wrapped up a majority of <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Convention </ORGANIZATION> delegates a month ago. The Democratic primary in <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION> was a non-binding preference poll and no delegates were at stake. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> won easily, with 77 percent to <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s 14 percent, with 24 percent of the precincts reporting. The next _ and last _ Democratic primary elections will be June 7, with contests in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION>. Although neither <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> nor <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> was out campaigning during the day, each took steps to rally the troops around their certain candidacies. The vice president's campaign officials announced that Sen. <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Grassley </PERSON> and Gov. <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> <PERSON> Branstad </PERSON> would play important roles in the fall campaign in <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Grassley </PERSON> was a staunch supporter of Sen. <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> in the state's heated caucus campaign _ which <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> lost in a third place finish _ while <PERSON> Branstad </PERSON> was neutral. On the Democratic side, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> arranged a visit to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> on Wednesday en route to campaigning in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>. His aides said he would meet with several groups of <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> members and senators, and expected to pick up endorsements from roughly a dozen lawmakers as he closes in on a nominating majority of Democratic National Convention delegates. Three top <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> advisers met with <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Republicans, and one of them, pollster <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Teeter </PERSON>, said polls indicate the vice president is running behind but the race is in a `` very artificial period.'' He said he told the lawmakers that, `` What you got to do is get past this <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> primary before people begin to focus on it -LRB- the presidential race -RRB-.'' Several lawmakers said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s decision to disagree with <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s policy of negotiations with <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> drew praise `` It's a very symbolic circumstance, where <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has moved from being vice president to being his own candidate,'' said Rep. <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Leach </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>. Ms. <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> added, `` Almost to a person, they were pleased about the separation on <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>.;'' But she also said there was concern about recent polls indicating <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> leads the vice president. `` There was n't anybody up screaming, ` My God, we've got the Titanic,''' she said. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' linkage of the trade bill veto with the <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> negotiations marked an attempt to hit <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> on two issues that <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> strategists believe damage the vice president. `` To veto this bill because it will give working people and their families 60 days notice before they're laid off, seems to me to be unconscionable,'' he said. He said <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> `` do n't understand that for working families who struggle to pay the mortgage, save for their children's education and care for their elders, there is nothing more painful than losing a job.'' `` I think the president is making a very serious mistake. This is a good trade bill. It's a responsible bill,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880525-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-25-88 0121EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Deaths 1stLd-Writethru a0815 05-25 0228</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Deaths, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0815,0232</SECOND>
<NOTE>Eds: Adds Vartan. No separates moved for the AMs cycle.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>William Bougher</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SUNNYVALE, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bougher </PERSON>, a retired electronics engineer who helped develop radar in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> before the nation entered World War II, died Friday of cancer. He was 69. <PERSON> Bougher </PERSON> adapted the British system of providing early warning against approaching enemy aircraft to <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s defense network when he started working for the <ORGANIZATION> Bendix </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Baltimore </LOCATION> in 1940. After the war he joined <ORGANIZATION> Philco </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION> as a technical representative at military installations and last worked for the company at the <ORGANIZATION> Mare </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Island </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Naval </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Shipyard </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Vallejo </LOCATION> in 1948.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>Vartanig Vartan</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Vartanig </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Vartan </PERSON>, a financial writer for <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> and the author of two novels, died Tuesday of cancer at age 64. <PERSON> Vartan </PERSON> worked for <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> from 1952 to 1955 in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> and was a financial writer with <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Herald </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tribune </ORGANIZATION> from 1955 to 1962. He also worked as a Wall Street columnist for The Christian Science Monitor from 1957 to 1962. <PERSON> Vartan </PERSON> joined the <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> in 1963 as a financial writer. He was the main writer of the `` Market Place'' column in the newspaper since 1983. <PERSON> Vartan </PERSON> wrote two novels, `` 50 Wall Street'' and `` The Dinosaur Fund.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880525-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-25-88 0212EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a BC-Dance     05-25 0274</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Dance,0285</SECOND>
<HEAD>Sydney Dance Company Opens in NY</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: No PMs Planned</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By MARY CAMPBELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 It is n't easy to hold an audience's attention with a full-length ballet which has no plot, and few choreographers try. <PERSON> Graeme </PERSON> <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON> has tried and succeeded with `` Shining.'' The Sydney Dance Company from <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION> danced the two-hour `` Shining'' Tuesday night as the opening program of a two-week season at the City Center. <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON> choreographed it in 1986 to mark 10 years as the company's artistic director. The first section, titled `` Dawn,'' had duets, trios, quartets and groups of 14. While the enormously vital and versatile dancers were on stage, <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON> allowed them no rest. They were swinging around, jumping, lifting or being lifted, swooping down for floor work, being dragged or dragging somebody along the floor. The music by <PERSON> Karol </PERSON> <PERSON> Szymanowski </PERSON> sounded like dramatic movie music, with something important about to happen every minute. When the tempo was especially fast, it was usually <PERSON> Nina </PERSON> <PERSON> Veretennikova </PERSON> who danced. <PERSON> Alfred </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> had a mesmerizing solo in the first section. He and <PERSON> Andrea </PERSON> <PERSON> Toy </PERSON> danced the second section, `` Pre-Dawn,'' which <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON> created in 1985 as a duet named `` Shimmering.'' The final section, `` Night,'' has duets, quartets and groups again and is almost entirely danced in couples. `` Shining'' was never predictable. The company gave the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> premiere of `` Shining'' May 16 at <LOCATION> Stanford </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>. After June 8 and 9 performances in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Antonio </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, the company will perform for two months in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> `` After <LOCATION> Venice </LOCATION>,'' which will be danced this season, had its American premiere when the company was last in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, in 1985.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880525-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-25-88 0025EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-ContraProposal 2ndLd-Writethru a0792 05-25 0933</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Contra Proposal, 2nd Ld-Writethru, a0792,860</SECOND>
<HEAD>Contras Peace Plan Includes Provision for Delivering U.S. Aid</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDs: SUBS 7th graf pvs bgng, `The proposal,' with 3 grafs to
UPDATE with Wright comments; INSERTS 3 grafs after 12th graf pvs
bgng, `An extension,' to UPDATE with report that US and Honduran
officials say Nicaragua seems to be preparing to attack Contras if
peace talks fail</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By JIM DRINKARD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>'s Contra rebels will offer to lay down their arms on Sept. 1 as part of a comprehensive peace accord to be presented to the Nicaraguan government Wednesday, a congressional aide said Tuesday. Members of the rebels' political directorate, in meetings on <LOCATION> Capitol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION> and at the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, also said they would not be the first to break a two-month cease-fire after it expires May 30, even if no new truce agreement is in effect. And they said they would accept a proposal for delivery of humanitarian aid to their forces inside <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> by an agency with ties to the Organization of <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. But they made it clear that did not mean they were accepting the Sandinista government's unilateral announcement, made a day earlier, that it simply would extend the current truce for another month. Rather, the Contra proposal will include `` all the necessary things for a permanent end to the war in <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>,'' said <PERSON> Alfredo </PERSON> <PERSON> Cesar </PERSON>, a member of the directorate and the leader of the negotiating delegation. An aide to House Speaker <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Texas </LOCATION>, who was briefed on the <ORGANIZATION> Contra </ORGANIZATION> proposal, said <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> hoped the move was sincere and constructive. The aide, <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> <PERSON> Morris </PERSON>, said the setting of a date for the rebels to lay down their arms, in particular, `` appears to be progress.'' In an interview Tuesday night, <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> said, `` Tomorrow I hope and believe that a major effort will be made to open up the peace plan and to reach a settlement between the two sides in <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> ...'' `` Broad suggestions -LRB- are -RRB- going to be made by the resistance, the Contras, that they will accept a certain time to lay down their arms and reintegrate into the society if the government will make certain guarantees of free elections at certain specific dates and guarantee of private properties and the restoration of those civil liberties,'' <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> said on <ORGANIZATION> Cable </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Network </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Larry King Live'' program. <PERSON> Cesar </PERSON> said the proposal will go beyond the cease-fire agreement reached two months ago in <LOCATION> Sapoa </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>, and include a timetable for specific political changes called for in last year's regional peace agreement. Those changes include a free and fair electoral system, an independent judiciary with the power to guarantee human rights, removal of the military from <LOCATION> Sandinista </LOCATION> party control and guaranteed property rights, he said. <PERSON> Cesar </PERSON> also said the rebels were prepared to accept a proposal to have $ 17.7 million in <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> humanitarian aid delivered through the <ORGANIZATION> Pan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION>, which would subcontract with commercial carriers to distribute supplies to troops inside cease-fire zones in <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>. The foundation is tied to the <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> States </ORGANIZATION>, whose secretary general, <PERSON> Joao </PERSON> <PERSON> Baena </PERSON> <PERSON> Soares </PERSON>, is on a commission to verify compliance with the cease-fire agreement. <PERSON> Cesar </PERSON> said the <ORGANIZATION> Sandinistas </ORGANIZATION> have failed to comply with commitments made in <LOCATION> Sapoa </LOCATION>, and that a simple extension of the current truce would not address those failures. `` An extension of the truce period means an extension for the <ORGANIZATION> Sandinistas </ORGANIZATION> to keep violating <LOCATION> Sapoa </LOCATION>, to keep imprisoning union leaders ... to keep interfering with freedom of the press,'' said <PERSON> Adolfo </PERSON> <PERSON> Calero </PERSON>, another directorate member. Meanwhile, <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Honduran </LOCATION> officials say <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> appears to be building up stocks of weapons and making other preparations for an attack on the Contras if the peace talks fail, according to a published report. The officials cite aerial reconnaissance photographs and other evidence they say suggest a military buildup, <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> reported in its Wednesday editions. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials said the photographs showed that airfields at <LOCATION> Wapsam </LOCATION> near the Honduran border and at <LOCATION> La </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Tranquera </LOCATION> in southern <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> have been upgraded; that new military storage depots are being built near <LOCATION> Sebaco </LOCATION>, about 50 miles north of <LOCATION> Managua </LOCATION>, and that military supplies are being stockpiled at <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Tempisque </LOCATION> just outside <LOCATION> Managua </LOCATION>. President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, meanwhile, accused the Sandinistas of foot-dragging, saying the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> was looking for `` deeds, not more words.'' `` If the current stalemate in the peace process persists and the <ORGANIZATION> Sandinistas </ORGANIZATION> continue their policies of repression, then we will call upon the <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to reconsider its Feb. 3 decision to curtail assistance to the Nicaraguan freedom fighters,'' <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said in a statement issued by the White House. The president said that despite the 60-day truce, `` the <ORGANIZATION> Sandinistas </ORGANIZATION> have continued, and indeed intensified their repression of the <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> people.'' Since the Sapoa accord was reached, the Contra ranks have been torn by internal bickering and power struggles. <PERSON> Cesar </PERSON> acknowledged that the rebels now are weaker militarily than they were in March, `` but not politically.'' He said the rebels' primary leverage in the new round of talks will be the threat that if the <ORGANIZATION> Sandinistas </ORGANIZATION> appear intransigent, <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> could be moved to grant new military aid to the Contras and renew the war. <PERSON> Cesar </PERSON> noted that the Sandinista attitude softened following a May 12 letter from 24 members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> who warned that military aid could be resumed if the leftist government did not facilitate delivery of aid to rebel troops inside the country. All five members of the directorate of the Nicaraguan Resistance _ <PERSON> Cesar </PERSON>, <PERSON> Calero </PERSON>, <PERSON> Pedro </PERSON> <PERSON> Joaquin </PERSON> <PERSON> Chamorro </PERSON>, <PERSON> Maria </PERSON> <PERSON> Azucena </PERSON> <PERSON> Ferrey </PERSON> and <PERSON> Aristides </PERSON> <PERSON> Sanchez </PERSON> _ will go to the talks.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880525-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-25-88 0253EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--Iran-Gangs     05-25 0165</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Iran-Gangs,0168</SECOND>
<HEAD>Arms And Drugs Smugglers Arrested In Iran</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NICOSIA, Cyprus (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Iranian security forces smashed several gangs smuggling arms and narcotics, <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> said. The official <ORGANIZATION> Islamic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> said on Tuesday that 30 `` armed highway bandits'' were arrested in <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Tabriz </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Khorramabad </LOCATION> for smuggling drugs and selling weapons to `` counterrevolutionaries.'' The report, monitored in <LOCATION> Nicosia </LOCATION>, said 12 members of an underground group were arrested in <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Tabriz </LOCATION> and other cities for selling arms to dissident groups and procuring forged passports and visas for Iranians, including draft dodgers, seeking to flee the country. Thirty members of a group of `` well-educated professionals'' were rounded up in <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Tabriz </LOCATION> and other towns for coating metals with a thin layer of gold and selling them as pure gold, the agency said. In East Azarbaijan Province, customs men seized 146 precious silk carpets that were to be smuggled abroad, the agency added. The security operations were carried out over the last few days, <ORGANIZATION> IRNA </ORGANIZATION> reported.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880525-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-25-88 0350EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--Britain-Queen     05-25 0144</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Britain-Queen,0148</SECOND>
<HEAD>Queen Elizabeth Attends 250th Anniversary Celebration Of Methodism</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Queen <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> II </PERSON> joined 2,500 people in a service at <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Paul </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cathedral </ORGANIZATION> celebrating the 250th anniversary of the religious movement that grew into the <ORGANIZATION> Methodist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION>. The interdenominational service on Tuesday, which was attended by represenatives of 50 nations, commemorated <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Wesley </PERSON>'s conversion at a Christian meeting in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> on May 24, 1738 The fiery preacher traveled by horseback through the English countryside spreading the gospel with his hymn-writing brother, <PERSON> Charles </PERSON>. Their followers separated from the state Church of <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> and established Methodism after <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Wesley </PERSON>'s death in 1791. Queen <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> is the titular head of the Church of <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>, and her presence at the service was seen as a gesture acknowledging the contribution of the <ORGANIZATION> Methodist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> to British life. She was accompanied by her husband, Prince <PERSON> Philip </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880525-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-25-88 0217EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-DukakisPay     05-25 0207</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Dukakis Pay,0212</SECOND>
<HEAD>House Lets Traveling Governor Keep All His Salary</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BOSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Gov. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> has survived a Republican attempt to scale back his pay to reflect the days he spends in his Statehouse office and not on the presidential campaign trail. Late Tuesday, after nearly 10 hours of debate over next year's state budget, Republican Rep. <PERSON> Kevin </PERSON> <PERSON> Poirier </PERSON> offered an amendment to the $ 1,888,828 intended to pay the governor and his staff Under the language offered by <PERSON> Poirier </PERSON>, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> would get paid only for days he is in the state. Since the start of this year, <PERSON> Poirier </PERSON> noted, the governor has spent 68 days out of state, 18 days in state and 51 days in which he spent part of the day here and part elsewhere. `` So therefore, for the 68 days he was out of the state, based on his salary of $ 85,000, he owes us $ 15,835,'' the assistant minority leader said. `` With this amendment, what I'm trying to do is bring some fiscal sanity back into the commonwealth. We do have a fiscal crisis. Let's try to address it in his office,'' he said. No Democrat rose to defend the governor, but the amendment was defeated on a voice vote.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880525-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-25-88 0221EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Dukakis-Crime     05-25 0388</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Dukakis-Crime,0402</SECOND>
<HEAD>Dukakis Calls For Tougher State Laws On Child Porn, DUI And
Sentencing</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CHRISTOPHER B. DALY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BOSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Gov. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> has asked <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> lawmakers to approve a crime package designed to tighten state laws on child pornography, drunken driving and criminal sentencing. `` Over the past five years, we have done a lot to fight crime and make our citizens safer here in <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION>,'' the Democratic presidential hopeful said Tuesday in testimony to the <ORGANIZATION> Legislature </ORGANIZATION>'s joint <ORGANIZATION> Criminal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> `` That's because we've worked together on a get-tough, no-nonsense approach to crime that's based on results, not rhetoric.'' But <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> said recent drug-related violence in <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> was `` a grim reminder'' of the expanding agenda of crime issues. `` When we find loopholes in our laws that allow criminals to avoid punishment, or when we find programs that could be strengthened to protect innocent children, then we need to work together and take action,'' he said. He appealed for swift action on: _ The latest version of his `` presumptive sentencing'' bill, which <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> has offered annually in his second and third terms The legislation would establish sentencing guidelines for crimes and allow prosecutors to appeal sentences they consider too low. _ A bill to restore the state law against child pornography, which was struck down earlier this year by the state <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> on the grounds that it was unconstitutionally broad On Monday, the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> agreed to review the state court's action, but <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> argued that the state needs a law on the books immediately, in order to prevent `` the devastating and lifelong psychological and physical damage'' caused by sexual exploitation. _ Legislation to increase penalties against drivers who leave the scene of an accident The governor's brother was killed by a hit-and-run driver. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' legislative package also would allow <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> police to cross state lines `` in hot pursuit'' of drunken drivers and increase the penalties for refusing to submit to a breath test. For the first time, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> also supported a measure allowing judges to revoke the driving license of anyone convicted of a drug offense. In his testimony, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> credited the <ORGANIZATION> Legislature </ORGANIZATION> and his own administration for making <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> safer. He said overall crime is down more than 13 percent in the last four years, the second-largest such decline of any state.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880525-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-25-88 0212EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     05-25 0864</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0899</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in The News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Q: Where are you if you see a bowl of M & amp; Ms and find that someone has removed all the brown ones? A: Chances are, you're backstage at a concert by <PERSON> Van </PERSON> <PERSON> Halen </PERSON>; members of the rock band specifically demand that all brown M & amp; Ms be deleted. That's according to <PERSON> Leonard </PERSON> `` Cy'' <PERSON> Kocis </PERSON>, 41, the <LOCATION> Mahwah </LOCATION>, N.J.-based caterer who services rockers and other entertainers on the road. Sometimes, he said recently, his clients make peculiar demands. For example: The rock group Rush wants <ORGANIZATION> Coca-Cola </ORGANIZATION>, but only in the old-fashioned glass bottles. U2 wants shepherd's pie and <PERSON> Dom </PERSON> <PERSON> Perignon </PERSON> champagne. <PERSON> Tiffany </PERSON> has a hankering for Evian water and `` a variety of kosher meats.'' <LOCATION> Bon </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jovi </LOCATION> requires Jolt cola, the caffeine-laden drink. <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Sinatra </PERSON>, by contrast, wanted only <ORGANIZATION> Campbell </ORGANIZATION>'s chicken and rice soup _ in a can.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Eddie </PERSON> <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON> has a lot of devoted fans, but the comedian really got his boat rocked during an outing in the <LOCATION> Bahamas </LOCATION>, where he's working on his second music album. <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON>, 27, was taking a break and boating with friends when `` a boat operated by overzealous fans collided with Mr. <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON>'s boat, slightly injuring him and his three companions,'' his publicist, <PERSON> Terrie </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>, said Tuesday. All four were treated at a hospital in <LOCATION> Nassau </LOCATION> and released, said <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>. <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON> is expected back in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> later this week.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Two musicians who knew <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> during his boyhood in <LOCATION> Gary </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ind. </LOCATION>, claim in a $ 400 million federal lawsuit that <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> and <PERSON> Lionel </PERSON> <PERSON> Richie </PERSON> pirated such songs as `` Thriller'' and `` We Are The World.'' <PERSON> Reynaud </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> and <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, both of <PERSON> Gary </PERSON>, and a third man, <PERSON> Clifford </PERSON> <PERSON> Rubin </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>, are seeking the money from the two singer-songwriters, producer <PERSON> Quincy </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>, and others. `` We deny the allegations vehemently in both suits. Both are frivolous,'' <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s attorney, <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Rotstein </PERSON>, said Tuesday. `` There are numerous such suits -LRB- against pop stars -RRB-,'' said <PERSON> Rotstein </PERSON>, who specializes in copyright cases. `` This happens all the time. ... People are trying to trade in on the success of a talented person.'' <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>, <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> and <PERSON> Rubin </PERSON> claim their music can be heard on <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s hit `` Thriller''' and `` We Are the World,'' the Jackson-Richie anthem that raised money for starvation victims in <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>. The defendants also say `` The Girl Is Mine'' and `` Another Part of Me,'' from <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s latest album `` Bad,'' contain lyrics from songs they wrote. The lawsuit was filed in November. <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> and <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> claim they grew up with the <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> family in <PERSON> Gary </PERSON>, and <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> claims to have helped the brothers launch their career as the `` Jackson 5.'' <PERSON> Rotstein </PERSON> said <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> may have known <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> and <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> during his boyhood, but `` I do n't think they had a close relationship with <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>. They may have known a couple of the other brothers,'' <PERSON> Rotstein </PERSON> said. The lawsuit is the second one pending against <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> federal court that claims the pop superstar pirated `` We Are The World.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LIVERPOOL, England (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Prince <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> helped dedicate a new gallery of modern art that will give a boost to this ailing industrial city once best known as the birthplace of the Beatles. <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> on Tuesday reopened a renovated complex of Victorian warehouses in a development he hailed as of `` immense importance.'' One of the the buildings contains an extension of <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>'s Tate Gallery. `` This project will help enormously to restore the confidence of people in areas which once knew great success and prosperity and which will, I know, in due course return to that prosperity,'' the prince said. The Tate Gallery is the national museum of <LOCATION> British </LOCATION> art and international modern art. In <LOCATION> Liverpool </LOCATION>, it will show paintings and sculpture that it does n't always have space for in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>. `` As <LOCATION> Liverpool </LOCATION> was already rich in museums and galleries, the Tate extension makes it the second art city in <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> after <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>,'' said the museum's curator, <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Francis </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>BERLIN (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s Princess <PERSON> Anne </PERSON> was in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> for a British military parade today celebrating the 62nd birthday of her mother, Queen <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> II </PERSON>. Princess <PERSON> Anne </PERSON>, who is representing her mother, was greeted after her arrival Tuesday by <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> Mayor <PERSON> Eberhard </PERSON> <PERSON> Diepgen </PERSON>. Officials say the procession includes 730 soldiers from the British garrison in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> turned 62 on April 21.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>SANTA MONICA, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Former `` Dynasty'' star <PERSON> Geoffrey </PERSON> <PERSON> Scott </PERSON>, hospitalized for two weeks after his legs were crushed between two cars, is recovering at home and expects to be walking soon. <PERSON> Scott </PERSON>, who played <PERSON> Krystal </PERSON>'s tennis-pro ex-husband and <PERSON> Alexis </PERSON>' former lover from 1982 to 1984 on `` Dynasty,'' was on a bicycle when he was struck by a car, his agent said Tuesday The actor had stopped between two cars when one of the vehicles lurched forward and pinned him between the bumper of another auto, said agent <PERSON> Erin </PERSON> <PERSON> Connor </PERSON>. `` He's at home and he's doing fine,'' she said. `` He expects to fully recover.'' The 41-year-old actor, who also starred in the movie `` The Morning After'' with <PERSON> Jane </PERSON> <PERSON> Fonda </PERSON>, was released from <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> John </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION> last week, Ms. <PERSON> Connor </PERSON> said
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880525-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-25-88 0127EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Reagan-Trade Bjt   05-25 0830</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Reagan-Trade, Bjt,800</SECOND>
<HEAD>Trade Bill Backers Expect Uphill Fight in Senate</HEAD>
<NOTE>With LaserPhoto WX9</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By MIKE ROBINSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> backers of a major trade bill are expecting an uphill battle to find enough votes to override President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s veto, in striking contrast to the quick and overwhelming <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> vote to reverse the president's action. `` We have to have another three votes at this point and I do n't know where they are going to come from,'' said <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Finance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Texas </LOCATION>, a chief sponsor of the 1,000-page trade measure The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> is expected to take up the legislation after it returns from the Memorial Day recess. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s veto of the legislation on Tuesday came as no surprise. He has been critical in numerous speeches of a provision that would require companies to give employees 60 days notice of plant closings and large-scale layoffs. He has said that businesses need flexibility to survive hard times. In his veto message to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> repeated that argument. `` I support voluntarily giving workers and communities as much advance warning as possible when a layoff or closing becomes necessary. ... It is the humane thing to do. `` But I object to the idea that the federal government would arbitrarily mandate, for all conditions and under all circumstances, exactly when and in what form that notification should take place.'' The president urged lawmakers to submit a revised version trade bill that he could sign in good conscience. Within hours of <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s veto, the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> voted, 308-113, to override it. That was far more than needed to be successful. Sixty Republicans broke with <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> to vote for the override, while only one Democrat, <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Mrazek </PERSON> of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, supported the president. The plant-closings measure is among scores of provisions contained in the bill. The main ones would overhaul the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> system of import restrictions. Others range from repealing the windfall profits tax to adding billions of dollars in agricultural subsidies. Democratic leaders have argued that patching together a stripped down trade bill might be tough before <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> leaves town for the campaign trail. Uncertain of override prospects in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>, many Democrats focused on making the debate a campaign issue. `` I happen to think it's a better issue for Democrats than for Republicans,'' House Speaker <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Texas </LOCATION>, said. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, the front-runner in the battle for the Democratic presidential nomination, called the president's action `` unconscionable.'' He said that <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and Vice President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> `` do n't understand that for working families who struggle to pay the mortgage, save for their children's education and care for their elders, there is nothing more painful than losing a job. He contrasted the veto to a tentative deal under which drug charges against <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>, the <LOCATION> Panamanian </LOCATION> leader, would be dropped if he agreed to relinquish power and leave <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> by August. `` Any administration that is willing to give General <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> 120 days notice and a plea bargain ought to be willing to give the American worker 60 days notice before they are thrown out on the street,'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said that he vetoed the measure `` with sincere regret,'' but said in his message that returning the measure to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> was necessary. `` I am convinced this bill will cost jobs and damage our economic growth,'' the president said. He said that the American economy has created 16 million jobs during his administration and that the unemployment rate is at its lowest point in 14 years. He also said that the measure would `` push us in the direction of protectionism. Closing our borders is not the solution to opening foreign markets,'' <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said. Administration supporters rallied to <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s support following the veto. Rep. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Frenzel </PERSON>, R-Minn., scoffed at the image of `` unfeeling and mean-spirited owners of large and small American businesses putting upon weak and defenseless workers who are about to be thrown out on the street ... unless big government puts its firm and fatherly hand'' on the situation `` As usual, this House believes that big government knows more than we in private life,'' <PERSON> Frenzel </PERSON> said. `` This debate paints a depressing view of <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> and it is inaccurate.'' But the veto also unleashed a torrent of criticism on the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> floor. `` The Japanese are laughing now that you have vetoed this trade bill,'' said Rep. <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Schumer </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.Y. </LOCATION> `` For seven years, the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration has just said no to <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> workers,'' Rep. <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Markey </PERSON>, D-Mass., said Sen. <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, D-Mass., issued a statement saying that `` the country understands the importance of notice about plant closings and layoffs, even if the White House does not. `` Voluntary notice is a fig leaf over the problem,'' <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> said. Sen. <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Murkowski </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Alaska </LOCATION>, however, recalled in a statement that restrictions on exports of oil from his state remain in the legislation. `` I voted against the trade bill when it passed the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> and intend to vote to sustain the president's veto,'' <PERSON> Murkowski </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880525-0025 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-25-88 0402EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Iran-Contra     05-25 0653</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Iran-Contra,630</SECOND>
<HEAD>Iran-Contra Lawyers Fight Efforts to Use Congressional Testimony</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JAMES ROWLEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Defense lawyers are accusing independent counsel <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Walsh </PERSON> of trying to punish former White House aide <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> North </PERSON> and two co-defendants for trying to tell <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> the `` whole truth'' about the Iran-Contra affair. The defense contends that <PERSON> Walsh </PERSON> was `` completely wrong on the law'' by claiming that hundreds of statements that <PERSON> North </PERSON>, former national security adviser <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Poindexter </PERSON> and arms dealer <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Hakim </PERSON> made to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> could be used against them as evidence of criminal wrongdoing. By claiming the defendants waived their limited immunity grants from <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Walsh </PERSON> `` seeks to punish defendants for responding fully and in good faith to congressional inquiries, when compelled to do so over vehement objection, and for relaying to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and the nation what occurred and why,'' the defense said in a brief filed Tuesday. Although North, <PERSON> Poindexter </PERSON> and <PERSON> Hakim </PERSON> testified under immunity grants that prohibit use of their statements as evidence against them, <PERSON> Walsh </PERSON> contends that the defendants waived the privilege against self-incrimination by volunteering answers that were not responsive to questions posed by the Iran-Contra committees. <PERSON> Walsh </PERSON> has said that he would not use any of this congressional testimony during the trial if the court denies a defense request to conduct an extensive hearing to determine if his investigation was tainted by impermissible use of the defendants' immunized statements. The defense called <PERSON> Walsh </PERSON>'s offer an attempt `` to threaten the court with a lengthy inquiry into immunized testimony, and then to use that threat as leverage to strike a favorable bargain with the court.'' `` This tactic is unseemly,'' the defense lawyers said in a joint pleading. North, the fired <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> aide, <PERSON> Poindexter </PERSON> and <PERSON> Hakim </PERSON> are accused of conspiring with retired <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> Maj. Gen. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> V. </PERSON> <PERSON> Secord </PERSON> to defraud the government by diverting <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> arms-sale profits to the Nicaraguan rebels. <PERSON> Secord </PERSON>, also an arms dealer, testified without an immunity grant from <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. North, <PERSON> Poindexter </PERSON> and <PERSON> Hakim </PERSON> contend that their Fifth Amendment right against self-incrimination would be violated if they were forced to stand trial on criminal charges following their compelled congressional testimony. They claim that <PERSON> Walsh </PERSON>'s prosecution was tainted by illegal use of their sworn statements to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> Gerhard </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gesell </PERSON> is scheduled to hear arguments on the issue on Thursday. In its latest filing, the defense said `` there is no claim that defendants uttered a single word, during the course of their congressional testimony, that was outside the subject matter of the congressional inquiry.'' North, <PERSON> Poindexter </PERSON> and <PERSON> Hakim </PERSON> were not waiving any rights when they `` explained their answers; or sought to provide useful, related information to be sure their answers were complete and accurate _ in short, the ` whole truth' they had sworn to provide.'' The defense said <PERSON> Walsh </PERSON>'s position would force <PERSON> Gesell </PERSON> to examine each and every one of the hundreds of statements to verify <PERSON> Walsh </PERSON>'s claim they were exempt from immunity <PERSON> Walsh </PERSON> contended that the unprotected statements include <PERSON> Poindexter </PERSON>'s admission that he approved the diversion of arms-sale profits to the Contras but did not tell President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> to ensure that the president could deny involvement if the operation were exposed. The unprotected statements also include <PERSON> Poindexter </PERSON>'s remarks that during Attorney General <PERSON> Edwin </PERSON> <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>'s November 1986 investigation, <PERSON> Poindexter </PERSON> destroyed a presidential intelligence finding authorizing <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> involvement in one 1985 arms shipment, <PERSON> Walsh </PERSON> contended. <PERSON> Walsh </PERSON> also claimed that <PERSON> North </PERSON>'s statements that he destroyed documents in October and November 1986 could be used as evidence to prove charges that the fired <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> aide obstructed <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>'s inquiry. In a separate filing on Tuesday, <PERSON> Walsh </PERSON>'s office said that `` it is clear beyond doubt'' that <PERSON> North </PERSON>, <PERSON> Poindexter </PERSON> and <PERSON> Hakim </PERSON> waged a `` public relations battle'' during their congressional testimony. `` In utter defiance of the questions put to them, they sought to win with speeches and arguments,'' the prosecution brief said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880525-0026 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-25-88 0052EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-TruckExplodes 1stLd-Writethru a0847 05-25 0376</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Truck Explodes, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0847,0380</SECOND>
<HEAD>Propane Tanker Burns on Long Island</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: CORRECTS in 1st graf that tanker burst into flames sted
exploded, UPDATES throughout with more homes evacuated, driver
arrested, amount of propane, other details. No pickup.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>SEAFORD, N.Y. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A propane tanker truck overturned, burst into flames and burned intensely through the day Tuesday, forcing police to close two highways, shut a section of the <LOCATION> Long </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rail </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Road </LOCATION> and evacuate 2,000 homes. There were no serious injuries, officials said. The driver and a trainee who was riding with him escaped before the explosion. The driver was treated at the scene for a shoulder cut. The fire was so intense and potentially explosive that firefighters had to move back from the fire early in the afternoon, leaving automatic pumpers to throw water on the blaze. Nearly 1,000 homes within half a mile of the burning truck were evacuated, with residents taken to a church, <LOCATION> Nassau </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> police spokeswoman Officer <PERSON> Donna </PERSON> <PERSON> Fairweather </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Hank </PERSON> <PERSON> McCann </PERSON>, a department public information officer, said more homes were evacuated at 10:30 p.m. bringing the total to about 2,000. `` -LRB- Police -RRB- cars went through the area with loudspeakers urging people to evacuate,'' he said. Two unmanned automatic fire trucks were pumping water onto the fire late Tuesday night, hours after the 9:30 a.m. accident. Authorities said the tanker, carrying about 2,500 gallons of propane, could burn for as long as 30 hours. Sections of the Seaford-Oyster Bay Expressway, where the accident occurred, and the Sunrise Highway, near the expressway, were closed, <PERSON> Fairweather </PERSON> said. The <LOCATION> Long </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rail </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Road </LOCATION> twice suspended service on its busiest branch, between <LOCATION> Wantagh </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Amityville </LOCATION>, said railroad spokesman <PERSON> Brian </PERSON> <PERSON> Dolan </PERSON>. He estimated that 70,000 train commuters were affected. <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> police Lt. <PERSON> Willard </PERSON> <PERSON> Krausch </PERSON> said the truck overturned on the southbound lane of the expressway when the driver experienced a problem with the truck's rear wheels. The driver, identified by police as <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> Vai </PERSON>, 35, of <LOCATION> Westbury </LOCATION>, was arrested at the scene on an outstanding traffic warrant and was also charged with driving with a suspended license and failure to produce a license. He was taken later released on $ 100 bail. <PERSON> Krausch </PERSON> said the truck was owned by Conservative Gas of <LOCATION> Hyde </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Park </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880525-0027 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-25-88 0249EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Bush-Trade Bjt   05-25 0628</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bush-Trade, Bjt,630</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHINGTON WIRE: Democrats Instantly Make Campaign Issue Of Veto</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP News Analysis</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DONALD M. ROTHBERG</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Political Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
