<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880701-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-01-88 2349EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Colombia-Kidnap     07-01 0185</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Colombia-Kidnap,0191</SECOND>
<HEAD>Leftist Guerrillas Kidnap U.S. Oil Executive</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BOGOTA, Colombia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Police said Friday they were still searching for the manager of a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> oil company who was kidnapped by leftist guerrillas this week for a $ 2 million ransom. <PERSON> Giacomo </PERSON> -LRB- <PERSON> Jake </PERSON> -RRB- <PERSON> Gambini </PERSON>, 42, an Italian-born <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> citizen, was abducted by leftist guerrillas Monday as he left his office in <LOCATION> Sabana </LOCATION> <LOCATION> de </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Torres </LOCATION>, 200 miles north of <LOCATION> Bogota </LOCATION>, police in the Department of <PERSON> Santander </PERSON> said. They said the rebels belonged to the pro-Cuban <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> and were demanding $ 2 million in ransom. <PERSON> Gambini </PERSON>'s hometown in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> was not immmediately available. In a telephone interview with The Associated Press Friday night, <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Gambini </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Galveston </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, confirmed that his brother <PERSON> Jake </PERSON> had been kidnapped in <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION>, but refused to comment further. Police said <PERSON> Gambini </PERSON> worked for the <ORGANIZATION> Piper </ORGANIZATION> company, which according to industry sources provides technical advice to companies searching for oil in northeast <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> has attacked several oil pipelines and abducted technicians in an attempt to pressure the <LOCATION> Colombian </LOCATION> government to cancel contracts with foreign petroleum companies.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880701-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-01-88 2352EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a BC-Jazz     07-01 0302</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Jazz,0314</SECOND>
<HEAD>Buddy Rich Celebrated at Jazz Festival</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: No PMs Planned</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By MARY CAMPBELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 `` Buddy swung,'' singer <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> said Friday before opening the <ORGANIZATION> JVC </ORGANIZATION> Jazz Festival concert celebrating the music of the late drummer and band leader <PERSON> Buddy </PERSON> <PERSON> Rich </PERSON>. `` He drummed the impossible drum,'' <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Greene </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Recording </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Arts </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sciences </ORGANIZATION>, said in giving a citation of merit to <PERSON> Rich </PERSON>'s daughter <PERSON> Cathy </PERSON> <PERSON> Rich </PERSON>, who produced the concert. The evening at <ORGANIZATION> Carnegie </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hall </ORGANIZATION> was a mixture of the classy and the homey. <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> and <PERSON> Mel </PERSON> <PERSON> Torme </PERSON> sang impeccably and with warmth. <PERSON> Louis </PERSON> <PERSON> Bellson </PERSON> played a couple of exciting and varied drum solos. There were film clips of <PERSON> Rich </PERSON> in the late 1930s and early 1940s with the <PERSON> Artie </PERSON> <PERSON> Shaw </PERSON> and <PERSON> Tommy </PERSON> <PERSON> Dorsey </PERSON> bands. <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> sang `` There Will Never Be Another You'' and `` Honeysuckle Rose'' in front of the Buddy Rich Big Band. <PERSON> Torme </PERSON> included `` Here's That Rainy Day,'' which he said was <PERSON> Rich </PERSON>'s favorite from a 1978 album they made, `` Together Again for the First Time. <PERSON> Cathy </PERSON> <PERSON> Rich </PERSON> sang a song praising her father while slides from the family scrapbook were shown. The last number was the lengthy `` Two in One Suite,'' with <PERSON> Rich </PERSON>'s drumming recorded in <LOCATION> Las </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vegas </LOCATION> in 1968 and the band playing. <PERSON> Annie </PERSON> <PERSON> Ross </PERSON> and <PERSON> Dominick </PERSON> <PERSON> Allen </PERSON>, souding very good, sang new, sometimes treacly lyrics in praise of <PERSON> Rich </PERSON>. Also appearing were saxophonist <PERSON> Stan </PERSON> <PERSON> Getz </PERSON>, who played <PERSON> Thad </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>' `` Yours and Mine,'' which he and <PERSON> Rich </PERSON> once heard together at the <ORGANIZATION> Village </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Vanguard </ORGANIZATION>, and singers <PERSON> Jon </PERSON> <PERSON> Hendricks </PERSON> and Company and <PERSON> Marlena </PERSON> <PERSON> Shaw </PERSON>. <PERSON> Rich </PERSON>, who died in 1987 at age 69, was a self-taught drummer credited with `` the fastest hands in the world.'' His career spanned vaudeville, the Big Band era and decades on the road.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880701-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-01-88 0030EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Deaths 1stLd-Writethru a0832 07-01 0421</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Deaths, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0832,0429</SECOND>
<NOTE>Eds: ADDS Roberts and Fishel; No separates moved for the AMs
cycle. Fishel also moved on the sports wire.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Laurence Beilenson</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Laurence </PERSON> <PERSON> Beilenson </PERSON>, who helped found the Screen Actors Guild and other <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION> unions in the 1930s as well as serving such clients as then-actor <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, died Monday of a stroke. He was 89. <PERSON> Beilenson </PERSON> helped to found or organize the original <ORGANIZATION> Screen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Writers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guild </ORGANIZATION>, the Screen Actors Guild, the <ORGANIZATION> Directors </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guild </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Television </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <ORGANIZATION> Radio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Artists </ORGANIZATION>. The writers guild later became the Writers Guild of <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Beilenson </PERSON> was a staff lawyer with SAG from its start in 1933, helped negotiate SAG's first contract with film producers in 1937, and stayed on as counsel until 1949. His show business clients ranged from <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> to <PERSON> Greta </PERSON> <PERSON> Garbo </PERSON> to <PERSON> Groucho </PERSON> <PERSON> Marx </PERSON>. After retiring from SAG he served as legal counsel to <ORGANIZATION> MCA </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Artists </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ltd. </ORGANIZATION> and wrote three books, `` The Treaty Trap,'' `` Power Through Subversion'' and `` Survival and Peace in the Nuclear Age.''
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>Bill Roberts</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SANTA MONICA, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Roberts </PERSON>, 63, a veteran political manager who engineered President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s early campaign triumphs and a major figure in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> Republican politics for more than three decades, died Thursday. Among hundreds of <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> campaigns managed by <PERSON> Roberts </PERSON>, either independently or with longtime colleague <PERSON> Stu </PERSON> <PERSON> Spencer </PERSON>, were <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s successful campaigns for governor in 1966 and 1970 and <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Deukmejian </PERSON>'s gubernatorial campaign in 1982. The most recent statewide campaign managed by <PERSON> Roberts </PERSON> was the successful drive in 1986 to remove Chief Justice Rose Bird and Justices <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Grodin </PERSON> and <PERSON> Cruz </PERSON> <PERSON> Reynoso </PERSON> from the <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>Robert Fishel</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> O. </PERSON> <PERSON> Fishel </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> League </ORGANIZATION> Executive Vice President and major-league executive for more than 40 years, died Thursday, apparently of a heart attack at age 74. <PERSON> Fishel </PERSON> began his connection with baseball as an advertising executive, handling the <ORGANIZATION> Indians </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ' </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Radio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Network </ORGANIZATION> account for a local agency. In 1951, he was named publicity director of the <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Louis </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Browns </ORGANIZATION> by owner <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Veeck </PERSON>, who had owned the <ORGANIZATION> Indians </ORGANIZATION> during <PERSON> Fishel </PERSON>'s time in <LOCATION> Cleveland </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Fishel </PERSON> joined the <ORGANIZATION> Yankees </ORGANIZATION> as publicity director in 1954 and served with them for 20 years. He rose to a vice-presidency before joining the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> League </ORGANIZATION> in 1974 as a special assistant to AL President <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> MacPhail </PERSON>, his former boss with the <ORGANIZATION> Yankees </ORGANIZATION>. Four years later, <PERSON> Fishel </PERSON> was voted League Secretary and was elected Executive Vice President in 1983.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880701-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-01-88 0122EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-SavingSalvador     07-01 0745</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Saving Salvador,0765</SECOND>
<HEAD>Campaign Under Way to Save Old Architecture in Brazil</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By LISA GENASCI</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SALVADOR, Brazil (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 International celebrities, including music star <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Simon </PERSON>, have joined in a campaign to save the world's largest example of Portuguese colonial architecture in downtown <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>, one of the <LOCATION> Western </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hemisphere </LOCATION>'s oldest cities. The 91-acre district is now a slum. It is called <LOCATION> Pelourinho </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> Portuguese </LOCATION> word for `` pillory,'' stemming from <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>'s former slave trade. <LOCATION> Pelourinho </LOCATION>'s largely abandoned facades line the narrow streets of the city that also was <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION>'s first capital and sometimes is known to outsiders as <LOCATION> Bahia </LOCATION>, the name of the coastal city's state. In addition to <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Simon </PERSON>, other international celebrities involved in the campaign include the <LOCATION> Spanish </LOCATION> crooner <PERSON> Julio </PERSON> <PERSON> Iglesias </PERSON> and <PERSON> Akio </PERSON> <PERSON> Morito </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> Sony </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>. Of the district's 978 buildings, some dating as far back as the 1500s, 300 are close to collapse, 48 are in ruins, and about 10 slide down hillsides every year in seasonal rainstorms, according to <PERSON> Maria </PERSON> <PERSON> del </PERSON> <PERSON> Carmen </PERSON>, coordinator of the save-Pelourinho campaign <LOCATION> Pelourinho </LOCATION>'s spacious mansions housed the elite when <PERSON> Salvador </PERSON> was, until 1763, the capital of <LOCATION> Portugal </LOCATION>'s vast South American Colony. Today it is a Skid Row, home to prostitutes, drug dealers and muggers. `` <LOCATION> Pelourinho </LOCATION> must be the world's largest Baroque slum,'' said the <LOCATION> Bahia </LOCATION> state secretary for culture, <PERSON> Gilberto </PERSON> <PERSON> Gil </PERSON>, who also is a popular singer and composer. `` There are people in this city who have n't dared venture into <LOCATION> Pelourinho </LOCATION> for the past 20 years.'' But for the first time authorities, encouraged by private business, have launched a massive campaign to clean up the winding streets and half-collapsed mansions, which in 1987 were designated by <ORGANIZATION> UNESCO </ORGANIZATION> as part of mankind's `` cultural heritage.'' The buildings are protected from demolition by a local decree. `` If we do n't do something now, the whole beautiful area will be completely irrecoverable in 10 years,'' said Ms. <PERSON> del </PERSON> <PERSON> Carmen </PERSON>, an engineer. But conversely, it was after the <ORGANIZATION> UNESCO </ORGANIZATION> designation that the colonial buildings, arcades, courtyards and cobblestone streets began fell into greater disarray. `` Landlords refused to invest in their properties, which were inhabited by tenants who could pay almost no rent,'' <PERSON> Gil </PERSON> said. `` And they were n't allowed to tear down their buildings. So the strategy was to let the buildings literally fall down _ with tenants inside them.'' So far, the so-called Historical Park of <LOCATION> Pelourinho </LOCATION>, operating with 150 functionaries borrowed from various municipal government offices, has raised the equivalent of about $ 7 million in government grants and loans, Ms. <PERSON> del </PERSON> <PERSON> Carmen </PERSON> said. But organizers hope a media campaign that began in February directed at foreign and domestic business communities will bring in much more. <PERSON> Morita </PERSON>, <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> and <PERSON> Iglesias </PERSON> are featured in 60-second public service announcements asking for donations and encouraging businesses to invest in the area. `` We need Brazilians and others to feel responsible for the area, to understand that <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION> was born here and want to leave this for their children,'' Ms. <PERSON> del </PERSON> <PERSON> Carmen </PERSON> said. `` Most of the people who actually live here exist in subhuman conditions and could care less about <LOCATION> Pelourinho </LOCATION>.'' Black groups have been some of the most active in rallying to save the decaying center, as part of a slow but growing black-consciousness movement in mixed-race <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Pelourinho </LOCATION> was a major port of entry for slaves from <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> from the 1500s through 1888, when slavery was abolished in <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION>. One of the area's most beautiful buildings, the Rosary of the <ORGANIZATION> Blacks </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION>, was built over a period of 150 years by and for slaves. `` Every stone here was laid with the sweat of blacks,'' said an area resident known only as `` Zoinho.'' `` We have to save this area. It's a monument to our suffering.'' Paulo de <PERSON> Jesus </PERSON>, 18, lives with his father and four brothers and sisters in two rooms of a massively subdivided old home. He was born in <LOCATION> Pelourinho </LOCATION>. `` I would n't leave this place,'' he said. `` This is my home. But if you knocked down our old home and built an apartment building in it's place, we'd be much happier.'' Some residents are worried that increased property values will drive out long-time inhabitants. `` We have to make sure we do n't turn <LOCATION> Pelourinho </LOCATION> into a picture postcard,'' Ms. <PERSON> del </PERSON> <PERSON> Carmen </PERSON> said. `` The sense of community here is rich and very strong. We need to bring in jobs, schools, health facilities and give people the chance to appreciate the fabulous historicl setting.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880701-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-01-88 2357EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Mexico-US     07-01 0356</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Mexico-US,0366</SECOND>
<HEAD>Reagan Sends Letter to Mexican President On Puerto Rican
Separatist</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CANDICE HUGHES</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MEXICO CITY (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> sent a letter to President <PERSON> Miguel </PERSON> de la <LOCATION> Madrid </LOCATION> regarding <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>'s refusal to extradite a Puerto Rican separatist accused of being a terrorist, the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> said Friday. <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. Ambassador <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Pilliod </PERSON> delivered the letter to de la <LOCATION> Madrid </LOCATION> Friday afternoon, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Arturo </PERSON> <PERSON> Montano </PERSON> said. He said he did not have any details of the message concerning 37-year-old <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Morales </PERSON>, who was freed from a Mexican prison June 24 and allowed to leave on a flight to <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION>. A spokesman at de la <LOCATION> Madrid </LOCATION>'s office said the president would respond to <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s letter `` as soon as possible.'' He did not comment on the contents of the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> message but said de la <LOCATION> Madrid </LOCATION> told Pilliod he has instructed the <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> to respond to a <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> protest delivered earlier this week to the <LOCATION> Mexican </LOCATION> ambassador in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. In <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman <PERSON> Phyllis </PERSON> <PERSON> Oakley </PERSON> said <PERSON> Pilliod </PERSON> had personally carried the letter to de la <LOCATION> Madrid </LOCATION> but she also would not discuss the contents. Mrs. <PERSON> Oakley </PERSON> said there had been no change in the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government's outrage at the release of <PERSON> Morales </PERSON>. The <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Deparment </ORGANIZATION> has called <PERSON> Morales </PERSON> a `` convicted terrorist and murderer.'' <PERSON> Montano </PERSON> said <PERSON> Pilliod </PERSON> returned to <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> Thursday night from <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> where he had been recalled for consultations Tuesday. <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> did not advise the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> that it had released <PERSON> Morales </PERSON> until Tuesday, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials have said. Mexican officials frequently characterized <PERSON> Morales </PERSON> as a `` political fighter,'' not a criminal, and local news reports usually did not mention <PERSON> Morales </PERSON> conviction in <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> for murder. <PERSON> Morales </PERSON> was released after serving five years of an eight-year sentence for the 1983 slaying of a Mexican police officer and for entering the country illegally. At the time of that killing, <PERSON> Morales </PERSON> was an escaped convict from the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, having fled in 1979 from a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> prison after being convicted of weapons and explosives charges in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>. After his capture in <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> pressed without success for his extradition.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880701-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-01-88 2359EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Japan-Stocks     07-01 0026</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Japan-Stocks,0025</SECOND>
<HEAD>Stocks Closed Lower</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Nikkei Stock Average closed at 27,362.52 points, down 141.01 points, on the <ORGANIZATION> Tokyo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Stock </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Exchange </ORGANIZATION> Saturday.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880701-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-01-88 0132EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-PearThrips     07-01 0276</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Pear Thrips,0282</SECOND>
<HEAD>Officials Map Out Pear Thrips Plan</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BENNINGTON, Vt. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Officials could relax state restrictions on pesticide spraying in an effort to control the pear thrips, an insect blamed for defoliating thousands of acres of maple trees in southern <LOCATION> Vermont </LOCATION>. Officials of the state <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forests </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Parks </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Recreation </ORGANIZATION>, along with experts from the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Vermont </ORGANIZATION> and entomologists experienced with thrips from other northeastern states, have come up with a research project designed to learn more about the insect's habits, life cycle and impact on maple crops and products. Pear thrips are insects whose feeding habits have damaged and weakened thousands of acres of <LOCATION> Vermont </LOCATION> sugarbush, particularly in <LOCATION> Bennington </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Windham </LOCATION> counties. The plans that experts have laid to improve the lot of maple trees may involve asking Gov. <PERSON> Madeleine </PERSON> <PERSON> Kunin </PERSON> to relax her 1986 policy strictly limiting pesticide spraying by state agriculture and transportation officials. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Paine </PERSON>, deputy commissioner of agriculture, has done a control pesticide test spray on a sugarbush in <LOCATION> Londonderry </LOCATION> with state permission to discover the most effective stage to spray in the thrips' life cycle. State forester <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Guenther </PERSON> said recently the committee also wants to check for trends using an earth-orbiting satellite that takes color coded infrared snapshots of <LOCATION> Vermont </LOCATION> forest land. The photos, which would cost between $ 10,000 and $ 12,000, could give foresters a better idea of what next year's maple crop will look like since the camera picks up signs of weakness and disease that human eyes can miss. Project members also plan to send out questionnaires to all known <LOCATION> Vermont </LOCATION> sugarmakers, asking them to comment on the extent of thrips damage.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880701-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-01-88 0132EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-TheReagans     07-01 0555</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-The Reagans,0572</SECOND>
<HEAD>Reagans Talk About Themselves On British TV</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By MARCUS ELIASON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> and <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> recall the white lies they told each other on their first date, and <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s daughter, <PERSON> Maureen </PERSON>, remembers her surprise when a friend told her she found the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> president sexy. These are a few of the tidbits of <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> lore that British television viewers will see on July 8, when the first of a three-part series on the life of <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> is broadcast. The film, shown to journalists Thursday, is filled with varied assessments of <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>. To Secretary of State <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON>, the president is `` a revolutionary and he's changed the agenda -LRB- in -RRB- the most sweeping presidency in this country probably since <PERSON> Franklin </PERSON> <PERSON> Roosevelt </PERSON>.'' Former budget director <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Stockman </PERSON> calls <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s economic policies `` the singular greatest episode of sustained economic mismanagement in the 20th-century history of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>.'' But Mrs. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> says of her husband: `` I think he made people feel good about themselves, good about the country. We now have a strong economy, unemployment is down, interest rates are down. ...'' The film traces <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> to his Midwestern boyhood, interviewing friends and schoolmates. Actress Olivia de Havilland recalls <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and the late actor <PERSON> Errol </PERSON> <PERSON> Flynn </PERSON> lining up as soldiers so that <PERSON> Flynn </PERSON>'s shoulder obscured <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>. She says <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> quietly kicked the sand into a mound, `` higher and higher, and finally, when the photographer said, ` All right everybody, let's smile,' the future president of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> stepped up on the mound and towered over <PERSON> Errol </PERSON> <PERSON> Flynn </PERSON>.'' Interviewer <PERSON> Godfrey </PERSON> <PERSON> Hodgson </PERSON> asked <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> why he spied for the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> on colleagues in the Screen Actors Guild of which he was president. `` They -LRB- the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> -RRB- came wanting some advice, some findings on people that I had dealt with, and I got an insight into what was happening to the motion picture business. It did give me a real understanding of the communist menace,'' <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> says. Mrs. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> recalls their first date when, mutually wary, they both said they had `` early morning calls'' so that they could leave early if they did n't like each other. They got home at 2:30 a.m, she says. `` I think by that time both of us knew that neither one us of had an early morning call.'' <PERSON> Maureen </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s daughter by his first marriage to actress <PERSON> Jane </PERSON> <PERSON> Wyman </PERSON>, says a friend who saw <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> doing a TV ad dressed as a cowboy exclaimed to her that `` he's so sexy.'' `` I said, my father sexy? You must be kidding. ` No no, he's wonderful. And he is wonderful,'' Miss <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> says. During his 50-minute interview, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> describes his wife as `` a helpmeet such as I think every man dreams of having, a relationship that sort of matches your dreams of marriage when you were an adolescent.'' He laughs about claims that she interferes in policy-making. `` She does n't go down and get involved in affairs like disarmament or anything else. She advises me of what she thinks is good for me, and I feel free to confide in her the things that are going on. `` As a matter of fact she's a help just by my knowing that she's up there when I go to meet her at the end of the day.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880701-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-01-88 0134EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-ScotusRdp Bjt   07-01 0706</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Scotus Rdp, Bjt,700</SECOND>
<HEAD>Supreme Court Will Take Another Look at Death Penalty</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JAMES H. RUBIN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The constitutionality of the death penalty for juvenile killers again will be on the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>'s agenda next term, a welcome surprise for capital punishment foes. <PERSON> Leigh </PERSON> <PERSON> Dingerson </PERSON>, head of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coalition </ORGANIZATION> to Abolish the Death Penalty, said, `` It's very encouraging. I assumed it would be another couple of years before they took the issue up in another case.'' <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> Schwarzschild </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Civil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberties </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION> said the court's willingness to restudy the issue `` is very startling.'' But he cautioned against reading too much into the court's announcement `` It's foolish to try and predict what the court will do,'' he said. The justices on Thursday provided a dramatic epilogue to their 1987-88 term by agreeing to consider banning capital punishment for all juvenile murderers when the court returns for the next term on the first Monday in October. Just 24 hours earlier, the court had come close to banning the death penalty for those who commit murders before they are 16. Few expected it would move so quickly to re-examine capital punishment for juvenile killers. But the justices said Thursday they will use cases from <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION> to reconsider the fate of young killers. The court said it will decide sometime in 1989 whether use of the death penalty for anyone under 18 when the crime was committed violates the Constitution's ban on `` cruel and unusual punishment.'' The court will consider overturning the death sentences of <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION> death row inmate <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Martinez </PERSON> <PERSON> High </PERSON>, who was 17 when he participated in a 1976 murder, and <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION> death row inmate <PERSON> Heath </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilkins </PERSON>, who was 16 when he committed a 1985 murder. High was just weeks shy of his 18th birthday when he took part in a gas station robbery in <LOCATION> Taliferro </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ga. </LOCATION>, in which an 11-year-old boy was shot to death. <PERSON> Wilkins </PERSON> helped rob an <ORGANIZATION> Avondale </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Mo. </LOCATION>, liquor store. <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> <PERSON> Allen </PERSON>, a store clerk, was fatally stabbed. The National Coalition to Abolish the Death Penalty said 30 death row inmates nationwide _ out of a total of 2,100 _ were under 18 when they committed their crimes. Of the 100 men and women executed in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> since the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> reinstated capital punishment in 1976, three committed their crimes when they were 17. Since 1948, no one has been executed for a crime committed when he or she was younger than 17. If the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> bans the death penalty for those under 18, it would affect most of the 37 states with death penalty laws _ including those that do not specify a minimum age for killers subject to capital punishment and states that specify age limits under 18. On Wednesday, four justices said the death penalty is unconstitutional for those who were younger than 16 when they committed murder. Three justices said the Constitution does not set such age limits for executions. Justice <PERSON> Sandra </PERSON> <PERSON> Day </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Connor </PERSON> provided a fifth vote to throw out the death penalty for a convicted <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION> killer who was 15 when he helped kill his former brother-in-law. But <PERSON> O'Connor </PERSON> stopped just short of calling for abolition of capital punishment for killers under 16. A key vote in next term's cases will be provided by Justice <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, who joined the court in February, too late to participate in the <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION> case. In other action Thursday, the court: _ Agreed to study alleged race discrimination in Alaskan salmon canneries, setting the stage for an important sequel to the court's ruling on Wednesday that makes it easier for workers to prove their bosses are guilty of illegal _ Cleared away the last legal obstacle to a $ 180 million settlement _ with interest now worth some $ 240 million _ between <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> veterans and manufacturers of the herbicide Agent Orange The court let stand rulings dismissing lawsuits by about 300 veterans who challenged the settlement, in which as many as 250,000 others could participate. _ Agreed to decide whether states may ban virtually all lawyer advertisements that feature testimonials or client endorsements The justices will review a <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> rule that presumes such ads are false or misleading.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880701-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-01-88 0137EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-OnTheRoadAgain Bjt   07-01 0637</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-On The Road Again, Bjt,660</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHINGTON WIRE: Shultz Spends 55 Hours In Central America</HEAD>
<BYLINE>An AP News Analysis</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>By BARRY SCHWEID</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Diplomatic Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Even in the jet age, a 55-hour trip is a pretty brisk pace for a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Secretary of State. How does <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> do it? Also: Why? He does it by relying on what appear to be enormous reserves of energy. But why did he decide to sweep through <LOCATION> Guatemala </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Costa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rica </LOCATION> in his first trip to the region since 1986? Some senior members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> are puzzled. Is <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> trying to lay the groundwork for a new <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> drive to win support for the Nicaraguan rebels known as Contras? And why did he ignore appeals from the Nicaraguan leader, <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON>, that he stop in <LOCATION> Managua </LOCATION>? A senior official who briefed reporters before <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON>'s departure Wednesday said renewed aid for the Contras would not be a major focus of the trip, <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> apparently shunned <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON> because <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> policy calls for avoiding <ORGANIZATION> Sandinista </ORGANIZATION> leaders until they display what the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration regards as serious interest in moving toward a democratic system From <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON>'s perspective, that would be a lot easier to do if the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> stopped trying to overthrow the Nicaraguan government. Sandinista leaders have been appealing to the Contras to resume peace talks, but the Contras say the Nicaraguan government would have to take certain steps first. These include granting permission to open a television station not run by the government, allow the taking of public opinion polls, declaring a general amnesty and suspending military recruitment. And so, round and round they go, with the prospect of renewed fighting always there. Peace talks ended June 9. The cease-fire has lasted three months, but the thousands of Contra soldiers who took sanctuary in <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION> during the lull may be ready to fight again. They are rested and have received food, clothing and medicine from the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> hopes the leaders of <LOCATION> Guatemala </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Costa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rica </LOCATION> will pressure <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> to take a more flexible position on peace talks with the Contras. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> aid to the rebels ended Feb. 29, and the mood on <LOCATION> Capitol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION> is strongly against a resumption. Ostensibly, the administration is trying to decide what to do. Conservatives on its right flank do not want to see the Contras foresaken. Critics have insisted from the start that President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s objective is to overthrow the Sandinista government one way or another <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON>'s harsh rhetoric over the past six years has lent support to this theory. `` The Sandinistas seek to build totalitarian society on the back of a massive military machine,'' he said Thursday in <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION>. The softened tone <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> have taken lately toward the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> is not duplicated in this hemisphere. <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> remain anathema to them, and a test of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> resolve in <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>. The military takeover in <LOCATION> Haiti </LOCATION> was a setback to <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> hopes. The <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> has stopped ticking off proudly the number of countries in the hemisphere deemed to have turned democratic since <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> entered the White House 7 -LCB- years ago. But <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> made the point in <LOCATION> Tegucigalpa </LOCATION> on Thursday that <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>'s per-person income is the lowest in the region while the picture is brighter elsewhere. `` <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> is out of step, a country isolated by its rejection of freedom, growth and the security of its neighbors,'' he said. <PERSON> Fidel </PERSON> <PERSON> Castro </PERSON> is firmly in charge in <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION>, and <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON> may be in <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>. But there is an armed resistance in <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> have not lost hope the rebels will force a change in <LOCATION> Managua </LOCATION> before the administration shuts down in January.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Barry </PERSON> <PERSON> Schweid </PERSON> has covered diplomacy for <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> for 15 years.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880701-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-01-88 0142EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-WaterProjects     07-01 0482</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Water Projects,450</SECOND>
<HEAD>Traditional Pork Barrel Bill Comes Up Lean</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID GOELLER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The first fiscal 1989 appropriations bill, a bare-bones energy and water development package, is a <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> vote away from heading to President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s desk. The $ 17.83 billion package worked out by <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> negotiators cleared the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> on a 384-17 roll call Thursday and is expected to win easy <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> approval next week following the July Fourth recess. The spending bill, the product of a tight-money year, is more noteworthy for what it lacks than what it contains. There is no money to begin construction of the superconducting super collider and, lawmakers say, not a dime to start work on new <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corps </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Engineers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reclamation </ORGANIZATION> water projects. Members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and staffers say they ca n't recall when even huge budget deficits prevented at least a few new dams or harbor projects from being tossed into the traditional pork barrel bill. The administration is not happy about the lack of construction money for the <ORGANIZATION> SSC </ORGANIZATION>, the multi-billion dollar high-energy physics project that backers say is needed to keep the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> technologically competitive. The White House, however, has not made any veto threats against the energy and water bill as it has against a number of the other 12 spending bills under consideration in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. Leaders on both sides the Capitol agreed to give the <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> $ 100 million next year to continue preliminary work on the SSC, but they said a decision to build it should be made by the next president. The bill contains money to continue construction work on more than 200 corps and bureau water projects. Although the administration sought six new corps starts, the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Appropriations committees approved none, taking the position that just one new start would set off a clamor among lawmakers for more. More than two-thirds of the money in the bill _ $ 13.16 billion _ is headed for the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION>, with that agency's nuclear activities for the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> accounting for $ 8.1 billion. The non-defense portion of the department's budget would finance a variety of activities, including research into solar and other renewable forms of energy and environmental restoration and safety programs. At the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>'s insistance, the bill contains $ 3 million to study the `` greenhouse effect,'' the global warming trend that scientists say threatens the <LOCATION> Earth </LOCATION> with climate changes and rising ocean waters. The corps would have $ 11 million less next year than in fiscal 1988 to spend on dams, harbors and other work, including a growing number of shoreline erosion projects. The <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reclamation </ORGANIZATION>, which operates irrigation and power facilities in the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION>, would get $ 40 million more in fiscal 1989, with more than 40 percent of the money going to three large projects: <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Arizona </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880701-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-01-88 0142EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-SiameseTwins     07-01 0146</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Siamese Twins,0149</SECOND>
<HEAD>Siamese Twins With Two Heads, One Body, Born In Hong Kong</HEAD>
<DATELINE>HONG KONG (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Newly born Siamese twins with two heads but one body were in stable condition today in a <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> hospital with a good chance of survival, a doctor said. The two boys, born Thursday, have two spines but only one pair of legs and one pair of arms, said Professor C.Y. <PERSON> Yeung </PERSON>, head of the <ORGANIZATION> Queen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION>'s pediatrics department. <PERSON> Yeung </PERSON> said an operation to separate the twins, who weighed nine pounds at birth, was `` almost impossible.'' He said, `` So far they have a good chance to survive but cases like that may have underlying problems in the future.'' <PERSON> Yeung </PERSON> refused to give more details about the twins or identify them. He said it was up to the parents to decide whether more information should be released.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880701-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-01-88 0146EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-People-Smith     07-01 0253</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-People-Smith,0259</SECOND>
<HEAD>Challenger Widow Fears for Next Shuttle Crew</HEAD>
<DATELINE>HOUSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The widow of space shuttle Challenger pilot <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, who sued the makers of shuttle rockets blamed for the Challenger explosion, says she will be praying for the safety of the next shuttle crew. Shuttle Discovery _ which has undergone 210 modifications and seven months of delay _ will be the first shuttle flight since Challenger exploded in January 1986 killing all seven aboard. The launch is scheduled for Sept. 4. `` I'll be saying my prayers for the crew and their families,'' <PERSON> Jane </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Houston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> after giving a tearful deposition on Wednesday to lawyers for <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government contractor <PERSON> Morton </PERSON> <PERSON> Thiokol </PERSON>. `` I hope they'll be safe.'' Mrs. <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> and her three children are the only relatives of the Challegner crew who have n't settled a lawsuit with the government or Thiokol. Last May, the 42-year-old widow filed a $ 1.5 billion wrongful death suit against <ORGANIZATION> Thiokol </ORGANIZATION>, the government and the director of <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION>'s solid rocket booster program. Since then, a <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> federal judge has denied two of her three claims _ that <ORGANIZATION> Thiokol </ORGANIZATION> be banned from supplying booster rockets for <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> shuttles and that the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aeronautics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Space </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> be named as a defendant in the lawsuit. Mrs. <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>'s remaining claim _ which will be heard in a <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> federal court Sept. 12 _ is aimed at <ORGANIZATION> Thiokol </ORGANIZATION>'s decision to recommend the ill-fated launch. A leaking seal on one of the booster rockets was blamed for the Challenger explosion.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880701-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-01-88 0125EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--Brazil-Gambling     07-01 0078</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Brazil-Gambling,0081</SECOND>
<HEAD>Brazil Congress Says No To Casinos</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BRASILIA, Brazil (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> has rejected a constitutional amendment to bring back casino gambling to <LOCATION> Latin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s largest nation. The vote, on Thursday, was 271-118 in favor, with 14 abstentions, but it fell nine short of the majority needed to pass a constitutional amendment. Casinos were outlawed in <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION> by presidential decree in 1946. The <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> is sitting as a constitutional convention to rewrite <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION>'s military-dictated constitution.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880701-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-01-88 0152EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Nicaragua-Sentences     07-01 0211</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nicaragua-Sentences,0217</SECOND>
<HEAD>Four Sentenced For Passing Secrets To U.S.</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MANAGUA, Nicaragua (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Three former government officials and a Nicaraguan businessman have been sentenced for passing economic secrets to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, news reports said. The pro-government <ORGANIZATION> Nuevo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Diario </ORGANIZATION> newspaper said Thursday that <PERSON> Nora </PERSON> <PERSON> Aldana </PERSON> <PERSON> Centeno </PERSON>, a former planning official, and <PERSON> Mario </PERSON> <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Alegria </PERSON> <PERSON> Castillo </PERSON>, an official of the <ORGANIZATION> Superior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Private </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Enterprise </ORGANIZATION>, were sentenced Wednesday to 16 years for passing secret economic documents to <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Embassy officials. They were arrested in late May and were accused of `` taking documents with the classification ` secret,''' the paper said. <PERSON> Alegria </PERSON> <PERSON> Castillo </PERSON>, director of the council's <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Social </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION>, also was charged with organizing `` a network of informants in some Nicaraguan state institutions,'' it added. <PERSON> Pedro </PERSON> <PERSON> Su </PERSON> <PERSON> Olivas </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> official, and <PERSON> Adrian </PERSON> <PERSON> Espinales </PERSON>, of the <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Industry </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION>, each drew a three-year term for providing the information to <LOCATION> Algeria </LOCATION> which then passed it to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. The opposition newspaper <ORGANIZATION> La </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Prensa </ORGANIZATION> called the 16-year sentences `` barbaric'' and said lawyers for all four defendants planned to appeal. It quoted lawyers for <PERSON> Aldana </PERSON> <PERSON> Centeno </PERSON> and <PERSON> Alegria </PERSON> <PERSON> Castillo </PERSON> as saying their clients had been convicted of a non-existent crime because <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> has no laws about revealing secret documents.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880701-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-01-88 0125EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-PoliticalRdp Bjt   07-01 0748</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Political Rdp, Bjt,750</SECOND>
<HEAD>Dukakis Campaigns With UAW; Bush Returns To Maine</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Will be topped after 10 a.m. EDT appearance by Dukakis in
Dayton</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT GREENE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Republican <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and Democrat <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> gave contrasting pictures of the economy as Republicans continued work on a party platform that they said would have more meat than the Democratic document. The disagreements over how well off Americans really are occurred as <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> prepared to visit a <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Auto </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Workers </ORGANIZATION> union hall in <LOCATION> Dayton </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, and <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> returned to his vacation home in <LOCATION> Kennebunkport </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION>, for a celebration of his mother's 87th birthday today. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> was returning tonight to <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>, where he and his wife, <PERSON> Kitty </PERSON>, planned to celebrate the Fourth of July with <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> and his wife, <PERSON> Jackie </PERSON>. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, who has pressed for an offer of the No. 2 position on the Democratic ticket, will meet Monday night with <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, said <PERSON> Dayton </PERSON> <PERSON> Duncan </PERSON>, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' campaign press secretary. The aide gave no indication what the two might discuss. The <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> governor faced continued heat from opponents in the Statehouse who criticized him for campaigning while the state ended its fiscal year with a nearly $ 400 million deficit Thursday and without a budget for the next year. A series of tax bills and fee-raising measures to help the state pay for expanded spending in fiscal 1989 was nearing enactment. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> told a luncheon group in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> that paid $ 10,000 a couple to hear him speak that the country has been enjoying an economic recovery since late 1982, the longest peacetime expansion in history. He said that two years ago economists predicted a downturn that has n't arrived. `` Wrong, wrong, wrong,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said. `` No wonder it's called the ` dismal science.''' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said: `` Liberals promise compassion but they deliver misery.'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> told employees at a <ORGANIZATION> Reynolds </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aluminum </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> plant outside <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> that the average weekly wage for jobs lost between 1979 and 1985 was $ 440, while the average weekly pay for new jobs during that period was only $ 270. `` Too many of our families are struggling to hold on, challenged by change, anxious about their jobs, burdened by the rising costs of health care and housing and college tuition, troubled by the lack of quality affordable child care,'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> said. Republicans meeting in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> to draft a party platform criticized the Democrats' platform document as lacking content and trying to conceal a tax and spend policy. Senate Minority Leader <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> said the Democrats kept their platform short because `` they do n't have much to talk about. ... I mean, who wants to talk about raising your taxes and more regulation and more spending?'' <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>, asked if he wanted the No. 2 job, said: `` I do n't think it's a question of wanting it. ... It's a question of winning the election, helping your party and trying to help your country. I'd want to be majority leader if I had my choice. Rep. <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> told reporters at the meeting he does not expect to be picked by <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> as a running mate, but said <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> might be. `` I'm not after it because I do n't think it's going to be offered,'' said <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON>, adding that from `` all of the signals, all of the press reports coming out of the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> campaign, it sounds to me like they're leaning to <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>.'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> won the backing Thursday of the political action committee of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Education </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, the nation's largest teacher union The 1.9-million member union's board is scheduled to meet today and almost certainly concur with the PAC's choice <ORGANIZATION> NEA </ORGANIZATION> officials said the endorsement applies only to the Democratic nomination. The union wo n't make a final presidential endorsement until Sept. 8, after both parties have held their conventions. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> refused to comment on whether he would use the <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> visit to disclose whether he wants to pursue the second spot on the ticket. `` At this point, I will simply pursue the process and convey my private conclusions to Gov. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>'' later, he said. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> played a game of role reversal Thursday in response to a pair of polls that showed the two candidates tied or <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> trailing <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> only slightly. Earlier polls have given <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> double-digit leads. `` I can only say what I've been saying for 16 months,'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> said. `` Early polls are meaningless.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, declared `` I'm feeling like <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> Truman </PERSON>,'' and depicted himself as a comeback winner.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880701-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-01-88 0154EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-China-Children     07-01 0522</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-China-Children,0536</SECOND>
<HEAD>More Than 1 Million Children Official Non-Entities</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 More than one million children in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> officially do not exist because they were born outside state birth control targets, rendering them unable to receive food rations, schooling and job assignments, an official report said. The children, most of whom are under age 10, are commonly referred to as `` black children.'' They are children whose parents did not have their births registered or who were refused registration by local authorities, the <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> reported Thursday. Under <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s one-child policy, officials in each county are responsible for ensuring that each woman has only one child and that the number of births in the county does not exceed the birth target set by the state. Parents are penalized for having more than one child, and officials are penalized if the county goes over the number of births that it is allowed. Officials, however, are financially rewarded if births stay within the target. Some parents did not register births of their second or subsequent children to avoid paying the fine, the paper said. Fines vary from region to region, but are generally $ 270 or more per year for five years, a huge fine by Chinese standards. Some local officials, seeing their bonuses jeapordized by too many births, simply refuse to register new babies, the paper said. In one city in southwestern <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Sichuan </LOCATION> province, local officials refused to register the births of 450 babies because the birth target had already been reached, the report said. Without a residence permit, children are deprived of the rights of a <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> citizen. They do not receive their ration of rice and edible oil, are unable to register for school and will not be able to get a job, join the military or sit for college entrance exams when they grow up, the newspaper said. The problem will become even greater when these children marry and have children of their own, who also will be unable to get residence permits, it said. The situation is most serious in the provinces of <LOCATION> Hebei </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Shandong </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Jiangxi </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Guizhou </LOCATION>. In each of these provinces, `` black children'' number more than 70,000, the report said. State officials have called attention to the problem, saying that the children are innocent victims, the newspaper reported. They said the situation not only hurts the children, it also affects the nation's family planning and population control efforts and creates social problems. <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s birth rate hit 2 percent in 1986 and stayed there last year. If the trend continues, <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s population of 1.08 billion will double by the year 2030, according to the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fund </ORGANIZATION> for Population Activities. <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> has said that it must keep the birth rate at 1.5 percent if it is to meet its goal of keeping the population under 1.2 billion by the year 2000. <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> will mark <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION>'s Three Billion Population Day today. In a televised speech for the occasion Chinese Premier <PERSON> Li </PERSON> <PERSON> Peng </PERSON> said Thursday, `` The country has listed family planning as one of its basic national policies and taken the control of population growth as a strategic task.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880701-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-01-88 0223EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-NicaraguaPoll     07-01 0693</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nicaragua Poll,620</SECOND>
<HEAD>Nicaraguans Critical of Sandinistas, Appreciate Soviet Union,
Dislike U.S.</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDS: Interamerican, 5th graf, is cq</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By DAVID BRISCOE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Many Nicaraguans are critical of their leftist government and do n't believe it is democratic, but they think Soviet policies are better than those of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, according to a private poll. A survey presented Thursday as the first independent poll of Nicaraguan opinion under nine years of <ORGANIZATION> Sandinista </ORGANIZATION> rule indicates strong support for President <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON>, 85 percent opposition to <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Contra aid, and 68 percent disapproval of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> policies in <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>. Asked what they most admire about the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, 42 percent of those polled said `` nothing,'' which was the most prevalent answer. The <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration for the past seven years has supported rebels attempting to overthrow the Nicaraguan government. The poll of 1,129 adults in <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> was sponsored by the <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Managua </LOCATION> and research groups in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Bollinger </PERSON>, director of the cosponsoring <ORGANIZATION> Interamerican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>, said the newly formed, private <ORGANIZATION> Nicaraguan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Opinion </ORGANIZATION> used accepted scientific polling methods, employing students at <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, which he described as the nation's most politically neutral university. The students interviewed 1,129 adults selected at random in five types of <LOCATION> Managua </LOCATION> neighborhoods on June 4-5. <PERSON> Bollinger </PERSON> did not offer a margin of error for the poll but he said at a news conference that several steps were taken to ensure its integrity and objectivity. But he did note that many educated people who might have given anti-Sandinista views have fled to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, with their homes taken over by government officials and military officers. He said about 27 percent of those polled worked for the government, and they were the most supportive of the Sandinistas. Thirty-eight percent of the respondents believed the ruling <ORGANIZATION> Sandinistas </ORGANIZATION>' management of the Nicaraguan economy has been either bad or terrible, while 36 percent described it as fair, and only 22 percent said it was good or excellent. Seventy-four percent of those interviewed said they rated their family's economic situation worse than a year ago, while only 7 percent said it was better. Forty-eight percent said they did not consider the Sandinista government democratic while 40 percent said they did. But there was general support for Sandinista peace efforts and the government's foreign policies A majority supported incorporation of the Contras into the country's political life but most of those interviewed also said they doubted the fighting would end soon. The overall results show the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> economic blockade of <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>, along with <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> support for the Contra rebels, has alienated even many anti-Sandinista Nicaraguans, <PERSON> Bollinger </PERSON> said. The <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> received higher positive responses than the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> among all income levels on several questions, with higher-income groups being more pro-Soviet and pro-Sandinista than poorer and less-educated Nicaraguans. Future polls _ the research group plans one of people in several <LOCATION> Latin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> countries later this year _ will attempt to obtain more detail about reaction to Soviet policies, said <PERSON> Bollinger </PERSON>. Only 1 percent of the respondents described <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Central American policy as excellent, 7 percent called it good, 17 percent said fair, 40 percent said bad and 28 percent called it terrible. Asked the same question about Soviet policy, 14 percent said it was excellent, 43 percent good, 14 percent fair, 9 percent bad and 4 percent terrible. In evaluating <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON>'s management of the government over the last four years, 42 percent said it was good or excellent, 29 percent fair and 21 percent bad or terrible. <PERSON> Bollinger </PERSON> said this is a high rating in Latin American terms. He said in a similar poll conducted in <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>, only 13 percent of respondents gave President <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Napoleon </PERSON> <PERSON> Duarte </PERSON> a good or excellent rating. The poll showed that 28 percent of those interviewed claimed affiliation with the ruling <ORGANIZATION> Sandinista </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> party </ORGANIZATION>, 9 percent with liberal or conservative opposition parties and 59 percent said they belonged to no party. <PERSON> Bollinger </PERSON> said the Nicaraguan government did not interfere with the survey even though laws apparently are still on the books prohibiting independent polling in the country.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880701-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-01-88 0223EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-US-Gulf     07-01 0668</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-US-Gulf,680</SECOND>
<HEAD>Iranian Silkworm Battery Could Pose New Threat, US Commander Says</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BRYAN BRUMLEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Construction of a permanent Silkworm battery by <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> near the entrance to the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> and the feared addition of a more advanced anti-ship missile to the Iranian arsenal may heighten risks to passing tankers, says the commander of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> forces in the region. Gen. <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Crist </PERSON>, the Marine four-star who heads the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Command </ORGANIZATION>, told reporters Thursday that completion of the Iranian Silkworm battery at Kuhe-Stak and the possible addition of another Chinese anti-ship missile, the CA-08, could make passage in or out of the gulf more dangerous. But he said that since a daylong naval battle on April 18, in which <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> lost two of its four frigates, Iranian forces have steered clear of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> warships and aircraft. `` They have been very careful not to engage us,'' said <PERSON> Crist </PERSON>. A crack team of electronics experts, sent from the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> to the gulf, determined several weeks after the clash that, despite reports to the contrary, <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> had not fired a Silkworm missile at <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> forces during the fray, he said. The false reports were generated by computers hooked up to radars aboard <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> warships that mistook a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> SM-1 missile fired at an Iranian target for a Silkworm, he said. For about two years, <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> has had Silkworm missiles at the port of <PERSON> Bandar </PERSON> <PERSON> Abbas </PERSON> near the <LOCATION> Strait </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hormuz </LOCATION>, with the ability to set them up at temporary sites to fire within a matter of hours, said <PERSON> Crist </PERSON>. But the permanent earth and concrete bunker, `` with a 57-mile range missile, will cover the entire <LOCATION> Strait </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hormuz </LOCATION>. It will allow <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> to have the missile ready to be fired within five minutes,'' he said. Work on the bunker, first reported in early 1987, was continuing, <PERSON> Crist </PERSON> said in his first briefing with reporters since the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> allowed Kuwaiti tankers to fly the Stars and Stripes last summer and began escorting them through the gulf. <PERSON> Crist </PERSON> said he was pondering what weapons would be needed to destroy the bunker, but meanwhile was stationing the cruise USS Vincennes, equipped with advanced Aegis radar and air-defense missiles, in position to protect any merchant ship passing throught the straits. <PERSON> Crist </PERSON> said the cruiser would be ordered to fire against any <ORGANIZATION> Silkworm </ORGANIZATION> launched, regardless of its intended target. `` The threat is not to our ships'' which have been equipped with defenses against missiles like the Silkworm, `` but to unarmed merchant ships,'' said <PERSON> Crist </PERSON>. `` We are not at war with <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>,'' said <PERSON> Crist </PERSON>. Therefore, before he orders the site bunker destroyed, `` <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> will have to do something to violate international law,'' said the general. Stationing an Aegis cruiser at the Strait of Hormuz may make the decision to fire easier, because if a Silkworm is fired, `` I think it will be a little hard to tell who the target is,'' and the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> warship will try to destroy the attacking missile, he said. And under the rules of engagement in the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> warships and aircraft are under orders to respond agressively to a ship, plane or shore installation they believe is attacking them. `` If they fired a Silkworm at me, I would go get them,'' said <PERSON> Crist </PERSON>. <PERSON> Crist </PERSON> said that despite repeated protests from the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> was continuing to sell advanced arms to the Iranians. He could not specify the exact arms, but said that a ship from <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> or <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> unloaded weaponry from those countries about once every three months at <PERSON> Bandar </PERSON> <PERSON> Abbas </PERSON>. He said <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> is believed to have about 20 Silkworms in the southern gulf, probably kept at <PERSON> Bandar </PERSON> <PERSON> Abbas </PERSON>, and more such missiles in the northern gulf, and he fears that <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> has also sold <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> CA-08 missiles. The CA-08 has a more sophisticated guidance system than the Silkworm, which he described as `` primitive,'' but carries a 500-pound warhead compared to the 1,100-pound warhead on the Silkworm.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880701-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-01-88 0228EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-GOP-Platform     07-01 0796</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-GOP-Platform,770</SECOND>
<HEAD>GOP Promise Their Platform Will Be More Specific Than Democratic
One</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CHRISTOPHER CONNELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Republican leaders are looking to construct a conservative platform that builds on the party's triumphs in 1980 and 1984, while carving out expanded new planks on such hot issues as drugs, AIDS, education and child care. Republican party chairman <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Fahrenkopf </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> and other top <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> officials pledged at a platform hearing here Thursday that they will offer <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> voters a clear picture of what policies a <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration will pursue _ in contrast to what they called the deliberate vagueness of the <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis-inspired </PERSON> Democratic platform. <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Kay </PERSON> <PERSON> Orr </PERSON>, the platform chairman, told reporters: `` Every indication to me is that we will have much the same platform we had in 1984. ... We clearly have been successful with the American electorate with that platform.'' She added that it would reflect `` a conservative political philosophy.'' Sen. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kasten </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, R-Wis., co-chairman of the platform committee, said the Republicans' 1984 vow not to raise taxes, at a time when <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> Mondale </PERSON> was promising a tax increase, `` was the basis on which we won 49 states. <PERSON> Kasten </PERSON> called the Democrats' 2,000-word draft platform approved in <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION> last Saturday `` a bland compromise'' designed to camouflage the true intentions of <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> and his party. But as the election nears, <PERSON> Kasten </PERSON> said, `` the disguise will come off and <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> will be exposed for the narrow-minded, liberal wolf in sheep's clothing that he really is.'' <PERSON> Kasten </PERSON> told reporters that while the 1988 GOP platform draws heavily from the 1984 platform on taxes, the economy and defense, the Republicans must pay more attention this time to such issues as drugs, AIDS, education and child care. `` The debate and the discussion and the dissension will probably be on those new issues which we're going to rassle with in the platform committee,'' said <PERSON> Kasten </PERSON>. Five members of what will ultimately be a 106-member <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> platform committee presided at the day-long hearing on the economy and jobs, along with <PERSON> Fahrenkopf </PERSON> and <PERSON> Maureen </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, co-chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Fahrenkopf </PERSON> challenged the Democrats to `` meet us on the battlefield of ideas'' with a platform that spells out `` not only what we want to accomplish, but how we intend to get there.'' He said the party platforms take on even more importance this year, the first presidential election in two decades without an incumbent in the race. The GOP platform will actually be written in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION> starting Aug. 8, the week before the convention. At Thursday's hearing, drugs were a main concern. The platform committee heard an assistant police chief of <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Vernon </PERSON>, call for draconian measures against drugs and drug-related crime, including denial of business and professional licenses to those who test positive for drugs. `` We are approaching a civilization crisis _ a literal civilization crisis,'' said <PERSON> Vernon </PERSON>, who called for a World War II-like mobilization to fight drugs. `` It should be unpopular and costly to abuse drugs in any form.'' <PERSON> Fahrenkopf </PERSON> and <PERSON> Kasten </PERSON> said later they felt taking away business licenses might be going too far. But the <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION> senator added that the toughest part of the drug issue `` for us to decide is the mandatory vs. voluntary parts.'' <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> Sheriff <PERSON> Sherman </PERSON> <PERSON> Block </PERSON> said drug education must start in fourth grade, because it is too late once kids `` have had the taste of big money'' from drug dealing. He said drugs were draining hundreds of millions of dollars from the American economy, and he questioned why the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> keeps sending aid to countries where the drugs come from. `` It's like handing a firearm to somebody who is threatening to kill you,'' said Block. `` There's no country in the world today who, short of a nuclear attack, could mount the kind of offensive that would even come close to equalizing the level of death, destruction and human misery that is being generated by substance abuse in this country.'' A black businessman, <PERSON> Barry </PERSON> <PERSON> Baszile </PERSON>, testified that drug dealers are entrepreneurs, too, and might turn to legal businessed if economic development funds were available in black communities. Two former rivals to <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, Sen. <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> and Rep. <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON>, said that to keep the White House, the Republicans must attract independent and cross-over Democratic voters. <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> told reporters flatly that he does not expect to be picked by <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> as a running mate, and predicted <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> would be. <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>, asked if he wanted the No. 2 job: `` I do n't think it's a question of wanting it. ... It's a question of winning the election, helping your party and trying to help your country. I'd want to be majority leader if I had my choice.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880701-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-01-88 0048EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-ElectricBoat     07-01 0497</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Electric Boat,0519</SECOND>
<HEAD>Electric Boat Employees Go On Strike</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LARRY ROSENTHAL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>GROTON, Conn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An estimated 10,200 Electric Boat employees went on strike at the company's shipyard here Friday after contract talks with the submarine builder broke down. `` We expect the strike to be strong and well-supported,'' said <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Manning </PERSON>, a lawyer for the <ORGANIZATION> Metal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Trades </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>. Electric Boat, a division of <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dynamics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, is one of only two shipyards making nuclear submarines for the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>, and the only manufacturer of subs capable of carrying the giant Trident ballistic missile. Talks broke down at 11:20 p.m. Thursday after a three-hour last-ditch effort, and the walkout began after midnight. No new talks were planned. Earlier in the day, the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> awarded this year's third and final SSN-688 fast-attack submarine contract to Electric Boat. The $ 347.4 million contract will go to EB's main shipyard in here and its other plant, in <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kingstown </LOCATION>, R.I. The strike does not affect the <LOCATION> Rhode </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> plant. In a letter to employees, shipyard General Manager <PERSON> Fritz </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Tovar </PERSON> said a strike will not stop submarine construction at the shipyard here. EB arranged to assign 3,000 salaried employees to shipyard jobs in the event of a strike. The two sides stalemated over the union's demand for percentage wage increases and the shipyard's insistence that it could afford no more than cash bonuses to remain competitive in its pursuit of <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> contracts. Union members voted earlier Thursday 4,921 to 3,140 to reject the company's latest offer but returned to the bargaining table with 4 -LCB- hours to go before the strike deadline in a last-ditch effort to reach a settlement. Talks began in November to replace a three-year contract that expired Friday. The last strike at the shipyard was in 1975, when the union walked out for five months and the region's economy sagged. In <LOCATION> Hartford </LOCATION>, state Labor Commissioner <PERSON> Betty </PERSON> <PERSON> Tianti </PERSON> said she would meet on Friday with members of the state's congressional delegation and others to see what could be done to lessen the economic impact of the strike. The union wanted straight hourly wage increases of 5 percent, 4 percent and 4 percent over three years. Electric Boat's `` last, best and final offer,'' presented Monday, calls for bonuses totaling $ 4,250 over three years for a first-class mechanic making $ 12.02 an hour, said <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Sotir </PERSON>, vice president of human resources. The company cited increased competition from the only other submarine shipyard in the country, the <ORGANIZATION> Newport </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Shipbuilding </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Drydock </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Newport </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION>, which pays its workers 60 cents an hour less than <ORGANIZATION> Electric </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Boat </ORGANIZATION>, recently won two contracts for nuclear attack submarines after it underbid Electric Boat. `` If the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> wants to get into the cheapest subs around, why do n't they get Yugos?'' said <PERSON> Wes </PERSON> <PERSON> Lamphere </PERSON>, 27, of <PERSON> Griswold </PERSON>, president of the foundry workers local. `` We do n't want to make a million bucks, we're not asking for the world. We just want to keep up.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880701-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-01-88 0050EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a PM-Names     07-01 0921</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0959</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in the News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actor <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Aykroyd </PERSON>'s wife, actress <PERSON> Donna </PERSON> <PERSON> Dixon </PERSON>, is expecting the couple's first child in January, a spokeswoman says. `` They're overjoyed,'' according to publicist <PERSON> Susan </PERSON> <PERSON> Patricola </PERSON>. <PERSON> Aykroyd </PERSON>, the 36-year-old former cast member of the `` Saturday Night Live'' television show and star of the current movie `` The Great Outdoors,'' met his wife during filming of the movie `` Dr. <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION>.'' Mrs. <PERSON> Aykroyd </PERSON>, 30, formerly of the <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> series `` Bosom Buddies,'' appears in the upcoming movie `` Mr. Christmas Dinner,'' Ms. <PERSON> Patricola </PERSON> said Thursday. The Aykroyds, who have been married five years, have homes in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A bevy of high-powered female celebrities, including Barbra Streisand, <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON> and <PERSON> Lucille </PERSON> <PERSON> Ball </PERSON>, were the first women elected to the <ORGANIZATION> Friar </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Club </ORGANIZATION> to comply with a recent <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> ruling. The 84-year-old private club's board of governors changed its constitution to allow female members and elected the women Thursday to honorary membership. Other newcomers were <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Sinatra </PERSON>, <PERSON> Carol </PERSON> <PERSON> Burnett </PERSON>, Eydie Gorme, <PERSON> Dinah </PERSON> <PERSON> Shore </PERSON>, <PERSON> Phyllis </PERSON> <PERSON> Diller </PERSON> and <PERSON> Martha </PERSON> <PERSON> Raye </PERSON>. <PERSON> Liza </PERSON> <PERSON> Minnelli </PERSON>, who applied for regular membership, was approved, according to <PERSON> Friar </PERSON>'s spokesman <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> Rylander </PERSON>. The club's decision to admit women followed a <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> ruling that upheld a <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> anti-discrimination law. The law prohibits private clubs from banning women. The <ORGANIZATION> Friar </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Club </ORGANIZATION> has more than 1,300 members in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, most of them active in the performing arts. <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Sinatra </PERSON> is its top officer, the abbot.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>CAPE TOWN, South Africa (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Anglican Archbishop <PERSON> Desmond </PERSON> <PERSON> Tutu </PERSON>, who has faced protesters at airports over the past month, says he filed a complaint with police against a white fellow plane passenger who harassed him. The Rev. <PERSON> Christopher </PERSON> <PERSON> Ahrends </PERSON>, an aide to the Nobel Peace Prize winner, said the incident occurred while he and <PERSON> Tutu </PERSON> were riding in an airport bus to their plane at <LOCATION> Jan </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Smuts </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Johannesburg </LOCATION> on Thursday. `` The man was with a number of other men on the bus. He seemed to be talking about the archbishop and the men were sniggering,'' Ahrends said. `` As we walked up the aircraft steps behind him, he turned around, looked down at the archbishop and said in a mocking tone, ` <PERSON> Hallo </PERSON> <PERSON> Desmond </PERSON>,''' Ahrends said. The archbishop, who is black, ignored the man, who persisted, using an obscenity in commenting on <PERSON> Tutu </PERSON>'s speeches about <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> overseas, <PERSON> Ahrends </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Tutu </PERSON> reported the encounter to a steward and later asked the abusive passenger his name as they disembarked, <PERSON> Ahrends </PERSON> said. The man, who spoke in <LOCATION> Afrikaans </LOCATION>, replied, `` I'm going to break your bloody neck,'' <PERSON> Ahrends </PERSON> said. The aide called a police officer and a complaint was made at the airport charge office. `` We will not tolerate threatening and abusive behavior towards the archbishop, who was clearly hurt by the incident,'' <PERSON> Ahrends </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>MONTPELIER, Vt. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Zaccaro </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, convicted of selling a quarter-gram of cocaine to an undercover officer, has won preliminary approval to serve his four-month sentence beginning today under house arrest. The son of former vice presidential candidate <PERSON> Geraldine </PERSON> <PERSON> Ferraro </PERSON> was to begin the sentence by 5 p.m., with his first 24 hours in maximum security at <ORGANIZATION> Chittenden </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Community </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Correctional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Burlington </LOCATION>, standard procedure for new inmates, said <ORGANIZATION> Addison </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION>'s Attorney <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Quinn </PERSON>. <PERSON> Zaccaro </PERSON>, 24, was sentenced two weeks ago, but the sentence was stayed 30 days pending appeal to the <ORGANIZATION> Vermont </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>. If an appeal had been granted, it may have been a year or more before the court decided the case. But <PERSON> Zaccaro </PERSON>'s lawyers dropped the request for the stay and asked that <PERSON> Zaccaro </PERSON> start serving his sentence today. Judge <PERSON> Francis </PERSON> <PERSON> McCaffrey </PERSON> agreed, deputy court clerk <PERSON> Kathy </PERSON> <PERSON> Moore </PERSON> said Thursday. <ORGANIZATION> Corrections </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Perry </PERSON> said <PERSON> Zaccaro </PERSON> had gained preliminary approval for a new state program under which he would live in a department-approved apartment and could leave only with permission. Under the program, <PERSON> Zaccaro </PERSON> could begin the 300 hours of community service his sentence entails. The judge fined <PERSON> Zaccaro </PERSON> $ 1,500 as well.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LEXINGTON, Ky. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A man accused of impersonating Grande Ole Opry singer <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Greene </PERSON> to buy a $ 700,000 horse farm and $ 350,000 worth of equipment has been arrested on forgery charges, police said. <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> <PERSON> Irving </PERSON> <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON> was being held in the <ORGANIZATION> Fayette </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Detention </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> on $ 3,000 cash bond pending grand jury action. <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON>, 55, was arrested June 17 at Blue Grass Airport, a week after police said he signed a contract, under the name of <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Greene </PERSON>, to purchase the farm in <LOCATION> Clark </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON> had been using his name for the past seven years, <PERSON> Greene </PERSON> said Wednesday. <PERSON> Dee </PERSON> <PERSON> Teater </PERSON>, a real estate agent, said she became suspicious after `` Greene'' agreed to buy the farm, ordered farm equipment and promised to have the money wired into an escrow account. It never arrived, and Ms. <PERSON> Teater </PERSON> said she telephoned <LOCATION> Nashville </LOCATION> and was told the real <PERSON> Greene </PERSON> was n't in <LOCATION> Lexington </LOCATION> but was performing at the Grand Ole Opry. Ms. <PERSON> Teater </PERSON> said she then went to the airport to meet <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON>, who was arrested by detectives who accompanied her.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Rep. <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON> <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> of <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> was in good condition after undergoing multiple bypass heart surgery. `` His condition is very good. He's been moved to a private room,'' <PERSON> Susan </PERSON> <PERSON> Tombrello </PERSON>, spokeswoman for <ORGANIZATION> Good </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Samaritan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION>, said Thursday. <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON>, 75, underwent the elective surgery Wednesday and was expected to return home to <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Pedro </LOCATION> by July 4, said his spokesman, <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Smallen </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880701-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-01-88 0230EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-PsychologicalTestimony Bjt   07-01 0786</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Psychological Testimony, Bjt,780</SECOND>
<HEAD>Study Shows Legal Testimony of Psychology Experts Often Wrong</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PAUL RECER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Science Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Courts trying to determine if defendants will commit violent crimes in the future would do just as well to flip a coin as to listen to the `` expert'' testimony of psychiatrists and psychologists, a study published today indicates. The inaccuracy of judgments by trained clinicians raises `` substantial doubt that psychologists or psychiatrists meet legal standards for expertise,'' says the report published in the journal Science. The study was conducted by <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Faust </PERSON>, an associate professor of psychology at <ORGANIZATION> Brown </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, and <PERSON> Jay </PERSON> <PERSON> Ziskin </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> lawyer and psychologist. They found that laymen without degrees or clinical experience often can make courtroom evaluations of violent defendants as accurately as psychologists and psychiatrists. And making decisions by just the flip of a coin, <PERSON> Faust </PERSON> said, often is more accurate than the judgments of the experts. Life or death decisions by juries may be influenced by psychological experts who are called to testify in criminal trials on the mental state of defendants, or their potential for violence. In many states, the punishment phase of capital murder trials takes into consideration a prediction of the continued violent behavior of the defendant. Prosecutors and defense lawyers frequently call on psychologists or psychiatrists for opinions. But <PERSON> Faust </PERSON>, in a telephone interview Thursday, said the accuracy of the these opinions is questionable. `` In many studies the error rate well exceeds the accuracy rate,'' <PERSON> Faust </PERSON> said. `` There is virtually no evidence that experts are any better equipped to make those judgments than are lay individuals.'' He said some studies have shown that experts are accurate in their predictions less than half the time. `` If you flip a coin, you ought to be right 50 percent of the time,'' said <PERSON> Faust </PERSON>. `` So there are studies showing accuracies of less than chance.'' Education, he said, often has little to do with predicting violent behavior. `` One study using high school students showed that their accuracy was similar to that of experts in predicting violent behavior,'' <PERSON> Faust </PERSON> said. In the Science article, <PERSON> Faust </PERSON> and <PERSON> Ziskin </PERSON> cited a series of studies that they said showed `` clinicians are wrong at least twice as often as they are correct'' in predicting violent behavior. They said one study followed 967 patients who had been placed in maximum security hospitals on the basis of a psychiatric determination of dangerousness. They later were transferred to ordinary mental hospitals. After four years, only half of the group was still in the hospitals and only 26 patients who had been judged potentially violent had actually committed violent acts during that time. In the article, the authors said they conducted their research to learn if expert psychological witnesses achieve `` reasonable certainty'' of facts and aid in establishing the truth in trials. `` The scientific evidence clearly suggests that clinicians fail to satisfy either legal standard for expertise,'' they said. Psychological clinicians often are unable to agree on diagnoses, `` much less provide trustworthy answers to ... more difficult forensic questions, which often demand projections backward and forward in time,'' the article said. Expert testimony often can have what the article called `` a prejudicial effect on juries.'' `` Confidence and accuracy can be inversely related, and yet the jury may well accept the opinion of an expert who exudes confidence over that of an opposing expert who expresses appropriate caution,'' the authors said. Evidence from experts, they said, `` is readily subject to abuse'' due to subjectivity and bias. `` The involvement of experts wastes many hours of already too scarce court time and costs taxpayers millions of dollars,'' the article says. When an expert testifies that a psychologist or psychiatrist can predict violent behavior `` he endorses a falsehood'' and could create the risk for malpractice suits against colleagues, the researchers said. <PERSON> Faust </PERSON>, in the interview, said he has testified as an expert in trials in the past, but now refuses to do so because of his belief that his science, at its present state of development, is unable to achieve the expected level of accuracy. Other experts said the question of reliability of psychological testimony has been a matter of controversy, but that it is not clear that such expertise is as unreliable as <PERSON> Faust </PERSON> and <PERSON> Ziskin </PERSON> contend. `` I do n't know of an opinion like that that is generally accepted in the scientific community,'' said <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Miller </PERSON>, a professor of psychology at <ORGANIZATION> George </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. `` That is a controversial position.'' Dr. <PERSON> Jon </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Brien </PERSON>, a forensic psychiatry expert at <ORGANIZATION> Georgetown </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, said, `` no professional could give a guarantee that an individual will or will not act violently.'' But he said trials can still benefit from the testimony of experts.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880701-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-01-88 0231EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-BlackBoxes-Commuters     07-01 0328</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Black Boxes-Commuters,330</SECOND>
<HEAD>Commuter Planes to Have `Black Box' Recorders</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By H. JOSEF HEBERT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
