<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880922-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-22-88 2352EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Burma 1stLd-Writethru a0684 09-22 0886</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Burma, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0684,0907</SECOND>
<HEAD>Opposition Leaders Ask Military Rulers To Stop Arrests</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: INSERTS 1 graf after 4th pvs `Ne Win...' UPDATING with U.S.
cutting off all but humanitarian aid. Pickup 5th pvs `A letter...'</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By SEIN WIN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>RANGOON, Burma (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Opposition leaders demanded Thursday that government troops stop arresting pro-democracy <ORGANIZATION> Buddhist </ORGANIZATION> monks and students after military ruler <PERSON> Gen </PERSON>. Saw <PERSON> Maung </PERSON> pledged to hold elections as soon as peace is restored. The capital was quiet for the third day since troops ruthlessly suppressed protests against the military coup that <PERSON> Saw </PERSON> <PERSON> Maung </PERSON> led Sunday. <PERSON> Saw </PERSON> <PERSON> Maung </PERSON>, who became prime minister Wednesday, is the third new leader in two months of chaos and bloodshed. Like the two government heads before him, he is closely associated with Ne Win, who seized power in 1962. Ne Win resigned in late July after widespread protests against 26 years of authoritarian rule that plunged resource-rich <LOCATION> Burma </LOCATION> into poverty. His successor, <PERSON> Sein </PERSON> <PERSON> Lwin </PERSON>, lasted for 17 days of massive street protests. The next ruler, President <PERSON> Maung </PERSON> <PERSON> Maung </PERSON>, was a civilian but was seen as close to the military. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> said Thursday it was cutting off all aid to <LOCATION> Burma </LOCATION> except humanitarian assistance. <PERSON> Rudi </PERSON> <PERSON> Boone </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> spokesman in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, said he believed <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> aid to <LOCATION> Burma </LOCATION> totaled $ 12.3 million, but he did not know how much of the aid is humanitarian. A letter sent to <PERSON> Saw </PERSON> <PERSON> Maung </PERSON> on Thursday from opposition leaders <PERSON> Aung </PERSON> <PERSON> Gyi </PERSON>, Tin Oo, and <PERSON> Aung </PERSON> <PERSON> San </PERSON> <PERSON> Suu </PERSON> <PERSON> Kyi </PERSON> urged the government `` not to arrest people including the monks, students, artists, etc., in connection with the recent unrest and also to release those already under detention.'' Since the coup, security forces have broken up protest centers manned mostly by monks and students in at least 95 towns. They have reported only eight arrests in those sweeps. The government also said security forces arrested 100 people in <LOCATION> Rangoon </LOCATION>; they were described as looters. The opposition figures also urged <PERSON> Saw </PERSON> <PERSON> Maung </PERSON>, who was armed forces commander before the coup, to end his ban on newspapers and announce a list of casualties in shooting. The government has acknowledged security forces killed at least 146 people since the coup, but a <LOCATION> Western </LOCATION> diplomat put the figure as high as 400, including many unarmed pro-democracy demonstrators. Opposition leaders did not reply to <PERSON> Saw </PERSON> <PERSON> Maung </PERSON>'s letter received Wednesday in which he said the army does not intend to hold onto power for long and asked for help to prepare for what would be the first multiparty elections since 1960. `` The army has no intention to retain the duties of state power for a long time, in addition to its existing onerous duties. We had to step in unavoidably because of the deteriorating general conditions in the country,'' said the letter, <PERSON> Saw </PERSON> <PERSON> Maung </PERSON>'s first contact with the opposition leadership. `` We promise you that free and fair general elections will be held as soon as peace and tranquillity is restored in the country.'' The letter added that political parties will be allowed to use government radio and television for their campaigns. But <PERSON> Saw </PERSON> <PERSON> Maung </PERSON> did not set a date for the promised elections. <PERSON> Maung </PERSON> <PERSON> Maung </PERSON>, a civilian who was briefly president before being ousted in Sunday's coup, bowed to massive street protests and agreed to end one-party rule and hold multiparty elections as soon as early October. But the opposition rejected that formula and instead continued street demonstrations demanding an interim government be formed to conduct the balloting. In <LOCATION> Rangoon </LOCATION>, more roadside shops were open Thursday than the previous day, but large markets remained closed. The doors of government offices were open, but no one was working. Most public employees have been on pro-democracy strikes since Aug. 8 and the government has set an Oct. 3 deadline for them to return to work. Sketchy reports received from <LOCATION> Mandalay </LOCATION>, the second-largest city, and other towns indicated security forces and protesters fought this week, though not as fierce as in the capital. State radio said security forces arrested eight people Wednesday night in a sweep of the protest center at <ORGANIZATION> Mandalay </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> and killed two other people in separate incidents in the city. <LOCATION> Mandalay </LOCATION> is about 350 miles north of <LOCATION> Rangoon </LOCATION>. Also Wednesday night, a group of people sent about 50 water buffaloes after soldiers on the Mandalay Golf Course and attacked the troops with catapults and metal darts. The radio said the attackers escaped but five buffaloes were reported killed. A diplomat said a few <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> officials in <LOCATION> Rangoon </LOCATION> would be evacuated to <LOCATION> Bangkok </LOCATION> in the next few days. More than 100 dependents of staff members were evacuated earlier. `` The embassy remains open. This is as a precaution,'' said <PERSON> Ross </PERSON> <PERSON> Petzing </PERSON>, spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Bangkok </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> expressed concern Thursday about political developments in <LOCATION> Burma </LOCATION> and said it would wait to decide whether to recognize the new military government. <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION> is the largest foreign aid donor to <LOCATION> Rangoon </LOCATION> although official assistance has dropped recently. <LOCATION> Burma </LOCATION>, once the world's largest rice exporter, last year joined 40 other countries officially designated by the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> as `` least developed nation.'' Officials said the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> and the European Economic community protested the recent bloodshed. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> earlier said it might withdraw aid in light of the military coup and bloodshed.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880922-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-22-88 0242EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-AtlantaSkyline     09-22 0849</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Atlanta Skyline,0873</SECOND>
<HEAD>New Buildings Changing Atlanta's Skyline, Giving City Respect</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By MARC RICE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ATLANTA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A new generation of skyscrapers is about to alter the skyline of <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>, previously dismissed as sterile and nondescript. Even homegrown architect <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Portman </PERSON>, whose glass towers and soaring atriums for years defined <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> and who in the past criticized post-modern architecture as a step backward, has given a nod to the style in his latest project, a 60-story office building planned for downtown <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>. Much of the excitement over the pending transformation of the capital of the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> started last fall with the opening of the 50-story <ORGANIZATION> IBM </ORGANIZATION> building. Officially called One <ORGANIZATION> Atlantic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>, it is a slender, post-modern tower of stone with tall arched entryways and Gothic finials, dramatically crowned by a 100-foot-high, eight-sided copper pyramid topped by a golden lantern. Rush-hour traffic on Interstate 85 slows to a cautious crawl as drivers gaze its way. At night, the lights in its crown command attention from all over town. Architecture writers have used words like `` gracious,'' `` truly wonderful,'' `` serene,'' `` imposing'' and `` glamorous'' to describe the tower. `` It certainly projects a vibrance to the rest of the world,'' said <PERSON> Roy </PERSON> <PERSON> Cooper </PERSON>, vice president for economic development with the <ORGANIZATION> Atlanta </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chamber </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION>. `` It's just beautiful. Everybody's just staggered by it. The tower is a dramatic departure from the glass boxes common in modern architecture and contrasts with the sleek look of most of the city's tallest buildings. Its influence shows up in at least three other skyscrapers going up in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>, and the design of the proposed Promenade skyscraper complex was altered to complement the rose-colored <ORGANIZATION> IBM </ORGANIZATION> tower. <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> architect <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Burgee </PERSON>, whose firm designed the <ORGANIZATION> IBM </ORGANIZATION> building with design consultant <PERSON> Philip </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>, wo n't take credit for transforming <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>'s skyline. But he said the city's image, as defined by the way it looks, is undergoing a change. `` <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> has been looking for its identity,'' <PERSON> Burgee </PERSON> said in a telephone interview from his <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> office. `` It's an historical city -LRB- but -RRB- its architecture and image is not strictly historical. You think of <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> and you think of ` Gone With The Wind.' Now, there is an attempt to come up with a visual image. `` We all know <LOCATION> Peachtree </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Street </LOCATION>, but you do n't think of its buildings,'' he said. `` Like in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, the Empire State Building; <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Sears </ORGANIZATION> building; <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> TransAmerica </ORGANIZATION> building. <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> does n't have that. It's moving toward that, very definitely.'' <PERSON> Burgee </PERSON> and <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> also are behind One Ninety One Peachtree Tower, a post-modern skyscraper planned for downtown <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>. Another planned project grouped in the `` Son of <ORGANIZATION> IBM </ORGANIZATION>'' building spurt is the Promenade in the tree-lined, historic Midtown section, a complex of three office buildings and a hotel being developed by <ORGANIZATION> AT </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; T and the Atlanta-based <ORGANIZATION> Landmarks </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Group </ORGANIZATION>. When unveiled last year, it was designed with an exterior of glittering green glass. But when Promenade officials saw the excitement over the nearby <ORGANIZATION> IBM </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tower </ORGANIZATION>, its architects, <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Ventulett </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> Stainback </PERSON>, redrew the plans to use rose glass above rose-toned stone and topped with a gray steel spire. The most recently announced skyscraper is a downtown giant by <PERSON> Portman </PERSON>, whose imprint is already deeply felt in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>, primarily through the <ORGANIZATION> Peachtree </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> and the towering cylindrical Westin Peachtree Plaza Hotel. <PERSON> Portman </PERSON>'s new building is slated to begin construction next year and, at 60 stories, will eclipse One <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> as the Southeast's tallest building Unveiling the design in May, <PERSON> Portman </PERSON> said it was `` respectful of the past but, like this city, is audacious and bold and forward-looking _ the beginning of post-post-modern architecture.'' <PERSON> Dale </PERSON> <PERSON> Durfee </PERSON>, a professor of architecture at <ORGANIZATION> Georgia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tech </ORGANIZATION>, said completion of the <ORGANIZATION> IBM </ORGANIZATION> tower signaled the acceleration of a change in the look of the city that began a decade ago. `` <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> was pretty much plain vanilla,'' he said, `` with no development of architectural significance.'' <PERSON> Burgee </PERSON> echoed that appraisal, saying, `` It was pretty nondescript. It might be anyplace. If they took you -LRB- to <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> -RRB- blindfolded and took off the blindfold, you would n't have a clue where you are.'' <PERSON> Durfee </PERSON> said that 10 years ago, <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> was groping to form an identity and had no demand for the type of buildings now are going up. Today, however, companies want sophistication in their office buildings, <PERSON> Durfee </PERSON> said, and corporate sponsorship of building projects has changed the rules of skyscraper financing. Some say that all the building activity simply makes good business sense. `` Sure, there's competitive prestige. Good architecture is good business,'' said <PERSON> Truman </PERSON> <PERSON> Hartshorn </PERSON>, chairman of the geography department at <ORGANIZATION> Georgia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> and a specialist in urban affairs. A good-looking building, he said, `` is easier to sell to the financing people as well as the tenants.'' <PERSON> Hartshorn </PERSON> said he expects the new projects in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> will bring special recognition. `` I think it's going to open some eyes,'' he said. `` We have prestige with our cultural buildings, but I do n't know that our office buildings are that distinctive nationally. `` These are n't just ultra post-modern. They're classic. They're different.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880922-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-22-88 0143EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lites     09-22 0406</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lites,0419</SECOND>
<HEAD>On the Light Side</HEAD>
<DATELINE>AUSTIN, Texas (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 State employees wo n't be dialing for dollars any longer after their attempts to cash in on a $ 1,000 radio call-in contest brought the Capitol's telephone system to a crashing halt. `` I guess the economy is so bad in <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> that everybody is trying to get money,'' <PERSON> Carl </PERSON> <PERSON> Stringfellow </PERSON>, state director of telecommunications, said Tuesday. `` But you should n't be using state phones to be calling on to radio contests.'' Officials reset the phone system to prevent any calls to the exchange set aside for radio call-in contests after service was disrupted several times, <PERSON> Stringfellow </PERSON> said. `` We thought we had just had an equipment failure,'' he said. `` But the second time it went down one of our employees suggested it was at the same time as one of the radio contests.'' Officials discovered the phone failure occurred within a minute of the start of a contest by a local radio station offering a $ 1,000 prize. The Capitol phone system has about 14,000 lines, and its usual capacity is about 2,000 calls at any time. But the radio contest bumped the phone traffic up to 8,000 calls, <PERSON> Stringfellow </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>OXFORD, Ohio (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Forget about toga parties. <ORGANIZATION> Miami </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> students have come up with something more relevant for the 1980s and this presidential year _ the Pledge party. As in Pledge of Allegiance, of course. Police were responding for the second time to noise complaints about a party at a student's house when <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> junior <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> LeBoeuf </PERSON> led 150 to 200 revelers in the Pledge. `` I thought it'd be funny,'' said <PERSON> LeBoeuf </PERSON>, who led the group from a trough containing beer kegs and ice. `` What are the police going to do with 200 people standing around saying the pledge _ arrest them for being patriotic?'' No, but they did cite host Kimberly A. Mart for violating the city's noise ordinance after the patriotic partyers pushed police noise meters over the town's 70-decibel limit. The citation, the second given for the Sept. 10 party, could cost Mart $ 128. She was scheduled to appear in court on Tuesday for the misdemeanor violation. `` The officers were kind of laughing when they took the meter reading,'' said <PERSON> Karen </PERSON> <PERSON> Stevens </PERSON>, 21, who lives at the house. `` People were n't saying it in any hostile way. They had smiles on their faces and some had hands over their hearts. No big deal, we thought.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880922-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-22-88 0242EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Italy-Mafia     09-22 0253</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Italy-Mafia,0261</SECOND>
<HEAD>Leading Mafia Investigator Agrees to Stay On</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ROME (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>'s top Mafia investigator has withdrawn his resignation, alleviating a crisis in the country's war on organized crime. <PERSON> Giovanni </PERSON> <PERSON> Falcone </PERSON>, an investigating magistrate in the Sicilian capital of <LOCATION> Palermo </LOCATION>, had charged when he offered his resignation July 30 that Mafia investigations were obstructed. He also said his methods `` differ radically'' from those of his superior, <PERSON> Antonino </PERSON> <PERSON> Meli </PERSON>, who was appointed chief investigating magistrate of the anti-Mafia judicial `` pool'' in February. <PERSON> Falcone </PERSON> asked for a transfer and the other members of the pool then announced their resignations. A former colleague of <PERSON> Falcone </PERSON> charged in July that <PERSON> Meli </PERSON> was weakening the pool by assigning its judges non-Mafia cases and sending Mafia cases to investigators outside the pool. <PERSON> Falcone </PERSON> told judicial officials Wednesday that he was staying on `` in conformance with the ruling'' last week by the <ORGANIZATION> Superior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Magistrates </ORGANIZATION>, the national judicial watchdog that appointed <PERSON> Meli </PERSON>. The council, praising the pool's work, found that <PERSON> Meli </PERSON> did not divert cases and called on <PERSON> Falcone </PERSON> not to quit. Magistrates in the pool, especially <PERSON> Falcone </PERSON>, have been credited for some of the country's biggest successes against organized crime, including the `` maxi'' anti-Mafia trial that ended in December with 338 convictions. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> authorities say <PERSON> Falcone </PERSON> provided critical help in investigations such as the one leading to the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> trial of suspects in the case of the `` Pizza Connection,'' which discovered that pizza parlors in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> were used as fronts for heroin dealing.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880922-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-22-88 0013EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-ShootingProtest 4thLd-Writethru a0770 09-22 1106</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Shooting Protest, 4th Ld-Writethru, a0770,1137</SECOND>
<HEAD>Tension Runs High after Louisiana Racial Disturbance</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Leads with 8 grafs to UPDATE with sporadic gunfire heard,
secured area expanded; CORRECTS that Shreveport is Louisiana's
third-largest city, sted second largest; picks up 3rd graf: ``We're
sitting ...; EDITS to conform.</NOTE>
<HEAD>LaserPhotos SHJ1,2</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KEVIN McGILL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SHREVEPORT, La. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Heavily armed police sealed off a 12-block area Wednesday night after hearing sporadic gunfire in a riot-scarred neighborhood where a white woman allegedly shot a black man to death 24 hours earlier. An emergency zone was expanded late Wednesday night in the <LOCATION> Cedar </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Grove </LOCATION> section soon after police rerouted traffic off a busy thoroughfare where blacks were throwing rocks, bottles and bricks at passing cars. No injuries or serious damages were reported Wednesday night, and there were no arrests immediately reported in <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION>'s third-largest city The white woman was accused of murder in Tuesday night's shooting and six blacks were arrested during the rioting that followed, police said Mayor <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Hussey </PERSON> said the strategy Wednesday night was to wait out troublemakers. Scores of police cars, a busload of camouflaged Special Response Team officers and canine units were stationed at a command post nearby. `` The shooting that we have is sporadic,'' said <PERSON> Hussey </PERSON>. `` It's still very much in a local area The idea is to seal off the area. If you seal it off, do n't let any cars through, then there's nothing for them to throw at. Though the atmosphere was tense, Police Chief <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Gruber </PERSON> said it was nothing like what the city faced after the earlier rioting. Wednesday night's violence occurred hours after black leaders called for <LOCATION> Cedar </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Grove </LOCATION> residents to stay calm and guard against a recurrence of the burning and looting late Tuesday night and early Wednesday. `` We're sitting on a powder keg,'' said state Rep. <PERSON> Alphonse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, who called for a biracial anti-crime committee. `` People want protection,'' said <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, who is black. `` I call on citizens to restore law and order.'' His plea followed a meeting of city officials and black leaders to discuss the rioting that persisted nearly five hours, until 3 a.m. Wednesday, and which officials said was related both to drugs and racial problems. Stores were looted and burned, and rioters threw rocks and bottles at whites. There were reports of racial slurs and chants of `` Hot Biscuit,'' the restaurant where a white teen-ager killed a black teen-ager on Aug. 4, an incident that set off racial tension in this northwestern <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION> city of 250,000, the state's third-largest after <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Baton </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rouge </LOCATION> <PERSON> Hussey </PERSON> and <PERSON> Gruber </PERSON> acknowledged at a news conference that the sparks for the riots were the two shootings, but both said there were deeper causes. `` We've got problems in our economy, we've got problems in our racism, we've got many other problems,'' said <PERSON> Hussey </PERSON>, adding that drinking and a soured drug deal preceded Tuesday's shooting. The Rev. <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>, pastor of <ORGANIZATION> Galilee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Baptist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION>, appeared with <PERSON> Hussey </PERSON> and <PERSON> Gruber </PERSON>. <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> said he and other black leaders believe the chief deserves credit for ordering officers to pull out of the riot area so the crowd could disperse without bloodshed. `` We are asking our young people to remain at home as much as possible, to dig in to their books and not to look for any excitement,'' said <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Baptist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Convention </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, the nation's second-largest black Baptist organization. On Tuesday night, police cordoned off a seven-block area and warned motorists to keep out. The crowd reached 1,000 people at its peak, said <PERSON> Gruber </PERSON>, but other police estimates said the total was 300 to 500 most of the time. The police chief said his car took a brick through the windshield and gunfire through the back passenger door, but he was not hurt. A KTBS-TV news car was burned and a new fire department pumper was attacked with bats and bricks. No serious injuries were reported, attributed in part to <PERSON> Gruber </PERSON>'s decision to let the disturbance run its course. Throughout the incident, police radios crackled with orders to maintain positions and hold fire. `` If <PERSON> Gruber </PERSON> had moved into the area, we would have had a large number of people hurt, so I commend him for it,'' said <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>. `` We chose to let it cool off,'' <PERSON> Gruber </PERSON> said. `` We felt our presence would do nothing but accelerate it.'' Six people were arrested, five on charges ranging from inciting to riot to resisting arrest, and two of those and one other person on on charges of possession of stolen goods. The outbreak was triggered by the shooting of a black man, identified as <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> McKinney </PERSON>, 20, who lived in the <LOCATION> Cedar </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Grove </LOCATION> neighborhood where the rioting took place. He was described by a witness as a bystander caught in gunfire when a drug deal went bad. A white teen-ager, <PERSON> Tamala </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Vergo </PERSON>, 17, of <PERSON> Greenwood </PERSON> was booked on a charge of second-degree murder, said police Cpl. E.T. Rushing. A second woman was questioned but not charged. A man who identified himself only as a cousin of <PERSON> McKinney </PERSON>'s named <PERSON> Charles </PERSON>, said <PERSON> McKinney </PERSON> was shot at random after a woman trying to buy cocaine from a group of men was robbed When they ran with her purse, she `` took out her frustration'' on <PERSON> McKinney </PERSON>, he said. The man talked to reporters after being interviewed by detectives. Officers said people in a convenience store tried to detain the woman until police came, but a crowd of blacks gathered outside and began throwing bricks at the business and all passing motorists who were white. A witness, <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>, said that after police took the women away, the crowd doused the store with lighter fluid, set it afire and went on a rampage. The building, containing the store and a liquor shop, was burned to the ground. Patients and workers at Eden Gardens Nursing Center, across the street, watched the burning and looting. `` Some of the guys had so much stuff in their bags they could n't walk,'' said <PERSON> Betty </PERSON> <PERSON> Truett </PERSON>, a nurse Looting and fires also were reported in other stores in the area. About 200 police were called in, <PERSON> Gruber </PERSON> said, including state troopers, sheriff's deputies, and officers from nearby <LOCATION> Bossier </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. In the Aug. 4 shooting, five white men were arrested and one admitted the shooting, saying he was defending himself. He is being held on $ 250,000 bond on second-degree murder charges. Charges against three of the others were dropped in return for their cooperation. The shooting enraged <LOCATION> Shreveport </LOCATION>'s black community, but calm prevailed when black ministers exhorted congregations to let police handle the investigation.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880922-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-22-88 0239EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-SummerSummary Bjt   09-22 0810</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Summer Summary, Bjt,790</SECOND>
<HEAD>Surprise: Summer Was Hot, Dry for Most Americans</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RANDOLPH E. SCHMID</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 When the autumn equinox bids farewell to summer today, millions of scorched Americans likely will be glad to see it go. It was a bummer summer, in the words of one headline writer, a season that saw millions of dollars lost in dying crops, rivers and reservoirs dry up and air conditioning bills go through the roof. According to the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Oceanic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Atmospheric </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>, only the Dust Bowl of the 1930s raised the nation's average temperature to higher levels than this summer Some communities may take pride in setting records for greatest average heat _ or most 90 degree days or least rain. But that does n't mean many want to see a return of the record-setting misery anytime soon. The <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> estimates that heat coupled with extraordinary dryness cut grain production by 31 percent, threatening many farmers with financial disaster. And the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Geological Survey noted that low water levels curtailed irrigation and river traffic and raised pollution levels in some areas. Wildfires swept large areas, discouraging tourists, scorching homes and forests. And even something as simple as keeping cool had a significant impact, with the cost of running air conditioners pushing the national electric bill up to $ 14.4 billion, some $ 746 million more than it would have been in normal summer weather. National statistics, though, obscure the impact of the hot, dry season, which differed in degree and response from town to town, but which was bad news nearly everywhere. From <LOCATION> Minneapolis </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Baltimore </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Cheyenne </LOCATION> the summer of 1988 was the hottest in local climate records going back nearly 40 years. And by that same standard, the drought played to record levels in <LOCATION> Peoria </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION>, Billings, <LOCATION> Mont. </LOCATION>, and <LOCATION> Asheville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.C. </LOCATION> `` Abnormally hot weather during much of June-August in the <LOCATION> Great </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Basin </LOCATION>, southern Intermountain Region, northern halves of the <ORGANIZATION> Rockies </ORGANIZATION> and <LOCATION> Great </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Plains </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Midwest </LOCATION> sent seasonal temperatures averaging more than 4 degrees Fahrenheit above normal,'' the federal Climate Analysis Center said. The summer's greatest heat focused on the region from central <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION> and northern <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION> eastward to lower <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION>, with hundreds of record highs and many cities setting records for consecutive days of 90 degrees or more. It was the warmest summer in the last 58 years in the east north central states and the third warmest in the west north central region and the Mountain states. Drought, meanwhile, struck in the spring and persisted through much of the summer in the northern <LOCATION> Great </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Plains </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> valleys. By mid-July, about 45 percent of the 48 contiguous states were experiencing severe or extreme drought. Increased thunderstorm activity in the eastern portion of the drought area eased the problem somewhat in late July and August, but even so, several cities set records for dryness. Climate experts compile local records in 30-year chunks and use the period from 1951-1980 as a standard for comparison for current trends. They define summer as June, July and August. On that basis, at least seven cities recorded their driest summer. They include <LOCATION> Asheville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.C. </LOCATION>, 5.39 inches of precipitation; <LOCATION> Peoria </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ill. </LOCATION>, 3.04 inches; <PERSON> Sheridan </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Wyo. </LOCATION>, 0.91 inches; <PERSON> Havre </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Mont. </LOCATION>, 0.20 inches; <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION>, 6.14 inches; <LOCATION> Rockford </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ill. </LOCATION>, 4.81 inches; and Billings, <LOCATION> Mont. </LOCATION>, 0.59 inches. For <LOCATION> Peoria </LOCATION>, for example, that represented only 27 percent of normal rainfall for the season. Even more cities set records for the highest average summer temperature since 1951, ranging from 86.7 in <LOCATION> Tucson </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ariz. </LOCATION>, to 68.4 in <LOCATION> Cheyenne </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wyo </LOCATION>. Average temperatures are derived from daily highs and lows, and the readings climbed as much as 6 degrees Fahrenheit above normal. <PERSON> Sheridan </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Wyo. </LOCATION>, for example., was 6.3 degrees above normal, while at Billings, <LOCATION> Mont. </LOCATION>, the average was high by 5.8 degrees Others among the communities setting record high average temperatures for this summer were <LOCATION> Newark </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.J. </LOCATION>, 77.7; <LOCATION> Salt </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, 77.5; <LOCATION> Baltimore </LOCATION>, 77.2; <LOCATION> Sioux </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Falls </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> S.D. </LOCATION>, 76.1; <LOCATION> Dayton </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, 75.6; <LOCATION> Minneapolis </LOCATION>, 75.6; <LOCATION> Huron </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> S.D. </LOCATION>, 75.2; <LOCATION> Waterloo </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>, 75.0; Billings, <LOCATION> Mont. </LOCATION>, 74.7. Also, <LOCATION> Rapid </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> S.D. </LOCATION>, 74.7; <LOCATION> Dubuque </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>, 74.3; <LOCATION> Fargo </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.D. </LOCATION>, 73.8; <LOCATION> Milwaukee </LOCATION>, 73.8; <LOCATION> Williston </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.D. </LOCATION>, 73.0; Lander, <LOCATION> Wyo. </LOCATION>, 72.9; <PERSON> Sheridan </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Wyo. </LOCATION>, 72.9; <LOCATION> Akron </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, 72.7; Casper, <LOCATION> Wyo. </LOCATION>, 72.0; <PERSON> Reno </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Nev. </LOCATION>, 71.6; and <LOCATION> Green </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wis. </LOCATION>, 71.2. As if to prove there are exceptions to every rule, some communities had cool and wet summers. <LOCATION> Albuquerque </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.M. </LOCATION>, for example, recorded 6.81 inches of rainfall this summer, a record at 208 percent of normal for the period. Summer rainfall totaled more than 47 inches at <ORGANIZATION> Homestead </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Base </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>, although there are no historical records for comparison. Such places as <LOCATION> Pensacola </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Palm </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION>, however, topped 30 inches, which was more than 150 percent of normal. And <PERSON> Meacham </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Ore. </LOCATION>, managed an average summer temperature of only 56.3 degrees, 3.6 degrees below normal.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880922-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-22-88 0240EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-SmartAmericans Bjt   09-22 0704</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Smart Americans, Bjt,700</SECOND>
<HEAD>U.S. Sets Record for High School, College Grads</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RANDOLPH E. SCHMID</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 More Americans have high school diplomas and college degrees than ever before, reflecting a continuing emphasis on education in society, a new <ORGANIZATION> Census </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> study shows. `` The entire post-Second World War era has been characterized by an expansion of educational opportunities and structures in the country,'' Census demographer <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Kominski </PERSON> commented. His new study of educational attainment found that, as of March 1987, more than three-quarters of people aged 25 and over have completed high school and nearly one in five has finished at least four years of college. Both shares have been increasing gradually over the years, said <PERSON> Kominski </PERSON>. `` In the 1960s the civil rights movement added another level of opportunity. And the expansion of college grant and aid programs in the'60s and'70s allowed this to continue,'' he said. <PERSON> Kominski </PERSON> added that changes in the age breakdown of the population have also had an impact on education averages, as the less educated elderly are replaced by younger people who have spent more time in school. For example, people in their teens, with 80 percent to 90 percent completing high school, are replacing older folks who were raised at a time when completion of six to eight years of schooling was a major accomplishment, he explained. Does this mean that Americans today are smarter than in the past? `` Not necessarily,'' <PERSON> Kominski </PERSON> said. `` We all like to think that we were raised in the generation which produced the best and the brightest.'' The study found that, overall, 75.6 percent of Americans have completed high school and 19.9 percent had finished four years of college. That was up from 74.7 percent and 19.4 percent a year earlier and 68.6 percent and 17.0 percent in 1980. By comparison, in 1940 only 24.5 percent of Americans aged 25 and older had completed high school and 4.6 percent were college graduates. The 1987 report also noted that males were slightly more likely to have finished high school than women, 76.0 percent to 75.3 percent, a change from the early 1970s when women led in this category. The shift is largely attributed to increasing share of black men pursuing their educations, <PERSON> Kominski </PERSON> said. In 1971, he pointed out, the last time women led men in overall share of high school graduates, young black women aged 25 to 29 led men 60.7 percent to 54.1 percent in high school graduates. Last year among young blacks 84.8 percent of males and 82.1 percent of women had finished high school. Other findings for the population aged 25 and over included: _ Whites had 77.0 percent high school graduates and 20.5 percent who finished four years of college. The figures for blacks were 63.4 percent and 10.7 percent. Other races, mostly Asians, had 78.4 percent high school grads and 33.4 percent who finished college. _ Hispanics recorded 50.9 percent who finished high school and 8.6 percent with college degrees. _ The West has the highest educational levels at 80.6 percent high school and 22.8 percent with college degrees. Figures for other regions were 76.5 percent and 22.2 percent in the East; 77.4 percent and 17.6 percent in the <LOCATION> Midwest </LOCATION>, and 70.8 percent and 18.3 percent in the South. _ In metropolitan areas 77.6 percent had finished high school and 22.1 percent college, compared to 68.7 percent and 12.6 percent in rural regions. _ The highest rate of high school graduates was for people aged 25 to 34 with 86.5 percent. That slipped to 85.9 percent in the 35 to 44 group, 77.6 percent for those aged 45 to 54, and 67.8 percent for people aged 55 to 64. Americans aged 65 to 74 included 56.9 percent high school graduates, and over age 75 the rate was 42.0 percent. _ Those finishing college totaled 23.9 percent in the 25 to 34 age group, then peaked at 26.5 percent among people aged 35 to 44. After that the rate declined, to 19.5 percent for those aged 45 to 54, 14.9 percent for the 55 to 64 group, 10.6 percent for those 65 to 74, and over 75 it was 8.9 percent.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880922-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-22-88 0203EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Greece-HolyIsland     09-22 0665</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Greece-Holy Island,0683</SECOND>
<HEAD>Greek Island of Patmos Holds Out against Nudity, Nightclubs</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report; note Sept. 25-26 dates in 2nd
graf from end.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By KERIN HOPE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PATMOS, Greece (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Nightclubs and nudity are banned on this island where tradition holds that St. <PERSON> John </PERSON> wrote the New Testament's Book of Revelation in a cave overlooking the <LOCATION> Aegean </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sea </LOCATION>. Under a special government decree, <LOCATION> Patmos </LOCATION> has a unique status among <LOCATION> Greece </LOCATION>'s 200 or so inhabited islands as a `` holy island'' still dominated by its 900-year-old Byzantine monastery. `` We prefer our visitors to be pilgrims rather than ordinary tourists and we would like them to respect our tradition,'' <PERSON> Abbot </PERSON> <PERSON> Isidoros </PERSON>, who heads the 30-member community at the Monastery of <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> John </ORGANIZATION> the Theologian, said in an interview. But plans for an airport coupled with widespread publicity for the monastery's 900th anniversary celebrations are expected to bring mass tourism to <LOCATION> Patmos </LOCATION> in the coming years. The tranquillity of <LOCATION> Patmos </LOCATION>, a rocky outcrop in the Dodecanese group of islands with around 2,000 residents, attracts wealthy Greeks and foreigners who have restored scores of traditional mansions clustered beneath the monastery's gray fortress-like walls. Many have given donations to the monastery, to help maintain its library of rare manuscripts and early books, along with a collection of priceless icons _ portraits of saints painted in gold and bright colors. `` <LOCATION> Patmos </LOCATION> is still a place apart, with a unique atmosphere. Unlike other islands, a conscious effort has been made to protect it,'' said <PERSON> Maria </PERSON> <PERSON> King </PERSON> <PERSON> Constantinides </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> antiques dealer with a family home there. Signs in Greek, French, German or English scattered around the island's beaches point out that nudity is not allowed. One disco operates on a remote bay, but the narrow alleys around the monastery fall silent by 10 p.m., even in summer. `` People sometimes go topless on the beaches, but ... on the whole the rules are respected,'' said <PERSON> Christos </PERSON> <PERSON> Kyrozis </PERSON>, the island's doctor and also its mayor. The development project planned by <LOCATION> Greece </LOCATION>'s state tourist organization EOT, together with the monastery and town authorities, calls for construction of an airport, zoning for new hotels and bungalows and improved harbor facilities. `` Past experience shows that once an island gets an airport, mass tourism is very difficult to avoid,'' said <PERSON> Eleni </PERSON> <PERSON> Bonou </PERSON>, who heads the project. `` But an airport is essential because it serves the islanders first.'' More than 30,000 visitors come to <LOCATION> Patmos </LOCATION> every year, but two-thirds of them arrive aboard cruise ships that steam away before sunset after a few hours' stay. On an island too barren to grow its own food, visitors are the only source of income apart from fishing. `` There's a delicate balance to be kept between God and mammon on this island,'' Mayor <PERSON> Kyrozis </PERSON> said. `` There has to be tourism, but not so much it kills what we have to offer.'' Trained for a more secluded life, the monks say it's already hard work taking turns to supervise the tourists swarming through the monastery museum, its frescoed chapels and stone colonnades. `` The sheer numbers of people coming through mean that we're exhausted by the time the season's over and there's time to get on with our own tasks,'' said <PERSON> Brother </PERSON> <PERSON> Chrysostomos </PERSON>, the monastery librarian The tourists also crowd into the Monastery of the Apocalypse, built over the cave where <PERSON> St. </PERSON> <PERSON> John </PERSON> supposedly wrote his visionary work while exiled on <LOCATION> Patmos </LOCATION> around A.D. 95. `` It's historical fact that St. <PERSON> John </PERSON> was on the island,'' said <PERSON> Athanassios </PERSON> <PERSON> Kominis </PERSON>, an <ORGANIZATION> Athens </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> professor of Byzantine studies. `` The tradition that he wrote Revelation there is certainly more than speculation, but not quite certainty,'' Patriarch <PERSON> Dimitrios </PERSON>, spiritual leader of <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Orthodox </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Christians </ORGANIZATION> worldwide, plans to lead Orthodox, Roman Catholic and <ORGANIZATION> Protestant </ORGANIZATION> churchmen in a two-day international pilgrimage to <LOCATION> Patmos </LOCATION> Sept. 25-26. It celebrates the 900th birthday of the Monastery of <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> John </ORGANIZATION>, founded in 1088 by a Byzantine scholar, the Blessed Christodoulos with special permission from the Emperor <PERSON> Alexius </PERSON> <PERSON> Comnenos </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880922-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-22-88 0248EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-DrugBill     09-22 0584</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Drug Bill,580</SECOND>
<HEAD>House Considering Measure To Revoke Drug Users' Drivers' Licenses</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: tops prospects uncertain</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By LARRY MARGASAK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 After expressing a mood that the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> wo n't tolerate any illegal narcotics use, lawmakers may be ready to toughen anti-drug legislation by voting to revoke drug users' drivers' As the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> returns to its comprehensive anti-drug bill today, lawmakers face two opposing amendments that could affect any convicted drug offender's right to drive. Rep. <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> McCollum </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Fla </LOCATION>., proposes withholding part of a state's federal highway money unless the state requires suspension or revocation of drivers' licenses of anyone convicted of a drug-related crime A substitute amendment by Rep. <PERSON> Glen </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Calif </LOCATION>., provides an incentive approach Instead of penalties, states would receive <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> grants for imposing the license penalties. The grants would pay part of the license enforcement program. The overall anti-drug bill would add some $ 2 billion to the nation's $ 3.9 billion effort against illegal drugs. While the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> expects to approve the legislation Thursday or Friday, the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> still must consider its own drug bill. A conference will almost certainly be needed to iron out differences, but lawmakers appear eager to pass a popular get-tough-on-drugs bill so close to the election. The House bill, as originally written, authorizes money and innovative programs for drug law enforcement, rehabilitation, treatment and education. Each time the House has amended the measure during the past two weeks, it's civil, administrative, or criminal penalties have toughened. Under <PERSON> McCollum </PERSON>'s driver's license plan, states would have to impose suspensions of at least six months for a first conviction and at least one year for repeat convictions within a five-year period. Five percent of a state's highway money would be withheld the first year if there was no compliance, and 10 percent would be held back for every subsequent year of non-compliance. The penalty for states would begin Oct. 1, 1991. Individuals penalized would have to have been convicted after the drug measure became law. The Anderson alternative would require the same six-month and one-year penalties as required under the <PERSON> McCollum </PERSON> plan. The incentive program would offer states additional money totaling $ 25 million in the 1989 fiscal year, $ 50 million in 1990 and $ 50 million in 1991. <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON>'s proposal also would apply to those convicted after the drug bill became law. Over the past two weeks, the House has inserted a number of amendments to the drug bill that reflect an attitude of `` zero tolerance'' toward any drug use, and a feeling that harsh penalties are needed for those who deal in drugs or merely possess them. Liberal lawmakers have complained that the House has ignored the Constitutional safeguards that protect civil liberties such as due process of law. Amendments already approved would: _ Permit the federal death penalty for anyone who intentionally kills a person during the course of committing a drug felony _ Deny many federal benefits, including assistance to Veterans and student loans, to anyone convicted of two or more drug-related offenses _ Allow introduction of evidence in federal criminal cases that was obtained through a search that violated constitutional protections, but undertaken in good faith _ Create civil penalties of up to $ 10,000 per violation for possession of small `` personal use'' amounts of marijuana, cocaine and other drugs The House also approved a requirement for a system that would allow gun dealers to identify convicted felons attempting to buy handguns. This amendment replaced language for a seven-day waiting period for handgun purchases.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880922-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-22-88 0244EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Soviet-Harvest     09-22 0374</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Soviet-Harvest,0384</SECOND>
<HEAD>Izvestia Says Grain Harvest Down This Year</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MOSCOW (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>'s grain harvest this year will be smaller than the relatively good harvests of the two previous years because of drought in the country's breadbasket, <ORGANIZATION> Izvestia </ORGANIZATION> reported. The Soviet government newspaper gave no figures, but said the harvest was just drawing to a close and it was clear it would fall short of the 231 million tons harvested in each of the past two years. A significant shortfall in the grain harvest would be a blow to Soviet leader <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s efforts to improve food supplies to consumers and reform agriculture. It also would require the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> to use more of its scare foreign currency to buy grain instead of machinery and equipment to modernize the economy. `` The summer drought has inflicted an appreciable blow on the principle grainaries of the country _ the <LOCATION> Volga </LOCATION> region, the Urals, western <LOCATION> Siberia </LOCATION> and northern <LOCATION> Kazakhstan </LOCATION>,'' <ORGANIZATION> Izvestia </ORGANIZATION> said in the report Wednesday. It said experts of the government's giant agro-industrial complex had determined `` the grain procurements as a whole around the country will be somewhat lower than the level of the two previous years.'' <ORGANIZATION> Izvestia </ORGANIZATION> said that although it was reporting bad news, it was a sign of progress in <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> society that the news about such a sensitive area of Soviet life could be reported at all. Last year's harvest was considered by Western observers to be good because the growing season was unusually damp and cool. Figures for 1986 and 1987 were well above the average for 1981-1985 of about 203.5 million tons but well below official targets, which Western observers consider unrealistic. The 1986 target was 255 million tons, and Soviet officials are trying to boost that to 275 million tons over several years' time. Western experts say the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> uses about 240-255 million tons of grain a year and must import what it can not produce. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> is trying to reform Soviet agriculture by giving families and small brigades of farm workers more responsibility and greater security on the huge state and collective farms. The Soviet leader hopes to encourage farmers to work harder by offering them a chance to earn more money and live better.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880922-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-22-88 0202EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-PoisonGas Bjt   09-22 0868</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Poison Gas, Bjt,820</SECOND>
<HEAD>Senate Report Features Eyewitness Accounts of Iraqi Gas Attacks</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDs: Note graphic descriptions of effects of gas attacks,
especially in 15th graf.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By LAWRENCE L. KNUTSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 `` The planes dropped bombs,'' the Kurdish survivor said. `` They did not produce a big noise. A yellowish cloud was created and there was a smell of rotten parsley or onions. There were no wounds. People would breathe the smoke, then fall down and blood would come from their mouths.'' The speaker, one of 200 Kurdish refugees interviewed in <LOCATION> Turkey </LOCATION> earlier this month by two members of the staff of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Relations </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, identified himself as a member of the Kurdish insurgent forces fighting <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>'s government. The staff investigators, <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Galbraith </PERSON> and <PERSON> Christopher </PERSON> <PERSON> Van </PERSON> <PERSON> Hollen </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, called the refugee accounts, describing attacks on more than 30 villages, persuasive and said the symptoms they reported are `` classically associated with mustard gas poisoning.'' While acknowledging that some of the witnesses obviously were biased against <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>, the two staff members concluded: `` To dismiss the eyewitness accounts would require one to believe that 65,000 Kurdish refugees confined to five disparate locations were able to organize a conspiracy in 15 days to defame <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> and that these refugees were able to keep their conspiracy a secret not only from us but from the world press.'' Kurds, a nomadic Moslem people, have fought unsuccessfully for years to gain autonomy for their region within <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Kurdistan </LOCATION> also extends into parts of <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Turkey </LOCATION>. Citing the interviews and other evidence, <PERSON> Galbraith </PERSON> and <PERSON> Van </PERSON> <PERSON> Hollen </PERSON> concluded that `` overwhelming evidence exists'' that <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> subjected Kurdish villages to three days of poison gas attacks last month. In a report to Foreign Relations Chairman <PERSON> Claiborne </PERSON> <PERSON> Pell </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-R.I. </LOCATION>, they conclude that the attacks were part of a deliberate policy by <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> to depopulate the Kurdish regions of the country. `` We find no question that <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>'s policy in <LOCATION> Kurdistan </LOCATION> has the characteristics of genocide,'' the staff investigators said. The <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Affairs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, prompted by earlier reports of Iraqi attacks against the Kurds, is debating legislation to impose economic sanctions on the <LOCATION> Baghdad </LOCATION> government. The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> already has approved sanctions legislation against <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>, earlier accused of using mustard gas against attacking Iranian soldiers, has denied it employed chemical weapons against the Kurds or anyone else. The Foreign Relations staff report uses dozens of eyewitness accounts of the alleged chemical attacks against the Kurds to paint a graphic narrative. `` As described by the villagers, the bombs that fell on the morning of August 25 did not produce a loud explosion,'' the report said. `` Only a weak sound could be heard and then a yellowish cloud spread out from the center of the explosion and became a thin mist. The air became mixed with a mixture of smells _ ` bad garlic,' ` rotten onions' and ` bad apples.'' `` Those who were very close to the bombs died instantly,'' the report said. `` Those who did not die instantly found it difficult to breathe and began to vomit. The gas stung the eyes, skin and lungs of the villagers exposed to it. Many suffered temporary blindness.'' `` After the bombs exploded, many villagers ran and submerged their faces in nearby streams to escape the spreading gas. Many of those who made it to the streams survived. Those who could not run from the growing smell, mostly the very old and the very young, died. `` The survivors who saw the dead reported that blood could be seen trickling out of the mouths of some of the bodies,'' the report said. `` A yellowish fluid could also be seen oozing out of the noses and mouths of some of the dead. Some said the bodies appeared frozen. Many of the dead bodies turned blackish blue. `` Most of the villagers quickly abandoned the contaminated areas, leaving the bodies unburied in the sun,'' the report said. `` In some cases they later returned to the poisoned villages to bury the bodies. ... `` In every village where chemical bombs were dropped, the livestock _ mostly donkeys and goats _ died,'' the report said. `` Birds are also reported to have ` fallen out of the sky.' Bees in the area are also said to have been killed by the gas.'' <PERSON> Galbraith </PERSON> and <PERSON> Von </PERSON> <PERSON> Hollen </PERSON> say the chemical attacks on Kurdish villages continued on Aug. 26 and Aug. 27 and they concluded that `` no area in the northeastern reaches of <LOCATION> Iraqi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kurdistan </LOCATION> was safe from chemical attack.'' Thousands of Kurds fled across the border into <LOCATION> Turkey </LOCATION>, but on Aug. 28 the <LOCATION> Iraqi </LOCATION> army blocked a road parallel to the border, trapping Kurdish villagers inside <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>, the report said. `` An Iraqi Kurd who managed to cross the road said, ` Whatever they saw they shot _ children, women, young and old,'' the report said. It said that by Sept. 5 the Iraqi army had set up camps along the border, slowing the flow of refugees to a trickle. `` In at least one village where Kurds remained _ the village of <LOCATION> Baze </LOCATION> _ survivors report <LOCATION> Iraqi </LOCATION> forces opened fire with machine guns on everyone in the village and then used bulldozers to push the bodies into mass graves,'' the report stated.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880922-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-22-88 0146EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Pope-SouthAfrica     09-22 0212</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Pope-South Africa,0215</SECOND>
<HEAD>Pope Condemns Apartheid</HEAD>
<DATELINE>VATICAN CITY (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Pope <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> II </PERSON> condemned <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>'s policy of apartheid on Wednesday but also expressed a desire to visit that country The pope returned Monday from a 10-day trip to <LOCATION> Zimbabwe </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Botswana </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Lesotho </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Swaziland </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Mozambique </LOCATION>. He also made a brief, unscheduled stop in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>. `` Apartheid remains in clear conflict with human dignity from the <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> point of view,'' said <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON>, because `` all human beings enjoy the same dignity that can not be weakened by belonging to a race.'' `` Surmounting discrimination in this field is an integral part of the program for liberation and self-determination of the African people,'' he told a general audience. The pontiff, whose plane stopped in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> because of stormy weather and mechanical difficulties at the airport in <LOCATION> Lesotho </LOCATION>, also said he believes that in the future he will be able to visit the faithful in such countries as <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Namibia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Sao </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Tome </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Principe </PERSON>. Some anti-apartheid leaders in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> said the <PERSON> pope </PERSON> did not speak out strongly enough against that nation during his southern <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> trip. <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>'s system of apartheid gives the nation's white minority control of the government and denies the 26 million blacks a vote in national affairs.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880922-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-22-88 0248EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-TownArson     09-22 0525</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Town Arson,0541</SECOND>
<HEAD>Another Fire Appears To End Hopes That Arson Siege Had Ended</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By MIKE RECHT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CONCORD, N.H. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Residents of <PERSON> Jefferson </PERSON> tried to go about business as usual Wednesday despite a fiery reminder that their small town on the edge of the <LOCATION> White </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mountains </LOCATION> remains under siege by an arsonist. At 10:10 Tuesday night, volunteer firefighters rushed to a burning unoccupied log cabin _ the 20th suspicious fire in the town of 900 since early May, but the first since Aug. 23. `` It's gone on so long now that people are making the effort to live each day as it comes, and live their normal lives,'' said state Sen. <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Bond </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Jefferson </LOCATION> resident. `` People had been trying to relax and hope that it is over,'' <PERSON> Bond </PERSON> said. `` There's a feeling of disappointment, I'm sure.'' The fire extensively damaged the interior of the cabin, which is about 10 miles from the center of town. Most residents have tired of talking about their ordeal and shrug off questions from reporters. But a phone call to the general store Wednesday morning revealed that residents were talking among themselves about the latest fire. Except for several cases of smoke inhalation, there have been no injuries in the house and brush fires. But several families have been left homeless and townspeople are fearful and angry. Many, with weapons ready, have taken to keeping watch over their homes all night. The <ORGANIZATION> Jefferson </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Firemen </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> has raised $ 5,000 for a reward for information leading to an arrest and conviction. Firefighters only hope it is n't a neighbor, or a good friend. State Fire Marshal <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Toland </PERSON> said he has received calls from current and former firefighting authorities throughout <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> with the names of known arsonists, and the possibility that one might be living in the <LOCATION> Jefferson </LOCATION> area. `` It takes time to check them all out,'' he said. The investigation has progressed, he said, declining to say more. <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> King </PERSON>, a national arson expert who spent 23 years with the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fire </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> and has investigated 10,000 fires, expects the fires to continue `` until they catch him. If he's not scared off by now, it's kind of a ` try and catch me' thing,'' he said `` When you have multiple fires, and have no leads, the person who is setting the fires has to continue setting them for you to catch them.'' <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION> authorities have `` just got to get lucky. They have a monster,'' he said. Bond and King point to the surrounding wilderness and sparse population as impediments to catching the arsonist with match in hand. There is no realistic way to patrol the area, <PERSON> Bond </PERSON> said of the town's 100 square miles. `` There are so many areas where they can do what they do and just melt into the woods,'' <PERSON> King </PERSON> said. `` How can you patrol the area around <PERSON> Jefferson </PERSON>?'' In <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, the population is more dense and there are more sources of information, <PERSON> King </PERSON> said. `` In the city, there's always that little old lady who sits up all night and sees everything.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880922-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-22-88 0249EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Reagan-UnitedNations     09-22 0556</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Reagan-United Nations,530</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHINGTON TODAY: Reagan Pictured as Great Friend of United
Nations</HEAD>
<HEAD>By W. DALE NELSON</HEAD>
<HEAD>Associated Press Writer</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, a sharp critic of the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> during much of his administration, is being pictured by his aides as one of the world body's stoutest champions as he prepares to say his <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> farewells. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> will make what is expected to be his final appearance before the international forum in a visit Monday and Tuesday for the opening of the annual General Assembly session in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>. Aides say he will deliver a major speech that may outline new proposals designed to deal with world trouble spots. It will be his sixth speech to a regular <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> session, or his seventh counting a 1982 appearance at a special session on disarmament. It has been heralded with unaccustomed hoopla _ a press briefing on Tuesday by Assistant Secretary of State <PERSON> Rozanne </PERSON> <PERSON> Ridgeway </PERSON> and another one on Wednesday by <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s national security adviser, <PERSON> Colin </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Powell </PERSON>. `` Well, it's an important two-day event, and we know you'd like to have as many briefings as possible,'' <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> explained. <PERSON> Powell </PERSON> told reporters that <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s involvement in <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION> activities has been `` unprecedented for an American president.'' `` As a result of the president's involvement, I think it is fair to say that our relations with the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> are excellent, better than they have been for a long time,'' the national security adviser said. In his previous appearances, however, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> often had criticized the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION>, calling for reforms in its budgetary and hiring practices. On Sept. 13, the White House announced that <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> would release $ 188 million that the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> had withheld from the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> because of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> misgivings about the way the organization was run. The president also said he would seek full funding for the next fiscal year. <PERSON> Powell </PERSON> said these payments have begun. The national security adviser also said, however, that more than just budget reform is involved in the president's new warmth toward the international organization. `` The <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> has started to play a more important role around the world in helping to deal with regional conflicts,'' he said. `` They are really doing what we always hoped they would do.'' <PERSON> Powell </PERSON> said the president's address Monday would be `` a major foreign policy speech, broad in scope. ... It will be forward looking even as it reflects on past accomplishments.'' `` We have a couple of new initiatives under consideration ... to help deal with some of the regional conflict issues around the world,'' he added. He also said he expects that the issue of chemical warfare will come up in some of <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s discussions with foreign leaders and that the issue might also be covered in the speech. On Monday night, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> will be host at a reception for heads of state and other dignitaries. `` It will be sort of a farewell to <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> members,'' <PERSON> Powell </PERSON> said. `` His criticism has produced results,'' he said, `` and he is acknowledging that there have been results. He's essentially taking a snapshot, in what he has done last week and the speech, of where the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> is now and where the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> can go in the future.''
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880922-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-22-88 0249EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--China-Execution     09-22 0190</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--China-Execution,0197</SECOND>
<HEAD>Canton Robber Put To Death</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Authorities executed a <LOCATION> Canton </LOCATION> man convicted of robbing tourists including a visitor from <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> who was forced to surrender a camera and $ 820 in yen, a newspaper reported today. The <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> Daily said the <ORGANIZATION> Canton </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Intermediate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> condemned to death <PERSON> Li </PERSON> <PERSON> Zhaoheng </PERSON>, who was executed Tuesday, and handed down life sentences to an accomplice for multiple armed robberies in the city's <LOCATION> Yuexiu </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Park </LOCATION> in August and September of last year. A third man was sentenced to seven years in prison. The ages and professions of the three men were not given. Among the victims, it said, was a Japanese tourist robbed of 110,000 Japanese yen -LRB- $ 820, a camera and his passport, and a Chinese man who was stabbed in the chest and stomach. The daily said the robbers were armed with a dagger. <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> usually metes out harsh punishment for crimes in which foreigners are victimized, and there have been several cases of the death sentence being given to Chinese who attack or rob foreigners. Execution is normally by a bullet to the back of the head.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880922-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-22-88 0143EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Obit-Norden     09-22 0198</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Obit-Norden,0204</SECOND>
<HEAD>Christine Norden, One-Time British Sex Symbol, Dead At Age 63</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actress <PERSON> Christine </PERSON> <PERSON> Norden </PERSON>, a one-time British sex symbol who was the first performer to appear topless in a Broadway play, died Wednesday at age 63, her agent said. <PERSON> Vincent </PERSON> <PERSON> Shaw </PERSON> said <PERSON> Miss </PERSON> <PERSON> Norden </PERSON> died at <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Middlesex </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION> following a heart attack that came two months after a double heart-bypass operation in July. Miss <PERSON> Norden </PERSON>, born <PERSON> Molly </PERSON> <PERSON> Thornton </PERSON> in the northern <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> town of <LOCATION> Sunderland </LOCATION>, began her career in the 1940s under contract to <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> Films and <ORGANIZATION> Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer </ORGANIZATION>. Her films included `` Night Beat,'' `` Mine Own Executioner,'' `` Idol of <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION>'' and `` Reluctant Heroes'' before she moved to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> in 1953. She made her Broadway debut in 1960 in the musical `` Tenderloin'' and later made headlines by being the first Broadway actress to appear on-stage topless in the 1967 comedy `` Scuba Duba,'' which also starred <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Orbach </PERSON>. She last appeared on the British stage in a 1979 revival of `` The Marriage Go Round,'' and had a small role in the 1986 movie musical `` Little Shop of Horrors.'' She is survived by her fifth husband, <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Heselden </PERSON>, a scientist for the <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880922-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-22-88 0201EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-PaulHarvey     09-22 0744</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Paul Harvey,0762</SECOND>
<HEAD>Broadcaster Not Slowing Down At 70</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By F.N. D'ALESSIO</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CHICAGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 At age 70, news commentator <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Harvey </PERSON> is about to become a museum piece, but he is n't letting that interfere with his three daily radio shows, his newspaper column or his speaking tours. `` Tomorrow's the most exciting day in world to me,'' <PERSON> Harvey </PERSON> said recently, and he has plenty of tomorrows planned _ new directions for his syndicated television program, a new second home and studio in <LOCATION> Phoenix </LOCATION> and adding a helicopter rating to his aviation licenses. On Saturday, he is to be inducted into <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Museum </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Broadcast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Communications </ORGANIZATION>. `` I wo n't retire until I find something that's more fun to do,'' <PERSON> Harvey </PERSON> said, gesturing around his office-studio, decorated with civic awards, keys to cities and cartoons. <PERSON> Harvey </PERSON> got his start at 15 with radio station <ORGANIZATION> KVOO </ORGANIZATION> in his native <LOCATION> Tulsa </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Okla. </LOCATION>. His name was <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Aurandt </PERSON> back then, and it remained so through stints in <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Louis </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Kalamazoo </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mich </LOCATION> He changed it on taking his first <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> job in 1944. Now, when he says `` Good morning, Americans, this is <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Harvey </PERSON>,'' he speaks to an estimated 22 million listeners on 1,348 radio stations, but <PERSON> Harvey </PERSON> tries to concentrate on one person. `` I'm usually talking to my wife's sister,'' <PERSON> Harvey </PERSON> said. `` She seems to epitomize grass-roots America to me. I keep asking myself, ` Would Aunt <PERSON> Betty </PERSON> really care? Would Aunt <PERSON> Betty </PERSON> really understand?' A lot of stories get rewritten or discarded because of that.'' <PERSON> Harvey </PERSON> shrugs off such adjectives as `` cornball'' and criticism of his format, in which ominous headlines are often juxtaposed with cute animal stories and <PERSON> Harvey </PERSON>'s comments. `` Hard, cold facts have to be made palatable with some leavening _ but you ca n't use too much of that leavening. No one wants to listen to just good news, after all _ it's been tried and it does n't work.'' He also does his own commercials, delivering them in the same tone of voice as the news itself. The practice is a <PERSON> Harvey </PERSON> trademark _ and he defends it, saying, `` I use the products myself and I can vouch for them.'' Interviewer and Pulitzer Prize-winning author <PERSON> Studs </PERSON> <PERSON> Terkel </PERSON>, who has been on <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> radio since 1945, says he understands <PERSON> Harvey </PERSON>'s popularity, but does not necessarily approve of the reasons `` At a certain point in the New Deal and a certain point in the war, <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> said the usual, expected things,'' <PERSON> Terkel </PERSON> said. `` <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> was offering pretty simplistic views, and they caught on like a house afire, I guess they were what some people wanted to hear.'' `` He's a nice guy, a very honest guy and a very fair-minded guy,'' said <PERSON> Terkel </PERSON>. `` I like him very much personally, but I do n't have much in common with his views In some ways, he's confined his mind to the 12th century _ and it's not the 12th century anymore. He sees things in blacks and whites, and the world is more complex than he realizes.'' <PERSON> Harvey </PERSON>'s family _ he and wife <PERSON> Lynne </PERSON> have been married 47 years _ has sometimes influenced his broadcasts, as when he reversed himself on the Vietnam War. He signaled the shift in a broadcast that opened: `` I love you, Mr. <PERSON> President </PERSON>, but you're wrong ...'' `` I changed my mind about <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> after a painful period of several months of soul-searching and discussions _ often around our own dinner table,'' he said. `` My son, <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, was exempt, but he felt so strongly about the war that he chose to announce himself as a conscientious objector anyway.'' It was the Cold War that brought <PERSON> Harvey </PERSON> to national prominence. Working as an <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> radio commentator in 1951, he was arrested on orders of the <ORGANIZATION> Atomic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> for scaling a fence and surreptitiously entering <ORGANIZATION> Argonne </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Laboratory </ORGANIZATION>, west of <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Harvey </PERSON> said it was investigative journalism and proved that security was lax at the <ORGANIZATION> AEC </ORGANIZATION>'s nuclear facilities; the <ORGANIZATION> AEC </ORGANIZATION> called it breaking and entering. `` No indictment was filed, but <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> Truman </PERSON> had me picking barbed wire out of my britches for about a decade,'' <PERSON> Harvey </PERSON> recalled. Having supported such political opposites as Sens. <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> McCarthy </PERSON> and <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Fulbright </PERSON>, <PERSON> Harvey </PERSON> says he once considered himself a conservative but can no longer define himself politically. `` Basically, I believe in Big People, as opposed to Big Government _ to the extent that a sardine society will allow,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880922-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-22-88 0252EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Britain-Politics     09-22 0771</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Britain-Politics,0794</SECOND>
<HEAD>Collapse Of Center Evident As Political Season Opens</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</NOTE>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MAUREEN JOHNSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The political season got into full swing this week, but it was starkly clear that the center can not hold. Three years after outstripping Prime Minister <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> in opinion polls and promising to break the mold of British politics, the two center parties have been shunted to the sidelines. <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> once again appears to be a two-party state _ the governing Conservatives, who are to meet Oct. 11-14, and the opposition <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, whose convention is Oct. 2-7. The <ORGANIZATION> Social </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, led <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Owen </PERSON>, who is often rated the most formidable politician in <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> after Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON>, ended its four-day convention Tuesday just barely alive. The newly-formed Social and <ORGANIZATION> Liberal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> is not in much better condition before its meeting Sept. 24-29 in the seaside resort of <LOCATION> Blackpool </LOCATION>. The party, a merger of <ORGANIZATION> Social </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democrats </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberals </ORGANIZATION>, once looked like it could turn British politics into a three-way race. The alliance polled 22.5 percent of the vote in the last general election in June 1987. Today, the two parties are fighting their political battles separately and ca n't reach even double digits in popular support. Recent polls show only 9 percent support for the Social and <ORGANIZATION> Liberal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democrats </ORGANIZATION> and 4 percent for the Social Democrats. The former political allies have become victims of unkind jokes and public indifference. Most analysts believe their main significance lies in their capacity to snatch just enough votes from <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> to ensure Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> an unprecedented fourth consecutive term in the next election. The <ORGANIZATION> Social </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> has only three members in <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION>. Except for <PERSON> Owen </PERSON>, a national figure with a big following in his district of <ORGANIZATION> Plymouth </ORGANIZATION>, the legislators may well lose their seats in the next elections. `` Perhaps -LRB- <PERSON> Owen </PERSON> will -RRB- reflect ... on the hopes thrown away and the opportunities bungled,'' lamented the liberal Guardian newspaper. <PERSON> Owen </PERSON>, 50, the former foreign secretary once tipped for the premiership, rallied only a handful of loyalists to debate apartheid, nuclear weapons and British shopping hours at the party convention this week in <LOCATION> Torquay </LOCATION>, a south <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> coastal resort. Three years ago the <ORGANIZATION> British </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Broadcasting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> gave <PERSON> Owens </PERSON>' party conference full and live television coverage, just like the Conservative, <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> and Liberal party conferences. The atmosphere was heady. This year, the trappings remained _ cameras, reporters, agendas, resolutions _ but the <ORGANIZATION> BBC </ORGANIZATION> covered less than half the proceedings and delayed screening <PERSON> Owen </PERSON>'s keynote address because it clashed with the Olympics. `` -LRB- The centrist parties -RRB- do n't speak to a clear constituency and their support has generally been negative _ from people who do n't like the Tories or do n't like Labor rather than having any clear perception of what the center's policies are,'' political analyst <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Keliner </PERSON> said in an interview In most other West European countries, center parties thrive, often in coalition governments under electoral systems that allocate parliamentary seats according to the percentage of the vote won. In <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>, a legislator wins only when he wins his district. `` Fundamentally, the British electoral system operates against center parties,'' <PERSON> Kellner </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Owen </PERSON> appealed in vain to the <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> for a new voting system less harsh on small parties. `` Does the <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> go on vainly pretending that they can challenge and beat the Conservatives outright?'' he asked. The Social and <ORGANIZATION> Liberal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> controls 19 seats in the 650-member <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commons </ORGANIZATION>, compared with the Conservatives' 374 and Labor's 228. The experiment in centrist politics began in 1981, when disenchanted Laborites broke away to form the <ORGANIZATION> Social </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>. The same year, the new party formed an alliance with the Liberals, a party started in 1828 that once governed the country but was reduced to a minority. In the 1983 election, the two-party alliance made an impressive debut, capturing one-fourth of the vote. Four years later, its share of the vote fell. The alliance promptly split after its Liberal co-leader, <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Steel </PERSON>, demanded a formal merger, arguing that a two-headed party had no chance. The merger, which resulted in the Social and <ORGANIZATION> Liberal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, was finalized in March 1988 after months of political infighting. <PERSON> Owen </PERSON> has remained with what is left of the original <ORGANIZATION> Social </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> and <PERSON> Steel </PERSON> retired and was succeeded by <PERSON> Paddy </PERSON> <PERSON> Ashdown </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Liberal </ORGANIZATION> legislator. `` Today, as a result, we see Dr. <PERSON> Owen </PERSON>, a leader without a party worth the name -LRB- and -RRB- the Social and <ORGANIZATION> Liberal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democrats </ORGANIZATION>, a party devoid of leaders worth the name,'' commented <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Jenkins </PERSON>, columnist in the <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> newspaper, the Independent.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880922-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-22-88 0237EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-CIA-Helicopters     09-22 0441</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-CIA-Helicopters,420</SECOND>
<HEAD>Report Says CIA Allowed Chopper Smuggling by North Korea</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> let <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korean </LOCATION> agents smuggle high-performance <PERSON> Hughes </PERSON> helicopters out of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and withheld the information from law enforcement officials for nearly a year, according to an <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> report. The agency was aware during the operation that shipments of the aircraft were being made through a West German trucking company between 1983 and 1985, <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> said Wednesday. Authorities told <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> the trucking company had been bugged, and the <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> had listened to North Korean agents plan details of the smuggling operation. The <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> believed its source of information was so sensitive that passing on details to law enforcement agencies might compromise <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> agents in <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> reported. <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Devine </PERSON> told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> the agency had no comment on the <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> report. `` We neither confirm nor deny the report,'' he said. <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Carlucci </PERSON> told NBC: `` This is the kind of thing we've got to stop. Very damaging, no question.'' The North Koreans protected their investment by obtaining a <ORGANIZATION> Lloyd </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> London </ORGANIZATION> insurance policy against confiscation of the helicopters, according to the report. <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> said it obtained a copy of the policy which contained details of the smuggling routes from <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>. The choppers took a circuitous route that included stops in <LOCATION> Belgium </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> Netherlands </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION>. Authorities in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> discovered the smuggling operation and seized the last shipment of 15 helicopters in 1985, but <PERSON> Dave </PERSON> <PERSON> Peters </PERSON>, the lead <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Customs agent on the case, told NBC: `` Had different information been passed along, perhaps these shipments could have been stopped.'' The helicopters were Hughes 500E models, commercial versions of the choppers used by <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> forces to raid an Iranian ship caught laying mines in the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION>. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> supplies the <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korean </LOCATION> army the same kind of helicopters to defend itself against <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>. Last Feb. 10, two brothers from <LOCATION> Southern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> pleaded guilty to charges in connection with illegally diverting aircraft to a communist country. `` The evidence at trial was that these two defendants knew from the beginning that these helicopters were going to <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>, that they secretly owned the West German company that did the deal and that they hid the profits in Swiss bank accounts,'' Assistant <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Attorney <PERSON> Jeffrey </PERSON> <PERSON> Modisett </PERSON> said when the men were sentenced in <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Court in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Semler </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Malibu </LOCATION> was sentenced to pay a $ 40,000 fine and serve three years in federal prison. His brother, <PERSON> Barry </PERSON> <PERSON> Semler </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Barbara </LOCATION>, was fined $ 40,000 and sentenced to one year in prison.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880922-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-22-88 0253EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Cavazos     09-22 0403</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Cavazos,400</SECOND>
<HEAD>New Education Secretary Says He'll Fight To Lower Dropout Rate</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JENNIFER DIXON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Education Secretary <PERSON> Lauro </PERSON> <PERSON> Cavazos </PERSON> may have only four months on the job, but he says he'll use the time to fight the dropout rate and advocate education for all. The first Hispanic member of a president's <ORGANIZATION> Cabinet </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Cavazos </PERSON> said he is concerned about keeping all students in school, and points to a Hispanic dropout rate of about 30 percent. `` We ca n't afford to lose that many people,'' <PERSON> Cavazos </PERSON> told a news conference Wednesday, his first day on the job, as he answered questions in Spanish. <PERSON> Cavazos </PERSON> said his mission would be to `` get out there ... and really have people understand the seriousness of the issue. We've got to start now We ca n't delay. We've waited too long.'' To get his message across, <PERSON> Cavazos </PERSON> said he would meet with local officials, professional education societies, and members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. `` The next few months will give us the forum to talk about the issues that are vital to <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>,'' he said. `` How do we position this country, this nation, to really be competitive at the turn of the century ... and I do n't just mean economically. `` Rather, let us look to make sure every person in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> today is educated to his or her full potential. My interest is to awaken <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> to recall that our strength really has come because we had an educated electorate,'' <PERSON> Cavazos </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Cavazos </PERSON> was confirmed by the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> and sworn in Tuesday by Vice President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. On Wednesday, <PERSON> Cavazos </PERSON> said he had `` struck absolutely no deal'' with the <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> presidential nominee to remain in office if <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> wins the November election. `` We never even discussed the possibility of my staying beyond the January date,'' said <PERSON> Cavazos </PERSON>, who is taking a leave of absence from his job as president of <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tech </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> and its medical school. But some Republicans have said they would n't mind seeing <PERSON> Cavazos </PERSON> in the next administration, and Sen. <PERSON> Orrin </PERSON> <PERSON> Hatch </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION> told fellow Republicans last week that Sen. <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, D-Mass., leaned over to him at the end of <PERSON> Cavazos </PERSON>' confirmation hearing and said that if <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> is elected `` I'm going to talk him into keeping him on as secretary of education. <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> told the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> on Wednesday that <PERSON> Cavazos </PERSON> `` has the perspective to be a superb secretary of education.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880922-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-22-88 0255EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-TWA-Consumers     09-22 0574</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-TWA-Consumers,550</SECOND>
<HEAD>Consumer Group Seeks Federal Investigation of TWA</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By H. JOSEF HEBERT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
