<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880914-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-14-88 2332EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>b w AM-Scotus-Bridge     09-14 0124</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Scotus-Bridge,120</SECOND>
<HEAD>URGENT</HEAD>
<HEAD>Top Court Grants Convicted Texas Killer Stay of Execution</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> late Wednesday granted a temporary stay of execution to a 28-year-old murderer convicted in a convenience store robbery that netted him and a co-defendant $ 24, a court spokeswoman said. `` The full court granted the stay'' for <LOCATION> Warren </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bridge </LOCATION> at 11:10 p.m. EDT, about two hours after his attorney filed the application, said spokeswoman <PERSON> Toni </PERSON> <PERSON> House </PERSON>. Bridge's execution by lethal injection had been scheduled for after 1 a.m. EDT Thursday. Bridge was convicted for the 1980 shooting of <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> Rose </PERSON>, 62. The court granted the temporary stay pending a timely filing of a request for a full review of the case by the court, she said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880914-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-14-88 2348EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-BridgeExecution 1stLd-Writethru a0870 09-14 0541</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Bridge Execution, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0870,0551</SECOND>
<HEAD>Scotus Grants Temporary Stay For Killer</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Leads with six grafs to UPDATE with execution stayed; picks
up 4th graf: `Galveston attorney ...</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By MICHAEL L. GRACZYK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>HUNTSVILLE, Texas (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> granted a temporary stay of execution Wednesday night for a 28-year-old murderer who was scheduled to die by injection for a fatal convenience story holdup that netted $ 24. <PERSON> Warren </PERSON> <PERSON> Bridge </PERSON>'s execution, scheduled for after 1 a.m. EDT Thursday, was stayed by the full court, spokeswoman <PERSON> Toni </PERSON> <PERSON> House </PERSON> said. The court granted the temporary stay pending a timely filing of a request for a full review of the case by the court, she said. A federal district judge in <LOCATION> Galveston </LOCATION> had refused to stay Bridge's execution for for the 1980 shooting of <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> Rose </PERSON>, 62, in a convenience store robbery. Bridge's lawyer then took his case to the 5th U.S. <ORGANIZATION> Circuit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appeals </ORGANIZATION>. Bridge would have been the 102nd inmate executed nationally, and the 28th in <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, since the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> ruling in 1976 allowing states to resume the use of the death penalty. <LOCATION> Galveston </LOCATION> attorney <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON> <PERSON> Griffin </PERSON> contended in his appeal that during the punishment phase of Bridge's murder trial, jurors were not allowed to consider mitigating circumstances, or facts that might have led them to settle on a lesser punishment. <PERSON> Griffin </PERSON> cited arguments used in an appeal filed on behalf of <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> death row inmate <PERSON> Johnny </PERSON> <PERSON> Penry </PERSON>, whose case the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> has agreed to hear. After his arrest for the shooting, Bridge escaped briefly from the <LOCATION> Galveston </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> Jail by knocking out a hole in the jail wall. He was captured 19 hours later hitchhiking along a freeway. <PERSON> Rose </PERSON> was shot four times with a .38 - caliber pistol as Bridge and his co-defendant, <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Costa </PERSON>, robbed the convenience store of $ 24 on Feb. 10, <PERSON> Rose </PERSON> died of his wounds on Feb. 24, 1980, four days after Bridge and Costa were arrested. Costa was convicted of aggravated robbery and sentenced to 13 years in prison. He was released under mandatory supervision in October 1986 after serving five years and eight months in prison. Bridge, a native of <LOCATION> Fauquier </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, said he was in trouble since he was 8. He grew up in <LOCATION> Albany </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ga. </LOCATION>, and before moving to <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, he served 13 months of a 15-year prison term for burglary in <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION>. Bridge said in a recent interview that he was sorry <PERSON> Rose </PERSON> died, but complained his life on death row was worse than the shooting victim's fate. `` I sit here on death row for 7 -LCB- years and think about dying, and I believe Mr. <PERSON> Rose </PERSON> got a better deal,'' he said. `` I keep wishing they would hurry up and do something. I tell you, this place will drive you crazy.'' During his time on death row, Bridge was implicated in the bombing of another inmate's cell and the non-fatal stabbing of a second inmate in incidents blamed on prison gang warfare. Bridge also was linked to membership in the <ORGANIZATION> Aryan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Brotherhood </ORGANIZATION>, a white supremacist prison gang. `` I'm not affiliated,'' he said in the interview. `` I'm friends with everybody. And now I've got a black attorney. It's a touchy subject.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880914-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-14-88 2351EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Poland-Solidarity     09-14 0402</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Poland-Solidarity,0412</SECOND>
<HEAD>Opposition and Authorities To Meet Thursday</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DEBORAH G. SEWARD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WARSAW, Poland (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Solidarity's <PERSON> Lech </PERSON> <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> appeared to stand firm Wednesday on the issue of legalizing his federation, on the eve of a second preparatory meeting with authorities before talks on <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>'s future. `` There is no freedom without Solidarity,'' he told reporters upon arriving in <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION> from his home in <LOCATION> Gdansk </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> refused to confirm he will be meeting with communist authorities on Thursday. When pressed for comment on the talks, the leader of the outlawed free trade union movement replied, `` We will know more tomorrow.'' Government spokesman <PERSON> Jerzy </PERSON> <PERSON> Urban </PERSON> said a meeting of <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON>, Interior Minister Gen. <PERSON> Czeslaw </PERSON> <PERSON> Kiszczak </PERSON> and two or three other people would take place at noon Thursday to resolve obstacles to convening the talks. <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> said he planned to remain in <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION> through Friday before departing for the southern city of <LOCATION> Czestochowa </LOCATION> to attend a workers' pilgrimage over the weekend at the <PERSON> Jasna </PERSON> <PERSON> Gora </PERSON> monastery Elsewhere, members of the official union for transport workers in <LOCATION> Gdynia </LOCATION> idled bus and streetcar service in that <LOCATION> Baltic </LOCATION> port city of 250,000 for about six hours Wednesday to protest their pay, a union spokesman said. <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> earlier this month ended a series of Solidarity-led strikes in exchange for the promise of talks on the federation's future But the brief <LOCATION> Gdynia </LOCATION> stoppage was mounted by an official trade union created after Solidarity was outlawed in 1982. Regional official union spokesman <PERSON> Stanislaw </PERSON> <PERSON> Koscielak </PERSON> said the transport workers want a pay increase of $ 6 a month which they were promised last year but never received. Average pay nationwide is about $ 100 monthly. <PERSON> Koscielak </PERSON> claimed the strike was legal under a 1982 law that allows strikes after a period of negotiation and arbitration. A spokesman at the main depot, who refused to give his name, said drivers began striking at 5 a.m. but went back to work at 11 a.m. The official trade union alliance, known by its Polish initials OPZZ, has been pressing the government to liberalize the laws on the right to strike. It has complained that denying official unions the strike weapon undermines their credibility with workers. The government acknowledges widespread worker unhappiness. This year's inflation rate has climbed to 60 percent, with supplies of consumer goods to stores even more erratic than usual because of increased exports to offset <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>'s $ 39 billion foreign debt.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880914-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-14-88 0001EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-HurricaneGilbert 4thLd-Writethru a0839 09-14 1054</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Hurricane Gilbert, 4th Ld-Writethru, a0839,1082</SECOND>
<HEAD>Killer Hurricane Roars Toward Mexico With 175 mph Winds</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: LEADS with 15 grafs to UPDATE with report from Jamaica of six
dead, 60,000 homeless; storm midnight advisory. PICKS up 14th pvs
`The center said ...' SUBS 20th pvs `Gene Graves ...' with 1 graf
to CORRECT that helicopters working to evacuate 10,000 in gulf.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON>, an `` extremely dangerous hurricane'' and one of the strongest storms in history, roared toward <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Yucatan </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Peninsula </LOCATION> Tuesday with 175 mph winds after battering the <LOCATION> Dominican </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Republic </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Jamaica </LOCATION> and the tiny <LOCATION> Cayman </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Islands </LOCATION>. The hurricane killed at least five people Sunday in the <LOCATION> Dominican </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Republic </LOCATION>, civil defense officials said. Six people died and 60,000 were left homeless in <LOCATION> Jamaica </LOCATION> on Monday, officials there said. Prime Minister <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Seaga </PERSON> said the hurricane swept the full length of <LOCATION> Jamaica </LOCATION>, `` leaving a trail of wreckage behind it.'' `` It will take us some time before we can assess the full damage without any doubt,'' <PERSON> Seaga </PERSON> said in a statement. `` But I have no doubt that this going to be the worst disaster that we have experienced in our modern history.'' Communications were down with many storm-ravaged areas and the death toll was expected to rise with the arrival of damage and casualty reports. The hurricane, traveling westward across the <LOCATION> Caribbean </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sea </LOCATION>, was upgraded Tuesday to a Category 5, the strongest and deadliest type of hurricane. Such storms have maximum sustained winds greater than 155 mph and can cause catastrophic damage. <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Sheets </PERSON>, director of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hurricane </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Coral </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gables </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>, described <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON> as `` a great hurricane ... in the top 10 percent -LRB- historically -RRB- as far as intensity, size and destructive potential.'' Only two Category 5 hurricanes have hit the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> _ a 1935 storm that killed 408 people in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>, and Hurricane Camille, which devastated the <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> coast in 1969 and killed 256 people. `` The people who need to be concerned now are those people over on the <LOCATION> Yucatan </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Peninsula </LOCATION> _ <LOCATION> Cancun </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Cozumel </LOCATION>, that whole area,'' Sheets said. <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>'s news media reported beachfront hotels were evacuated in the Yucatan resorts of <LOCATION> Cancun </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Cozumel </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION>. They gave no figures on the numer of evacuees, but said people in <LOCATION> Cancun </LOCATION> were being sent from the hotel zone into the city center, about 6 miles away. <LOCATION> Cozumel </LOCATION> is south of <LOCATION> Cancun </LOCATION> and the reports said hotel guests also were being moved to more secure areas away from the shoreline. Mexican officials expected the storm to hit in the early morning hours Wednesday. At midnight EDT the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Weather </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> said <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON> was centered near latitude 19.9 north, longitude 84.8 west, or about 150 miles east-southeast of <LOCATION> Cozumel </LOCATION>. It said <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON> was moving west-northwest at about 15 mph with maximum sustained winds of 175 mph. The center said tropical storm-force winds extend outward up to 250 miles to the north and 200 miles to the south of the center. `` People in the warned areas should have completed all possible preparations for this extremely dangerous hurricane,'' it said. The center said Hurricane <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON> was the most intense storm on record in terms of barometric pressure. It said by 8 p.m. EDT it was measured at 26.13 inches, breaking the 26.35 inches recorded for the 1935 hurricane that devastated the <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Keys </LOCATION>. `` That's the lowest pressure ever measured in the <LOCATION> Western </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hemisphere </LOCATION>,'' said forecaster <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Zimmer </PERSON>. `` There is very serious flooding'' in the <LOCATION> Cayman </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Islands </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Erina </PERSON> <PERSON> Nichols </PERSON>, a tourism official in <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION>, said Tuesday after speaking with residents of the islands. `` The Run Point -LRB- community -RRB- is taking a real beating.'' The storm later knocked out all telephone service to the <LOCATION> Cayman </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Islands </LOCATION>, a British dependency of 23,000 people that was expecting 12-foot tides. <PERSON> Warren </PERSON> <PERSON> Chase </PERSON>, an amateur radio operator in <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Myers </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>, said he received a report of sailboat with seven people aboard missing near the <LOCATION> Cayman </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Islands </LOCATION>. Oil companies evacuated thousands of workers from rigs in the <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, according to reports from <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Gene </PERSON> <PERSON> Graves </PERSON>, marketing director for <ORGANIZATION> Petroleum </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Helicopters </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Lafayette </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> La. </LOCATION>, said his company's 18 helipads were working at full capacity to evacuate about 10,000 oil rigs in the <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>. The Cuban news agency <ORGANIZATION> Prensa </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Latina </ORGANIZATION> said 40,000 people, many of them foreign vacationers and students, were evacuated Tuesday from the Isle of Youth off the southwestern coast as the hurricane passed 200 miles to the south. In <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, a ham radio operator who was monitoring amateur radio communications in <LOCATION> Jamaica </LOCATION> said Tuesday, `` <LOCATION> Kingston </LOCATION> is devastated, <LOCATION> Montego </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION> is hit hard and <PERSON> Ocho </PERSON> <PERSON> Rios </PERSON> is flooded. The operator, <PERSON> Norm </PERSON> <PERSON> Chwat </PERSON>, an officer with the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Radio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Club </ORGANIZATION>, said therth coast had been wrecked by the hurricane. <PERSON> Herb </PERSON> <PERSON> Schoenbaum </PERSON>, a radio ham operator in the <LOCATION> Virgin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Islands </LOCATION>, said he spoke Tuesday with <PERSON> Dave </PERSON> <PERSON> Porter </PERSON>, an American staying in the <ORGANIZATION> Wyndham </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hotel </ORGANIZATION> on <LOCATION> Jamaica </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Montego </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION>. `` <PERSON> Porter </PERSON> reported that the hotel ` peeled apart like a banana' when the force of Hurricane <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON> hit last night,'' <PERSON> Schoenbaum </PERSON> said. `` This morning he says there is just nothing left. Boats that were on the beach, the little rental Sailfishes or Sunfishes, were driven into cars like spears _ power lines down, almost every tree in the area is on the ground.'' <PERSON> Schoenbaum </PERSON> said <PERSON> Porter </PERSON> told him people who were trying to enter the hotel on their hands and knees at the height of the storm were swept into the ocean. <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON> <PERSON> Baxter </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Belgrade </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lakes </LOCATION>, Me., said he spoke with a ham operator in <LOCATION> Jamaica </LOCATION> who told him the roof of a hospital in <LOCATION> Mandeville </LOCATION> ripped off `` and the hospital has caved in And that is the worst horror show that I've heard about because that would imply that a lot of people could have been hurt.'' The Jamaican consulate in <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> said today it had n immediate information on the extent of damages or casualties. <LOCATION> Jamaica </LOCATION> was still out of contact with the rest of the world by telephone. <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> Myers </PERSON>, southern regional spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aviation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>, said both international airports in <LOCATION> Jamaica </LOCATION> are closed. `` We've been told the government has asked commercial radio stations to remain silent so Radio <LOCATION> Jamaica </LOCATION> can broadcast information,'' <PERSON> Myers </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880914-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-14-88 0006EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Iran-Contra-Propaganda     09-14 0730</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Iran-Contra-Propaganda,720</SECOND>
<HEAD>Report Says Covert Operatives Boosted Reagan's Central American
Policies</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LARRY MARGASAK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A House staff report says <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> experts in covert intelligence and psychological operations exceeded their authority in helping rally public support for President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s Central America policies The House Foreign Affairs Committee staff said Tuesday these operatives `` conspired, through the staff of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>, to use the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> as a cover for a domestic operation which went far beyond the legal and ethical scope of their authority.'' Individuals and organizations working in the 1983-86 operation raised and spent money to influence congressional votes and the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> news media, the report said. The `` domestic political and propaganda operation'' was run through the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Diplomacy </ORGANIZATION> for <LOCATION> Latin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Caribbean </LOCATION>, known as `` S @ <ORGANIZATION> LPD </ORGANIZATION>,'' according to the committee's chief counsel, <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Spencer </PERSON> <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON>, and staff consultant <PERSON> Bert </PERSON> <PERSON> Hammond </PERSON>. The office reported directly to the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> rather than through the normal <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> channels, a system established over the objections of Secretary of State <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON>. The staff report said many of the activities on behalf of <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s Central American policies were carried out by recipients of no-bid contracts `` hidden from public view.'' Some of the organizations with no-bid contracts also were part of former <ORGANIZATION> NSC </ORGANIZATION> aide <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> North </PERSON>'s secret program to raise money for the Nicaraguan Contra rebels. North used these fund-raising efforts along with funds diverted from <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> arms sales to <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> in an elaborate scheme to aid the Contras at time when <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> had banned such aid. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, when asked about the report by reporters Tuesday, held his thumb and forefinger about an inch apart to show how much attention he thought the study deserved. `` One day, I promise you, in a paragraph only about that long, I'm going to tell you the truth about Iran-Contra, as I did when it first came to light and which no one is reporting today,'' he said. Presidential spokesman <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> indicated that <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> may write more than a paragraph. Calling the allegations `` old hat,'' <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said the president plans to tell his side of the Iran-Contra affair in a book that <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> will author after leaving office. `` He feels it has been told, but that it just keeps coming up over and over again and people forget the original answers and the original investigations,'' the spokesman said. The report did not cite any laws or presidential directives that were violated, and it was not endorsed by the <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Affairs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> members. It was sent to the panel's chairman, <PERSON> Dante </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Fascell </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Fla </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Hammond </PERSON> said the committee staff has asked the <ORGANIZATION> Congressional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> the </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Library </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to investigate whether the operation violated laws restricting <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> domestic activities; government lobbying; and use of appropriated money for domestic propaganda purposes While many of the activities of the <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Diplomacy </ORGANIZATION> have been reported extensively in the past, the new study emphasized the role of intelligence experts applying their craft in a domestic operation, instead of the foreign covert operations for which they were trained. A presidential executive order on intelligence activities says <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> covert operations can not include an effort to influence the public opinion or public policy of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. While the transfer of intelligence operatives to domestic agencies is not improper under the order, the activities they perform could violate the order, according to congressional intelligence experts. The report said <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Gregg </PERSON>, a former high-ranking <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> official who is now national security adviser to Vice President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, initiated the recommendation that led to the assignment of former <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> propaganda expert <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> Raymond </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> to the <ORGANIZATION> NSC </ORGANIZATION> group that directed the public diplomacy office. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> presidential nominee, has been questioned during the campaign about his role as chief of a <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration task force on <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> policy and his association with <PERSON> Gregg </PERSON>. <PERSON> Raymond </PERSON>, according to the report, `` was instrumental in facilitating the assignment of intelligence personnel from the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> to S @ <ORGANIZATION> LPD </ORGANIZATION> and the expansion of <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> resources available to S @ <ORGANIZATION> LPD </ORGANIZATION>,'' the report said. `` On one occasion,'' the report said, `` five intelligence experts from the <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> 4th </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Psychological </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Operations </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Group </ORGANIZATION> at <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bragg </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.C. </LOCATION>'' were assigned to work with the office, then headed by <PERSON> Otto </PERSON> <PERSON> Reich </PERSON>, the current <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> ambassador to <LOCATION> Venezuela </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880914-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-14-88 0014EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FarmScene     09-14 0769</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Farm Scene,760</SECOND>
<HEAD>White House Aide Wary Of Proposed Labeling Change</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DON KENDALL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Farm Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> wants to change the rules governing the labels on <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> hot dogs but is proceeding over the objections of a White House regulatory official. Department officials thought a proposal to allow processors to include salvaged meat and ground bone in their recipes without explicitly noting the contents in product labels would be in line with President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s policy of stripping away some of the layers of federal regulation. The proposal would allow up to 10 percent mechanically reclaimed meat and tiny bone chips in hot dogs and a number of similar items without explicitly noting the contents in product labels. When animals are slaughtered, most of the red meat is cut or scraped from bones by hand. But a lot of edible tissue clings to the bones and gristle, particularly in neck bones, ribs, joints and other hard-to-scrape places. The bones and the attached meat remnants are put through a grinder and forced through fine sieves. Although most of the bones are strained out, the resulting mixture still contains bits of bone about the size of ground pepper. Under current regulations, the salvaged meat and bone chips are allowed in up to 20 percent of the meat portion of these products, but the labels must state that the products contain the reclaimed mixture. The mixture is known as `` mechanically separated'' meat, or <ORGANIZATION> MSM </ORGANIZATION>, although current regulations describe it as MS -LRB- S -RRB- to acknowledge the species of animal involved. Thus, salvaged meat from a hog would be mechanically separated pork, or MSP. According to a group of meat processors who asked <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> for the rule change, no company at present is commercially producing MS -LRB- S -RRB- for consumer products because of `` unwarranted negative connotations'' associated with the term MS -LRB- S -RRB-. The <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> plan did not set well with <PERSON> Jay </PERSON> <PERSON> Plager </PERSON>, administrator of information and regulatory affairs in the Office of Management and Budget. He told <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> in a letter on Aug. 19 that the proposed rule change `` does not appear to be consistent with several of the administration's basic regulatory principles.'' <PERSON> Plager </PERSON> added: `` Nor does it appear that the potential benefits to society of this regulation outweigh the potential cost to society.'' <PERSON> Christopher </PERSON> <PERSON> Hicks </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION>'s general counsel, replied that department officials `` do not agree with the conclusions'' set forth by <PERSON> Plager </PERSON>. `` There are compelling reasons for proposing this rule, including the fact that it may produce benefits to society that outweigh societal costs,'' <PERSON> Hicks </PERSON> told <PERSON> Plager </PERSON> in a Sept. 6 letter. Copies of the letters by <PERSON> Plager </PERSON> and <PERSON> Hicks </PERSON> were provided to The Associated Press on Tuesday. Advocates of the rule change contend that consumers wo n't buy products containing the salvaged material if labels inform them about it. The proposal, which began a 60-day rulemaking procedure on Sept. 9, was announced on Monday by the department's <ORGANIZATION> Food </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inspection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>. Under various names, MS -LRB- S -RRB- has been authorized for use in the meat products since 1978 and has undergone numerous legal challenges from consumer groups opposed to the salvaged product itself or labeling requirements. According to the plan, which will be open for public comment until Nov. 8, processors would be able to use MS -LRB- S -RRB- to comprise up to 10 percent of the meat in franks, bologna, luncheon meats, sausage and similar products without stating so on product labels. However, the label would have to indicate the percentage of the Recommended Daily Allowance of calcium that the product contained. Calcium is a primary ingredient of bone tissue. The <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Meat </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION>, a private association that represents meat packers and processors, said in a statement that the use of calcium on labels would be `` a more meaningful and useful term'' to consumers than MS -LRB- S -RRB-, particularly to those who have a calcium deficiency and to a few who are allergic to calcium and should be warned away from such products. In its brief statement, the institute said, `` There is no wholesomeness or safety issue involved'' in the MS -LRB- S -RRB- proposal. But <PERSON> Plager </PERSON> said the assertion that consumers would avoid products labeled as containing MS -LRB- S -RRB- had not been documented in the proposed rule change. `` Furthermore, if one accepts the assertion that some consumers would be reluctant to purchase a product that they know to contain MS -LRB- S -RRB-, why should this information be omitted from the label?'' he said. <PERSON> Plager </PERSON> said that in seeking ways to carry out less burdensome food safety regulations, `` We must also provide consumers with more, rather than less, information about food products so that they may reach informed market decisions.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880914-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-14-88 0019EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-ElectedHispanics     09-14 0326</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Elected Hispanics,320</SECOND>
<NOTE>For release at 9:30 a.m. EDT, time set by source.</NOTE>
<HEAD>Hispanic Candidates Making Gains In Elections</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JENNIFER DIXON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Hispanic candidates continued to make gains in local, state and federal elections this year and now hold 3,360 elective positions nationwide, said a report released today. The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Latino </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Elected </ORGANIZATION> and Appointed Officials said the number of Hispanic elected officials increased by 1.3 percent this year, based on elections from August 1987 to August 1988. <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> Pachon </PERSON>, national director of the association, said measuring the number of Hispanic elected officials `` is a good barometer of Hispanic progress in the political arena.'' The association is a non-partisan, non-profit research organization with more than 3,300 members. President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> on Tuesday proclaimed this week as National Hispanic Heritage Week, saying people of Hispanic descent have `` written countless chapters in the unique saga of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>.'' Most of the Hispanic elected officials hold municipal and school board seats. Association researcher <PERSON> Luis </PERSON> <PERSON> Baquedano </PERSON> said a breakdown of party membership was not available because many local officials do not run as Democrats or Republicans. The association said the largest gains were made in the <LOCATION> Southwest </LOCATION>, with <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> accounting for 1,611 of the elected officials and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> coming in second with 595. <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> has the nation's second-largest Hispanic population, with 4.1 million of the nation's estimated 19.4 million Hispanics <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, with the country's largest Hispanic population at 6.6 million, had 466 Hispanic elected officials. <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, with a third-ranked Hispanic population of 2.1 million, had 68 elected Latino leaders, fewer than states with smaller Hispanic populations such as <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION>, with 237 elected officials, and <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION> with 157. Other states with double-digit numbers of elected Hispanics were <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>, 50; <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION>, 44; <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION>, 28; <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION>, 15; and <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, 12. Hispanics hold 11 seats in the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> but none in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>. There is one Hispanic governor, <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Martinez </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880914-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-14-88 0020EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-TeacherSurvey     09-14 0538</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Teacher Survey,540</SECOND>
<HEAD>Survey Disputes Predicted Teacher Shortage</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto WX9</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CRISPIN Y. CAMPBELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An independent education group says its survey of American schools and education officials indicates there is no shortage of qualified teachers despite frequent talk to the contrary. `` The facts are that there is no teacher shortage,'' <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Emily </PERSON> <PERSON> Feistritzer </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Education </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Information </ORGANIZATION> said Tuesday. She said the group's `` Teacher Supply and Demand Surveys 1988'' report shows that not only is the alleged teacher shortage unsubstantiated, the teaching market was glutted, with some school districts maintaining large applicant lists. The center's surveys, conducted June 28-Aug. 28, were directed at teacher certification and education offices across the nation, 75 school districts, and more than 1,000 individuals who had been seeking teaching jobs The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Education </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> disputed the results, with <ORGANIZATION> NEA </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> <PERSON> Carroll </PERSON> saying past <ORGANIZATION> NEA </ORGANIZATION> surveys indicated that vacancies reported during the summer months usually were not filled by new full-time hires in September. `` These school districts say they hired temporaries, or substitutes, reassigned teachers' aides, misassigned teachers, eliminate or reduce course offerings,'' he said. `` We generally find that 20 percent of the schools will increase class size.'' `` This is merely a smokescreen to mask the hiring of temporaries and uncertified teachers,'' he said. <PERSON> Feistritzer </PERSON> said the state boards maintained that all their teachers were certified and noted that many had a policy of placing all new hires on a probationary or temporary status. She acknowledged that the surveys found a shortage in bilingual and special education teachers, but ascribed the outcry over a teacher shortage partly to political considerations. `` As long as you keep presenting a crisis, you've got control over what happens to solve it,'' she said. `` And I do think the unions have held onto this prediction _ it does give them control over who gets into the profession.'' The center's surveys also found: _ Teachers are not leaving the profession at the rate predicted and many who left the field are trying to re-enter It cited <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Teachers </ORGANIZATION> data showing a decrease in retirements from 2.4 percent in 1985-86 to 2.2 percent in 1986-87. AFT figures also indicated that 53 percent of new hires in 1987-88 were re-entering teachers, up from the 50 percent in 1986-87. _ Data from the school districts indicate that recent college graduates comprise 50 percent to 60 percent of applicants for teaching positions, at least 20 percent are former teachers trying to re-enter the field or are substitute or part-time teachers seeking full-time status; and at least 4 percent are people making mid-career changes or retirees wanting to become teachers _ Those applying and getting hired are older, highly educated, academically able and experienced _ The average age of those responding to the center's job bank advertisements for `` qualified teachers'' was 38, with 40 percent being 40 or older Thirty-five percent of those hired were 40 or older. _ Half of those job applicants responding were willing to teach in rural areas, and another 46 percent were willing to teach in inner city schools Sixty-eight percent of those who applied and were not hired said the market was glutted; there were no vacancies or too many applicants.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880914-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-14-88 0034EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Kemp-Heritage     09-14 0389</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Kemp-Heritage,380</SECOND>
<HEAD>Kemp To Join Think Tank But Says He's Not Leaving Politics
Completely</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KIM I. MILLS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Rep. <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> says his decision to join a conservative think tank in January when he leaves <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> does n't mean he's leaving politics completely. The nine-term <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> congressman, who earlier had said he would not seek a 10th House term, said Tuesday his position as a distinguished fellow at the <ORGANIZATION> Heritage </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION> would be `` another phase'' in his career. `` I'm not going to be in public office but I will be doing things before -LRB- congressional -RRB- committees, lecturing, writing, speaking and staying active in support of those policies and issues and ideas that I have been associated with for a number of years,'' he said. <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON>, who for nearly 18 years has represented <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>'s 31st Congressional District around <LOCATION> Buffalo </LOCATION>, announced earlier this year that he would retire from <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> at the end of this term. At the time, he was waging an unsuccessful bid for the Republican presidential nomination. He was mentioned as a possible running mate for <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and made no secret of the fact that he would accept the job gladly. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> instead selected Sen. <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> said he would keep his political action committee running so he will have a hand in helping the candidates he supports. He also plans to continue working for <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s presidential campaign, `` and then see what happens.'' `` I expect that <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> will win, and what the future holds, I do n't know,'' he said. `` But I think this is a good place from which to be active in public policy and keep my options open. So I'm not ruling anything in or out.'' <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON>, 53, in the past has been a guest lecturer at the foundation and has written articles for the foundation's quarterly journal, <ORGANIZATION> Policy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Review </ORGANIZATION>. The fellowship is slated to last at least two years, he said. <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> is a former all-pro quarterback for the <ORGANIZATION> San </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Diego </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chargers </ORGANIZATION> and the Buffalo Bills. He first won his congressional seat in 1970. In <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, he became the architect of many economic proposals, including the 1981 supply-side tax cuts, urban enterprise zones and a bill passed last year that enables inner-city poor people living in public housing to purchase their apartments.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880914-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-14-88 0040EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-US-UnitedNations Bjt   09-14 0867</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-US-United Nations, Bjt,850</SECOND>
<HEAD>Reagan Agrees To Send U.N. Past-Due American Dues Payments</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MERRILL HARTSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> is releasing $ 188 million in overdue <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> payments to the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> after becoming convinced that the world body has reformed some administrative and budgetary procedures. At the same time, the White House said <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> told the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> to work out `` a multi-year'' repayment plan involving some $ 520 million in arrearages that have piled up in recent years because of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> dissatisfaction with the way the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> was run. `` In announcing these decisions, the president called on the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> to continue progress in areas where reform remains incomplete,'' spokesman <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> told reporters Tuesday. `` The president reiterated the commitment of the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> to assist the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> in its reform program as well as in its new peace keeping efforts,'' he said. In addition to the roughly $ 520 million in late dues payments, the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> is in arrears to the tune of $ 111.8 million in the assessments it is supposed to pay toward the separate <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> peace keeping budget. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> pays 25 percent of the cost of running the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION>, and 31 percent of the cost of the peace keeping operations. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> is scheduled to visit the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> for two days later this month, and will address the <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION> on Sept. 26. He also will meet with a number of foreign leaders while in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>. Considering the financial burden the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> shoulders for the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION>, both the administration and a majority in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> have concluded there has been too little accountability from the U.N. But <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> `` has made progress'' toward streamlining and improving budget-making procedures and cracking down on the hiring of temporary employees for the secretariat. He also said that where <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> interests are concerned, the `` political environment'' had improved. <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> Secretary-General <PERSON> Javier </PERSON> <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Cuellar </PERSON> told reporters as he left <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> headquarters in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> that <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s decision `` is a very positive development which I very much welcome and which alleviates our difficulties. Of course, it is not the end of our financial problems, but it will alleviate them very much.'' In an earlier statement issued on his behalf, <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Cuellar </PERSON> said, `` Until the outstanding contributions by all member states are paid, the organization will continue to operate with inadequate current income and virtually without reserves.'' Sen. <PERSON> Claiborne </PERSON> <PERSON> Pell </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-R.I. </LOCATION>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Relations </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, said <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s actions `` breathe new life into our hopes for world peace.'' Rep. <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Leach </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Iowa </LOCATION>, a member of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Affairs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, said, `` The <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> decision appears to signal a new era of cooperation rather than confrontation with the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION>. The only question is whether <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> has the vision and the fortitude to reverse course and follow the president's lead.'' <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> `` will release $ 44 million, which was withheld in fiscal 1988, and $ 144 million which was withheld in fiscal 1989. He will request full funding of the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> in fiscal 1990, which amounts to approximately $ 476 million.'' The $ 44 million will be released immediately, <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said, while the $ 144 million that had been earmarked in fiscal 1989, beginning Oct. 1, will be set free after the first of next month. The spokesman noted that <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> required the president to determine that the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> had made reforms, `` including cutbacks in the -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> -RRB- secretariat, the hiring of temporary employees'' and improved budgeting procedures. <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> was convinced that the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> had made progress in instituting reforms and that the president noted the increasing peace keeping role of the world body in such hot spots as <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Namibia </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION>. `` We have seen in the last six months some important reforms in terms of the budget and hiring practices, and so forth, and so that has been a determining factor,'' he said. `` During the seven and a half years of this administration, the president has sought to change the political environment,'' <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said. `` Although the reform is incomplete, the progress is striking,'' he said. The aim, he said, was to `` prod the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> to become an even greater force for peace throughout the world.'' <PERSON> Vernon </PERSON> <PERSON> Walters </PERSON>, the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> ambassador to the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION>, had said in late July that the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> hoped to pay $ 188 million of its debt to the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> before the year was out to help prevent the world body from running out of money at a time of heightened peace keeping activities. Testifying July 29 before the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Relations </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Walters </PERSON> said that if progress were reached at resolving such world problems as Soviet occupation of <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> Cuban </LOCATION> presence in <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION>, a transition to independence for <LOCATION> Namibia </LOCATION> and theVietnamese occupation of <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> could face an annual peace keeping bill of more than $ 1.5 billion. `` All of these are important to the interests of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and all are likely to involve the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> significantly,'' he said at the time. `` This increase in activity takes place at a time when the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> is facing a very tight cash situation.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880914-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-14-88 0048EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-MedicaidAbortions Bjt   09-14 0555</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Medicaid Abortions, Bjt,550</SECOND>
<HEAD>Senators Bow To Political Reality In Scrapping Medicaid Abortion
Proposal</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JILL LAWRENCE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> abandoned an effort to expand federal coverage for Medicaid abortions in the face of strong opposition from the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and the White House. The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> in July had voted 73-19 to allow federal financing for Medicaid abortions for women who are victims of rape or incest, but it backed down on Tuesday in a bow to political reality. Under current law, federal spending for Medicaid abortions is permitted only if the procedure is needed to save a woman's life. The <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> reaffirmed its support for that policy last week, and in the process rejected the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>'s proposal for rape and incest exceptions. President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> had promised to veto a $ 140 billion spending bill containing all the fiscal 1989 money for the departments of <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Human </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION>, and Education if it came to him with the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>'s abortion provision. The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> on Tuesday voted 47-43 to kill a motion insisting on the expanded Medicaid abortion coverage it had approved earlier. `` It's stand up and be counted time,'' said Sen. <PERSON> Lowell </PERSON> <PERSON> Weicker </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Conn </LOCATION>., the chief proponent of expanded Medicaid coverage `` We're going to see how politically expedient we want to be,'' added Sen. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Exon </PERSON>, D-Neb., sponsor of the provision adopted by the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> in July Sen. <PERSON> Lawton </PERSON> <PERSON> Chiles </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Fla </LOCATION>., chairman of the subcommittee that handled the spending bill, told his colleagues it would be futile to resist the will of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and White House `` We're talking about a <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> that we're 50 votes short in. We're talking about a president that's going to veto the bill. We're talking about a clock that's ticking,'' <PERSON> Chiles </PERSON> said. Countered Exon: `` Sometimes I think we quiver and retreat all too soon.'' It took <PERSON> Chiles </PERSON> two tries to kill <PERSON> Weicker </PERSON>'s motion insisting on the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> abortion position. He lost the first vote 46-44 but prevailed on the second, 47-43. The outcome was hailed by the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Right-To-Life </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> as `` a sharp setback for the pro-abortion movement'' and those groups, who label themselves pro-choice, had to agree. <PERSON> Kate </PERSON> <PERSON> Michelman </PERSON>, executive director of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Abortion </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rights </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Action </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> League </ORGANIZATION>, said `` politics played a heavy role'' in the vote. `` Arms got twisted so that our friends voted against us,'' she said. `` They deserted us in the interest of pragmatic politics. It's clear they did n't want this bill to be held up.'' `` We are terribly disappointed,'' said <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Andrews </PERSON>, executive director of the <ORGANIZATION> Planned </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Parenthood </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION>. `` These are clearly cases that cry out for public funding.'' Anti-abortion forces got a big boost last week from <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, who wrote a letter to congressional leaders reiterating his veto threat. `` The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> language would permit the use of federal funds for the slaughter of unborn children, depriving the innocent of the most basic of civil rights _ the right to life,'' <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said in the letter. `` I urge the <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to vote to protect the lives of <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s unborn children.'' <PERSON> Weicker </PERSON> charged that the administration was trying `` to use their last gasp and their last piece of political capital'' to deny abortions to rape and incest victims. Fourteen states and the <LOCATION> District </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION> pay for Medicaid abortions, but they receive federal reimbursement only in life-threatening cases.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880914-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-14-88 0050EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-UndergroundTanks     09-14 0621</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Underground Tanks,620</SECOND>
<HEAD>Rules On Underground Tanks Seek To Prevent Groundwater
Contamination</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GUY DARST</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Hundreds of thousands of operations, ranging from corner service stations to giant oil companies, are being subjected to the first federal rules aimed at preventing contamination of groundwater by underground tanks. Almost 2 million tanks, roughly 97 percent of them holding gasoline or some other petroleum product, are covered by a 370-page set of regulations released Tuesday by the <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION>. The rules apply to new tanks starting in December, but give owners until December 1998 to bring all existing tanks up to the new standards. The rules require protection against corrosion, either electrical devices or plastic liners for steel tanks or use of non-steel tanks; leak detection systems, which may be inventory record-keeping in some cases if an annual tightness test is performed; and devices to prevent spills and overfilling. Existing tanks gradually will come under the regulations, the oldest tanks first. Tanks that are 25 years old or of unknown age will have to get a leak detection system by December 1989. Tanks may be exempted from the rules if a corrosion expert certifies that they will not corrode in the particular soil they're in, but <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> expects this to be rare Home heating oil tanks and fuel tanks of less than 1,100 gallons for non-commercial home or farm use are not covered. <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> surveys have shown that anywhere from 10 percent to 30 percent of the 750,000 installations with tanks are having or have had a significant leak, and anywhere from 8,000 to 10,000 tanks are involved in some kind of cleanup project. Concerned that a gallon of gasoline can contaminate a million gallons of groundwater, <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> in 1984 required the <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> to adopt the regulations and two years later allocated $ 500 million to help with cleanups. The agency said it tightened provisions for piping from an April 1987 draft because of growing evidence that many leaks start there, rather than in the tank itself. However, environmental groups criticized the agency for failing to require double-walled tanks or other double-barrier containment systems for gasoline tanks. The agency specified their use only for some 60,000 chemical tanks. `` It will cost a lot more to clean up after the fact than it would to put in double-walled tanks to begin with,'' said <PERSON> Morgan </PERSON> <PERSON> Gopnik </PERSON>, an engineer with the <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Action </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION>. `` EPA is leaving the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> supply of drinking water vulnerable to petroleum contamination,'' said staff scientist <PERSON> Lois </PERSON> <PERSON> Epstein </PERSON> of the Environmental Defense Fund. `` The regulations are designed to minimize their impact on the regulated community, not to protect the environment and the public from the hazards of petroleum contamination,'' she said. Although the agency did n't perform a cost-benefit calculation, <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Winston </PERSON> <PERSON> Porter </PERSON>, assistant <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> administrator for solid waste and emergency response, said that `` secondary containment is quite expensive'' and would add unspecified billions to the cost of the final regulations. `` Whether you're mom and pop or <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION>, it does n't make a lot of sense to keep a leaking gasoline tank in the ground. The liability is enormous,'' <PERSON> Porter </PERSON> said. A service station with three 5,000-gallon tanks might have to spend $ 3,000 to $ 8,000 on a leak detection system and $ 10,000 to $ 48,000 on an electrical rust-prevention system, <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> estimated. The agency estimated the benefits from reduced spills in future years at $ 73 billion in today's dollars, with costs to tank owners at $ 54 billion. A dozen states have tank programs of their own, and any state may operate a more stringent regulatory program than the national rules if the <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> approves. The regulations become effective 90 days from publication in the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Register </ORGANIZATION>, expected any day.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880914-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-14-88 0105EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Reagan     09-14 0398</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Reagan,400</SECOND>
<HEAD>Reagan Stumping for GOP Ticket in Missouri, Where He Won Big in
1984</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDs: Top expected about 10 a.m. EDT with remarks embargoed for
1:30 p.m. EDT</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By W. DALE NELSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 As President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> follows Vice President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> into <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION>, he is taking his campaign for the Republican ticket to a state he carried narrowly in 1980 and resoundingly four years ago. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> was flying today to <LOCATION> Cape </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Girardeau </LOCATION>, a shipping center on the <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION>, for a rally at <ORGANIZATION> Southeast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Missouri </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, and then on to <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Louis </LOCATION> to address 1,000 guests at a $ 250-a-plate fund-raising dinner. `` The general thrust of both of these speeches is support for the Republican ticket, acknowledgement of the economic successes of this administration, discussion of the differences between liberals and conservatives,'' <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said Tuesday. `` The first rally speech may focus a little more on the economy and the second one a little more on military strength,'' the spokesman said. `` But they will both be traditional political speeches, covering the themes that the president has discussed in the past.'' The president plans one or two speaking forays each week until the Nov. 8 election. <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> candidates who will benefit from the <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION> events include Gov. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Ashcroft </PERSON>, seeking a second term against <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> Rep. <PERSON> Betty </PERSON> <PERSON> Hearnes </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Charleston </LOCATION>, the wife of former Gov. <PERSON> Warren </PERSON> <PERSON> Hearnes </PERSON>; and Sen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Danforth </PERSON>, opposed by State Sen. <PERSON> Jay </PERSON> <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Hillsboro </LOCATION> as he seeks his third term. Both <PERSON> Ashcroft </PERSON> and <PERSON> Danforth </PERSON> enjoy comfortable leads in state public opinion polls. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, speaking Tuesday in <LOCATION> Jefferson </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, the state capital, pledged, `` We will never go back to the grain-embargo days of those Democrats, <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> and <PERSON> Mondale </PERSON>, and who knows who else.'' <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> took <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION>'s 11 electoral votes with 51 percent of the popular vote against then-President <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> in 1980 and swept the state with 60 percent of the popular vote against <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> Mondale </PERSON> in 1984. Records showed that the only incumbent president to visit <PERSON> Cape </PERSON> <PERSON> Girardeau </PERSON> previously was <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> <PERSON> Taft </PERSON> on Oct. 26, 1902. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> will speak at the year-old Show Me Center. In <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Louis </LOCATION>, the state's most populous city with a metropolitan area population of more than 2 million, the president will speak at the <ORGANIZATION> Omni </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hotel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Louis </ORGANIZATION> at an event for the <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION> GOP Victory'88 fund.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880914-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-14-88 0118EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Shultz-Philippines     09-14 0431</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Shultz-Philippines,430</SECOND>
<HEAD>US-Filipino Impasse on Bases Continues</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto WX11</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GEORGE GEDDA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A new effort to end the impasse between the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION> over the terms of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> access to strategic bases in the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION> ended with no apparent narrowing of differences. `` There has been nothing to justify my saying that we are closer together,'' <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION> Foreign Secretary <PERSON> Raul </PERSON> <PERSON> Manglapus </PERSON> told reporters after a 45-minute meeting Tuesday with Secretary of State <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> at the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>. The major issue in the talks is <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> compensation to the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION> for use of the bases. <PERSON> Manglapus </PERSON>, who also plans meetings with <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Carlucci </PERSON> and congressional leaders during his visit, said the two sides are not far apart on a cash aid figure but that there has been no agreement on other components of an aid package. <PERSON> Manglapus </PERSON> declined to provide details of the aid figures being discussed but congressional sources and reports in the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION> indicated he is asking for about $ 1.2 billion annually over the next two years. This would represent a sizeable increase over the $ 180 million a year to which the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration has been committed since 1983. In addition to cash aid, the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION> also is said to be seeking trade concessions, debt relief and other `` soft components,'' as <PERSON> Manglapus </PERSON> described them. The administration reportedly has offered $ 360 million yearly in 1989 and 1990 in addition to food assistance and other concessions for a total of just under $ 500 million. <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> said last week the Filipino demands were `` out of bounds,'' adding that `` we will be patient and we will be persistent'' in efforts to overcome the impasse. The <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> had no comment on the meeting with <PERSON> Manglapus </PERSON>. The talks revolve around the terms for continued American use of <ORGANIZATION> Subic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bay </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Naval </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Base </ORGANIZATION> and <PERSON> Clark </PERSON> <PERSON> Air </PERSON> <PERSON> Base </PERSON>, two of the most important <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> facilities outside the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. The ongoing talks involve other issues, including the presence of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> nuclear weapons at the bases, but most of the attention has focused on compensation. <PERSON> Manglapus </PERSON> said a substantial aid increase is warranted partly to correct what he suggested was a historical injustice, contending that the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> used military facilities in the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION> for more than 70 years without compensating Filipino authorities. In other countries, he said, the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has provided aid immediately after establishing military bases. <PERSON> Manglapus </PERSON> said American analysts have concluded that the bases benefit the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> more than the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION> because `` there is no external threat to the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION> today.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880914-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-14-88 0154EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     09-14 0690</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0713</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in The News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SANTA BARBARA, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Burl </PERSON> <PERSON> Ives </PERSON> the balladeer will become <PERSON> Walt </PERSON> <PERSON> Whitman </PERSON> the poet during a one-man show that depicts the 19th century literary master on the day after his 70th birthday. `` I would say he is the most singular man since <PERSON> Christ </PERSON> in his work,'' <PERSON> Ives </PERSON> said in a recent interview. `` I believe he had that kind of freedom, understanding and compassion. <PERSON> Emerson </PERSON> termed ` Leaves of Grass' the most extraordinary piece of wit and wisdom, but the Victorian world was n't ready for <PERSON> Whitman </PERSON>'s celebration of the human body and spirit.'' <PERSON> Ives </PERSON>, 79, who won an Academy Award for best supporting actor for `` The Big Country'' in 1958, and wife, <PERSON> Dorothy </PERSON>, chose to write the script for `` The Mystic Trumpeter _ <PERSON> Whitman </PERSON> at 70'' because they were unable to find a playwright who was as familiar with <PERSON> Whitman </PERSON>'s works as they were `` I have a feeling that we had little to do with creating this play,'' <PERSON> Ives </PERSON> said. `` It was more instinct and feeling, and it just dropped into place. I think we both got lots of help from the man himself.'' <PERSON> Ives </PERSON>, whose white-bearded appearance is strikingly similar to <PERSON> Whitman </PERSON>'s, begins his appearances as the poet Thursday at the Lobero Theater here.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>AVALON, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Ashby </PERSON> <PERSON> Harper </PERSON>, who's held records as the oldest to swim across the English Channel and around <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION>, had to stop a 19.1-mile ocean swim midway between <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Catalina </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> and the mainland when he fell ill. <PERSON> Harper </PERSON>, 71, said he had completed nine miles through the 68-degree <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ocean </LOCATION> waters when he was forced to stop Tuesday because he became nauseated and aggravated an old shoulder injury <PERSON> Harper </PERSON>, who plunged into the water at the island's Emerald Cove at 11 p.m. on Monday, was forced to quit at 5:45 a.m. `` I feel fine physically,'' he said in a ship-to-shore telephone interview about an hour after he climbed aboard his escort boat, the Golden Greek. `` But I'm naturally disappointed.'' He does n't plan to try the endurance swim again this summer. `` If I do try again, it will be next summer, I think,'' said <PERSON> Harper </PERSON>, adding, `` I'm only 71, you know.''
</TEXT>
<NOTE>Eds: Version of the following moved on sports wire.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>STOCKHOLM, Sweden (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Mats </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilander </PERSON>, the U.S. Open champion and top-ranked tennis player in the world, says he's withdrawing from the Olympic Games because of a leg injury. `` I'm not going to <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Wilander </PERSON> told the Swedish news agency <ORGANIZATION> TT </ORGANIZATION> from his home in <LOCATION> Greenwich </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Conn. </LOCATION>, on Tuesday. `` It's not worth it. I have a problem with shin splits in my leg and I'm not going to take a chance.'' <PERSON> Wilander </PERSON> had indicated after his five-set victory over <PERSON> Ivan </PERSON> <PERSON> Lendl </PERSON> in Sunday's U.S. Open final that he would skip the Olympic Games, which begin this weekend. <PERSON> Wilander </PERSON>, who was troubled by periostitis five weeks ago during the ATP Championships in <LOCATION> Cincinnati </LOCATION>, was advised by his doctor to withdraw from the Olympics, <ORGANIZATION> TT </ORGANIZATION> said. `` My doctor told me that the injury can get worse if I do n't rest,'' <PERSON> Wilander </PERSON> was quoted as saying The 24-year-old Swede, who also won the Australian and French Opens this year, said he will rest more than one month.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>INDIANAPOLIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Broadcast analyst <PERSON> Hank </PERSON> <PERSON> Stram </PERSON>, who coached the <ORGANIZATION> Kansas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chiefs </ORGANIZATION> to three <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Football </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> League </ORGANIZATION> championships and a Super Bowl victory, was listed in stable condition after undergoing open heart surgery. Doctors at <ORGANIZATION> Methodist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION> replaced <PERSON> Stram </PERSON>'s aortic valve with an artificial one during a four-hour operation Tuesday, a hospital spokesman said. <PERSON> Stram </PERSON>, 65, was suffering from calcific aortic stenosis, a narrowing of the aortic valve, said his surgeon, <PERSON> Harold </PERSON> <PERSON> Holbrook </PERSON>. The aorta is the main artery of the body and carries blood from the left chamber of the heart to all parts of the body. `` Doctors report that the surgery went well and described it as routine,'' said hospital spokesman <PERSON> Jon </PERSON> <PERSON> White </PERSON>. <PERSON> Stram </PERSON> was hospitalized Saturday after complaining of dizziness. He was in <LOCATION> Indianapolis </LOCATION> to work on the CBS Sports broadcast of Sunday's <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Football </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> League </ORGANIZATION> game between the <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> Bears and <ORGANIZATION> Indianapolis </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Colts </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880914-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-14-88 0155EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Pesticides     09-14 0629</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Pesticides,600</SECOND>
<HEAD>Pesticide Safety Bill Moving in House</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MIKE ROBINSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Farm lawmakers are moving to impose an eight-year deadline for the completion of safety research on hundreds of chemicals that are used to protect crops from damaging pests. The plan, aimed at toughening federal regulation because of growing concern about potential health hazards, won <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> apprval Tuesday on a voice vote and now heads to the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> floor. Under the legislation, the <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> would have eight years to complete its safety reviews of hundreds of pesticides. The agency, working under no deadline, has been finishing reviews of about two dozen chemicals a year since the mid-1970s when it took over the job from the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>. The legislation also would largely end government payments to chemical companies to buy up supplies of recalled pesticides. Such payments have totaled $ 20 million so far. Critics say the cost of these `` indemnities'' has caused the <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> to drag its feet in proceeding with the safety reviews. Under the bill, chemical companies and the agency would share the cost of storing and disposing of the pesticides, and manufacturers would bear the costs of conducting the reviews. Lawmakers have been stymied since 1983 in efforts to reauthorize the 1949 Federal Insecticide, Fungicide and Rodenticide Act -LRB- <LOCATION> FIFRA </LOCATION> -RRB-. They had been saying no action was likely until next year. Committee approval of the latest bill, however, signaled an effort to send legislation to the president before <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> adjourns next month. Few, however, expressed much enthusiasm for what they called a modest effort in which the lack of far-reaching features could prove the key to political success. Committee aides issued a bill summary headlined `` <LOCATION> FIFRA </LOCATION> Lite.'' `` I doubt very much that there's a man on the dais who thinks that we're doing the right thing, but we're doing what we have to do,'' Rep. <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Stenholm </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Texas </LOCATION>, told the committee. He said recalled pesticides currently in storage should be burned but that lawmakers lacked the political will to push through legislation requiring it. <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> Chairman E. `` Kika'' de la <PERSON> Garza </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Texas </LOCATION>, said the problem was that no lawmaker wanted the incinerator in his or her home district. Environmentalists were concerned about the absence of any provision calling for federal regulation of pesticides in ground water, which represents the basic drinking supply for half of all Americans. But they said the legislation could be worse. `` Like the first law of medicine, they have done no harm,'' said <PERSON> Rick </PERSON> <PERSON> Hind </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Interest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Group </ORGANIZATION>, an organization founded by <PERSON> Ralph </PERSON> <PERSON> Nader </PERSON> that has waged a long pesticide safety battle. The group issued a report Tuesday saying a search of <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> records showed 73 pesticides have been found in ground water in 34 states, a slight increase over previous reports from the agency. `` Putting off action on ground water is better than doing something awful on ground water, which is what they would have done,'' said <PERSON> Maureen </PERSON> <PERSON> Hinckle </PERSON>, lobbyist from the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Audubon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION>. `` Pesticide regulation in this country is a public health scandal that affects each and every consumer,'' said <PERSON> Michelle </PERSON> <PERSON> Meier </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Consumers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION> counsel for government affairs. `` This clean piece of legislation shows that <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> is serious about tackling the problem once and for all this year.'' Farmers and exterminators use some 2.6 billion pounds of pesticides in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> every year. Perhaps 40,000 products are sold, but they are basically formulations of 656 active ingredients. An outgrowth of World War II chemical warfare research, pesticides have played a major part in increasing crop yields and placing better-looking farm products on grocers' shelves. But some of the chemicals have been found to cause cancer and other severe health problems in laboratory animals.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880914-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-14-88 0158EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-6MilesUpandSleepyIII 2Takes   09-14 0819</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-6 Miles Up and Sleepy III, 2 Takes,0834</SECOND>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</NOTE>
<HEAD>6 Miles Up and Sleepy</HEAD>
<HEAD>Part III: The Search For Solutions _ As Simple As Naptime?</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Airline pilots must fly when passengers want to travel: early in the morning, late at night, across continents and oceans, regardless of the vagaries of delays and bad weather. Despite these grueling schedules, however, dangerous fatigue is not inevitable. This final story in a three-part AP Extra series, `` 6 Miles Up and Sleepy,'' examines ways of coping with sleepiness in the cockpit.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>By FRED BAYLES</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>and</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writers</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 One often-proposed solution to the dangers of pilot fatigue is legalization of a remedy that is obvious and widely practiced, but forbidden _ naps in the cockpit. Passengers may blanch at the idea of their captain snoozing while they watch a movie six miles above the Earth. But sleep researchers contend this is a sensible way to cope with the flight crew exhaustion caused by late-night arrivals, early-morning departures and time-zone crossings. While air travel is generally safe, the experts say it could be safer still if human frailties were considered in the design of flight rules, pilot schedules and the planes themselves. Some in the flying business, however, are reluctant to acknowledge fatigue as a concern. The <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aviation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> has publically voiced skepticism that sleepy pilots create a hazard in the skies. The airlines seem to fear that proposed rule changes would make scheduling more difficult, and some pilots fret that they would lose the large blocks of free time they now enjoy. Industry observers, moreover, contend that one of the most powerful impediments to change is the very image of the airline pilot: fit, trim and male, calm, confident and capable. Surely such a person can deal with a little thing like sleepiness. `` There is a widely held belief that mental toughness, good management or physical fitness will overcome sleepiness. That is categorically incorrect,'' said Dr. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Dinges </PERSON>, a sleep researcher at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pennsylvania </ORGANIZATION>. `` Your brain still needs sleep, and you get yoursef into serious trouble when you try to tough that out.'' Several approaches are being considered: cockpits that monitor their operators, medicines that help flight crews sleep when off duty, schedules that figure in the time of departure and the direction of travel as well as the length of the work day. But one of the easiest and simplest solutions is the nap. `` It's common knowledge that people are napping in the cockpit because they are so tired,'' said <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Curtis </PERSON> <PERSON> Graeber </PERSON>, a sleep scientist at the <ORGANIZATION> NASA-Ames </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>. `` We are looking very closely at the potential safety benefits of allowing limited napping in the seat.'' The <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> encourages its crews to nap on long cargo flights, and some foreign countries, <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> among them, allow sleeping in airline cockpits. Under <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aviation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> rules, however, napping is considered careless and reckless operation of the aircraft. Yet on the long mid-flight stretches across continents and oceans, pilots have little to do but monitor their dials. Nature takes its course. In interviews with <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>, pilots reported frightening instances of awakening to find their two colleagues sound asleep as the airliner cruises through the night skies. <PERSON> Graeber </PERSON> proposes that naps be carefully scheduled so each member of the flight crew anticipates a rest period. `` Napping will be very helpful, if it's ever implemented,'' agreed <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Carskadon </PERSON>, a sleep researcher at <ORGANIZATION> Brown </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. `` It makes so much more sense to schedule it in than to all of a sudden have all three members of the flight crew asleep because no one is scheduled to sleep.'' Far more difficult, the experts agree, is improving pilot schedules. Rules set by the <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> and union agreements dictate how many hours a day pilots can be on duty and in the air. But the standards allow myriad permutations of day and night departures and arrivals that often leave crews out of synchronism with their internal circadian clocks. `` I think pilot scheduling is as good as it can be right now reflecting what we know,'' said <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> McArtor </PERSON>, head of the <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION>. `` As we understand it better, the scheduling, I think, will reflect that.'' <PERSON> McArtor </PERSON> and airline officials are awaiting results of research now being conducted jointly by <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Airline </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pilots </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION>. Beginning this fall, <PERSON> Graeber </PERSON> and other researchers will fly with pilots on long, over-ocean routes, monitoring their body temperatures and brain waves as they fly through the night. The resulting advice may not please either pilots or airlines. Pilots, often vehement critics of schedules, might find their flight time spread over a longer calendar period, eliminating the intense two to three weeks of flying that gives them the rest of the month off.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>MORE</NOTE>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880914-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-14-88 0158EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w BC-Senate-AbortionRollCall     09-14 0401</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Senate-Abortion Roll Call,300</SECOND>
<HEAD>With PM-Medicaid-Abortions Bjt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here is the 47-43 roll call Tuesday by which the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> voted to drop from pending legislation language that would have allowed Medicaid payments for abortions for poor victims of rape and incest. On this vote, a `` yes'' vote was a vote to drop the abortion provision, and there were 47 `` yes'' votes; while a `` no'' vote was a vote to keep it, and there were 43 `` no'' votes. Voting yes were 20 Democrats and 27 Republicans. Voting no were 30 Democrats and 13 Republicans. xxx denotes senators not voting. <PERSON> Adams </PERSON>, D-Wash., no; <ORGANIZATION> Armstrong </ORGANIZATION>, R-Colo., yes; <PERSON> Baucus </PERSON>, D-Mont., no; <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Texas </LOCATION>, no; <PERSON> Biden </PERSON>, D-Del., yes; <PERSON> Bingaman </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.M. </LOCATION>, no; <PERSON> Bond </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Mo </LOCATION>., xxx; <PERSON> Boren </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Okla </LOCATION>., no; <PERSON> Boschwitz </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Minn </LOCATION>., xxx; <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.J. </LOCATION>, no; <PERSON> Breaux </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-La </LOCATION>., yes; <PERSON> Bumpers </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Ark </LOCATION>., no; <PERSON> Burdick </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.D. </LOCATION>, no; <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON>, D-W. <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, yes; <PERSON> Chafee </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-R.I. </LOCATION>, xxx; <PERSON> Chiles </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Fla </LOCATION>., yes; <PERSON> Cochran </PERSON>, R-Miss., yes; <PERSON> Cohen </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Maine </LOCATION>, no; <PERSON> Conrad </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.D. </LOCATION>, yes; <PERSON> Cranston </PERSON>, D-Calif., yes; <PERSON> D'Amato </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-N.Y. </LOCATION>, yes; <PERSON> Danforth </PERSON>, R-Mo., yes; <PERSON> Daschle </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-S.D. </LOCATION>, no; <PERSON> DeConcini </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Ariz </LOCATION>., xxx; <PERSON> Dixon </PERSON>, D-Ill., yes; Dodd, <LOCATION> D-Conn </LOCATION>., no; <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Kan </LOCATION>., yes; <PERSON> Domenici </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-N.M. </LOCATION>, yes; <PERSON> Durenberger </PERSON>, R-Minn., yes; <PERSON> Evans </PERSON>, R-Wash., no; <PERSON> Exon </PERSON>, D-Neb., no; <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION>, D-Ky., yes; <PERSON> Fowler </PERSON>, D-Ga., yes; <PERSON> Garn </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Utah </LOCATION>, yes; <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Ohio </LOCATION>, no; <PERSON> Gore </PERSON>, D-Tenn., no; <PERSON> Graham </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Fla </LOCATION>., yes; <PERSON> Gramm </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Texas </LOCATION>, yes; <PERSON> Grassley </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Iowa </LOCATION>, yes; <PERSON> Harkin </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Iowa </LOCATION>, no; <PERSON> Hatch </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Utah </LOCATION>, yes; <PERSON> Hatfield </PERSON>, R-Ore., yes; <PERSON> Hecht </PERSON>, R-Nev., yes; <PERSON> Heflin </PERSON>, D-Ala., yes; <PERSON> Heinz </PERSON>, R-Pa., no; <PERSON> Helms </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-N.C. </LOCATION>, yes; <PERSON> Hollings </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-S.C. </LOCATION>, no; <PERSON> Humphrey </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-N.H. </LOCATION>, yes; <PERSON> Inouye </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Hawaii </LOCATION>, yes; <PERSON> Johnston </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-La </LOCATION>., yes; <PERSON> Karnes </PERSON>, R-Neb., yes; <PERSON> Kassebaum </PERSON>, R-Kan., no; <PERSON> Kasten </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Wis </LOCATION>., yes; <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, D-Mass., no; <PERSON> Kerry </PERSON>, D-Mass., xxx; <PERSON> Lautenberg </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.J. </LOCATION>, no; <PERSON> Leahy </PERSON>, D-Vt., no; <PERSON> Levin </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Mich </LOCATION>., xxx; <PERSON> Lugar </PERSON>, R-Ind., yes; <PERSON> Matsunaga </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Hawaii </LOCATION>, xxx; <PERSON> McCain </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Ariz </LOCATION>., yes; <PERSON> McClure </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Idaho </LOCATION>, xxx; <PERSON> McConnell </PERSON>, R-Ky., yes; <PERSON> Melcher </PERSON>, D-Mont., yes; <PERSON> Metzenbaum </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Ohio </LOCATION>, no; <PERSON> Mikulski </PERSON>, D-Md., no; <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Maine </LOCATION>, no; <PERSON> Moynihan </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.Y. </LOCATION>, no; <PERSON> Murkowski </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Alaska </LOCATION>, xxx; <PERSON> Nickles </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Okla </LOCATION>., yes; <PERSON> Nunn </PERSON>, D-Ga., yes; <PERSON> Packwood </PERSON>, R-Ore., no; <PERSON> Pell </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-R.I. </LOCATION>, no; <PERSON> Pressler </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-S.D. </LOCATION>, yes; <PERSON> Proxmire </PERSON>, D-Wis., yes; <PERSON> Pryor </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Ark </LOCATION>., no; <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Ind </LOCATION>., xxx; <PERSON> Reid </PERSON>, D-Nev., yes; <PERSON> Riegle </PERSON>, D-Mich., no; <PERSON> Rockefeller </PERSON>, D-W. <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, yes; <PERSON> Roth </PERSON>, R-Del., no; <PERSON> Rudman </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-N.H. </LOCATION>, no; <LOCATION> Sanford </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D-N.C. </LOCATION>, yes; <PERSON> Sarbanes </PERSON>, D-Md., no; <PERSON> Sasser </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Tenn </LOCATION>., no; <PERSON> Shelby </PERSON>, D-Ala., no; <PERSON> Simon </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Ill </LOCATION>., no; <PERSON> Simpson </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Wyo </LOCATION>., no; <PERSON> Specter </PERSON>, R-Pa., no; <LOCATION> Stafford </LOCATION>, R-Vt., no
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880914-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-14-88 0159EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-6MilesUpandSleepyIII-1stAdd     09-14 0604</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-6 Miles Up and Sleepy III - 1st Add,0608</SECOND>
<HEAD>BOSTON: month off.</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Airlines, already pinched by deregulatory competition and a pilot shortage, may have trouble staffing their cockpits and paying additional salaries if researchers say pilots should fly reduced schedules. <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> scheduling regulations have changed little since the 1930s, when lumbering prop planes rarely crossed more than one time zone a day. Among those who think they can be improved is <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Lauber </PERSON>, a sleep researcher on the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION>. `` An arbitrary restriction on flight and duty time and mandatory rest time that does n't take into account circadian factors is simply not 20th century,'' he said. `` We know that an hour of sleep is not an hour of sleep, depending on when you take it. One of the biggest improvements we could make in our regulations would be to recognize those factors and adjust schedules appropriately.'' The experts contend that schedules should consider the time of departure, the number of time zones crossed and the direction of travel. -LRB- The body adjusts more quickly when traveling west to east than east to west. -RRB- Another part of the problem is the plane itself. The modern cockpit is a fine place for involuntary slumber. The lights are dim. The seats are comfortable. The air rushes past with a soothing hum. Planes are so automated that they quite literally fly themselves. Except while landing and taking off, there is often little for crew members to do. The newest planes do n't even require a flight engineer, so standard crew size is being reduced from three members to two. Some pilots and sleep experts complain that this increases the odds the entire crew will doze off. `` The fewer people in the cockpit, the fewer safeguards you have,'' said Dr. <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Moore-Ede </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION>, a sleep expert at <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION>. `` It's easier for two people to nod off than three.'' But <PERSON> Delmar </PERSON> <PERSON> Fadden </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> administrator, asserts just the opposite is likely: `` If there are only two in the cockpit, both know that they ca n't rely on a third person, so they are more attentive to the tasks they are doing and are much less likely to allow themselves to go to sleep.'' <PERSON> Fadden </PERSON>, who establishes design requirements for the <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> 747 and 767, said, `` We ca n't do a lot about the fact that the crew might be fatigued. What we try to do is make the airplane tolerant of the crew's reaction.'' This means designing planes to be safe even when flown by bored, drowsy, inattentive pilots. If something goes wrong, such as a generator failure, the plane automatically compensates without waiting for the crew to act. <PERSON> Fadden </PERSON> said some planes being built will monitor their crews. Alarms will sound if pilots do nothing for 20 minutes. Such a lapse of activity could mean the pilots are daydreaming or worse. Another possible solution, used by the British during the <LOCATION> Falkland </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Islands </LOCATION> crisis, is a drug to help pilots sleep before night flights. <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Storm </PERSON>, a psychologist at <ORGANIZATION> Brooks </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Base </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Antonio </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, said the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military is experimenting with the drug temazepam. All of these suggested changes are intended to lessen the chance that cockpit fatigue will combine with bad weather, equipment failure and other random hazards to trigger a disaster. `` We run a very safe air transportation system,'' said <PERSON> Lauber </PERSON>. `` But we are pushing people harder. We know from anecdotal data that people are not as alert as they should be. They are falling asleep in some circumstances. I think it's appropriate that we re-examine the way we approach these things.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880914-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-14-88 0202EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-6Miles-WorkWeek     09-14 0976</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-6 Miles-Work Week,1001</SECOND>
<HEAD>Worst Schedules Leave Pilots Groggy, Inattentive</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-6 Miles Up and Sleepy III</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By FRED BAYLES</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>and</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writers</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
