<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880602-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-02-88 0018EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names CORRECTIVE   06-02 0080</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names, CORRECTIVE,0079</SECOND>
<NOTE>Eds: Members who used the New York-dated last item of PM-Names,
sent as a0433 on June 1, are asked to use the following story.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> erroneously reported Wednesday that <ORGANIZATION> Procter </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ; </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Gamble </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> contributed 56,000 books of baseball cards, valued at $ 500,000 or more, to a fund aimed at helping destitute former players. The contribution of Surf Baseball Card Collectibles to the Baseball Alumni Team was made by <PERSON> Lever </PERSON> <PERSON> Bros </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880602-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-02-88 0018EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--Cuba-Storm     06-02 0118</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Cuba-Storm,0120</SECOND>
<HEAD>Storm Floods Central Cuba, Killing Four People</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MEXICO CITY (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A weeklong storm caused heavy flooding in central <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> that killed four people and forced about 10,000 to evacuate their homes, the Cuban news agency <ORGANIZATION> Prensa </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Latina </ORGANIZATION> reported. An agency dispatch from <LOCATION> Havana </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> Cuban </LOCATION> capital, said Wednesday that flooding occurred in the provinces of <LOCATION> Cienfuegos </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Sancti </PERSON> <PERSON> Spiritus </PERSON>, <PERSON> Villa </PERSON> <PERSON> Clara </PERSON> and <PERSON> Ciego </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Avila </PERSON>. It said the storm produced power outages and paralyzed transportation. The dispatch, monitored here, said the four victims were all from <PERSON> Cienfuegos </PERSON>, which was hit the hardest. It said rescue crews, using helicopters and amphibious vehicles, evacuated about 10,000 people from their homes Wednesday and moved them to higher ground.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880602-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-02-88 0022EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Summit-EvilEmpire Bjt   06-02 0796</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Summit-Evil Empire, Bjt,780</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHINGTON WIRE: Gorbachev Heard What He Wanted To Hear</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP News Analysis</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ALISON SMALE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MOSCOW (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Perhaps the most important thing <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> gave <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> this summit was the statement that he no longer thinks the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> is `` an evil empire.'' As a bonus, to <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s delight, the renunciation came `` within the walls of the <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION>, next to the czar's gun.'' <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s characterization of this vast communist nation in a March 1983 speech unleashed a torrent of comment in the Soviet media at the time, the start of a deep freeze in superpower relations symbolized by the break-off of <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> arms talks in November that year. In a nation that craves international respect, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s criticism was taken as an intensely personal slight His retraction of the comment in remarks Tuesday to reporters at the <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION> was duly remarked upon by <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> at an unprecedented <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> news conference on Wednesday _ a session televised across the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, with excerpts repeated on the evening news. `` Within the walls of the <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION>, next to the czar's gun, right in the heart of the evil empire,'' <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> beamed, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> had responded `` No'' when asked if the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> still deserved the appellation. `` We take note of this,'' added <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>, speaking not just for himself, but for the communist leadership of a nation of 280 million people. It was just weeks after <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> branded the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> an `` evil empire'' that the Soviets launched one of their most ambitious efforts to counteract what they see as malicious American propaganda about a nation of which they are raised to feel supremely proud. On April 25, 1983, then Soviet leader <PERSON> Yuri </PERSON> <PERSON> V. </PERSON> <PERSON> Andropov </PERSON> invited <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION> schoolgirl <PERSON> Samantha </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> to visit his country and see for herself that his people do not want war. In July, <PERSON> Samantha </PERSON>, then 11, came to <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> and was given a topflight tour of the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, visiting <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Leningrad </LOCATION>, and spending four days with Soviet kids at an elite camp for <ORGANIZATION> Young </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pioneers </ORGANIZATION> on the <LOCATION> Black </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sea </LOCATION>. Loaded down with 17 suitcases of presents from Soviets who warmed to her bright smile, <PERSON> Samantha </PERSON> left <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> and delivered the judgment <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> wanted to hear _ that the Soviets `` are almost just like Americans.'' Similar, but less lavish, efforts are expended when <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> peace groups visit the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. Since <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> came to power, these groups have come ever more regularly to `` the evil empire,'' promoting peace and friendship with the Soviets and joining <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> in denouncing the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> president for pushing <ORGANIZATION> Star </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wars </ORGANIZATION> and strengthened Western defenses. With arms talks dead throughout 1984 and cultural contacts at a virtual standstill, these groups were almost the only Americans that Soviets got to see _ and they made sure to put on their best show. The Kremlin, which has long financed a finely tuned, expensive system to train some of the world's premier athletes, even gave up on the chance to prove Soviet prowess that year at the Olympics. <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> boycotted the 1984 <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> extravaganza that in so many ways epitomized the glitzy, we-feel-good-again spirit of <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s first term In January 1985, arms control talks resumed again. In March 1985, <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> came to power, promoting `` new thinking'' in foreign policy and doing a rapid image makeover on Kremlin politicians. The new leader and his wife <PERSON> Raisa </PERSON> had wowed Fleet Street on a trip to <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> in December 1984, astonishing Britons used to dour, dumpy Russians with their lively manners, good humor and handling of the press. With a sure touch sometimes attributed to <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> ally <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON> <PERSON> Yakovlev </PERSON>, now a Politburo member but once a student of <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> ways as ambassador to <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> has successfully projected a new image. Reforms at home, greater openness to the outside world and improved relations with the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> have given the new image substance, adding up to an act that apparently has changed <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s mind about the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> somewhat And <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> can show his home audience that his efforts to mend relations with the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> _ criticized at first by hardliners _ have paid dividends. The <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> 1985 declaration he signed with <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> at their first summit committed <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> to saying that `` a nuclear war must never be fought and can not be won.'' The now-ratified INF treaty removed the danger of <ORGANIZATION> Pershing </ORGANIZATION> 2 missiles reaching <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> in eight minutes from <LOCATION> Western </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>. With the <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> summit, the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> is no longer `` the evil empire,'' even in <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s book. As the president himself explained it, that description belonged to `` another time, another era.''
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Alison </PERSON> <PERSON> Smale </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION>'s chief of bureau for much of <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, covered the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> for four years.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880602-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-02-88 0023EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Summit-ANightOut     06-02 0493</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Summit-A Night Out,490</SECOND>
<HEAD>Reagans Treated To A Night On The Town, Moscow Style</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MASHA HAMILTON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MOSCOW (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Reagans </ORGANIZATION> did up the town, Moscow-style, on their last night here, taking in the ballet at the opulent Bolshoi Theater, dining with the <ORGANIZATION> Gorbachevs </ORGANIZATION> at a dacha owned by the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> and strolling through a moonlit Red Square. With summit business over, President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and Soviet leader <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> seemed in good spirits Wednesday night, moving their seats closer together in the `` Royal Box'' the Soviet and American first couples shared at the Bolshoi and briefly clasping one another's waists as they left the ballet. But their wives, who ruffled one another's feathers earlier in the day during a visit to <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>'s Tretyakov Gallery, appeared cool to one another and did not speak. After their private dinner at the Communist Party-owned country home on the outskirts of western <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Reagans </ORGANIZATION>, holding hands, made an impromptu stop at Red Square, walking on the cobblestone plaza between St. Basil's Cathedral and the Kremlin. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> described his Soviet evening on the town as `` wonderful ... very warm and hospitable.'' He said the couple stopped at Red Square `` because <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> has n't seen it We're leaving tomorrow and I did n't want her to miss it.'' The Reagans leave this morning for <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>, where they will spend a day before returning Friday to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. In the six-tiered, gold and red Bolshoi on Sverdlov Square, the audience of about 2,000, most of them Soviets, applauded the <ORGANIZATION> Reagans </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Gorbachevs </ORGANIZATION> both at the ballet's beginning and again at its end. The dancers also ended their performance by clapping for the leaders and their wives. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> waved back at the audience, both grinning broadly. The Reagans appeared to enjoy the hour and a half of ballet. It was the first night of pure entertainment on their schedule, which had previously included official dinners complete with political toasts and journalists. But even the last evening included a touch of patriotism. American and Soviet flags hung on either side of the `` Royal Box'' at the rear of the theater, and the orchestra played national anthems from both countries before the ballet began. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> mouthed the words of the American anthem while <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> held her right hand at her heart. The Reagans and <PERSON> Raisa </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> used opera glasses to watch the Bolshoi Ballet perform excerpts from `` Sleeping Beauty,'' `` Swan Lake'' and `` Romeo and <PERSON> Juliet </PERSON>.'' The last excerpt was performed by <PERSON> Nine </PERSON> <PERSON> Ananiashvili </PERSON> and <PERSON> Andris </PERSON> <PERSON> Liepa </PERSON>, winners of a 1986 world ballet competition in <LOCATION> Jackson </LOCATION>, Miss. The Bolshoi Theater, founded in 1776, was the first permanent theater in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>, and its ballet and opera companies gained an international reputation in the 1950s and 1960s. Tickets cost about three rubles -LRB- five dollars -RRB- but are nearly impossible for Soviets to obtain without contacts in the theater or luck enough to receive an allocation at their jobs.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880602-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-02-88 0024EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-US-SovietBaseball     06-02 0530</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-US-Soviet Baseball,530</SECOND>
<HEAD>Yanks Beat Reds, 15-2, in Historic Baseball Matchup</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BRIAN FRIEDMAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MOSCOW (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 In a match marked more by good will than athletic prowess, <ORGANIZATION> Johns </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hopkins </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> capitalized on eight errors by a team of Soviet engineers to take a 15-2 victory in the first baseball showdown between the superpowers. Before the historic game, played at the <ORGANIZATION> Lenin </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Komsomol </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Automobile </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Factory </ORGANIZATION> stadium, the <PERSON> Johns </PERSON> <PERSON> Hopkins </PERSON> team presented the Soviets with souvenir T-shirts, and both sides clasped hands and hugged as Western reporters in town for the summit meeting crowded around. President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, busy elsewhere, was unable to throw out the first pitch. A public address announcer chattered away about the rules of baseball, even during play, to a crowd just learning about the sport. But the 300 or so fans still seemed to enjoy the game, cheering lustily when the Soviet team from the D.I. <ORGANIZATION> Mendeleyev </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chemical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Engineering </ORGANIZATION> did well and whistling in derision when it botched a play. <PERSON> Johns </PERSON> <PERSON> Hopkins </PERSON> struck immediately in the first inning when leadoff batter <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Finegan </PERSON> doubled off the left field fence and scored on two successive wild pitches by <PERSON> Alexei </PERSON> <PERSON> Koshivoy </PERSON>. The <ORGANIZATION> Blue </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Jays </ORGANIZATION> put the game out of reach in the third inning, while leading 2-0, when first baseman <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Durocher </PERSON> walked, advanced to second on a Koshivoy wild pitch and scored on a single by second baseman <PERSON> Andy </PERSON> <PERSON> Bernstein </PERSON>. After two successive errors loaded the bases, third baseman <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Horner </PERSON> hit a drive that eluded centerfielder <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON> <PERSON> Krupenchenkov </PERSON> and <PERSON> Horner </PERSON> came all the way home to make the score 7-0. The Soviets did n't get a base runner until the fourth inning and scored their runs in the fifth and seventh innings on errant pickoff attempts. `` It was not our best game,'' said <PERSON> Leonid </PERSON> <PERSON> Korneyev </PERSON>, the Soviets' third baseman The <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> began its baseball program in 1987, in anticipation of baseball becoming an Olympic sport in 1992. A national squad played a team from <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> last summer, but lost by scores of 22-0 and 30-2. Earlier this week, the <PERSON> Johns </PERSON> <PERSON> Hopkins </PERSON> players spent several practice sessions teaching the Soviets the finer points of the game, and although the <ORGANIZATION> Blue </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Jays </ORGANIZATION> praised their competitors' desire and athletic abilities, they expected the game to be a bit of a mismatch. `` They made some outstanding plays out there,'' said <PERSON> Johns </PERSON> <PERSON> Hopkins </PERSON> Coach <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Babb </PERSON>. `` But they still have problems with routine ones.'' <PERSON> Finegan </PERSON>, a senior from <LOCATION> Garden </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION>, praised the Soviets' athletic ability, but noted that `` baseball is a unique sport You need to have skills that are more refined. They also have not seen pitchers that are more refined.'' <PERSON> Johns </PERSON> <PERSON> Hopkins </PERSON> alumnus <PERSON> Max </PERSON> <PERSON> Flaxman </PERSON>, a Moscow-based businessman, was responsible for bringing the Soviets together with the <ORGANIZATION> Blue </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Jays </ORGANIZATION>, who had a 26-12 record this year. He had heard the Soviets were seeking an American squad for some exhibition games, and suggested the <PERSON> Johns </PERSON> <PERSON> Hopkins </PERSON> team. The Soviet media publicized the game, and several newspapers ran stories that caught the spirit of good will. A front-page article in Tuesday's editions of the newspaper Sovietsky Sport carried the headline: `` When the score does n't count.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880602-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-02-88 0028EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Summit-NoSecrets     06-02 0500</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Summit-No Secrets,500</SECOND>
<HEAD>Security Agents Show Off Limos, Pool Guesses on Reagan Departure</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CAROL J. WILLIAMS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>USOVO, U.S.S.R. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Music poured from the front-seat tape deck. <PERSON> Anatoly </PERSON> <PERSON> Kalinin </PERSON> snapped his fingers to the beat, and his friends passed around cigarettes and pictures of their wives for the visiting Americans to see. This was n't an impromptu gathering of youth on the Arbat pedestrian mall, but an assemblage of the usually staid gray-suited security agents who guard Soviet leader <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>. Relaxing during a two-and-a-half hour wait for President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and his wife to finish dinner at a Communist Party-owned dacha outside <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>, a dozen security men bantered with their <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> counterparts, showing off the Zil limousines they travel in and joining in an American betting pool on when the Reagans would emerge from the walled compound. `` At exactly 12 midnight!'' contended an agent identified only as <PERSON> Yevgeny </PERSON>, arguing with an <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> agent who insisted that <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> never stays out that late. `` I'm not just taking a guess, I'm providing you with information,'' <PERSON> Yevgeny </PERSON> stated knowingly. The American stuck by his 11 p.m. estimate, challenging, `` We'll see whose intelligence is better. Some of the security detachment had accompanied <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> in December, but the agents who had never seen <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> showed the most curiosity about life in the other superpower. They compared housing costs, divorce rates and the vastly different attitudes toward smoking in their countries. The Zil tour was impressive for the journalists, who acted as translators between the security squads. The sleek black limos are usually seen flashing past at 60 miles per hour on the broad avenue that leads from this parklike estate to the <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION>. `` This costs 100,000 rubles -LRB- $ 167,000 at the official exchange rate -RRB- here,'' one of the Soviets offered with an aim to impress that would rival any car salesman. `` It's got genuine Karelian birchwood lining on the doors and all around the windows.'' One of the Americans, who did not want to be identified, said that the Soviets were a little tense on the first day of <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s visit, but that the two groups quickly became accustomed to working together on their nearly identical tasks of protecting the leader `` Discipline is discipline and surveillance is surveillance,'' <PERSON> Yevgeny </PERSON> explained, when asked how the two teams worked together. The nattily dressed agents from both superpowers took turns posing for souvenir pictures. Floodlights blinked and a telephone call to the guard shack outside the compound at 10:40 p.m. alerted both teams to the presidential party's intended departure, causing moans from the bettors who had guessed the party would break up later. The agents instantly snapped to attention, with the Soviets diving into the limousines and escort cars and the Americans climbing into their wagons. The entourage got back to business so quickly that the head of the American security detachment had no chance to collect his bet winnings. His guess of 11 p.m. was only six seconds off the mark.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880602-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-02-88 0033EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Nancy     06-02 0577</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nancy,570</SECOND>
<HEAD>Mrs. Reagan `Rolls With Punches' In Uncertainties Of Raisa
Relationship</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Top prospects uncertain.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By SUSANNE M. SCHAFER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MOSCOW (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> has `` learned to roll with the punches'' when dealing with the uncertainties of meeting <PERSON> Raisa </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> and has achieved more balance in their relationship, the first lady's spokeswoman says. The clear impression left after the two strong-willed women squared off in a Soviet art gallery Wednesday was that Mrs. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> has become far more assertive in dealing with the outspoken Soviet first lady. President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and his wife fly to <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> today after wrapping up their summit activities here with a farewell visit to the <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION> and a meeting with <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Embassy employees. They return home Friday after the <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> stopover. For the first time, Mrs. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> acknowledged during a tour of the Tretyakov Gallery's icons that the frosty relationship, the focus of months of intense media scrutiny, is real. `` A Mexican standoff,'' the first lady said with a shrug, when asked how the relationship stood. <PERSON> Elaine </PERSON> <PERSON> Crispen </PERSON>, the first lady's press secretary, later observed, `` They are from two totally different worlds.'' Under a veneer of politeness, the two first ladies engaged in an intense competition for the spotlight. `` I want to say something. I want to say something now, OK?'' Mrs. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> insisted sharply one point as Mrs. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> attempted to stop reporters from questioning the American first lady. Mrs. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> backed away, but pointedly looked at her watch as the first lady chatted with members of the White House press corps. When Mrs. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> tried to break in again and start the gallery tour, Mrs. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> rebuffed her and returned to her conversation with reporters. On the surface, things were pleasant enough, but the delicately arched eyebrows and strained smiles told a far different story. Instead of strolling hand-in-hand as they had at events earlier this week, the two women apparently had decided to show more of their true feelings. It brought to mind a similar encounter during the December summit in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, when Mrs. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> dominated a White House tour by seeking out the press with lengthy commentaries on history, art and political life, as Mrs. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> was left trying to get her long-planned tour under way. During Wednesday's session with reporters, Mrs. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> and her Soviet aides kept changing the arrangements for the event, <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> aides said. Instead of meeting Mrs. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> as planned by the outside door of the gallery, Mrs. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> had come to the special vault where they were to view the art and talked at length with the press corps. Mrs. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> has learned to be flexible with the Soviets at Mrs. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s events, Mrs. <PERSON> Crispen </PERSON> said. `` She's learned to roll with the punches,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Crispen </PERSON> said. Noting that Mrs. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> has spoken out more in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> than she did at the December summit, Mrs. <PERSON> Crispen </PERSON> said she believed they now had `` more balance'' and equality in their relationship. Not surprisingly, the first lady said that her five days of exposure to the glories of <LOCATION> Russian </LOCATION> art and architecture wo n't change her mind about the Soviet system `` We have two different ways of living, two different philosophies,'' she said. One day earlier, Mrs. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> had termed the Soviet system a `` more controlled'' society than the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. Asked if she'd become a convert to communism during her stay here, the first lady gave a hearty laugh, saying, `` Oh, no!''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880602-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-02-88 0017EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Hallmark-AlcoholCards     06-02 0261</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Hallmark-Alcohol Cards,0269</SECOND>
<HEAD>Cardmaker Halts Shipment Of Alcohol-Related Graduation Cards</HEAD>
<DATELINE>KANSAS CITY, Mo. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Hallmark Cards will stop making graduation cards that emphasize drinking, following protests by a <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> chapter of <ORGANIZATION> Mothers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Against </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Drunk </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Driving </ORGANIZATION>, the company said Wednesay. <PERSON> Diane </PERSON> <PERSON> Wall </PERSON>, a spokeswoman for the <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> City-based card manufacturer, said the company decided Tuesday `` to discontinue manufacturing and shipping alcohol-related graduation cards.'' The controversy started last week in <LOCATION> Huntington </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, when <ORGANIZATION> Edison </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> High </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> parents showed <ORGANIZATION> MADD </ORGANIZATION> officals a card depicting a refrigerator filled with Coors beer and a single egg. `` Do n't go to graduation without a good breakfast first,'' the card reads. Another card suggests that graduates wear loose-fitting gowns so they can `` hide at least two bottles of champagne underneath.'' `` How can a company, which advertises, ` When you care enough to send the very best, send Hallmark,' produce cards which encourage alcohol and drunken driving?'' asked <PERSON> Janet </PERSON> <PERSON> Cater </PERSON>, director of the <ORGANIZATION> Orange </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> chapter of Mothers Against Drunk Driving. Ms. <PERSON> Cater </PERSON> said Tuesday's decision was insufficient because the cards are still available in some stores. However, Ms. <PERSON> Wall </PERSON> said graduation season is coming to an end and `` most of the cards will come down very shortly.'' Ms. <PERSON> Wall </PERSON> said she did not have exact figures on the number of graduation cards that had reference to alcohol. `` Hallmark offers about 600 graduation card designs, and less than 1 percent deal with alcohol-related subject matter,'' she said. `` It is a very small percentage.'' She said the complaints that spurred the company's action came primarily from <LOCATION> Orange </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880602-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-02-88 0034EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Summit-Refuseniks     06-02 0377</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Summit-Refuseniks,380</SECOND>
<HEAD>Diplomatic Sources Say 28 Refusenik Cases Unresolved</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARK J. PORUBCANSKY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MOSCOW (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A Western diplomatic source says 28 refusenik cases have not been resolved, contrary to information from Soviet Jewish leaders that the cases were cleared for emigration as a result of meetings between <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and Soviet officials. The source, speaking on condition of anonymity, said the Jewish leaders had evidently misunderstood the situation. The confusion arose over a meeting between Assistant Secretary of State <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Schifter </PERSON> and a group of six refuseniks Wednesday morning. Refusenik scientist <PERSON> Yuli </PERSON> <PERSON> Kosharovsky </PERSON> showed reporters a list of 400 names that he said had been submitted to <PERSON> Schifter </PERSON> on Saturday for discussion with Soviet officials at meetings during the <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> summit. He said <PERSON> Schifter </PERSON> told the group that 28 of the cases had been solved in the meetings taking place during the <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> summit between President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and Soviet leader <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>. But the Western diplomatic source said later that no cases had been solved. Other refusenik sources said more than a dozen families from <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Leningrad </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Kiev </LOCATION> had received permission to emigrate in the past 10 days. <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> refusenik <PERSON> Bella </PERSON> <PERSON> Gulko </PERSON> said the <PERSON> Boris </PERSON> <PERSON> Weinshtock </PERSON> and <PERSON> Iosif </PERSON> <PERSON> Pilmenshtein </PERSON> families of <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> had received permission to emigrate this week. <PERSON> Refusenik </PERSON> <PERSON> Sergei </PERSON> <PERSON> Mkrtchyan </PERSON>, who demonstrated daily in downtown <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> with his wife and year-old daughter last week, said he was summoned to the <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> visa office on Saturday and was told he could leave the country on Monday. <PERSON> Mkrtchyan </PERSON> said he knew of three <LOCATION> Kiev </LOCATION> families who also had received permission to leave the country. About 40 other refuseniks, many of them accompanied by their children, held a peaceful, half-hour demonstration Wednesday within sight of the <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION>, waving banners demanding that they be allowed to emigrate. An agency helping Jewish emigres said in <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> on Wednesday that the number allowed to leave the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> reached 1,145 in May, a seven-year high. The May figure was the fourth straight monthly increase and brought the total for 1988 to 4,547, said the <ORGANIZATION> Intergovernmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Migration </ORGANIZATION>. More than 8,000 Jews were permitted to emigrate in 1987, a sharp increase from previous years but far below the peak of more than 51,000 in 1979.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880602-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-02-88 0034EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Summit-Quotes     06-02 0118</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Summit-Quotes,</SECOND>
<HEAD>With PM-Summit Rdp Bjt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MOSCOW (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
</TEXT>
<HEAD>REAGAN:</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 `` I just have to believe that in any government some of us do find ourselves bound in by bureaucracy'' -LRB- describing emigration problems in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> -RRB-.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>___</HEAD>
<HEAD>GORBACHEV:</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 `` He said no and he said this within the walls of the <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION>, right in the heart of the evil empire.'' -LRB- on whether <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> still though of the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> as an `` evil empire'' -RRB-.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>___</HEAD>
<HEAD>MRS. REAGAN:</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 `` I want to say something. I want to say something now, OK?'' -LRB- cutting in after Mrs. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> attempted to stop reporters from questioning her -RRB-.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880602-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-02-88 0040EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Reagan-Thatcher Bjt   06-02 0708</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Reagan-Thatcher, Bjt,700</SECOND>
<HEAD>Reagan's First Post-Summit Stop: A Call on a Close Friend</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MAUREEN JOHNSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The relationship has never been more special. So it is only natural that President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> is visiting <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON>, his ideological soulmate and closest foreign ally, to tell her about the <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> summit. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s two-day visit, another boost to the <LOCATION> British </LOCATION> prime minister's prestige on the international stage, comes six months after Soviet leader <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> stopped off to confer with her en route to the <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> superpower summit. Today's is <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s third and probably last visit as president to a prime minister of whom he said recently, `` We're very good friends and it is a friendship I treasure very much.'' He will confer with Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> at her No. 10 Downing St. residence, dine there tonight and make a speech Friday on East-West relations before returning home. For <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> British </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conservative </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> leader has been a sometimes costly, occasionally reproving but super-loyal friend. She rarely criticizes him. Asked in <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION> about revelations about astrology in the <LOCATION> White </LOCATION> <LOCATION> House </LOCATION>, all she would say was: `` I come under <PERSON> Libra </PERSON>, which is a very balanced sign.'' The Anglo-American bond, rooted in a common language, heritage and alliances in two world wars, is the cornerstone of her foreign policy. She stood alone in backing the 1986 <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> bombing raid on <LOCATION> Libya </LOCATION>; followed <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> out of <ORGANIZATION> UNESCO </ORGANIZATION> in 1985; was the first to deploy <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> cruise missiles in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> in 1983, and last year, when the superpowers agreed to remove the missiles, she put aside her reservations and gave the deal a ringing endorsement. When other European leaders in the 16-nation <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> alliance sometimes grumble about <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> domination, Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON>'s response is blunt. `` She's the largest, most prosperous nation in the world, and let's be thankful she has taken a leadership role,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> said in a radio interview in March. `` None of us can substitute for it. We could all help with it.'' Her <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> policy draws opposition taunts of `` <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s poodle,'' to which she retorts: `` I do n't think I would make a very good poodle. I might be more a sort of bulldog.'' However, some analysts see her as having subtly moved into a prime role in <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION>, using both her special influence with <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and, more recently, her good relations with <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> to exercise power. Elected to office 18 months before <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and recently re-elected for an unprecedented third consecutive term, 62-year-old Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> is the senior stateswoman of the Western world. She shares <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s hostility to communism and belief in free markets. She fervently believes nuclear weapons are peacekeepers. After <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> flirted with the idea of a non-nuclear world at the 1986 summit at <LOCATION> Reykjavik </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Iceland </LOCATION>, Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> sped to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> to make sure he did n't carry disarmament too far _ without consulting his allies. At her instigation, <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> leaders held a special summit before <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s latest meeting in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> with <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>. She said the aim was to demonstrate Western unity and show `` that the president is always seen consulting his <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> allies.'' There have been some disagreements. In 1982, when <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> sought to withhold U.S.-originated technology from a Soviet natural gas pipeline, Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> ordered British companies to fulfill their contracts despite the threat of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> sanctions. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> backed off, after Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> complained publicly she felt `` deeply wounded by a friend.'' A year later, Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> criticized the U.S.-led invasion of <LOCATION> Grenada </LOCATION> to overthrow Marxist coup leaders in the former British colony, saying `` You just do n't walk into countries like that.'' More recently, she has chided the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> about its budget deficit, making disapproving comparisons with her own stringent policies which have produced a budget surplus. But she has never shied away from backing the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> in a crisis, even when it has left her isolated. She says she has never forgotten that <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> put his entire Latin American policy at risk to support <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> in the 1982 <LOCATION> Falkland </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Islands </LOCATION> war against <LOCATION> Argentina </LOCATION>. In April 1986 she braved uproar in <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION> for allowing <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> to use British-based bombers in the raid on <LOCATION> Libya </LOCATION>, when other <LOCATION> European </LOCATION> allies had refused to help. She declared, `` I believe friendship is two ways.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880602-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-02-88 0042EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-McCarthy-Presidency     06-02 0452</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-McCarthy-Presidency,450</SECOND>
<HEAD>Eugene McCarthy Running For President At 72</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LEE LINDER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PHILADELPHIA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Eugene </PERSON> <PERSON> McCarthy </PERSON>, whose presidential candidacy two decades ago helped galvanize opposition to the <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> War, has placed himself in the running again this year at the age of 72. `` This year the one thing we have to do is shake up the two-party system, and that's what I hope to do,'' the silver-haired <PERSON> McCarthy </PERSON> told reporters and onlookers Wednesday near Independence Hall. `` There is no real choice between Democrats and Republicans.'' <PERSON> McCarthy </PERSON> dismissed the expected <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> nominee, Vice President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, and his likely Democratic opponent, <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>. `` There are two kinds of people who do n't make good presidents,'' he said, `` vice presidents and governors.'' The former senator, whose anti-war campaign in 1968 helped bring down President <PERSON> Lyndon </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>, is running this year on the Consumer Party ticket. In <PERSON> McCarthy </PERSON>'s first campaign, fellow Minnesotan <PERSON> Hubert </PERSON> <PERSON> Humphrey </PERSON> won the Democratic nomination and Republican <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> won the election. <PERSON> McCarthy </PERSON> also tried for the Democratic presidential nomination in 1972 and ran as an independent in 1976. This time he hopes to be on the ballot in at least 30 states. <PERSON> McCarthy </PERSON> said his latest candidacy was not a futile gesture. `` Sure I've lost before, but I did n't feel I wasted my time, and I expect to have a significant impact,'' <PERSON> McCarthy </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Max </PERSON> <PERSON> Weiner </PERSON>, who founded the <ORGANIZATION> Consumer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> in 1967 in <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION>, said: `` We think both the Democrats and Republicans have failed the country, and that we are an alternative, not a spoiler. We'll give the voters an alternative. Millions do n't want to vote for anyone, and we think that <PERSON> McCarthy </PERSON> will attract them.'' The party has about 4,000 members, almost all in <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION>. Its platform calls for guaranteed jobs for all Americans, sharp reductions in the military budget, passage of the Equal Rights Amendment and provision of affordable housing for everyone. The party's most successful candidate to date has been <PERSON> Weiner </PERSON>, a 1987 candidate for <ORGANIZATION> Philadelphia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Weiner </PERSON> won 21 percent of the vote, which was not enough for a seat. The party affiliated itself with the campaigns of <ORGANIZATION> Citizens </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> candidates <PERSON> Barry </PERSON> <PERSON> Commoner </PERSON> and <PERSON> Sonia </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> in the 1980 and 1984 presidential campaigns. <PERSON> Lance </PERSON> <PERSON> Haver </PERSON>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Pennsylvania </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Consumer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, said <PERSON> McCarthy </PERSON> would be formally nominated at a convention in <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION> late this summer. No date was announced. <PERSON> Haver </PERSON> said that he expected <LOCATION> Florence </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rice </LOCATION>, who founded the <ORGANIZATION> Harlem </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Consumer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Education </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> based in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, to be the party's vice presidential nominee. But <PERSON> McCarthy </PERSON>, who says the vice presidency should be abolished, said he expected there would be different running mates in different states.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880602-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-02-88 0153EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Hastings-Impeach     06-02 0515</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Hastings-Impeach,510</SECOND>
<HEAD>FBI Agent Says Judge Hastings Leaked Wiretap Information</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto WX7</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TOM SEPPY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Three major investigations in the <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> area broke off in 1985 when wiretap information was allegedly leaked by <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> Alcee </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Hastings </PERSON>, an <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> agent told a <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> subcommittee conducting impeachment proceedings against the judge. `` There is nothing to lead me to believe that it could have been any other source than Judge <PERSON> Hastings </PERSON>,'' agent <PERSON> Christopher </PERSON> <PERSON> Mazzella </PERSON> testified Wednesday before the subcommittee on criminal justice. <PERSON> Mazzella </PERSON> said the three investigations into labor racketeering and public corruption had to be ended for fear of endangering the lives of undercover agents and informants. He said <PERSON> Hastings </PERSON> approved a 30-day wiretap on July 15, 1985, and received `` progress reports'' on it every seven days. On Aug. 15, the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> applied to <PERSON> Hastings </PERSON> for an extension of the tap, attaching an affidavit containing references to <LOCATION> Dade </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> Mayor <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Clark </PERSON> and a man named <PERSON> Kevin </PERSON> `` Waxy'' <PERSON> Gordon </PERSON>, who was a target of one of the probes. <PERSON> Mazzella </PERSON>, who was in charge of the probes, said the investigations became tainted when <PERSON> Clark </PERSON> told <PERSON> Gordon </PERSON> of information he said he received from <PERSON> Hastings </PERSON>. <PERSON> Gordon </PERSON> surmised that the only way anyone would know the information was from a wiretap. <PERSON> Mazzella </PERSON> said the cases involved the local longshoremen's union in zoning code cases in <LOCATION> Hialeah </LOCATION> and police selling drugs in <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Village </LOCATION>. He said the wiretap was involved in all three cases. <PERSON> Hastings </PERSON>, who still sits on the federal bench in <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION>, has not had a chance to rebut the allegations before the subcommittee. He refused to discuss the case Wednesday with reporters outside the hearing room. <PERSON> Mazzella </PERSON> said he could not find any statement to a law enforcement officer in which <PERSON> Hastings </PERSON> either confirmed or denied the allegations. The agent said reporter <PERSON> Bryan </PERSON> <PERSON> Duffy </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Miami </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Herald </ORGANIZATION> told the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> he discussed the allegation with <PERSON> Hastings </PERSON> on March 25, 1986, but that <PERSON> Hastings </PERSON> did not say whether he was the source of the leak. The impeachment proceedings against <PERSON> Hastings </PERSON> stem from a bribery case in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> involving <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> attorney <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Borders </PERSON>. Borders was convicted in 1982 of arranging a $ 150,000 bribe for <PERSON> Hastings </PERSON> in exchange for modifying the sentences of two convicted racketeers. In a separate trial in 1983, <PERSON> Hastings </PERSON> was acquitted of the bribery conspiracy charges. But a five-member panel of the Atlanta-based 11th <ORGANIZATION> Circuit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appeals </ORGANIZATION>, which covers <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>, concluded there was convincing evidence that <PERSON> Hastings </PERSON> actually took part in the bribery scheme and then attempted a cover-up by lying under oath and manufacturing evidence. The panel's findings were endorsed unanimously by the <ORGANIZATION> Judicial </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conference </ORGANIZATION> of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, the chief policy-making body of the federal judiciary, and forwarded to <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> leaders in March 1987 with the advice that `` consideration of impeachment may be warranted.'' The judiciary subcommittee must determine whether <PERSON> Hastings </PERSON> committed the `` high crimes and misdemeanors'' that warrant impeachment. If <PERSON> Hastings </PERSON> is impeached by the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> will conduct a trial to determine whether he should be removed from office.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880602-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-02-88 0156EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-WeatherRadar     06-02 0645</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Weather Radar,650</SECOND>
<HEAD>New Radars Will Sharpen America's Weather Eye</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RANDOLPH E. SCHMID</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> will turn a sharper eye to the weather in the next few years with the installation of a snazzy new radar system jointly funded by a quartet of federal agencies. The new radar will allow meteorologists, for the first time, to see the formation of tornadoes before they reach the ground. They also will be better able to pinpoint the landing site of hurricanes, predict floods and measure the flow of wind, weather scientists say. The first Next Generation Weather Radar installation is under way at <LOCATION> Norman </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Okla. </LOCATION>, with as many as 175 to follow by the mid-1990s, officials of <ORGANIZATION> Unisys </ORGANIZATION>, the private company building the system, reported Wednesday. The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Weather </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aviation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Weather </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Naval </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Oceanographic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> are anteing up $ 450 million for the new system, dubbed NEXRAD. Under development for eight years, the first system was tested at a <ORGANIZATION> Unisys </ORGANIZATION> facility in <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION> before the <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION> installation, expected to be operational in thefall. <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION>, one of the nation's leading areas for tornadoes, will test the new radar's `` unique capability to identify rotating wind patterns within storms,'' according to <PERSON> Kurt </PERSON> <PERSON> Merl </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> Unisys </ORGANIZATION>. While current radar detects only the amount of moisture in the air, the new one can follow its movement. Thus, an operator seeing wind rushing away from him, right next to a severe gust heading toward him, will recognize the signature of a rotating movement, the first sign of tornado development, said <PERSON> Les </PERSON> <PERSON> Lemon </PERSON>, a former <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Oceanic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Atmospheric </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> researcher now directing the radar development program for <ORGANIZATION> Unisys </ORGANIZATION>. Radar tests have shown that movement can be seen in mid-level clouds, before the twister reaches down for the ground. This means warning time could be expanded to `` tens of minutes,'' <PERSON> Lemon </PERSON> said. Currently the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Weather </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> issues a tornado watch when conditions exist which could spawn a tornado, but ground spotters have to spot the tornadoes to issue actual warnings. The new system could cut false alarms in half, <PERSON> Lemon </PERSON> added. NEXRAD will replace a 30-year-old radar system that provides only limited weather data. <PERSON> Merl </PERSON> said the NEXRAD installations also will be coupled with on-ground rain gauges to measure precipitation for forecast areas where flooding is likely, a system that should improve warnings in flood-prone areas. In addition, <PERSON> Lemon </PERSON> noted that the system will be able to measure the winds within hurricanes within its 145-mile range. With that information, meteorologists will be better able to predict the course of hurricanes to give warnings about where they will strike land, and also to estimate the wind and surge of sea water being pushed ahead of the storm. The system's 28-foot radar dish, enclosed in a fiberglass dome, draws a profile of the air from the surface up to 70,000 feet every six minutes, <PERSON> Lemon </PERSON> explained, providing detailed information even in clear air. Many radars can not detect clear air movement, only air with water vapor or dust or some other debris to reflect the signal. The radar uses the Doppler effect, which depends on a change in frequency in a radio wave. The pencil-thin wave is sent out at a constant frequency, and bounces back off clouds, moving air, dust or whatever it strikes. There is a subtle change of frequency in signals bouncing off something coming toward the radar compared to things moving away. It's the same principle that causes a police or ambulance siren to have a slightly lower pitch when the vehicle is driving away from listeners than it does when coming toward them. <PERSON> Merl </PERSON> also said research is under way for short-range Doppler radar systems at airports to detect local wind shears, sudden shifts in wind speed and direction that have caused several airplane crashes in recent years.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880602-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-02-88 0158EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-AirForceInventory     06-02 0433</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Air Force Inventory,440</SECOND>
<HEAD>GAO Says Air Force Inventory Accuracy Problems Continue</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JAMES HANNAH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION>'s inability to keep track of its huge equipment and supply inventory has resulted in excessive purchases costing `` billions of tax dollars,'' a senator says. Sen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Ohio </LOCATION>, on Wednesday released a report by the <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Accounting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> concluding that the accuracy of <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> inventory records continues to be a problem despite improvements in inventory control. The report also said the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> continues to have difficulty determining the causes of inventory inaccuracies and that physical security of the supplies needs to be improved. <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Governmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Affairs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, said <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> supply items and repair parts are worth more than $ 21 billion. `` While many of these parts are essential to keeping our planes in the air, poor inventory control has resulted in excessive supply purchases costing billions of tax dollars,'' said <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON>. `` The <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> needs to straighten up and fly right when it comes to inventory management.'' The <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION> study was based on audits of the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Logistics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Command </ORGANIZATION> headquartered at <ORGANIZATION> Wright-Patterson </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Base </ORGANIZATION> near <LOCATION> Dayton </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, and air logistics centers in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Antonio </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Sacramento </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>; and <PERSON> Ogden </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION>, the investigative arm of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, said the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION>'s adjustment policy allows inventory records and on-hand supplies to remain out of balance by as much as 10 percent and $ 4,999 `` Air Force item managers continue to adjust inventory records without performing adequate research to identify the primary cause for discrepancies,'' the <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION> said. `` The risk in this policy is that the records may be erroneously adjusted, possibly resulting in apparent shortages of needed items which are actually on hand, or excess procurements.'' The <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION> also said the physical security at the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> centers in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Antonio </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Sacramento </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Ogden </LOCATION> needs to be improved to lessen the risk of theft. It said the storage buildings at <LOCATION> Sacramento </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Ogden </LOCATION> are not separately surrounded by security fencing and that privately owned and contractor vehicles are permitted to park right next to warehouses at all three centers. <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Katzen </PERSON>, a deputy assistant secretary of defense at the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION>, said there have been steady and significant improvements in inventory accuracy at the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION>, with accuracy rates approaching 95 percent. `` While these improvements are commendable, the department recognizes that problems still exist that require continued dedication and vigilance,'' <PERSON> Katzen </PERSON> said in a March 17 letter to the <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION>. `` The department is pursuing its aggressive action plan to continue improving the process.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880602-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-02-88 0200EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-AgingAircraft     06-02 0569</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Aging Aircraft,560</SECOND>
<HEAD>Conference Focuses On When Aging Aircraft Should Be Retired</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto WX8</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By H. JOSEF HEBERT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A long-held industry axiom that a jetliner can fly many years beyond its initial design life if maintained and inspected properly is coming under closer scrutiny, say some participants in a three-day conference on aging aircraft. It is only one of many technical issues being debated by more than 350 aircraft design and maintenance experts meeting at the FAA-sponsored conference that began Wednesday. The participants represent airlines, aircraft manufacturers, government and aviation safety groups. All were brought together because of an increased concern about the safety of older jetliners since the in-flight breakup of a 19-year-old <ORGANIZATION> Aloha </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> 737 in April. A 20-foot section of the plane tore away at 24,000 feet and a flight attendant was swept to her death, although the pilots managed to land the aircraft safely. <ORGANIZATION> Aloha </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> officials have said repeatedly that they followed all required inspections on the jetliner. <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> Administrator <PERSON> Allan </PERSON> <PERSON> McArtor </PERSON> said that until the federal investigation into the incident is concluded, he could not say whether <PERSON> Aloha </PERSON> violated any <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> requirements in connection with the plane. But <PERSON> McArtor </PERSON> said during a break in the conference Wednesday that a key question that must be resolved in the coming months is whether to continue the current philosophy that relies heavily on inspections or shift the focus to a system of mandatory repairs or, at some point, mandatory aircraft retirement. In the case of <LOCATION> Aloha </LOCATION>, inspectors from both the airlines and the <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> failed to detect the cracking and corrosion that is believed to have caused the breakup. `` I think we might find that the procedures are adequate, but I'm not convinced the procedures are being done with as much discipline as we might expect,'' <PERSON> McArtor </PERSON> told reporters. He said the conference is likely to spawn additional, private sessions among industry experts in the coming months on aircraft design, the human pitfalls in the inspection process and whether new federal requirements might be needed. Rep. <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Glickman </PERSON>, D-Kan., one of several congressmen to address the industry group, said that the <LOCATION> Aloha </LOCATION> incident demonstrates `` the inadequacies of the <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION>'s maintenance inspection system. <PERSON> Glickman </PERSON> suggested that the <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> must increase its research and development programs on aging aircraft and that the agency should buy old jetliners to determine how long they can be considered to be safe. `` Only by answering the question ` How long can airplanes really last?' will we be able to put into place guidelines which could save thousands of lives,'' <PERSON> Glickman </PERSON> told the conference. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Enders </PERSON>, an aviation consultant for the <ORGANIZATION> Flight </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION>, suggested in an interview that the <LOCATION> Aloha </LOCATION> accident will prompt increased debate over `` whether the economic life of an airplane'' should remain as dominant a factor as it has been in determining when a plane should be taken out of service. Before the Aloha accident `` generally there was a feeling that you can fly a plane indefinitely'' as long as it is properly maintained and inspected, said <PERSON> Enders </PERSON>, suggesting this philosophy may be changing. But <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Hoover </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transport </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, the airline trade group, reiterated that with proper maintenance and inspections aircraft `` can fly safely throughout their economically useful life.'' The Aloha plane was one of the oldest <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> 737s in service and had accumulated nearly 90,000 takeoffs and landings.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880602-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-02-88 0035EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-OliverNorth     06-02 0453</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Oliver North,0466</SECOND>
<HEAD>One Marine Stumps for California GOP Congressional Hopeful</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LAUREN BLAU</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LONG BEACH, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> <PERSON> North </PERSON> brought his unabashedly patriotic message to <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> on Wednesday, lending his conservative star status to the congressional campaign of an old White House buddy. North, the former <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> lieutenant colonel who faces federal conspiracy charges for his role in the Iran-Contra affair, sounded themes of freedom, military might and family values in urging election of conservative Republican <PERSON> Dana </PERSON> <PERSON> Rohrabacher </PERSON> to the state's 42nd Congressional District `` Freedom is not free, it must be won, preserved and defended, again and again,'' <PERSON> North </PERSON> told a cheering crowd of about 100 at a late-morning rally at a hangar at <LOCATION> Long </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION>. He urged voters to return a conservative majority to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> that will support continued military spending, saying, `` Freedom is only as strong as its defenders.'' North, sporting his trademark crew cut and gap-toothed grin and attired in a civilian gray suit, ignored about a dozen sign-toting protesters who shouted at him as left the hangar and got into a waiting car. was making his first campaign appearance ever and his second formal public speech since the Iran-Contra hearings, said <PERSON> Rohrabacher </PERSON> spokesman <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Rule </PERSON> said <PERSON> North </PERSON> was to attend fund-raisers for <PERSON> Rohrabacher </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Pasadena </LOCATION>, then address a $ 250-a-person dinner for <PERSON> Rohrabacher </PERSON> at the Spruce Goose. Participants were invited to donate $ 1,000 to attend a reception next door on the ocean liner Queen <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> and have a picture taken with <PERSON> North </PERSON>. He was set to spend Thursday campaigning for <PERSON> Christopher </PERSON> <PERSON> Cox </PERSON>, a candidate in the 40th Congressional District Republican primary. <PERSON> Cox </PERSON>, 35, of <LOCATION> Newport </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION>, was senior associate counsel for President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> from 1986 to this year, when he resigned to seek election. The front-runner in the crowded 42nd District race, <LOCATION> Orange </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> supervisor <PERSON> Harriet </PERSON> <PERSON> Wieder </PERSON>, denounced <PERSON> North </PERSON>'s visit as a `` mercenary'' effort on behalf of <PERSON> Rohrabacher </PERSON>, 40, whom <PERSON> North </PERSON> knew as a special assistant and senior speechwriter for President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> from 1981 to 1988. `` <PERSON> Rohrabacher </PERSON> is just snuggling up to <PERSON> Ollie </PERSON> and president,'' Ms. <PERSON> Wieder </PERSON> said. `` What does <PERSON> Ollie </PERSON> <PERSON> North </PERSON> know about issues in this congressional district?'' At a news conference before <PERSON> North </PERSON> appeared Wednesday, <PERSON> Rohrabacher </PERSON> rejected suggestions that voters might react negatively to a man facing criminal charges. `` I think that if people in the district consider that <PERSON> Ollie </PERSON> <PERSON> North </PERSON> is for me, maybe they should be too,'' he said. The candidate said he doubted voters would object to support from <PERSON> North </PERSON>, who was indicted by a federal grand jury on charges of conspiracy to defraud the government for his role in selling arms <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> and using the profits to support the Contra rebels in Marxist <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880602-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-02-88 0203EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Asbestos-Schools     06-02 0519</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Asbestos-Schools,510</SECOND>
<HEAD>EPA Asbestos Training Program Falls Down On Job, Witnesses Say</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID GOELLER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A government program aimed at training contractors to remove deadly asbestos from public schools is turning out inexperienced people who can still get by with shoddy work while scoffing at health concerns, witnesses told a <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> subcommittee. `` We can not feel confident about the current state of contractor accreditation,'' <PERSON> Emil </PERSON> <PERSON> DeVito </PERSON>, president of <ORGANIZATION> Fidelity </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Insurance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, said in a letter to Rep. <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Synar </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Okla </LOCATION>., chairman of the Government Operations subcommittee on environment, energy and natural resources <PERSON> DeVito </PERSON> said his <ORGANIZATION> Princeton </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> N.J. </LOCATION>, company has refused to insure 30 of the 105 government-accredited contractors seeking coverage. The accreditation program was set up by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> in 1986 in response to widespread reports that untrained people were doing removal work, frequently making a bad situation worse by improper procedures that filled the air with asbestos fibers that cause lung cancer. The 240 instruction centers around the nation are turning out some 2,000 inspectors and contractors monthly who are certified by the <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION>. The 1986 law requires that school districts hire only certified firms and at least begin asbestos removal work by July 1989. <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> estimates that some 30,000 schools could need asbestos work. <PERSON> Synar </PERSON> said the testimony could strengthen efforts of a sizable number of lawmakers and local school boards to amend the law to delay the mandatory asbestos removal beyond July 1989. <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Kitchen </PERSON> of the <LOCATION> Johnstown </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION>, school board told the subcommittee's hearing Wednesday that when he took an EPA-approved course, he encountered lackadaisical attitudes and instructors who questioned the proven dangers of asbestos fibers. <PERSON> DeVito </PERSON> said the background of many course instructors `` is flimsy at best.'' He said there is no requirement that a contractor have any experience, meaning anyone can get into the removal business after five days of training. Even if the training is good, <PERSON> DeVito </PERSON> said, there is no guarantee that contractors will not try to boost profits by cutting corners because they know <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> and the states can not inspect all removal work. `` The programs are not tough enough,'' <PERSON> DeVito </PERSON> said. `` As a result of the weaknesses with <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION>'s accreditation of contractors, FEIC is essentially accrediting every contractor and approving each job the company insures.'' Kitchen said students at the course he took joked about health concerns and made comments like `` we're going to be laughing all the way to the bank.'' `` The courses themselves do not approach the subject matter in a serious way,'' he maintained. Kitchen said one principal lecturer questioned health concerns about asbestos and that students were given an <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> publication that `` espouses the -LRB- asbestos -RRB- industry viewpoint that there is a safe level of exposure'' to a substance that health experts say has no safe level. Asked by <PERSON> Synar </PERSON> to comment on <PERSON> DeVito </PERSON>'s letter, Assistant <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> Administrator <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Moore </PERSON> described it as `` disquieting.'' <PERSON> Susan </PERSON> <PERSON> Vogt </PERSON>, deputy director of the <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION>'s office of toxic substances, said that while the agency audits an accreditation course once, `` it is an unfortunate fact'' that <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> lacks the manpower to do continued monitoring.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880602-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-02-88 0036EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Obit-Hurkos 1stLd-Writethru a0910 06-02 0425</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Obit-Hurkos, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0910,0432</SECOND>
<HEAD>Dutch Psychic Peter Hurkos Dead at 77</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: LEADS with 7 grafs to UPDATE with Hurkos maintaining
Strangler's innocence, details on Manson case; picks up 6th graf:
`Hurkos reportedly ...</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By BARBARA METZLER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Dutch psychic detective <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Hurkos </PERSON>, who helped authorities seek clues in the <PERSON> Manson </PERSON> family murders and the <ORGANIZATION> Boston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Strangler </ORGANIZATION> case, died of a heart attack Wednesday, his publicist said. He was 77. <PERSON> Hurkos </PERSON>, who had part of his cancerous right lung removed in April, had just left his doctor's office when he was stricken in the hallway of a medical complex near <ORGANIZATION> Cedars-Sinai </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>, said publicist <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Silver </PERSON>. He was best known for helping authorities in the 1969 <PERSON> Manson </PERSON> family murders of actress <PERSON> Sharon </PERSON> <PERSON> Tate </PERSON> and supermarket owner <PERSON> Leno </PERSON> <PERSON> LaBianca </PERSON> and his wife, <PERSON> Rosemary </PERSON>. <PERSON> Hurkos </PERSON> reportedly told authorities the person responsible for the murders was a bearded man named <PERSON> Charlie </PERSON>, according to `` The Psychic World of <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Hurkos </PERSON>'' by <PERSON> Norma </PERSON> <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Browning </PERSON>, published in 1970. The book also detailed <PERSON> Hurkos </PERSON>' involvement in the Strangler case of 1964, which later was made into a movie starring <PERSON> Tony </PERSON> <PERSON> Curtis </PERSON>. <PERSON> Hurkos </PERSON> refused to budge from his position that a man he picked as the <ORGANIZATION> Boston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Strangler </ORGANIZATION> was the killer and that confessed strangler <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> DeSalvo </PERSON> was not, the author wrote. `` He was very helpful in any of the police things that he worked on. Why did he go into it? Because he could felt that he probably could contribute.'' Ms. <PERSON> Silver </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Hurkos </PERSON> reportedly became psychic in 1941 after falling from a ladder and suffering a brain injury. On regaining consciousness, he realized he had `` an ability to pierce the barriers that separate the past, present and future,'' his biography states. <PERSON> Hurkos </PERSON> said he was able to see things by touching objects. `` I see pictures in my mind like a television screen. When I touch something, I can then tell what I see,'' he said. He made appearances on several television talk shows and appeared in the motion pictures `` The Amazing World of Psychic Phenomena,'' `` Mysterious Monsters,'' `` Now I Lay Me Down to Sleep'' and `` The <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> Strangler.'' He was the author of three books, `` Psychic,'' ` The Psychic World of <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Hurkos </PERSON>'' and `` <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Hurkos </PERSON>: I Have Many Lives.'' Born in <LOCATION> Dordrecht </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Holland </LOCATION>, he came to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> in 1956 for psychic experiments, and lived in the <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> area about 25 years. Surviving are his wife, <PERSON> Stephany </PERSON> <PERSON> Courtney </PERSON>; a daughter and six children from a previous marriage.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880602-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-02-88 0210EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-LieDetectors     06-02 0433</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lie Detectors,420</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bill Restricting Company Lie Detector Tests Clears House</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LARRY MARGASAK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Legislation that would significantly reduce the number of lie detector tests administered by private companies now needs only <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> approval to go to the president for signature into law. The <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> voted 251-120 on Wednesday in favor of the conference report, a compromise version of differing bills passed earlier by the two chambers. <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> approval would send the legislation to the president. The Office of Technology Assessment estimated that about 2 million such tests were administered last year, and that 90 percent were administered by private employers, mostly to job applicants but also to workers under investigation. The accuracy of test results has been questioned, and so has the competency of some examiners. Twenty-two states prohibit the tests in the private sector, and 19 regulate their private use. The legislation would permit private sector testing of applicants for only two types of jobs. Those applying for security guard positions could still be tested, and so could prospective employees who would have direct access to the manufacture, storage, distribution or sale of controlled substances. The bill also has several provisions to protect the rights of workers subject to tests. The bill would prohibit an employee from being discharged, dismissed, disciplined, discriminated against, or denied employment or promotion solely on the basis of the test, or solely for refusal to take the test. To take action against the worker, an employer would have to have additional supporting evidence. Questions on religious or political beliefs could not be asked, and all questions would have to be submitted to the examinee in writing before the examination. The examinee could end the test at any time. An employer could test an employee during an investigation involving economic loss or injury to the company. However, the employee would have to have had access to the property that is the subject of the investigation, and the employer would have to have a reasonable suspicion that the worker was involved in the incident. Before the test began, the worker would have to be given specific information about the incident under investigation. Only the federal government would be permitted to administer tests to those employed by, assigned to, or detailed to the nation's intelligence agencies and to <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> contract employees. Qualification standards would be set for examiners, who would need a license granted by the state, if one was required. The examiner also would have to maintain a $ 50,000 bond. The legislation would take effect six months after it became law.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880602-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-02-88 0214EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Shipyards-Jobs     06-02 0608</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Shipyards-Jobs,650</SECOND>
<HEAD>Navy Forecasting Job Losses at Eight Public Shipyards</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JEFF BARKER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> is forecasting new job reductions at its eight public shipyards, where employment already has dropped 9 percent since 1985. An unpublished naval planning document shows that the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> is projecting a 21 percent cutback in employment at the yards between now and the end of fiscal 1991. The job figures are only estimates, and are subject to change because of schedule shifts, new work or other factors. The May 11 document, obtained this week from congressional sources, projects employment requirements based on ship repair and modernization assignments for the 1989, 1990 and 1991 fiscal years. The Naval Sea Systems Command document resulted from a recent ship scheduling conference sponsored by the systems command, which oversees the eight yards. Overall, employment in the yards would shrink from about 71,100 now to 64,050 in the fall of 1989. The workforce then would shrink further to 57,150 the next year and 56,400 the year after that. The current 71,100 figure includes about 4,000 temporary and part-time employees. The systems command, in a statement in response to a reporter's query, said the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> has neither published employment projections nor announced layoffs `` However, shipyard employment figures are routinely reviewed and working documents are prepared to determine what employment levels are necessary to meet fleet operational requirements,'' the statement said. `` Exact naval shipyard employment figures will not be determined until the budget process is completed for fiscal year 1989 and beyond,'' it said. The eight yards have already seen their collective workforce trimmed by 7,000 from the 78,100 who were employed in January 1985. The <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> said those reductions were prompted in part by a declining number of ship overhauls. Some yards would see their workforce dip and then swell again, under the projections of the May 11 document. For example, employment at the Puget Sound Naval Shipyard in <LOCATION> Bremerton </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wash. </LOCATION>, is estimated to dip from 11,400 to 8,500 by the fall of 1990, before climbing back to 10,000 the following year. Puget Sound spokesman <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Andrae </PERSON> said that while he was not familiar with the working document, the yard was `` pretty well aware'' of its workload over the next few years. `` I think you'll find we're not the only shipyard where you'll see some rather wide swings in manpower,'' <PERSON> Andrae </PERSON> said `` You go down for a couple of years and all of a sudden you've got to make a dramatic increase. Skilled labor does n't come easily, and that presents some challenges.'' A similar pattern was projected at the <LOCATION> Norfolk </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Naval </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Shipyard </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Portsmouth </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>. Employment at <LOCATION> Norfolk </LOCATION>, whose 12,700 workers make it the largest public yard, was forecast at 11,350 in the fall of 1989, 9,700 in 1990, and 10,900 in 1991 Employment at the <ORGANIZATION> Philadelphia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Naval </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Shipyard </ORGANIZATION>, now at about 8,700, is projected to decline to 6,800. The yard likely would lay off 749 temporary workers first, officials said. The <LOCATION> Long </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, shipyard would suffer the least disruption to its workforce, with its employment remaining between 5,000 and 5,250 during the three years. The Mare Island yard in northern <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> would see its workforce drop to 10,000 in the fall of 1989, followed by a loss of another 3,800 workers and then a gain of 1,300 to bring it back up to 7,500. <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Pearl </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Harbor </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Yard </LOCATION>, which employs about 6,100 now, would drop to 4,000. Among Eastern yards, <LOCATION> Charleston </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> S.C. </LOCATION>, would go from about 8,600 to 6,200. The <LOCATION> Portsmouth </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.H. </LOCATION>, yard would remain at about 8,000 workers until 1991, then dip to 5,800 at the end of 1991.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880602-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-02-88 0219EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-UnusualBirth     06-02 0192</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Unusual Birth,0195</SECOND>
<HEAD>Woman Bears Child From Frozen Embryo Conceived With Donated Egg
And Sperm</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEWARK, N.J. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A woman has given birth to a healthy child produced from a frozen embryo that was conceived in a laboratory dish with sperm from her husband and an egg donated by her sister, doctors said Wednesday. The birth in May at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medicine </ORGANIZATION> and Dentistry of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> is believed to be the first of its kind in the <LOCATION> Northeast </LOCATION> and one of 10 in the world, the doctors said. The procedure was used because the unidentified mother, a <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> woman in her 30s, suffered premature ovarian failure and was unable to become pregnant, said Dr. <PERSON> Cecilia </PERSON> <PERSON> Schmidt </PERSON>, director of the <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fertility </ORGANIZATION> and Reproductive Technology. Doctors retrieved several of the sister's eggs using a new ultrasound procedure that does not require surgery. The eggs were fertilized in vitro with sperm from the woman's husband. After an initial pregnancy attempt failed, the remaining embryos were frozen and kept at 190 degrees below zero Celsius. One embryo was thawed three months later and implanted, producing the healthy baby.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880602-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-02-88 0019EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p AM-Bush-Interview     06-02 0441</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Bush-Interview,410</SECOND>
<HEAD>Vice President Shrugs Off Conservative Figures' Influence</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Vice President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said in a published interview that two of the nation's well-known and outspoken conservatives are fringe elements whose support is n't necessary for victory in the presidential election. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, interviewed by The <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> at his oceanside retreat in <LOCATION> Kennebunkport </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION> on Wednesday, shrugged off the influence of <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Viguerie </PERSON>, a writer and direct-mail specialist, and <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Phillips </PERSON>, head of the <ORGANIZATION> Conservative </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Caucus </ORGANIZATION>. `` There's only one or two that polarize, and <PERSON> Viguerie </PERSON> and <PERSON> Howie </PERSON> <PERSON> Phillips </PERSON> are two of them; it does n't matter in terms of total vote,'' the vice president said in the interview, published in Thursday's editions of the Times. `` There is only a handful of <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Vigueries </PERSON> out there,'' said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, the all-but certain Republican presidential nominee. Asked if he had to do business with <PERSON> Viguerie </PERSON> to win the election, he said: `` I do n't believe that.'' `` The fact that he -LRB- <PERSON> Viguerie </PERSON> -RRB- does n't agree with me on a lot of things or has opposed me for many years, that does n't bother me one iota,'' said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. <PERSON> Viguerie </PERSON>, the vice president said, `` gets his name in the paper by criticizing other Republicans all the time.'' A <PERSON> Viguerie </PERSON> spokeswoman, <PERSON> Carolyn </PERSON> <PERSON> Melenick </PERSON>, said Wednesday night that <PERSON> Viguerie </PERSON> would have no immediate comment on <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s remarks. <PERSON> Viguerie </PERSON> said last month that he would vote for <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> also told the newspaper he would be meeting soon with Attorney General <PERSON> Edwin </PERSON> <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said over the weekend that the two had met recently, and <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> said he would not do anything to harm <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s presidential campaign. The attorney general is under investigation by an independent counsel, and the Democrats have been using the issue to attack <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. `` I think he's been made aware by the polls and by a lot of public comment that there is the danger that this matter, if it stays exactly the way it is, could not only adversely affect me, but affect others as well,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said of <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was also asked if he agreed with President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s contention, made at the superpower summit in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>, that Soviet bureaucracy, rather than <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION> policy, was apparently responsible for delays in granting exit visas, or refusal to grant them at all The newspaper said the vice president did not answer directly, but said the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> have `` fundamental differences'' on human rights. `` There is a long way to go before they have lived up to provisions of the <LOCATION> Helsinki </LOCATION> final act,'' he said, adding that the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> was committed to `` broad, objective standards on human rights.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880602-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-02-88 0053EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Germany-Mine 4thLd-Writethru a0885 06-02 0654</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Germany-Mine, 4th Ld-Writethru, a0885,0673</SECOND>
<HEAD>Explosion Kills 31 Miners, Traps 26 with Little Chance</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Leads with 8 grafs to UPDATE with 31 dead. PICKS up 6th graf
pvs, `Family members ...'</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By JOAN FISCHER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BORKEN, West Germany (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An explosion about 300 feet underground in a coal shaft Wednesday killed 31 miners and trapped 26, who were given little chance of survival. About 30 rescue workers used large drills early Thursday to bore through tons of debris in an urgent effort to reach the trapped miners. The explosion scorched the ground on the surface, where eight men were critically injured. The blast also blew the roofs off at least three work buildings at the mine, knocked down sheds and shattered windows. Early Thursday, <ORGANIZATION> Hessiche </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rundfunk </ORGANIZATION> radio quoted authorities as saying 31 bodies had been found, raising by 15 the number of dead that had been earlier confirmed. Twenty-six other miners were still trapped 330 feet below ground, the Frankfurt-based radio station said. <PERSON> Dieter </PERSON> <PERSON> Wickert </PERSON>, a spokesman for the company that owns the mine, said the latest confirmed count he'd heard was 29 dead. Rescue authorities could not be immediately reached to comment on the radio's figures. <PERSON> Gottfried </PERSON> <PERSON> Milde </PERSON>, <PERSON> Hesse </PERSON> state interior minister, said 57 miners were in the shaft when the blast occurred at midday at the mine near <LOCATION> Borken </LOCATION>, 70 miles northeast of <LOCATION> Frankfurt </LOCATION>. He said there was little hope of finding any others alive. About one-third of the men were foreigners, including 14 Turks, he said. Family members and friends of the missing men went to the mine and clung to each other for support as they waited. `` It's horrible. My husband is down there,'' said <PERSON> Ingrid </PERSON> <PERSON> Henke </PERSON>, 35. `` My daughters aged just 1 and 2.'' A woman who would not give her name, but said that her husband was not in the shaft, added: `` All the women in this part of town are doing their best to comfort each other.'' Around them was the mangled wreckage of the steel beams, sheds and fences blown away by the explosion. <PERSON> Erwin </PERSON> <PERSON> Braun </PERSON>, head of the Hesse state mining board, said all indications pointed to a gas explosion caused by a buildup of coal dust. Radio reports said the accident may have been caused by detonation of 4,400 pounds of explosives stored in the mine. The lignite coal mine belongs to <ORGANIZATION> Preussen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Elektra </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Hanover </LOCATION>, one of the largest West German utility companies. Mayor <PERSON> Bernd </PERSON> <PERSON> Hessler </PERSON> of <PERSON> Borken </PERSON> told a news conference 16 bodies had been found. <PERSON> Milde </PERSON>, the state interior minister, said rescue workers were leaving the bodies where they found them in the shaft and moving on to search for others. Wives and children watched from nearby as workers rushed to reach the miners and pump oxygen into the shaft. Many family members were crying. Some had brought small baskets filled with food, a sign they planned for a long night of waiting. Dense smoke engulfed the area after the blast at about 12:30 p.m., half an hour before the change of shifts. Hundreds of rescue workers rushed to the mine and several helicopters were brought in. <PERSON> Gerhard </PERSON> <PERSON> Heinz </PERSON>, an engineer, said the explosion occurred at a depth of between 200 and 460 feet. It critically injured eight miners on the surface and left the ground scorched. <PERSON> Otto </PERSON> <PERSON> Kraft </PERSON>, a miner still blackened from the explosion, said: `` I've never seen anything like it.'' He still appeared dazed. <PERSON> Klaus </PERSON> <PERSON> Hausmann </PERSON>, a mine mechanic, said: `` I have no real hopes. I think we'll have to bury a lot of people.'' <PERSON> Hausmann </PERSON> said he was working at the pit and saw several co-workers knocked over. Late Wednesday, police spokesman <PERSON> Wolfgang </PERSON> <PERSON> Rudolph </PERSON> said he doubted earlier reports that a mine shaft had collapsed, hampering rescue efforts. A police spokesman, who spoke on condition of anonymity, had said there was a collapse and `` this reduces the chance of finding many survivors.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880602-0025 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-02-88 0235EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF-SoldierEarring     06-02 0126</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF-Soldier Earring,0128</SECOND>
<HEAD>Court Rules Soldiers Can Wear Earring</HEAD>
<DATELINE>OSLO, Norway (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Male Norwegian soldiers can wear an earring if they wish, a court has ruled. The civilian court in <LOCATION> Hammerfest </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Norway </LOCATION>'s northernmost town, recently handed down the decision on a soldier's appeal against a $ 48 fine he received last fall for refusing to remove a small earring, the national <ORGANIZATION> NTB </ORGANIZATION> news agency reported. <ORGANIZATION> NTB </ORGANIZATION> quoted the <ORGANIZATION> Finnmark </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dagblad </ORGANIZATION> newspaper, published in <ORGANIZATION> Tromsoe </ORGANIZATION>, as saying the unidentified soldier challenged a military regulation stating that only women are allowed to wear `` ear jewelry.'' The magistrates voted 2-1 that the code was discriminatory. The two judges voting in the soldier's favor were women, while the male judge voted to uphold the previous dress codes, <ORGANIZATION> NTB </ORGANIZATION> reported.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880602-0026 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-02-88 0249EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-DancersCovered     06-02 0245</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Dancers Covered,0252</SECOND>
<HEAD>City Covers Up Pornography Law's Loophole</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Note contents</NOTE>
<DATELINE>EL PASO, Texas (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Flustered </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> members closed a loophole in a pornography ordinance after topless dancers began smearing themselves with transparent grease to slip out of a requirement that they cover up. Before it was amended Tuesday, the ordinance specified what parts of dancers' bodies had to be covered but did n't say the covering had to be opaque. `` Some of the girls ... were covering their breasts with Vaseline or grease,'' said <PERSON> Brenda </PERSON> <PERSON> Nichols </PERSON>, assistant city attorney. There were reports that other dancers used see-through fabric and clear adhesive tape to skirt the ordinance. Tuesday's Council action banned all such clear coverings. The Council also amended the ordinance to make sure adult entertainment establishments are at least 1,000 feet from homes, schools, churches, parks or other adult businesses. The amendment went into effect immediately. Those who still want to see strippers can easily cross an international bridge to <LOCATION> Ciudad </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Juarez </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, where nude dancing and prostitution are legal. <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Gibson </PERSON>, a lawyer who represents some of the adult businesses here, said <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> simply is trying to stamp out adult businesses in <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Paso </LOCATION>. `` If you comply with the first ordinance they pass, they change it to make sure no one can comply,'' he said. `` With the new definition of the type of covering, you might as well set up outside a swimming pool and charge admission to it.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880602-0027 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-02-88 0059EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p PM-Reagan-Fallout 1stLd-Writethru a0420 06-02 0706</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Reagan-Fallout, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0420,640</SECOND>
<HEAD>Republicans See a Bush Opportunity to Part Company from Reagan</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDs: INSERTS Bush comment in New York Times interview in grafs
9-10; picks up 9th graf pvs</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By DONALD M. ROTHBERG</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Political Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
