<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880313-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-13-88 2347EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-DressofaSalesman     03-13 0409</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Dress of a Salesman,0417</SECOND>
<HEAD>Car Salesman Says He Was Fired After Wearing Ugly Sport Coats</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PAT LEISNER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>TAMPA, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Grant </PERSON>'s boss says the veteran salesman was fired because of his unseemly habit of wearing loud and ugly sport coats. <PERSON> Grant </PERSON>, 62, had filed a discrimination suit to prove he was forced out because of his age. <PERSON> Grant </PERSON> said before he lost his job at <LOCATION> Darby </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Buick </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Sarasota </LOCATION> in May 1985, the dealership was undergoing a `` new image'' campaign and he was told to start wearing sport coats on the used car lot for a more professional look. The 30-year sales veteran promptly went shopping for two jackets he describes as a pale pink and a rainbow plaid. He said the latter has every color in it and goes well with his gray slacks or green or red or blue. `` I saw nothing wrong with them,'' <PERSON> Grant </PERSON> said in a sworn statement in <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Tampa </LOCATION>. At 6-foot-8, he said, he has to buy his clothes at specialty shops that fit tall men. And he wanted coats to go with his different trousers. `` So that's what I bought, you know, because I had gray pants, blue pants, green pants, every kind. So you had to have something to go with all of them.'' But his boss, <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Conrad </PERSON> <PERSON> Darby </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>, said that neither jacket went well with the image he was trying to create for his dealership. `` Rather than promote an image of professionalism, <PERSON> Grant </PERSON>'s selections took the opposite direction,'' an attorney for <ORGANIZATION> Darby </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Buick </ORGANIZATION> said in court documents `` One jacket was multi-colored ... and the other was a loud fuchsia color.'' In the lawsuit, wryly dubbed `` the dress of a salesman'' in courthouse corridors, <PERSON> Grant </PERSON> claims the dress code and other charges against him, including catnapping and snacking in the office, are pretexts to hide the real problem _ age bias. <PERSON> Grant </PERSON>, the oldest salesman and the dealership's top in used car sales in 1984, was replaced by a less experienced person in his 20s, was never reprimanded and had an excellent job performance record, said <PERSON> Grant </PERSON>'s attorney, <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> <PERSON> K. </PERSON> <PERSON> Donnellan </PERSON>. <PERSON> Darby </PERSON>'s attorney, <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Sizemore </PERSON>, acknowledged that <PERSON> Grant </PERSON> was among the best in the sales force. As a result, <PERSON> Sizemore </PERSON> said, there was no motive to fire <PERSON> Grant </PERSON> for age discrimination, only for his poor behavior. The case is expected to go to trial this month.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880313-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-13-88 2353EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-WallarooSurgery     03-13 0215</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Wallaroo Surgery,0222</SECOND>
<HEAD>Doctors Treat Blinded Kangaroo</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A wallaroo apparently blinded by the milk of human kindness underwent cataract surgery by two doctors who volunteered their services and usually treat people. In Saturday's three-hour operation, Dr. <PERSON> Raymond </PERSON> <PERSON> Weinstein </PERSON>, a family practitioner, and Dr. <PERSON> Gene </PERSON> <PERSON> Zdenek </PERSON>, an ophthalmologist, removed a marble-sized cataract from the eye of the animal, a stocky kangaroo. The doctors tentatively declared the operation a success. <PERSON> Weinstein </PERSON> said an improper diet probably blinded the animal, named <PERSON> Menehuni </PERSON>, who apparently had been blind most of its seven to 11 years. Milk sugars collect in the eyes of wallaroos and cause cataracts because the animals can not break them down, <PERSON> Weinstein </PERSON> said. `` This poor guy's condition illustrates the reason why most people should n't have exotic animals,'' <PERSON> Zdenek </PERSON> said. `` The people probably had no idea they were blinding their pet.'' State authorities took <PERSON> Menehuni </PERSON> from its owners and gave him to the Wildlife Way Station in the <ORGANIZATION> Angeles </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION>, a nonprofit group that cares for exotic and wild animals that are sick or abandoned. The surgery was performed for free at the station with the help of resident veterinarian <PERSON> Silvio </PERSON> <PERSON> Santinelli </PERSON>. <PERSON> Weinstein </PERSON> said it was the first time he had to worry about `` moving a patient's tail out of the way.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880313-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-13-88 2356EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-QueensDrugs     03-13 0799</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Queens Drugs,0822</SECOND>
<HEAD>Community Where Cop Died Being Taken Over By Dealers</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By MITCHELL LANDSBERG</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Dorothy </PERSON> was coming downstairs for some tea when she heard five shots in the middle of the night. Right away she thought of police Sgt. <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Byrne </PERSON>, sitting alone in a patrol car a block away, guarding the home of a threatened witness. `` I said, ` Oh my God, he's in trouble,''' she recalled. Now, sitting in her tidy living room in the <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jamaica </LOCATION> section of <LOCATION> Queens </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Dorothy </PERSON> _ a middle-age woman afraid to give her last name _ mourns <PERSON> Byrne </PERSON>, 22, a rookie who police believe was slain on the orders of a jailed drug kingpin. And she mourns for her neighborhood of small wood-frame houses that once must have seemed promising to working-class people looking for a slice of prosperity. It does n't anymore. <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jamaica </LOCATION> has been overwhelmed by drugs, especially crack, in an epidemic that reached a peak of violence in the murder of <PERSON> Byrne </PERSON>, who was guarding the home of a man who had complained about drug dealers. Although police have taken the neighborhood by storm in efforts to ferret out <PERSON> Byrne </PERSON>'s killers and drive away the drug merchants, residents remain cynical and scared. <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jamaica </LOCATION>, solidly black and poor, has been a troubled neighborhood for a long time. It shows in peeling paint, sagging porches, abandoned storefronts. But things have taken a turn for the worse in the past few years and police, clergy and residents blame crack and the people who sell it. `` They have taken over, completely taken over,'' said City Councilman <PERSON> Archie </PERSON> <PERSON> Spigner </PERSON>, who represents <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jamaica </LOCATION>. `` Everywhere I go, there are complaints. Every community meeting I attend, the inevitable complaint is narcotics.'' The users commit other crimes to support their habits. Children, seeing drug dealers in flashy clothes and fancy cars, are drawn to the drug life. Lawbreakers are drawn to the neighborhood. And dealers engage in turf wars that endanger all around them. `` You hear gunshots here and you hear gunshots there,'' said <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Barnes </PERSON>, who lost a new television set and a videocassette recorder in a burglary he blames on drug addicts. `` If I had the money, I'd move.'' When crack first spread through <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> several years ago, experts said it was sold by small-time entrepreneurs who would buy an ounce of cocaine and process it into a flaky, smokable drug. But now officials say a new hierarchy of violent, well-armed drug kingpins is taking over the crack trade in <LOCATION> Queens </LOCATION>. `` It starts in a very low-key way,'' said <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Hopkins </PERSON>, who supervises the Street Research Unit of the state Division of Substance Abuse Services. An entrepreneur begins selling drugs in a neighborhood and builds up a reputation. Buyers begin driving into the neighborhood. After a while, the dealer's success comes to the attention of a nearby drug gang. They make him an offer that he ca n't refuse, `` Work for us or get killed.'' `` Once that organized group comes in there, you're dealing with guns and it's not easy to get rid of,'' <PERSON> Hopkins </PERSON> said. What makes a neighborhood susceptible to drug infestation, beyond having at least some drug users? <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Beshers </PERSON>, a demographer at <ORGANIZATION> Queens </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION>, believes that an influx of different ethnic groups into a neighborhood can create a breakdown in the social structure that is conducive to illegal activity. `` You get a loss of communication,'' <PERSON> Beshers </PERSON> said. He noted that <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jamaica </LOCATION> has seen an influx of <LOCATION> Asian </LOCATION> and West Indian immigrants who ca n't necessarily communicate well with each other or with the established residents, mostly blacks who grew up in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> or in the South. For <PERSON> Archie </PERSON> <PERSON> Spigner </PERSON>, the reason for the infestation in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jamaica </LOCATION> is more prosaic: `` The police just allowed it to exist. They just accepted it, and it became entrenched, it became institutionalized.'' The Police Department, shocked by <PERSON> Byrne </PERSON>'s murder, has set out to end such criticism. Police Commissioner <PERSON> Benjamin </PERSON> <PERSON> Ward </PERSON> announced plans last week for a new, 118-member Tactical Narcotics Team whose mission is to stamp out drug dealing in southeast <LOCATION> Queens </LOCATION>. And an intense investigation has already led to the indictment of four men on charges of murdering the young cop. But skepticism runs high in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jamaica </LOCATION>, where some residents are bitter that it took the murder of a police officer to bring attention to their plight. `` What about the kids being killed in the drug wars?'' asked a man who walked down a street a block from the murder site and refused to give his name. `` That's what people ought to be crying about. I know about 10 cases of young kids getting killed in the neighborhood, and nobody ever did anything about that.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880313-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-13-88 2354EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-Deaths 1stLd-Writethru a0805 03-13 0792</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Deaths, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0805,0821</SECOND>
<NOTE>Eds: AMs separates moved on Steno, a0762, and Holmes, a0847.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>John Holmes</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Porno star <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Holmes </PERSON>, who boasted of 14,000 sexual conquests, on and off screen, during a career in X-rated films and peep shows that spanned two decades, died Saturday at age 43. <PERSON> Holmes </PERSON>, the leading male sex film star of the 1970s and early 1980s, died at the <ORGANIZATION> Veterans </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>, said adult-film producer <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Amerson </PERSON>, a longtime friend and business associate. The <ORGANIZATION> Los </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Angeles </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> earlier this month quoted unidentified sources as saying <PERSON> Holmes </PERSON> was gravely ill with AIDS. <PERSON> Amerson </PERSON> said the cause of death was not immediately known. <PERSON> Holmes </PERSON>, best known for his portrayal of the character <PERSON> Johnny </PERSON> <PERSON> Wadd </PERSON>, a detective, made thousands of peep shows and sexually explicit films, including `` Liquid Lips,'' `` Blonde Fire,'' `` Tell Them <PERSON> Johnny </PERSON> <PERSON> Wadd </PERSON> is Here'' and `` Exhausted.'' He once admitted that he had a $ 1,000-a-day cocaine habit. Two weeks ago detectives again questioned <PERSON> Holmes </PERSON> at his hospital bedside about the unsolved 1981 slayings of four people in a house in <LOCATION> Laurel </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Canyon </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Holmes </PERSON> was acquitted of the slayings in 1982 but had never told authorities what he knew about the crime.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>Romare Bearden</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Romare </PERSON> <PERSON> Bearden </PERSON>, a leading American artist whose collages expressed the dignity of black people and Southern living, died Saturday. He was 75. <PERSON> Bearden </PERSON>'s work ranged from political cartoons to water colors, sets and costumes for the <PERSON> Alvin </PERSON> <PERSON> Ailey </PERSON> Dance Theater, public murals and eventually collages. He was awarded the National Medal of Arts by President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> in June. <PERSON> Lowery </PERSON> <PERSON> Sims </PERSON>, associate curator of 20th century art at the Metropolitan Museum of Art, said <PERSON> Bearden </PERSON>'s collages `` raised it to such a fine art it's hard to think of any other artist who is so closely associated with that medium.'' <PERSON> Bearden </PERSON> was born in <LOCATION> Charlotte </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.C. </LOCATION>, and grew up in <LOCATION> Harlem </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION>. He attended <ORGANIZATION> Boston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, majoring in mathematics and planning to become a doctor. He started drawing in college, and cartoons published in the Afro American, a weekly, led to a career in art.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>Hugh Wolfe Frank</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MERE, England (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Hugh </PERSON> <PERSON> Wolfe </PERSON> <PERSON> Frank </PERSON>, chief interpreter at the <LOCATION> Nuremberg </LOCATION> war crimes trials, was found dead Thursday. He was 75. <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> was a skillful linguist who led the team of interpreters at the trials in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> of top Nazis, including <PERSON> Hermann </PERSON> <PERSON> Goering </PERSON> and <PERSON> Rudolf </PERSON> <PERSON> Hess </PERSON>. <PERSON> Frank </PERSON>, whose body was found in a fume-filled car, had been suffering from Parkinson's disease and was known to be depressed about his worsening health. An inquest was ordered.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>Joseph T. Sternaman</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>OAK PARK, Ill. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> T. </PERSON> <PERSON> Sternaman </PERSON>, the first quarterback of the <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> Bears, died Thursday at age 88. In the Bears' first season, in 1922, <PERSON> Sternaman </PERSON> and his brother <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> `` Dutch'' <PERSON> Sternaman </PERSON>, a halfback and co-owner of the fledgling <ORGANIZATION> NFL </ORGANIZATION> team with Bears founder <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Halas </PERSON>, accounted for 73 of the team's 123 points. At 135 pounds, <PERSON> Sternaman </PERSON> also served as a runner, drop-kicker and blocker. He called plays featuring Red Grange, the `` Galloping Ghost'' of the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Illinois </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>Murray M. `Buddy' Weiss</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ARLINGTON, Va. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Murray </PERSON> M. `` Buddy'' <PERSON> Weiss </PERSON>, former editor of The <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Herald </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tribune </ORGANIZATION>, died Saturday at age 64. The <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> native, who worked for the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Information </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> at the time of his death, was editor of the Paris-based newspaper from its creation in 1966 until 1979. In 1946, he joined the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Herald </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tribune </ORGANIZATION> as a copy boy and was managing editor by the time the paper folded in 1966. After leaving the <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Herald </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tribune </ORGANIZATION>, he served as editor of The Advocate in <LOCATION> Stamford </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Conn. </LOCATION>, and managing editor of Parade magazine. He left Parade in 1983. At <ORGANIZATION> USIA </ORGANIZATION>, he was in charge of the news file distributed to <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> embassies and diplomatic missions around the world.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>J.W. Jung</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>RANDOLPH, Wis. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 J.W. <PERSON> Jung </PERSON>, founder of one of the nation's biggest mail-order seed companies, died Friday at the age of 100 The <ORGANIZATION> Jung </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Seed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, founded here in 1906, circulates between 2 million and 3 million seed catalogs a year and also operates a garden center in <LOCATION> Randolph </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Jung </PERSON> traced his interest in gardening and seeds to his boyhood, when his mother taught him to save seeds from the vegetable garden for planting. He soon was going from farm to farm selling extra seeds.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>Steno</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ROME (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Steno, an Italian director of film comedies, died of a stroke Sunday. Born <PERSON> Stefano </PERSON> <PERSON> Vanzina </PERSON> in 1917, he began his career as a screenwriter in 1945 and soon after began directing. Some, such as `` Guardie e Ladri'' -LRB- Guards and Thieves -RRB-, starred one of <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>'s best-loved comics, Toto
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880313-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-13-88 2355EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p AM-PoliticalRdp 3rdLd-Writethru a0826 03-13 1105</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Political Rdp, 3rd Ld-Writethru, a0826,1,080</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush Under Fire From Republican Dole and Democrat Jackson</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDS: TOPS with 8 grafs to UPDATE with Washington Post-ABC News
poll showing Simon with strong lead in Illinois; PICKS UP 8th graf
pvs bgng, `Simon and'</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By DONALD M. ROTHBERG</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Political Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CHICAGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 With signs pointing to another <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> primary victory by <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION>, the vice president came under renewed criticism Sunday from GOP rival <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> and from Democrats <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> and <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> Jr.. Two polls published in Monday's editions of two newspapers gave contradictory indications of how the Democratic voters were expected to cast ballots in Tuesday's primary The poll in the <ORGANIZATION> Chicago </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tribune </ORGANIZATION> showed <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> moving into the lead, favored by 32 percent of the Democrats, <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> Sen. <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> by 29 percent and <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> by 20 percent. Five hundred likely Democratic primary voters were contacted Thursday and Friday and the survey had a margin of error of 5 percent, meaning the numbers could be off that much up or down. However, a poll for <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> showed <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> holding a strong lead with 42 percent, <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> 33 percent, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> 14 percent, Sen. <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> Tennessee </ORGANIZATION> 4 percent, Rep. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> Missouri </ORGANIZATION> 3 percent and others and undecided, 4 percent. That poll was based on telephone interviews Friday night and Saturday with 287 Democratic voters who were likely to cast ballots. The margin of error was 6 percent. <PERSON> Simon </PERSON>, dependent on a home-state victory to remain in the race, said he had overcome poor showings in polls during other campaigns. `` If I get my message across to the people of <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION>, they're going to vote for me,'' he said The new <ORGANIZATION> Chicago </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tribune </ORGANIZATION> poll indicated slippage in <PERSON> Simon </PERSON>'s support A survey published in the <ORGANIZATION> Tribune </ORGANIZATION> on Sunday said the senator was leading with support from 35 percent of likely Democratic voters, while <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> had the backing of 30 percent and <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> that of 18 percent. <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> and <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> also traded barbs on the question of whether the Democratic nomination would be determined by a brokered convention next July in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> Tribune </ORGANIZATION> poll on Sunday also showed <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> with a 34-point lead over <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>. The newspaper did not continue surveying Republicans. <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>, struggling to revive his presidential campaign, insisted he would fight on `` full bore'' after <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> though he said he had no obligation `` to look ridiculous.'' <PERSON> Gore </PERSON>, who hopes to demonstrate some Northern support in <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION>, said he would `` almost certainly'' turn down his party's vice presidential nomination <PERSON> Gore </PERSON>, at a campaign stop later, also blasted <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> over the Iran-Contra affair. `` The Reagan-Bush administration violated the law in a brazen way,'' he said, adding: `` We still do n't know what <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s role was. Interviewed on the CBS show, `` Face the Nation,'' <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> said he received telegram from former President <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> who urged him `` hang in there, do n't give up, make <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> your finest hour.'' `` I believe I have some obligation _ not to look ridiculous _ but some obligation to stay in this race,'' said the <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> senator. Asked if there was any chance he's drop out after <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> said, `` We're going full bore'' on the <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION>, which holds its primary on April 5. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> attended a Polish-language Mass at <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hyacinth </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> on the city's northwest side and described his trip to <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> last year and his meeting with Solidarity leader <PERSON> Lech </PERSON> <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON>. `` It is the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> that must keep alive the hope of the Polish people,'' the vice president told a crowd that filled the church and spilled onto the sidewalk outside. After church, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> planned a day of appearances at shopping malls and restaurants, each event described by his staff as a `` photo opportunity only.'' On the possibility of a brokered convention, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> said, `` I ca n't imagine anything worse _ the idea of taking the right of the people to elect their president with their votes and putting it in some backrooms in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>.'' <PERSON> Simon </PERSON>, predicting no Democrat would be able win the nomination on the first ballot at the convention, said <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' attitude demonstrated `` a touch of arrogance.'' He described the <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> governor as saying, `` You either vote for me or you'll have a brokered convention.'' <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> also came to <PERSON> Simon </PERSON>'s defense and criticized <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, saying, `` Gov. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' commercial tries to lump him in with back-room politics of a kind <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> has not been associated with.'' <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, fresh from a victory in Democratic caucuses in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> on Saturday where he won 54 percent of the vote and picked up 23 delegates, said he hoped by the end of the primary and caucus season in June to have received `` a majority of the popular vote.'' Asked about the prospects of running against <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> in the general election, <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> said on the <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> show, `` Meet the Press,'' `` He certainly has a lot of baggage. `` <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was supposed to be over the commission on the drug situation, yet drugs are coming into this country at a rate that threatens our national security. ... To that continuous flow of drugs, Mrs. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> says no and <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> says nothing.'' The latest <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> delegate count showed <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> the Democratyic leader with 460 and <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> second with 423. <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> was third with 352. A total of 2,082 is needed for the nomination. On the Republican side, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> had 705 and <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> 165, with 1,139 need for the nomination. <PERSON> Gore </PERSON>, who received 18 percent of the <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> vote and 6 delegates, said he consideed that `` a very good showing.'' `` I do n't know of anyone weho was surprised to see <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> win a big victory in his home state, his native state,'' the <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> senator said on `` Face the Nation.'' <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> denied he dislikes <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, but said, `` I do believe that he's sort of had a charmed life in politics, he's gotten quite a ways without doing very much Maybe that's a key to success I had n't thought of. The senator renewed his debate challenge to <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and raised again the question of a possible tie between the vice president and Panamanian strong man Gen. <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> who has been accused of involvement in drug trafficking. `` I'd like <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> to tell us whether <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> was on his payroll when he was <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> director,'' said <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>. As for his prospects for a comeback, <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> said, `` Sooner or later, the voters in one of these states are going to say, wait a minute, we're about to nominate someone who ca n't win in November.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880313-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-13-88 0024EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p AM-SouthCarolinaDems 6thLd-Writethru a0671 03-13 0795</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-South Carolina Dems, 6th Ld-Writethru, a0671,790</SECOND>
<HEAD>Jackson Wins South Carolina Caucuses</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: SUBS grafs 3-5 to UPDATE with later returns; INSERTS 2 grafs
after 5th graf to include effect on national delegates.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By BRUCE SMITH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>COLUMBIA, S.C. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> won easily Saturday in his native <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>'s Democratic precinct caucuses, giving his already surging campaign a boost just days before the primary in his adopted <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION>. `` Just because you're born in the slum does n't mean the slum's borne in you,'' <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> said in <LOCATION> Greenville </LOCATION> `` I came home tonight to tell <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> there is a way out.'' With 93 percent of the state's 1,788 precincts reporting, <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> won 8,114 county convention delegates for 54 percent, followed by uncommitted with 2,853 delegates for 19 percent. <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> Sen. <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> was in third place with 2,777 delegates for 18 percent. <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> trailed far behind with 1,018 county convention delegates for 7 percent, followed by <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION> Rep. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> with 307 delegates for 2 percent and <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> Sen. <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> with just 36 delegates. If the results of the caucuses hold up at the state convention in April, <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> would win 23 delegates to the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Convention </ORGANIZATION>, 15 would be uncommitted and <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> would gain 6. In addition another four party officials in the state, who automatically are delegates to the national convention, have said they are uncommitted. The results from <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> put <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s overall national delegate tally at 423.55, just behind <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, who has 460.5. `` In <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> ... I want to win another gold medal,'' <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> said, noting his strong showing in the Super Tuesday primaries. `` I hope to walk away with the majority,'' <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> said. `` I should be the favorite son from <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>.'' <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON>, who was campaigning in <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION>, congratulated <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> on his victory, saying `` I thought he would do very well there - it's his home state - and he did. <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> spokesman <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> called his candidate's performance `` a strong showing'' and added `` we expect to pick up a majority of the uncommitted.'' <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> officials expected as many as 20,000 voters would participate in the caucuses in which 44 convention delegates were at stake. During a campaign swing across the state Friday, <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> predicted he would emerge as the leader in the muddled race for convention delegates once the votes are tallied in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION>, which holds a primary on Tuesday. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> trails <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> but leads <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> in the race for delegates to the Democratic National Convention. <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> has waged an active campaign in the state and a newspaper survey of <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> chairmen statewide found <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> expected to finish second to <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>. In the past, <ORGANIZATION> South </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Carolina </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democrats </ORGANIZATION> have had a penchant for going to the caucuses and voting for uncommitted delegates. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> was the top candidate four years ago but a plurality of the delegates remained uncommitted at the precinct level. This time around, campaign aides for <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> and <PERSON> Simon </PERSON>, were asking their supporters to remain uncommitted and work to become delegates at county conventions later in the month. But <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> urged supporters during a stop in <LOCATION> Charleston </LOCATION> Friday to stand up for his candidacy and `` do n't let anyone talk you into being an uncommitted delegate.'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> aides wanted voters to commit to him. The caucuses are the first stage of a three-stage process to select national convention delegates. Voters were to select delegates to the county conventions which in turn selects delegates to the state convention. The delegates are divided proportionally based on a candidates' showing But only those candidates with 15 percent of the vote at the state convention are entitled to national convention delegates. Delegates selected Saturday are bound to their candidates through the county and state conventions. <PERSON> Jake </PERSON> <PERSON> Hill </PERSON>, <PERSON> Gore </PERSON>'s assistant campaign coordinator, suggested neither <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> nor <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> would be able to round up the 15 percent of votes to allow them to receive any delegates. The campaigns would ask their people to stay uncommitted in the hopes something could be worked out at the county or state conventions to allow them to secure some delegates, he suggested. Although the caucuses have been overshadowed by <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>'s Republican primary and the parade of <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> candidates it attracted, <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON>, <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> all stumped in the state during the past week <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> had the endorsements of former Govs. <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Riley </PERSON> and <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> McNair </PERSON>. He promoted his trade policy this week at a campaign stop at a <LOCATION> Clearwater </LOCATION> textile plant that will be closed next month. But during the stop, <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> said he hoped to get his campaign back on track by winning the <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION> primary March 26. While <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> and <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> both campaigned in the state earlier, neither has returned in recent weeks.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880313-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-13-88 0058EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Bangladesh-Storm     03-13 0156</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Bangladesh-Storm,0163</SECOND>
<HEAD>15 Feared Dead, 7 Injured in Storm</HEAD>
<DATELINE>DHAKA, Bangladesh (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A storm packing winds of up to 60 miles per hour capsized scores of small fishing boats, flattened hundreds of mud and straw huts and at least 15 people were feared dead, police said Sunday. Rescue workers searched the banks of the <LOCATION> Jamuna </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> on Sunday for survivors of the Friday storm in <LOCATION> Mankiganj </LOCATION> <LOCATION> District </LOCATION>, northwest of <LOCATION> Dhaka </LOCATION>, officials said. `` We see slim chances that the missing are still surviving,'' said a police official in <LOCATION> Manikganj </LOCATION>, who spoke in a telephone interview on condition of anonymity. He said no bodies had yet been recovered. The storm along the river was slow in being reported because the wind also damaged electrical and telephone wires in the region. More than 300 mud and straw huts were flattened, and trees and crops damaged, officials said. More than 50 fishing boats were believed capsized or sunk.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880313-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-13-88 0159EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i BC-Iran-Iraq     03-13 0269</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Iran-Iraq,0279</SECOND>
<HEAD>Iraq Says Iranian Ground Offensive Repulsed</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NICOSIA, Cyprus (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> said Sunday its warplanes attacked a supertanker off the Iranian coast, while its ground forces beat back an Iranian offensive in a pre-dawn battle in the central sector of the war front. The official <ORGANIZATION> Iraqi </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION>, monitored in <LOCATION> Nicosia </LOCATION>, reported more than 1,000 Iranians were killed in the 3 -LCB- - hour battle which began at 1 a.m. <ORGANIZATION> INA </ORGANIZATION> said two Iranian brigades, backed by tanks and artillery, were involved in the thrust `` Infantry units of <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>'s 2nd <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corps </ORGANIZATION> repulsed the thrust, exterminating the bulk of the force. More than 1,000 Iranians were killed and the others were forced to retreat,'' the agency quoted an unnamed spokesman as saying. There was no immediate word from <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> on the reported battle. <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> did not say where exactly the battle took place, but judging from the size of the force, the attack did not appear to signal the beginning of <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'s long-awaited major offensive. The large-scale attack is expected to be launched in the southern sector of the 730-mile front around <LOCATION> Basra </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>'s second-largest city and its only outlet to the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'s last thrust in January 1987, brought Iranian troops to within six miles of <LOCATION> Basra </LOCATION>. But Western military analysts say <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> has had difficulties mobilizing forces needed for a new attack. In a separate dispatch, <ORGANIZATION> INA </ORGANIZATION> quoted a military spokesman as saying Iraqi planes `` dealt an accurate and effective blow to a very large maritime target,'' a reference to a supertanker, off the Iranian coast during the night. The report could not be immediately confirmed.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880313-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-13-88 1143EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-ChallengerSettlements Bjt   03-13 1214</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Challenger Settlements, Bjt,1251</SECOND>
<HEAD>Challenger: Why U.S. Settled With Some Astronauts And Not Others</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MICHAEL J. SNIFFEN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Ellison </PERSON> <PERSON> Onizuka </PERSON> and <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> both were military officers. They trained together for two years to be astronauts. And they died together when the space shuttle Challenger blew up above the <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> coast. Though both were servicemen, the government contributed to a money award for <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> Lt. Col. <PERSON> Onizuka </PERSON>'s relatives but went to court to avoid paying damages in <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> Cmdr. <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>'s case. <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Scobee </PERSON>, <PERSON> Judith </PERSON> <PERSON> Resnik </PERSON> and <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> McNair </PERSON> were civilian <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> astronauts who died in the Jan. 28, 1986, explosion. The government contributed to a settlement with <PERSON> Scobee </PERSON>'s dependents, but refused to contribute to settlements reached with the <PERSON> Resnik </PERSON> and <PERSON> McNair </PERSON> families by rocket maker <ORGANIZATION> Morton </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Thiokol </ORGANIZATION>. `` I'm hoping some of this inequity will lead to legislation to address the problems of the government's negligence,'' says lawyer <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Oldak </PERSON>, <PERSON> Resnik </PERSON>'s ex-husband. Why did the government settle with some astronaut families and not with others? One crucial difference: the families of <PERSON> Resnik </PERSON>, <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, and <PERSON> McNair </PERSON> hired lawyers to negotiate for them. Their lawyers objected to <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> positions in the case, and these three families are not likely to see any money from the government. The government did settle _ along with <ORGANIZATION> Thiokol </ORGANIZATION> _ with the four families who hired no lawyers: the Scobees, the Onizukas and the survivors of the two non-government crew members, teacher <PERSON> Christa </PERSON> <PERSON> McAuliffe </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> Hughes </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aircraft </ORGANIZATION> engineer <PERSON> Gregory </PERSON> <PERSON> Jarvis </PERSON>. These four spouses and six children shared in cash and annuities that cost $ 7,735,000. The government paid 40 percent; <ORGANIZATION> Thiokol </ORGANIZATION>, 60 percent. They had relied on informal advice from the law partner of <PERSON> McAuliffe </PERSON>'s husband, <PERSON> Steven </PERSON>, and they talked only with the government, never directly with the company. Another difference is that once those four cases were settled Dec. 29, 1986, <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> lawyers took an our-way-or-no-way approach to negotiating with the other families. The government sought to apply the same formula for financial benefits to each family. At the same time, it tried to negotiate a legal minefield bounded by two key <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> decisions. In one decision, the high court gave the government immunity from being sued for damages for its military and civilian employees who are killed on the job. <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> lawyers did not want to see that doctrine weakened. In the other decision, the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> said a contractor who pays damages for the death of a federal worker can try to get some of that money back from the government, if federal employees shared in the blame. The government did not want to be dragged into court by <ORGANIZATION> Thiokol </ORGANIZATION> for a replay of the errors by government officials who spurned the protests of company engineers that it was too cold to launch Challenger. The two decisions left the government with direct liability for two Challenger astronauts and only indirect liability for the five federal workers aboard. The <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>'s solution: settle only when the company also was a party. The split between the families had its roots in the government's financial benefit formula, based on the number and age of dependents and their needs and goals Justice spokeswoman <PERSON> Amy </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> said `` generous offers based on the same formula'' were made to all seven families. But the families with lawyers rejected them. The formula left out an element common to most court-awarded damages _ a calculation of lost wages. Legal experts say this benefited the <PERSON> McAuliffe </PERSON> family, because the earning potential of public school teacher <PERSON> Christa </PERSON> <PERSON> McAuliffe </PERSON> was dwarfed by that of her fellow crew members, who were engineers and physicists, all but one with advanced degrees. One lawyer involved in the negotiations said <PERSON> Steven </PERSON> <PERSON> McAuliffe </PERSON> helped devise the formula and pressed other families to accept it because the government wanted a package settlement. A single settlement covering military, civilian federal and non-government crew members would ease the government's legal problem of having direct liability for some and indirect liability for others, this source said. But the benefit formula did not offer enough money to satisfy <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Oldak </PERSON>, lawyer for <PERSON> Resnik </PERSON>'s divorced father, <PERSON> Marvin </PERSON>, and her niece and nephew. A 36-year-old, Ph.D. engineer, <PERSON> Resnik </PERSON> was the only astronaut with neither spouse nor children. <PERSON> Oldak </PERSON> said the formula only provided several hundred thousand dollars for the Resniks _ between a quarter and a half of what the government and company were offering the other families. After rejecting two government-company offers, <PERSON> Oldak </PERSON> went to <ORGANIZATION> Thiokol </ORGANIZATION>. The company was agreeable to a joint government-company settlement with the Resniks for an amount roughly equal to that of <PERSON> Jarvis </PERSON>' widow, <PERSON> Marcia </PERSON>. Hers was the lowest of the four settlements because the <ORGANIZATION> Jarvises </ORGANIZATION> had no children. <ORGANIZATION> Thiokol </ORGANIZATION> would even make up the difference between this figure and the government-company offer that <PERSON> Oldak </PERSON> had rejected. Checking with <PERSON> Marcia </PERSON> <PERSON> Jarvis </PERSON> and other relatives, <PERSON> Oldak </PERSON> found none who objected to bending the formula this much. But Justice officials heard differently. `` It's not accurate that it would not offend other families,'' said <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION>'s <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>. `` One might have said OK. Two might have, but all of them would not subscribe to that Concern was voiced that an offer might not be in line with the formula used for the others, and we could n't do that.'' Last July, <ORGANIZATION> Thiokol </ORGANIZATION> lawyer <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Adler </PERSON> wrote the government, `` I do n't believe that the department's position with respect to the <PERSON> Resnik </PERSON> claim has been fair either to the <PERSON> Resnik </PERSON> claimants or to <ORGANIZATION> Morton </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Thiokol </ORGANIZATION>.'' Ulimately, <ORGANIZATION> Thiokol </ORGANIZATION> settled alone with the Resniks; the astronaut's father said it came to $ 2 million to $ 3.5 million. <ORGANIZATION> Thiokol </ORGANIZATION> also settled with <PERSON> McNair </PERSON>'s widow and two infants. Their lawyer, <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Krist </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION>, says he would not let the family accept a joint government-company offer as low that accepted by the other families. He offered to settle separately with the government for whatever it calculated its share was, and he would take on <ORGANIZATION> Thiokol </ORGANIZATION> independently. But the government refused. Justice's <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> explained, `` We could n't settle on behalf of the government alone, because there was no direct government liability. Our settlement offers were all on behalf of both the government and the company.'' But the joint settlements left the question of liability too murky for <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>'s widow, <PERSON> Jane </PERSON>. `` She did n't feel justice was being served,'' her lawyer, <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Maready </PERSON> said. `` She feels now that the people whose negligence caused the accident should be accountable for their actions.'' She sued <ORGANIZATION> Thiokol </ORGANIZATION>, the government and <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> <PERSON> Mulloy </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> engineer responsible for the booster rocket that was blamed for the accident. But last year, the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> expanded its 35-year-old doctrine that military survivors may not sue the government. It extended the government's immunity to a case like the Challenger disaster, where a military pilot was killed while supervised by federal civilian employees. Government lawyers appeared in court and got both the government and <PERSON> Mulloy </PERSON> dismissed as defendants. <PERSON> Maready </PERSON> has filed notice he intends to appeal. `` That ruling says, in effect, that a military person is a second class citizen, that no matter how negligent our government was in this situation that the people in the agencies involved are n't accountable,'' <PERSON> Maready </PERSON> said. `` It's a dangerous thing for the space program to be run by people who are n't fully accountable.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880313-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-13-88 1144EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w AM-Budget Bjt   03-13 0676</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Budget, Bjt,680</SECOND>
<HEAD>Despite Summit Agreement, Requests Mounting for More 1988 Federal
Spending</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ALAN FRAM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The highly touted budget summit agreement, long since enacted into law, definitively settled the question of how much money the federal government should spend this year. Right? Wrong. Congressional leaders are girding for a fight over whether spending in fiscal year 1988, which is nearly half over, needs to be increased. Whether lawmakers adhere to the summit pact and only provide extra money for what the agreement called `` dire emergencies'' rests on whether they succumb to the urge to spend more _ an urging fueled by the fact that this is an election year. In an era of $ 1 trillion federal budgets, requests for an additional several billion dollars for unforeseen needs are made by the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and approved by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> virtually every year. They are called supplemental spending bills. But the budget pact concluded by President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and congressional leaders forbade supplementals `` except in the case of dire emergency.'' The term was left undefined. Lawmakers are already beginning to submit new spending proposals said to be for dire emergencies. One, with 37 co-sponsors, would provide $ 105 million to the financially strapped <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION>. Another, with 20 co-sponsors, would add $ 263 million in spending for the homeless. `` My experience around here is it's sort of like a pent-up lake and the dam could break very easily,'' Sen. <PERSON> Pete </PERSON> <PERSON> V. </PERSON> <PERSON> Domenici </PERSON> of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, senior Republican on the <ORGANIZATION> Budget </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> and one of the negotiators at last fall's budget summit, says of the congressional proclivity for spending money. House Speaker <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Texas </LOCATION>, said last week that he interprets dire emergencies to include crises such as natural disasters or military operations. `` Aside from that kind of thing, it's not our expectation, nor our intention'' to approve other kinds of new spending, <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> said. Indeed, many lawmakers seem to believe that in this election year it could be bad politics to openly preach more spending because of the effect on the deficit. There is another reason for Democrats to be leery of a supplemental spending bill. Many of them believe it could become a way for aid to the Nicaraguan Contra rebels to be restored. `` The administration will ultimately use the supplemental for Contra aid,'' predicts Rep. <PERSON> Vic </PERSON> <PERSON> Fazio </PERSON>, D-Calif. Despite those incentives, some are pessimistic that lawmakers seeking new spending will be thwarted. `` They'll be caving, and it's unfortunate,'' said Rep. <PERSON> Delbert </PERSON> <PERSON> Latta </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, ranking Republican on the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Budget </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> and another summit participant. `` It seems like per usual, everybody's got their program they're particularly interested in that's just not getting enough money. Lawmakers will be watching closely this week, when the administration says it will submit a supplemental spending bill of its own. The package is expected by congressional aides to be worth between $ 1 billion and $ 2 billion, but administration officials say it will produce no red ink. Instead, they say the spending for veterans, black lung benefits, the judicial branch, <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION>, prisons and other programs will be offset by cuts in other unspecified areas. If legislators believe that some of the spending in <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s request is not truly for emergencies, some lawmakers might be encouraged to press for money for programs they favor Under any circumstances, some members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> might try to attach their requests for new spending to the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> proposal. Such requests, once submitted, might be hard for other lawmakers to resist, especially with elections coming in a few months. For example, the <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> guard </ORGANIZATION>, because it is low on money, has already announced plans to curtail more than half of its drug enforcement patrols and to close several facilities. Members could be hard-pressed to vote against restoring such cuts. Even if such efforts lose, lawmakers lose nothing by introducing them and showing their constituents that at least they tried. `` This is how they start brewing the stew,'' said one congressional aide, who asked not to be identified, about how extra spending gets generated.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880313-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-13-88 1145EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-BabyMonitors     03-13 0263</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Baby Monitors,0267</SECOND>
<HEAD>Company Says Alarms Faulty On Some Machines Monitoring Babies'
Breathing</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MINNEAPOLIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 As many as 5,000 machines designed to monitor babies at risk of sudden infant death syndrome have faulty alarms that could leave infants vulnerable to death or injury, warns the company that makes them. The devices, manufactured by <ORGANIZATION> Aequitron </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, are designed to sound an alarm if an infant suddenly stops breathing or has an abnormal heart rate. But the machines have a `` higher than acceptable failure rate,'' the company's president, <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, said last week. The company issued a safety alert, warning dealers about the defect in its new model, No. 9200, which has been shipped to homes and hospitals nationwide since last July. The alert does not affect about 40,000 earlier models. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> said that no injuries or deaths have been reported, but that the company learned within the last two or three weeks that the alarm had failed in some instances. The device primarily is used in homes to monitor children believed to be at high risk for SIDS. The mysterious malady is the seventh leading killer of younger Americans, according to the national <ORGANIZATION> Centers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Disease </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Control </ORGANIZATION>. In some cases, the infants suffer from apnea, a tendency to stop breathing while asleep, <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> said. If the alarm sounds in time, an adult often can awaken the child and restart his or her breathing. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> said the company is notifying its dealers about the problem by registered letter. The dealers will alert individual customers, who lease the machines for home use.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880313-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-13-88 1145EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-MemoryLoss     03-13 0289</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Memory Loss,0299</SECOND>
<HEAD>Prosecutors Drop Fraud Count Due To Defendant's Memory Loss</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BECKLEY, W.Va. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Federal prosecutors say they have dropped a fraud count against a former insurance agent who lost all memory of his alleged crime after suffering a heart attack. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>, 52, had been charged with pocketing $ 76,386 by filing a false insurance policy claim. Federal prosecutors dismissed the charge Friday, basing their decision on medical opinion that <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> is unable to proceed in court. Prosecutors said <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> filled out a bogus life insurance form on Dec. 14, 1983, backdated it and invented a fake beneficiary to receive the money from his former employer, <ORGANIZATION> Peoples </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Life </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Insurance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>. Assistant <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Attorney <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Lynette </PERSON> <PERSON> Ranson </PERSON> said <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> scanned newspapers for stories on violent or accidental deaths and used those victims' names in the fraudulent policies She said <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> had used the scheme more than once but said prosecutors agreed to press only one count in exchange for a guilty plea. But <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>' deteriorating health prevented him from ever making a plea, <PERSON> Ranson </PERSON> said. `` We thought ... that he was playing games, and that's why we held off for a long time,'' <PERSON> Ranson </PERSON> said. `` But he really is in bad shape.'' <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> was disabled since November 1986, when he suffered a cardiac arrest that included `` one episode of sudden death,'' according to Dr. M.I. <PERSON> Dababnah </PERSON>. The seizure came three months after <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> was charged. It apparently caused him to lose his memory, <PERSON> Dababnah </PERSON> said in reports to federal court. That diagnosis was supported by Dr. <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Andrews </PERSON>, a clinical psychologist for the <ORGANIZATION> West </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Virginia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Disability </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Determination </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>. `` He has virtually no memory for significant events within the last five years,'' <PERSON> Andrews </PERSON> advised the court.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880313-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-13-88 1146EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-LufthansaSuit     03-13 0187</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Lufthansa Suit,0192</SECOND>
<HEAD>Lawyer Reportedly Wins $40,000 From Airline For Drink Spilled on
Head</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MANAMA, Bahrain (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A man who said his hearing was damaged when a <ORGANIZATION> Lufthansa </ORGANIZATION> airline attendant spilled hot drinks over his head has won nearly $ 40,000 in damages, a newspaper reported Sunday. The plaintiff, a <LOCATION> Bahraini </LOCATION> lawyer identified as <PERSON> Abdul-Wahab </PERSON> <PERSON> Ahmed </PERSON> <PERSON> bin </PERSON> <PERSON> Harmas </PERSON>, had filed the suit against the West German airline in <LOCATION> Bahrain </LOCATION>'s High Civil Court. The lawsuit alleged negligence and said the flight attendant accidentally spilled four pots of hot coffee and tea over his head, according to the English-language Gulf Daily News. The newspaper said the court awarded him 15,000 dinars, or $ 39,750, which was one-tenth the amount sought. The paper said the accident occurred during a flight from <LOCATION> Frankfurt </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Bahrain </LOCATION>, when the plane hit severe turbulence. It gave no precise dates. The man's injuries led to three months' treatment in <LOCATION> Bahrain </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, the newspaper said. The court ruled that it was the airline's responsibility to ensure the safety of passengers, the paper said. <ORGANIZATION> Lufthansa </ORGANIZATION> officials in <LOCATION> Bahrain </LOCATION> have refused to comment on the case.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880313-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-13-88 1146EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Bangladesh-Election     03-13 0301</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Bangladesh-Election,0308</SECOND>
<HEAD>Ershad Tally Rises to 249 in Parliamentary Vote</HEAD>
<DATELINE>DHAKA, Bangladesh (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Hussain </PERSON> <PERSON> Muhammad </PERSON> <PERSON> Ershad </PERSON>'s party increased its already wide margin in <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION> by picking up two more seats in weekend repolling, the <ORGANIZATION> Election </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> announced Sunday Voting was held Saturday in nine districts where violence during the main election March 3 had forced it to be called off. At least 13 people were killed and 300 others injured in clashes March 3, and two more people died in bomb blasts in <LOCATION> Dhaka </LOCATION> during repolling Saturday, police said. The country's major opposition parties, which have been waging a campaign since November to oust <PERSON> Ershad </PERSON>, boycotted the Parliament balloting. They contend that fair elections can not be held until <PERSON> Ershad </PERSON> resigns and have denounced the latest vote as fraudulent. <PERSON> Ershad </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> Jatiya </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> had 249 seats in the 330-member house, according to the latest results. The <ORGANIZATION> Election </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> said the <ORGANIZATION> Combined </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Opposition </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, a coalition of scores of small groups, won 18 seats. Two minor parties won two seats each, and independents won 25 seats. The results in three districts have not yet been announced. In one district, where a candidate was killed, voting has been scheduled for April 7. Another 30 seats in <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION> are reserved for women, who are chosen later. The major opposition parties contend that less than 1 percent of the nation's 48 million registered voters cast ballots in the Parliament elections. But government officials say the turnout appeared to be more than 50 percent. <PERSON> Ershad </PERSON> scheduled the elections after dissolving <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION> 3 -LCB- years before its five-year term was set to expire in an effort to appease his foes. The former army general took power in a 1982 bloodless coup and was elected president in a 1986 election. Major opposition parties contended that vote was fraudulent.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880313-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-13-88 1149EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-BRF--Turkey-Collision     03-13 0088</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Turkey-Collision,0091</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bus-Truck Collision Kills 13 Turks</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ANKARA, Turkey (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A truck on the wrong side of the road collided head-on with a bus Sunday, killing 13 Turks, authorities said. Thirty-five passengers were reported injured in the accident, about 90 miles south of <LOCATION> Ankara </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> Anatolia </ORGANIZATION> news agency said the accident occurred at 6:30 a.m. near <LOCATION> Sereflikochisar </LOCATION> township and that the truck driver, among the dead, apparently had fallen asleep at the wheel. The bus was going from <LOCATION> Ankara </LOCATION> to the <LOCATION> Mediterranean </LOCATION> coastal city of <LOCATION> Mersin </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880313-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-13-88 1151EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-BRF--HongKong-Heroin     03-13 0132</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Hong Kong-Heroin,0135</SECOND>
<HEAD>Police Seize 440 Pounds of Heroin</HEAD>
<DATELINE>HONG KONG (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Police on Sunday seized 440 pounds of heroin and arrested two men in an apartment raid, authorities said. Police said it was the largest seizure ever in the British colony of No. 3 heroin, which is not top-grade and is used mostly by local drug addicts. The raided apartment on <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> was also the largest drug manufucturing center ever discovered in the colony, police said, adding that the seizure following long surveillance of the premises. Police said they also seized a van containing more than 440 pounds of caffeine, needed to manufacture the drug. They said the van, which was found in another district of the island, was owned by the syndicate using the raided apartment.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880313-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-13-88 1152EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-BRF--Germany-Soviet     03-13 0114</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Germany-Soviet,0118</SECOND>
<HEAD>Kohl To Visit Moscow This Fall For Talks With Soviet Leaders</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BONN, West Germany (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Chancellor <PERSON> Helmut </PERSON> <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON> will travel to <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> this fall for talks with Soviet leader <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>, government officials said Sunday. Chief government spokesman <PERSON> Friedhelm </PERSON> <PERSON> Ost </PERSON> said <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> has also agreed to visit <LOCATION> Bonn </LOCATION> during the first half of next year. <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON> had asked <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> to visit <LOCATION> Bonn </LOCATION> in the first half of this year. But after a meeting with Soviet Foreign Minister <PERSON> Eduard </PERSON> <PERSON> Shevardnadze </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Bonn </LOCATION> in January, West German officials said scheduling problems would delay the visit. <PERSON> Ost </PERSON>, in a statement, said the exact dates of the visits have not yet been set.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880313-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-13-88 1154EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-LouisianaGovernor Bjt   03-13 0695</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Louisiana Governor, Bjt,0713</SECOND>
<HEAD>Roemer Says He Will Mix Dreams With Reality</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ALAN SAYRE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BATON ROUGE, La. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> `` Buddy'' <PERSON> Roemer </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>, a brash self-styled reformer who unseated a political legend to take office Monday as governor, says he faces `` a difficult and interesting job'' in trying to solve <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION>'s problems. `` I think I'm just a representative of the people in this. I think it's a make-or-break situation for the kinds of things we want,'' <PERSON> Roemer </PERSON>, 44, said in a recent interview. As Gov. <PERSON> Edwin </PERSON> <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON> leaves office, the state faces the immediate problems of a four-year, $ 1.2 billion budget deficit and a cash shortage that threatens to shut down state government. Fiscal analysts have warned that the state faces as much as a $ 1 billion shortfall for the 1988-89 fiscal year. The state's unemployment rate hit 12 percent in January, one of the highest in the nation, due primarily to the long-running downturn in the oil and gas industry. At the same time, <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION>'s education systems are under challenge as second-rate, business interests are demanding a major overhaul of the state's tax system in order to attract new industry, and environmental groups are calling for tougher regulations to protect the air and water. <PERSON> Roemer </PERSON>, who plans major reforms in those areas and others such as in campaign finance practices, said the challenge is unlike that facing any other <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION> governor. `` We need a combination in the next four years of a crisis manager and a long-term planner,'' he said. `` It's rare that you combine the two. That's what I'm going to have to do as governor. `` But I've got to do both to get us out of debt and build _ education development, economic development, better environment. It's going to be a difficult and interesting job.'' To get started, the Democratic former congressman is planning a low-budget inauguration minus the traditional parade and inaugural night ball. According to his transition office, only $ 48,000 will be spent on the entire event, less than the $ 60,000 Gov. <PERSON> Dave </PERSON> <PERSON> Treen </PERSON> spent on the stage used for his swearing-in ceremony in 1980. <PERSON> Roemer </PERSON>, who campaigned on the need for a `` revolution'' to turn around the state's declining fortunes, said the first year of his administration will be dedicated to reversing the financial problems and creating a new image for <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION>, often associated with scandal. `` Confidence, attitude and legislative programs _ and then we will slowly fund them over the next four years,'' he said. `` This plan wo n't be magic, it wo n't be instant. We've had to build from the ground up. But I'm very pleased with the progress we've made.'' <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON>, who served as governor from 1972 to 1980 and returned for a third term in 1984, was occupied for much of his last administration defending himself successfully against federal racketeering charges. As solutions for the state's budget problems, he proposed a statewide lottery and casino gambling in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Roemer </PERSON> is opposed to both. <PERSON> Roemer </PERSON> said he was happy that <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON> was willing to help during the transition between the Oct. 24 election and Monday's inauguration At <PERSON> Roemer </PERSON>'s request <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON> appointed <PERSON> Brian </PERSON> <PERSON> Kendrick </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Baton </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION> department store executive, as commissioner of administration. <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON> also approved about $ 36 million in budget cuts requested by <PERSON> Roemer </PERSON>, but shielded the giant <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Human </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Resources </ORGANIZATION> from the fiscal ax. <PERSON> Roemer </PERSON> is considering splitting the agency into two departments as part of a reorganization program to be studied by a special legislative session later this month. Short-term budget reductions also will be on the agenda. <PERSON> Kendrick </PERSON> has spearheaded efforts to minimize the cash-flow problem by pushing back more than $ 480 million in expenditures until the new fiscal year begins July 1. The cash-saving measures include delaying payments to government retirement systems, holding state income tax refund checks for 90 days and pushing one state payday back. In the meantime, <PERSON> Roemer </PERSON> said he will cut the budget back as far as he can before the subject of taxes is broached. `` We are not going to raise taxes or change taxes until we cut this budget,'' <PERSON> Roemer </PERSON> said. `` It is out of control.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880313-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-13-88 1157EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-MissingScientist     03-13 0329</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Missing Scientist,0339</SECOND>
<HEAD>Papers Link Missing Scientist to Alleged Plan to Make Nuclear
Weapons</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TAIPEI, Taiwan (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A top Taiwanese nuclear scientist has disappeared and may have fled to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> with confidential blueprints disclosing that <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION> plans to make nuclear weapons, newspapers reported Sunday. Government officials repeatedly have denied any plans to produce nuclear weapons and said all nuclear research programs in <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION> are for peaceful purposes. On Friday, Defense Minister <PERSON> Cheng </PERSON> <PERSON> Wei-yuan </PERSON> told the lawmaking <ORGANIZATION> Legislative </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Yuan </ORGANIZATION> that a warrant had been issued for the arrest of Col. <PERSON> Chang </PERSON> <PERSON> Hsien-yi </PERSON>, 45, who was deputy director of the nuclear energy research center at the military-run <ORGANIZATION> Chungshan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Science </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Technology </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Cheng </PERSON> said the warrant was issued because <PERSON> Chang </PERSON> had not asked permission for leave. <PERSON> Chang </PERSON> has been missing since January, and officials said they have no information on his whereabouts. But the mass circulation <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> said <PERSON> Chang </PERSON>'s daughter, Pei-fen, wrote from <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION> to a classmate at an elementary school in <LOCATION> Taipei </LOCATION> last month saying she missed <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION> The letter gave no return address and the girl gave no indication whether she was living with her father, the newspaper said. Without disclosing the source of their information, several newspapers claimed that <PERSON> Chang </PERSON> was a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> spy and had fled to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> together with his wife and three children. The liberal newspaper <ORGANIZATION> Independence </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Morning </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION>, quoting an unidentified institute official, said <PERSON> Chang </PERSON> earlier had collected `` a whole bunch'' of pictures and confidential information on <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION>'s nuclear plans. Some newspapers said <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION> may have recycled key elements from waste from its three nuclear power plants to make nuclear weapons. The <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION>, quoting an unidentified source, said the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> may have become suspicious of <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION>'s plans and this may have been behind a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> decision earlier this year to stop supplying <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION> with heavy water, which is needed for nuclear development. Officials were unavailable for comment because of the Sunday holiday.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880313-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-13-88 1205EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Gorbachev-Yugoslavia     03-13 0683</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Gorbachev-Yugoslavia,0707</SECOND>
<HEAD>Visit May Offer Soviet Leader Comparisons To Soviet Reform</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MICHAEL PUTZEL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BELGRADE, Yugoslavia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Soviet leader <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> will spend five days in this communist country studying economic and social problems that he hopes the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> can avoid as it embraces reform. <LOCATION> Yugoslavia </LOCATION>, which has jealously guarded its independence from <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> power for 40 years, presents a picture of prosperity to a visitor from <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>. A crush of private automobiles in the capital and store windows displaying local and Western-made consumer goods of every description make <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>'s truck-cluttered streets and drab facades seem all the more barren. But the country's system of `` self-managed, market socialism'' is struggling with high inflation, high unemployment, widespread labor unrest and a paralyzing $ 20 billion debt to Western creditors. And <LOCATION> Yugoslavia </LOCATION>'s leadership must constantly perform a delicate balancing act to prevent the country from being torn apart by nationalistic rivalries within its borders. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> arrives here Monday for a five-day visit that includes <LOCATION> Belgrade </LOCATION>, the northern industrial city of <LOCATION> Ljubljana </LOCATION> and the southern resort city of <LOCATION> Dubrovnik </LOCATION> on the <LOCATION> Adriatic </LOCATION>. The Soviet leader, who has just marked the end of his third year in power, is trying to boost the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> out of economic stagnation. He has decentralized control over production and introduced market forces to shake workers and managers out of their notorious complacency. During his tour <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> may gain some pointers on his programs of `` perestroika,'' or restructuring of the Soviet economy, and `` glasnost,'' which encourages more open expression of ideas for solving the nation's problems. With the development in recent years of a free-wheeling press and a mixed economy that encourages both private enterprise and central planning, <LOCATION> Yugoslavia </LOCATION> offers something of a window on the future for the reform-minded Soviet leader. Runaway inflation and the government's powerless decrees aimed at curing the country's economic ills serve notice that the path may not be an easy one. In recent months, as ethnic minorities have attempted to take advantage of the Soviet government's new tolerance to express their long-held grievances, <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> has faced challenges from nationalists of several stripes. Despite some rioting and huge mass demonstrations in the southern republics of <LOCATION> Azerbaidjian </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Armenia </LOCATION>, no Soviet ethnic group has the strength that <LOCATION> Yugoslavian </LOCATION> nationalities have used to guarantee each a share of governing power at the expense of the central authorities. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> is the first Soviet leader to visit <LOCATION> Yugoslavia </LOCATION> since the death of <PERSON> Josip </PERSON> <PERSON> Broz </PERSON> <PERSON> Tito </PERSON> in May 1980. <PERSON> Tito </PERSON> broke with <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> in 1948 and steered a stubbornly independent course outside the Soviet bloc. After being forced by a Soviet-led blockade to open trade with the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Yugoslavia </LOCATION> has since re-established economic ties with <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>. The <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> today is <LOCATION> Yugoslavia </LOCATION>'s largest trading partner, with the Yugoslavs importing primarily crude oil and other raw materials and exporting manufactured goods, including much-prized shoes, clothing and technology to the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. A $ 1.4 billion trade surplus is a subject of concern in <LOCATION> Belgrade </LOCATION>, but there has been speculation the Soviets may agree to pay off their paper debt by building a subway system for the traffic-clogged Yugoslav capital. The present <LOCATION> Yugoslav </LOCATION> leadership, headed by an eight-member state presidency, has continued <PERSON> Tito </PERSON>'s independent political course, and <LOCATION> Yugoslavia </LOCATION> remains an important nation in the non-aligned movement. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> is expected to formally acknowledge that special status with the issuance during his visit of a joint declaration guaranteeing full Yugoslavian independence. But in the context of his public statements in <LOCATION> Prague </LOCATION> and to fellow <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> leaders in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> last year, the <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> declaration may signal more independence for other East European nations as well. The Soviet leader has said his nation has no monopoly on the proper path to socialism, and reform-minded leaders elsewhere in <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> are expected to test his words with experiments aimed at reinvigorating their own economies. Yugoslav deputy foreign minister, <PERSON> Ilija </PERSON> <PERSON> Djukic </PERSON>, has said the new Soviet-Yugoslav document would update previous declarations signed by the two countries in 1955 and 1956 and will `` further confirm principles of non-interference on the basis of equality and soveregnty.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880313-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-13-88 1206EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Afghanistan Bjt   03-13 0603</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Afghanistan, Bjt,0622</SECOND>
<HEAD>Soviet Deadline Near On Afghan Talks</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By HANNS NEUERBOURG</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>GENEVA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Talks aimed at ending the Afghan war are one day away from a Soviet deadline for their completion, but a crucial dispute on who will run the country still stands in the way of a signed settlement. Soviet leader <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> said last month that Soviet troops would begin withdrawing troops from <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> by mid-May if an agreement is reached by March 15. But sources close to the U.N.-sponsored negotiations say they do n't view the deadline as rigid. Delegations from the Soviet-backed government in <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION> and from <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>, which is representing the <LOCATION> Afghan </LOCATION> resistance, both say they are ready to extend the negotiations. U.N. Undersecretary General <PERSON> Diego </PERSON> <PERSON> Cordovez </PERSON>, the talks' mediator, said he asked both sides to seek `` strengthened instructions'' during the weekend to prepare for Monday's session. Soviet troops intervened in <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> in 1979. An estimated 115,000 troops have been helping the government fight the U.S.-backed Moslem guerrillas. The latest round, the longest since the talks began in 1982, opened with a confident mood on March 2. Two days later, an accord was announced on an issue that had stalled negotiations for years, with both sides agreeing on a timetable and the basic logistics for withdrawing the <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> troops. Under that accord, the pullout would be completed within nine months after its start, with half of the troops leaving in the first three months. <PERSON> Cordovez </PERSON> said later there remained no `` differences of substance'' that would bar tying up a peace package of agreements. The agreements include a bilateral agreement pledging the two countries to not interfere in each other's affairs and arrangements for the return of more than 5 million Afghan refugees from <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>. But the quick pace of the early talks quickly ran into snags. <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>'s chief representative, acting Foreign Minister <PERSON> Zain </PERSON> <PERSON> Noorani </PERSON>, said the talks were `` inching slowly'' forward, but that he expected them to regain speed this week. He did not elaborate why. The <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> and its <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION> allies, represented at <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> by Foreign Minister <PERSON> Abdul </PERSON> <PERSON> Wakil </PERSON>, blame <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> for holding up final agreement. They fault <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>'s insistence on linking the proposed settlement to the formation of a transitional government acceptable to the resistance. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> has said that the makeup of the future government should be decided by the Afghans themselves. <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> is insisting on a transitional government that would allow for the safe return of anti-Soviet refugees. So far, <PERSON> Noorani </PERSON> has given no indication that <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> would drop its demand. But sources close to the talks said <LOCATION> Islamabad </LOCATION> still hopes to strike a deal with <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>, perhaps on the timing of the establishment of a new government. But another issue had cast an increasingly larger shadow on the talks: superpower aid to the two opposing sides. On March 4, the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> demanded that all foreign military aid to the warring parties must stop simultaneously. The <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> has flatly rejected the demand, saying the accords will leave it free to continue military aid to <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION> after the troop withdrawal. <PERSON> Wakil </PERSON> said the draft agreements provide only for a cessation of military aid to the U.S.-backed guerrillas. In a strong statement on Friday, <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Redman </PERSON> said <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> aid to the Afghan rebels will not be halted until the Soviets stopped their assistance to the <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION> government. The Soviets sent troops into <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> in 1979 to prop up the wobbly Marxist government. The guerrillas, meanwhile, have formed their own government and have rejected any power sharing with the Soviet-backed government of President <PERSON> Najib </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880313-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-13-88 1207EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-AfghanResistance     03-13 0662</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Afghan Resistance,0681</SECOND>
<HEAD>Infighting Plagues Afghan Guerrilla Factions</HEAD>
<HEAD>With AM-Afghanistan, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BRYAN WILDER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> ISLAMABAD </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> -LRB- ap -RRB- _ <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>'s tough stand at the slow-moving Afghan peace talks has touched off a power struggle among guerrilla leaders fighting the Soviet-backed Afghan government. <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> Prime Minister <PERSON> Mohammad </PERSON> <PERSON> Khan </PERSON> <PERSON> Junejo </PERSON> has been barnstorming the country to drum up support for his demand that an accord on a Soviet troop withdrawal be coupled with a plan for a future <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION> government. In the meantime, the fractious guerrilla alliance, whose factions all want a voice in that new government, has been plagued by upheaval. During the weekend, <PERSON> Yunis </PERSON> <PERSON> Khalis </PERSON> resigned as chairman of the seven-party alliance, ostensibly for health reasons. But there were numerous reports, unconfirmed by guerrilla spokesmen, that the 69-year-old <LOCATION> Khalis </LOCATION> quit to protest plans to send a resistance delegation to the U.N.-sponsored peace talks at <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION>, which resume Monday. Another insurgent leader, <PERSON> Sibghatullah </PERSON> <PERSON> Mojaddedi </PERSON>, pulled his moderate <ORGANIZATION> Afghan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION> out of the alliance complaining of undue pressure from the body's four-party majority of Moslem extremists. Two days later, <PERSON> Mojaddedi </PERSON> returned to the fold, saying he had received `` certain assurances'' from the fundamentalists and from Pakistani officials. He did not elaborate. There has been intense Pakistani pressure on the guerrillas to come up with an acceptable plan for forming a transitional government that would preside over the withdrawal of the estimated 115,000 Soviet troops who back <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION>'s communist rulers. <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>, which for years insisted the Soviet presence was the root of the Afghan conflict, reversed itself this year by declaring it would not sign an agreement that does not address <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>'s political future <LOCATION> Islamabad </LOCATION> speaks for the guerrillas at the <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> talks and cares for about 3.5 million Afghan refugees living in camps near the Afghan border. It also channels <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> arms to the guerrillas, who are headquartered in the northwest Pakistani city of <LOCATION> Peshawar </LOCATION>. Although <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION> have accused <LOCATION> Islamabad </LOCATION> of blocking what could be an imminent Soviet pullout, <PERSON> Junejo </PERSON>'s public relations campaign indicates <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>'s stand has solid public support. Soviet leader <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> has said his troops could begin going home on May 15 if <LOCATION> Islamabad </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION> sign an agreement by March 15. The deadline pressure has taken its toll on the guerrilla alliance. While rejecting the <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> talks because of the guerrillas' exclusion, the alliance nevertheless responded with a proposal for a heavily Moslem government headed by alliance leaders. <PERSON> Mojaddedi </PERSON> protested when the extremists used their majority to vote in one of their own as future president, <PERSON> Ahmed </PERSON> <PERSON> Shah </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Ittehad </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>. The moderate factions favor a compromise government that could include some communists now in power in <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION>, possibly headed by former King <PERSON> Zahir </PERSON> <PERSON> Shah </PERSON>. <PERSON> Mojaddedi </PERSON> insisted that the 73-year-old monarch, currently in exile in <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION>, is the only neutral figure acceptable to a majority of Afghans. <LOCATION> Khalis </LOCATION>'s resignation, meanwhile, threatened to widen the split because the next leader in line for the rotating chairmanship is <PERSON> Gulbaddin </PERSON> <PERSON> Hekmatyar </PERSON>, head of the Hezb-i-Islami and the most extremist Moslem guerrilla of all. While fending off acusations that his fighters have attacked rival groups inside <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Hekmatyar </PERSON> recently had taken to upstaging <LOCATION> Khalis </LOCATION> by calling press conferences of his own to promote <ORGANIZATION> Hezb-i-Islami </ORGANIZATION>'s hardline vision of a fundamentalist Islamic regime. <PERSON> Mohammad </PERSON> <PERSON> Uaqub </PERSON> <PERSON> Sharafat </PERSON>, press spokesman for the alliance, said there were plans to send a guerrilla delegation to the <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> talks to help clear up the confusion over the insurgents' stand. Even that move threatened to cause a rift. <PERSON> Rasul </PERSON> <PERSON> Sayyaf </PERSON>, leader of the Ittehad party, issued a statement Sunday declaring his opposition to sending a delegation. `` And under no circumstances shall we agree to any kind of direct or indirect talks with the <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION> regime or the -LRB- ruling <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Afghanistan </ORGANIZATION> -RRB-,'' he said. Pakistani officials publicly have urged the guerrillas to soften their stand in the interest of peace. But so far, the extremists among the insurgents have equated compromise with capitulation.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880313-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-13-88 1208EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-BRF--Greece-Israel     03-13 0139</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Greece-Israel,0143</SECOND>
<HEAD>Says Greece Will Not Recognize Israel</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ATHENS, Greece (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Premier <PERSON> Andreas </PERSON> <PERSON> Papandreou </PERSON> has ruled out establishing full diplomatic relations with <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> because of violence in <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s occupied territories. Addressing Parliament, <PERSON> Papandreou </PERSON> said it `` would have been useful to have full diplomatic relations with <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>,'' before <LOCATION> Greece </LOCATION> assumed the presidency of the <ORGANIZATION> European </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Community </ORGANIZATION> in July. `` But we deeply regret that we ca n't do so after the recent treatment that the state of <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> reserved for the <LOCATION> Palestinians </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Papandreou </PERSON> told the 300-member body Friday. Israeli bullets and beatings have left scores of Palestinians dead in the occupied <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strip </LOCATION> since anti-occupation riots began Dec. 8. <LOCATION> Greece </LOCATION> is the only NATO-member country and <ORGANIZATION> EEC </ORGANIZATION> member that does n't fully recogize <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>. The two countries have maintained diplomatic relations in each other's capitals since 1971.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880313-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-13-88 1254EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Soviet-Detentions     03-13 0404</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Soviet-Detentions,0416</SECOND>
<HEAD>Dissidents Detained En Route To Seminar On Ethnic Problems</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MOSCOW (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Police detained at least seven dissidents and former political prisoners who planned to attend a seminar on the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>'s increasingly volatile ethnic problems, the meeting's organizer said Sunday <PERSON> Lev </PERSON> <PERSON> Timofeyev </PERSON> told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> that the 70 people who did attend the unsanctioned weekend seminar issued a statement condemning the `` unreasonable and irresponsible'' behavior of police agencies in detaining would-be participants. <PERSON> Timofeyev </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> human rights activist, said the group that met at his southern <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> apartment learned that seven activists from <LOCATION> Lithuania </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Estonia </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Ukraine </LOCATION> were taken off of trains and planes headed for the capital. At least five others were told they should n't leave their homes over the weekend or they would be arrested, <PERSON> Timofeyev </PERSON> said. Among those kept under house arrest was <PERSON> Genrikh </PERSON> <PERSON> Altunyan </PERSON>, an Armenian activist who lives in the Ukrainian city of <LOCATION> Kharkov </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Armenia </LOCATION> and the neighboring republic of <LOCATION> Azerbaijan </LOCATION> have been the scene of the most intense unrest among the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>'s more than 100 ethnic groups. A dispute over control of a region in <LOCATION> Azerbaijan </LOCATION> known as <LOCATION> Nagorno-Karabakh </LOCATION>, where more than three quarters of the population is Armenian, triggered mass demonstrations in <LOCATION> Yerevan </LOCATION> in recent weeks and rioting in the Azerbaijani city of <LOCATION> Sumgait </LOCATION> that killed at least 32. <PERSON> Timofeyev </PERSON>, who was released from a labor camp a year ago following a government review of political sentencings, said the seminar adopted three resolutions that will be forwarded to the <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION> on how to resolve ethnic problems. The first demands broad public discussion of ethnic tensions to correct widespread ignorance of the causes of nationalistic outbursts. Another calls for discussion of limitations on religious freedom and the government's propagation of atheism, which the activists said is the root of some ethnic turmoil. The third proposal calls on the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> government to let Crimean Tatars return to their historic homeland, the <LOCATION> Black </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sea </LOCATION> peninsula from which they were routed during World War II when dictator <PERSON> Josef </PERSON> <PERSON> V. </PERSON> <PERSON> Stalin </PERSON> accused the entire population of collaborating with Nazi invaders. The Tatars were exonerated two decades later, but they have been banned from returning to the <LOCATION> Crimea </LOCATION>, now the site of some of the best resorts and official retreats. He said the documents produced at the seminar would be circulated among activists so the `` unofficial viewpoint'' on nationalities questions can reach the Soviet public.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880313-0025 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-13-88 1257EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-SpringBreak     03-13 0620</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Spring Break,0637</SECOND>
<HEAD>Where the Boys Were: The Demise of Spring Break</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DONALD W. SWINTON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>FORT LAUDERDALE, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
