<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880529-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-29-88 2348EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Mexico-Civilization     05-29 0945</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Mexico-Civilization,0974</SECOND>
<HEAD>Delta Yields Traces Of Another Ancient Mexican Civilization</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</NOTE>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ISAAC A. LEVI</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>XALAPA, Mexico (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Deep in a mangrove swamp near the <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, archaeologists have discovered traces of what could be another ancient Mexican civilization. So far, the only clues to these mysterious people are a four-ton stele, or stone slab, covered with hieroglyphic writing and a 19-inch-high clay figure of a fertility-rite priest. `` But,'' says <PERSON> Fernando </PERSON> <PERSON> Winfield </PERSON> <PERSON> Capitaine </PERSON>, director of the <ORGANIZATION> Xalapa </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Museum </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Anthropology </ORGANIZATION>, `` the finds are so promising that the museum is planning to mount an expedition to that area of <LOCATION> Veracruz </LOCATION> state in cooperation with the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Geographic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION>.'' The stele was found in November 1986. It is covered with inscriptions in an unknown language but with some Mayan numerals. The priest in the clay figure is wearing the human skin of a flayed sacrificial victim. Both are about 1,800 years old. `` That would place them in the second century A.D., which is after the archaeological Olmecs, who flourished in the area from around 1050 to 500 B.C., and before the Mayas who emerged around the fourth century A.D,'' <PERSON> Winfield </PERSON> said in an interview. Adding to the intrigue, the <ORGANIZATION> Mayas </ORGANIZATION> lived in the <LOCATION> Yucatan </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Peninsula </LOCATION>, more than 700 miles to the east, <PERSON> Winfield </PERSON> said at the museum in <LOCATION> Xalapa </LOCATION>, where the stele and figure are kept. `` But there are two dates on the stele in Mayan writing, in their so-called Long Count Calendar made up of dots and bars, equivalent to May 22, 143 -LRB- A.D. -RRB-, and July 13, 156 A.D.,'' <PERSON> Winfield </PERSON> said. If the mysterious people did exist, <PERSON> Winfield </PERSON> said, they also appeared to be unrelated to the other two of the four known civilizations that inhabited the gulf coast: the Totonacas, who emerged around the seventh century A.D. in the area where the artifacts were found, or the Huaxtecas farther north, about one century later. `` They could be the Xicalancas, of which <PERSON> Clavijero </PERSON> briefly talked about,'' <PERSON> Winfield </PERSON> said, referring to the Rev. <PERSON> Francisco </PERSON> <PERSON> Javier </PERSON> <PERSON> Francisco </PERSON> <PERSON> Javier </PERSON> <PERSON> Clavijero </PERSON> -LRB- 1731-1787 -RRB-, a Jesuit priest who was the first to systematically study <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>'s ancient languages and peoples. In his `` History of Ancient <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>,'' Clavijero in three lines briefly mentioned the Xicalanca civilization in relation to the Olmecs, but did not go into details. In `` nahuatl,'' the trading language of the <ORGANIZATION> Aztecs </ORGANIZATION>, who came much later, <LOCATION> Xicalanca </LOCATION> means `` the people who live by the Great Body of Salt Water,'' as the Gulf of <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> was called. The two artifacts were found within 130 feet of each other in the village of <LOCATION> La </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mojarra </LOCATION>, where the <LOCATION> Piojo </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> meets the <LOCATION> Acula </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION>. The crocodile-infested region is so swampy that it can be reached only by boat, <PERSON> Winfield </PERSON> said. La Mojarra, with a population of fewer than 200, is up the <LOCATION> Acula </LOCATION> about 20 miles south of the port of <LOCATION> Alvarado </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Veracruz </LOCATION> state. But neither the village nor the <LOCATION> Piojo </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> can be found on any map of <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>. Carved in relief on the previously polished stele, which is of basalt, one of the world's hardest rocks, is the full length profile of a regal figure, a man about 25 years old, holding out in both hands a vessel in a gesture of offering. `` He was probably a ruler, or a chief warrior, or a high priest _ or maybe all three since that was the custom in the gulf region in ancient times,'' <PERSON> Winfield </PERSON> said. The figure wears ear-stops, a tall headdress adorned with four representations of something like a rain god, trimmed with eight feathers, and a breastplate full of other allegorical figures over what appears to be a pleated cotton shirt or tunic. A total of 577 glyphs, or picture-words, divided into 21 neat rows running from top to bottom, plus 33 `` elements'' like the rain-god representations, cover the rest of the slab. `` It was all carved during one continuous period,'' <PERSON> Winfield </PERSON> said. `` It was a single piece of work. It is the oldest and richest piece of writing found yet about this area of ancient <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>.'' About 7 feet tall, slightly oblong and with a gently rounded top, the stele once stood on the right bank of the <LOCATION> Acula </LOCATION>, just outside <LOCATION> La </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mojarra </LOCATION>. Over the years, erosion toppled it, and it lay in the river until a fisherman discovered it and dragged it out with the help of villagers. Archaeologists retrieved the stele, but <PERSON> Winfield </PERSON> said he kept the find quiet for two years so work could proceed `` without the pressure that such a discovery creates.'' The second piece, the ceramic figure of a priest made with the region's thick orange clay, has a square base. It is the only one of two artifacts from that area with a base. The other, also in the museum, is so badly damaged it can not be studied, <PERSON> Winfield </PERSON> said. In the La Mojarra figure, only the head is missing. That type of clay figure was very popular among the four gulf cultures. The Aztecs called it in <LOCATION> Xipe </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Totec </LOCATION>, or the Lord of the Flayed, and it was variously worshiped as the god of spring, of fertility, of abundance and of the metalworkers. A peasant at <LOCATION> La </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mojarra </LOCATION> found the shattered figure many years ago while digging the foundations for his house and kept the pieces in a cardboard box. `` We got wind of it three weeks ago, and we convinced him to let the museum have it,'' <PERSON> Winfield </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Winfield </PERSON> suspects the <LOCATION> La </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mojarra </LOCATION> area could have been a ceremonial site. `` If so, there surely must be more stele and artifacts to be found,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880529-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-29-88 2351EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-AnotherLook:TornadoesAnniversary Bjt   05-29 1006</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Another Look: Tornadoes Anniversary, Bjt,1036</SECOND>
<HEAD>`Tornado Coming!' Three Years Later, Albion Rebuilding</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY24 of 5@26</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PETER MATTIACE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ALBION, Pa. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 When the `` Albion Tornado'' roared toward <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> State </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Street </LOCATION> three years ago, <PERSON> Earl </PERSON> <PERSON> Rice </PERSON> ran to warn his wife, <PERSON> Ruth </PERSON>, on their front porch `` when I saw the wind pick her up and throw her over the rail.'' Across the street, the Rev. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Reilly </PERSON> prayed hard as the gathering winds sucked him toward a second-floor window and his strength ebbed. Next door, 5-year-old <PERSON> Katie </PERSON> <PERSON> Steff </PERSON> screamed `` Tornado coming!'' as her father, <PERSON> Samuel </PERSON>, huddled the family above their funeral home. In a moment of eerie silence a few seconds later, <PERSON> Steff </PERSON> knew they were in the eye of the huge twister. Forty-one tornadoes, including nine of the highest intensities, swept through <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Ontario </LOCATION> during eight hours of May 31, 1985, killing 88 people and injuring more than 1,000. The tornado outbreak, worst since April 1975, caused $ 450 million in property damage in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. Of the dead, 62 were killed in their houses or mobile homes and a disproportionate number, 15, were between 66 and 70 years old, according to the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Weather </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>. The Albion tornado was among the worst, packing winds estimated at up to 260 miles per hour as it fell upon farmland on the <LOCATION> Ohio-Pennsylvania </LOCATION> border. The twister, estimated at 1,200 feet across, quickly moved northeast through this pleasant crossroads town near <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Erie </LOCATION> on a 14-mile tear that killed 12 people. `` I watch the sky now, just like everyone else,'' Mayor <PERSON> Bonda </PERSON> <PERSON> Dahlin </PERSON> said recently. `` Tornadoes were <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION> kind of things. But I do n't think it's something we'll ever forget.'' `` People here still cringe the minute there's a dark cloud in the sky. There's such anticipation,'' said Borough Secretary <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> McKnight </PERSON>. <PERSON> Rice </PERSON>, 72, a retired railroad worker, heard the first frantic warnings on the police scanner and ran to the door to see his wife get swept away. He woke up trapped in his own house. `` I started hollering,'' <PERSON> Rice </PERSON> recalled. `` There were timbers all over me. The beams were across my legs and I could n't move. They tried to jack up the beams, but that just put more pressure on my legs. Then they got a chain saw and cut the beams in half and pulled me out.'' <PERSON> Rice </PERSON> suffered only cuts and bruises. His wife suffered broken arms and a dislocated shoulder. <PERSON> Reilly </PERSON>, 68, pastor of <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lawrence </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Roman </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION>, was in his rectory's living room `` when the roof went off and the windows went out.'' `` I kind of spread-eagled in front of the window as the thing began to suck me out. I grabbed anything. I just hung on until it ended,'' <PERSON> Reilly </PERSON> said. `` I asked God to make it that I was ready to meet Him.'' The church and rectory were destroyed, but two days later <PERSON> Reilly </PERSON> said Mass under a tarpaulin in the ruins. <PERSON> Steff </PERSON>, 43, a mortician, gathered his wife, four daughters and a friend in the family room of their second-floor apartment. <PERSON> Katie </PERSON> screamed just as <ORGANIZATION> Albion </ORGANIZATION>'s fire siren began to wail. `` Then something hit the house and we all got into the bathroom. Things just bombarded the building,'' <PERSON> Steff </PERSON> recalled. `` Then we heard a silence, just for a second, like in the eye of a hurricane. Then everything hit us from the other side. <PERSON> Patty </PERSON>, my wife, opened the door of the family room and it was gone.'' The Steffs' business and home were destroyed, a $ 200,000 loss. <PERSON> Steff </PERSON> ran across the street to help free <PERSON> Cathy </PERSON> <PERSON> Gibson </PERSON> from her three-story Victorian house, which was down. `` I called into the debris to tell her help was coming,'' <PERSON> Steff </PERSON> said. `` Later, she told me she was never so glad to hear an undertaker's voice.'' A deputy Erie County coroner, <PERSON> Steff </PERSON> helped set up a morgue at <ORGANIZATION> Northwestern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> High </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION>. They brought in 11 bodies. Today, the tornado's southwest-to-northeast path can be clearly seen in rebuilt split-level houses and new mobile homes, grassy lots and sharply pruned oak trees that make the east side of <LOCATION> Albion </LOCATION> look like a new subdivision. It was only a few months ago, <PERSON> McKnight </PERSON> said, that he `` closed the books'' on <ORGANIZATION> Albion </ORGANIZATION>'s claims with federal and state disaster officials. Mayor <PERSON> Dahlin </PERSON> estimated that fewer than 200 of the town's 1,800 people moved away after the tornado `` because of memories, lack of money or whatever.'' `` People are getting on with their lives,'' she said. `` Businesses are being rebuilt, changing hands, and there are new ones.'' <PERSON> Reilly </PERSON>'s modern new 400-seat church is linked by a glass breezeway to a new three-bedroom rectory. Behind, a new recreation building stands in red brick. The complex cost $ 1.1 million, he said. `` One of the greatest experiences of my life, as tragic as it was, was to see the spirit of the people of this town. They took a tragic blow. They rebuilt the town,'' <PERSON> Reilly </PERSON> said. `` It's almost profane to say it was a good thing, but the bottom line is that the community is stronger and closer knit and the town is even physically better with all the new construction,'' he said. The Steffs, fully insured, rebuilt their small funeral home with two viewing rooms, but took the opportunity to move their living quarters to a house in another part of town. `` We shed our tears over it. We're trying to get our lives together. You can dwell on the negatives, but the positives are the concern and the love of the community,'' <PERSON> Steff </PERSON> said. `` When I walked out the door that day, I knew I was going to stay.'' The Rices built a modern two-bedroom split-level house. `` It's starting to feel like home,'' <PERSON> Rice </PERSON> said with a shrug `` You still think about it. Last September, I had an operation for cancer and when I was in the recovery room, I thought I was still under the house,'' he said. `` I do n't want to see another one.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880529-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-29-88 2352EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Mexico-Campaign     05-29 0757</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Mexico-Campaign,0781</SECOND>
<HEAD>Candidate Sounds Like Reformer In Final Weeks Of Presidential
Campaign</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</NOTE>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ELOY O. AGUILAR</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MEXICO CITY (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 At times, <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Salinas </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Gortari </PERSON> sounds too much like a reformer to be the presidential candidate of the <ORGANIZATION> Institutional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Revolutionary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, which has governed <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> since 1929. The 40-year-old candidate preaches democratic reforms and clean elections as he campaigns not so much for the office, which he is certain to win, but to regain his party's lost credibility. <PERSON> Salinas </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Gortari </PERSON>, whose thick black moustache and balding head feature prominently in political cartoons, is described by those close to him as a pragmatist, influenced strongly by his <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> education. Before his nomination last fall as a candidate in the July 6 election, he was President <PERSON> Miguel </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> La </PERSON> <PERSON> Madrid </PERSON>'s budget and planning secretary, a key figure in developing the economic austerity programs that have prevailed in <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> since 1982. <PERSON> Salinas </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Gortari </PERSON> has strong family ties to the northern state of <LOCATION> Nuevo </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Leon </LOCATION>, home to political conservatives who oppose the guided economy and government controls dear to governing party ideologues in <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. Some foes within the party felt <PERSON> Salinas </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Gortari </PERSON> would be identified too strongly with the business sector and with conservative groups within the party. But this has worked to the party's advantage. <PERSON> Salinas </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Gortari </PERSON> has managed to bring private business back into the party fold by advocating fewer government controls and urging business leaders to join the government `` in the battle for world markets.'' `` The time is past when the state was the instrument to solve all of society's problems,'' he told a cheering crowd at a recent meeting of business leaders in <LOCATION> Monterrey </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Nuevo </PERSON> <PERSON> Leon </PERSON>'s capital. He also wants more foreign investment to `` modernize <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> technologically.'' `` What he says agrees with what private business thinks <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> must be,'' said <PERSON> Agustin </PERSON> <PERSON> Legorreta </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> Business </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coordinating </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>. Mexican business traditionally has identified with the conservative <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Action </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, although it must maintain a close relationship with government agencies. <PERSON> Salinas </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Gortari </PERSON> speaks confidently of the resurgence of <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>. The country has a $ 105 billion foreign debt but has renegotiated it and is keeping up payments. Last month in <LOCATION> Puebla </LOCATION>, a politically conservative state in central <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Salinas </PERSON> de Gortari upset some party officials with his call for reforms. `` The citizens' vote must be respected,'' he said. `` The party will defend its victories, but it must accept its defeats.'' He also promised reforms to encourage more independent judiciary and legislative branches. `` Let us lead the democratic reform the country demands,'' he stated. The political reforms may be difficult because they imply the acceptance by the <ORGANIZATION> PRI </ORGANIZATION> of electoral losses and the consequent loss of power of local or regional party bosses. The party never has lost a presidential election or gubernatorial race in any of <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>'s 31 states since its founding. It is generally conceded in <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> that the governing party wins elections, but it often is criticized for `` winning'' by more than the necessary votes _ by stuffing ballots to claim overwhelming victories. `` There is a great internal debate going on now,'' said a source close to the candidate. `` <PERSON> Salinas </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Gortari </PERSON> is demanding elections free of fraud and there is a lot of pressure being put on local party leaders to be more democratic.'' This year, with the country in the middle of a serious economic crisis, and an increasingly vociferous opposition that includes a dissident group led by former party leaders, those close to <PERSON> Salinas </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Gortari </PERSON> believe reforms have a good chance in his six-year term. `` It is better in the long run to win by a small margin than to announce we won by a large margin and lose all credibility,'' said a source in <PERSON> Salinas </PERSON>' entourage during a recent campaign trip. Some <ORGANIZATION> PRI </ORGANIZATION> officials privately admit the party may even lose a <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> seat, something that has never happened before. De la <LOCATION> Madrid </LOCATION> won the elections in 1982 for the <ORGANIZATION> PRI </ORGANIZATION> with an official 71 percent of the vote, a figure many considered exaggerated. <ORGANIZATION> PRI </ORGANIZATION> officials now predict <PERSON> Salinas </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Gortari </PERSON> may win the July 6 election with a more realistic 55 percent to 60 percent of the votes. `` We do not know if he will have the freedom to do what he wants to do,'' said <PERSON> Alejandro </PERSON> <PERSON> Junco </PERSON>, publisher of the newspaper <ORGANIZATION> El </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Norte </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Monterrey </LOCATION> and a frequent government critic. `` But we are condemned to be optimistic evey six years.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880529-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-29-88 2356EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-UnquietGrave     05-29 0897</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Unquiet Grave,0930</SECOND>
<HEAD>Grave Of Sylvia Plath Unmarked In English Village</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By GRAHAM HEATHCOTE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>HEPTONSTALL, England (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 First her married name was chiseled off her tombstone three times. Later the stone vanished, and so did its replacement. Even in death, <PERSON> Sylvia </PERSON> <PERSON> Plath </PERSON> is not at peace. The admired American poet lies in an unmarked grave high in the <LOCATION> Yorkshire </LOCATION> hills, a bleak resting place for a tormented soul who killed herself when she was 30. Nobody knows who is tampering with her grave, but some suspect feminist activists of erasing `` Hughes'' from the stone in the belief that <PERSON> Plath </PERSON>'s marriage to British poet <PERSON> Ted </PERSON> <PERSON> Hughes </PERSON> contributed to her misery by turning her into a housewife. <PERSON> Plath </PERSON>'s reputation has grown since her suicide in 1963. `` The Bell Jar,'' her semi-autobiographical novel, has sold 200,000 copies in <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>. She posthumously won the 1982 Pulitzer Prize for her `` Collected Poems.'' Her grave in <LOCATION> Heptonstall </LOCATION>, a clutch of stone houses in the austere south <LOCATION> Pennine </LOCATION> <LOCATION> hills </LOCATION>, has become a place of pilgrimage. A little rosebush grows on it, and some modest wreaths and cut flowers lie about. Crows and magpies fly above. A large granite tombstone once stood on the grave, inscribed, `` In Memory. <PERSON> Sylvia </PERSON> <PERSON> Plath </PERSON> <PERSON> Hughes </PERSON>. 1932-1963.'' Below were two lines of poetry: `` Even amidst fierce flames The golden lotus can be planted.'' They were written by <PERSON> Hughes </PERSON>, now <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s Poet Laureate. He was estranged from his wife she gassed herself in their <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> apartment Feb. 11, 1963. In February of last year, residents say two women were seen picking the lead letters of the <PERSON> Hughes </PERSON> name off the tombstone. They said the name had been removed twice before. The stone then disappeared. `` We get visitors from all over the world to see the grave, and they come in to say they ca n't find it. It seems a shame,'' said <PERSON> Judith </PERSON> <PERSON> Parish </PERSON>, who runs the newspaper shop. `` I think feminists interfered with the inscription because they object to the addition of <PERSON> Hughes </PERSON>' name to <PERSON> Sylvia </PERSON>'s,'' said <PERSON> Elaine </PERSON> <PERSON> Connell </PERSON>, a local teacher. `` Some people think <PERSON> Hughes </PERSON> was somehow to blame in his wife's death because he left her to cope with the children,'' Miss <PERSON> Connell </PERSON> said She said a local newspaper had reported the tombstone was removed for restoration. `` But that was hardly true as only the one name had been picked off, and the tombstone was never returned,'' she said. The question of feminist involvement was raised again after the publication this year of `` <PERSON> Sylvia </PERSON> <PERSON> Plath </PERSON>,'' a biography by <PERSON> Linda </PERSON> <PERSON> Wagner-Martin </PERSON>, professor of English at <ORGANIZATION> Michigan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Hughes </PERSON>, 57, was reportedly furious with <PERSON> Wagner-Martin </PERSON> for writing that he left his wife to do the housework and raise the couple's two children while he pursued his career. <PERSON> Hughes </PERSON> was recognized as a fine poet when he married <PERSON> Plath </PERSON> after they met in 1956 at <ORGANIZATION> Cambridge </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, and critics say his influence deepened his wife's poetic creativeness. The poet, who remarried 18 years ago, never talks to the media, and his sister <PERSON> Olwyn </PERSON>, who sometimes speaks for him, did not return phone calls. The Sunday Times of <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> reported in March that <PERSON> Hughes </PERSON> sent it a 15-page rebuttal of <PERSON> Wagner-Martin </PERSON>'s book after reading an early draft of it. <PERSON> Hughes </PERSON> conceded that <PERSON> Plath </PERSON> may have resented his `` comparative freedom'' but insisted that to suggest she was jealous of his poetic ability would be `` a major misjudgment of her character,'' the paper said. <PERSON> Wagner-Martin </PERSON> told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> that she felt <PERSON> Hughes </PERSON> was not sensitive enough to his wife's needs in the last months of their marriage. `` I saw her daily calendar of the things she had to do, like mowing, cooking and shopping, and there was no suggestion that <PERSON> Ted </PERSON> was going to help with them,'' the professor said. However, critic <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Kermode </PERSON>, reviewing the biography in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Sunday </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Telegraph </ORGANIZATION>, wrote: `` Surely the enemies she had to deal with were n't housewifely duties and the selfishness of men, but interior demons much more terrible.'' <PERSON> Plath </PERSON>'s best-known poems dealt with illness, suffering and death _ she had already survived a suicide attempt at age 20. She is buried near <PERSON> Hughes </PERSON>' parents outside the churchyard wall of <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Thomas </LOCATION> the Apostle. `` I was told that it took some pressure to get a tombstone and it was only put on her grave five or six years after the burial,'' <PERSON> Wagner-Martin </PERSON> said. `` I have no idea who interfered with the stone and the grave, but I am sure it is not the people of <LOCATION> Yorkshire </LOCATION>.'' Villager <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Eveleigh </PERSON>, 76, a retired engineer and admirer of <PERSON> Plath </PERSON>'s poetry, said he made a border of little stones around the grave when the tombstone disappeared. `` I also got larger stones and scratched or painted the name of <PERSON> Sylvia </PERSON> <PERSON> Plath </PERSON> on them so the grave could be identified by visitors, but those were taken away, eight times altogether,'' he said. <PERSON> Eveleigh </PERSON>'s wife <PERSON> Evelyn </PERSON> said she tried to discover who was responsible for the grave. `` I could n't find out, and it seemed the church authorities were being evasive,'' she said, adding: `` I presume it's up to <PERSON> Ted </PERSON> <PERSON> Hughes </PERSON>.'' The Rev. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Harrison </PERSON>, vicar of <LOCATION> Heptonstall </LOCATION>, confirmed that the <PERSON> Hughes </PERSON> family was responsible for the upkeep of the grave. `` The gravestone was removed last year because of vandalism. I have no idea if the stone is going to be replaced,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880529-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-29-88 2343EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Summit-FirstLadies 1stLd-Writethru a0792 05-29 1063</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Summit-First Ladies, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0792,1,000</SECOND>
<HEAD>Nancy and Raisa Reunited; Things Go Mostly Well</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: To CORRECT name of cathedral to Assumption sted Annunciation,
SUB 12th graf, ``The Soviet...''
^By SUSANNE M. SCHAFER</NOTE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MOSCOW (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and <PERSON> Raisa </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> toured <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION> churches Sunday, holding hands and dismissing their reported feuds as `` rumors,'' but when talk turned to religious activities, the Soviet first lady abruptly cut the conversation short. While President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and General Secretary <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> squared off over human rights inside the <ORGANIZATION> Kremlin </ORGANIZATION>'s Great Palace, the two women wore smiles and strolled hand-in-hand toward the cameras in an attempt to put to rest the stories about the tense relationship that emerged from their last meeting at the <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> summit. `` We've gotten along very well every other time,'' a smiling Mrs. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said in response to queries about the supposed frosty relationship. The Soviet first lady, true to the forthright style she displayed at the White House, chimed in at length and insisted that she considered such reports frivolous. `` Rumors have it, and there was a question, that there is some misunderstanding between myself and the -LRB- president's -RRB- wife,'' she replied through an interpreter. `` ... I would like to say, I think it's not serious.'' Mrs. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> said her contacts with Mrs. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> have been part of the on-going improvement in relations between the two superpowers. `` We do have a lot to talk about and we are going to have something to remember, which is very important. I welcome Mrs. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> here and the president to <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>,'' she said. At one point, Mrs. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> was asked whether former White House chief of staff <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> T. </PERSON> <PERSON> Regan </PERSON> incorrectly portrayed her in his book as having asked, after an extended dinner lecture from Mrs. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>, `` Who does that dame think she is?'' Mrs. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, with an icy stare, replied curtly, `` Yes.'' Even though the two women offered nearly constant smiles, the first lady did display a bit of the impatience she'd shown during the <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> summit as Mrs. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> maintained an extensive dialogue with the press corps. During a tour of the Kremlin's sun-splashed Cathedral Square and its ancient, golden-domed stone churches, the two first ladies were often shoulder-to-shoulder, pointing at the sights and talking through interpreters abot the fortress' collection of buildings that served as the residence, places of worship and tombs of the Czars. Mrs. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>, attired in a fitted, winter white wool suit and dark suede high heels, repeatedly patted the back of her neck to smooth her closely-cropped red hair. On her left shoulder, she wore a gold and green-stone firebird, a famous figure in Russian fairy tales. Mrs. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> wore a black-and-white checked Oscar de la Renta two-piece suit, complete with black patent heels and purse and white pique bowed blouse, all set off by a matching set of gold and black bracelets, sparling earrings and a large stone ring. The Soviet first lady quickly took charge of the tour as she put her arm about Mrs. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s waist and guided her about the inside the 14th century Cathedral of the Assumption, the largest and one of the oldest churches-turned muesums in the Kremlin. The vaulted stone church, crowned with five gilded domes, has 40-foot high walls covered with a rich collection of priceless paintings and icons that show scenes from the life of Christ and the <PERSON> Virgin </PERSON> <PERSON> Mary </PERSON>. It is the repository of the finest and most revered icons in <LOCATION> Russia </LOCATION>, some dating from the 12th century, brought to the church and restored. After they entered the Cathedral, Mrs. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> was asked about what she wanted to tell the <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> people about what the summit should produce. `` Peace and friendship and that they understand the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> people,'' she replied. Asked what else, the former university lecturer shot back, `` What do you mean, what else? That's the most important thing. `` Mrs. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, appearing a bit bewildered, was asked her impressions of the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> `` Wonderful, very exciting, it's a little overwhelming,'' she replied, eyes wide and blinking. At that point, Mrs. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> interrupted, insisting, `` Please, I beg you, allow us to see the cathedral.'' The Soviet first lady then guided Mrs. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> from reporters and launched into a lecture about the religious paintings that adorned the golden wall that divides the church sanctuary from its main hall. As they reached one icon depicting a sorrowful Virgin and the infant <PERSON> Jesus </PERSON> touching the mother's cheek, Mrs. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> remarked that it was one of the most beloved images in the nation. `` Very, very, very maternal,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> remarked. Mrs. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> then turned from Mrs. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> and towards the interpreter, asking, `` Now let me finish,'' and she queried whether the cathedral was used mainly as a museum or for religious activities. `` Nyet,'' responded Mrs. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>, to which the first lady quickly replied, `` Oh, yes, nyet, the word ` nyet,' that I understand.'' Mrs. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> then added that there had been no religious observances in the Cathedral since 1918, but the interpreter apparently corrected the date to 1917. `` It has obviously a very religious feeling,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said, softly of the paintings. She then turned to Mrs. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> and asked if it were true that a concert was planned for the cathedral during next month's celebration of the millenium, the observance of the 1,000-year anniversary of the spread of <LOCATION> Christendom </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Russia </LOCATION>. `` Nyet,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> replied curtly, putting her arm around Mrs. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s waist, briskly guiding her out the door and jumping into a discussion of icons, frescoes, and wood carvings _ out of reporters' earshot. According to Mrs. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s press secretary, <PERSON> Elaine </PERSON> <PERSON> Crispen </PERSON>, the two women held hands again as they took a walk along the <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION> embankment that overlooks the <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION>. Spectators applauded the two women as they strolled about the cobblestone square, and they then retired to the <LOCATION> Great </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Palace </LOCATION>, where they had tea. Mrs. <PERSON> Crispen </PERSON> said the two discussed the supposed feud, and she quoted Mrs. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> as saying, `` All these rumors are trivial stories.'' Mrs. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> then replied, speaking of the media, `` Yes, but you ca n't get them to change their minds. I've told them so many times that the rumors are not true,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Crispen </PERSON> quoted her as saying. The two ladies agreed that what was important was their husbands' work and the change in relations between their two nations, Mrs. <PERSON> Crispen </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880529-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-29-88 2355EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-Holiday-Resort 1stLd-Writethru a0844 05-29 0362</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Holiday-Resort, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0844,0368</SECOND>
<HEAD>Search Continues for Three Missing in Fatal Boating Accident</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: LEADS with 5 grafs to UPDATE number of dead to two, search
suspended, missing presumed dead; picks up 5th graf: ``Most of .. .</NOTE>
<DATELINE>OCEAN CITY, Md. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A drowning, a missing swimmer, and a boating accident that killed two people, injured five and left two men missing and presumed dead marked this seaside resort's Memorial Day weekend. Searches continued until Sunday night for a missing 16-year-old boy who apparently was caught by undertow Saturday afternoon, and for two men still missing from the boating accident late Saturday night, authorities said. One woman was killed when an 19-foot boat carrying seven passengers plowed into an anchored, 25-foot boat with two aboard about a quarter-mile north of <LOCATION> Ocean </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, said <PERSON> Ralph </PERSON> <PERSON> Parker </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Maryland </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Natural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Resources </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION> spokesman. The seven were ejected into the water and none was wearing a lifejacket, authorities said. Searchers found the body of a second victim around 8 p.m. Sunday about 300 yards from the collision site, officers said. The two men still missing were presumed dead, officials said. `` Most of the injuries seem to be impact injuries,'' said Sgt. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Bloxom </PERSON> of the Natural Resources Police. `` And there's a possibility some of them might not have known how to swim. Authorities would give no further details other than that a 23-year-old <LOCATION> Baltimore </LOCATION> woman died at the scene and five people were taken to hospitals. The names of all nine people were withheld until relatives were notified. Authorities confiscated both boats, but issued no citations pending completion of the investigation. The 16-year-old <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> boy was reported missing Saturday afternoon after he and a friend went swimming and were caught in the undertow. The friend reached shore and alerted lifeguards. A search by <LOCATION> Ocean </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> police, the beach patrol, the <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> and a state police helicopter Saturday turned up no trace of the youth, whose name was not released. Around 8:30 a.m. Saturday, <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Hinkleman </PERSON>, 28, of <PERSON> Glen </PERSON> <PERSON> Burnie </PERSON>, apparently drowned in the surf, 90 minutes before lifeguards went on duty for the first time in the beach season, police said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880529-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-29-88 0004EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-B-52Rocket     05-29 0369</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-B-52 Rocket,0380</SECOND>
<HEAD>Pentagon Plans Experimental Rocket Program</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> plans to build an experimental rocket that would be dropped from a B-52 bomber and used to launch military satellites into space, a newspaper reported Sunday. The three-stage, winged rocket would be dropped about seven miles above the earth and then blast into space, placing payloads of up to 600 pounds into orbit, <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> reported, quoting government and industry experts. Officials have said they hope a prototype will fly next year. The <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> wants to test the rocket for a program designed to develop light-weight satellites and launchers for various military uses, including spy and communication satellites. The experimental rocket is being pursued by the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Advanced </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Projects </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION>, which develops futuristic projects for the Pentagon. There is concern on Capitol Hill that the rocket could be launched in secrecy, the Times reported. Although there is an agreement requiring space-faring countries to notify the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> of all payloads going into orbit, the rocket could be fired from remote parts of the world, far from Soviet trawlers and spy satellites that monitor military launchings from the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. The Pentagon has given no indication that it would violate the treaty obligation, but some military officials say privately that it would be useful for the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> to have the option of quick, secret launchings in the event of war. The Lightsat program, which includes the rocket, is part of a five-year, $ 240 million effort. On May 13, the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> signed a letter of contractual intent with <ORGANIZATION> Orbital </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sciences </ORGANIZATION> to buy one test rocket, with an option for five more, industry sources say. <ORGANIZATION> Orbital </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sciences </ORGANIZATION> would be joined by <ORGANIZATION> Hercules </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> , </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> which makes solid-fuel rockets. The three-stage, solid-fuel rocket would weigh 15 tons and measure 50 feet in length. Proponents say the air-launched rocket system would be inexpensive, less vulnerable to attack than ground-based spaceports and ideal for quickly launching small spy satellites to monitor fast-moving battles. <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Latham </PERSON>, a former assistant secretary of defense, said: `` The nation looked into air-launched rockets 20 years ago and found them wanting. There are better ways to make systems low cost and survivable.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880529-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-29-88 0332EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i BC-SummitRdp-1stLd-Writethru a0720   05-29 0913</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Summit Rdp-1st Ld-Writethru, a0720,880</SECOND>
<HEAD>Reagan Heading Toward Soviet Union</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDs: SUBS 5th graf, bgng, Reagan's chief ... etc., to UPDATE with
Baker's arrival; INSERTS new 6th graf; Picks up 6th graf pvs,
Reagan and Gorbachev xxx etc; Will be topped with Reagan departure,
scheduled for 4:30 a.m. EDT;</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By SUSANNE M. SCHAFER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>HELSINKI, Finland (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> becomes the first <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> leader in 14 years to step foot on Soviet soil Sunday, carrying the only superpower treaty to ban an entire class of nuclear weapons. But the summit was clouded by uncertainties that developed Saturday, when <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials said prospects had faded for signing three secondary arms agreements and the Soviets harshly criticized <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> aid to Afghan rebels. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and his wife <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> were scheduled to board Air Force One midmorning for a 90-minute flight to <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> and the president's fourth summit with Soviet leader <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> The couple planned to bid farewell to Finnish President <PERSON> Mauno </PERSON> <PERSON> Koivisto </PERSON> and his wife, Tellervo, at an airport ceremony. The <ORGANIZATION> Reagans </ORGANIZATION> spent three days in this Baltic capital recuperating from jet lag and preparing for their historic five-day visit to <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s chief of staff, <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> arrived in <LOCATION> Helsinki </LOCATION> on an overnight flight from <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, bringing with him the newly ratified Intermediate-Range Nuclear Forces treaty -LRB- INF -RRB-. <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> carried two bulging briefcases into the VIP lounge at the <LOCATION> Helsinki </LOCATION> airport, where he waited to link up with <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> for the flight to <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> will exchange ratification documents during a <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION> ceremony Wednesday morning. It is the first ratified superpower arms treaty in 16 years, the first major arms control agreement of the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration and the only treaty to ban an entire class of nuclear weapons. The exchange ceremony substitutes for the previously hoped-for signing of an agreement slashing by half the arsenals of strategic nuclear weapons _ the most powerful and dangerous in the superpower arsenals. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> was described Saturday by his national security adviser Lt. Gen. <PERSON> Colin </PERSON> <PERSON> Powell </PERSON> as `` well rested,'' and looking forward to his first session with the general secretary, scheduled withing an hour of the president's arrival. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> and his wife <PERSON> Raisa </PERSON> arranged to greet their <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> guests in the <ORGANIZATION> Kremlin </ORGANIZATION>'s 200-foot long St. <PERSON> George </PERSON>'s Hall, a gilded and marble reception room on the second floor of the former residence of the Czars. As the first ladies planned an afternoon tour of the fortress' collection of churches, apartments and bell towers, the two men were scheduled to meet over a table in the Hall of <PERSON> St. </PERSON> <PERSON> Catherine </PERSON> at the west end of the palace The <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> voted 93-5 on Friday to approve the INF treaty, signed by <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> at their <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> December summit. In a rare televised session, the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>'s collective presidency unanimously ratified the pact 17 hours later. A Soviet government spokesman described the action as `` a very good prelude'' to <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s visit. But in a pre-summit snag, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials revealed that chances had evaporated for signing an agreement on advance notification of ballistic missile tests by the superpowers. And they said two lesser arms-control measures may not be ready for signing during <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s talks with <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>. The agreements, while not major, would have given the leaders grounds to boast of progress on arms control issues _ particularly in view of the failure of the superpowers to conclude a treaty to curb strategic nuclear weapons. Aside from the arms agenda, officials said they did not expect `` announceable progress'' on differences on human rights and regional disputes. Asked by reporters in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> about problems with the secondary arms agreements, <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> said `` nothing will seriously detract'' from the importance of the summit meeting. Soviet officials, meanwhile, criticized the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> for its insistence on sending <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> aid to Afghan rebels after the withdrawal of <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> troops. And they hinted they might halt their withdrawal from <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> if neighboring <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> failed to stop aiding Afghan rebels. The <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> statement, carried by the <ORGANIZATION> Tass </ORGANIZATION> news agency and the evening news show Vremya, took aim at the `` lavish supplies of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> arms to <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>, intended specifically for the anti-government Afghan forces.'' The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has been supplying Afghan rebels with an estimated $ 500 million annually in arms and other military supplies channeled through <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>. It has pledged to continue to do so as long as the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> keeps up its military support of the Afghan government. Asked about the Soviet comments, <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> told reporters, `` The relationship between the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> is complex and spans many issues. A single summit or four summits, as we've had now, is n't going to solve them all at one time. The general relationship is better and I think prospects for general peace are improved.'' <PERSON> Gerald </PERSON> <PERSON> Ford </PERSON> was the last <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> president to visit the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, traveling to the port of <LOCATION> Vladivostock </LOCATION>, located on the Sea of <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, in 1974. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> met the same year in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> with the late <PERSON> Leonid </PERSON> <PERSON> Brezhnev </PERSON>. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, in an interview with Soviet television broadcast over the weekend throughout the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, said he could not have envisioned a trip to <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> under the Soviet leadership before <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>. `` Very frankly, I have to say I think there is a difference between this general secretary and other leaders of your country ... I do n't think they had any dreams of perestroika'' _ <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s program to restructure the nation's troubled economy.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880529-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-29-88 0812EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i BC-Summit-GorbachevStatement     05-29 0666</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Summit-Gorbachev Statement,660</SECOND>
<HEAD>Text of Gorbachev Speech Welcoming Reagan</HEAD>
<HEAD>With AM-Summit Rdp Bjt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MOSCOW (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here is the statement by Soviet Communist Party General Secretary <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> welcoming President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> to <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>: Esteemed Mr. <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, president of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, esteemed Mrs. <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, on behalf of the people and government of the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, I extend to you my sincere greetings on the occasion of your visit. Welcome. It is now almost six months since our meeting in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, which went down in history as a major milestone in Soviet-American and international relations. Now on this return trip, you, Mr. <PERSON> President </PERSON>, have traversed the great distance that lies between our two capitals to continue our dialogue. This is a fact we duly appreciate. As this is our fourth meeting, we can already make some meaningful assessments. As we see it, long-held dislikes have been weakened, habitual stereotypes stemming from enemy images have been shaken loose. The human features of the other nation are now more clearly visible. This in itself is important, for at the turn of the two millenniums history has objectively bound our two countries by a common responsibility for the destinies of mankind. The peoples of the world and, in the first place the Soviet and the <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> people, welcome the emerging, positive changes in our relationship and hope that your visit and talks here will be productive, providing a fresh impetus in all areas of dialogue and interaction between our two great nations. You and I are conscious of our two peoples' longing for mutual understanding, cooperation and a safe and stable world. This makes it incumbent on us to discuss constructively the main aspects of disarmament. The set of issues related to 50 percent cuts in strategic offensive arms while preserving the 1972 ABM treaty, problems of eliminating chemical weapons, reductions in armed forces and conventional armaments in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, cessation of nuclear testing. The world is also looking to us, Mr. <PERSON> President </PERSON>, for responsible judgments on other complex issues of today, such as the settlement of regional conflicts, improving international economic relations, promoting development, overcoming backwardness, poverty and mass diseases, and humanitarian problems. And of course we shall discuss bilateral relations. Our previous meetings have showed that constructive Soviet-U.S. relations are possible. The treaty on intermediate and shorter range missiles is the most impressive symbol of that. But even more important and complex problems lie ahead of that. And so, Mr. <PERSON> President </PERSON>, you and I still have a lot of work to do and it is good when there's a lot of work to be done and people need that work. We are ready to do our utmost in these coming days in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>. Mr. President, you and Mrs. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> are here on your first visit to the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, a country which you have so often mentioned in your statements. Aware of your interest in Russian proverbs, let me add another one to your collection: It is better to see once than to hear a hundred times. Let me assure you that you can look forward to hospitality, warmth and good will. You will have many meetings with Soviet people. They have a centuries-old history behind them. They love their land and take pride in their accomplishments. They resent things that are presently standing in their way and they are heatedly discussing how their country can best progress. They are full of plans for the future. Being ardent patriots, Soviet people are open to friendship and cooperation with all nations. They harbor sincere respect for the <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> people and want good relations with your country. Here within the walls of the ancient Kremlin, where one feels the touch of history, people are moved to reflect over the diversity and greatness of human civilization. So may this give greater historical depth to the Soviet-American talks to be held here, infusing them with a sense of mankind's shared destinies. Once again, I bid you welcome.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880529-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-29-88 0816EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i BC-Pope-Cardinals     05-29 0397</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Pope-Cardinals,0405</SECOND>
<HEAD>Pope Names 25 New Cardinals</HEAD>
<DATELINE>VATICAN CITY (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Pope <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> II </PERSON> named 25 new cardinals Sunday, including the archbishops of <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> and a prelate from <LOCATION> Lithuania </LOCATION>, the Roman Catholic stronghold of the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. The pope made the announcement at the end of a Mass in <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Peter </LOCATION>'s Basilica during which ordained 69 new priests from 25 countries. He said he would formally elevate the new cardinals at the <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION> on June 28. The new cardinals include Archbishops <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Hickey </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Edmund </PERSON> <PERSON> Casimir </PERSON> <PERSON> Szoka </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Hans </PERSON> <PERSON> Groer </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION>, and <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Baptist </PERSON> <PERSON> Wu </PERSON> <PERSON> Cheng-Chung </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION>. The new Lithuanian cardinal is <PERSON> Vincentas </PERSON> <PERSON> Sladkevicius </PERSON>, apostolic administrator of <LOCATION> Kaisiadorys </LOCATION>. Other new `` princes'' of the <ORGANIZATION> Roman </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> include Archbishops <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Gregoire </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Montreal </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>; <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Freire </PERSON> <PERSON> Falcao </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Brasilia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION>; <PERSON> Alexandre </PERSON> <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Maria </PERSON> <PERSON> dos </PERSON> <PERSON> Santos </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Maputo </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mozambique </LOCATION>; <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> <PERSON> Ignatius </PERSON> <PERSON> Pimenta </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Bombay </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>; <PERSON> Mario </PERSON> <PERSON> Revollo </PERSON> <PERSON> Bravo </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Bogota </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION>; <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Clancy </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Sydney </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION>; <PERSON> Lucas </PERSON> <PERSON> Moreira </PERSON> <PERSON> Neves </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Sao </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION> da <LOCATION> Bahia </LOCATION>, the primate of <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION>; and <PERSON> Laszlo </PERSON> <PERSON> Paskai </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Esztergom </LOCATION>, primate of <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>. The pope also named Archbishop <PERSON> Christian </PERSON> <PERSON> Tumi </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Garoua </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Cameroon </LOCATION>; <PERSON> Franz </PERSON> <PERSON> Hengsbach </PERSON> of bishop of <LOCATION> Essen </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>; <PERSON> Jean </PERSON> <PERSON> Margeot </PERSON>, bishop of <LOCATION> Port </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Louis </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mauritius </LOCATION>; <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON> <PERSON> Padiyara </PERSON>, archbishop of <LOCATION> Ernakulam </LOCATION> of the <PERSON> Siro </PERSON> <PERSON> Malabaresi </PERSON> rite in <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>; and Swiss theologian <PERSON> Hans </PERSON> <PERSON> Urs </PERSON> <PERSON> von </PERSON> <PERSON> Balthasar </PERSON>. The appointments bring membership to the college of cardinals to 161, of whom 120 are under the age of 80 and eligible to vote to elect a new pope. Pope <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> VI </PERSON> had ruled that only cardinals under 80 could participate in a conclave and he also limited their number to 120. In his announcement Sunday, the <PERSON> pope </PERSON> said he still will not reveal the name of a cardinal he chose `` in pectore'' _ in his heart _ in 1979. There has always been speculation the prelate came from a communist country. In all, the new cardinals come from 18 countries and include several Vatican-based officials. Among them are Archbishop <PERSON> Achille </PERSON> <PERSON> Silvestrini </PERSON>, who is equivalent to the <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION>'s foreign minister; Archbishop <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Maria </PERSON> <PERSON> Javierre </PERSON> <PERSON> Ortas </PERSON>, head of the <ORGANIZATION> Congregation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Education </ORGANIZATION>, and Archbishop <PERSON> Jacques </PERSON> <PERSON> Martin </PERSON>, prefect of the papal household. The session on June 28 will be the fourth held by <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> II </PERSON> since his election as pope in 1978. The last was in 1985.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880529-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-29-88 0833EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i BC-SummitRdp 7thLd-Writethru a0737 05-29 1214</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Summit Rdp, 7th Ld-Writethru, a0737,1,200</SECOND>
<HEAD>Gorbachev and Reagan Open Summit</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDs: SUBS 11th graf pvs, bgng, Speaking of xxx etc., to UPDATE
with Russian version of proverb Reagan used; INSERTS grafs 13-14
with material form photo session.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By SUSANNE M. SCHAFER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MOSCOW (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and Soviet leader <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> opened their historic summit Sunday with an exchange of Russian proverbs and a vow to continue the work begun 2 -LCB- years ago in <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION>. `` We both know it wo n't be easy,'' <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said. Not long after the <ORGANIZATION> Reagans </ORGANIZATION> arrived by motorcade from <LOCATION> Vnukovo </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION> outside <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>, they walked across a long red carpet to the center of a 200-foot-long chandaliered and gilded reception room in <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> George </LOCATION><LOCATION> 's </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hall </LOCATION>, where their paths crossed <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s and his wife's. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> and <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> reminisced briefly about earlier summits in <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Reykjavik </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Iceland </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, while their wives, <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and <PERSON> Raisa </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>, looked on in an inside-the-Kremlin scene broadcast live by Soviet television and seen by millions in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and around the world. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, who once called the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> an `` evil empire,'' had arrived on Soviet soil for the first time, under sunny skies, just after 2 p.m. local time. He was greeted there by Soviet President <PERSON> Andrei </PERSON> <PERSON> Gromyko </PERSON>, for years the foreign minister, and <PERSON> Gromyko </PERSON>'s wife, <PERSON> Lidia </PERSON>, who gave a bouquet of roses to Mrs. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>. Amid mixed expectations about the success of the five days of talks, coming in the wake of problems with secondary arms-control measures and new Soviet complaints of continuing <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> aid to Afghan rebels, <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> set a conciliatory tone, telling <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> that `` important tasks lie ahead.'' `` You and I are conscious of our two people's longing for mutual understanding, cooperation and a safe world,'' said <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>, speaking through an interpreter. `` This makes it incumbent upon us to discuss ... the major aspects of disarmament.'' <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> told his Soviet counterpart that U.S.-Soviet relations have improved since their first meeting, in <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> in November 1985, saying `` we have taken our work, step by step, and I have come here to continue that work.'' Inside the <ORGANIZATION> Kremlin </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> seemed to gently tweak <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> about the president's many speeches and jokes about life in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. `` Mr. President, you and Mrs. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> are here on your first visit to the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, a country which you have so often mentioned in your public statements ... Let me add another to your collection, ` It is better to see once than to hear a hundred times.''' <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> had his own proverb for <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>. Speaking of the gradual progress in superpower relations over recent years, and noting that differences remain, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, speaking first in Russian, told <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>: `` Rodilsya, ne toropilsya,'' or `` It was born. It was n't rushed.'' `` Mr. General Secretary, we did not rush. We have taken our work step by step, and I have come here to continue that work. We both know it will not be easy.'' Sitting down with <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> for a picture-taking session at the outset of their first meeting, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> was asked whether he intended to lecture the <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION> leader about human rights. `` I have no intention of trying to be a teacher,'' he replied. The <ORGANIZATION> Reagans </ORGANIZATION> spent three days in <LOCATION> Helsinki </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Finland </LOCATION>, recuperating from jet lag and preparing for their historic five-day visit to <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>. Reporters shouted questions as <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> posed briefly with <PERSON> Gromyko </PERSON> and other members of the arrival party here. `` We're getting along just fine,'' <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said. As reporters continued to yell questions, <PERSON> Gromyko </PERSON> turned to <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and said, `` They want to know in advance everything. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> then shook hands with a host of dignitaries, including <PERSON> Yuri </PERSON> <PERSON> Dubinin </PERSON>, currently the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> ambassador to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, and paused briefly while standing under the Soviet flag bearing the hammer and sickle. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> stood before march Soviet troops, swinging their legs in the traditional Russaian military goose-step fashion. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s chief of staff, <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> arrived in <LOCATION> Helsinki </LOCATION> on an overnight flight from <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, bringing with him the newly ratified Intermediate-Range Nuclear Forces treaty -LRB- INF -RRB-. <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> carried two bulging briefcases into the VIP lounge at the <LOCATION> Helsinki </LOCATION> airport, where he waited to link up with <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> for the flight to <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> will exchange ratification documents during a <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION> ceremony Wednesday morning. It is the first ratified superpower arms treaty in 16 years, the first major arms control agreement of the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration and the only treaty to ban an entire class of nuclear weapons. The exchange ceremony substitutes for the previously hoped-for signing of an agreement slashing by half the arsenals of strategic nuclear weapons _ the most powerful and dangerous in the superpower arsenals. The <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> voted 93-5 on Friday to approve the INF treaty, signed by <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> at their <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> December summit. In a rare televised session, the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>'s collective presidency unanimously ratified the pact 17 hours later. In a pre-summit snag, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials revealed that chances had evaporated for signing an agreement on advance notification of ballistic missile tests by the superpowers. And they said two lesser arms-control measures may not be ready for signing during <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s talks with <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>. The agreements, while not major, would have given the leaders grounds to boast of progress on arms control issues _ particularly in view of the failure of the superpowers to conclude a treaty to curb strategic nuclear weapons. Aside from the arms agenda, officials said they did not expect `` announceable progress'' on differences on human rights and regional disputes. Soviet officials, meanwhile, criticized the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> for its insistence on sending <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> aid to Afghan rebels after the withdrawal of <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> troops. And they hinted they might halt their withdrawal from <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> if neighboring <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> failed to stop aiding Afghan rebels. The <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> statement, carried by the <ORGANIZATION> Tass </ORGANIZATION> news agency and the evening news show Vremya, took aim at the `` lavish supplies of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> arms to <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>, intended specifically for the anti-government Afghan forces.'' The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has been supplying Afghan rebels with an estimated $ 500 million annually in arms and other military supplies channeled through <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>. It has pledged to continue to do so as long as the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> keeps up its military support of the Afghan government. Asked about the Soviet comments, <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> told reporters, `` The relationship between the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> is complex and spans many issues. A single summit or four summits, as we've had now, is n't going to solve them all at one time. The general relationship is better and I think prospects for general peace are improved.'' <PERSON> Gerald </PERSON> <PERSON> Ford </PERSON> was the last <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> president to visit the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, traveling to the port of <LOCATION> Vladivostock </LOCATION>, located on the Sea of <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, in 1974. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> met the same year in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> with the late <PERSON> Leonid </PERSON> <PERSON> Brezhnev </PERSON>. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, in an interview with Soviet television broadcast over the weekend throughout the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, said he could not have envisioned a trip to <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> under the Soviet leadership before <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>. `` Very frankly, I have to say I think there is a difference between this general secretary and other leaders of your country ... I do n't think they had any dreams of perestroika'' _ <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s program to restructure the nation's troubled economy.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880529-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-29-88 0834EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i BC-ReaganStatement     05-29 0678</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Reagan Statement,660</SECOND>
<HEAD>Text of Reagan Arrival Speech at Kremlin</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MOSCOW (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here is a transcript of President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s statement Sunday at the opening of his summit with Soviet leader <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> Mr. General Secretary, Mrs. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>. Mr. General Secretary, thank you for those kind words of welcome. We've traveled a long road together to reach this moment, from our first meeting in <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> in November 1985 when I invited you to visit me in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> and you invited me to visit <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>. It was cold that day in <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> and even colder in <LOCATION> Reykjavik </LOCATION> when we met the following year to work on the preparations for our exchange of visits. We faced great obstacles, but by the time of your visit to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> last December, although we still had to grapple with difficult issues, we had achieved impressive progress in all the areas of our common agenda, human rights, regional issues, arms reduction and our bilateral relations. We signed a treaty that will reduce the level of nuclear arms for the first time in history by eliminating an entire class of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and Soviet independent range missiles. We agreed on the main points of a treaty that will cut in half our arsenals of strategic offensive nuclear arms. We agreed to conduct a joint experiment that would allow us to develop effective ways to verify limits on nuclear testing. We held full and frank discussions and planted the seeds for future progress. It is almost summer and some of those seeds are beginning to bear fruit thanks to the hard work we have both done since our last meeting, including monthly meetings of our foreign ministers and the first meeting of our defense ministers. We have signed the <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> accords providing for the withdrawal of all Soviet troops from <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> and the first withdrawals have begun. We and our allies have completed technical arrangements necessary to begin implementing the INF treaty as soon as it enters into force. For the next major step in arms control, reductions in <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and Soviet strategic offense arsenals, our negotiators in <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> have produced hundreds of pages of joint draft treaty text, recording our areas of agreement as well as those issues still to be resolved. Our new nuclear risk reduction centers have begun their transmissions of routine notifications to reduce the risk of conflict. Our scientists are installing the equipment for our joint experiment to verify limits on nuclear testing. Our experts have held broad-ranging discussions on human rights and important steps have been taken in that area. We have greatly expanded our bilateral exchanges since we signed our agreement in 1985. I hope you'll agree with me that more of our young people need to participate in these exchanges, which can do so much to lay the basis for mutual understanding in the next generation. I could go on. The list of accomplishments goes far beyond what many anticipated. But I think the message is clear: Despite clear and fundamental differences and despite the frustrations that we have encountered, our work has begun to produce results. In the past, Mr. General Secretary, you've taken note of my liking for Russian proverbs. And so as not to disappoint anyone on this visit, I thought I would mention a literary saying from your past, another example of your peoples' succinct wisdom. `` Rodilsya, ne Toropilsya'' _ It was born, it was n't rushed. Mr. General Secretary, we did not rush. We have taken our work step by step, and I have come here to continue that work. We both know it will not be easy, we both know it will not be easy. We both know there are tremendous hurdles yet to be overcome. But we also know that it can be done because we share a common goal, strengthening the framework we have already begun to build for a relationship that we can sustain over the long term, a relationship that will bring genuine benefits to our own peoples and to the world. Thank you and God bless you.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880529-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-29-88 1132EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-RememberingMadam     05-29 0403</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Remembering Madam,0415</SECOND>
<HEAD>Brass Band to Pay Tribute to Pioneer Madam</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAN DAY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>OMAHA, Neb. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 After paying tribute to the nation's war dead in a traditional Memorial Day ceremony, a brass band will wend its way through a pioneer cemetery Monday to salute a 19th century madam called `` the hooker with the heart of gold.'' `` It's tongue-in-cheek,'' said ceremony chairman <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> McNichols </PERSON>. `` It's certainly not a part of the formal program.'' <ORGANIZATION> McNichols </ORGANIZATION>' mother for years brought a yellow rose to mark <PERSON> Anna </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON>'s grave as part of a tradition begun by those who had benefited from the madam's charitable donations. <ORGANIZATION> McNichols </ORGANIZATION> and several friends rekindled interest in the generous woman he calls a `` soiled dove.'' The Prospect Hill Preservation Brass Band has played in her memory each Memorial Day since 1980. The 25-piece band will visit Miss <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON>'s grave after the traditional Memorial Day observance at Prospect Hill Cemetery, which sits on a hill near the old <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Trail </LOCATION> where thousands of pioneers pushed their way west past <LOCATION> Omaha </LOCATION>. Miss <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> ran the city's highest-priced house of ill-repute for about 30 years. She retired from the business in the mid-1890s, investing her money in real estate. Miss <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> died in 1911, soon after giving her former house of prostitution to the city for use as a hospital. Her will left an estate valued at $ 1 million to be divided among the city, hospitals, a mission, children's charities and the cemetery. The madam-turned-philanthropist is buried among some of the leading citizens of her time _ judges, doctors, politicians, ministers and brewery barons. `` Everybody that was anybody is buried in that cemetery,'' said <PERSON> Louise </PERSON> <PERSON> Baumann </PERSON>, president of the cemetery foundation. Details are sparse on the early life of <PERSON> Miss </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON>, born the daughter of a Baptist minister in <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION> in 1835. She achieved notoriety soon after arriving in <LOCATION> Omaha </LOCATION> in 1867, the year <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION> became a state. `` The first territorial capitol was between <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON> and <LOCATION> Farnam </LOCATION> on Ninth Street, and <PERSON> Anna </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON>'s establishment was right around the corner from it,'' <ORGANIZATION> McNichols </ORGANIZATION> said. Miss <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> met riverboat gambler <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Allen </PERSON> in 1871. They lived together, unmarried, until he died 1884, and they are buried side-by-side under a large stone slab. The <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> house of prostitution was one of several in the city's old red-light district, a few blocks from the <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> adjacent to what is now downtown <LOCATION> Omaha </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880529-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-29-88 1140EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Summit-USMedia     05-29 0709</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Summit-US Media,720</SECOND>
<HEAD>U.S. Invades Moscow _ TV Style</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOAN MOWER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MOSCOW (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 It's 2 a.m. in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Jennings </PERSON> ought to be asleep, but he is n't. He's taping the evening news for <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>. In daylight hours, <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s <PERSON> Pierre </PERSON> <PERSON> Salinger </PERSON> wanders around the Hotel Rossiya with shirttail out; <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>'s <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Kuralt </PERSON> dashes upstairs to file a story; columnist <PERSON> Roland </PERSON> <PERSON> Evans </PERSON> looks despairingly for the <ORGANIZATION> CNN </ORGANIZATION> studio so he can interview Soviet spokesman <PERSON> Gennady </PERSON> <PERSON> Gerasimov </PERSON>. And the gofers _ go for this, go for that _ are everywhere. Like invading armies, the television networks have moved in, bringing an entourage of hundreds and a mountain of high-technology. Their beachhead is the Hotel Rossiya overlooking Red Square and the Kremlin. And the toughest negotiations of the summit may have preceded President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s arrival here Sunday. The networks convinced Soviet authorities to improve the lighting of Red Square for a backdrop on the evening newscasts. Virtually every big-name network personality is vying for summit air time. <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>'s <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Rather </PERSON> wants to put the summit in the context of changes under way in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>; <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s <PERSON> Jennings </PERSON> did some man-on-the-street interviews; <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Brokaw </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> has the only terrace anchor station, and <ORGANIZATION> CNN </ORGANIZATION> is the only network shown in Soviet hotels. The networks have brought their own satellite dishes, microwave transmissions, walkie-talkies, telephones, electrical generators, copying machines, Fax machines _ and, in some cases, shipped in their food. `` Be Careful _ Radio Radiation,'' reads a sign in front of three giant satellite dishes outside the Rossiya. <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> offered to provide its staff with smoke alarms at the <ORGANIZATION> Rossiya </ORGANIZATION>, a 3,000-room hotel where more than 30 people were killed in a fatal fire in 1977. It even has a daily newsletter for its people, entitled `` <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> Newsletter.'' Uniformed Soviet officials pace up and down the Rossiya's halls, where rooms are packed with televisions, monitors and other gear. On the fifth floor, the networks built outdoor booths so reporters can conduct interviews with the <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION> wall and St. Basil's Cathedral as a backdrop <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> said it plans to broadcast its Nightly News live, while <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> plan something called `` tape live,'' which provides a slight delay. That's the middle of the night <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> time. Thus the lighting of St. Basil's took on added import for the networks. They entered into negotiations with the <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> city officials and <PERSON> Gostelradio </PERSON>, the Soviet broadcast network, and the lighting crisis was resolved satisfactorily, said <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Lord </PERSON>, executive director at <ORGANIZATION> ABC-TV </ORGANIZATION>. Each network has about 100 people in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>, including Russian-speaking <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> students who have been recruited to serve as everything from office gofers to interpreters. But for all the trouble and expense, network executives say serious summit scoops may be difficult to come by in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, where bureaucrats and officials are n't as sensitive to the demands of television. `` They are less responsive in terms of time,'' said <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Angotti </PERSON>, an <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> executive producer. Added <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> executive producer Lane Vernardos: `` When in <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION>, do as the Romans do does not work for television.'' With their own technology, television is able to transmit directly to a satellite, and then back to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. `` We are independent of the Soviets,'' <PERSON> Lord </PERSON> said. But while the American broadcasters, along with their European and Japanese counterparts, have tried to stay clear of the Soviets, network executives say the people at <LOCATION> Gostelradio </LOCATION> have given them unprecedented leeway. `` They really want to cooperate and they are trying to be flexible,'' said <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s <PERSON> Angotti </PERSON>. Television reporters say the Soviets essentially have kept to their pre-summit pledge that journalists `` can talk to anybody they wish.'' They've interviewed dissidents, took trips outside <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> by train and talked with students at <ORGANIZATION> Moscow </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. `` People are more willing to talk about more than they have been before,'' Rather said. No one wants to say how much money they're spending on the summit, but <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Bettag </PERSON>, a CBS producer for the nightly news, thinks it's going to be worth it. `` We've made a heavy commitment because other news is likely to be slight,'' he said. `` Congress is on the Memorial Day vacation, and there is a hole before the primaries so it will be extremely quiet back home.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880529-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-29-88 1141EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Vietnam-Cambodia     05-29 0366</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Vietnam-Cambodia,0379</SECOND>
<HEAD>Khmer Rouge Denounce Vietnamese Withdrawal from Cambodia</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BANGKOK, Thailand (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION> guerrillas denounced as `` stinking and deceitful'' an announcement by <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> that it would pull 50,000 troops from <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION> this year, according to a broadcast made available Sunday. A communique released Saturday by the <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION> military command said <LOCATION> Hanoi </LOCATION> actually was shifting its troops around <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION> in a frantic attempt to counter escalating guerrilla attacks. <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>, which invaded <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION> in late 1978, is fighting a coalition of three resistance groups including the communist <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION>. On Thursday, it announced a partial pullout of 50,000 troops to be followed by a total withdrawal in 1990. <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> says it has made annual withdrawals since 1982, but the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> says the only genuine pullout was in November, when 20,000 troops were withdrawn. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> estimates <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> still has 120,000 to 125,000 troops in <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION> and says the other troop movements were only rotations. <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> and the pro-Hanoi regime in <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION> said better security in the country made possible the Vietnamese reduction scheduled to begin next month. But the <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION> communique, broadcast over the clandestine <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION> radio, said <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> this month has been `` moving troops back and forth from one battlefield to another aimlessly like a frightened monkey'' to withstand guerrilla strikes. It called the claim `` stinking and deceitful.'' `` There is no sign that the Vietnamese enemy is preparing to withdraw 50,000 troops from <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION>,'' the communique said. `` This is more shameless propaganda to deceive world public opinion.'' The communique cited details of what it claimed to be Vietnamese troop movements in recent months. Western analysts regard <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION> claims with suspicion and most are not verified by independent sources. On Saturday, <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> also said the Vietnamese claims of troop withdrawal were deceptive. The <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION> is the most powerful of three rebel groups in a coalition led by Prince <PERSON> Norodom </PERSON> <PERSON> Sihanouk </PERSON>. Announcements of the Vietnamese withdrawal have sparked some fears that the <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION> could return to power. The <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION> ruled <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION> from 1975 until the Vietnamese invasion. Millions of Cambodians were killed or died of starvation or disease in the regime's attempt to impose radical agrarian communism.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880529-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-29-88 1141EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-SriLanka     05-29 0381</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Sri Lanka,0394</SECOND>
<HEAD>Six Dead in Assassination Attempt; Three Indian Soldiers Slain In
Ambush</HEAD>
<DATELINE>COLOMBO, Sri Lanka (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Sinhalese extremists opened fire with automatic rifles at the home of a politician and killed six people, including the politician's 10-year-old daughter, police said Sunday. In northern <LOCATION> Sri </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lanka </LOCATION>, Tamil rebels ambushed a convoy of Indian troops and killed at least three soldiers, residents said. The politician, K.W.R. <PERSON> Dharmasena </PERSON>, his wife and three supporters were injured in the assassination attempt late Saturday night, said a police officer, who spoke on condition of anonymity in accordance with police regulations. He said the dead included <PERSON> Dharmasena </PERSON>'s daughter and his father. The other victims, all men, were relatives of <LOCATION> Dharmasena </LOCATION>, he said. The attack occurred in the town of <LOCATION> Homagama </LOCATION>, 12 miles southeast of <LOCATION> Colombo </LOCATION>. Earlier Saturday, an opposition party candidate and two of his supporters were shot to death by suspected Sinhalese nationalists in the town of <LOCATION> Natala </LOCATION>, 65 miles northeast of <LOCATION> Colombo </LOCATION>. They were the latest in a series of attacks blamed on the <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION>, an underground group of nationalist Sinhalese opposed to an accord signed last July to end violence by Tamil separatists. The Tamil ambush in the northern district of <LOCATION> Vavuniya </LOCATION> killed three soldiers and wounded at least five other Indian troops, said residents who spoke on condition of anonymity. They did not know of any rebel casualties. There was no comment from the Indian government. At least 50,000 Indian soldiers have been deployed in <LOCATION> Sri </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lanka </LOCATION> to disarm Tamil rebels who renounced the peace accord. <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>, which as a large Tamil population of its own, sponsored the accord. The plan calls for Tamils to lay down their arms in exchange for the creation of district councils. Sinhalese extremists contend the pact makes too many concessions to the Tamils, who are fighting for a separate homeland. <PERSON> Dharmasena </PERSON> is a candidate from the governing <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> for elections scheduled next Thursday. At least 19 candidates have been killed by the Sinhalese front in the past two months, and there have been 12 assassination attempts on candidates. Tamils, who are mostly Hindus, make up 18 percent of <LOCATION> Sri </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lanka </LOCATION>'s 16 million population They claim they are discriminated against by the majority <PERSON> Sinhalese </PERSON> <PERSON> Buddhists </PERSON>, who control the government and military.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880529-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-29-88 1143EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Greece-Explosion     05-29 0179</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Greece-Explosion,0186</SECOND>
<HEAD>Explosion Rips Through Mosque in Northern Greece</HEAD>
<DATELINE>KOMOTINI, Greece (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A bomb exploded in a Moslem mosque in this northern town early Sunday, damaging its interior and shattering windows of neighboring buildings. Police said no one was injured. Police said a gasoline bomb was tossed into another mosque in the area 15 minutes later, sparking a fire that was immediately extinguished. No group immediately claimed responsibility for the attacks. A police official, who spoke on condition of anonymity, said the bomb was placed at the mosque's entrance. About half of <LOCATION> Komotini </LOCATION>'s 35,000 residents are Moslems. The town in the province of <LOCATION> Thrace </LOCATION> is about 35 miles west of the Turkish border. The attacks came two days after political cooperation talks ended in <LOCATION> Athens </LOCATION> between senior <LOCATION> Greek </LOCATION> officials and a <LOCATION> Turkish </LOCATION> delegation led by Foreign Minister <PERSON> Mesut </PERSON> <PERSON> Yilmaz </PERSON>. Relations between the two countries have improved since premiers <PERSON> Andreas </PERSON> <PERSON> Papandreou </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Greece </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Turgut </PERSON> <PERSON> Ozal </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Turkey </LOCATION> met in <LOCATION> Davos </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Switzerland </LOCATION>, in January. Another meeting between the two leaders is scheduled in the Greek capital June 13.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880529-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-29-88 1144EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Bangladesh-Floods     05-29 0267</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Bangladesh-Floods,0276</SECOND>
<HEAD>Five Dead, Thousands Displaced by Flooding</HEAD>
<DATELINE>DHAKA, Bangladesh (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 At least five people have died and thousands have been forced to flee their homes because of flooding in <LOCATION> Bangladesh </LOCATION>'s northeastern districts, government officials and news reports said Sunday. Last summer, more than one-quarter of the nation's 105 million people were forced to flee the worst flooding in 70 years. This year, heavy rains and the annual snow melt from the <LOCATION> Himalaya </LOCATION> mountains have sent the <PERSON> Surma </PERSON> and <LOCATION> Kushiara </LOCATION> rivers in the northeastern districts of <LOCATION> Sylhet </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Sunamganj </LOCATION> over their banks. Government officials in <LOCATION> Sylhet </LOCATION>, 100 miles northeast of <LOCATION> Dhaka </LOCATION>, said Sunday that three people died when their house was washed away and that two others drowned. The officials, who spoke on condition of anonymity, said at least 30,000 people have been marooned. Thousands of others made their way to relief camps and were being aided by local <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION> officers and government agencies. The government-owned Bengalai-language <ORGANIZATION> Dainik </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bangla </ORGANIZATION> newspaper said at least 500,000 people had been driven from their homes during the past week of rain and flooding. Thousands of acres of tea plantations and rice paddies were reported inundated. <PERSON> Rice </PERSON> is a staple food in <LOCATION> Bangladesh </LOCATION>. Some market towns in <LOCATION> Sunamganj </LOCATION> <LOCATION> District </LOCATION> were reported under two feet of water. Schools in both districts have been closed, and some have been converted to relief centers for the homeless, the officials said. The government officials said flights were disrupted at the airport at <LOCATION> Sylhet </LOCATION> on Saturday. Last year, two months of serious flooding killed about 1,500 people and destroyed thousands of acres of crops.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880529-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-29-88 1150EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-AfghanParliament     05-29 0561</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Afghan Parliament,0578</SECOND>
<HEAD>Najib Convenes Parliament, Calls For Guerrilla Cease-Fire</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Najib cq as one name</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By EARLEEN FISHER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>KABUL, Afghanistan (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
