<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880614-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-14-88 2332EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Wallach     06-14 0399</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Wallach,0411</SECOND>
<HEAD>Meese's Friend Says He Rejected Leniency Offer</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SAN FRANCISCO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Wallach </PERSON> says he refused to testify against his longtime friend, Attorney General <PERSON> Edwin </PERSON> <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>, in exchange for a government offer of leniency in the <ORGANIZATION> Wedtech </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> influence peddling case. <PERSON> Wallach </PERSON>, 54, made the statement in an interview broadcast Tuesday night on <ORGANIZATION> KRON-TV </ORGANIZATION>, an <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> affiliate. <PERSON> KRON </PERSON> said the interview was recorded earlier and that further portions would be broadcast on a Wednesday night news program. The <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> trial lawyer called <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> `` an honorable man'' and said there `` is nothing to talk about'' with prosecutors investigating allegations that <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> improperly used his influence on <PERSON> Wallach </PERSON>'s behalf in a proposed Iraqi pipeline deal. <PERSON> Wallach </PERSON>, who has known <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> since law school, made the statement about leniency when asked if prosecutors had approached his lawyers to work out a deal. `` Yes, they did,'' <PERSON> Wallach </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Wallach </PERSON> told <ORGANIZATION> KRON </ORGANIZATION> he learned he was about to be indicted on Dec. 22, when <PERSON> Baruch </PERSON> <PERSON> Weiss </PERSON>, an assistant <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> attorney for the <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION>, contacted <PERSON> Wallach </PERSON>'s lawyer. `` -LRB- <PERSON> Weiss </PERSON> -RRB- notified my then-counsel that they had to give up the arrangements they had entered into with him for a series of meetings to discuss possible allegations against me,'' <PERSON> Wallach </PERSON> said. Instead, <PERSON> Wallach </PERSON> added, <PERSON> Weiss </PERSON> presented his lawyer with a draft of the indictment. `` -LRB- He -RRB- gave me three days in which to plead guilty and cooperate _ and then said if, in fact, I would give it some thought, perhaps they would n't indict me on a racketeering charge,'' <PERSON> Wallach </PERSON> said. The station said <PERSON> Weiss </PERSON> replied, `` I can not comment on that'' when asked if <PERSON> Wallach </PERSON> had been offered leniency in exchange for testimony against the attorney general. <PERSON> Wallach </PERSON> said he was an unpaid adviser to <ORGANIZATION> Wedtech </ORGANIZATION>, a Bronx-based, minority-owned defense contractor. He is under indictment on federal racketeering charges for allegedly taking payoffs from <ORGANIZATION> Wedtech </ORGANIZATION> officials to influence <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> and other public officials. Former <ORGANIZATION> Wedtech </ORGANIZATION> officials have testified they paid $ 800,000 to <PERSON> Wallach </PERSON> to influence <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>. They have said <PERSON> Wallach </PERSON> told them he got the attorney general to intercede on the company's behalf for a series of contracts worth $ 143 million. <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> has denied any wrongdoing. <PERSON> Wallach </PERSON> told <ORGANIZATION> KRON </ORGANIZATION> he expects to be acquitted of the racketeering charges and said the indictment `` appears to be very contrived and very contorted and extremely difficult to find a crime within it.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880614-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-14-88 2334EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-DefenseProbe-List 3rdLd-Writethru a0835 06-14 0343</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Defense Probe-List, 3rd Ld-Writethru, a0835,330</SECOND>
<NOTE>EDs: SUBS 25th graf pvs bgng, `Norden, Black' to include street
name change</NOTE>
<HEAD>With AM-Defense Probe</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> confirmed Tuesday that search warrants have been served on the following individuals and companies. The bureau gave the following locations for the searches, which were part of a massive investigation of alleged defense procurement fraud: _ <PERSON> Victor </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Cohen </PERSON>, separate warrants at his Pentagon office and at a location in <LOCATION> Potomac </LOCATION>, Md _ <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Technologies </ORGANIZATION>, 1825 I St <ORGANIZATION> N.W. </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION> _ <ORGANIZATION> Loral </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Ridge </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rd. </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Yonkers </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION> _ <ORGANIZATION> Loral </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, 1210 <LOCATION> Massillon </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rd. </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Akron </LOCATION>, _ <ORGANIZATION> Unisys </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Marcus </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ave. </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Great </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Neck </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION> _ <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Gardner </PERSON>, a former vice president of <ORGANIZATION> Unisys </ORGANIZATION>, 50 <ORGANIZATION> Roosevelt </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Malverne </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION> _ <ORGANIZATION> Teledyne </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Electronics </ORGANIZATION>, 649 <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> <PERSON> Dr. </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Newbury </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Park </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION> _ <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Muldoon </PERSON>, 2310 <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ave. </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION> _ <ORGANIZATION> Litton </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Data </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Systems </ORGANIZATION>, 8000 <LOCATION> Woodley </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Blvd. </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Van </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Nuys </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION> _ Cubic, 9233 <LOCATION> Balboa </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Diego </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION> _ <ORGANIZATION> Executive </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associates </ORGANIZATION>, 2011 <LOCATION> Crystal </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ave. </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Arlington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION> _ <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Parkin </PERSON>, 1120 <PERSON> N. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gaillard </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Alexandria </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION> _ <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Sanda </PERSON> _ <ORGANIZATION> Northrop </ORGANIZATION>, 1515 <ORGANIZATION> Rancho </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conejo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Blvd. </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Newbury </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Park </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION> _ <ORGANIZATION> Unisys </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Eagan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Minn. </LOCATION> _ Wittaker, 1, <LOCATION> Farmington </LOCATION>, Ark. _ <PERSON> Norden </PERSON>, 101 <LOCATION> Merritt </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Blvd. </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Trumbull </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Conn. </LOCATION> _ <ORGANIZATION> McDonnell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Douglas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Banshee </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rd. </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Louis </LOCATION>, _ <ORGANIZATION> Hazeltine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, 1235 <PERSON> Jefferson </PERSON> <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> <PERSON> Hwy </PERSON>., <LOCATION> Arlington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION> _ <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Sherman </PERSON>, 1300 <LOCATION> Wilson </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Blvd. </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Rosslyn </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION> _ <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Stone </PERSON>, 2511 <LOCATION> Jefferson </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hwy </LOCATION>., <LOCATION> Arlington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION> _ <LOCATION> Stuart </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION>, 2511 <LOCATION> Jefferson </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hwy </LOCATION>., <LOCATION> Arlington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION> _ <PERSON> Norden </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Norden </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Place </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Norwalk </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Conn. </LOCATION> _ <LOCATION> Norden </LOCATION> The name of this section of the turnpike has been changed to <LOCATION> Canfield </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Avenue </LOCATION>. _ <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Galvin </PERSON>, 600 <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ave. </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION> _ <PERSON> Ken </PERSON> <PERSON> Brooke </PERSON>, 1945 <LOCATION> Old </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gallows </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rd. </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION> _ <ORGANIZATION> Varian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associates-Continental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Electronics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Manufacturing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, 4212 <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Buckner </PERSON> <PERSON> Blvd. </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION> _ <PERSON> Marcus </PERSON> <PERSON> Saunders </PERSON>, 5937 <ORGANIZATION> Woodfield </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Estates </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dr. </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Alexandria </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION> _ <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> Lackner </PERSON>, 6124 <LOCATION> Ellenview </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ave. </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Woodland </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hills </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION> _ <ORGANIZATION> Hazeltine </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rd. </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Greenlawn </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION> _ <PERSON> Melvyn </PERSON> <PERSON> Paisley </PERSON>, separate warrants at two locations, 600 <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ave. </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION>, and 6516 <LOCATION> Ridge </LOCATION> <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> McLean </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION> _ <ORGANIZATION> Armtec </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, 410 Highway 19 <LOCATION> South </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Palatka </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION> _ <ORGANIZATION> Zubier </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Enterprises </ORGANIZATION>, 6201 <LOCATION> Pine </LOCATION> <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Harrisburg </LOCATION>,
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880614-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-14-88 2344EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AMBritain-Amnesty     06-14 0189</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM Britain-Amnesty,0193</SECOND>
<HEAD>Amnesty says 85 U.N. members violate human rights charter</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Amnesty </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> said Wednesday that 85 of the 159 members of the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> violate the organization's <ORGANIZATION> Universal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Declaration </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Human </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rights </ORGANIZATION> In a report covering the first four months of 1988, London-based <ORGANIZATION> Amnesty </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> said it had identified 3,352 individual cases of people jailed for the non-violent excercise of their rights as defined by the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> document. The declaration, adopted by the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION> in 1948, calls for civil, political, economic, social, and cultural rights for all people. <ORGANIZATION> Amnesty </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> reported it had issued 115 appeals since Jan. 1 to 45 countries involving more than 450 prisoners who the human rights organization said it considers at risk of violations of their rights including torture and death. The report said <ORGANIZATION> Amnesty </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> sent 18 missions to 15 countries from January-April and issued 98 documents on human rights violations. `` None of these reports or initiatives should have been necessary,'' it said. `` In the 40th anniversary of the <ORGANIZATION> Universal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Declaration </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Human </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rights </ORGANIZATION>, such abuses should have become only a ghost from the past.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880614-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-14-88 0038EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-China-TaiwanTrade     06-14 0727</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-China-Taiwan Trade,0748</SECOND>
<HEAD>Taiwan Businessmen Quietly Setting Up Shop In Old Homeland</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By JIM ABRAMS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>FUZHOU, China (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The ancestral home of millions of people on <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION> is here in <LOCATION> Fujian </LOCATION> province on the Chinese mainland, and local officials are trying to lure Taiwanese businessmen back. They have even enlisted the aid of a Chinese sea goddess. <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Fujian </LOCATION> are separated by 100 miles of water in the <LOCATION> Formosa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strait </LOCATION> and 40 years of hostility between the Communist mainland and Nationalist <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION>. Some businessmen have come to <LOCATION> Fujian </LOCATION>, nevertheless, even at the risk of prosecution at home. Deputy Gov. You <PERSON> Dexin </PERSON> told visiting foreign reporters that 50 <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION> firms have defied their government's ban on trade contacts with the mainland to invest about $ 50 million in the province. The actual number may be much higher. Most Taiwanese avoid trouble at home by contracting under the names of <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> agents or relatives on the mainland. Taiwan-Fujian trade, which totalled $ 40 million last year, reached $ 20 million in the first four months of 1988, You said. Most goes through middlemen in <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION>, although more than 10 percent is done out on the <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strait </LOCATION>. Overall, indirect trade between <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION> and the entire Chinese mainland was an estimated $ 1.5 billion last year. <LOCATION> Fujian </LOCATION> officials said among the ideas for bringing in more <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION> money are plans to turn three offshore islands into economic zones for <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION> investors. One is <LOCATION> Meizhou </LOCATION>, home of the 10th century legendary figure <PERSON> Mazu </PERSON> who is worshipped on both sides of the strait as a protrectress for seafarers. For businessmen braving the still stormy waters of the strait, <LOCATION> Mazu </LOCATION> could provide welcome shelter. <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION> has been estranged from the mainland since the Nationalists lost a civil war to the Communists in 1949 and fled to the island. <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, which regards <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION> as a renegade province, encourages direct trade and communications links as a first step toward reunification. In the past, <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION> adamantly refused all contacts with the mainland, but it began in October to allow people to visit relatives in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>. In the first six months after travel restrictions were lifted, 65,000 Taiwanese came to <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, many to <LOCATION> Fujian </LOCATION>, where about 80 percent of <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION>'s 19.6 million people have their roots. <LOCATION> Fujian </LOCATION> officials say it is inevitable that <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION>, with its currency appreciating against the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> dollar and its wage costs rising, will move factories to <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, where labor is much cheaper and where language and customs are the same. `` They can make money here,'' said Chen He, magistrate of a township in the provincial capital of <LOCATION> Fuzhou </LOCATION>, which is building a $ 2.4-million sports equipment factory with a Taiwanese businessman. `` This is their homeland and they love it.'' During a recent press tour of the province, people frequently talked of contacts with <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION> enterprises. <PERSON> Hong </PERSON> <PERSON> Ziwei </PERSON>, a 29-year-old toy manufacturer in <LOCATION> Shishi </LOCATION>, said he would meet a <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION> businessman in August to discuss a joint venture to export toys. The Taiwanese man, he said, had written a letter to a local relative asking for help in finding a mainland partner. In <LOCATION> Quanzhou </LOCATION>, Mayor <PERSON> Chen </PERSON> <PERSON> Rongchun </PERSON> said sweet potatoes, a favorite among millions of Taiwanese with roots in <LOCATION> Fujian </LOCATION>, could be a big seller on <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION>. `` <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION> compatriots will cherish an intimate kind of emotion for goods coming from this place,'' he said. Much of the Taiwanese investment goes to <LOCATION> Xiamen </LOCATION>, a southern <LOCATION> Fujian </LOCATION> port that is one of the nation's four designated special economic zones with greater authority to attract foreign investment. <LOCATION> Xiamen </LOCATION>'s authorities said 39 projects with anticipated Taiwanese investment worth $ 42 million have been approved in such fields as jewelry, shoes, bicycle parts and aluminum window frames. While emphasizing that <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION> is part of <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, mainland officials say Taiwanese are given the same preferential treatment as foreign investors, or better. In <LOCATION> Xiamen </LOCATION>, for example, Taiwanese-funded joint ventures receive a four-year tax holiday, rather than the three years given foreign enterprises. Two Taiwanese business executives in May were given five-year prison terms by a <LOCATION> Taipei </LOCATION> court for business dealings on the mainland. Because of that <LOCATION> Fujian </LOCATION> officials promise to keep secret the details of all Taiwanese transactions. `` The first question we take into consideration is their personal security,'' Deputy Gov. You said. `` We take measures to keep their names secret.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880614-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-14-88 0040EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-CancerPrizes     06-14 0262</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Cancer Prizes,0271</SECOND>
<HEAD>Four Win Cancer Research Prizes</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Four scientists will share three $ 130,000 prizes for their work into breast cancer screening, the genetics of cancer and a substance that helps cells communicate. The <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Motors </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cancer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Prizes </ORGANIZATION> will be presented Wednesday at the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sciences </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION>, the foundation said. Each prize includes $ 100,000 plus $ 30,000 to cover expenses for a scientific conference or workshop. <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> <PERSON> Shapiro </PERSON>, professor emeritus of health policy and management at the <ORGANIZATION> Johns </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hopkins </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hygiene </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Baltimore </LOCATION>, will share one award with <PERSON> Philip </PERSON> <PERSON> Strax </PERSON>, clinical professor of oncology and radiology at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Miami </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medicine </ORGANIZATION>. They will be honored for conducting a massive study demonstrating that using mammography, or breast X-rays, to detect breast cancer in its early stages can save lives. <PERSON> Alfred </PERSON> <PERSON> Knudson </PERSON>, senior member of the <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cancer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> at the <ORGANIZATION> Fox </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chase </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cancer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION>, will be honored for proposing a theory of `` anti-cancer'' genes. Damage to these genes can lead to cancer. Evidence for such genes has been found in some rare tumors and in cancers of the breast, colon, and lung. The third prize will go to <PERSON> Yasutomi </PERSON> <PERSON> Nishizuka </PERSON>, professor and chairman of biochemistry at the <ORGANIZATION> Kobe </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Univerisity </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medicine </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>. He discovered and purified a substance called protein kinase C, which plays a key role in handling chemical messages that come to a cell. He also showed that environmental chemicals can act directly on that substance to promote cancer.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880614-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-14-88 0041EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Dial-a-Poem     06-14 0537</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Dial-a-Poem,0565</SECOND>
<HEAD>Culture A Phone Call Away For Britons</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By MARCUS ELIASON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The telephone company launched a new service for culture-lovers Monday _ Dial-a-Poem. For 70 cents a minute, <ORGANIZATION> British </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Telecom </ORGANIZATION>'s customers can hear five-minute recordings of leading poets reciting their verse. Callers dialing 0898-222255 could hear <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Heath-Stubbs </PERSON>, 70, saying: `` I'm very happy to be the first poet to be recorded in this dial-a-poem series,'' before reciting from four of his poems, ranging in subject matter from <PERSON> Noah </PERSON>'s Ark through cats in poetry to clocks and space. <PERSON> Heath-Stubbs </PERSON> is among six contemporary poets chosen for Dial-a-Poem. It's too soon to tell whether the innovation will confound the 19th-century historian <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Macaulay </PERSON>'s conviction that `` as civilization advances, poetry almost necessarily declines.'' But something clearly is astir. The <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> subway has beun displaying verses of <LOCATION> Shelley </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Burns </PERSON> and de la Mare on some of its trains, and a year ago the railroad company organized poetry readings at some of its stations. <PERSON> Sarah </PERSON> <PERSON> Chesney </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> English </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Language </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION>, the literary group that selected the poets for Dial-a-Poem, explained in a telephone interview: `` We felt we should make poetry more accessible.'' Added <PERSON> Lisa </PERSON> <PERSON> Bourne </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> British </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Telecom </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman: `` Poetry was slowly fading away, and we thought it would be a great idea to bring it back.'' State-owned until it was floated on the stock market in 1984, <ORGANIZATION> British </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Telecom </ORGANIZATION> is ever on the lookout for a profit-making sideline, and it said that if <PERSON> Dial-a-Poem </PERSON> attracted 1,000 calls a week, it would make the service permanent. Others poets reading their verse for telephone callers during the six-week trial run are <PERSON> Kathleen </PERSON> <PERSON> McPhilemy </PERSON>, <PERSON> Jeremy </PERSON> <PERSON> Reed </PERSON>, <PERSON> Bernard </PERSON> <PERSON> Kops </PERSON>, <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Berry </PERSON> and <PERSON> Gillian </PERSON> <PERSON> Allnutt </PERSON>. `` We wanted something refreshingly adventurous _ poetry that is not so obscure that it does n't come across well on the phone, but that is also not strictly traditional,'' said Ms. <PERSON> Chesney </PERSON>. She said each poet would receive 10 percent of the profits from the service. One problem is <ORGANIZATION> British </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Telecom </ORGANIZATION>'s phone lines, which are n't famous for their clarity <PERSON> Heath-Stubbs </PERSON> came through somewhat faintly and would only be comprehensible in a quiet room. `` I do n't think the telephone does the poets justice in a way that hearing them firsthand would,'' Ms. <PERSON> Chesney </PERSON> said. `` But many people wo n't have the chance to hear them firsthand, and for them it's refreshing to hear them -LRB- the poets -RRB- in their own voices.'' To listen to Heath-Stubbs' entire five minutes costs $ 3.45 between 8 a.m. and 6 p.m. But a cheaper rate during slack hours brings the cost down to $ 2.25. A sampling from <PERSON> Heath-Stubbs </PERSON>'s `` The Cosmic Clock'': Planets, stars, galaxies _ the whole Winking and blinking caboodle _ This, it seems, is the only reliable clock: A beam from a star crossed a sensitive plate _ Then came the pips: the British nation Turned on the 10 o'clock news. This is the moving image of eternity _ I do n't mean <PERSON> Paley </PERSON>'s watch discarded By the absconding Watchmaker Upon a bank of Wordsworthian daffodils, But pulsars, quasars, decaying elements, black holes; Yet this, they say, is likewise winding down _ And hickory _ dickory, men and mice we run in it!
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880614-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-14-88 0001EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-Presbyterians 2ndLd-Writethru a0828 06-14 0883</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Presbyterians, 2nd Ld-Writethru, a0828,0904</SECOND>
<HEAD>Presbyterians Call On Israel To End Occupation</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Leads with 7 grafs to UPDATE with Middle East statement.
Picks up 5th graf ``The major.'' SUBS outdated 15th graf ``Also
scheduled'' with four grafs of detail. Picks up 16th graf pvs ``The
agenda...''</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Will be led with later action.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>By JOHN A. BOLT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ST. LOUIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The nation's largest Presbyterian body Monday called on <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> to end its 20-year occupation of the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strip </LOCATION>, where the church said <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> had used `` repressive'' measures to quell Palestinian violence. The 200th <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> the </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Presbyterian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> declined to include in its resolution language calling on Palestinians to recognize <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s right to exist as a nation. The Rev. <PERSON> Benjamin </PERSON> <PERSON> Weir </PERSON>, a Presbyterian leader and former hostage in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>, told the 630 commissioners the <ORGANIZATION> Palestine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> has made such statements several times. <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> maintains that such <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> statements have been ambiguous or unauthoritative. The statement adopted Monday on a 494-67 vote said <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> had responded to uprisings in the occupied territories with `` rigid censorship, mass arrests, torture of prisoners, administrative detention and deportation.'' The resolutions adopted also call upon the `` Palestinian people and leadership to exert sustained efforts to control acts of violence in order to facilitate the peace process.'' Earlier Monday, a major Presbyterian statement on nuclear war was revised to make the document more closely follow the original intention, according to the two former seminary professors who led the writing effort. The Committee on Peacemaking and International Relations of the <ORGANIZATION> Presbyterian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> -LRB- </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> U.S.A. </ORGANIZATION> -RRB- continued review Monday evening of `` Christian Obedience in a Nuclear Age,'' making minor changes in the recommendations of a subcommittee that extensively reviewed the paper. The major change by the Peacemaking committee was made at the suggestion of the Rev. <PERSON> Arnold </PERSON> <PERSON> Come </PERSON>, former president of the <ORGANIZATION> San </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Francisco </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Theological </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Seminary </ORGANIZATION> and a co-chairman of the task force that wrote the paper last year. Originally, the paper said nuclear war and the theory of nuclear deterrence were both immoral, but the subcommittee revised that to say `` nuclear deterrence has been in danger of becoming an end in itself rather than an interim measure of self-defense. Such a policy as an end in itself is not morally defensible.'' Come and the Rev. <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Winn </PERSON>, the task force's co-chairman and former president of the <LOCATION> Louisville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ky. </LOCATION>, Theological Seminary, complained the phrase `` as an end in itself'' was ambiguous. At Come's suggestion, the language was clarified to say nuclear deterrence `` is being regarded as an adequate and permanent means to national security,'' and that is `` not morally defensible.'' The committee has yet to deal with the major question of the subcommittee's recommendation that the Christian obedience paper be adopted as church policy. The subcommittee, which met for parts of four days, amended the paper to make it clear Presbyterians considered obedience to government the normal course. <PERSON> Winn </PERSON> said he disliked many changes, but added, `` in many respects, they clarified the paper and deleted some statements that were not carefully worded.'' Supporters of the original paper expect many of the revisions _ including elimination of a recommendation that the church aid tax resisters _ would be restored in some form in the full committee. Opponents of the paper want it to be sent back to the churches for further study. An effort to get the subcommittee to recommend that delay was defeated 9-5 and the subcommittee eventually agreed to recommend the revised report as a church policy by a 15-1 vote. The report is not expected to come before the 630 delegates until Tuesday. The nine-day meeting adjourns at noon Wednesday. The resolution on the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> also: _ Asks <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> to `` cease the systematic violation of human rights of Palestinians ... end the policies and-or practices of beatings and of food and fuel embargoes in the attempt to subjugate and break the will of the Palestinian population. ... end the settlements policy and the acquisition of land within the occupied territories, since -LRB- they -RRB- provoke the Arab peoples and reduce the opportunity for a peaceful resolution.'' _ Asks the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> to `` discourage retaliation as a counter-terror strategy in the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> and to address the injustices which are among the root causes of terrorism ... insist that weapons supplied by the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> for <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s defense not be used against civilian populations in the occupied territories or in aggressive attacks or disproportionate retaliation upon other countries, and that further military and security assistance to <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> be contingent upon the honoring of these principles. _ Ask all parties to participate in a United Nations-sponsored international peace conference The agenda included discussion of several decisions, including the recommendation that the pension board headquarters remain in <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION>. A minority report suggests the board be moved to <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>. The headquarters of the 3 million-member denomination was moved to <LOCATION> Louisville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ky. </LOCATION>, last year. Anti-abortion groups also have objected to the pension board's paying for abortions The denomination has adopted a generally pro-choice position, condemning abortion as a method of birth control, but saying it remains a decision by a woman, her physician and her conscience. Anti-abortionists say the pension board should not pay for abortions. Another committee has recommended the denomination undertake a new study on the issue of abortion.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880614-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-14-88 0049EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-TestingSurvey     06-14 0586</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Testing Survey,0601</SECOND>
<HEAD>Reform Has Made Public Schools `Test Happy'</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: FairTest cq</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By LEE MITGANG</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Education Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Big-city school districts and Southern states are requiring students to take an ever-mounting number of standardized tests in the name of reform, according to a nationwide survey. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> students are now taking at least 100 million standardized tests a year, says a report published Monday by <LOCATION> FairTest </LOCATION>, a non-profit <LOCATION> Cambridge </LOCATION>, Mass.-based advocacy group that has attacked standardized tests as biased against women and minorities. The first-of-its-kind survey found: _ Elementary and secondary school students took 17.5 million standardized achievement, competency and basic skills tests to fulfill state mandates in the 42 states requiring them, and in the <LOCATION> District </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION> in 1986-87. _ Students took 38.9 million additional standardized tests to fulfill local school district testing mandates, according to the group. _ Between 30 million and 40 million standardized tests, including I.Q. tests, were administered to compensatory and special education students, and schools administered between 1.5 million and 1.75 million screening tests for kindergarten and prekindergarten students. _ College and secondary school admissions tests including the Scholastic Aptitude Test, ACT, high school achievement tests, and the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assessment </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Educational </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Progress </ORGANIZATION> tests, accounted for 6 million to 7 million more. `` In this country now, pupils are being tested far too often with far too simplistic a measure. School reform has led many schools to become too test happy. The fallout hits those least able to defend themselves,'' said <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Monty </PERSON> <PERSON> Neill </PERSON>, managing director of <LOCATION> FairTest </LOCATION> and co-author of the survey. The report, `` Fallout from the Testing Explosion: How 100 Million Standardized Exams Undermine Equity and Excellence in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s Public Schools,'' included statistics compiled n a telephone survey last spring of education departments in all 50 states. It also surveyed 56 school districts, including those with enrollments of at least 100,000 pupils. It found that in the 1986-87 school year, the number of states using tests as part of statewide assessment programs rose from 37 to 42. Twenty-four states required students to pass a standardized test to graduate from high school rose in 1987, compared with 15 in 1985. Large school districts required the most standardized testing by far. Students in <LOCATION> Newark </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.J. </LOCATION>, averaged nine district-mandated standardized exams in 1986-87, according to <LOCATION> FairTest </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Cleveland </LOCATION> students took an average of 2.92, <LOCATION> Broward </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>, 2.60, <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Louis </LOCATION> 2.45, <LOCATION> Cincinnati </LOCATION> 2.34, <LOCATION> Baltimore </LOCATION> 2.30, and <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION> 2.0. <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, the nation's largest school district, required its students to take an average 1.23 standardized tests. The District of <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION> mandated an average 1.39 per pupil. Southern states had the most state-mandated tests. The nation's 39.8 million public school students took 17,545,159 such state-mandated tests in 1986-87, an average 0.44 per student But Southern states often had testing rates more than double that national average. <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> required its 975,135 public school students to take 1,069,000 tests during the 1986-87 school year, meaning 1.10 such state-mandated tests per pupil. <LOCATION> Kentucky </LOCATION> students took an average of 1.01 state-mandated exams, <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> 1.0, <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION> 0.98, <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION> 0.93, <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION> 0.90, and <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION> 0.83. `` Historically the South has been viewed as having weak school systems. There is a belief that you can test your way to better schools, and the South jumped on it,'' said <PERSON> Neill </PERSON> in a telephone interview. <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Ewing </PERSON>, a spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> Educational </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Testing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>, which administers the SAT and a variety of other standardized exams, said he had n't seen the report and could not comment on it.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880614-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-14-88 0008EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-FBISurveillance 1stLd-Writethru a0764 06-14 0793</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-FBI Surveillance, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0764,760</SECOND>
<NOTE>Eds: INSERTS 3 grafs after pvs 6th graf to include information
about internal FBI report; picks up pvs 7th graf bgng ``According
to ...''</NOTE>
<HEAD>Lawmakers to Tighten Standards for Probing Domestic Terrorists</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PHYLLIS MESSINGER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Members of a <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Judiciary subcommittee, examining alleged abuses in the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION>'s investigation of a group opposed to the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration's <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> policy, said Monday they intend to draft more restrictive standards for probes of terrorists in this country. `` What we've tried to do in the past is rely on the Constitution for protecting individual rights,'' said Rep. <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON>, D-Calif., chairman of the civil and constitutional rights subcommittee `` I am thinking seriously of sometime early next year taking another quick look at this issue and writing the beginnings of an <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> charter.'' <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON> and other members of the panel appeared to agree with recommendations from four witnesses that there should be one standard, instead of the current two sets of guidelines, for <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> probes of domestic terrorism and that this standard should be written into law instead of left to the attorney general to determine. One witness, <PERSON> Morton </PERSON> <PERSON> Halperin </PERSON>, director of the <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> office of the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Civil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberties </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION>, said he believes that `` all investigations of political organizations should be based on public, codified guidelines and should include frequent review to ensure that they stay within the prescribed bounds.'' <PERSON> Halperin </PERSON> added, `` The <ORGANIZATION> ACLU </ORGANIZATION> believes that one publicly enunciated standard should apply for all criminal intelligence investigations.'' Spurring Monday's hearings was the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION>'s handling of an investigation into the <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> in Solidarity with the People of <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>, or <ORGANIZATION> CISPES </ORGANIZATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> reported in Tuesday's editions that government officials said an internal <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> report has recommended disciplinary action against some bureau personnel, possibly including field agents, involved in the <ORGANIZATION> CISPES </ORGANIZATION> investigation. The officials said the report is the most critical to date from senior bureau officials and was sent last month to <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> director <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Sessions </PERSON> from the bureau's Inspection Division. But the officials told the newspaper Sessions has not made a decision on whether to punish anyone for action in the CISPES operation. <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Milt </PERSON> <PERSON> Ahlerich </PERSON> would not comment on the contents of the division's report but said `` This agency has no hesitancy in disciplining its own people ...'' According to <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> documents released in January and comments by <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> officials since then, that investigation began in September 1981 as a probe into alleged criminal violations of domestic security laws. Specifically, the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> was looking into whether <ORGANIZATION> CISPES </ORGANIZATION> was supplying money and material to leftist rebels in <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>. That investigation was closed the following February. But in March 1983, the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> began a new investigation of <ORGANIZATION> CISPES </ORGANIZATION> under a different set of guidelines, those governing international terrorism. Although much of those guidelines are classified, it is known that they give the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> far more sweeping authority to investigate <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> citizens. <PERSON> Eric </PERSON> <PERSON> Richard </PERSON>, a former <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> aide, told the subcommittee that `` it may not have been fully realized how frequently the groups that would be the targets of such -LRB- international terrorism -RRB- investigations would be composed primarily of American citizens.'' <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> and other witnesses agreed that although the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> said it was looking into whether <ORGANIZATION> CISPES </ORGANIZATION> was a front group for a core of people who were aiding international terrorists, the bureau's investigation ended up focusing on public CISPES meetings and statements `` Widescale monitoring of public events served on apparent purpose toward achieving the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION>'s stated objective,'' <PERSON> Halperin </PERSON> testified. `` A front organization ... is not going to reveal its hidden agenda in its public activities.'' <PERSON> Halperin </PERSON> argued and <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Finn </PERSON>, an assistant professor of government at <ORGANIZATION> Wesleyan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, disagreed that the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> violated the First Amendment rights of <ORGANIZATION> CISPES </ORGANIZATION> members by using that tactic. However, all four witnesses agreed that the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> never would have been able to conduct its investigation that way had it been required by law to look for criminal violations. `` The domestic security guidelines require a criminal link,'' <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> said, adding that that is not so with the international terrorism guidelines. `` The domestic security ... guidelines have worked so well in balancing civil liberties, intelligence and law enforcement concerns that it may be time to spread the benefits of these guidelines more widely,'' he said. The witnesses also said that an <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> statute should require that investigations of suspected terrorists in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> be reviewed frequently by top <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> officials. <PERSON> Kenneth </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bass </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>, also a former <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> official, told the panel that he thought there was a need for frequent reviews because `` it it my experience these investigations often continue a year or more after they should have ended.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880614-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-14-88 0113EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-SpyBook     06-14 0409</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Spy Book,0423</SECOND>
<HEAD>`Spycatcher' Author Says HE Has Plenty More To Tell, But Plans No
Sequel</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto HOB1</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SYDNEY, Australia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Author <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> says he has much more to tell about <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s MI5 intelligence service but plans no sequel to `` Spycatcher,'' the memoirs the British government failed to suppress here. `` There are 10 major stories which I have not put in and probably others if I thought hard enough,'' <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> told the <ORGANIZATION> Australian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Broadcasting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>. Monday It was the first time <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> had spoken publicly since the High Court ruled against the British government on June 2, ending a three-year court battle to block Australian publication of his story. <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> said it was the stories he had not told that led the government to fight so hard to suppress the book. `` They have always been frightened of what I know and what I might say publicly and they still are,'' he said. `` Spycatcher'' describes <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>'s 20-year career in the MI5 counterespionage service. It alleges that the security service eavesdropped on foreign embassies, burgled offices, stole documents, plotted assassination attempts and discussed how to bring down <PERSON> Harold </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> government in the 1970s. <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> said he had not decided what to do with the unpublished material but doubted he would write a sequel. `` I'm too tired at the moment, we'll have to recover from all this and I think that perhaps I have done my bit,'' he said. <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>'s wife, <PERSON> Lois </PERSON>, commented, `` There will be a sequel to Spycatcher over my dead body.'' <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>, who retired to <LOCATION> Tasmania </LOCATION> in 1976, said the court battles in <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION> helped make `` Spycatcher'' a bestseller. `` I thought initially we might get a print run of about 50,000 at most. Now we are looking at more than 1 million copies sold in the <LOCATION> U.S.A. </LOCATION> alone,'' he said. So far, more than 1.4 million copies have been sold in 40 countries, including the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, despite the government's continued ban in <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> The book is frequently smuggled into <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> and excerpts have been published in British newspapers. The British government has sought to clamp down on these as well, prompting outcries over freedom of the press. The government maintains it has pursued the case to uphold the principle that former security officers are bound by a lifetime oath of silence about their work. The Australian High Court said <LOCATION> Australian </LOCATION> courts had no jurisdiction to enforce a British security regulation.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880614-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-14-88 0010EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-ComputerHostages     06-14 0293</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Computer Hostages,0302</SECOND>
<HEAD>Fired Employee Takes Hostages, Fatally Shoots Self</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TIM LOTT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>RICHARDSON, Texas (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A fired computer company employee returned to his offices Monday and fatally shot himself after earlier holding two hostages at gunpoint for much of the day, authorities said. Police spokesman <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Wheatley </PERSON> said <PERSON> Mervin </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gilliam </PERSON>, 28, entered Zeus Components in this <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION> suburb with a 12-gauge shotgun shortly after 8 a.m. looking for his former boss and attempted to take four hostages, but two escaped. One man and one woman were held for much of the day. <PERSON> Donna </PERSON> <PERSON> Dippel </PERSON>, a company secretary in her 20s, was released early afternoon and <PERSON> Roman </PERSON> <PERSON> Gonzales </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION> resident in his early 30s, was released at about 4 p.m., <PERSON> Wheatley </PERSON> said. Associates said they were shocked by the incident. `` He was a very nice guy,'' said <PERSON> Greg </PERSON> <PERSON> Foster </PERSON>, pastor of <ORGANIZATION> Hamilton </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Park </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> First </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Baptist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION>, which <PERSON> Gilliam </PERSON> attended. `` Sometimes something in a person's life comes up that you ca n't explain <PERSON> Mervin </PERSON> was n't capable of this.'' `` I'm surprised to see him do something like this,'' said co-worker <PERSON> Brad </PERSON> <PERSON> Davis </PERSON>, 36. The gunman's brother, <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Gilliam </PERSON>, and his mother arrived at the offices late Monday morning to help police negotiate, <PERSON> Wheatley </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Dwain </PERSON> <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON>, who described <PERSON> Gilliam </PERSON> as a friend and `` a very talented young man,'' said <PERSON> Gilliam </PERSON> had recently been through a period of depression after losing his girlfriend and his job. The company did not make public the reason for the firing. Police were on a direct telephone line with the man when they heard a muffled gunshot and the phone went dead about 5:20 p.m., said Capt. <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Hanna </PERSON>. Police entered the building immediately after hearing the shot and found <PERSON> Gilliam </PERSON> dead, <PERSON> Hanna </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880614-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-14-88 0127EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-TheaterWar Bjt   06-14 0550</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Theater War, Bjt,0569</SECOND>
<HEAD>Theater Drama Holds Austrians In Thrall</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ALISON SMALE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>VIENNA, Austria (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The country's foremost theater is gripped by a real-life drama that rivals the classics presented on its historic stage. The star is West German Claus Peymann, imported to direct the Burgtheater and embroiled in battles with his actors and the <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION> cultural establishment. A premier of `` Oedipus'' Sunday night turned into a demonstration for and against <ORGANIZATION> Peymann </ORGANIZATION>, with banners unfurled on stage and the divided audience booing and cheering. A city that relishes scandal and prizes its theaters and opera, got the first whiffs of sensation on May 26, when the West German weekly <ORGANIZATION> Die </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Zeit </ORGANIZATION> published an interview with <PERSON> Peymann </PERSON>. The director said `` this country is a madhouse'' and that he was often involved in `` dreadful things of the most banal kind.'' He even suggested that the famed Burgtheater be torn down. Reaction was swift. The Socialist politicians who appointed <ORGANIZATION> Peymann </ORGANIZATION> in 1986 predictably defended their choice, arguing that the director had brought life and exciting art to the marble halls of the <PERSON> Burg </PERSON>. Conservatives offended by <PERSON> Peymann </PERSON>'s stark productions of beloved German classics seized the chance to call for the director's resignation The Burgtheater actors were quick to criticize Peymann for cutting salaries and for changing the way tickets, rehearsals and roles are allocated. Nearly everybody attacked Peymann for bringing in 15 actors from <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>. Most of them are friends from <ORGANIZATION> Peymann </ORGANIZATION>'s days as director of the West German theater in <LOCATION> Bochem </LOCATION> before he was lured to <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION>. The newcomers have gotten almost all the leading roles in Peymann's new productions. But locals ridiculed the new actors for their northern German vernacular, which offends the ear of an audience used to the distinctive delivery long considered among the Burgtheater's greatest merits. The issue became the chief topic of conversation in Viennese coffeehouses and the media entered the fray with debates on Peymann. Many commentators saw an attempt by Germans to subvert <LOCATION> Austria </LOCATION>'s distinctive German language and culture <PERSON> Franz </PERSON> <PERSON> Morak </PERSON>, anti-Peymann spokesman for the Burgtheater ensemble, spoke of a `` de-Austrianization'' of the <PERSON> Burg </PERSON>. <ORGANIZATION> Peymann </ORGANIZATION> countered Monday with accusations of `` nationalism and hatred for strangers'' in <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION>. That charge has often been made in a city that prizes the imperial past that gave it the Burgtheater and many other artistic institutions. When <PERSON> Lorin </PERSON> <PERSON> Maazel </PERSON> stepped down as director of the city's famous opera in 1984, two years before his contract expired, he bitterly charged that critics and officials had united to get him out. Criticism of the directors of the <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Opera </LOCATION> and the Burgtheater has a long tradition in <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION>, where the posts are often described as <LOCATION> Austria </LOCATION>'s most impossible jobs. But the drama over <ORGANIZATION> Peymann </ORGANIZATION> has reached an unusual pitch. With discussion in full swing, prominent commentator <PERSON> Hans </PERSON> <PERSON> Rauscher </PERSON> in the tabloid Kurier was one of the few to chide his compatriots for their absorption in the Peymann affair. In a column, <PERSON> Rauscher </PERSON> described the effect of picking up Austrian newspapers on the plane while on his way home. `` One can only shake one's head in amusement and despair,'' wrote <PERSON> Rauscher </PERSON>. `` Are these really our worries? This orgy of small-mindedness? These childish quarrels? Is the plane landing in a republic of dwarfs? Or in a kindergarten?''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880614-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-14-88 0129EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Sweden-AIDS     06-14 0169</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Sweden-AIDS,0173</SECOND>
<HEAD>Authorities Give Travelers Condoms and Sex Dictionary</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-AIDS Meeting, Bjt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>STOCKHOLM, Sweden (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 As part of the campaign against the spread of AIDS, travelers are being given the opportunity to learn how to suggest the use of a condom in seven languages. `` Sex has become more dangerous. ... This does not mean that one should be afraid of sex, but observant and careful of oneself and others,'' says a pamphlet included in a package for sale at travel agencies and train stations around <LOCATION> Sweden </LOCATION>. The package includes a packet of condoms and a dictionary of sex-related phrases, according to the Social Affairs ministry. Among the phrases are, `` I want us to use a condom,'' and `` I think I might have a venereal disease.'' `` Only the condom can provide any good protection against sexually transmitted diseases,'' the pamphlet says. Health authorities this year sent 4 million pamphlets to homes to explain in graphic detail how AIDS is transmitted and distributed camouflage condoms to military conscripts.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880614-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-14-88 0132EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FBISurveillance Bjt   06-14 0785</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-FBI Surveillance, Bjt,790</SECOND>
<HEAD>FBI Probe of US Political Group Prompts Call for Limits</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto WX7</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PHYLLIS MESSINGER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A House Judiciary panel is considering writing tougher standards for <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> terrorism investigations in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> to prevent the bureau from violating the rights of legitimate domestic political groups. Lawmakers concede that election-year politics probably will delay action until 1989. But during a hearing on Monday into alleged <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> abuses in an investigation of anti-Reagan administration activists, members of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Judiciary </ORGANIZATION> subcommittee on civil and constitutional rights agreed with witnesses who recommended new controls on such investigations. <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> officials have said an internal investigation of the operation found several problems with it, and <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> reported today that an internal <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> report recommends disciplinary action against some of those involved. <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Milt </PERSON> <PERSON> Ahlerich </PERSON> would not comment on the contents of the report and said that <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> Director <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Sessions </PERSON> had made no decision on its recommendations. The <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> conducted much of its probe of the <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> in Solidarity with the <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> El </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Salvador </ORGANIZATION>, a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> group opposed to <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration policies in <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, under guidelines that are supposed to cover investigations of international terrorism. Using those guidelines allowed the bureau to conduct widespread surveillance of political rallies and individuals including nuns, union officials and college professors opposed to administration policy. Witnesses and lawmakers at Monday's hearing said there should be just one set of guidelines instead of the current two _ domestic and international _ governing such investigations. The standard, witnesses agreed, should specify that the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> look for criminal actions and steer clear of a group's political activity. Lawmakers and witnesses also agreed that the standard should be written into law instead of left to the attorney general to determine. `` What we've tried to do in the past is rely on the Constitution for protecting individual rights,'' said Rep. <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON>, D-Calif., chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> panel `` I am thinking seriously of sometime early next year taking another quick look at this issue and writing the beginnings of an <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> charter.'' The <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> justified its use of the international terrorism probe guidelines in the <ORGANIZATION> CISPES </ORGANIZATION> investigation by citing an informant's claim that some of the group's members were giving money and supplies to a leftist group in <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION> But no criminal charges were ever filed against <ORGANIZATION> CISPES </ORGANIZATION> or any of its members, and the investigation was closed in June 1985. One witness at Monday's hearing, <PERSON> Morton </PERSON> <PERSON> Halperin </PERSON>, director of the <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> office of the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Civil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberties </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION>, said the current guidelines `` accommodate the demands of law enforcement without fully protecting the lawful exercise of our constitutional rights.'' <PERSON> Halperin </PERSON> said the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION>'s investigation of <ORGANIZATION> CISPES </ORGANIZATION> `` demonstrates that the current <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> guidelines have failed to protect Americans from improper government surveillance.'' According to <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> documents released in January and comments by <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> officials since then, the bureau's initial probe of <ORGANIZATION> CISPES </ORGANIZATION> began in September 1981 as an investigation into alleged criminal violations of domestic security laws. That investigation was closed the following February. But in March 1983, the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> began a new investigation of <ORGANIZATION> CISPES </ORGANIZATION> under the broader guidelines governing international terrorism. Although much of those guidelines are classified, it is known that they give the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> far more sweeping authority to investigate <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> citizens than the domestic guidelines do. <PERSON> Eric </PERSON> <PERSON> Richard </PERSON>, a former <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> aide, told the panel that when the international terrorism guidelines were written, `` it may not have been fully realized how frequently the groups that would be the targets of such investigations would be composed primarily of American citizens.'' <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Finn </PERSON>, an assistant professor of government at <ORGANIZATION> Wesleyan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, disagreed with <PERSON> Halperin </PERSON>'s contention that the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> violated the First Amendment rights of <ORGANIZATION> CISPES </ORGANIZATION> members by attending <ORGANIZATION> CISPES </ORGANIZATION> meetings, obtaining the group's literature and recording the license plate numbers of cars parked outside <ORGANIZATION> CISPES </ORGANIZATION> meetings. But all of the witnesses, including <PERSON> Finn </PERSON>, agreed that the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> would not have been able to mount such an extensive domestic surveillance campaign had it been limited to looking for actual criminal violations. `` Widescale monitoring of public events served no apparent purpose toward achieving the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION>'s stated objective. A front organization ... is not going to reveal its hidden agenda in its public activities,'' <PERSON> Halperin </PERSON> said. `` The domestic security guidelines require a criminal link,'' <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> said, adding that those rules have worked well `` in balancing civil liberties, intelligence and law enforcement concerns.'' The witnesses also said that an <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> statute should require that investigations of suspected terrorists in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> be reviewed frequently by top <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> officials to ensure that there is sufficient evidence to continue.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880614-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-14-88 0136EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-ScotusRdp Bjt   06-14 0771</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Scotus Rdp, Bjt,750</SECOND>
<HEAD>Impact of Supreme Court's Vaccine Ruling Debated</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDs: Kevan, graf 2, cq</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By JAMES H. RUBIN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> has reduced the government's protection against lawsuits by victims of defective federally licensed vaccines, but some authorities say the ruling's impact may be limited The justices ruled unanimously Monday that the parents of <PERSON> Kevan </PERSON> <PERSON> Berkovitz </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> boy crippled by polio, may sue the government. But <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Greene </PERSON>, a lawyer for <ORGANIZATION> Lederle </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Laboratories </ORGANIZATION> which manufactures polio vaccine, said the impact is unclear. The decision appears to cover all government-licensed vaccines and possibly other drugs as well, he said. But he added that the standards enunciated by the court may affect few cases. `` The facts alleged here are unusual and I do n't know whether they -LRB- the <PERSON> Berkovitz </PERSON> family -RRB- can prove them,'' he said. `` These are circumstances that are unlikely to arise'' very often. Health experts, meanwhile, said the nation's common vaccines pose little risk. `` In terms of serious side effects, it's far better to be vaccinated than to get the disease,'' said <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Scott </PERSON> <PERSON> Giebink </PERSON>, professor of pediatrics at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Minnesota </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION>. Polio paralysis results only from about one out of every 3.2 million doses of oral polio vaccine, he said. In another example, about one in 110,000 children who get the Diphtheria-Tetanus-Pertussis -LRB- DTP -RRB- vaccine develop a brain dysfunction that can include seizures. It is usually temporary. Only about one in 310,000 vaccinated children suffer permanent damage that includes mental retardation or movement difficulties, according to the <ORGANIZATION> Centers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Disease </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Control </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration lawyers had warned that exposing the government to financial liability for faulty vaccines could have serious consequences. The <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> said the threat of big-money damages against the government could threaten availability of lifesaving vaccines by prompting federal officials to reconsider the approval of polio vaccine, and delay or withhold approval for new vaccines. <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Food </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Drug </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>, which licenses more than 40 vaccines, declined to comment on the ruling. A financial analyst said the decision may be good news for drug manufacturers. `` This is very good for the vaccine companies, but there are not that many of them,'' said <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Vieter </PERSON>, a drug industry analyst with <ORGANIZATION> Merrill </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lynch </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> `` One might look ahead to vaccines such as AIDS vaccines and other bio-tech applications, though. `` It seems the government will have to exert quite a bit more care in the approval process to prevent placing the government in a liability situation,'' <PERSON> Vieter </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Kevan </PERSON> <PERSON> Berkovitz </PERSON> was two months old in May 1979 when his pediatrician in <LOCATION> Charleroi </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION>, gave him a dose of <LOCATION> Orimune </LOCATION>, a polio vaccine made by <ORGANIZATION> Lederle </ORGANIZATION>. Orimune, a form of <PERSON> Sabin </PERSON> oral vaccine, was licensed by the government in 1963. <PERSON> Kevan </PERSON> was stricken with polio within a month after taking the vaccine and the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Communicable Disease Center determined he contracted the disease from the vaccine. The boy, now 9, is paralyzed from the neck down and uses a respirator to help him breathe. Monday's ruling provides an opportunity in court to seek compensation for him from the government. His lawyer, <PERSON> Ellen </PERSON> <PERSON> Viakely </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION>, said of the ruling, `` It's a case where the government knew that this particular polio vaccine violated its own regulatory safety standards. By the government's own regulatory standards, this vaccine was unsafe. But it licensed it anyway.'' Ms. <PERSON> Viakely </PERSON> said the ruling will not affect cases in which those who received a vaccine had an allergic reaction. The polio vaccine is the only common vaccine clearly shown to cause the disease it was supposed to prevent, said <PERSON> Samuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Katz </PERSON>, chairman of the pediatrics department at the <ORGANIZATION> Duke </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Sabin </PERSON> vaccine is now administered routinely to nearly every child in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and has all but eliminated polio. But each year a small number of people suffer adverse reactions to the vaccine, federal officials say. In other actions, the court: _ Agreed to judge the constitutionality of a new sentencing system for people convicted of federal crimes By the time the justices announce their decision sometime in 1989, more than 10,000 federal court defendants will have been subjected to the new sentencing system. _ Armed police with new authority as it ruled unanimously in a <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION> case that officers sometimes may pursue someone who starts running at the sight of them, even though they have no reason to suspect criminal conduct _ Barred states from banning all direct-mail advertisements sent by lawyers to potential clients Voting 6-3, the justices struck down <LOCATION> Kentucky </LOCATION>'s policy of prohibiting lawyers from sending letters to people they know face legal problems.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880614-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-14-88 0137EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-AIDS-BreastFeeding     06-14 0630</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AIDS-Breast Feeding,0651</SECOND>
<HEAD>AIDS Risk Should Not Deter Breast-Feeding in Third World, Experts
Say</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-AIDS Meeting, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DANIEL Q. HANEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Science Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>STOCKHOLM (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 New findings showing that AIDS can be transmitted through breast milk should not deter Third World mothers from breast-feeding their babies, experts say. Six cases of the lethal AIDS virus, called HIV, being spread through breast milk were reported Monday at the <ORGANIZATION> Fourth </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conference </ORGANIZATION> on AIDS. But the hazards of bottle-feeding in poor countries are probably higher, some of the scientists said. `` The benefits of being breast-fed by an HIV-infected mother clearly outweigh the risks in developing countries,'' said <PERSON> Kathy </PERSON> <PERSON> I. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> Family </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> in Research Triangle Park, <LOCATION> N.C. </LOCATION>. She and her colleagues conducted a statistical analysis showing that babies in poor countries are far more likely to die from diseases resulting from bottle-feeding than from the possible risk of catching the AIDS virus In poor parts of the world, bottle-feeding is often risky, in large part because infant formula can be mixed with contaminated water. Researchers from <ORGANIZATION> Cornell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> studied 45 AIDS-infected children in <LOCATION> Haiti </LOCATION>, where AIDS infections are relatively common. They said they found no evidence that any of them caught the virus from breast milk. `` We feel that transmission from breast milk is quite low,'' said Dr. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Ho </PERSON>, one of the <ORGANIZATION> Cornell </ORGANIZATION> researchers. `` On a broad basis, it is probably not an important factor.'' Experts believe that most babies with AIDS got the infection from their mothers before birth. There is a 25 percent to 50 percent risk that an infected mother will pass the virus to her developing child. The risk of contracting the disease through breast-feeding is probably substantially greater from mothers infected after birth as opposed to those carrying the virus before conception, said Dr. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Ziegler </PERSON> of Prince of <LOCATION> Wales </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Children </LOCATION><LOCATION> 's </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Westmead </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION>. `` Breast-feeding women should be aware that if they become infected, their baby is likely to be infected as well,'' he said. <PERSON> Ziegler </PERSON> has reviewed nine cases in which breast-feeding women became infected with the AIDS virus after giving birth and found that three of their babies caught the virus. He described two of the cases, while a third in <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION> was reported by Dr. <PERSON> Marion </PERSON> <PERSON> Bucens </PERSON> of Princess <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Hospital </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Perth </LOCATION>. `` We do n't know how often this happens,'' <PERSON> Bucens </PERSON> said. `` In the Third World countries, this is of great importance because of the enormity of heterosexual transmission'' of the AIDS virus. `` There are so many women who are infected.'' <PERSON> Ziegler </PERSON> said that for uninfected babies whose mothers had the virus before they were born, the risk of breast-feeding is probably relatively small. But it appears to be substantially higher if the woman catches the virus while she is breast-feeding. This is because she is likely to produce high levels of virus in her breast milk early in the infection. One typical case was presented by Dr. <PERSON> Pierre </PERSON> <PERSON> Weinbreck </PERSON> and colleagues from the <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Limoges </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>. A 28-year-old woman received a transfusion of AIDS-tainted blood after giving birth. She then breast-fed her baby for a month. Two years later, she developed AIDS, and her child was also found to be infected. Two other cases were reported by Dr. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Colebunders </PERSON> from <LOCATION> Mama </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Yemo </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Kinshasa </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Zaire </LOCATION>. In one of them, a baby caught the virus from an AIDS-infected wet nurse. Acquired immune deficiency syndrome attacks the body's immune system, leaving victims susceptible to a wide variety of infections and cancers. It is is most often transmitted through sexual contact. Other means of transmission include transfusions of tainted blood or blood products, and the sharing of contaminated hypodermic needles or syringes by drug abusers.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880614-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-14-88 0110EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     06-14 0963</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,1001</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names In The News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SPRINGFIELD, Mass. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actor <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> De </PERSON> <PERSON> Niro </PERSON> is preparing for his role as an illiterate mill worker by having a researcher interview men who ca n't read or write. <PERSON> Cynthia </PERSON> <PERSON> Ryan </PERSON> was here last week videotaping current and former illiterate adult men from western <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION>, where part of the film tentatively named `` Union Street'' will be shot. <PERSON> Ryan </PERSON> said some of the men she is videotaping agreed to the interviews only after she promised to conceal their identities. The researcher is making 10 hours of videotapes for <PERSON> De </PERSON> <PERSON> Niro </PERSON> to study for his role as a man who is taught how to read. He is now on a movie set in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> making a film about a <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> veteran. <PERSON> De </PERSON> <PERSON> Niro </PERSON>'s co-star in `` Union Street,'' <PERSON> Jane </PERSON> <PERSON> Fonda </PERSON>, has raised the ire of some veterans in a few <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> towns for her anti-war work during the Vietnam War. <LOCATION> Holyoke </LOCATION> aldermen voted in January to approve a symbolic resolution protesting <PERSON> Fonda </PERSON>'s plans to film in the city because of her visit to <LOCATION> Hanoi </LOCATION> during the war. <PERSON> Beverly </PERSON> aldermen narrowly defeated a similar resolution.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Entertainer <PERSON> Marie </PERSON> <PERSON> Osmond </PERSON> says she admires her mother, <PERSON> Olive </PERSON>, and still finds it hard to believe that her mom raised nine children. `` I have to applaud people like my mother,'' <PERSON> Osmond </PERSON>, 28, said in an interview in July's <PERSON> McCall </PERSON>'s magazine. `` I do n't know how she raised nine children. And she's a brillant woman. People send her computer problems to find bugs. ... She is the most incredible human being.'' `` Contrary to what you may have read _ how my brothers led me with an iron fist and how my mother was domineering _ that's really not true. Even as a teenager, I was very much in control of the things I was doing.'' `` I think its important to say, too, that my beliefs do n't come from my parents,'' <PERSON> Osmond </PERSON> said. `` I am a member of my Mormon faith because I want to be.'' About her career plans, <PERSON> Osmond </PERSON> said: `` I would love to go into films. ... I would not get into nudity or anything like that ... and maybe that will be the thing that will keep me from doing major parts.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actress <PERSON> Bernadette </PERSON> <PERSON> Peters </PERSON> could n't refuse the role of the mother of <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Rothenberg </PERSON>, a boy set afire by his vengeful father, in a based-on-fact TV movie. The <ORGANIZATION> ABC-TV </ORGANIZATION> movie `` David'' features <PERSON> Miss </PERSON> <PERSON> Peters </PERSON> as the bewildered but courageous mother of the boy. The youngster survives the motel room fire, but emerges horribly scarred. `` She was thrilled to get this role. The script was spectacular. She just could n't resist,'' <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Grant </PERSON>, publicist for the actress, said Monday. Miss <PERSON> Peters </PERSON> begins rehearsals this month, and filming starts July 6 in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Grant </PERSON> said. The movie will be directed by <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Irman </PERSON>, best known for his AIDS movie `` An Early Frost.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>KNOXVILLE, Tenn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Joy </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON>, wife of White House Chief of Staff <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON>, was resting in a <LOCATION> Knoxville </LOCATION> hospital where she was being treated for a chronic back problem, a hospital spokeswoman said. Mrs. <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> was admitted to <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mary </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> on Thursday and was in satisfactory condition Monday, said hopital spokeswoman <PERSON> Janice </PERSON> <PERSON> Webster </PERSON>. Ms. <PERSON> Webster </PERSON> said <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> visited his wife at least once Monday. Also Monday, <PERSON> Baker </PERSON>'s stepmother, <PERSON> Irene </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON>, was being treated at <LOCATION> Baptist </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Knoxville </LOCATION>. Hospital officials said <PERSON> Irene </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> was admitted Sunday with stomach pains and was in fair condition Monday.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Prime Minister <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> and <PERSON> Prince </PERSON> <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> have joined in a campaign to win for <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> one of the greatest private art collections in the world, according to news reports. The 1,600 paintings of Swiss <PERSON> Baron </PERSON> <PERSON> Heinrich </PERSON> <PERSON> Thyssen-Bornemisza </PERSON> are regarded as the finest art collection in private hands after that of Queen <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> II </PERSON>. They are conservatively valued at $ 1.41 billion. There has been a fierce international competition for the collection, with <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION> regarded as the favorite. The baron, grandson of the Ruhr steel magnate who armed the German forces in World War I, has made a commitment to <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION> to show most of his paintings in <LOCATION> Madrid </LOCATION> for at least 10 years. But government sources in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> said Monday that Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> has written the baron. A spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> Thyssen-Bornemisza </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION> said Monday that a long-term proposal `` may have been received from the British government,'' but no decision had been made. Its commitment to <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION> remained unaffected by any proposals from <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>, the spokesman said. Prince <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> reportedly broke away from a vacation in <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION> to visit <ORGANIZATION> Thyssen </ORGANIZATION> at his <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lugano </LOCATION> home May 4 to discuss the long-term future of the collection. On May 21, Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> sent <ORGANIZATION> Cabinet </ORGANIZATION> Secretary Sir <PERSON> Robin </PERSON> <PERSON> Butler </PERSON> to <LOCATION> Switzerland </LOCATION> for further talks at the baron's home. The prime minister followed up her offer of a purpose-built gallery for the collection in a two-page, handwritten letter, the domestic news agency <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> said. <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Grey </PERSON>, president of <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Royal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Arts </ORGANIZATION>, said <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> and Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> had done everything possible to see that <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> did not miss a great opportunity. `` The intervention of Prince <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> is the sort of thing that would count in the baron's mind,'' said <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Grey </PERSON>. The Times said the 67-year-old baron has been concerned about the disposition of the collection, begun by his father but broken up at the order of the <LOCATION> Swiss </LOCATION> courts at his father's death. <ORGANIZATION> Thyssen </ORGANIZATION> was adamant that the collection should remain basically intact, the <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> said, in a country prepared to give it a respectful home. <LOCATION> Switzerland </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Getty </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> are also competing for the chance to house the collection.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880614-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-14-88 0140EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-CapitolAdvertising Bjt   06-14 0678</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Capitol Advertising, Bjt,670</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHINGTON WIRE: Is Capitol Salesmanship `What This Country
Needs?'</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LAWRENCE L. KNUTSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Americans wanting to sell anything from biscuits and cigars to plumbing and whiskey often have tried to cloak their wares in the presumed respectability of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and its most illustrious members. <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Webster </PERSON>, for example. <PERSON> Webster </PERSON>, perhaps the most famous senator and orator of the mid-19th century, had his face and his name used to promote cigars, flour, and a concoction known as Dr. <ORGANIZATION> J.C. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ayres </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cherry </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pectoral </ORGANIZATION>, promoted as a cure for coughs, colds, bronchitis, croup, whooping cough and other ailments. According to a new three-case exhibit recently installed in a <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> corridor, the claim that <PERSON> Webster </PERSON> endorsed Dr. <PERSON> Ayres </PERSON>' elixer may have been somewhat exaggerated. Promoters of the product claimed that <PERSON> Webster </PERSON> praised it in 1853. The famed statesman died in 1852. The exhibit, organized by the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> on Art and Antiquities, includes a shiny metal spatula from 1910 which demonstrates that even 58 years after <PERSON> Webster </PERSON>'s death his name still had commercial appeal. <PERSON> Webster </PERSON>'s features are engraved on the widest spot of the antique pancake turner, which is also emblazoned with the words: `` <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Webster </PERSON> Flour, Better Than the Best'' and `` One Good Turn Deserves Another.'' <PERSON> Webster </PERSON>'s face was also used on the flour bag with the words: `` <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Webster </PERSON> Flour Bakes Everything Better.'' In an age when a cigar brought to mind a politician, <PERSON> Webster </PERSON> also was used to promote a brand of cigars. Their name? `` Websters,'' of course. The names and faces of <PERSON> Webster </PERSON>'s contemporaries, Sens. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Calhoun </PERSON> of <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> Clay </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Kentucky </LOCATION> also were used to peddle cigars. And for years, <LOCATION> Old </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Crow </LOCATION> whiskey identified itself as, `` The Whiskey That <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> Clay </PERSON> Took to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>.'' `` From the earliest days of advertising, senators have been known to endorse commercial products,'' notes a news release issued by the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> commission. From the beginning of the advertising age in the mid-19th century, `` our country's enterprises have understood the power of national legislative symbols to influence the American consumer,'' the commission said. The display has a title _ `` What This Country Needs'' _ taken from the 1917 declaration of Vice President <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Marshall </PERSON> that `` What this country needs is a good five cent cigar.'' Although <PERSON> Marshall </PERSON> did not recommend any particular brand of nickel cigar, the exhibit makes clear that he would not have been breaking new ground had he done so. A much later advertisement for Lucky Strike cigarettes reads: `` <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Sen. <PERSON> Gerald </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Nye </PERSON> Says: ` I enjoy the comfort a light smoke gives my throat.'' The familiar image of the Capitol dome has been used, according to the exhibit, to symbolize `` purity, wholesomeness, respectability and success, innovation and leadership, prosperity and celebration.'' In one 1890's advertisement, the Capitol looms in the background as two bearded senators are served Schlitz beer at a table surrounded by ferns. `` The Capitol at <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> is painted with oxide of zinc,'' proclaims another advertisement, implying that <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> homeowners would do well to use that ingredient on their own domicile. On display are advertisements for breakfast cereals, stationery, soft drinks, biscuits, tires, soap, cameras, and plumbing, all using the Capitol theme. One proclaims that the <ORGANIZATION> Durham </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Plumbing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> System </ORGANIZATION> has been installed in `` the greatest building on this continent _ the Capitol at <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>.'' In another, fashionably dressed men, presumably senators, are shown striding up the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>'s marble steps. All of this has caused an occasional raised eyebrows, and the Arts and <ORGANIZATION> Antiquities </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> notes that the use of the Capitol in commercial advertising never has been sanctioned by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. But neither has the practice been banned. In 1956 the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Judiciary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> reported out a bill banning the use of `` pictures of the Capitol or other public buildings in ... advertising when it would be reasonably calculated to convey the false impression that the company has some connection with, or was insured by, the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> Government.'' The measure passed the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>. But the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> failed to act on it.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880614-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-14-88 0150EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-PoliticalRdp Bjt   06-14 0713</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Political Rdp, Bjt,720</SECOND>
<HEAD>Dukakis Intensifies Veep Search; Bush Courts Cuban-Americans</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDS: Material between dashes embargoed until 9:30 a.m EDT; will be
topped</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT GREENE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 The search for <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' running mate begins in earnest today as his manager travels to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> to discuss prospects, and rival <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> courted the <LOCATION> Cuban-American </LOCATION> vote with some sharp words for <PERSON> Fidel </PERSON> <PERSON> Castro </PERSON>. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> was in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> to address a <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> group, plugging his alternative to President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s Star Wars program and his plans for strengthening the European alliance. And <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> continued his conciliatory mood by saying he could rally supporters behind <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> even if the all-but-certain Democratic nominee did not choose <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> for the No. 2 spot on the ticket. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> campaign chairman <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Brountas </PERSON>, point man in the Democrat's search for a running mate, was to spend several days in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> starting today to discuss vice presidential prospects. Campaign aides said <PERSON> Brountas </PERSON> would seek advice from members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and other <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> leaders but declined to name them. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> gave the <ORGANIZATION> Atlantic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>, a private, pro-NATO group, his assessment of the recent U.S.-Soviet summit and called for negotiations between <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> and <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION> Pact countries on conventional military forces.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>(Begin embargoed material)</HEAD>
<HEAD>___</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 `` We do n't need SDI; we need <ORGANIZATION> CDI </ORGANIZATION>, the Conventional Defense Initiative begun by leaders in the <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to apply advanced technology to the challenge of fighting and winning a conventional war,'' the <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> governor said. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> praised the U.S.-Soviet treaty banning intermediate-range nuclear missiles, and he hailed President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s stance on human rights at the recent <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> summit. But <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> also criticized the administration, saying the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> should never again `` announce radical changes in our strategic doctrine or adopt dramatic new bargaining positions on nuclear weapons without consulting our allies in advance.''
</TEXT>
<HEAD>___</HEAD>
<TEXT>
