<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880820-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-20-88 0309EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Megamouth     08-20 0324</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Megamouth,0335</SECOND>
<HEAD>Mysterious Creature Of The Deep Washes Ashore In Australia</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RICHARD BILL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SYDNEY, Australia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A shark named `` megamouth'' with lips that glow in the dark washed ashore off the coast of <LOCATION> Western </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION>, and scientists said it was only the third time such a specimen has been found. `` In this day and age, it is quite a remarkable find,'' Dr. <PERSON> Gerald </PERSON> <PERSON> Allen </PERSON> of the Fish Department of the <ORGANIZATION> Western </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Australia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Museum </ORGANIZATION> said Friday. `` Something like this does n't happen every day.'' The fish, which measured 16 feet and looks like a cross between a whale and a shark, swam ashore on Wednesday near the resort town of <LOCATION> Mandurah </LOCATION>. Locals pushed it back to sea, but it beached itself again and died. <PERSON> Allen </PERSON> said only two other specimens had been found. He said a megamouth _ as researchers call the shark _ was first discovered in 1976 off <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION>. A second specimen was caught in 1984 off the coast of <LOCATION> Southern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>. `` It's the first time a megamouth has been found in the <LOCATION> Southern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hemisphere </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Allen </PERSON> said in a telephone interview with The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Allen </PERSON> said the fish lives at depths of 660 feet to 3,300 feet and has bioluminescent lips that glow in the dark to attract jellyfish, plankton, shrimp and other food. `` We do n't know very much about it other than that it swims at great depths apparently with its mouth open, filtering food,'' said <PERSON> Allen </PERSON>. He said the megamouth has a bulbous head with a mouth measuring 2 -LCB- feet across and tiny teeth. `` It's definitely a shark and it is not prehistoric,'' <PERSON> Allen </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Allen </PERSON> also noted that the megamouth, weighing about 1,500 pounds, feels very flabby. `` It's sort of like jelly,'' he said. `` That is because it does n't need strong muscles or a hard skeleton for the sort of environment in which it lives.'' He said the museum planned to display the megamouth.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880820-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-20-88 0147EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-NightclubEvacuated     08-20 0225</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Nightclub Evacuated,0233</SECOND>
<HEAD>Dozens Injured, Club Evacuated After Tear Gas Canister Tossed</HEAD>
<DATELINE>INDIANAPOLIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A man tossed a tear gas canister onto the crowded dance floor of a teen-age nightclub Friday night, causing dozens of injuries and prompting authorities to evacuate the club and a restaurant. A total of 24 people were treated for nausea and skin and eye irritations at area hospitals. Forty-five others were treated at the scene for the same symptoms after the 10:30 p.m. incident, said District Fire Chief <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> Tibbetts </PERSON>. Witnesses said a man was seen fleeing the club after throwing the military-type tear gas grenade. Police had no suspects. `` The effects will probably be short-lived and minor on most of them with mainly copious amounts nausea, vomiting and skin irritation,'' said <PERSON> Tibbetts </PERSON>. The incident occurred at The Bar Down Under, which police described as a non-alcoholic club for teen-agers in the basement of Union Station, a popular restaurant and shopping complex in the renovated train station. A total of 200-300 people were evacuated from the club and a restaurant above it, police said. `` All of a sudden the smoke started coming in there and started burning. The people were pushing and pulling everybody, trying to get out,'' an unidentified witness told television station <ORGANIZATION> WRTV </ORGANIZATION>. `` The smoke was so thick it made people sick,'' said Patrolman <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880820-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-20-88 0342EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-WashingtonInBrief     08-20 0490</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Washington In Brief,480</SECOND>
<HEAD>Union Head Hails Court Ruling on Hiring Test</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The head of a federal employees union says a federal appeals court ruling will force the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration to replace a civil service test that was found to discriminate against minorities. The Office of Personnel Management `` can no longer ignore their obligation to develop an alternative system,'' <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Employees </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION> President <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Tobias </PERSON> said Friday following the ruling by the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appeals </ORGANIZATION>. The three-judged panel ruled that <ORGANIZATION> OPM </ORGANIZATION> acted `` arbitrarily and capriciously'' in not providing figures to back its claim that high costs rule out developing a new test for filling entry-level jobs. Because the old test was found to be biased earlier in the long-running court dispute, the agency has been using a non-competitive hiring system based on grades and performance in interviews. <ORGANIZATION> OPM </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> McGowan </PERSON> said the agency would have no comment on the ruling.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>___</HEAD>
<HEAD>Recall Ordered for More Than 22,000 Trucks</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 More than 22,000 heavy trucks are being recalled because of potential defects in power steering gears that could result in `` sudden and catastrophic failure,'' the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Highway </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Traffic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> says. The TRW Ross Gear division, which produced the steering gears, and manufacturers of Peterbilt, <LOCATION> Kenworth </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Freightliner </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Western </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Star </ORGANIZATION> and White GMC trucks, urged that affected trucks be removed from highways immediately and towed to the nearest truck dealer, the agency said Friday. The recall affects 22,687 trucks carrying certain steering gears manufactured by <ORGANIZATION> TRW </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ross </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Gear </ORGANIZATION> division since last March. The safety agency said <ORGANIZATION> TRW </ORGANIZATION> has confirmed seven incidents of steering gear failure since June. The agency said the suspect equipment includes certain <ORGANIZATION> TRW </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ross </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Gear </ORGANIZATION> division TAS-65 truck steering gears sold for production and a limited number of TAS-65, TAS-40 and TAS-55 gears sold as prototypes. The TAS-65 gears have date codes of 085-88 or higher and were shipped after March 24.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>___</HEAD>
<HEAD>Court Asked to Block Lawn Darts Sales</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A federal commission says <ORGANIZATION> Sears </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Roebuck </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> has continued to sell lawn darts in violation of a promise to stop marketing the allegedly hazardous game. The <ORGANIZATION> Consumer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Products </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> filed suit Friday in <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> here, asking that <ORGANIZATION> Sears </ORGANIZATION> be found in contempt and be ordered to halt sales of the horseshoes-like game in which darts are thrown at targets on the ground. `` I'm disappointed at <ORGANIZATION> Sears </ORGANIZATION> for this new violation but expect this contempt action will send a strong message to <ORGANIZATION> Sears </ORGANIZATION> and other retailers that the <ORGANIZATION> CPSC </ORGANIZATION> will enforce its regulations on lawn darts,'' said <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Terrence </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Scanlon </PERSON>. <ORGANIZATION> Sears </ORGANIZATION> headquarters in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> said in a statement: `` We received the motion today from the <ORGANIZATION> CPSC </ORGANIZATION> and we are in the process of reviewing it.'' The company signed a consent agreement in March under which the sales would stop but commission investigators said the darts still were being sold in <LOCATION> Puerto </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rico </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880820-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-20-88 0203EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-WildfiresRdp 4thLd-Writethru a0881 08-20 0948</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Wildfires Rdp, 4th Ld - Writethru, a0881,0969</SECOND>
<HEAD>Forest Fire Burns On Southeast Of Helena</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: SUBS 5th graf, `Elsewhere, a ...,' to CORRECT number of
injured in crash to three sted four. Picks up 6th grav pvs, `The
Warm ...'.</NOTE>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto HL1</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By FAITH CONROY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>HELENA, Mont. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Firefighters struggled Friday to encircle a 27,000-acre forest fire that had destroyed 10 houses, forced evacuations and killed cattle in rugged terrain before wind steered flames away from other houses. The leading edge of the 10-day-old Warm Springs Creek fire moved out of the <LOCATION> Elkhorn </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mountains </LOCATION> toward the small town of <LOCATION> Winston </LOCATION>, about 15 miles southeast of <PERSON> Helena </PERSON>. But that area of flames did not threaten houses or other building, and no more evacuations were expected, said <PERSON> Art </PERSON> <PERSON> Howell </PERSON> of the Inter-agency Fire Dispatch Center. `` There's no more homes in the way,'' he said Friday. `` But that depends a lot on the weather and the wind's a big factor.'' A weather inversion trapped cooler air, smoke and flames in the lower valleys throughout most of the day and kept the 27,000-acre fire's growth to only 600 acres, said <PERSON> Anne </PERSON> <PERSON> Jeffery </PERSON>, fire information officer. Elsewhere, a helicopter involved in firefighting efforts in <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Bighorn </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> crashed Friday, killing one person and injuring three others. Firefighters also battled fires in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION>. The Warm Springs Creek fire grew by 7,000 acres Thursday night, despite the efforts of 1,700 heavily equipped firefighters. But on two fronts, the fire took turns that could help suppress it, said fire information officer <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Krepps </PERSON>. He said westerly wind at about 20 mph late Thursday `` pushed the fire back into itself'' on its western border, depriving it of new fuel and lifting a threat to about 500 residents of the <LOCATION> Saddle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mountain </LOCATION> subdivision. At the fire's eastern edge Friday, flames moved out of forested high country and onto grassland. `` That's a real benefit to us also,'' <PERSON> Krepps </PERSON> said, because of the lighter fuel. In addition, its movement took it out of rough, inaccessible terrain into gentler ground where firefighters could work more easily, said <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Adelblue </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Helena </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION>. Barring a return of strong, shifting winds, he said, firefighters should have `` just another day at the office out there.'' Although no new evacuations were expected, <LOCATION> Broadwater </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> Sheriff <PERSON> Rich </PERSON> <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON> said Winston-area residents were on the alert. `` Everybody's aware of what's going on,'' he said. `` If it comes down that mountain, they'll have to get out.'' At least three <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> transport planes, modified to drop fire retardant, were brought in from <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> on Friday and were expected to begin flights Saturday, said <PERSON> Krepps </PERSON>. Erratic wind late Wednesday and and early Thursday had caused the fire to quadruple in size, destroying 10 homes and cabins scattered in the mountains. One cabin owner lost 30 head of cattle. About 40 people remained out of their homes Friday while fire crews backed by bulldozers shored up lines along the north, east and west sides of the fire. <PERSON> Adelblue </PERSON> said the fire was about 30 percent contained. About 35 miles north of <LOCATION> Helena </LOCATION>, fire crews were expected to finish mop-up work on a 110-acre grass fire that initially threatened summer homes near <LOCATION> Wolf </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Creek </LOCATION>. In southeastern <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION>, about 1,000 firefighters began disbanding Friday after tightening a noose around three fires that had burned 13,600 acres of scattered timber and grass near Lame Deer. In north-central <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION>, 980 firefighters attacked the 4,500-acre Lost Canyon fire on the Rocky Boys Indian Reservation. It was about half contained by fire lines, said fire information officer <PERSON> Chris </PERSON> <PERSON> Comstock </PERSON>. <PERSON> Comstock </PERSON> said the fire moved farther into thick timber and was not threatening any buildings. `` I think we're past that point,'' he said. About 60 smaller lightning-caused fires burned Friday in the <LOCATION> Flathead </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> drainage of northwestern <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION>. Elsewhere, officials had few details about the helicopter crash in the <ORGANIZATION> Cloud </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Peak </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wilderness </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Area </ORGANIZATION>, southwest of <LOCATION> Sheridan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wyo. </LOCATION>, in the <ORGANIZATION> Bighorn </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION>, said <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Thoney </PERSON>, a member of the forest's recreation lands staff. Forest spokesman <PERSON> Harvalou </PERSON> <PERSON> Buchanan </PERSON> said the helicopter was privately owned. The affiliations of the people inside were unknown and their names were being withheld. Wind had pushed the Lost fire in the Bighorn forest past fire lines and it had charred 5,400 acres, approaching within a mile of a ranch and summer homes on its northern edge. A wind shift later, however, helped firefighters, pushing the fire to the west, away from the area. Wind gusting to 30 and 35 mph hampered firefighters in Yellowstone National Park, and park officials closed a road from <LOCATION> Grant </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Village </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Lewis </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> again Friday because trees that had been left unburned earlier by the Shoshone fire ignited, sending flames into the road. Elsewhere in <LOCATION> Yellowstone </LOCATION>, wind pushed the North Fork fire to cover about 74,000 acres, a growth of 5,000 acres from reports Thursday. The <ORGANIZATION> Norris </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Junction </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Madison </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Junction </ORGANIZATION> campgrounds were closed while firefighters worked to protect buildings in <LOCATION> Norris </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Junction </LOCATION> from the fire 3 to 4 miles south. In southern <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, an arson brush fire in the <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jacinto </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mountains </LOCATION> grew to 1,073 acres Friday, a fire spokesman said. The fire, between <PERSON> Barker </PERSON> and Cabazon peaks and on part of the <LOCATION> Morongo </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Indian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Reservation </LOCATION>, was expected to be controlled during the night, said <PERSON> Tim </PERSON> <PERSON> Spann </PERSON> of the state <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forestry </ORGANIZATION> and Fire. Firefighters in southwest <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION> contained an 580-acre brush fire, believed to be man-caused, that burned about 20 miles northwest of <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> George </LOCATION>. Firefighters also controlled a 600-acre blaze in northern <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION>. Firefighters in <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Challis </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> squelched a nearly 14,000-acre fire and were being sent elsewhere.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880820-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-20-88 0347EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Iran-Vincennes     08-20 0418</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Iran-Vincennes,0431</SECOND>
<HEAD>Iran's Envoy Rejects U.S. Claim That Iran At Fault In Airliner
Disaster</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Vincennes Report, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PETER JAMES SPIELMANN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>UNITED NATIONS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An Iranian official rejected <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> claims that his country was partly responsible for the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>'s downing of an Iranian jetliner, and he said the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>'s presence in the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> was to blame. `` Our civil airliner was using an internationally recognized air corridor, used five times a week by the same captain,'' Iranian Ambassador <PERSON> Mohammad </PERSON> <PERSON> Ja'afar </PERSON> <PERSON> Mahallati </PERSON> said Friday. During a naval skirmish with Iranian gunboats, the crew of the USS Vincennes misinterpreted radar and electronic signals from the civilian airliner and shot it down July 3, killing all 290 people aboard. Conclusions of a <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> investigation released Friday blamed human error by the crew, but <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Carlucci </PERSON> said <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> bore a heavy responsibility for letting the plane fly over a battle. The report said several of the crew's assumptions about the approaching flight were wrong, including that it was descending toward the <LOCATION> Vincennes </LOCATION> and was flying off course. Of the crew's mistaken beliefs, which the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> released immediately after the disaster, <PERSON> Mahallati </PERSON> said: `` In the view of the American administration, when such incidents take place at the price of the lives of 290 people, first you can not provide the <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> people with facts; it is better to forge information, to misinform them than to keep quiet and wait until the facts come out.'' The Iranian envoy laid the blame on the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>'s presence in the gulf. `` One should conclude that the mere presence of such highly dangerous equipment, which can not be controlled even by trained <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> personnel, is the source of tension,'' he said. `` By itself it can cause miseries, one ofter the other.'' He called for the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> fleet to pull out of the gulf, saying the cease-fire between <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> that started today makes it unnecessary. <PERSON> Mahallati </PERSON> also called on the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> to pay reparations to <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> for the loss of the plane and its passengers and crew and to issue a formal apology. President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> sent <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s regrets and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> accepted responsibility for shooting down the plane. But the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> blames <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> for sending the flight over a combat zone and has not apologized. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> has approved the payment of damages directly to the families of the victims, but not reparations to <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>, or any payment that <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION>'s government would receive.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880820-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-20-88 0348EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Whistle-Off Bjt   08-20 0463</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Whistle-Off, Bjt,0477</SECOND>
<HEAD>Warblers Of The World Pucker For Prizes</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARTIN GRIFFITH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CARSON CITY, Nev. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The world's top warblers are puckering up for tunes ranging from <PERSON> Tchaikovsky </PERSON> to Led Zeppelin at the 11th annual International Whistle-Off this weekend. `` I do n't want to sound boastful, but I think it's a God-given gift,'' said contestant <PERSON> Patty </PERSON> <PERSON> Ediger </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Dayton </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ore. </LOCATION> `` I think maybe the shape of a person's mouth and his teeth have something to do with it she practices two to three hours a day in the months preceding the Whistle-Off. `` I go up to the wee hours of the morning,'' she said. `` It takes a lot of time if you want to be good.'' `` Whistling as an art ranks very high in comparison with other musical arts,'' said <ORGANIZATION> Chamber </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman <PERSON> Jean </PERSON> <PERSON> Stokke </PERSON>. `` These are serious musicians and they're very competitive.'' Thirty people were competing in four divisions today and Sunday in what is billed as the nation's premier whistling event. Whistlers from 15 states, <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> compete for a round-trip flight to <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> or the <LOCATION> Caribbean </LOCATION>. The prize will go to the event's grand champion, with trophies going to the top three in each division. Among the whistlers are former three-time grand champion <PERSON> Roy </PERSON> <PERSON> Thoreson </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Calgary </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Alberta </LOCATION>, and former two-time grand champion <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> <PERSON> Foran </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Yakima </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wash. </LOCATION>. Other contestants include <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Sherman </PERSON> of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jose </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, who will perform Led <ORGANIZATION> Zeppelin </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Stairway to Heaven'' in the novelty division, and <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Reichard </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Ashland </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ore. </LOCATION>, who will perform an abbreviated version of <PERSON> Tchaikovsky </PERSON>'s Symphony No 5 in the solo classical division. Time limits are set to `` keep the event moving,'' Ms. <PERSON> Stokke </PERSON> said. Each contestant must whistle three to six minutes for each performance, except in the solo classical division, where four to eight minutes are allowed. Whistlers can compete in as many as three of the four divisions: solo classical, solo popular, novelty and duets. Judges score them from 1 to 5 for artistry, interpretation and performance. `` You never know what to expect at this thing,'' Ms. <PERSON> Stokke </PERSON> said. `` Last year, a guy wore a space suit and whistled the theme from `` 2001: A Space Odyssey.'' Past performers also have offered a medley from the <ORGANIZATION> Rolling </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Stones </ORGANIZATION> and the rousing music of <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Cohan </PERSON>. Contestants were to meet in preliminary rounds today, with the top four in each category advancing to Sunday's finals. Those who succeed today ca n't repeat the same tune Sunday. About 5,000 people are expected to attend the Whistle-Off. There's no admission charge. Ms. <PERSON> Stokke </PERSON> said the event has `` really caught on.'' `` We're finding that there are many people interested in whistling and many whistlers who have not had a stage prior to this time.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880820-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-20-88 0348EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Angola-UNITA     08-20 0302</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Angola-UNITA,0310</SECOND>
<HEAD>Rebels Claim 42 Government Troops Killed</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LISBON, Portugal (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Guerrillas fighting <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION>'s Marxist government claimed they killed 42 Angolan government troops this week. <ORGANIZATION> UNITA </ORGANIZATION>, which sta Total Independence of <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION>, said Friday in a statement released in the Portuguese capital that its forces killed eight Angolan soldiers in central <LOCATION> Bie </LOCATION> province Aug. 14. The statement said its fighters killed 19 Angolan soldiers in southern <LOCATION> Huila </LOCATION> province Aug. 16, and another 15 in northern <LOCATION> Kuanza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> province the same day. There was no independent confirmation of the report by <ORGANIZATION> UNITA </ORGANIZATION>, which is backed by the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>. The reported fighting occurred despite a cease-fire declared by <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> UNITA </ORGANIZATION> is not a party to the talks that led to the truce. On Aug. 12, <ORGANIZATION> UNITA </ORGANIZATION> said it had killed 42 Angolan soldiers during the week beginning Aug. 8, when the cease-fire went into effect in the southern African nation. <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> maintains an estimated 50,000 troops in <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION> in support of President <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Eduardo </PERSON> <PERSON> dos </PERSON> <PERSON> Santos </PERSON>. Both <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> have justified their support of <ORGANIZATION> UNITA </ORGANIZATION> on the Cuban presence. <ORGANIZATION> UNITA </ORGANIZATION> was not involved in U.S.-mediated southern African peace talks, which are aimed at ending 13 years of civil war in <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION> and securing independence for South African-controlled <LOCATION> South-West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>, also known as <LOCATION> Namibia </LOCATION>. The sixth round of talks is scheduled to open Wednesday in <LOCATION> Brazzaville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Congo </LOCATION>. The Angolan government has said it will not negotiate with <ORGANIZATION> UNITA </ORGANIZATION>, which seeks to share power in the African nation following its failure to gain control of the government upon independence from <LOCATION> Portugal </LOCATION> in 1975. But chief <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> mediator <PERSON> Chester </PERSON> <PERSON> Crocker </PERSON> has said a final agreement for the region can not be reached without an internal political settlement in <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880820-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-20-88 0351EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-BudgetDeficit     08-20 0508</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Budget Deficit,550</SECOND>
<HEAD>Budget Red Ink Surged to $22.9 Billion Last Month</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The federal budget deficit climbed by $ 22.9 billion last month after posting a rare surplus in June, the <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> said. The new batch of red ink brought the deficit for the first 10 months of the fiscal year that began Oct. 1 to $ 142.0 billion, only slightly less than the amount for the same period last year. Government ledger books were in the black with a $ 9.3 billion surplus for June, mainly as a result of quarterly tax payments by businesses and individuals. But the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration is projecting the deficit for the fiscal year that ends Sept. 30 at $ 152.3 billion. That is above the administration's $ 146.7 billion deficit estimate in February but below the $ 157 billion forecast by the <ORGANIZATION> Congressional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Budget </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> at the beginning of the year. The <ORGANIZATION> CBO </ORGANIZATION> revised its figures Friday, however, to project a $ 155 billion deficit. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Blum </PERSON>, acting director of the congressional agency, said stronger economic growth than expected for the first half was responsible. The <ORGANIZATION> CBO </ORGANIZATION> is not expecting across-the-board spending cuts to be triggered this month by a law calling for a balanced budget by 1993, <PERSON> Blum </PERSON> said. He said <ORGANIZATION> CBO </ORGANIZATION> projections indicate there is no way the budget could be balanced by 1993 in the absence of further policy changes, such as spending cuts or tax increases. The agency, in fact, projects a $ 121 billion deficit in 1993 if present policies are unchanged. Surprising economic growth, which has boosted government revenues and lowered government spending for such programs as unemployment benefits, has been credited with reducing the deficit this year. Many economists believe the deficit will rise again in the fiscal year beginning. Oct. 1. The administration, however, predicts it will drop to $ 140.1 billion in 1989, when figured according to guidelines contained in the Gramm-Rudman deficit reduction law. Last month's deficit was 2.7 percent higher than the imbalance in July a year ago. Government spending in July actually dropped 6.9 percent when compared to June. Spending fell to $ 83.6 billion but tax receipts dropped even more sharply, falling by 38.8 percent to $ 60.7 billion. Tax receipts for the first 10 months of the fiscal year were up 5.7 percent to $ 741.7 billion while spending is up 4.6 percent to $ 883.7 billion. As usual, the largest spending categories were the military, Social Security and other programs in the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Human </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION>, and interest on the national debt. Military spending totaled $ 23.9 billion in July and $ 237.1 billion in the first 10 months of this fiscal year, up 3.3 percent from the same period last year. Social Security payments totaled $ 17.2 billion in July and $ 178 billion so far this budget year, an increase of 5.8 percent. Spending for other HHS programs amounted to $ 12.0 billion last month and $ 130.8 billion this budget year, up 3.3 percent. Interest payments on the $ 2.6 trillion national debt cost $ 14.5 billion in July and $ 183.6 billion so far this year.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880820-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-20-88 0329EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-SpaceShuttle     08-20 0407</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Space Shuttle,0418</SECOND>
<HEAD>NASA Hopes Soon To Set Space Shuttle Launch Date</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By HOWARD BENEDICT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Aerospace Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CAPE CANAVERAL, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The third positive development for the space shuttle program in 10 days _ sealing a fuel line leak _ could lead <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> to announce a launch date soon for Discovery on the first post-Challenger flight. The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aeronautics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Space </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> has been aiming for a late September or early October liftoff and hopes to be able to establish the date by late next week for the often-delayed mission. Technicians bolted a clamshell-like device over the leak in a Discovery fuel line Friday and filled it with a sealing compound. A subsequent pressure test showed no additional leakage, but officials said they planned to monitor it for a few days. The leak of nitrogen tetroxide was detected July 14. Officials originally thought they would have to move Discovery off the launch pad and back to a hangar for repair, a move that could have delayed the flight by as much as two months. But engineers decided to cut holes in the rear wall of the shuttle's cargo bay to gain access to the leak The holes were cut Wednesday, and the technicians finished the job Friday. The work was delayed until after the launch pad test firing of Discovery's three liquid fuel main engines. That critical test, which certified the engines for flight, was conducted successfully Aug. 10. Another milestone was passed Thursday, when an intentionally flawed solid fuel booster rocket was test-fired for two minutes at the <ORGANIZATION> Morton </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Thiokol </ORGANIZATION> plant in <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION>. Officials said that while initial test results looked excellent, it would be several days before all the data were analyzed. The test-firing was the fifth and final prelaunch test for the redesigned booster, two of which are already attached to Discovery on the launch pad. A faulty joint in one of Challenger's two boosters triggered the explosion that destroyed the shuttle and killed its seven-member crew on Jan. 28, 1986. Meanwhile, engineers here continued to try to learn why a small amount of hydrogen leaked during the main engine test. It was detected in an area where electrical and fuel lines join the shuttle with its external fuel tank. The leak disappeared quickly and was not considered a flight safety hazard, but officials said they would like to understand why it happened. They expect to have test results next week.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880820-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-20-88 0406EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Korea     08-20 0566</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Korea,0583</SECOND>
<HEAD>North, South Deadlock After Talks and Blame Each Other</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PAUL SHIN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PANMUNJOM, Korea (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Delegates from <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> deadlocked today on peace measures and on sharing the Olympics during a second round of talks, and each side blamed the other for lack of progress. Neither side budged from their positions during today's session at the truce site in the Demilitarized Zone separating the nations. The communist <PERSON> North </PERSON> insisted on being a co-host at the Olympics. The South said it was impossible. They did agree to meet again Monday. `` <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> was insincere throughout the meeting,'' the North's chief delegate, <PERSON> Chon </PERSON> <PERSON> Kum </PERSON> <PERSON> Chol </PERSON>, told a press conference. The chief South Korean delegate, <PERSON> Park </PERSON> <PERSON> Joon-kyu </PERSON>, said any hope of progress depended on the North being more flexible. Park called on the North to give up its demand to be a co-host at the Olympics and simply agree to participate in the Games, which start in <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION> on Sept. 17. `` I still think the chance of <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> participating in the <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION> Games is one in a thousand,'' Park told reporters. The twp five-member teams met in the South Korean pavilion. On Friday, they met in the North Korean building. They shook hands and smiled at the start of the talks, but the mood was guarded. The two Koreas, technically still at war, are archenemies with hundreds of thousands of troops poised along the 150-mile border. The main purpose of the talks was to arrange a full-scale North-South Parliamentary session, but the two sides disagree on what that session should involve. South Korean delegates continued to insist on small delegations for Parliamentary talks instead of participation of the full legislatures of both sides as demanded by the North. The South said the North's plan is unworkable. The South said it would drop its demand for a presidential summit to be discussed. <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> wants the meeting to urgently address drawing up a non-aggression pact and its demand to be a co-host at the Olympics. The North Korean delegates were drawn from the rubber-stamp <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Peoples </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ' </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION>. The South Korean delegation consisted of two government <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION> lawmakers and a legislator from each of the three main opposition parties. The North is demanding to be a co-host at the Olympics to stave off a major political defeat. Both sides claim to be the sole legitimate government of <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>. The South sees its selection to hold the Olympics as international recognition of its claim. The International Olympic Committee says <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> can not share the Games because they are awarded to a single city. South Korean authorities fear the North may use terrorism to try to disrupt the Olympics. Previous, sporadic talks between the two sides since the early 1970s failed to make progress. The last talks collapsed in January 1986 when <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> pulled out to protest annual South Korean-U.S. military exercises. The <LOCATION> Korean </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Peninsula </LOCATION> was divided in 1945 by Soviet and <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> forces that ended the Japanese occupation at the end of World War II. <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> invaded the South in 1950 to start the Korean War, which ended in stalemate in 1953 without a peace treaty being signed. The South has evolved into a major economic power and started to move toward full democracy, while the North has remained one of the most isolated nations in the world.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880820-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-20-88 0414EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-CVN--NewOrleansReax Bjt   08-20 0654</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-CVN--New Orleans Reax, Bjt,0676</SECOND>
<HEAD>City Should Benefit From GOP Convention For 20 Years</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LINDA ASHTON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW ORLEANS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION>, looking to burnish its image, should reap benefits for many years from the exposure its prize city received while hosting the Republican National Convention, some of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION>' major boosters say. `` <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION> has never looked better; <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION> has never looked brighter,'' said <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Moffett </PERSON>, head of the Fortune 500 company <ORGANIZATION> Freeport-McMoRan </ORGANIZATION> and a key convention fund-raiser. The city rolled out its plushest red carpet for the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> visitors, with sumptuous parties, tasty native cuisine, riverboat rides and Gov. <PERSON> Buddy </PERSON> <PERSON> Roemer </PERSON> reminding everyone <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION> was polishing a tarnished image. `` Sooner or later, the message was going to come across that <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION> is not strictly a party town or a place for good food and music,'' said <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Orleans </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chamber </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION>. `` We are starting to do the right things to make this a viable economic center.'' `` It will probably have gains for <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION> for the next 20 years,'' said <PERSON> Mervin </PERSON> <PERSON> Trail </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION> businessman and another key fund-raiser. Complaints were few during the four-day convention that ended Thursday. But then, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION> handles <LOCATION> Mardi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gras </LOCATION> every year with 20 times as many visitors and a different kind of crowd, police said. `` At <LOCATION> Mardi </LOCATION> Gras ... it's a party crowd and there are a few more untoward incidents,'' said <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION> police Capt. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Hughes </PERSON>. `` It was very good as far as we're concerned.'' Suffocating humidity and 90-degree temperatures also made it too hot to misbehave, <PERSON> Hughes </PERSON> said. The subtropical weather and the sound system at the giant <ORGANIZATION> Louisiana </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Superdome </ORGANIZATION> drew most of the complaints. Technicians began adjusting the system after Sen. <PERSON> Barry </PERSON> <PERSON> Goldwater </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION>'s 1964 presidential nominee, said he could n't hear a word of President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s farewell speech Monday The complaints diminished during the week, but they did n't go away. `` It is not the Superdome system,'' said dome manager <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>, explaining that the Republicans installed their own. Some of the more conservative delegates were not charmed by <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION>' tolerance for the weird, the drunken and the sexy. `` Now that we have visited Sodom, where is Gomorrah?'' one <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> state delegate was reported asking. But others were seduced by the city's history, its laid-back attitudes and the mighty <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION>. `` Our goal was to put together one of the most successful conventions in history,'' said <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>. Lt. Gov. <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Hardy </PERSON> said he was hard pressed to find anyone who was n't enamored of the French Quarter, the streetcars and the oak-lined avenues. `` I do n't believe that we could have spent $ 1 billion in advertising and reaped the benefits equal to the fantastic free press, the free media, we are receiving,'' <PERSON> Hardy </PERSON> said. `` Fortunately, we've been given the opportunity to redeem ourselves after the world's fair fiasco.'' The 1984 World Exposition here was a delight for those who attended but a financial disaster because so many people stayed away. The state's image also has suffered because of the slump in <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION>'s energy-based economy and its history of shady politics. <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION>'s jobless rate has been No. 1 or No. 2 in the country the last three years. The state's storied corruption spans from the legendary <PERSON> Huey </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Long </PERSON> _ whose life was chronicled in fictionalized form in the Pulitzer Prize-winning novel `` All the King's Men'' _ to <PERSON> Roemer </PERSON>'s predecessor, <PERSON> Edwin </PERSON> <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON>, who spent much of his third term successfully defending himself against federal racketeering charges. <PERSON> Hardy </PERSON> said the city already is looking forward to hosting the Republicans, the Democrats or both four years from now. `` It's very seldom both parties have their convention in the same city,'' he noted. It happened in 1952 in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> and 1972 in <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION>, and <PERSON> Hardy </PERSON> hopes <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION> will claim that fame at the next 20-year interval, 1992. `` We're hoping history repeats itself,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880820-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-20-88 0432EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-BoyHero 1stLd-Writethru a0860 08-20 0277</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Boy Hero, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0860,0281</SECOND>
<HEAD>9-Year-Old Boy Revives Infant Brother</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: CORRECTS dateline.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>LAGUNA NIGUEL, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A 9-year-old boy rescued his baby brother from the bathtub and performed mouth-to-mouth resuscitation after he found the infant had stopped breathing, police said. When the 9-month-old child began to breathe again Friday, <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Swain </PERSON> called emergency number 911, then telephoned his mother at work, said Capt. <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Hayden </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Orange </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fire </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>. With all that done, the boy waited outside to guide paramedics to the right house in this community about 50 miles southeast of downtown <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Hayden </PERSON> said. `` I've never seen such a calm, cool, young man,'' <PERSON> Hayden </PERSON> said. `` He did it all and he did an excellent job of it. `` I have kids of my own and I kinda doubt they could do what <PERSON> John </PERSON> did. Most adults ca n't do what he did.'' The boys' babysitter could not speak English and apparently did n't realize what had to be done in the situation, <PERSON> Hayden </PERSON> said. `` We were thrilled to see someone that young so knowledgeable,'' <PERSON> Hayden </PERSON> said. `` He was real instrumental in saving his brother's life. It was not immediately known where <PERSON> John </PERSON> learned to give mouth-to-mouth resuscitation, <PERSON> Hayden </PERSON> said. A message left on the family's answering machine Friday evening was not immediately returned. The infant, <PERSON> Bill </PERSON>, was taken to <ORGANIZATION> Mission </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Community </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION> in nearby <LOCATION> Mission </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Viejo </LOCATION>, where he was treated and released, said nursing supervisor <PERSON> Sue </PERSON> <PERSON> Donofrio </PERSON>. <PERSON> Hayden </PERSON> said another boy, age 3 or 4, also was present but was `` just in awe of everything.'' The fire captain said he would recommend a bravery certificate for the 9-year-old hero.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880820-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-20-88 0433EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Canada-Politics     08-20 0509</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Canada-Politics,0524</SECOND>
<HEAD>Mulroney Government Hit By Kickback Allegations</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JEFF BRADLEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>TORONTO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Two legislators from Prime Minister <PERSON> Brian </PERSON> <PERSON> Mulroney </PERSON>'s Conservative government say kickbacks are a way of life in the administration _ charges that could hurt <PERSON> Mulroney </PERSON> in elections expected next month. The allegations, which surfaced Thursday and Friday, are political fodder for opposition parties. Polls show the opposition <ORGANIZATION> Liberal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> with a narrow overall lead, followed by the Conservatives and the socialist <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>. The government said the accusations, by a disgruntled former <ORGANIZATION> Cabinet </ORGANIZATION> member and another Conservative member of <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION>, were unsubstantiated. <PERSON> Suzanne </PERSON> <PERSON> Blais-Grenier </PERSON>, a Conservative member of <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Montreal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rosemount </ORGANIZATION>, was quoted in the <LOCATION> Montreal </LOCATION> daily <ORGANIZATION> La </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Presse </ORGANIZATION> as saying that companies routinely pay kickbacks to get federal contracts in <LOCATION> Quebec </LOCATION>. Another Conservative member from <LOCATION> Montreal </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Vincent </PERSON> <PERSON> Della </PERSON> <PERSON> Noce </PERSON>, was quoted in the <LOCATION> Ottawa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Citizen </LOCATION> as saying the most difficult part of his job was to `` stay clean.'' Ms. <PERSON> Blais-Grenier </PERSON>, who resigned as junior transport minister in 1985 in a dispute over aid to <LOCATION> Montreal </LOCATION> oil refineries, said she lacked the detailed proof for police charges. But she called for an impartial commission to investigate federal contracts. Ms. <PERSON> Blais-Grenier </PERSON> is under pressure from party leaders in <LOCATION> Quebec </LOCATION> not to seek re-election. Other Conservative legislators from the province met Friday to consider expelling her from the caucus. <PERSON> Della </PERSON> <PERSON> Noce </PERSON> was quoted as saying, `` I could put a dozen people in prison.'' But on Friday, <PERSON> Della </PERSON> <PERSON> Noce </PERSON> said he had no proof and said he had not expressed himself clearly in the original interview. <PERSON> Mulroney </PERSON> was absent from the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commons </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Ottawa </LOCATION> when opposition leaders hammered the government about the alleged patronage. He is expected to call an election next month, a year before his five-year term expires, because of <ORGANIZATION> Liberal </ORGANIZATION> plans to hold up ratification of the Canada-U.S. Free Trade Agreement, which is to take effect on Jan. 1. Liberal <PERSON> Raymond </PERSON> <PERSON> Garneau </PERSON>, a leading <LOCATION> Quebec </LOCATION> legislator, said: `` I've never seen such serious admissions on the part of a government.'' But Solicitor General <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Kelleher </PERSON> said: `` We as a government have no information whatsoever to substantiate the allegations.'' The <ORGANIZATION> Royal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Canadian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mounted </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION> interviewed Ms. <PERSON> Blais-Grenier </PERSON> on Friday, and Sgt. <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Watts </PERSON> said she `` had no details of any activity which could permit the <ORGANIZATION> RCMP </ORGANIZATION> to initiate a criminal investigation.'' He said the <ORGANIZATION> Mounties </ORGANIZATION> had not yet spoken with <PERSON> Della </PERSON> <PERSON> Noce </PERSON>. Police confirmed they have asked the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> to interview officials at <ORGANIZATION> Metropolitan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Life </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Insurance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> headquarters in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> in connection with a 2-year-old investigation of possible kickbacks in a $ 820,000 Canadian government contract to lease office space from the company. Liberal leader <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Turner </PERSON>, poised to take over as prime minister if his party wins the election, told the Commons that a royal commission should `` investigate the whole course of conduct of this government.'' But Deputy Prime Minister <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Mazankowski </PERSON> dismissed the suggestion and said the government had moved quickly in the past by ousting ministers and ordering inquiries when there was `` clear evidence of wrongdoing.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880820-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-20-88 0441EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-FBI-Hispanics     08-20 0528</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-FBI-Hispanics,0546</SECOND>
<HEAD>Plaintiff: Discrimination Exists Systemwide In FBI</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By HOLDEN LEWIS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>EL PASO, Texas (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The lead plaintiff in a class-action suit against the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> says bias is so institutionally ingrained at the agency that even he treated fellow Hispanics unfairly. `` Bigotry is not the problem,'' <PERSON> Bernardo </PERSON> `` <PERSON> Matt </PERSON><PERSON> '' </PERSON> <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> testified Friday in <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>. `` What we're talking about is a system of discrimination. As a supervisor, I've been part of that system. I'm not talking about a particular person. I'm talking about an organization.'' <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> and the 310 Hispanic agents who joined him in the lawsuit contend the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> discriminates against Hispanics in hiring, promotion, assignments and discipline. They are seeking damages and changes in <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> policy. About 400 of the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION>'s 9,000 agents are Hispanic. <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> Personnel Director <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Rarity </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> testified earlier that the agency does not discriminate against Hispanics. <PERSON> Perez </PERSON>, who filed the suit in January 1987, was one of the last witnesses to testify for the plaintiffs in what is scheduled to be a two-week, non-jury trial. The plaintiffs rested Friday after five days of testimony and about 40 witnesses; the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> is scheduled to start calling witnesses for its defense Monday. During the first week of the trial, agents testified that Hispanics are assigned a disproportionate number of Spanish-language wiretaps and temporary out-of-town assignments. Because those assignments are not considered as prestigious or difficult as street investigations, Hispanics are given lower performance appraisals than non-Hispanics, agents testified. Other agents testified that Hispanics are more likely to be given dangerous undercover assignments, but that they do n't receive the same recognition for that work as non-Hispanics. Hispanics are assumed to know Spanish even when they do n't, and non-Hispanic Spanish-speakers are much less likely than Hispanics to be assigned low-glamor or highly dangerous jobs, according to testimony. <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> said he had no choice but to engage in such discriminatory actions because the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> is structured that way and because the agency has not tried hard enough to hire bilingual agents or teach agents Spanish. Every Hispanic agent who testified expressed fear of retaliation for cooperating with the lawsuit. During three hours of testimony Friday, <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> described what he called a systematic pattern of discrimination against him. <PERSON> Perez </PERSON>, second-in-command at the <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Paso </LOCATION> bureau, said he first noticed discrimination when he was attending the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> academy at <LOCATION> Quantico </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION> `` One time the assistant director called me into his office and said, ` What would you say if I called you a blankety-blank blank blank Mexican?' I said, ` I would say you're an ignorant person.' `` He said he wanted to know because they would be handing me a weapon and he did n't want me flying off the handle and hurting people.'' <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> testified his problems intensified in 1982, after he was demoted from the top post in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Juan </LOCATION> and sent to <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>, where he was the No. 2 man under agent <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Bretzing </PERSON>. <PERSON> Bretzing </PERSON> kept <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> uninformed about investigations and repeatedly harassed him, <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Bretzing </PERSON> demoted <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> twice, before finally forcing him to <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Paso </LOCATION>. `` Butte and <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Paso </LOCATION> are considered dumping grounds for agents who are malcontents,'' <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> testified.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880820-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-20-88 0442EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Soviet-Zia     08-20 0275</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Soviet-Zia,0281</SECOND>
<HEAD>Soviets Report Pakistan's Suspicions of Sabotage</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Pakistan, Bjt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MOSCOW (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The official <ORGANIZATION> Tass </ORGANIZATION> news agency reported today that <LOCATION> Pakistani </LOCATION> authorities suspect sabotage in the plane crash that killed President <PERSON> Mohammed </PERSON> <PERSON> Zia </PERSON> <PERSON> ul-Haq </PERSON>, but it did not mention that <PERSON> Zia </PERSON>'s son suspects Kremlin involvement. <PERSON> Zia </PERSON> and 29 others were killed Wednesday when the C-130 military transport plane they were in exploded and crashed. The blast also killed <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. Ambassador <PERSON> Arnold </PERSON> <PERSON> Raphel </PERSON>, several Pakistani generals and other senior military men. `` It is supposed that this action was perfectly planned and faultlessly executed, the newspaper <ORGANIZATION> Muslim </ORGANIZATION> points out,'' said <ORGANIZATION> Tass </ORGANIZATION>'s <LOCATION> Islamabad </LOCATION> correspondent in a dispatch. `` An explosive device might have been installed in the plane.'' But <ORGANIZATION> Tass </ORGANIZATION> was silent on comments made Friday in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> by <PERSON> Zia </PERSON>'s eldest son concerning possible Soviet involvement <PERSON> Ijaz </PERSON> <PERSON> ul-Haq </PERSON> said, `` Some of the superpowers may be involved in it. Naturally, I would think about the Soviets at this time.'' <PERSON> Zia </PERSON> was a strong supporter of guerrillas fighting the Soviet-backed government of <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>, giving them bases in <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> to conduct military operations in <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>. Soviet officials had accused him repeatedly of violating <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> accords that provided for the withdrawal of Soviet troops from <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Tass </ORGANIZATION> also reported on some of the theories about the crash. The dispatch said some officials believe the plane might have been hit by a missile fired from the ground. `` But all officials believe the air crash was not accidental,'' <ORGANIZATION> Tass </ORGANIZATION> said. <ORGANIZATION> Tass </ORGANIZATION> also noted a <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> delegation arrived in <LOCATION> Islamabad </LOCATION> for the funeral of the 64-year-old leader. The delegation was led by <PERSON> Vitautas </PERSON> <PERSON> Astrauskas </PERSON>, vice president of the presidium of the Supreme Soviet.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880820-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-20-88 0449EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-WildfireRdp Bjt   08-20 0695</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Wildfire Rdp, Bjt,0716</SECOND>
<HEAD>Firefighters Battling Montana Wildfires Brace For High Winds</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto BIL1</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By FAITH CONROY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>HELENA, Mont. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Firefighters braced for 40 mph winds today as they battled an 11-day-old, 27,000-acre wildfire south of <PERSON> Helena </PERSON> that consumed at least 10 homes and 30 head of cattle. Meanwhile, dozens of other fires _ some of them potentially serious _ broke out in <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION>, state and federal officials said. In <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION>, firefighters at <ORGANIZATION> Yellowstone </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Park </ORGANIZATION> also were expected to encounter high winds, and a team began investigating a helicopter crash that killed one person in <ORGANIZATION> Bighorn </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> during firefighting efforts. Wildfires continued to rage in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION>. The devastating fire near <PERSON> Helena </PERSON> cooled somewhat Friday after dramatic runs earlier in the week. The fire turned just before reaching a mountain subdivision with scores of residences and surrounding ranches. `` We're looking pretty good,'' said <PERSON> Anne </PERSON> <PERSON> Jeffery </PERSON>, a fire information officer. She said the fire had grown by 600 acres Friday, but that was a small increase compared with the 7,000 - and 15,000-acre runs the two previous nights With a part of the fire heading southeast toward flatter land, officials said they would have more of a chance of checking its advance once it left the rugged mountain ridges. Another portion of the fire was moving into even rougher country to the south, but there was no danger of damage to structures there. `` There's no more homes in the way,'' said <PERSON> Art </PERSON> <PERSON> Howell </PERSON> of the Inter-agency Fire Dispatch Center. `` But that depends a lot on the weather, and the wind is a big factor.'' The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Weather </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> forecast winds gusting to 40 mph today. Fires were burning over thousands of acres elsewhere in <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION>, many of the blazes resulting from lightning strikes earlier in the week. At least one summer residence was destroyed and others threatened in a small but dangerous blaze that erupted in logging slash Friday afternoon about 12 miles northwest of Butte, said <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Cullen </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Deerlodge </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION>. Other fires were reported in southeastern <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION>, including one that threatened to overrun a ranch in southern <LOCATION> Bighorn </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> near the <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION> line. Some of the 1,000 firefighters on three fires that have burned 14,000 acres of scattered timber and grasslands near Lame Deer in southeastern <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION> were released from lines Friday, and officials said those blazes should be controlled by Sunday evening. In north-central <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION>, 980 firefighters put finishing touches on a 4,500-acre fire on the Rocky Boys Indian Reservation. Spokesman <PERSON> Chris </PERSON> <PERSON> Comstrock </PERSON> said the fire should be fully encircled by tonight if the weather cooperates. About 40 smaller lightning-caused fires burned Friday in the <LOCATION> Flathead </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> drainage of northwestern <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION>. In <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Yellowstone </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman <PERSON> Amy </PERSON> <PERSON> Vanderbilt </PERSON> said firefighters began removing debris and flammable materials from the structures in the <LOCATION> Norris </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Junction </LOCATION> area to prepare for the arrival of a 74,000-acre fire. `` If the forecast brings winds as anticipated, we expect -LRB- the fire -RRB- will reach <PERSON> Norris </PERSON> -LRB- today -RRB-,'' she said. The blaze is one of several burning in the nation's oldest national park. In <ORGANIZATION> Bighorn </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION>, investigators representing the agencies fighting a 5,400-acre blaze on Friday reached the site of the fatal helicopter crash, which left its three other occupants injured. The privately owned helicopter, under contract with the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>, crashed in a rugged wilderness area west of the fire's western boundary. A wildfire set by an arsonist in the <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jacinto </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mountains </LOCATION> of <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> charred 1,237 acres but firefighters encircled it, while a blaze burning out of control blackened at least 300 acres in the <ORGANIZATION> San </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bernardino </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION>. The arson fire, on part of the <LOCATION> Morongo </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Indian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Reservation </LOCATION> about 95 miles east of downtown <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>, was contained Friday night and full control was expected by early today, the <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forestry </ORGANIZATION> said. Firefighters contained a 580-acre southern <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION> brush fire and hoped to bring the blaze under control by the weekend, but crews were being sent to another fire burning in the <LOCATION> Wahwah </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mountains </LOCATION> about 50 miles northwest of <LOCATION> Cedar </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. Firefighters in <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Challis </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> squelched a nearly 14,000-acre fire and were being sent elsewhere.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880820-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-20-88 0520EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Quayle 1stLd-Writethru a0866 08-20 0812</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Quayle, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0866,800</SECOND>
<HEAD>Quayle's Hometown Crowd Angered by Questions About His Military
Record</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDs: INSERTs two new grafs after 7th graf to update with
Washington Post report Quayle passed physical; pkup 8th graf pvs:
``The senator xxx; trims last 2 grafs pvs for space</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By EILEEN PUTMAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>HUNTINGTON, Ind. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 What began as a hometown salute to Sen. <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> and the Republican ticket turned into mass catcalls and jeers as thousands of <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> supporters reacted angrily to reporters' questions about whether he had strings pulled to avoid the draft during the Vietnam War. As the audience chanted `` Quayle! Quayle!'' the 41-year-old senator said there was nothing improper in the way he entered the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> in 1969. The Republican vice presidential nominee acknowledged that a family friend made calls on his behalf after he expressed interest in joining the Guard but insisted: `` I got in fairly.'' <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> said he resented implied slurs on his patriotism by media reports of the controversy and said it should help, not hurt, him with the voters. `` You're going to be surprised at how outraged people and families that identify with the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> around <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> are going to be towards these accusations,'' <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> said as the crowd cheered. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> campaign officials denied that the event had been orchestrated to include the crowd in <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>'s first detailed answers to questions about his military record. But the event provided another example of how Vice President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s running mate has seemed to overshadow the campaign. Meanwhile, <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> reported in Saturday editions that <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> passed an armed forces physical examination on April 9, 1969, which meant that he would have been eligible to be drafted at any time after his May 25 graduation day. He was called to take the physical by his local draft board while he was still a <ORGANIZATION> DePauw </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> senior, the <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> said. He entered the National Guard on May 19, but the newspaper quoted Guard officials as saying they were still reviewing <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>'s military records, presumably showing when he applied to join, and could not release them The senator had promised to respond Friday to questions that have dogged him since he was picked by <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> as his running mate. But the opportunity provided by <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> aides came at the end of a rousing rally for the popular senator at a courthouse square across from his father's newspaper. After <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> shook hands with his supporters, aides brought him before a throng of reporters at an outdoor news conference, which was piped over an public address system. Boos and hoots of `` b-o-r-i-n-g'' sang out across the courtyard as <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> was asked about the sequence of events that led to his entry into the Guard. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> said that during his senior year in college, as he pondered future military service, he turned to his parents for advice `` like any 22 year old.'' He faced the loss of his college deferment after graduation. The family discussed the matter with <PERSON> Wendell </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Phillippi </PERSON>, a former commander of the <ORGANIZATION> Indiana </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> who worked for <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>'s grandfather at the <ORGANIZATION> Indianapolis </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> said, in an account that was similar to that <PERSON> Phillippi </PERSON> has provided to reporters. `` I did not ask him to make any calls. I told him I was interested in getting into the <ORGANIZATION> Indiana </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION>. ... I would assume that calls would be made,'' <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Phillippi </PERSON>, who has said he contacted the Guard on <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>'s behalf, `` knew that I wanted to get into the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> and I hoped he would help me,'' <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> said `` I did not join to avoid service in <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> because by joining the <ORGANIZATION> Indiana </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION>, I could have gone to <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> if my unit had been called up,'' <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> said. The senator said he would not have done things differently if he had known he would be running for vice president. He said he did not consider the matter an embarrassment for the ticket and had not offered to remove himself from the race. `` Vice President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> agrees with me that it is patriotic to serve in the <ORGANIZATION> Indiana </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> and he's proud of my service,'' <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> said. At the rally, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> praised <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> as `` a young man of vision, of character.'' But it was <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> for whom the crowd reserved its greatest enthusiasm. Scores of residents dotted the road to <LOCATION> Huntington </LOCATION> from the <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Wayne </LOCATION> airport, and <LOCATION> Huntington </LOCATION>'s police chief estimated the crowd at the rally to be as many as 20,000 people. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> told them: `` We have the values, the character, the work ethic of all small towns.'' `` My roots, my values, my friends, my neighborhoods _ it is indeed a proud day, but most importantly, I am just proud of <LOCATION> Huntington </LOCATION>,'' he said. The crowd roared when he added: `` We love the National Guard.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880820-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-20-88 0532EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Superconductivity 1stLd-Writethru a0412 08-20 0489</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Superconductivity, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0412,0499</SECOND>
<HEAD>Report of Superconductor Advance Met Wit Skepticism</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: SUBS 2nd graf to delete ``Chinese'' to conform to style.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By MALCOLM RITTER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Science Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Scientists in <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION> say a new material shows possible superconductivity at up to 66 degrees above the current record temperature, but other scientists have reacted with caution. The new report does not include a crucial test for proving superconductivity, so the material should be considered only a possible superconductor, the other experts said. Superconductivity is the ability of some materials to conduct electricity without loss to resistance. If the materials can be made practical, they may lead to such advances as smaller, more powerful computers and magnetically levitated high-speed trains. Materials created so far must be chilled before they will superconduct. Researchers are trying to develop materials with as high a superconducting temperature as possible, to minimize the expense of cooling and so make superconductors more practical. The new report from <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION> says five samples of the material showed no electrical resistance at temperatures above minus 208 degrees Fahrenheit. One sample showed no resistance at minus 168 degrees, the researchers said. The current widely accepted record is minus 234 degrees. The new research is disclosed in `` High Tc Update,'' a newsletter published by the <ORGANIZATION> Ames </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Laboratory </ORGANIZATION> at <ORGANIZATION> Iowa </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> under contract to the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION>. `` Tc'' refers to the temperature at which a material begins to superconduct. The newsletter obtained a copy of a paper by researchers at the <ORGANIZATION> Industrial </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Technology </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tsing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hua </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, both in <LOCATION> Hsinchu </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION>. The researchers reported their material includes the same ingredients as the current record-holding compound: thallium, calcium, barium, copper and oxygen. Some samples that conducted electricity without resistance at temperatures above minus 208 degrees eventually lost that ability. Others that could do so above minus 226 degrees still had that ability after a week, the researchers said. The reason for the changes in performance in some samples has not yet been pinpointed, they said. Superconductivity researcher <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Chu </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Houston </ORGANIZATION> said he found no errors in the reported resistance measurements when he visited the researchers recently in <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION>. But he also said he knew of no measurements of the magnetic characteristics of the new material. Superconducting materials give off a characteristic magnetic signal when exposed to a magnetic field, and existence of this signal is considered a crucial test of whether a material is a true superconductor. Without a report of that measurement, the material should be considered only a possible superconductor, he said. Similarly, physicist <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Clem </PERSON> at the Ames laboratory said the manuscript from the <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION> researchers is `` very convincing,'' but that the lack of magnetic measurements is disturbing. <PERSON> Clem </PERSON> said he ` would n't get excited'' about the new material until such measurements are reported and the experimental results are duplicated by other researchers.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880820-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-20-88 0532EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Spain-BusCrash     08-20 0136</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Spain-Bus Crash,0138</SECOND>
<HEAD>Five Dead, 30 Injured When Bus Overturns</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BILBAO, Spain (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A bus carrying West German and Portuguese nationals veered off a highway and rolled into a ravine today, killing five people and injuring 30, police said. The names and nationalities of the dead and injured were not immediately known, but the official said most were West Germans or Portuguese. He said the injured had been taken to six hospitals in <LOCATION> Vizcaya </LOCATION> and Alava provinces for treatment for a variety of injuries, most of them serious. The white Mercedes bus with West German licence plates had been near <LOCATION> Altube </LOCATION>, near this northern city, when it overturned, the official said, speaking on condition of anonymity. Rescue workers took more than an hour to free all of the injured from the wreckage, he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880820-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-20-88 0433EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-PalauAssassination     08-20 0239</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Palau Assassination,0248</SECOND>
<HEAD>URGENT</HEAD>
<HEAD>President Salii Fatally Wounded By Unknown Gunman</HEAD>
<DATELINE>KOROR, Palau (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Lazarus </PERSON> <PERSON> Salii </PERSON> was fatally wounded today by a gunman who entered his home. It was the second presidential assassination in this western <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> island chain in three years. <PERSON> Salii </PERSON>, in his mid 50's, was shot once in the head in the living room of his home in the capital city of <LOCATION> Koror </LOCATION>, said police Officer <PERSON> Theodore </PERSON> <PERSON> Obak </PERSON>. <PERSON> Salii </PERSON> was alone in the house at the time of the 1 p.m. shooting, while a security guard and a maid were outside, <PERSON> Obak </PERSON> said. The president was pronouced dead an hour later at <ORGANIZATION> McDonald </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Memorial </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION>, he said. A .38 - caliber handgun believed to be the murder weapon was found at the house, <PERSON> Obak </PERSON> <PERSON> Salii </PERSON> had not received any death threats recently, the officer said. Vice President <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Remengesau </PERSON> Sr. assumed control of the nation, <PERSON> Obak </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Salii </PERSON> was elected in August 1985 to succeed President <PERSON> Haruo </PERSON> <PERSON> Remeliik </PERSON>, who was shot to death at his home June 30, 1985. Three men were charged with <PERSON> Remeliik </PERSON>'s murder, but were acquitted at trial. <PERSON> Palau </PERSON>, with a population of about 15,000, is located 4,593 miles from <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Palau </PERSON> is the last political entity of the Trust Territory of the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Islands </LOCATION>, which the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has administered under a <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> mandate since the late 1940s. It has been trying to gain independence from the trust territory.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880820-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-20-88 0538EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Taiwan-Earthquake     08-20 0115</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Taiwan-Earthquake,0117</SECOND>
<HEAD>Strong Earthquake Jolts Eastern Taiwan</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TAIPEI, Taiwan (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A strong earthquake centered off the coast of <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION> shook the island early today, but there were no reports of casualties or damage, the <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Weather </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> said. The earthquake struck at 2:10 a.m. and registered 6.7 on the <PERSON> Richter </PERSON> scale, the bureau said. The epicenter was at sea about 65 miles southeast of the coastal city of <LOCATION> Ilan </LOCATION> in eastern <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION>. The tremor was felt in the capital, <LOCATION> Taipei </LOCATION>, where residents reported their houses shook violently, the bureau said. The Richter scale measures ground motion as recorded on seismographs. An earthquake of magnitude 6 can cause severe damage in a populated area.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880820-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-20-88 0540EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Bangladesh-Floods     08-20 0122</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bangladesh-Floods,0124</SECOND>
<HEAD>Four Drown In Flooding In Northwestern Bangladesh</HEAD>
<DATELINE>DHAKA, Bangladesh (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Floods in northwestern <LOCATION> Bangladesh </LOCATION> have killed four people and left at least 50,000 people homeless, officials said today. The four drowned Friday when their boat capsized while sailing to a relief center for the homeless in <LOCATION> Chapainawabganj </LOCATION> district, about 75 miles from <LOCATION> Dhaka </LOCATION>, the capital, said the officials, speaking on condition of anonymity. The homeless in <LOCATION> Chapainawabganj </LOCATION> and neighboring <LOCATION> Rajbari </LOCATION> district are being housed in relief centers and school buildings or staying on highways, the officials said. The official <ORGANIZATION> Bangladesh </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sangbad </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sangstha </ORGANIZATION> news agency said the <LOCATION> Padma </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> was about 22 inches above flood stage. The northwestern region has been drenched since annual monsoon rains began in July.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880820-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-20-88 0509EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-GulfShipping     08-20 0494</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Gulf Shipping,0510</SECOND>
<HEAD>Iraqi Merchant Vessels Sail Gulf for First Time in Eight Years</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Iran-Iraq, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By NABILA MEGALLI</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MANAMA, Bahrain (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Iraqi </LOCATION> merchant vessels sailed the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> and the Gulf of <LOCATION> Oman </LOCATION> for the first time in eight years today under protection of a cease-fire in the Iran-Iraq war. Iraqi Oil Minister <PERSON> Issam </PERSON> <PERSON> Abdel-Rahim </PERSON> said the <LOCATION> Ain </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Zalah </LOCATION>, a government-owned 35,338-ton oil tanker, took on cargo and left <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> to sail the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> `` a few hours after the truce began'' at 7 a.m. -LRB- 11 p.m. EDT -RRB-. <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> often attacked shipping during the war, leaving hundreds of vessels damaged or destroyed in the gulf. Iraqi shipping through the gulf stopped shortly after the outbreak of the war in September 1980. It relied on pipelines for the export of its oil and on shipments via <LOCATION> Kuwait </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION> for its commercial trade. In his statement, carried by the official <ORGANIZATION> Iraqi </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> and monitored in <LOCATION> Nicosia </LOCATION>, the oil minister did not say where the vessel was loaded or from where it sailed. `` Some people were betting that <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> would not be able to renew its oil exports through the gulf for months or years after the halt of the war,'' he said. `` But here we are, and within a few hours, already launching our first shuttle.'' He did not disclose the destination of <ORGANIZATION> Ain </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Zalah </ORGANIZATION> nor mention another ship, the <PERSON> Khawla </PERSON>, which shipping executives said sailed earlier today from a <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arab </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Emirates </LOCATION> port in the <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Oman </LOCATION> toward the gulf. The <PERSON> Khawla </PERSON> honked its horns as it began its northbound voyage from the port of Fujairah toward the <LOCATION> Iraqi </LOCATION> port of <LOCATION> Basra </LOCATION> almost immediately after the truce began, shipping executives said. One of the shipping executives monitoring spillovers of the war on gulf shipping said: `` There has been nothing special, everything is quiet. ... let's see if it lasts.'' The London-based <ORGANIZATION> Lloyd </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Shipping </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Intelligence </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Unit </ORGANIZATION> says 546 commercial vessels have been damaged in the so-called `` tanker war.'' <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> attacked Iranian-chartered ships and <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> retaliated by attacking neutral shipping since <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>'s port of <LOCATION> Basra </LOCATION> was shut down during the war. <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON>'s authoritative register of vessels lists the <PERSON> Khawla </PERSON> as a 3,985-ton cargo vessel that could also be used as a tank-landing troop ship.'' The <PERSON> Idrissi </PERSON> is not listed. The <PERSON> Khawla </PERSON>, which the executives said has an Iraqi captain and a 21-man crew on board, would first sail through a 100-mile stretch from the Gulf of <LOCATION> Oman </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Hormuz </LOCATION>. The vessel would then sail up the gulf to the southern <LOCATION> Iraqi </LOCATION> port of <LOCATION> Basra </LOCATION>, 600 miles from <LOCATION> Hormuz </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> navy </ORGANIZATION> chief, Rear Adm. <PERSON> Mohammad </PERSON> <PERSON> Malekzadegan </PERSON>, said <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> will continue to search vessels in the gulf until `` the establishment of comprehensive peace'' between the two countries. Iranian and <LOCATION> Iraqi </LOCATION> delegations are scheduled to begin negotiations in <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> next week. <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> has intercepted hundreds of commercial vessels in the past years, searching for Iraq-bound war-related cargo.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880820-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-20-88 0514EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Iran-Iraq 1stLd-Writethru a0882 08-20 0786</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Iran-Iraq, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0882,0810</SECOND>
<HEAD>U.N.-Monitored Cease-Fire Takes Effect</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: SUBS 3rd graf, `Official media...' and inserts 3 grafs after
17th, ```Our bitter...'' to update with Iraqi vessels sailing gulf.
Pick up 18th pvs, ``Direct peace...''</NOTE>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MONA ZIADE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NICOSIA, Cyprus (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A cease-fire between <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> took hold this morning after hundreds of <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> observers moved into position along the war front to monitor the first truce in eight years of war. Peace officially began at 7 a.m. -LRB- 11 p.m. EDT -RRB-. Official media in the two countries carried no reports of any violations or other incidents along their common 730-mile border. For the first time in eight, years <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> resumed shipping in the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION>. Iraqis marched in the streets of <LOCATION> Baghdad </LOCATION> and in towns throughout their country late Friday, celebrating what <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>'s media called that nation's `` victory'' in the conflict. In <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION>, acting Commander-in-Chief <PERSON> Hashemi </PERSON> <PERSON> Rafsanjani </PERSON> warned that <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> might not want peace and that if it renewed hostilities, it would face a much stronger <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> said it was reopening the international airport in the war-battered southern city of <LOCATION> Basra </LOCATION> and announced that merchant ships will soon sail into the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> for the first time since the early months of the Iran-Iraq war. As night fell Friday, tens of thousands of people took to the streets and public parks of <LOCATION> Baghdad </LOCATION>, many waving portraits of President <PERSON> Saddam </PERSON> <PERSON> Hussein </PERSON> and chanting slogans in praise of peace. `` It is the happiest day in my life,'' said <PERSON> Alaa </PERSON>, an 18-year-old on <LOCATION> Karada </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Street </LOCATION>, a main artery in downtown <LOCATION> Baghdad </LOCATION>. He said he was due to be conscripted to the front in January. About 150 unarmed Blue Berets from the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Iran-Iraq </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Military </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Observer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Group </ORGANIZATION> were deployed along the <LOCATION> Iraqi </LOCATION> side of the border to monitor the truce, worked out during talks between <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> Secretary of State <PERSON> Javier </PERSON> <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Cuellar </PERSON> and Iranian and <LOCATION> Iraqi </LOCATION> leaders. <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION> radio, monitored in <LOCATION> Cyprus </LOCATION>, said 200 <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> observers would monitor the truce from the Iranian side. The officers were drawn from 24 countries. The <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> has set a $ 75.6 million budget for the mission. <PERSON> Rafsanjani </PERSON>, who also is <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION> speaker and a powerful protege of <PERSON> Ayatollah </PERSON> <PERSON> Ruhollah </PERSON> <PERSON> Khomeini </PERSON>, said in a Friday prayer sermon: `` We are facing two paths, war and peace. We chose peace, but we are not sure about <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>. If the enemy wants to continue the war, it will continue much more seriously.'' <PERSON> Rafsanjani </PERSON> also noted that `` Iranian forces have become much stronger and more experienced. This war was a great help to the export of our revolution and all the world realized that <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> resisted without any help.'' The Iraqi general command, in a statement carried by Iraqi radio and television, also said <LOCATION> Baghdad </LOCATION>'s forces would abide by the cease-fire `` conscientiously and responsibly.'' It expressed hope for better relations with <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> but added: `` Our bitter experience, and the sea of blood that the Iranian aggression caused, make it our responsibility not to deal with <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> on the basis of wishful thinking but on the basis of reality so that we are not cheated again.'' <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>'s oil minister, <PERSON> Issam </PERSON> <PERSON> Abdel-Rahim </PERSON> said <PERSON> Ain </PERSON> <PERSON> Zalah </PERSON>, a government-owned 35,338-ton oil tanker, loaded up and sailed down the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> `` a few hours after the truce began.'' Another Iraqi ship, the <PERSON> Khawla </PERSON>, left the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arab </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Emirates </LOCATION> port of Fujairah in the <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Oman </LOCATION> and headed north for the <LOCATION> Iraqi </LOCATION> port of <LOCATION> Basra </LOCATION> in the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> almost immediately after the truce began, said shipping executives speaking on condition of anonymity. <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> often attacked shipping during the war, leaving hundreds of vessels damaged or destroyed in the gulf. Direct peace talks between the foreign ministers of <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> open Thursday in <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION>, mediated by <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Cuellar </PERSON>. The <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> talks will focus on the peace plan decribed in Security Council Resolution 598. The resolution calls for the cease-fire, withdrawal of troops to their own territory, exchange of prisoners of war, direct peace talks, and establishment of an impartial commmission to establish responsibility for the outbreak of the conflict. The resolution was passed in July 1987 and accepted by <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> at that time. <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> finally accepted in last month, clearing the way for the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> talks that led to the truce. Most Western estimates of the number of people killed since the conflict broke out in September 1980 range from a half million to 1 million, with some figures even higher. The countries participating in the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> peacekeeping force are <LOCATION> Argentina </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Austria </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Bangladesh </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Denmark </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Finland </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ghana </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Indonesia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Kenya </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Malaysia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Zealand </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Nigeria </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Norway </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Senegal </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Sweden </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Turkey </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Yugoslavia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Zambia </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880820-0025 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-20-88 0544EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-AirlineLayoffs     08-20 0388</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Airline Layoffs,410</SECOND>
<HEAD>Major Layoff Coming at Continental Airlines, Chairman Says</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Continental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION>, plagued by losses in recent months, is planning a layoff of up to 1,000 pilots, flight attendants and other employees, its chairman says. Chairman <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Lorzenzo </PERSON> disclosed the plan here Friday outside a court hearing at which he defended plans for a major layoff at <ORGANIZATION> Continental </ORGANIZATION>'s sister <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Lorenzo </PERSON>, also chairman of <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, which owns both <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Continental </ORGANIZATION>, said a formal announcement of the <ORGANIZATION> Continental </ORGANIZATION> layoff would come in the next few days along with the carrier's new fall schedule. He told reporters the layoff would involve 2 percent to 6 percent of the company's 36,000 employees and include flight attendants as well as some management personnel. Between 300 and 500 pilots would be involved, <PERSON> Lorenzo </PERSON> said. <ORGANIZATION> Continental </ORGANIZATION> posted a net loss of $ 231 million in the first six months of this year and announced earlier that there would be service cutbacks. At the hearing, <PERSON> Lorenzo </PERSON> said its was necessary to lay off some 4,000 employees and cut back service at Miami-based Eastern. The cuts, which would curtail service to 14 cities, were announced earlier but have been blocked thus far under terms of a temporary restraining order issued by <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> Barrington </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Parker </PERSON> at the request of three unions that represent <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION> employees. <PERSON> Lorenzo </PERSON> said the cuts were needed to save the financially troubled line. `` If <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION>'s management is not permitted to take the actions to save this company, then <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION> may run out of cash,'' <PERSON> Lorenzo </PERSON> said. He denied suggestions by attorneys for the employees that he has been attempting to engage in so-called union busting by transferring <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION>'s assets to <ORGANIZATION> Continental </ORGANIZATION>. He also said there was no plan to merge the lines. The cutbacks represent an effort `` to stabilize the company ... and decrease the losses,'' <PERSON> Lorenzo </PERSON> said. Union attorneys did question <PERSON> Lorenzo </PERSON> about the draft of a speech that he was to give to Japanese investors in 1986 after <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> bought Eastern. It said the purchase gave <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> leverage over the union. `` Eastern's airplanes can be repainted and moved over to <ORGANIZATION> Continental </ORGANIZATION> where they will be flown by non-union pilots,'' it said. <PERSON> Lorenzo </PERSON> said an investment banking firm prepared the speech. It was unclear whether he ever delivered it.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880820-0026 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-20-88 0544EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-LightBulbScam     08-20 0674</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Light Bulb Scam,0698</SECOND>
<HEAD>Man Suspected In $16 Million In Scams Finally Arrested</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LARRY NEUMEISTER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
