<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880601-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-01-88 2335EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Ecuador 1stLd-Writethru a0893 06-01 0493</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Ecuador, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0893,0506</SECOND>
<HEAD>Police Use Water Cannon, Tear Gas as General Strike Hits Ecuador</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: New material and editing throughout, UPDATING with reports of
violence, other. No pickup</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By CARLOS CISTERNAS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>QUITO, Ecuador (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Riot police firing water cannons and tear gas broke up street protests in this capital city on Wednesday during a Communist-led general strike that paralyzed transportation. Small pockets of strikers blocked streets with flaming tires and rubble before being driven off. The government said 13 protesters were arrested in <LOCATION> Quito </LOCATION>. News reports said six people were detained in <LOCATION> Guayquil </LOCATION>, the nation's financial center and largest city with 2 million people, 180 miles southwest of the capital Interior Minister <PERSON> Heinz </PERSON> <PERSON> Moeller </PERSON> called the strike a failure. He said nearly all of the nation's labor force of 3 million workers ignored the strike call. <PERSON> Moeller </PERSON> told a news conference a capital policeman was injured by a firebomb tossed by a protester. There were no other reports of injury. Strike leader <PERSON> Fausto </PERSON> <PERSON> Dutan </PERSON> said 80 percent of <LOCATION> Ecuador </LOCATION>'s business activity was halted by the strike, called to back demands for higher pay. Radio reports said the strike had little impact in provincial cities across this Andean nation, which is the size of <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION> and has 10 million people. Strike protests waned as night fell. The downtown of this highland capital of 1.4 million residents was filled with tear gas, making breathing difficult for the few pedestrians left on the streets. President <PERSON> Leon </PERSON> <PERSON> Febres </PERSON> <PERSON> Cordero </PERSON> said the strike, the seventh during his tenure, was illegal and declared a nationwide state of emergency. Combat troops were sent to guard electric generating plants, gasoline stations and other installations. Riot police patrolled streets and industrial sectors of <LOCATION> Ecuador </LOCATION>'s major cities. The nationwide strike was organized by the Communist-led <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Laborers </ORGANIZATION>, the nation's most powerful labor federation, to seek wage increases. <PERSON> Dutan </PERSON> said the 200,000-member confederation wants the minimum monthly wage raised from $ 31 to $ 76. <PERSON> Moeller </PERSON> admitted that bus and taxi service in <LOCATION> Quito </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Guayaquil </LOCATION> was nearly halted as drivers stayed off the job either in strike sympathy or in fear of violence. Many of <LOCATION> Quito </LOCATION>'s factories did not open because workers could not reach their jobs, news reports said. Banks, stores and shops in downtown <LOCATION> Quito </LOCATION> opened normally or slightly late but closed in early afternoon to avoid trouble. The government suspended school classes nationwide. <PERSON> Febres </PERSON> <PERSON> Cordero </PERSON>, a conservative whose four-year term ends Aug. 10, has faced increasing labor unrest over the past two years amid mounting economic woes, caused mainly by depressed world prices for oil, <LOCATION> Ecuador </LOCATION>'s main export. <PERSON> Rodrigo </PERSON> <PERSON> Borja </PERSON>, a lawyer who heads the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Left </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> party </ORGANIZATION>, won a presidential runoff election in May to replace <PERSON> Febres </PERSON> <PERSON> Cordero </PERSON>. <PERSON> Moeller </PERSON> said the state of emergency, which permits the government to deploy the military, ban public meetings and censor the media, would stay in force only until the strike officially ended at midnight Wednesday.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880601-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-01-88 0120EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-APArts:Hart     06-01 0866</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AP Arts: Hart,0888</SECOND>
<HEAD>`ET' Host Gives Showgirl Role a Try</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT MACY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LAS VEGAS, Nev. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 When <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Hart </PERSON> was growing up in <LOCATION> Sioux </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Falls </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> S.D. </LOCATION>, her mother often worried about the future `` Entertainment Tonight'' host running away to become a showgirl. Well, Mom, do n't look now, but ... The perky blonde, who taught high school English and piano while doing community theater and dreaming of a show business career, recently made her stage debut in <LOCATION> Las </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vegas </LOCATION>. With more bookings here and in <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, plus summer stock and music festivals this summer, <PERSON> Hart </PERSON>'s ready to continue her dual professional role, although she'd just as soon skip those 18-hour days, juggling two careers in two cities. Her grueling daily grind _ shuttling between this city's <LOCATION> Glitter </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulch </LOCATION> for her long-awaited fling at singing and dancing, then back to a <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION> `` ET'' set for more TV patter _ gave new meaning to the concept of commuting to work. <PERSON> Hart </PERSON> realized a lifelong dream when she spent two weeks appearing with comedian <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Brenner </PERSON> at the Golden Nugget Hotel and Casino earlier this month. But she admits she would n't care for a steady diet of the double duty. `` I performed at 8 and again at 11,'' she said. `` Then I caught a 1 a.m. flight to <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>, and hit the house about 2:45. I got up at 7:30 and was at Paramount -LRB- where ` ET' is filmed -RRB- by 8 a.m.. We did our promos and other spots, then began taping the show at 11:30 a.m.. At 2:45 in the afternoon I was on a flight back to `` Both worlds is not an ideal situation,'' she laughed as she relaxed between shows during her two-week engagement. `` It's conceivable to do one show a night and commute for a short period of time. In her show, <PERSON> Hart </PERSON> does several dance numbers and displays a surprisingly good singing voice. Her appearance and style are reminiscent of Ann-Margret when she was a <LOCATION> Las </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vegas </LOCATION> headliner for years. <PERSON> Hart </PERSON>'s sexy legs _ insured by <ORGANIZATION> Lloyd </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> London </ORGANIZATION> for $ 2 million _ are amply displayed in the <LOCATION> Las </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vegas </LOCATION> show. The legs are a product of a lot of hard work, including a treadmill, rowing machine and Exercycle at home, 25 miles of speed-walking a week, and aerobics and dance classes. She admits that coming into this town with a nationally known name did n't hurt her chances for success. But she thinks she had to have more than just a pretty, recognizable face _ and $ 2 million legs. `` You know, you're putting it all on the line when you come in here as a co-headliner,'' she said. `` There's no way of hiding it. But I wanted to do it. I was both exhilarated and intimidated by the experience.'' Her song-and-dance debut has given her a new appreciation of the people she covers on ` ET.' `` There's a lot of rejection and hard knocks. I'm far more appreciative for having experienced it firsthand.'' <PERSON> Hart </PERSON> admits to something of a <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitty </PERSON> lifestyle since her days in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION>. She's been a finalist in the Miss America Pageant -LRB- 1971 -RRB-, been a host of `` ET'' for five years, sparred with <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Letterman </PERSON>, sung the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Anthem </ORGANIZATION> at <ORGANIZATION> Los </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Angeles </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dodgers </ORGANIZATION> games, ridden with the <ORGANIZATION> Blue </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Angels </ORGANIZATION> flight team, danced on the Emmy awards show, injured one leg in a fall from the high wire on a `` Circus of the Stars'' performance and been co-host of the Tournament of Roses Parade coverage and the `` Regis Philbin Show.'' Despite all those credits she thinks her stage debut at the Golden Nugget was one of her toughest gigs. `` I prepared for the opening for months,'' she recalled. `` Then the day of the opening, after working all afternoon in dress rehearsals, I almost felt like I could n't do it. I proceeded to cry for three hours. `` Part of it was sheer fear; part of it was excitement. There were moments of being panic-stricken. But the overriding emotion was one of exhilaration. `` I have really always seen myself as an entertainer,'' she said. `` You dream those things, but you do n't know for sure if they'll ever happen. I think that was part of my emotionalism, realizing those things had come true.'' A few dreams _ a Broadway play and her own TV sitcom _ remain unfulfilled. But, at age 35, she thinks time is on her side. She's learned to roll with the punches, to be patient. After doing radio and TV talk shows in <LOCATION> Sioux </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Falls </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Cedar </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rapids </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>, and <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, she moved West to headline `` PM Magazine.'' She left that show to co-host `` <ORGANIZATION> Regis </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Philbin </ORGANIZATION>'' _ which folded four months later. `` I was out of work and out of money,'' she recalled. `` That was a time I was terribly disappointed. Then ET came along. Thank heaven for my Midwestern upbringing, and positive thinking. `` My parents always told me that the bad times accentuate the good. I've always translated the negative experiences into good in the long run. I'm a big believer that life goes on. You get back from life what you put into it.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880601-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-01-88 0120EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-HandsofUruguay     06-01 0649</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Hands of Uruguay,0665</SECOND>
<HEAD>Handwork Of Rural Women Reaches Out To The World</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in report for Wednesday AMs.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By RANDALL HACKLEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MONTEVIDEO, Uruguay (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 It began with rural women passing on the traditional crafts of knitting and weaving, grandmother to mother to daughter. Today it is a $ 4-million-a-year business cooperative, shipping colorful sweaters around the world, including the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. Manos del <LOCATION> Uruguay </LOCATION> -LRB- Hands of <LOCATION> Uruguay </LOCATION> -RRB- is made up of 18 rural cooperatives whose workers spin, knit, weave and dye virgin wool, one of <LOCATION> Uruguay </LOCATION>'s top commodities, entirely by hand. It was founded in 1968 by <PERSON> Sara </PERSON> <PERSON> Beisso </PERSON> and four other members of <LOCATION> Uruguay </LOCATION>'s high society who had second homes on ranch estates outside <LOCATION> Montevideo </LOCATION>. Unemployment was high in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s smallest republic at the time, so the five devised a way for rural women to do what they knew best _ weave colorful sweaters using natural vegetable dyes and <LOCATION> Uruguay </LOCATION>'s virgin wool. The result is a richly colored wool woven in bright, distinctive sweaters, as well as in rugs, tapestries and placemats. Each article bears the name of the artisan and where it was made on a card accompanying the product. Finding many of the artisans' work sites on a map is often difficult: they include Tacuarembo, said to be the birthplace of famed tango singer <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Gardel </PERSON>, and villages such as <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mellizos </LOCATION> and Quebracho. One thousand workers in more than 40 sites, some using just a loom or a table under a tree, labor over the sweaters, tapestries and rugs. Each sweater takes 12 to 28 hours to finish, Mrs. <PERSON> Beisso </PERSON> said. Most of the sweaters end up in shops in neighboring <LOCATION> Argentina </LOCATION>, but many are shipped to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Belgium </LOCATION>. Seventy percent of Manos' sweaters are exported, said <PERSON> Maria </PERSON> <PERSON> Orfila </PERSON> <PERSON> Algalarronda </PERSON>. Ms. <PERSON> Algalarronda </PERSON>, 36, was with Manos from its start, weaving from the village of <LOCATION> Paso </LOCATION> <LOCATION> de </LOCATION> <LOCATION> la </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Cruz </LOCATION>. Two decades later, she is secretary counsel of the seven-member directorate -LRB- five women, two men -RRB- that oversees Manos' operations from <LOCATION> Montevideo </LOCATION>. Now one of <LOCATION> Uruguay </LOCATION>'s largest exporters of wool, <LOCATION> Manos </LOCATION> is well-regarded in business circles for the quality of its work and fashion acumen. `` Manos is an experience that's practically unique in the world,'' Ms. <PERSON> Algalarronda </PERSON> said in an interview. `` The world is a very competitive place and <LOCATION> Uruguay </LOCATION> is a very small place. But at a minimum Manos has turned into a source of work for 1,000 women.'' Each sweater, which costs the equivalent of about $ 30 in <LOCATION> Uruguay </LOCATION>, sells for up to $ 300 in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> or <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, said <PERSON> Maria </PERSON> <PERSON> Cecilia </PERSON> <PERSON> Fernandez </PERSON>, an aide in the promotion department of Manos' main office in the oldtown section of this capital city. In the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, Manos sweaters can be found in some <ORGANIZATION> Saks </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fifth </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Avenue </ORGANIZATION> and <PERSON> Ann </PERSON> <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON> stores, Mrs. <PERSON> Beisso </PERSON> said. Manos recently opened a small showroom in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. Ms. <PERSON> Algalarronda </PERSON> said 50 designs are ready for the 1989 summer collection, including sweaters specially made for <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> -LRB- `` smaller sizes because the Japanese are smaller'' -RRB-, the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> -LRB- `` simpler designs'' -RRB- and <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION> -LRB- `` reds and blacks are popular'' -RRB-. A specially designed sofa that Pope <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> II </PERSON> used at a Mass in <LOCATION> Salto </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Uruguay </LOCATION>, on his visit in May was produced by <PERSON> Manos </PERSON>, Mrs. <PERSON> Beisso </PERSON> said. Manos is set up so that regional leaders from each cooperative elect representatives who then report to the directorate in <LOCATION> Montevideo </LOCATION>. All business decisions, from designs to marketing and exports, are made only after receiving input from the interior, Ms. <PERSON> Algalarronda </PERSON> said. Any profits _ 1987 sales were $ 4 million _ are plowed back into the business, helping keep those workers employed, which was the founding purpose of <LOCATION> Manos </LOCATION>. `` It's a fine source of employment but not a good business,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Beisso </PERSON> said. `` The people in the country are the ones who really profit from this.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880601-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-01-88 0124EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-NMSenate     06-01 0632</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-NM Senate,0649</SECOND>
<HEAD>Four Republicans Seek GOP Nomination For U.S. Senate</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By BILL FEATHER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SANTA FE, N.M. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Some Republicans refer to first-term Sen. <PERSON> Jeff </PERSON> <PERSON> Bingaman </PERSON> as the `` invisible senator,'' and their conviction that he can be beaten has lured four candidates to seek the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> nomination in the June 7 primary. <PERSON> Bingaman </PERSON> is vulnerable because of his liberal voting record and his position on national defense issues, said state <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Lattauzio </PERSON>. `` <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>'s congressmen philosophically have always supported defense spending until <PERSON> Jeff </PERSON> <PERSON> Bingaman </PERSON> came along,'' he said. `` And economically defense spending is very important to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>. `` If we can articulate these issues effectively, the <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> candidate will do very well,'' Lattauzio said. `` Another thing we will be able to talk about a lot is that <PERSON> Bingaman </PERSON> is the ` invisible senator.' New Mexicans are accustomed to their congressmen staying in touch with them,'' Lattauzio said. `` <PERSON> Jeff </PERSON> just has n't been around up until recently.'' <PERSON> Bingaman </PERSON> said in January when he announced for re-election that as one of only two first-term Democrats running this year _ the other is <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> Sen. <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Lautenberg </PERSON> _ he expected his race to be targeted by the national <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>. But Democrats question whether the Republican field of state Sens. <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Valentine </PERSON>, 44, and <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Carraro </PERSON>, 43, both of <LOCATION> Albuquerque </LOCATION>, long-time party activist <PERSON> Corky </PERSON> <PERSON> Morris </PERSON>, 52, of <LOCATION> Albuquerque </LOCATION>, and former <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Interior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> official <PERSON> Rick </PERSON> <PERSON> Montoya </PERSON>, 41, of <LOCATION> Las </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Cruces </LOCATION> can produce a strong challenger to <PERSON> Bingaman </PERSON>. Polls showing a high percentage of undecided Republicans, far greater than the percentage favoring any candidate, indicate none of the four has caught fire with the voters. Valentine and <PERSON> Morris </PERSON>, however, appear to be the front-runners. <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> <PERSON> Ingram </PERSON>, a former state <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> chairman, said <PERSON> Bingaman </PERSON> may be vulnerable but not with any of this year's Republican candidates `` Those guys are all wallflowers who follow the old party line,'' <PERSON> Ingram </PERSON> said. `` I think had the Republicans had a charismatic candidate running against <PERSON> Bingaman </PERSON>, he would have a tough time in the fall.'' <PERSON> Valentine </PERSON>, who sold his dentistry practice to campaign fulltime, and <PERSON> Carraro </PERSON>, who owns and operates two pizza restaurants, are giving up their state <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> seats to try for the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Morris </PERSON>, who owns trucking and warehousing companies in <LOCATION> Albuquerque </LOCATION>, is a former state <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> chairman and was <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> chairman of the Reagan-Bush campaign in 1984. <PERSON> Montoya </PERSON> left the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration as assistant secretary of <ORGANIZATION> interior </ORGANIZATION> for terriorities and international affairs to return to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> and seek elective office for the first time. <PERSON> Bingaman </PERSON>, who is unopposed in the Democratic primary, is a Harvard-educated lawyer who in 1982 defeated first-term Republican Sen. <PERSON> Harrison </PERSON> `` <PERSON> Jack </PERSON><PERSON> '' </PERSON> <PERSON> Schmitt </PERSON>, a former astronaut. <PERSON> Ingram </PERSON> said <PERSON> Bingaman </PERSON> has recognized his problems and corrected most of them, including that he had not been communicating with his constituency on a regular basis. He also has been spending more time in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> in the last year, meeting with residents. The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> race and presidential voting top <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>'s primary ballot, but the retirement after 20 years of Republican Rep. <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Lujan </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> has thrown open the door in the 1st Congressional District. Three Republicans, including <PERSON> Lujan </PERSON>'s younger brother <PERSON> Edward </PERSON>, and nine Democrats aspire to succeed <PERSON> Lujan </PERSON>, who has called it quits after 20 years in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Lujan </PERSON>, 55, is an <LOCATION> Albuquerque </LOCATION> insurance executive and former state <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> chairman. Challenging him are <LOCATION> Bernalillo </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> <LOCATION> District </LOCATION> Attorney <PERSON> Steven </PERSON> <PERSON> Schiff </PERSON>, 40, of <LOCATION> Albuquerque </LOCATION> and state Sen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Budagher </PERSON>, 41, of <LOCATION> Albuquerque </LOCATION>. The top Democratic contenders are former state Land Commissioner <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Baca </PERSON>, 42, former state <LOCATION> District </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Judge </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Patricia </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Madrid </LOCATION>, 41, <LOCATION> Bernalillo </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> Commissioner <PERSON> Lenton </PERSON> <PERSON> Malry </PERSON>, 57, city Councilor <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Gallegos </PERSON>, 35, and former Assistant <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Attorney <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Udall </PERSON>, 39. All are from <LOCATION> Albuquerque </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880601-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-01-88 0125EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-RentUproar     06-01 0709</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Rent Uproar,0726</SECOND>
<HEAD>Annual Rite Of NYC Spring: Brawling Landlords And Tenants</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Wedneday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By LARRY McSHANE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Ah, springtime in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>: The first robin in Central Park. The first ballgame at Yankee Stadium. And the first angry protester ejected from Police Headquarters in the annual brawl over city rents. `` People get frustrated, people get thrown out, their blood pressure goes way up,'' says <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>, head of a landlord group, in summing up the yearly hike-or-hold-the-rent fight before the city <ORGANIZATION> Rent </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guidelines </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION>, beginning its hearings today. The proceedings match angry tenants with irate landlords, with roughly the same results as introducing <PERSON> Billy </PERSON> <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> to patrons in a topless bar. Rhetoric is thick and animosity thicker, with supporters on both sides cheering, jeering and -LRB- with the aid of police -RRB- disappearing during the session. Slightly more than 50 percent of the city's apartments are covered by the board's guidelines under a system that has its roots in the city's World War II housing scarcity. Although the owners routinely request double-digit increases on one - and two-year leases, the board generally grants a much lower increase This year, <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON> asked for increases of 15 percent on one-year leases and 19 percent on two-year leases. The hearings _ once held privately, but opened to the public by court order in 1979 _ are held inside Police Headquarters for security reasons. Dozens of police officers are assigned to the hearings, and others are available if verbal arguments get out of hand. `` The headquarters is the only place where we have the ability to keep things under restraint,'' explained veteran board member <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Forstadt </PERSON>, who's seen several participants dragged out over the past four years. `` Otherwise ...'' Otherwise there'd be more stories like these: _ A woman was arrested two years ago for biting the finger of the police officer who was dragging her from the auditorium. `` It was unclear which point of view she was biting for,'' recalled <PERSON> Forstadt </PERSON>. _ <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON>, whose <ORGANIZATION> Rent </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Stabilization </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> represents 25,000 building owners, stood up and dramatically tore a dollar bill in half last year to demonstrate how landlord profits were down 50 percent from 1971. Tenants derisively greeted the display with boos. _ In 1984, after the usual spate of insults, obscenities and outbursts in English, a group of Spanish-speaking tenants enlivened the hearing with chants of `` Callate! Callate!'' _ `` Shut up! Shut up!'' _ as a landlord spoke. After all the sign-waving and screaming is finished, the nine-member <ORGANIZATION> Rent </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guidelines </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> determines whether rent increases should be granted, and if so, how much. The oldest and most stringent guideline, rent control, covers 218,000 apartments; when they become vacant, they come under a rent stabilization guideline, which covers 943,000 apartment. `` When you have landlords and tenants at the same meeting _ which I think is a mistake _ you're bound to have turmoil,'' said 77-year-old <PERSON> Jane </PERSON> <PERSON> Benedict </PERSON>, founder and chairman emeritus of the <ORGANIZATION> Metropolitan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> on </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Housing </ORGANIZATION>, a tenant group. <PERSON> Benedict </PERSON>, a fixture in rent fights since 1969, has attended every board hearing since they went public. She sees no end to the near-anarchy of the hearings; in fact, the problem of homelessness could make this year's affair even wilder, she predicted. `` Everybody knows <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> rents are outrageous. The feelings are intense,'' she said. `` It's not just an academic debate. We're talking about people with no place to live.'' At least one landlord group blames the media for stirring up anti-landlord sentiment and making the hearings contentious. <PERSON> Jimmy </PERSON> <PERSON> Silber </PERSON>, vice-president of the <ORGANIZATION> Small </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Property </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Owners </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION>, cited recent tabloid stories on `` The Dracula Landlord'' and `` The Reptile Landlord'' as well as the annual Village Voice listing of the city's 10 worst landlords. Nevertheless, <PERSON> Silber </PERSON> believes the animosity level has decreased over the past two years; <PERSON> Benedict </PERSON>, almost predictably, disagrees. But <PERSON> Forstadt </PERSON> said there is an interesting phenomenon which occurs each year among the participants. `` After six or seven hours, it's hard to tell the landlords from the tenants when they're talking,'' he said. `` They're both under such distress, they begin to feel sympathetic toward one another. ... There's a sense of cohesion. They're all in the same boat.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880601-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-01-88 0146EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lites     06-01 0625</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lites,0649</SECOND>
<HEAD>On The Light Side</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SANFORD, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 School officials here learned a lesson the hard way after a quarter of the students played hooky _ many with their parents' approval. `` I do n't think any member of the present school board will ever vote to hold classes on Memorial Day again,'' said <PERSON> Karen </PERSON> <PERSON> Coleman </PERSON>, a spokeswoman for the <ORGANIZATION> Seminole </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Seminole </PERSON> was one of 24 of <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>'s 67 counties to hold classes Monday. Absentees totaled 5,000 of Seminole's enrollment of 20,033. Many parents called the school district's offices to make it clear they regarded the day as a family holiday, <PERSON> Coleman </PERSON> said. `` Some were really angry about having school on Memorial Day,'' she said. `` They were all blunt in saying they were keeping their kids home and were going to celebrate the holiday.'' `` I know we're taking a beating on this,'' said School Board Chairman <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>. `` I guarantee it wo n't happen next year.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>GLENDALE, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The warming trend in U.S.-Soviet relations has prompted the <LOCATION> Russians </LOCATION> to order out for ice cream. Baskin-Robbins Ice Cream announced Tuesday it has signed a licensing agreement to open its first store in a communist country, with its 31 flavors becoming available in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> by July. However, a spokeswoman said it is too soon to say if Moscovites will be ordering ice cream with such names as `` Catherine the Grape,'' `` <PERSON> Lenin </PERSON>'s <LOCATION> Lemon </LOCATION>,'' `` Tutti-Frutti Rasputti,'' or `` Ivanilla the Terrible.'' <ORGANIZATION> Baskin-Robbins </ORGANIZATION> executives have n't yet thought of Russian names for their 31 flavors, said spokeswoman <PERSON> Marilyn </PERSON> <PERSON> Novak </PERSON>. Still, `` the Soviets have expressed particular interest in having Pralines' n Cream and <PERSON> Jamoca </PERSON> <PERSON> Almond </PERSON> <PERSON> Fudge </PERSON>,'' Ms. <PERSON> Novak </PERSON> said. `` They have requested those two, along with other typical American ice creams.'' The Soviets, who already enjoy excellent domestic ice cream, will operate the store, while the company will train Soviet employees, provide the necessary equipment and decor, and supply the ice cream itself, she said. A cone will sell for about a ruble, or roughly $ 1.60, Ms. <PERSON> Novak </PERSON> said. `` We're going to be putting our first store at the Rossiya Hotel,'' Ms. <PERSON> Novak </PERSON> said. The 8,000-room hotel is located near Red Square.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>IRVINE, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>'s and <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION>'s most colossal cockroaches faced off feeler-to-feeler for the honor of representing the two-state region in a national `` roach-off.'' The largest Oriental cockroach entered in Tuesday's contest measured 1.18 inch and was nurtured on a diet of paper, eggs and breakfast cereal by two <ORGANIZATION> Elm </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Street </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Elementary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> students in <LOCATION> Oxnard </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Nick </PERSON> <PERSON> Preston </PERSON> and <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Parrish </PERSON> said they will donate their $ 500 prize toward a science camp for their class of gifted 3rd - and 4th-graders, even though their teachers and classmates would n't let them bring the bugs to school `` They thought it was pretty disgusting,'' said <PERSON> Paul </PERSON>, 9, whose father is an exterminator. `` I like bugs. I like to catch spiders.'' But alas, the boys' roach wo n't represent <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION> in the `` Great American Roach-Off,'' a national event sponsored by a pest-control company that recognizes a different variety of the household pest, the American cockroach, as the continent's pre-eminent insect The regional roach-off entrant will be a 1.71-inch American cockroach submitted by a Mrs. <PERSON> Rauich </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Palm </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Springs </LOCATION>, said contest organizer <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Bohdan </PERSON>, who did n't know her first name. Both bugs were dead, in keeping with contest rules, and neither measured up to <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>'s entrant in the contest, 1.75 inch. The grand prize in the national contest, to be judged July 7 at the <ORGANIZATION> Philadelphia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Zoo </ORGANIZATION>, is $ 1,000. <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> and <PERSON> Nick </PERSON> produced their winner as part of a science project to determine roaches' favorite food. The bugs turned up their feelers at almost nothing, devouring paste, paper and electrical wiring as well as scrambled eggs and cereal.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880601-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-01-88 0153EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Runner-Raffle     06-01 0369</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Runner-Raffle,0382</SECOND>
<HEAD>Runner Stumbles Over Raffle</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By NICHOLAS K. GERANIOS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>YAKIMA, Wash. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A distance runner's plan to finance a 964-mile jog across <LOCATION> Great </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> with a raffle has been tripped up by the state <ORGANIZATION> Gambling </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION>, which says the plan is illegal. `` We did n't know anything about it,'' <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Goodman </PERSON>, a 68-year-old real-estate agent and long-distance runner, said Tuesday. `` I've never don anything in my life that is wrong.'' <PERSON> Goodman </PERSON> said he has located two corporate sponsors willing to put up the $ 10,000 to $ 12,000 needed, and will return the approximately $ 800 he had raised from the $ 10 raffle tickets, as the commission has ordered. Only bona fide non-profit organizations are allowed to operate raffles, and state law sets the maximum raffle ticket price at $ 5, said <PERSON> Ron </PERSON> <PERSON> Layton </PERSON>, a commission spokesman. <PERSON> Goodman </PERSON> had enticed raffle purchasers with the chance to win round trip tickets for two to <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>. He said the setback wo n't alter plans for his 20-day jaunt from <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Groats </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Scotland </LOCATION>, to Land's End, on the southern tip of <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>, scheduled to begin June 21. The 5-foot-8 <PERSON> Goodman </PERSON>, who weighs 140 pounds, plans to run 50 miles a day to complete the route. `` No man 68 years old ever ran it,'' said <PERSON> Goodman </PERSON>, a World War II veteran who took up running 26 years ago because he was getting out of shape. Plans call for running nine to 10 hours a day, with breaks for massages and meals. <PERSON> Goodman </PERSON>'s coach is <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Emmerton </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Monica </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, a long-distance runner who ran the <LOCATION> Great </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> route in 1965. It is the longest run yet for <PERSON> Goodman </PERSON>, whose past efforts have raised thousands of dollars for charities around the state. The current run is not for charity, he said. The money is needed to pay for air fare, a training van and pace car, food and hotels. In 1985, <PERSON> Goodman </PERSON> ran 130 miles from the <LOCATION> Kingdome </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION> to the Peace Arch near <LOCATION> Blaine </LOCATION>, his boyhood home, on the Canadian border. That raised $ 20,000 for a nursing home in <LOCATION> Blaine </LOCATION>. Next May, he plans to run 2,000 miles across the old <ORGANIZATION> Pony </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Express </ORGANIZATION> route from <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Joseph </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mo. </LOCATION>, to <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880601-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-01-88 0153EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--China-Children     06-01 0166</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--China-Children,0169</SECOND>
<HEAD>Number Of Children In China Declines</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s family planning policy, which calls for no more than one child per couple, has in six years reduced by 30.1 million the number of children under the age of 14, the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Statistics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> said today. The bureau said <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> now has 307.15 million children under 14, compared to 337.25 million in 1982. It found the proportion of children in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s total population of 1.07 billion to be 28.68 percent, down from 33.45 percent six years ago, the official <ORGANIZATION> Xinhua </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> reported. The bureau attributed the decline to the family planning policy, which has been largely successful in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s crowded cities but has met resistance in many rural areas, where two or more children is still the norm. The bureau said children account for just 18.36 percent of the population in <LOCATION> Shanghai </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s largest city, while making up 36 percent in the remote western areas of <LOCATION> Tibet </LOCATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Ningxia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hui </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Autonomous </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Region </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880601-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-01-88 0155EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-ScotusRdp Bjt   06-01 0672</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Scotus Rdp, Bjt,660</SECOND>
<HEAD>Supreme Court Upholds Discount Store Practice</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JAMES H. RUBIN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Distributors of discount merchandise say consumers are the big winners in a <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> ruling upholding a lion's share of the multibillion-dollar `` gray market'' that allows costly imports to be sold at reduced prices. Sen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Chafee </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-R.I. </LOCATION>, sponsor of a bill favoring gray market imports, also praised the decision. `` This is very good news for everyone in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> who likes to save a dollar or many dollars on imported goods like televisions, cameras, and perfume,'' he said. <PERSON> Nathan </PERSON> <PERSON> Lewin </PERSON>, a lawyer for discount dealer 47th <ORGANIZATION> Street </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Photo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, said the decision will mean savings for buyers of brand-name imports. `` I think the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>'s ruling today is a great victory for American consumers and for the right of merchandisers in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> seeking to bring products manufactured abroad into the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> at realistic and honest prices,'' he said. By a 5-4 vote, the court upheld key <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Customs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> regulations that permit the gray market _ brand-name, foreign-made goods bearing valid <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> trademarks sold in this country without approval from trademark owners. The gray market is estimated to produce $ 5 billion to $ 10 billion a year in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, with consumers buying everything from German sedans and French champagne to Japanese cameras and watches. The business began to flourish when the value of the dollar on the international currency exchange rose dramatically in the early 1980s. But the more recent decline in the dollar apparently has not substantially depressed the American appetite for gray market foreign goods. The gray market is created when foreign goods are purchased abroad and sold through discount retailers in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> in competition with the owners of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> trademarks of those products. Trademark owners say they are being shortchanged because they are forced to charge a markup to help cover advertising, warranty and service costs. K mart <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> and 47th Street Photo, two leading discount distributors, joined with the <ORGANIZATION> Customs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> to defend the gray market. Justice <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> _ the court's newest member _ provided the pivotal vote in the decision. By a separate 5-4 vote, the court struck down another <ORGANIZATION> Customs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> rule that could have been used to expand the gray market. Some lawyers for discounters said that rule probably is inconsequential. But another attorney representing discounters said there may be loopholes in the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> decision that would allow trademark owners to block the gray market in the future. That lawyer, who asked to remain anonymous, said trademark holders `` could get around the ruling in time'' by conveying their trademark to an independent company that then would be able to block competing imports. The Customs Service for more than 50 years permitted gray market imports when foreign manufacturers of the goods are affiliated with the owners of the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> trademarks. The rules apply when the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> trademark holder is a subsidiary of, parent of or the same as the foreign manufacturer. The regulations were challenged by some 60 major trademark owners that banded together to form the Coalition to Preserve the Integrity of American Trademarks. In other matters, the court: _ Ruled by a 5-3 vote that states sometimes may execute convicted murderers even if their constitutional right to a lawyer's help was violated The justices said such violations may be deemed `` harmless'' but they overturned a <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> killer's death sentence after ruling that the violation in his case was not harmless. _ Unanimously struck down the way <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> promotes through tax credits the use of `` gasohol,'' a motor vehicle fuel less environmentally troublesome than gasoline _ Cleared the way for price deregulation of some natural gas _ an 8-0 decision the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration said could save consumers an estimated $ 100 million a year _ Unanimously gave federal regulators, in a test case from <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>, broad power to oust bank executives from their jobs temporarily when the executives are accused of serious crimes
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880601-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-01-88 0154EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Korea-StudentSuicide     06-01 0220</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Korea-Student Suicide,0226</SECOND>
<HEAD>Report: Growing Number Of Students Commit Suicide Over Exams</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SEOUL, South Korea (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Pressure from school work and exams drove at least 50 secondary school students to commit suicide last year and 10 students killed themselves in May alone, a newspaper reported today. The <ORGANIZATION> Korea </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Herald </ORGANIZATION> reported a growing number of suicides among high school and middle school students because of pressure from school work and college entrance examinations. It warned that the number of student suicides would increase unless education policy changes. The latest death was reported Monday, when a 17-year-old student, upset over his poor academic performance, jumped from a bridge to his death. He left a note that said, `` Sorry for my lack of responsibility.'' On May 18, the newspaper said, a 16-year-old high school girl jumped to her death from an apartment one day after two high school girls killed themselves over their poor school record. Most suicide notes left behind by students blamed pressure from hard school work or poor exam results. `` I want to live in a country where there is no examination,'' said a suicide note from an 18-year-old student in the southern city of <LOCATION> Andong </LOCATION>. To reduce the pressure, educators are proposing drastic reforms of the system, which puts heavy emphasis on rote learning, the paper said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880601-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-01-88 0203EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-DeficitCommission     06-01 0378</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Deficit Commission,380</SECOND>
<HEAD>Deficit Panel Debates Goal; Republicans Leery of Specifics</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By STEVEN KOMAROW</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> created to solve the government's budget troubles is finding it tough to agree on just what that task entails. <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> co-chairman <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Strauss </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> lawyer and political dealmaker, says the `` mandate is clear.'' The president and next <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> need `` a political solution'' for reducing the federal deficit, in the form of recommendations to close the gap between spending and taxes. But commission member <PERSON> Caspar </PERSON> <PERSON> Weinberger </PERSON>, the former defense secretary, expressed surprise at a meeting Tuesday when a witness suggested that making policy choices would be difficult. `` Are you suggesting that this commission is supposed to make specific recommendations for budget cuts and tax increases?'' <PERSON> Weinberger </PERSON> asked <PERSON> Alice </PERSON> <PERSON> Rivlin </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Brookings </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institution </ORGANIZATION>, a <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> think tank. <PERSON> Weinberger </PERSON> and fellow Republican <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Rumsfeld </PERSON>, another former <ORGANIZATION> defense </ORGANIZATION> secretary, had focused their remarks on changing the cumbersome budget process. The two former administration officials suggested changing the system to give the president more power over what they described as a spendthrift <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. But Rep. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gray </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>, D-Pa., another commission member, noted that President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> has never submitted balanced budgets Trying to blame <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> for the deficits misses the point, said <PERSON> Gray </PERSON>, the chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Budget </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>. `` I thought we had to come up with specific recommendations,'' said <ORGANIZATION> Chrysler </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Iacocca </PERSON>, another commission member. By the end of the session, <PERSON> Strauss </PERSON> admonished the members not to get `` too tied up in possible philosophical differences.'' <PERSON> Strauss </PERSON> is co-chairman of the 12-member commission along with <PERSON> Drew </PERSON> <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pacific </ORGANIZATION> railroad and President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s former transportation secretary Ms. <PERSON> Rivlin </PERSON>, a former director of the <ORGANIZATION> Congressional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Budget </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION>, said the commission should seek ways to improve the process to keep the deficit under control in the long run. But, she said, the panel will be a failure unless it proposes short-term improvements as well. <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> created the commission last year to develop proposals for reducing the federal deficit. Its members were appointed by <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and the bipartisan congressional leadership, and two additional slots will be filled by the next president. The commission has announced it plans to issue a report on Dec. 21.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880601-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-01-88 0203EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Hutton-Libel     06-01 0649</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Hutton-Libel,650</SECOND>
<HEAD>Former Attorney General In Court Over Check-Kiting Investigation</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JAMES ROWLEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Former Attorney General <PERSON> Griffin </PERSON> B. <PERSON> Bell </PERSON> ignored evidence that top <PERSON> E.F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Hutton </PERSON> executives orchestrated a widespread check-kiting scheme when he blamed mid-level managers in a defamatory report, the lawyer for one of those managers says. <PERSON> Bell </PERSON>, a defendant in a defamation suit brought by one of six branch managers he criticized in the 1985 report about the check-kiting scheme, was trying to shift the blame away from top management, the lawyer argued Tuesday in <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>. `` He cleared the company, he cleared the management and put the blame out on regional managers and branch managers,'' <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Milliken </PERSON>, a lawyer for former <PERSON> Hutton </PERSON> manager <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Pearce </PERSON>, said as the defamation trial got under way. <PERSON> Bell </PERSON>, a private attorney in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>, was retained by <PERSON> Hutton </PERSON> to conduct the internal investigation after the company pleaded guilty May 2, 1985, to 2,000 counts of mail and wire fraud for manipulating its checking accounts. The company admitted writing checks for amounts exceeding money in the accounts, thereby giving itself interest-free loans. The accounts were replenished before the overdrawn checks cleared, enabling <PERSON> Hutton </PERSON> to make extra money by `` riding the float.'' <PERSON> Hutton </PERSON>, which is now part of <ORGANIZATION> Shearson </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lehman </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hutton </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, agreed to pay a $ 2 million fine and reimburse banks that were victims of the check-kiting scheme. Federal investigators said the company had interest-free use of $ 250 million a day. <PERSON> Milliken </PERSON> said the practice was conceived in the late 1970s by <PERSON> Hutton </PERSON> management and promoted as a way to get interest-free loans from banks. `` The entire operation was known to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, understood by <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, created by <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Milliken </PERSON> said. But `` Mr. <PERSON> Bell </PERSON>, by his investigation cleared everybody in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>.'' <PERSON> Bell </PERSON>, a partner in the <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> law firm of <ORGANIZATION> King </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> Spalding </PERSON>, was retained shortly after the guilty plea was entered by the company. He produced a report three months later that recommended that <PERSON> Pearce </PERSON> and eight other branch and regional executives be disciplined. The report exonerated all but one top management official, whom <PERSON> Bell </PERSON> recommended be stripped of any duties involving <PERSON> Hutton </PERSON>'s banking activities <PERSON> Bell </PERSON>'s attorney, <PERSON> Earl </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Silbert </PERSON>, said the former attorney general's probe `` was a carefuly, thorough, meticulous and fair and independent investigation.'' <PERSON> Silbert </PERSON> charged that <PERSON> Pearce </PERSON> violated company policies limiting overdrafts in order to make extra money. <PERSON> Pearce </PERSON> overdrew by as much as 400 percent to take his 10 percent share of interest profits that were given branch managers as an incentive for efficient cash management, <PERSON> Silbert </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Bell </PERSON> carefully refrained from accusing top managers because there was insufficient evidence they did anything wrong, he said. But <PERSON> Pearce </PERSON> and the others named in the report were criticized because `` their conduct was so egregious and abusive and so aggravated and the evidence of proof so overwhelming that he would have been derelict in his responsibility if he had not so named them,'' said <PERSON> Silbert </PERSON>, a former <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> attorney. <PERSON> Milliken </PERSON> said the overdrafting policies were so important to <PERSON> Hutton </PERSON>'s business strategy that <PERSON> Pearce </PERSON> was admonished when he did not write checks for more than the amounts in the accounts. `` They taught him to overdraft, they told him what branches to use,'' he said. <PERSON> Milliken </PERSON> argued that <PERSON> Bell </PERSON>'s independence was undermined by his relationship to <PERSON> Hutton </PERSON>, which paid <ORGANIZATION> King </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; Spalding $ 2.5 million to conduct the investigation. `` <PERSON> Hutton </PERSON> was supplying the information, <PERSON> Hutton </PERSON> was supplying the fee, <PERSON> Hutton </PERSON> was controlling the timing of when the report would be released,'' <PERSON> Milliken </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Bell </PERSON>, a former federal appeals judge who was President <PERSON> Carter </PERSON>'s first attorney general, was paid at a rate of $ 1,711 an hour for 518 hours of work <PERSON> Pearce </PERSON> also sued <PERSON> Hutton </PERSON>, but a federal appeals court ruled that his claim against the brokerage firm must first be submitted to arbitration by the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Stock </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Exchange </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880601-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-01-88 0207EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Religion-Schools     06-01 0637</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Religion-Schools,630</SECOND>
<HEAD>Groups Set Guidelines For Teaching About Religion</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto WX6</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CHRISTOPHER CONNELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Education Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Fourteen school and church groups are giving their imprimatur to a new pamphlet that lays out constitutional ways for public schools to teach about religion in a way that does not advocate a particular belief. The sponsors said Tuesday that endorsement of the document by such diverse groups as the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Boards </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Evangelicals </ORGANIZATION> and the research arm of <ORGANIZATION> Americans </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Separation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> indicates that the time is ripe for a resurgence of instruction about religion. `` The question is no longer should we teach about religion,'' <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Haynes </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> Americans </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> told a news conference. `` The question is how do we do this?'' Other participants called the 1,000-word pamphlet historic and expressed hope it will embolden teachers and principals to give religion its due in history, literature and other classes. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Dunn </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Baptist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Joint </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> on </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Affairs </ORGANIZATION> said it shows `` there is a nobler and better way to deal with religion in public schools than simply to yell at each other and threaten a lawsuit.'' All too often, debates about religion in public schools have degenerated into `` a hog-calling or a shouting match,'' <PERSON> Dunn </PERSON> said. Secular and religious groups alike, as well as Secretary of Education <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON>, have complained in recent years that religion gets short shrift in most American classrooms and textbooks, even in courses that teach about historical events in which religion played a prominent part. Some critics blamed publishers' fear of controversy, while others attribute it to an overreaction by educators to <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> rulings in the 1960s that barred state-sponsored school prayer and Bible reading. The pamphlet provides guidance in question-and-answer form for school boards, teachers and others. The pamphlet, called `` Religion in the Public School Curriculum: Questions and Answers,'' notes that the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> has ruled unconstitutional a <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION> law that required schools to teach the Biblical account of creation in science classes. But it said the high court also acknowledged a variety of scientific theories about origins can appropriately be taught in a science class. The pamphlet added, `` Though science instruction may not endorse or promote religious doctrine, the account of creation found in various scriptures may be discussed in a religious studies class or in any course that considers religious explanations for the origin of life.'' The pamphlet gives the following general advice on how to teach about religion: _ `` The school's approach is academic, not devotional.'' _ `` The school may sponsor study about religion, but may not sponsor the practice of religion.'' _ `` The school may educate about all religions, but may not promote or denigrate any religion.'' _ `` The school may inform the student about various beliefs, but should not seek to conform him or her to any particular belief.'' `` Because religion plays a significant role in history and society,'' the pamphlet said, `` study about religion is essential to understanding both the nation and the world. Omission of facts about religion can give students the false impression that the religious life of humankind is insignificant or unimportant.'' `` Failure to understand even the basic symbols, practices and concepts of the various religions makes much of history, literature, art and contemporary life unintelligible.'' The pamphlet recommends `` careful'' handling of religious holidays in the classroom, with information focusing `` on the origin, history and generally agreed-upon meaning of the observances.'' Other sponsors include the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Religion </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Boards </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administrators </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Legal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conference </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Christians </ORGANIZATION> and Jews, the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Churches </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Christ </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> the </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Social </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Studies </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supervision </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Curriculum </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Teachers </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Education </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880601-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-01-88 0213EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Summit-Indians Bjt   06-01 0759</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Summit-Indians, Bjt,750</SECOND>
<HEAD>Reagan Outrages Indians by Saying America `Humored' Their
Ancestors</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 EDs: <PERSON> Suzan </PERSON> in 4th graf is correct
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>By GUY DARST</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The only American Indian in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> says President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> _ in claiming the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> `` humored'' native Americans by putting them on reservations _ appears to have learned all he knows on the subject from his old Western movies. `` I only wish the president knew as much about <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Indians </ORGANIZATION> as he seems to know about the Russians,'' said Rep. <PERSON> Ben </PERSON> <PERSON> Nighthorse </PERSON> <PERSON> Campbell </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Cheyenne </LOCATION> who represents the western half of <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION>. `` It's incredible he knows so little.'' <ORGANIZATION> Campbell </ORGANIZATION>, a Democrat, joined a chorus of Indian groups and others in denouncing <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s remarks to students at <ORGANIZATION> Moscow </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> on Tuesday. `` Maybe we made a mistake'' in trying to maintain Indian cultures, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said. `` Maybe we should not have humored them in that, wanting to stay in that kind of primitive lifestyle. Maybe we should have said, ` No, come join us. Be citizens along with the rest of us.''' <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> misspoke. All American Indians were made full <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> citizens by an act of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> in 1924. <PERSON> Suzan </PERSON> <PERSON> Harjo </PERSON>, executive director of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Indians </ORGANIZATION>, said she found the remark about `` humoring'' the <ORGANIZATION> Indians </ORGANIZATION> `` particularly insulting.'' <PERSON> Gregory </PERSON> <PERSON> Frazier </PERSON>, president of the Denver-based <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Urban </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Indian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>, said, `` I'm a fan of the president, but the president is a little bit removed from the reality of American Indians.'' <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> volunteered his comments when he was asked by a student if he would meet with three Indians visiting <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> under the auspices of the militant <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Indian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Movement </ORGANIZATION>. They went to the summit city to call attention to the problems of American Indians. `` We have provided millions of acres of land for what are called preservations _ or the reservations, I should say,'' <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said. `` They, from the beginning, announced that they wanted to maintain their way of life, as they had always lived there in the desert and the plains and so forth. And we set up these reservations so they could, and have a <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Indian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Affairs </ORGANIZATION> to help take care of them.'' Though many Indians leave the reservations, many stay, the president noted. The 1980 census found 1.37 million Indians, among whom 332,000 were living on 260 reservations. `` We've done everything we can to meet their demands as to what they _ how they want to live,'' <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Campbell </PERSON> said, `` He appears not to know that Indians are citizens. `` He must have been learning from these old celluloid Westerns of the 1930s he used to act in,'' the congressman said. `` There's no question that <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Indians </ORGANIZATION> do n't want to lose their traditions. But I do n't know any Indians who want to be primitive.'' <PERSON> Harjo </PERSON> said, `` I thought his notion of having granted Indians millions of acres of land was astonishing ... There was no grant involved; his ancestors were n't dragging any land behind them when they came to this country. `` He has headed the worst administration for <ORGANIZATION> Indians </ORGANIZATION> since the days of outright warfare and extermination,'' she said, because of `` consistent efforts by this administration to undo legal, long-standing rights and wipe out programs that meet our needs.'' Indians leave reservations for better jobs and education `` and politics,'' <PERSON> Frazier </PERSON> said. `` Life can be very hard on a reservation if you're part of the ` Out' party.'' But, `` Many Indians do n't have the choice to move off the reservation'' because they have no job skills that mainstream society will pay for, <PERSON> Frazier </PERSON> said. American Indians are among the poorest, worst-off of Americans. A government study noted that the 1980 census found 12 percent of all Americans living in poverty, but poverty among Indians affected 22 percent of those living off the reservation and 41 percent of Indians living on reservations. Unemployment on reservations frequently exceeds 60 percent and can reach 80 percent. Young Indian adults commit suicide at a rate six times their counterparts in mainstream society. <PERSON> Campbell </PERSON> noted that government policy had tried to dissolve tribes and force Indians to join mainstream culture as small farmers in 1887-1934, then turned around and tried to maintain tribes and tribal governments, but then flipped again to `` termination'' of tribes in the <PERSON> Eisenhower </PERSON> administration in the 1950s and flopped back to `` government-to-government'' policy in subsequent administrations, a policy <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> has affirmed. As for AIM and its three members in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Campbell </ORGANIZATION> said, `` People in AIM do not speak for all Indians. They speak for only a small minority.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880601-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-01-88 0015EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-AcidLeak     06-01 0191</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Acid Leak,0195</SECOND>
<HEAD>Fumes Overcome 38 After Acid Leak</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NILES, Mich. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Noxious fumes from an acid leak at a factory forced an evacuation of more than 130 residents and sent at least 38 people to a hospital for treatment, authorities said. Many of those treated at <LOCATION> Pawating </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION> were players and spectators at softball fields near the National-Standard wire and cable plant where the leak occurred about 6:15 p.m. Tuesday, nursing supervisor <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Ann </PERSON> <PERSON> Weaver </PERSON> said. Hydrochloric acid and another acid were mixed in a storage tank, causing the tank to rupture and the acids to form a puddle on the plant floor, said <PERSON> Dennis </PERSON> <PERSON> Sexton </PERSON>, a dispatcher with the <ORGANIZATION> Berrien </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sheriff </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>. The leak was contained with no fire or explosion, he said. Residents within three miles of the plant on <PERSON> Niles </PERSON>'s northeast side were ordered evacuated, but they returned when the area was declared safe within three hours, Mayor <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Clymer </PERSON> said. At least 130 people were sheltered temporarily at <ORGANIZATION> Ballard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Elementary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION>, about six miles from the plant on the west side of the southwestern <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION> city of 15,000, school Superintendent <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Huffman </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880601-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-01-88 0222EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Summit-Agreements     06-01 0192</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Summit-Agreements,180</SECOND>
<HEAD>Nine Agreements Signed at U.S.-Soviet Summit</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Summit Rdp Bjt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MOSCOW (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the agreements reached so far at the U.S.-Soviet summit.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>ICBM MISSILE TESTS:</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Each superpower will notify the other of the time, place and intended target of intercontinental-range ballistic missile tests. The notice of a test launching must be given at least 24 hours in advance and will be made through risk-reduction centers in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>___</HEAD>
<HEAD>NUCLEAR TESTING:</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 The superpowers will conduct an experiment to tighten verification techniques on a 1974 treaty limiting nuclear tests to 150 kilotons.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>___</HEAD>
<HEAD>CULTURE:</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 A cultural agreement signed in 1985 will be extended another three years.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>___</HEAD>
<HEAD>SPACE:</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Five working groups will explore cooperation in solar and other outer space programs.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>___</HEAD>
<HEAD>FISHING:</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Fishermen in the two countries will have access to each other's waters
</TEXT>
<HEAD>___</HEAD>
<HEAD>SEA RESCUE:</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> and the Soviets will cooperate in search and rescue operations.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>___</HEAD>
<HEAD>RADIO NAVIGATION:</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Cooperation in radio navigation techniques will be extended.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>___</HEAD>
<HEAD>ATOMIC ENERGY:</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 A 1973 accord for peaceful uses of atmomic energy will be extended.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>___</HEAD>
<HEAD>TRANSPORTATION:</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 The accord calls for cooperation in transportation.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880601-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-01-88 0225EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i BC-Reagan-StudentsText 5Takes   06-01 1056</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Reagan-Students Text, 5 Takes,1,000-up</SECOND>
<HEAD>Text of Reagan Speech Before University Students</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MOSCOW (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Following is the text of President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s speech Tuesday before a student assembly at <ORGANIZATION> Moscow </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>: Well, thank you, <PERSON> Rector </PERSON> <PERSON> Lagunov </PERSON>. And I want to thank all of you very much for a very warm welcome. It's a great pleasure to be here at <ORGANIZATION> Moscow </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, and I want to thank you all for turning out. I know you must be very busy this week, studying and taking your final examinations. So let me just say, -LRB- speaks in Russian -RRB-. -LRB- Applause. -RRB- <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> could n't make it today because she's visiting <LOCATION> Leningrad </LOCATION>, which she tells me is a very beautiful city. But she, too, says hello, and wishes you all good luck. Let me say it's also a great pleasure to once again have this opportunity to speak directly to the people of the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. Before I left <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, I received many heartfelt letters and telegrams, asking me to carry here a simple message, perhaps, but also one of the most important business of this summit. It is a message of peace and good will and hope for a growing friendship and closeness between our two peoples. As you know, I've come to <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> to meet with one of your most distinguished graduates. In this, our fourth summit, General Secretary <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> and I have spent many hours together, and I feel that we're getting to know each other well. Our discussions, of course, have been focused primarily on many of the important issues of the day, issues I want to touch on with you in a few moments. But first, I want to take a little time to talk to you, much as I would to any group of university students in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. I want to talk not just of the realities of today, but of the possibilities of tomorrow. Standing here before a mural of your revolution, I want to talk about a very different revolution that is taking place right now, quietly sweeping the globe without bloodshed or conflict. Its effects are peaceful, but they will fundamentally alter our world, shatter old assumptions and reshape our lives. It's easy to underestimate, because it's not accompanied by banners or fanfare. It's been called the `` technological'' or `` information'' revolution. And, as its emblem, one might take the tiny silicon chip, no bigger than a fingerprint. One of these chips has more computing power than a roomful of old-style computers. As part of an exchange program, we now have an exhibition touring your country that shows how information technology is transforming our lives, replacing manual labor with robots, forecasting weather for farmers, or mapping the genetic code of DNA for medical researchers. These microcomputers today aid the design of everything from houses to cars to spacecraft. They even design better and faster computers. They can translate English into Russian, or enable the blind to read, or help <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> produce on one synthesizer the sounds of a whole orchestra. Linked by a network of satellites and fiber optic cables, one individual with a desktop computer and a telephone commands resources unavailable to the largest governments just a few years ago. Like a chrysalis, we are emerging from the economy of the industrial revolution, an economy confined to and limited by the earth's physical resources, into, as one economist titled his book, `` The Economy in Mind,'' in which there are no bounds on human imagination and the freedom to create is the most precious natural resource. Think of that little computer chip. Its value is n't in the sand from which it is made, but in the microscopic architecture designed into it by ingenious human minds. Or take the example of the satellite relaying this broadcast around the world, which replaces thousands of tons of copper mined from the earth and molded into wire. In the new economy, human invention increasingly makes physical resources obsolete. We are breaking through the material conditions of existence to a world where man creates his own destiny. Even as we explore the most advanced reaches of science, we are returning to the age-old wisdom of our culture, a wisdom contained in the book of the Genesis in the Bible. In the beginning was the spirit, and it was from this spirit that the material abundance of creation issued forth. But progress is not foreordained. The key is freedom _ freedom of thought, freedom of information, freedom of communication. The renowned scientist, scholar and founding father of this university, <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> Lomonosov </PERSON>, knew that. `` It is common knowledge,'' he said, `` that the achievements of science are considerable and rapid, particularly once the yoke of slavery is cast off and replaced by the freedom of philosophy.'' You know, one of the first contacts between your country and mine took place between <LOCATION> Russian </LOCATION> and American explorers. The Americans were members of <PERSON> Cook </PERSON>'s last voyage on an expedition searching for an Arctic passage. On the island of <LOCATION> Unalaska </LOCATION>, they came upon the Russians, who took them in, and together with the native inhabitants, held a prayer service on the ice. The explorers of the modern era are the entrepreneurs, men with vision, with a courage to take risks and faith enough to brave the unknown. These entrepreneurs and their small enterprises are responsible for almost all the economic growth in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. They are the prime movers of the technological revolution. In fact, one of the largest personal computer firms in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> was started by two college students, no older than you, in the garage behind their home. Some people, even in my own country, look at the riot of experiment that is the free market and see only waste. What of all the entrepreneurs that fail? Well, many do, particularly the successful ones, often several times. And if you ask them the secret of their success, they'll tell you it's all that they learned in their struggles along the way Yes, it's what they learned from failing, like an athlete in competition or a scholar in pursuit of the truth. Experience is the greatest teacher. And that's why it's so hard for government planners, no matter how sophisticated, to ever substitute for millions of individuals working night and day to make their dreams come true.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>MORE</NOTE>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880601-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-01-88 0228EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i BC-Reagan-StudentsText 1stAdd   06-01 1034</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Reagan-Students Text, 1st Add,990</SECOND>
<HEAD>MOSCOW: come true.</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 The fact is, bureaucracies are a problem around the world. There's an old story about a town _ it could be anywhere _ with a bureaucrat who is known to be a good-for-nothing, but he somehow had always hung onto power. So one day, in a town meeting, an old woman got up and said to him, `` There is a folk legend here, where I come from, that when a baby is born, an angel comes down from heaven and kisses it on one part of its body. If the angel kisses him on his hand, he becomes a handyman. If he kisses him on his forehead, he becomes bright and clever. And I've been trying to figure out where the angel kissed you so that you should sit there for so long and do nothing.'' -LRB- Applause. -RRB- We are seeing the power of economic freedom spreading around the world. Places such as the Republic of <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Singapore </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION> have vaulted into the technological era, barely pausing in the industrial age along the way. Low-tax agricultural policies in the sub-continent mean that in some years, <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> is now a net exporter of food. Perhaps most exciting are the winds of change that are blowing over the People's <LOCATION> Republic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, where one-quarter of the world's population is now getting its first taste of economic freedom. At the same time, the growth of democracy has become one of the most powerful political movements of our age. In <LOCATION> Latin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> in the 1970s, only a third of the population lived under democratic government. Today, over 90 percent does. In the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION>, in the Republic of <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>, free contested democratic elections are the order of the day. Throughout the world, free markets are the model for growth. Democracy is the standard by which governments are measured. We Americans make no secret of our belief in freedom. In fact, it's something of a national pastime. Every four years, the <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> people choose a new president, and 1988 is one of those years. At one point, there were 13 major candidates running in the two major parties, not to mention all the others, including the Socialist and <ORGANIZATION> Libertarian </ORGANIZATION> candidates, all trying to get my job. About a 1,000 local television stations, 8,500 radio stations and 1,700 daily newspapers, each one an independent private enterprise, fiercely independent of the government, report on the candidates, grill them in interviews and bring them together for debates. In the end, the people vote. They decide who will be the next president. But freedom does n't begin or end with elections. Go to any <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> town, to take just an example, and you'll see dozens of churches, representing many different beliefs, in many places, synagogues and mosques, and you will see families of every conceivable nationality worshiping together. Go into any school room, and there you will see children being taught the Declaration of Independence; that they are endowed by their creator with certain inalienable rights, among them life, liberty, and the pursuit of happiness, that no government can justly deny; the guarantees in their Constitution for freedom of speech, freedom of assembly and freedom of religion. Go into any courtroom and there will preside an independent judge beholden to no government power. There, every defendant has the right to a trial by a jury of his peers, usually 12 men and women, common citizens. They are the ones, the only ones, who weigh the evidence and decide on guilt or innocence. In that court, the accused is innocent until proven guilty, and the word of a policeman or any official has no greater legal standing than the word of the accused. Go to any university campus and there you will find an open, sometimes heated discussion of the problems in American society and what can be done to correct them. Turn on the television, and you will see the legislature conducting the business of government right there before the camera, debating and voting on the legislation that will become the law of the land. March in any demonstration _ and there are many of them. The people's right of assembly is guaranteed in the Constitution and protected by the police. Go into any union hall where the members know their right to strike is protected by law. As a matter of fact, one of the many jobs I had before this one was being president of a union, the Screen Actors Guild. I led my union out on strike, and I'm proud to say we won. But freedom is more even than this. Freedom is the right to question and change the established way of doing things. It is the continuing revolution of the marketplace. It is the understanding that allows us to recognize shortcomings and seek solutions. It is the right to put forth and idea, scoffed at by the experts, and watch it catch fire among the people. It is the right to stick _ to dream, to follow your dream or stick to your conscience, even if you are the only one in a sea of doubters. Freedom is the recognition that no single person, no single authority or government has a monopoly on the truth, but that every individual life is infinitely precious, that every one of us put on this world has been put there for a reason and has something to offer. <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> is a nation made up of hundreds of nationalities. Our ties to you are more than ones of good feeling. They're ties of kinship. In <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, you'll find Russians, Armenians, Ukrainians, peoples from <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION>. They come from every part of this vast continent, from every continent, to live in harmony, seeking a place where each cultural heritage is respected, each is valued for its diverse strengths and beauties and the richness it brings to our lives. Recently, a few individuals and families have been allowed to visit relatives in the West. We can only hope that it wo n't be long before all are allowed to do so, and Ukrainian-Americans, Baltic-Americans, Armenian-Americans can freely visit their homelands, just as this Irish-American visits his.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>MOREE</NOTE>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880601-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-01-88 0233EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i BC-Reagan-StudentsText 2ndAdd   06-01 0989</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Reagan-Students Text, 2nd Add,990</SECOND>
<HEAD>MOSCOW: visits his.</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Freedom, it has been said, makes people selfish and materialistic. But Americans are one of the most religious peoples on earth, because they know that liberty, just as life itself, is not earned but a gift from God. They seek to share that gift with the world. `` Reason and experience,'' said <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Washington </PERSON> in his farewell address, `` both forbid us to expect that national morality can prevail in exclusion of religious principle.'' And it is substantially true that virtue or morality is a necessary spring of popular government. Democracy is less a system of government than it is a system to keep government limited, unintrusive, a system of constraints on power to keep politics and government secondary to the important things in life, the true sources of value found only in family and faith. But I hope you know, I go on about these things not simply to extol the virtues of my own country, but to speak to the true greatness of the heart and soul of your land. Who, after all, needs to tell the land of <PERSON> Dostoyevsky </PERSON> about the quest for truth, the home of <PERSON> Kandinsky </PERSON> and <PERSON> Scriabin </PERSON> about imagination, the rich and noble culture of the Uzbek man of letters, <PERSON> Ali </PERSON> <PERSON> Sheer </PERSON> <PERSON> Nevoyai </PERSON>, about beauty and heart? The great culture of your diverse land speaks with a glowing passion to all humanity. Let me cite one of the most eloquent contemporary passages on human freedom. It comes not from the literature of <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, but from this country, from one of the greatest writers of the 20th century, <PERSON> Boris </PERSON> <PERSON> Pasternak </PERSON>, in the novel `` Dr. Zhivago.'' He writes: `` I think that if the beast who sleeps in man could be held down by threats, any kind of threat, whether of jail or of retribution after death, then the highest emblem of humanity would be the lion tamer in the circus with his whip, not the prophet who sacrificed himself.'' `` But this is just the point: What has for centuries raised man above the beast is not the cudgel, but an inward music, the irresistible power of unarmed truth _ the irresistible power of unarmed truth.'' Today the world looks expectedly to signs of change, steps toward greater freedom in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. We watch and we hope as we see positive changes taking place. There are some I know in your society who fear that change will bring only disruption and discontinuity, who fear to embrace the hope of the future. Sometimes it takes faith. It's like that scene in the cowboy movie, `` Butch Cassidy and the Sundance Kid,'' which some here in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> recently had a chance to see. The posse is closing in on the two outlaws, <PERSON> Butch </PERSON> and Sundance, who find themselves trapped on the edge of a cliff with a sheer drop of hundreds of feet to the raging rapids below. Butch turns to Sundance and says their only hope is to jump into the river below. But Sundance refuses. He says he'd rather fight it out with the posse, even though they're hopelessly outnumbered. <PERSON> Butch </PERSON> says that's suicide, and urges him to jump. But Sundance still refuses, and finally admits, `` I ca n't swim.'' <PERSON> Butch </PERSON> breaks up laughing and says, `` You crazy fool. The fall will probably kill you.'' And by the way, both <PERSON> Butch </PERSON> and Sundance made it, in case you did n't see the movie. I think what I've just been talking about is perestroika and what its goals are. But change would not mean rejection of the past. Like a tree growing strong through the seasons, rooted in the earth and drawing life from the sun, so too, positive change must be rooted in traditional values _ in the land, in culture, in family and community. And it must take its life from the eternal things, from the source of all life, which is faith. Such change will lead to new understandings, new opportunities, to a broader future in which the tradition is not supplanted but finds its full flowering. That is the future beckoning to your generation. At the same time, we should remember that reform that is not institutionalized will always be insecure. Such freedom will always be looking over its shoulder. A bird on a tether, no matter how long the rope, can always be pulled back. And that is why, in my conversation with General Secretary <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>, I have spoken of how important it is to institutionalize change, to put guarantees on reform. And we have been talking together about one sad reminder of a divided world: the Berlin Wall. It's time to remove the barriers that keep people apart. I am proposing an increased exchange program of high school students between our countries. General Secretary <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> mentioned on Sunday a wonderful phrase you have in Russian for this, `` Better to see something once than to hear about it a hundred times.'' Mr. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> and I first began working on this in 1985. In our discussion today, we agreed on working up to several thousand exchanges a year from each country in the near future. But not everyone can travel across the continents and oceans. Words travel lighter, and that's why we'd like to make available to this country more of our 11,000 magazines and periodicals, and our television and radio shows that can be beamed off a satellite in seconds. Nothing would please us more than for the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> people to get to know us better and to understand our way of life. Just a few years ago, few would have imagined the progress our two nations have made together. The INF treaty, which General Secretary <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> and I signed last December in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, and whose instruments of ratification we will exchange tomorrow, the first true nuclear arms reduction treaty in history, calling for the elimination of an entire class of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and Soviet nuclear missiles.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>MOREE</NOTE>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880601-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-01-88 0236EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i BC-Reagan-StudentsText 3rdAdd   06-01 0522</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Reagan-Students Text, 3rd Add,510</SECOND>
<HEAD>MOSCOW: nuclear missiles.</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 And just 16 days ago, we saw the beginning of your withdrawal from <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>, which gives us hope that soon the fighting may end and the healing may begin, and that that suffering country may find self-determination, unity and peace at long last. It's my fervent hope that our constructive cooperation on these issues will be carried on to address the continuing destruction of conflicts in many regions of the globe, and that the serious discussions that led to the <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> Accords on <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> will help lead to solutions in southern <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ethiopia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>. I have often said nations do not distrust each other because they are armed; they are armed because they distrust each other. If this globe is to live in peace and prosper, if it is to embrace all the possibilities of technological revolution, then nations must renounce, once and for all, the right to an expansionist foreign policy. Peace between nations must be an enduring goal, not a tactical stage in a continuing conflict. I've been told that there's a popular song in your country -- perhaps you know it -- whose evocative refrain asks the question, `` Do the Russians want a war?'' In answer, it says, `` Go ask that silence lingering in the air above the birch and poplar there. Beneath those trees the soldiers lie. Go ask my mother, ask my wife. Then you will have to ask no more, do the Russians want a war?'' But what of your one-time allies? What of those who embraced you on the Elbe? What if we were to ask the watery graves of the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> or the European battlefields, where <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s fallen were buried far from home? What if we were to ask their mothers, sisters and sons, do Americans want war? Ask us, too, and you'll find the same answer, the same longing in every heart. People do not make wars _ governments do. And no mother would ever willingly sacrifice her sons for territorial gain, for economic advantage, for ideology. A people free to choose will always choose peace. Americans seek always to make friends of old antagonists. After a colonial revolution with <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>, we have cemented for all ages the ties of kinship between our nations. After a terrible civil war between <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> South </LOCATION>, we healed our wounds and found true unity as a nation. We've fought two world wars in my lifetime, against <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> and one with <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>. But now the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Germany </ORGANIZATION> and <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> are two of our closest allies and friends. Some people point to the trade disputes between us as a sign of strength, but they're the frictions of all families, and the family of free nations is a big and vital and sometimes boisterous one. I can tell you that nothing would please my heart more than in my lifetime to see American and Soviet diplomats grappling with the problem of trade disputes between <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> and a growing, exuberant, exporting <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> that it opened up to economic freedom and growth.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>MORE</NOTE>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880601-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-01-88 0018EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a PM-Names     06-01 0967</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,1004</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in The News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Chrysler </ORGANIZATION> Chairman and best-selling author <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Iacocca </PERSON> is back with another autobiography, this time revealing that he once considered taking over <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Motors </ORGANIZATION> but decided `` it might be easier to buy <LOCATION> Greece </LOCATION>.'' `` Talking Straight'' arrives in bookstores today. The initial printing is 750,000; booksellers can only hope it measures up to `` Iacocca: An Autobiography,'' which has sold 2.6 million hardcover copies and 3.5 million paperbacks worldwide. In the new book, <PERSON> Iacocca </PERSON> writes that last spring, automobile dealer <PERSON> Victor </PERSON> <PERSON> Potamkin </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> Allied-Signal </ORGANIZATION> chairman <PERSON> Ed </PERSON> <PERSON> Hennessy </PERSON> approached him separately to suggest an unsolicited takeover of the industry behemoth, <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Motors </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>. At first, <PERSON> Iacocca </PERSON> wrote, he dismissed the idea But talks continued, and <PERSON> Iacocca </PERSON> even met secretly with investment banker <PERSON> Felix </PERSON> <PERSON> Rohatyn </PERSON>, consulted a takeover lawyer and investigated financing before dropping the proposal. `` I concluded that it might be easier to buy <LOCATION> Greece </LOCATION>,'' he said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
