<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880926-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-26-88 0003EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p BC-DebateText 17thadd   09-26 0710</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Debate Text, 17th add,710</SECOND>
<HEAD>WINSTON-SALEM, N.C.: American people.</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Lehrer: <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Jennings </PERSON>, a question for the vice president. Jennings: Mr. Vice President, I'm struck by your discussion of women and the sanctity of life and it leads me to recall your own phrase that you are `` haunted'' by the lives which children in our inner cities live. Certainly the evidence is compelling, there's an explosion of single-parent families, and by any measure these single-parent families _ many with unwanted children _ are the source of poverty, school dropouts, crime which many people in the inner city simply feel is out of control. If it haunts you so, why over the eight years of the Reagan-Bush administration have so many programs designed to help the inner cities been eliminated or cut? <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>: One of the reasons _ and I first would like to know which programs you're talking about and then we could talk on the merits of the programs _ but you see my fundamental philosophy is give local and state government as much control as possible. That might be the explanation if you tell me the program. I do strongly support the WIC program. I think it is good. I think part of the answer to the haunting of these children that are out there and suffering lies in extension of Medicaid to challenge the states and maybe, maybe we're going to have to enforce more on the states in terms of Medicaid taking care of these. But, <PERSON> Peter </PERSON>, so much of it is _ gets into a whole other phase of things. The neighborhood, the kind of environment people are growing up in. And that leads me to the programs I'm talking about in terms of education. I think part of it is the crime-infested neighborhoods, and that's why I'm a strong believer in trying to control crimes in the neighborhood, why I was so pleased to be endorsed by the policemen on the beat _ the <ORGANIZATION> Boston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> _ the other day. I think they understand my commitment to helping them in the neighborhoods. And so, it's a combination of these things. But do not erode out of the system the thousand points of light, the people that are out there trying to help these kids, the programs like cities and schools, the work that <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> is doing so people can learn to read in this country, and then go on and break this cycle of poverty. I'm for Head Start, moving that up, and I've already made a proposal. And yes, it'll cost some money, but I favor that. So these are the combination of things I want, and the fact that I do n't think the federal government can endorse a $ 35 billion program does not mean I have less compassion than the person who endorses such a program. Q. Governor? <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>: Well, I must have been living through a different eight years from the one that the vice president's been living through, because this administration has cut and slashed and cut and slashed programs for children, for nutrition, for the kinds of things that can help these youngsters to live better lives. It's cut federal aid to education; it has cut <ORGANIZATION> Pell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Grants </ORGANIZATION> and loans to close the door to college opportunity on youngsters all over this country. And that, too, is a major difference between the vice president and me. Let me just give you one other example. We have a great many people _ hundreds of thousands of people _ living on public assistance in this country. The 50 governors of this nation have proposed to the <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> that we help those families to get off of welfare, help those youngsters, help their mothers to become independent and self-sufficient. It's taken months and months and months to get Mr. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and the administration to support that legislation, and they're still resisting. Now, that's the way you help people. Being haunted _ `` a thousand points of light'' _ I do n't know what that means. I know what strong political leadership is. I know what's happened over the course of the past eight years These programs have been cut and slashed and butchered, and they've hurt kids all over this country.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>MORE</NOTE>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880926-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-26-88 0008EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p BC-DebateText 18thadd   09-26 0417</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Debate Text, 18th add,400</SECOND>
<HEAD>WINSTON-SALEM, N.C.: this country.</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Jennings: Governor, the crisis is no less a crisis for you if you were elected president. Where would you get the money to devote to the inner cities, which is clearly needed? And can you be specific about the programs not only you'd reinstate, but the more imaginative ones that you'd begin? <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>: Well, I said a few minutes ago, <PERSON> Peter </PERSON>, that you could improve the lives of families and youngsters and save money at the same time. Welfare reform is one way to do it. If we invest in job training, in child care for those youngsters, in some extended health benefits so that that mother and her kids do n't lose their health benefits when she goes to work, we can help, literally, hundreds of thousands, if not millions, of families to get off of welfare, to become independent and self-sufficient, to be taxpaying citizens, and to improve their lives _ the quality of lives, their futures, and the futures of those children. That's just one example of how you can save money and improve the quality of life at the same time. In my own state, for example, we now have that universal health care system, which the vice president opposes, I think very unwisely. One of the greatest barriers to opportunity for a family and for those children is the threat that they may lose their health insurance. Think about that father down there in <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION> who has to tell his youngster that he ca n't play <ORGANIZATION> Little </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> League </ORGANIZATION> ball, that he ca n't go out on that ball field, because he's afraid he's going to get hurt And, yet, Mr. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> says, `` Well, I do n't think we ought to expect businesses to provide health insurance for their employees.'' When responsible employers, a majority of employers in this country do and are paying more for their insurance to reimburse hospitals for free care on account of people that are not employed, that are not insured that have to go to that hospital. So, these are the ways that you help families, you help youngsters to live better lives and more decent lives. And we're ready to go to work at the state and local level, all of us I know the private sector is. People are all over the country. But, it takes presidential leadership. It takes a commitment to being involved and to leading. And that's the kind of presidency I want to lead.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>MORE</NOTE>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880926-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-26-88 0055EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lites     09-26 0360</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lites,0373</SECOND>
<HEAD>On The Light Side</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WALNUT CREEK, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Anita </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Hearn </PERSON> has come up with a not-so-subtle way to attract suitors: a huge balloon tethered to a building by a heavily traveled interstate that reads, `` MARRY ME!!! INTERESTED?'' The 12-foot by 10-foot balloon floating along Interstate 680 near this <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION> area city also sports a painting of a platinum blonde in a black velvet dress reclining on a red couch _ and <PERSON> O'Hearn </PERSON>'s phone number. A call to that number gets a tape-recorded voice of <PERSON> O'Hearn </PERSON> singing `` The Man I Love.'' Callers also get a letter and a questionnaire from <PERSON> O'Hearn </PERSON>, who describes herself as the over-40, 250-pound, almost 6-foot-tall `` blonde on the balloon.'' She says she is a professional singer, comedian, writer and entrepreneur. `` If you are still interested and would love a woman who just fell, fully clothed, out of a Rubens painting ... read on,'' she said in her letter. <PERSON> O'Hearn </PERSON> said recently that she's gotten 20 calls so far.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>Eds: This item also moved on the financial wire.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Children can begin learning about banking at a tender age at the <ORGANIZATION> First </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Children </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION>, which has opened at famed toy store F.A.O. <PERSON> Schwarz </PERSON>. The bank, which drew more than 2,000 youngsters and their parents to its opening Sunday, will offer savings and deposit accounts, sell certificates of deposit and hold lectures and seminars on banking and money, according to a news release. `` If this bank can help young people learn more about financial matters, then maybe it wo n't be such a daunting experience when they take out their first mortgage 20 years later,'' said <PERSON> Neale </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Godfrey </PERSON>, president and chief operating officer of the <ORGANIZATION> First </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Women </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION>, which opened the children's bank She said the idea for the bank came to her two years ago after her daughter asked why there was bank for adults and not for children. Savings accounts may be opened on behalf of children of any age. Checking accounts must be opened jointly with a child of at least 6 years old and an adult, both of whom must sign the checks.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880926-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-26-88 0013EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-BARTStrike 3rdLd-Writethru a0796 09-26 0319</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BART Strike, 3rd Ld-Writethru, a0796,0323</SECOND>
<HEAD>Tentative Settlement Reached With San Francisco Commuter Rail
Union</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: UPDATES throughout with ratification vote set for Wednesday,
quotes from union officials; Waalkens cq in 4th graf.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By RICH CARTIERE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>OAKLAND, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Union officials and <ORGANIZATION> Bay </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Area </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rapid </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transit </ORGANIZATION> authorities reached a tentative contract settlement Sunday on the eve of a threatened strike that would affect about 100,000 commuters on the 71-mile train line. `` Both sides compromised and compromised, and then we met _ sort of happily _ in the middle,'' said <PERSON> Suzanne </PERSON> <PERSON> Angeli </PERSON>, vice president of <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Employees </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Local </ORGANIZATION> 790. Union negotiators and <ORGANIZATION> BART </ORGANIZATION> officials held face-to-face talks throughout the weekend with a state mediator before a settlement was reached late Sunday afternoon. The agreement was announced at a joint news conference Sunday evening. A ratification vote is set for Wednesday, and Local 790 President <PERSON> Milt </PERSON> <PERSON> Waalkens </PERSON> predicted approval. `` I think they will be as happy as they can be with what we've gotten,'' he said Details of the tentative settlement were not released. A strike had been called for Monday morning after 1,200 janitors, maintenance workers and clerks rejected a contract offer last week. As negotiations took place Sunday, agency managers were being trained in operations of the train system, <ORGANIZATION> BART </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Sy </PERSON> <PERSON> Mouber </PERSON> said. A wildcat strike threatened for Sunday by union representatives angry about the training did not materialize, <PERSON> Mouber </PERSON> said. <ORGANIZATION> BART </ORGANIZATION> hoped the training would enable it to operate about half its normal service Monday with the use of 42 management employees. Another union, which represents 500 station agents and train operators had agreed to a contract with <ORGANIZATION> BART </ORGANIZATION> but promised to honor Local 790's picket lines. Those lines had been scheduled to form at 6 a.m. Monday at 34 stations. The disputed contract proposals involved profits from retirement fund investments, union activity during work hours, sick leave restrictions and overtime.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880926-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-26-88 0014EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p BC-DebateText 19thadd   09-26 0459</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Debate Text, 19th add,400</SECOND>
<HEAD>WINSTON-SALEM, N.C.: to lead.</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Lehrer: Mr. Vice President. Bush: What troubles me is that when I talk of the voluntary sector and a `` thousand points of light'' and a thousand different ways to help on these problems, the man has just said he does n't understand what I'm talking about And this is the problem I have with the big-spending liberals. They think the only way to do it is for the federal government to do it all. The fact happens to be that education spending is up by the federal government. It is up, it is not down. The federal, but here's the point he misses, the federal government spends 7 percent of the total money on education, and the rest of the state governments and local governments, and the `` thousand points of light'' _ and I'm talking about private schools, and private church schools, and things of this nature _ are putting up 93 percent. But the federal spending for education is up. And I want to be the `` education president,'' because I want to see us do better. We're putting more money per child into education, and we are not performing as we should. We've gotten away from the values and the fundamentals, and I would like to urge the school superintendents and the others around the country to stand up now and keep us moving forward on a path toward real excellence. And we can do it, but it's not going to be dictated by some federal bureaucracy in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION> Lehrer: All right. Let's move now to some questions on foreign and national security policy. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Mashek </PERSON> will ask the first question of the governor. <PERSON> Mashek </PERSON>: Governor, the vice president continually refers to your lack of experience, weakness, naivete on foreign policy and national security matters. He says you are prepared to eliminate weapons systems that will result in the unilateral disarmament of this country. Is that true? <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>: Of course not. Of course, that's a charge that's always made against any governor who runs for the presidency. I think it was one of the things that Mr. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said about Mr. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> back in 1980. Remember that, <PERSON> George </PERSON>? And yet, some of our finest presidents, some of our strongest international leaders were governors: <LOCATION> Franklin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Roosevelt </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Woodrow </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON>, <PERSON> Theodore </PERSON> <PERSON> Roosevelt </PERSON>. It's not the amount of time you've spent in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, it's not the length of your resume. It's your strength, it's your values, it's the quality of the people you pick, it's your understanding of the forces of change that are sweeping the world, and whether or not you're in a position to provide leadership to make those forces of change work for us and not against us.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>MORE</NOTE>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880926-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-26-88 0133EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Reagan-UnitedNations Bjt   09-26 0565</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Reagan-United Nations, Bjt,550</SECOND>
<HEAD>Reagan's U.N. Speech Focuses on World View</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Top expected before 9:15 a.m. EDT based on text of speech</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By W. DALE NELSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> promised to outline his view of what lies ahead for the world as he went before the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> today for his seventh appearance and his last before leaving office. Asked as he returned from a weekend at Camp David, <LOCATION> Md. </LOCATION>, on Sunday whether he was looking forward to his annual visit for the opening of the <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, the president answered with a single word: `` Yes.'' An official who spoke on the condition of anonymity said over the weekend that <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> would deal in his speech with the thorny issue of chemical weapons, which the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and many other Western nations manufacture. The president's national security adviser, Lt. Gen. <PERSON> Colin </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Powell </PERSON>, predicted last week that the president also would press efforts to stem the proliferation of such weapons in individual talks with world leaders. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> has addressed the opening session of the <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION> each year since 1983. He also spoke at a special <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> session on disarmament in 1982. In his weekly radio speech Saturday, the president said he would talk today about his administration's record of `` successes for our philosophy of peace through strength.'' `` The great question now is, what next?'' he added. `` Where does the world go in the next eight years and the next 80 years? What are the steps we might take toward a safer, better, freer world? And I'll have some thoughts of my own on Monday.'' `` One thing is certain,'' he said. ` If we're to continue to advance world peace and human freedom, <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> must remain strong. We must turn a deaf ear to those born-again patriots who talk about strength while serving up the same old menu of weakness.'' The president did n't say whom he was talking about, but the words were similar to those he has used to describe the campaign of Democratic presidential nominee <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>. After his speech, the president planned to meet with <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> Secretary General <PERSON> Javier </PERSON> <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Cuellar </PERSON>; with senior advisers at the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> mission to the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION>; with Egyptian Foreign Minister <PERSON> Esmat </PERSON> <PERSON> Abdel-Meguid </PERSON> and Israeli Foreign Minister <PERSON> Shimon </PERSON> <PERSON> Peres </PERSON>; with President <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Mugabe </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Zimbabwe </LOCATION>; with <PERSON> Sheik </PERSON> <PERSON> Sabah </PERSON> <PERSON> Al-Ahmed </PERSON>, foreign minister of <LOCATION> Kuwait </LOCATION>; and with members of the <ORGANIZATION> Persian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Gulf </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cooperation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Powell </PERSON> told reporters the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> is `` committed to a comprehensive, worldwide ban on chemical weapons'' and he expected <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> to `` press the issue'' in his talks. Both <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> used chemical weapons in their eight-year <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> war. In addition, the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has accused <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> of using poison gas against its Kurdish minority. It will be <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s first meeting with <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Cuellar </PERSON> since the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>'s announcement on Sept. 13 that the president was releasing $ 188 million the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> had withheld from the organization to show displeasure with <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> budgetary and hiring practices. <PERSON> Powell </PERSON> said the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> had responded to <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> suggestions by making changes in its budget procedures and the size of its staff and that the president wanted to recognize this as well as the fact that the organization `` has started to play a more important role around the world in helping to deal with regional conflicts.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880926-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-26-88 0137EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-SiberianMigration     09-26 0554</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Siberian Migration,530</SECOND>
<HEAD>U.S.-Soviet Exhibit Showcases Rare Alaskan Artifacts</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BRYAN BRUMLEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 When <PERSON> Spencer </PERSON> <PERSON> Fullerton </PERSON> <PERSON> Baird </PERSON> sent a team of scientists to <LOCATION> Russian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> in 1865, he expected them to return to the Smithsonian Institution with samples of birds, animals and Eskimo artifacts. They brought back all that, as well as evidence of mineral wealth that helped persuade a reluctant <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> two years later to spend $ 7.2 million to buy <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> from the Russian czar. `` Seward's Folly'' it was called, after <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> Seward </PERSON>, who was then secretary of state Many of the samples collected in those and later expeditions, including some native American hunting cloaks of astounding beauty, have gone on display at a joint U.S.-Soviet exhibit that also features samples collected by 18th century Russian pioneers but never before shown. The exhibit is at the <ORGANIZATION> Smithsonian </ORGANIZATION>'s Museum of Natural History. `` This is a story that no one country can tell,'' said <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzhugh </PERSON>, curator of the show, which is the fruit of a decade of planning and cooperation between American and Soviet anthropologists. The exhibit, `` Crossroads of Continents: Cultures of <LOCATION> Siberia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>,'' also highlights recent scientific findings about the migration of people across the <LOCATION> Bering </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strait </LOCATION> 11,000 years to 12,000 years ago and the development of native American culture in the far Northwest. And now, 121 years after <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> was sold for a song, Russian scholars flocked to the <LOCATION> Smithsonian </LOCATION> last week for a series of seminars on the links between ethnic groups in <LOCATION> Far </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Siberia </LOCATION> and the Eskimo, Aleut, Athapaskan, <ORGANIZATION> Eyak </ORGANIZATION> and Tlingit peoples of <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> and northwestern <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>. `` So we learn that the <ORGANIZATION> Smithsonian </ORGANIZATION> played a leading role in convincing <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> in the 19th century to buy <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>,'' said <PERSON> Aleksandr </PERSON> <PERSON> Potemkin </PERSON>, cultural attache at the Soviet Embassy in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. `` It is the same Smithsonian Institution that is playing a leading role in bringing the neighbors together again,'' he said. The exhibition, part of increased cultural cooperation between the superpowers, breaks new ground in several respects. It provides Western scholars with their first look at examples of Eskimo and Tlingit art collected for the czars by explorers like <PERSON> Vitus </PERSON> <PERSON> Bering </PERSON>, and by scientists and Russian traders who settled as far south as <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION>. Many of the objects have been stored out of public sight in the Museum of Anthropology and Ethnography, the oldest museum in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, founded in what is now <LOCATION> Leningrad </LOCATION> by <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> the Great in 1714. In another first, after the exhibition tours the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, with stops in <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Indianapolis </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Anchorage </LOCATION>, it will go to <LOCATION> Ottawa </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>, and then to <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Leningrad </LOCATION> and two Soviet cities yet to be chosen. The rich collection of clothes, hunting devices and other utensils on display testify to the links between the native cultures of <LOCATION> Siberia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>, and also the differences. Many of the Siberian peoples, said <PERSON> Fitzhugh </PERSON>, learned to raise herds of reindeer. That form of life involves a more complex social structure than that of the <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> peoples, who remained largely hunter-gatherers. `` The hunters had a spiritual relation with the animals that were their prey,'' said <PERSON> Fitzhugh </PERSON>. And when they hunted, they wore their best clothes, including one elaborate cloak sewn of gut and decorated with cormorant feathers, <PERSON> Fitzhugh </PERSON>'s favorite object in the exhibit.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880926-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-26-88 0136EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-MetOpening     09-26 0579</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Met Opening,0589</SECOND>
<HEAD>Opera Season Opens With War Horse; Real Excitement Lies Ahead</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By MIKE SILVERMAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Metropolitan Opera's 105th season may be opening with something of a musical whimper, but it promises to end with a bang. The gold curtain will rise tonight on a production of <PERSON> Verdi </PERSON>'s `` Il Trovatore'' that, when it premiered last season, provoked some of the most scathing critical catcalls in recent memory When the season ends in May, it will be with a musical event of historic proportions _ three performances of <PERSON> Wagner </PERSON>'s four-opera Ring Cycle, not seen in its entirety at the Met for a generation. In between are a number of promising evenings _ starting with the second night of the season when <PERSON> Handel </PERSON>'s `` Giulio Cesare'' will be presented at the Met for the first time. <PERSON> Kathleen </PERSON> <PERSON> Battle </PERSON> and <PERSON> Tatyana </PERSON> <PERSON> Troyanos </PERSON> will star, along with <PERSON> Jeffrey </PERSON> <PERSON> Gall </PERSON>, the first countertenor ever to sing at the Met. The Handel masterpiece will be conducted by <PERSON> Trevor </PERSON> <PERSON> Pinnock </PERSON>, the British early music specialist who not only has never conducted at the Met before but has never conducted any opera before. He will be leading an orchestra of about 30 players, unusually small for the Met pit. By contrast, there is little new or unusual about `` Il Trovatore.'' Met artistic director <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Levine </PERSON> will conduct an all-star cast that includes <PERSON> Luciano </PERSON> <PERSON> Pavarotti </PERSON>, <PERSON> Eva </PERSON> <PERSON> Marton </PERSON> and <PERSON> Sherrill </PERSON> <PERSON> Milnes </PERSON>, but whether they can overcome the dreary staging remains to be seen. `` Normally it takes a new opera production years to decline to the point of terminal weariness and ineptitude, but the Metropolitan Opera's ` Trovatore' reached that sad state in one evening,'' <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> chief music critic <PERSON> Donal </PERSON> <PERSON> Henahan </PERSON> wrote after the premiere last fall. Of <LOCATION> Fabrizio </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Melano </LOCATION>'s production, <PERSON> Henahan </PERSON> said, `` The idea that anyone actually directed the solo singers or the chorus strained belief.'' <PERSON> Ezio </PERSON> <PERSON> Frigerio </PERSON>'s sets, he wrote, `` consisted mostly of six groups of marbleized pillars that moved about for reasons known perhaps only to the designer.'' Despite this and other pans, most upcoming performances of `` Trovatore'' have been sold out for weeks. That includes opening night, when tickets cost up to $ 1,000, a price that entitles the holder to attend a post-opera party. Total gross revenues from the evening will come to $ 629,000. `` Gradually, we're making opening night into the gala social event it was 25 years ago,'' explained Met spokeswoman <PERSON> Johanna </PERSON> <PERSON> Fiedler </PERSON>. `` If you approach it that way, then it makes sense to do something like <PERSON> Verdi </PERSON> that is popular with the kind of audience that goes to galas.'' A key ingredient of success for such a gala seems to be the presence of either <PERSON> Pavarotti </PERSON> or the world's other leading operatic tenor, <PERSON> Placido </PERSON> <PERSON> Domingo </PERSON>. One or the other has starred in five out of the last six opening nights, and <PERSON> Domingo </PERSON> will be on hand when the Met puts on another gala in December _ a new production of <PERSON> Verdi </PERSON>'s `` Aida. The three Ring Cycles that will climax the season represent the fulfillment of a longtime dream for <PERSON> Levine </PERSON>, restoring to the repertory for the first time since the early 1970s one of the crowning works of opera. The production by <PERSON> Otto </PERSON> <PERSON> Schenk </PERSON> has sets and projections by <PERSON> Guenther </PERSON> <PERSON> Schneider-Siemssen </PERSON> that combine an old-fashioned literalism with modern technology. The cast, led by <PERSON> Hildegarde </PERSON> <PERSON> Behrens </PERSON> as <PERSON> Bruennhilde </PERSON>, is about the best available in today's impoverished world of Wagnerian singing.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880926-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-26-88 0139EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-BrailleGreetings     09-26 0732</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Braille Greetings,0750</SECOND>
<HEAD>Greeting Card Designer Wants To Bridge Gap Between Blind And
Sighted</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By LISA PERLMAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>KALAMAZOO, Mich. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 With something as simple as a greeting card, <PERSON> Truesillia </PERSON> <PERSON> Ruth </PERSON> <PERSON> Shank </PERSON> hopes to help bridge the gap between the worlds of the sighted and the blind. `` It seems so unfair that a blind person should miss out on the simple, little pleasures of life,'' said Mrs. <PERSON> Shank </PERSON>, sitting in the living room of her modest home that doubles as the office for her 7-month-old card company, Sucurre Greetings. Sucurre is an Old French word meaning `` to assist.'' `` Can you imagine being 30, 40 or 50 years old and having to wait for someone to read a stack of Christmas cards to you? Or not being able to go into a store and pick out an anniversary card for your wife or a birthday card for your child?'' she asked. The inspiration for Sucurre Greetings, which Mrs. <PERSON> Shank </PERSON> owns with her husband, came while she was working on an advertising project with a blind businessman. `` He was doing things I could n't do even with my sight,'' she said. `` It just did n't seem right that he needed someone to go to a store with him just to pick out a card.'' Because of the limited market, Braille greeting cards have not been manufactured by established card companies, said <PERSON> Adam </PERSON> <PERSON> Ash </PERSON>, publisher of the Gift Reporter, a trade publication for the gift industry. Some rehabilitation agencies have been known to sell some Braille cards at Christmas, and others translate greeting cards to Braille when requested. `` At best, what you've been able to get up until now is a card for a sighted person that's been Brailled. These cards are designed specifically for a visually impaired person, but are still appealing to a sighted person as well,'' said <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Ponchillia </PERSON>, a professor in the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Blind </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rehabilitation </ORGANIZATION> at <ORGANIZATION> Western </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Michigan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Ponchillia </PERSON>, who is blind, helped the Shanks design the cards. The Shanks, also co-owners of a year-old advertising and printing company, hope the pastel colors and simple but elegant designs embossed on the front of the cards will appeal to a wide audience. Underneath the design is a description of the object in <LOCATION> Braille </LOCATION>. Inside, Braille appears under the message, typically a short phrase with slightly raised letters. One lavender card has an embossed bird in flight on the cover. Inside, the message is `` My heart's all a-flutter.'' In addition to her basic line of 25 cards, Mrs. <PERSON> Shank </PERSON> said she also has a line of Christmas cards. `` We want the person to get the full impact of the card _ a card that everyone can enjoy,'' said Mrs. <PERSON> Shank </PERSON>, a bubbly, 32-year-old mother of three. She does the embossing by hand. Her husband, <PERSON> Michael </PERSON>, art director at a television station, does much of the designing and printing. Most of the Brailling is done by blind volunteers. Distribution of the cards is mostly limited to local card shops, but Mrs. <PERSON> Shank </PERSON> says she fills mail orders and is trying to line up distributors for the cards in other parts of the country. The cards sell for $ 2 and $ 2.50 locally. If the cards catch on, the <PERSON> Shanks </PERSON> would like to provide jobs for blind rehabilitation and training groups. And it looks as if the cards may be catching on. <PERSON> Marshall </PERSON> <PERSON> Field </PERSON> has expressed interest in buying the line for their chain of department stores, as well as an alphabet book Mrs. <PERSON> Shank </PERSON> designed for use by both sighted and blind children. `` Before getting involved in this, I never really knew a blind person and I do n't think I ever remember seeing a book that's shown me what <PERSON> Braille </PERSON>'s like,'' she said. `` We planned the book to get rid of the gap between sighted and blind children. We want a sighted child to know what Braille feels like and a blind child to be able to feel the letters that we're seeing Maybe that way we can get rid of some of the prejudice.'' Prejudice is a subject Mrs. <PERSON> Shank </PERSON> knows well. `` Because I'm black, some people might ask why I'm not doing something for a black cause. Well, blindness knows no color. When people stop being prejudiced against blind people or handicapped people, maybe they'll stop being prejudiced about black people,'' she said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880926-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-26-88 0140EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Hirohito-News     09-26 0647</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Hirohito-News,0665</SECOND>
<HEAD>Frustration Over Lack of Information, Conflicting Reports On
Emperor</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Hirohito</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By TETSUO JIMBO</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 As Emperor <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON> lies in his sickbed, a lack of information and conflicting reports on his health are provoking frustration and concern. The <ORGANIZATION> Imperial </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Household </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION>'s stubborn reluctance to release detailed information about the monarch is drawing increasingly strong criticism. `` I am getting the strong impression that the emperor's real condition may be much worse than what's been reported,'' said <PERSON> Naoki </PERSON> <PERSON> Inose </PERSON>, author of several books on the imperial family. `` Only a handful of doctors, nurses and servants actually get to see the emperor other than those in the imperial family.'' The <ORGANIZATION> Imperial </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Household </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION>, which handles all matters concerning the monarchy, has been releasing only the emperor's temperature, blood pressure and pulse three to four times a day along with a brief comment about his condition `` What we are interested in is how the emperor is really doing, not those medical numbers,'' said a middle-aged man who came to the palace Sunday to sign his name in a registry of well-wishers. `` His condition is everyone's interest.'' A reporter for a nationally circulated newspaper said the <ORGANIZATION> Imperial </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Household </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> had its `` own standards about the news, which apparently differ considerably from today's ordinary standard.'' He spoke on condition of anonymity. The <ORGANIZATION> Asahi </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Shimbun </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s second largest circulation newspaper, said Saturday that the emperor apparently has cancer. It quoted pathologists who examined tissue taken from the emperor's pancreas when he underwent intestinal bypass surgery last September as saying `` cancer cells were found in the tissue.'' The article said pathologists at <ORGANIZATION> Tokyo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> believe the emperor has either pancreatic or duodenum cancer and that palace officials decided he should not be told about it. Instead, the article said, they announced the illness as merely an inflammation of the pancreas. <PERSON> Shouichi </PERSON> <PERSON> Fujimori </PERSON>, director general of the <ORGANIZATION> Imperial </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Household </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION>, telephoned the publisher of the <ORGANIZATION> Asahi </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Shimbun </ORGANIZATION>, expressed regret and asked the newspaper to exercise self-restraint. `` At this point where the emperor's consciousness is still clear and he is struggling with his illness, publishing the article was deemed totally inappropriate,'' said <PERSON> Kenji </PERSON> <PERSON> Maeda </PERSON>, an <ORGANIZATION> Imperial </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Household </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> spokesman. `` Taking into account the emperor's feeling, the decision to publish such an article apparently lacks consideration. But he refused to confirm or deny the report, saying only: `` Matters regarding the fact of the article and publishing such an article are on different dimensions.'' Deputy Managing Editor <PERSON> Hisao </PERSON> <PERSON> Kuwashima </PERSON> said the paper printed the article after its editors decided the emperor would not be able to read a newspaper again. `` Everyone is frustrated about the lack of information about his condition,'' said <PERSON> Kuwashima </PERSON>. `` His conditions have been clearly showing signs of pancreatic cancer since a long time ago. After he was listed in critical condition, we decided we must run this article.'' He said the decision also was based on the fact that <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON> is a public figure. In <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, the decision whether to tell patients they have cancer is left to doctors and relatives. When <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON>'s temperature soared Saturday afternoon, some news services and television stations quoted unidentified government sources as saying the emperor was in critical condition, was hooked to a respirator and was receiving heart massages. <PERSON> Maeda </PERSON> hastily denied those reports and angrily said: `` Which can you trust, speculation by unknown soruces or us?'' The emperor has no political power but serves as a symbol of <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>. `` Secrecy is an important part of the imperial family,'' said <PERSON> Inose </PERSON>. `` If an imperial family gave away all secrets and everything became open, they would not be able to maintain the implicit authority they have now. `` For the people surrounding the imperial family, what's good for the emperor always comes before what's good for people, and that's been taken for granted for centuries,'' <PERSON> Inose </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880926-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-26-88 0036EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-ABattleforSeoul Bjt   09-26 0775</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-A Battle for Seoul, Bjt,0791</SECOND>
<HEAD>Olympic Park Overlooks Site Of Bloody Battle 38 Years Ago</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Hometowns not available for Marines, whose interviews appear
in corps records and other historical sources.</NOTE>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BARRY RENFREW</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SEOUL, South Korea (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Olympic stadiums where athletes from 160 nations are competing overlook another battlefield, where <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> troops were locked in ferocious combat 38 years ago today. It is the anniversary of the Sept. 26, 1950 capture of <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION> by <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korean </LOCATION> forces from communist North Korean troops _ three months after the beginning of the Korean War. About 4 million soldiers and civilians were killed or wounded in the war. <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION> and almost every other city on the <LOCATION> Korean </LOCATION> <LOCATION> peninsula </LOCATION> was badly damaged in the bitter ideological clash. `` Starting in <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION> I finally found out there is no glory in war. It's cruel, miserable, dirty and nothing worth bragging about,'' said former <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Marine <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> in an interview. <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION> has been rebuilt and is now a sprawling, modern metropolis of 10 million people. The city's skyscrapers and broad avenues are a monument to <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>'s astonishing growth since the war. But the scene was very different in 1950 when the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and 15 other nations intervened under <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> command to help <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> after it was invaded on June 25 by <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>'s ill-equipped and poorly trained army was knocked back and <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION> captured within a few days of the invasion. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> forces that rushed into <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> were pushed back with the <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korean </LOCATION> army until they held the southwestern tip of the peninsula around the port of <LOCATION> Pusan </LOCATION>. Bloody battles raged through August 1950 as the <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Koreans </LOCATION> attempted to break through the <LOCATION> Pusan </LOCATION> perimeter. The war took a dramatic turn Sept. 15, 1950 when Gen. <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON> <PERSON> MacArthur </PERSON> outflanked the North Koreans with an amphibious assault at <LOCATION> Inchon </LOCATION> next to <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION> and far behind communist lines. MacArthur's gamble paid off and within days <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and some South Korean forces reached the south bank of the <LOCATION> Han </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION>, including the area around where the Olympic Park is now. <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> rushed 10,000 reinforcements into <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION> and the northern bank of the Han was bristling with tanks and artillery that could fire straight into any assault across the river. The <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> commanders on the spot wanted to advance slowly and outflank the <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Koreans </LOCATION>. But MacArthur's headquarters in <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION> ordered <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION> retaken by Sept. 25, exactly three months after the communist invasion. American ground commanders were forced to attack across the Han in the face of deadly <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korean </LOCATION> gunfire, according to historical accounts. All of the bridges had been destroyed and the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> troops went across in barges and boats. <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Saluzzi </PERSON>, another <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Marine who took part in the attack, saw dead bodies for the first time when he arrived on the banks of the Han. `` We were assembled near an area covered with litters of dead Marines ... I was afraid to look but eventually forced myself to. Only hours before those Marines had been joking and telling sea stories,'' he said in an interview. `` I saw myself covered by one of those blankets and remember thinking, ` When it comes, let it be quick and without pain.''' Much of the city was burned and destroyed by massive artillery and air attacks before the assault. Entire streets were demolished by cannon fire and fires swept unchecked across the ancient capital. Once the troops got across the Han, they found the <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Koreans </LOCATION> ready to fight for every house and street. Units battled their way across <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION>, dislodging communist troops who would not surrender. `` It seemed that every building in <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION> housed an enemy sniper. We cleaned out doorways and rooftops; we went from street to street, house to house,'' said former <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> sergeant <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Bergee </PERSON>. The <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> commanders in <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION> were furious when <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> military headquarters announced the city was retaken Sept. 25, according to historical accounts, because the main attack did not begin until early Sept. 26 and there was scattered fighting until Sept. 28. <ORGANIZATION> MacArthur </ORGANIZATION> and <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korean </LOCATION> President <PERSON> Syngman </PERSON> <PERSON> Rhee </PERSON> arrived Sept. 28 for a ceremony at the National Capitol to mark the return of the city to the <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korean </LOCATION> government. <PERSON> Rhee </PERSON> said to the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> commander, `` We love you as the savior of our race.'' <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION> would fall again in January 1951 after <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> intervened in the war in November and pushed back the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> forces _ and later be recaptured by the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> forces and held until the war finally ended in stalemate in 1953.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880926-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-26-88 0139EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-China-Graves     09-26 0185</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-China-Graves,0190</SECOND>
<HEAD>Graves For Sale For Chinese Living Abroad</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Chinese who live abroad and wish to be buried in the motherland can now buy a plot under a grave-marketing venture by <LOCATION> Canton </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> companies, the official <ORGANIZATION> Xinhua </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> reported today. The joint venture is offering 2,000 `` tombs'' on a hillside 12 miles from <LOCATION> Canton </LOCATION>, with a 50-square-foot site costing $ 2,050, the agency said. People wishing a more prominent post-life return to the mainland will be able to put up personal statues, and the plots come in a variety of styles to meet the needs of people of different religions, the report said. The project is a joint venture between the <LOCATION> Guangzhou </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Canton </LOCATION> -RRB- Funeral and <ORGANIZATION> Interment </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> and a <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> interment service company. <PERSON> Xinhua </PERSON> did not specify whether those buying the sites would follow Chinese custom and be cremated before being put to rest. The <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> government has tried to make cremation a universal practice in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> because of the country's severe land shortage, but has met some resistance in rural areas where people are traditionally buried.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880926-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-26-88 0038EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p BC-DebateText 21stadd   09-26 0786</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Debate Text, 21st add,780</SECOND>
<HEAD>WINSTON-SALEM, N.C.: a mistake?</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>: Well, if this is Christmas, I hope it's Christmas when you make that decision. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>: These are the, these are the, these are the _ my answer is: do not make these unilateral cuts. And everybody now realizes that peace through strength works. And so this is where I have a big difference. Of course we're going to have to make some determination on this, and we're going to have to make it on conventional forces. But now, we've got a very good concept called competitive strategies. We will do what we do best. It's a strategy that we've been working on for a couple of years. It is going to take us to a much better advantage in conventional forces. But look, let me sum it up. I want to be the president that gets conventional forces in balance. I want to be the one to banish chemical and biological weapons from the face of the <LOCATION> Earth </LOCATION>. But you have to have a little bit of experience to know where to start, and I think I've had that. Lehrer: Governor? <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>: Well, first, let me say with respect to the freeze, that back in the spring of 1982, Mr. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was a lot more sympathetic to the freeze than he seems to be today. As a matter of fact, he said it was not and should not be a subject of partisan demagoguery, because it was too important to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, or for the world. I did n't hear, <PERSON> John </PERSON>, exactly where he was going to cut and what he was going to do, but I know this. We have serious financial problems in this country. We've piled up over $ 1 trillion in debt, and the next president of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> is going to have to make some choices. Mr. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> wants to spend billions on Star Wars. He apparently wants to spend billions on the MX on railroad cars, a weapons system we do n't need and ca n't afford. I thought the administration was opposed to the Midgetman. I thought the administration was at the negotiating table in <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> suggesting that we ban mobile missile systems entirely. But those are the choices the next president of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> is going to have to make. I am for the Stealth, I am for the D-5, I am for going ahead with the advanced cruise missile. But I do n't think we need these other systems. I do n't think we need them to remain strong. We've got to move ahead with the strategic arms negotiation process, with the comprehensive test-ban treaty, and _ Lehrer: Governor? <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>: _ with negotiations leading to conventional force reduction in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, with deeper cuts on the Soviet side. And Senator <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> and I will pursue that policy. Lehrer: <PERSON> Anne </PERSON> <PERSON> Groer </PERSON>, a question for the vice president. Groer: Well, Mr. Vice President, you said you met with Secretary General <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>, you have met with Mr. <PERSON> Shevardnadze </PERSON>. But for the last 40 years, Americans have been taught to regard the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> as the enemy. Yet, President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> has signed two arms control treaties, and he's promised to share Star Wars technology with the very country he once called the `` evil empire.'' So, perhaps you could tell us this evening, should we be doing a lot to help the economics and the social development of a country that we have so long regarded as an adversary? <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>: What I think we ought to do is take a look at perestroika and glasnost, welcome them, but keep our eyes open, be cautious, because the Soviet change is not fully established yet. Yes, I think it's fine to do business with them, but I do n't want to see us exporting our highly-sensitive national security oriented technology to the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> I do n't want to see us making unilateral cuts in our strategic systems while we are negotiating with them. And so I'm encouraged by what I see when I talk to Mr., what I hear when I talk to Mr. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> and Mr. <PERSON> Shevardnadze </PERSON>. But can they pull it off? And when they have deals that are good for us as <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> started to do _ the changes in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> since <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> and I lived there is absolutely amazing in terms of incentive and partnerships and things of this nature. And now the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> seems to be walking down that same path. We should encourage that. We ought to say this is good. But where I differ with my opponent is, I am not going to make unilateral cuts in our strategic defense systems or support some freeze when they have superiority.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>MORE</NOTE>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880926-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-26-88 0145EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Philippines-Corruption     09-26 0625</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Philippines-Corruption,0642</SECOND>
<HEAD>No ``Smoking Gun'', But Charges Still Tarnish Aquino Government
Luster</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT H. REID</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MANILA, Philippines (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Corruption charges are tarnishing the image of President <PERSON> Corazon </PERSON> <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON>'s government, even though no one has produced evidence she is sanctioning practices that led to the downfall of her predecessor, <PERSON> Ferdinand </PERSON> <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON>. For months, <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION> newspapers have been replete with allegations of official corruption. They include `` disappearing'' food stocks, rake-offs from state-run companies, bribery in the <ORGANIZATION> Customs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> and shakedowns by crooked policemen. Last week, retired Maj. Gen. <PERSON> Cesar </PERSON> <PERSON> Tapia </PERSON>, who was appointed security chief at <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION> airport to clean up corruption there, quit in disgust, saying he was powerless to root out `` institutionalized graft.'' Mrs. <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON>'s personal integrity remains unquestioned. But critics allege some of her relatives used their connections to enhance their wealth in questionable business deals. In August, <PERSON> Ramon </PERSON> <PERSON> Diaz </PERSON> quit as chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Presidential </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> on Good Government, citing interference by relatives of `` powers that be'' in efforts to retrieve the billions of dollars <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> and his associates allegedly embezzled during his 20-year administration. <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> fled to <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION> in February 1986 after he was ousted in civilian-military uprising that placed Mrs. <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON> in power. Few of the recent allegations against Mrs. <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON> have been proven, and so far no senior official has gone to jail. Many of the charges have been leveled by self-serving opposition politicians seeking to find an issue with which to embarrass the president. Last week, opposition Sen. <PERSON> Juan </PERSON> <PERSON> Ponce </PERSON> <PERSON> Enrile </PERSON> admitted he was wrong in claiming Mrs. <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON>'s brother-in-law, <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON>, had secretly assumed the chairmanship of <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION>, which was taken over by the government because of its links to <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON>. Nonetheless, political commentators believe the sheer volume of the charges has sullied the reputation of an administration which came to power promising to clean up government after rampant corruption under <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON>. At best, the charges point to widespread inefficiency, incompetence and mismanagement in the bureaucracy. In some cases, government investigators acknowledged widespread irregularities in state agencies but found no evidence of criminal wrongdoing. Mrs. <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON> has vowed to stamp out corruption but demands proof before she will crack down on alleged offenders. She has said frequently that most of the allegations have been raised by her enemies to undermine her personally. But some analysts believe strong measures are necessary because of public sensitivity after years of blatant, state-sanctioned corruption under <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON>. `` The president must start giving her people some big fish to fry,'' said the pro-government <ORGANIZATION> Philippine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inquirer </ORGANIZATION>. `` Otherwise, they will set their hooks elsewhere. And the blood will spatter not just the walls of bureaucray but on the foundations of our new democracy as well.'' Some analysts believe Filipinos are quick to accept corruption allegations _ regardless of proof _ because many see examples of petty graft every day. These include policemen who shake down motorists for bribes to ignore traffic violations to bureaucrats who accept `` tips'' to speed processing of licenses and other official documents. Vast timberlands are being systematically denuded of trees by illegal logging operations. It is widely assumed such operations continue under the protection of corrupt military officers. Impatience with high-level corruption has also been heightened because millions of Filipinos must struggle daily simply to earn enough to feed, clothe and shelter themselves and their families. Coupled with that is the continuing failure of the government to improve the economic livelihood of millions, especially those who live in the impoverished countryside. `` There is a strong perception here that Mrs. <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON> is personally honest,'' said Most Rev. <PERSON> Leonardo </PERSON> <PERSON> Legaspi </PERSON>, archbishop of <LOCATION> Naga </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, located about 190 miles southeast of <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION>. `` But people do not see goodness translated into something that is effective.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880926-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-26-88 0146EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-HurricaneGilbert     09-26 0835</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Hurricane Gilbert,0860</SECOND>
<HEAD>Hurricane Gilbert Smashed Resorts And Cities In Deadly Eight-Day
Rampage</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By ELOY O. AGUILAR</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MEXICO CITY (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Rising out of the azure waters like the <LOCATION> Caribbean </LOCATION> god of wind, Hurricane <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON> smashed idyllic resorts and industrial cities during an eight-day rampage across the <LOCATION> Caribbean </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON> grew into a hurricane with winds of 74 mph on Sept. 10, 100 miles southwest of <LOCATION> Puerto </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rico </LOCATION>, sending the first waves of torrential rain and panic to impoverished towns in <LOCATION> Haiti </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Dominican </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Republic </LOCATION>. By the time <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON> lost its hurricane status over northeastern <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, it had killed more than 300 people, left hundreds of thousands homeless and caused billions of dollars damage to the <LOCATION> Caribbean </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON>'s trail of destruction across nine nations occurred despite the technological advances of modern-day weather forecasting. Airplanes flew into the eye of the hurricane several times daily and meteorologists with computers predicted the storm's next target `` It was one of the top 10 as far as intensity, size and destructive potential,'' said <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Sheets </PERSON>, director of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hurricane </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Coral </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gables </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>. After leaving more than eight dead in the <LOCATION> Dominican </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Republic </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON> punished <LOCATION> Jamaica </LOCATION>'s capital <LOCATION> Kingston </LOCATION> and the resort of <LOCATION> Montego </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION>, then pushed northwestward past the <LOCATION> Cayman </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Islands </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jamaica </LOCATION>, which needs tourism for much of its hard currency, sustained $ 8 billion in damage and at least 30 people died. <ORGANIZATION> Kingston </ORGANIZATION> lost much of its drinking water, electricity and many services. A half-million people, nearly one-fourth the island population, were left homeless. Luckiest perhaps was the low-lying three-island British colony called the <ORGANIZATION> Caymans </ORGANIZATION>, which suffered remarkably little damage. `` All 23,000 people of the islands got on their knees and said ` Thank You,''' journalist <PERSON> Carol </PERSON> <PERSON> Winker </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON> moved into the Yucatan Channel between <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, gathering strength over warm waters to become a Category 5 storm or `` great hurricane'' with winds of up to 160 mph. The Caribbean Indians called their god of wind Huracan, and the winds of <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON> were terrifyingly strong, up to 218 mph at one point as it neared <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>. Rain spread more than 400 miles from north to south. <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON>'s tail dumped up to 10 inches of rain in portions of <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, leaving more than 15 dead in <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION> Next struck was <LOCATION> Cancun </LOCATION>, a 110-hotel Mexican island resort off the Yucatan that was built in the 1970s after computer studies showed it would be rarely hit by hurricanes. Said tourist <PERSON> Wendy </PERSON> <PERSON> Kidd </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Montreal </LOCATION>: `` The wind came in the bedroom one way and went out the other and took everything with it.'' In one <LOCATION> Cancun </LOCATION> hotel, where 450 were packed into a banquet room, refugees had to hold up a wall against the strong winds. There was no water. Toilets, in some cases one to a shelter, could not be flushed. `` We do not know what it is to be dirty ... sharing bathrooms that do n't work. We are not used to it,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Kidd </PERSON> said of the American and Canadian tourists caught by the storm. `` Some people handle it graciously and some do n't.'' <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON> uprooted palms, Indian laurels and other trees and snapped antenna support cables in the nearby resorts of <LOCATION> Cozumel </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Isla </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mujeres </LOCATION>. Electrical poles fell, breaking power lines. Thatched huts and wooden structures collapsed. After the storm, a 118-foot Cuban fishing boat was found tossed up beside a beach hotel, dramatic proof of <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON>'s strength. <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON> caused more than $ 300 million in damage to the tourist industry of <LOCATION> Cancun </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Cozumel </LOCATION>. In nearby <LOCATION> Merida </LOCATION>, it destroyed nearly all the corn and fruit crops. At least 24 died in the area. <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON> next moved into the <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, threatening oil drilling installations and populated areas from <LOCATION> Veracruz </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>, before moving over land in the state of <LOCATION> Tamaulipas </LOCATION>, 100 miles south of <LOCATION> Brownsville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>. Ocean waters more than three feet deep pushed several miles inland over the barren flats. At least 11 villagers drowned along the coast. But the worst lay ahead. About 160 miles northwest was <LOCATION> Monterrey </LOCATION> and its 2.8 million people. <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON> collided with the 14,000-foot-high mountains around <LOCATION> Monterrey </LOCATION>, creating killing torrents with a load of rain that swept away passenger buses traveling along the normally dry bed of the <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Catarina </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION>. More than 200 died Sept. 17 in <LOCATION> Monterrey </LOCATION> alone, the biggest single toll from the storm. In recent years the state government had used the riverbed as a thoroughfare, for electricity towers and for miles of fields for baseball and soccer. `` The water was kind of running through,'' said witness <PERSON> Cosme </PERSON> <PERSON> Garibay </PERSON>. `` Then all of a sudden, it came, bam, all at once. I have never seen anything like it in my life.'' Two Americans also died from Gilbert-spawned tornadoes in <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, but the dying rains did some good, filling dams near the <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> border and bringing an abrupt end to a long summer drought.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880926-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-26-88 0150EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Lebanon-Crisis     09-26 0722</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lebanon-Crisis,0748</SECOND>
<HEAD>Outside Powers Fuel Crisis In Lebanon</HEAD>
<HEAD>AP News Analysis</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By ED BLANCHE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NICOSIA, Cyprus (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The emergence of rival Christian and Moslem governments threatens to plunge <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> once again into a civil war fueled by outside powers that long have used the country as a proxy battlefield. The crisis could formalize the de facto partition of <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> into sectarian cantons carved out during the 13-year civil war, which killed about 150,000 people. <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION>, the major power broker in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>, backs the Moslem government and the Shiite Moslem Amal militia. <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> support the right-wing Christians. <LOCATION> Libya </LOCATION> funds the Druse militia, which sent volunteers to fight alongside Col. <PERSON> Moammar </PERSON> <PERSON> Gadhafi </PERSON>'s army in <LOCATION> Chad </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> arms and bankrolls the Shiite fundamentalists. <LOCATION> Saudi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arabia </LOCATION> helps the Sunni Moslems, but fundamentalist <PERSON> Sunnis </PERSON> also look to <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> for support. The Christians and Moslems each are split by internal rivalries. The Maronite Catholics, the dominant Christian sect, are patronized by the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>. The Greek Orthodox, traditionally more leftist, are pro-Syrian. The failure of <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION> to elect a successor to President <PERSON> Amin </PERSON> <PERSON> Gemayel </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Maronite </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION>, when his six-year term expired Thursday spawned competing Christian and Moslem governments. <PERSON> Gemayel </PERSON> appointed army commander Gen. <PERSON> Michel </PERSON> <PERSON> Aoun </PERSON> as prime minister. <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION> backs Sunni Moslem Prime Minister <PERSON> Salim </PERSON> <PERSON> Hoss </PERSON>, who took office in June 1987. At best, <PERSON> Gemayel </PERSON> was little more than a figurehead. He had no control of Moslem-held areas, and even in the shrunken Christian enclave the real power was the <LOCATION> Lebanese </LOCATION> forces, the Christians' main militia The 42,000-man army is fractured, with some units backing <PERSON> Gemayel </PERSON> or allied with the Lebanese Forces. Shiite and Druse Moslem brigades have either sat on the sidelines or actively backed Moslem militias. The cease-fire in the Iran-Iraq war and the 9-month-old Palestinian uprising in the Israeli-occupied <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strip </LOCATION> also have significantly affected the region. Particularly important is the intensification of the long feud between <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION>, which backed <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> in the eight-year <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> war. <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> are ruled by rival wings of the <ORGANIZATION> Baath </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Arab </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Socialist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>. <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION> has been weakened by <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'s apparent military collapse, and <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> has stepped up its propaganda campaign against <LOCATION> Damascus </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION> also fears it could be eclipsed as a key player in the <LOCATION> Arab-Israeli </LOCATION> dispute by the support the <ORGANIZATION> Palestine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> has gained from the uprising. Syrian President <PERSON> Hafez </PERSON> <PERSON> Assad </PERSON> looked to <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> to provide him with a success by restoring stability to the divided country through the election of one of its allies as president. The Syrians, with 40,000 troops in north and east <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>'s Moslem sector, consider their tiny western neighbor vital to their security. The cease-fire freed the Iraqis to take revenge on <LOCATION> Damascus </LOCATION> for siding with <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> by confronting the Syrians' ambitions in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> and stirring trouble for them in their own backyard. <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>, influential in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> until the <ORGANIZATION> Syrians </ORGANIZATION> moved in in 1976 seeking to quell the civil war, has provided weapons and ammunition to the right-wing Lebanese Christian forces opposed to <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION>. Arab diplomats said <LOCATION> Baghdad </LOCATION>, which long has had links with the Lebanese Forces, recently shipped 50 armored personnel carriers to the Christian militia. It was the Lebanese Forces' fierce opposition to Syrian-backed candidates in the presidential election that foiled <LOCATION> Damascus </LOCATION>' efforts to secure political reforms that would give <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>'s Moslem majority an equal share of constitutional power with the long-dominant <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>'s claim that it defeated <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>, justified to some extent by its military victories, pushed <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION> to seek to impose greater control over <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> and prevent any <LOCATION> Iraqi </LOCATION> intervention. The Iraqis also support <PERSON> Yasser </PERSON> <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> Palestine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION>, which is feuding with <PERSON> Assad </PERSON>. The Syrians also have to contend with Iranian-backed Shiite Moslem fundamentalists, who seek to create the world's second Islamic Republic in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION>'s Shiite ally, the Amal militia, sought to crush the pro-Iranian <ORGANIZATION> Hezbollah </ORGANIZATION>, or Party of God, this year. When <ORGANIZATION> Hezbollah </ORGANIZATION>, aided by Iranian Revolutionary Guards, came out on top, the <ORGANIZATION> Syrians </ORGANIZATION> intervened to corral <ORGANIZATION> Hezbollah </ORGANIZATION> in its stronghold in south <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>'s slums The fundamentalists, quiet for the moment, remain a threat to <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION>'s efforts to control <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Ed </PERSON> <PERSON> Blanche </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> news editor for <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>, is based in <LOCATION> Nicosia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Cyprus </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880926-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-26-88 0151EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Yugoslavia-Ethnic     09-26 0918</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Yugoslavia-Ethnic,0946</SECOND>
<HEAD>Ethnic Tension Mounts In Yugoslavia</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By ALISON SMALE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PRISTINA, Yugoslavia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 In the tense capital of <LOCATION> Yugoslavia </LOCATION>'s backward region of <LOCATION> Kosovo </LOCATION>, the majority Albanians and minority Slavs are divided from the cradle to the grave It starts in kindergarten, where parents say Albanian and Slav children trade racial slurs. It ends with the death notices on trees lining main streets _ black borders for Slavs, green for Albanians. In good times, there was some fraternization, even intermarriage, among the Albanians, who make up 90 percent of <LOCATION> Kosovo </LOCATION>'s 2 million people, and the 200,000 Slavs. But the closeness is increasingly rare since ethnic riots in 1981 left at least nine dead and 200 injured. In the past months, the tension has increased in this region the Slavs see as their historic homeland. The Albanians, most of whom are Moslems, want to win a greater voice in governing <LOCATION> Kosovo </LOCATION>, now administered by the republic of <LOCATION> Serbia </LOCATION>. The Slavs are pushing to absorb the autonomous province into <LOCATION> Serbia </LOCATION>. For the mostly <PERSON> Christian </PERSON> <PERSON> Slavs </PERSON>, made up of Serbs and Montenegrins, the Albanian demand is impossible. They argue that a separate republic would oust them from <LOCATION> Kosovo </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Kosovo </LOCATION> was settled by Serbs in the 7th century and was the heart of <LOCATION> Serbia </LOCATION>'s medieval empire. The Turks conquered it in 1389 and ruled until the Balkan War of 1913, when it was partitioned between <LOCATION> Serbia </LOCATION> and what is now the republic of <LOCATION> Montenegro </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Yugoslavia </LOCATION>. Albanians, believed to be descended from the ancient Illyrians, have been in the region since ancient times. Slavs say the Albanians would precipitate the breakup of this communist <LOCATION> Balkan </LOCATION> country by seceding and uniting with <LOCATION> Albania </LOCATION>, the neighboring communist country. Thousands of Serbs and Montenegrins have left <LOCATION> Kosovo </LOCATION> because of arson and other attacks they blame on the Albanians, who are rarely given a chance to publicly respond to what appear to be grossly distorted accounts. The animosity, exacerbated by emotional Slav rallies protesting alleged Albanian attacks, is now so high that many residents believe a military crackdown will come within months, or even weeks. Police equipped with armored personnel carriers have been sent to the province by the federal government in <LOCATION> Belgrade </LOCATION>. The Slavs say <LOCATION> Kosovo </LOCATION>'s Albanians, who have the highest birthrate in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, are making a conscious effort to outbreed them. They claim the Albanians are chasing them out of <LOCATION> Kosovo </LOCATION> by attacking their women and children and offering irresistibly high amounts of money for their properties. `` You could buy in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> for what they pay here,'' said a <LOCATION> Western </LOCATION> resident of <LOCATION> Pristina </LOCATION>, who spoke on condition of anonymity. He cited prices of $ 222,000 for a house in the hilly city. The Slavs have found a champion for their cause in <PERSON> Slobodan </PERSON> <PERSON> Milosevic </PERSON>, the leader of <LOCATION> Serbia </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, who advocates more direct Serbian control over <LOCATION> Kosovo </LOCATION> and the autonomous province of <LOCATION> Vojvodina </LOCATION>, near the Hungarian border. Both areas control their own judiciary, police and other insitutions. The position of the <ORGANIZATION> Serbian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> has thrown <LOCATION> Yugoslavia </LOCATION> into its most explosive political crisis of the postwar era. <PERSON> Milosevic </PERSON>'s views have drawn hundreds of emotional crowds to rallies where they vent their frustrations with <LOCATION> Yugoslavia </LOCATION>'s economic crisis by chanting for arms and vowing to keep <LOCATION> Kosovo </LOCATION> Slavic `` We are shaking the country,'' said <PERSON> Miroslav </PERSON> <PERSON> Solevic </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Pristina </LOCATION> Serb who heads a committee to organize the rallies. But leaders of <LOCATION> Yugoslavia </LOCATION>'s other republics say <PERSON> Milosevic </PERSON>'s emotional tactics could lead to civil war The rallies `` have a negative effect on the situation in <LOCATION> Kosovo </LOCATION>,'' said <PERSON> Albanian </PERSON> <PERSON> Hashim </PERSON> <PERSON> Rexhepi </PERSON>, a member of <LOCATION> Kosovo </LOCATION>'s Communist leadership `` It's very bad for us now,'' said student <PERSON> Nazim </PERSON> <PERSON> Rexhepi </PERSON>, an ethnic <PERSON> Albanian </PERSON> with no known family ties to the politician. `` Nobody asks us anything. If we even organized a similar rally -LRB- to those held by the Serbs -RRB-, we would all be proclaimed Albanian separatists and sentenced.'' The ethnic crisis has been worsened by <LOCATION> Kosovo </LOCATION>'s economic backwardness. Seventy percent of the population is under 30, and 135,000 people are jobless. Listless, bored young men gather by the hundreds on <LOCATION> Pristina </LOCATION>'s refuse-strewn streets. Those with jobs earn as little as $ 75 a month, less than half the national average. A middle-class family of four is lucky to live in a one-bedroom apartment in a building with broken light bulbs and windows and an entrance that reeks of garbage. Money from the richer republics has produced some incongruously luxurious buildings, such as the university library. `` We're the only country in the world that has borrowed money to finance its own destruction,'' said a <LOCATION> Serbian </LOCATION> journalist in <LOCATION> Kosovo </LOCATION> who spoke on condition of anonymity. He was referring to <LOCATION> Yugoslavia </LOCATION>'s $ 21 billion debt and child support paid to Albanians for each of their many children. In the village of <LOCATION> Prekale </LOCATION>, armed Serbian vigilantes protect children from harassment by Albanian villagers and police patrol the area every six hours. `` The ordinary people _ it's not their fault. It's all the big heads that do this,'' says Serb villager <PERSON> Slobodan </PERSON> <PERSON> Maksimovic </PERSON>. The villagers are ready to flee if ethnic violence erupts, but Serbian nationalists anxious to stem emigration from <LOCATION> Kosovo </LOCATION> have persuaded many people to stay. `` I had to come back from -LRB- working in -RRB- <LOCATION> Switzerland </LOCATION> to protect my family,'' said <PERSON> Maksimovic </PERSON>. `` I have to go with my kids every day to school, wait until they finish and then come back with them. We feel as if we are in a zoo, encircled by Albanians and guarded by police.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880926-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-26-88 0041EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-PrisonDisturbance     09-26 0236</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Prison Disturbance,0242</SECOND>
<HEAD>Prisoner Found Dead After Disturbance Over Jail Liquor</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By QUANE KENYON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BOISE, Idaho (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Prisoners briefly seized control of a high-security section of the <ORGANIZATION> Idaho </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Penitentiary </ORGANIZATION> on Sunday, and guards later found an inmate dead in his cell, authorities said. The 3 -LCB- - hour rampage began when two unarmed guards ran into resistance trying to confiscate homemade liquor from inmates, said <PERSON> Tim </PERSON> <PERSON> McNeese </PERSON>, executive assistant to state <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corrections </ORGANIZATION> director <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON> The prisoners broke glass and burned mattresses and papers before surrendering. The death was being investigated as an apparent homicide, said <LOCATION> McNeese </LOCATION>. He said the victim's name was being withheld pending notification of relatives. He refused to release details of how the man was killed. After SWAT teams entered the building and inmates ended their disturbance without force, officers found the body during an inspection, <PERSON> McNeese </PERSON> said at a news conference. `` It appears there was significant damage,'' said <LOCATION> McNeese </LOCATION>. It was mainly glass damage. `` There is n't that much in there to burn,'' he said. Someone broke through a cinderblock cell wall to get at the inmate, he said. He said there was no immediate information whether the disturbance was staged to aid the slaying. The cellblock involved normally has a population of 120. <PERSON> McNeese </PERSON> said he had no immediate indication how many inmates took part in the disturbance and destruction, but many remained in their cells.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880926-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-26-88 0047EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p BC-Debate-Glance     09-26 0468</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Debate-Glance,450</SECOND>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> WINSTON-SALEM </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.C. </LOCATION> -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> -RRB- _ Here, at a glance, are highlights of comments at Sunday night's presidential debate by Democrat <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> and Republican <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>:
</TEXT>
<HEAD>___</HEAD>
<TEXT>

</TEXT>
<HEAD>PATRIOTISM</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said that in his attacks on <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> `` I hope people do n't think I'm questioning his patriotism. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> retorted, `` Of course the vice president is questioning my patriotism. I do n't think there's any question about that And I resent it. I resent it.''
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>___</BYLINE>
<TEXT>

</TEXT>
<HEAD>DRUGS-NORIEGA</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> accused the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration, including <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, of dealing with Panamanian Gen. <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>, whom he referred to as a `` drug-running dictator. We've been dealing with him, he's been dealing drugs to our kids.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said the administration had moved quickly to indict <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> on drug charges as soon as it had evidence.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>___</BYLINE>
<TEXT>

</TEXT>
<HEAD>IRAN-CONTRA</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> said it was a `` tragedy'' for the president to sell arms to <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> in exchange for hostages, and he said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> endorsed the deal. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> replied, `` Yes, we should n't trade arms for hostages, but we have made vast improvements in our anti-terrorism.''
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>___</BYLINE>
<TEXT>

</TEXT>
<HEAD>DEFICIT</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Arguing over ways to cut the federal budget deficit, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> depicted his rival as a tax-raiser and the Democrat suggested that <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> would cut Social Security.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>___</BYLINE>
<TEXT>

</TEXT>
<HEAD>MILITARY</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' support for a nuclear freeze in the 1970s would have worked to the advantage of the communist bloc. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> accused the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration of cutting into the `` fiber and the muscle'' of conventional forces.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>___</BYLINE>
<TEXT>

</TEXT>
<HEAD>ONE-LINERS</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 `` If he keeps this up, he's going to be the <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Isuzu </PERSON> of American politics,'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> said, drawing laughter from the audience with his reference to the television advertising character who exaggerates everything he says about the cars he's selling. `` Is this the time to unleash our one-liners?'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said in response. `` That answer was about as clear as <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Harbor </LOCATION>,'' he said in reference to environmental problems in <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' home state.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>___</BYLINE>
<TEXT>

</TEXT>
<HEAD>DAN QUAYLE</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> defended his youthful running mate, said he had been subjected to unfair speculation and added, `` he has my confidence.'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> guessed that `` for most people the notion of President <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> is a very, very troubling notion.''
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>___</BYLINE>
<TEXT>

</TEXT>
<HEAD>CLOSING STATEMENT</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Each man used his closing statement to deliver a two-minute version of his standard campaign speech. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said the voters want change but contended, `` We are the change, I am the change.'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> said, `` The best <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> is not behind us. The best <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> is yet to come.''
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>___</BYLINE>
<TEXT>

</TEXT>
<HEAD>WHO WON?</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Asked if he won, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> replied, `` People seemed to be pretty enthusiastic.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> declined to claim victory at a post-debate rally, but he repeatedly stuck his thumbs in the air in a triumphant gesture.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880926-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-26-88 0051EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p BC-DebateText 22ndadd   09-26 0726</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Debate Text, 22nd add,780</SECOND>
<HEAD>WINSTON-SALEM, N.C.: have superiority.</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 I'm not going to do that because I think the jury is still out on the Soviet experiment. And the interesting place, one of the things that fascinates me about this perestroika and glasnost is what's going to happen in <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>. You see the turmoil in <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> today. And I think we have enormous opportunity for trade. I do n't want to go back to the Carter grain embargo on the Soviets. We are once again reliable suppliers and I would never use food as a political tool like our predecessors did. But this is an exciting time. But all I'm suggesting is, let's not be naive in dealing with the Soviets and make a lot of unilateral cuts hoping against hope that they will match our bid. Look at the INF treaty. And if we have n't learned from the negotiating history on that we'll never learn. The freeze people were wrong. The <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration was right. Excuse me. Lehrer: Governor <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>: That was a very different <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> who was talking much more sympathetically about the freeze in the spring of 1982 than he is today, and you were right then <PERSON> George </PERSON> when you said that it was no time for partisan demagoguery. Nobody is suggesting that we unilaterally disarm or somehow reduce our strength. Of course not. What we're talking about is a combination of a strong and effective and credible nuclear deterrent, strong, well-equipped, well-trained, well-maintained conventional forces, and at the same time, a willingness to move forward steadily, thoughtfully, cautiously. We have serious differences with the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. We have very fundamental differences about human rights, democracy, and in our basic system, our basic view of human beings and of what life is all about. But there are opportunities there now. Senator <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> and I have a plan for the 1990s and beyond; Mr. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and Mr. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> do not. And we want to pursue that plan in a way which will bring down the level of nuclear armament, will build a more stable and more peaceful world, and we can do so while making choices here at home. Let's not forget that our national security and our economic security go hand in hand. We can not be strong militarily when we're teeter-tottering on top of a mountain of debt which has been created in the past eight years That's why we need a Democratic administration in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> in 1989. Lehrer: <PERSON> Anne </PERSON> <PERSON> Groer </PERSON>, a question for the governor. Groer: Yes. Governor <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, speaking of seeming changes of position, you have gone from calling the Strategic Defense Initiative, or Star Wars, `` a fantasy and a fraud'' to saying recently you would continue SDI research, and might even deploy the system if <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> supported such a move. Why the change of heart? <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>: No, there's been no change of heart. I've said from the beginning that we ought to continue research into the strategic system at about the level it was at in 1983. That's about a billion dollars a year. But I do n't know of any reputable scientists who believe that this system, at least as originally conceived, could possibly work, this notion of some kind of an Astrodome over ourselves that could protect us from enemy attack, makes real sense. And as a matter of fact, the system that the administration's now talking about is very different from the one that was originally proposed in 1983. So, I am for continued research. But I also want strong conventional forces. Now, the other day Mr. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said, `` Well, if we continued with Star Wars, we'd have to cut some place.'' He has n't told us where. We know where they're cutting We know where you're cutting right now. You're cutting into the fiber and muscle of our conventional forces. You're cutting back on maintenance and equipment There was an <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> general, not too long ago, in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, who said that pretty soon we'd have airplanes without engines, tank commanders who ca n't drive their tanks more than three-quarters of a mile because they do n't have enough fuel, <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> cutters tied up at the dock this summer, not patrolling _ they're supposed to be our first line of defense against drugs and the war against drugs _ because they do n't have enough fuel.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>MORE</NOTE>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880926-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-26-88 0153EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Haiti-Army     09-26 0801</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Haiti-Army,0823</SECOND>
<HEAD>Army Revolt Uproots Tonton Macoutes And Remnants Of Duvalierism</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By PIERRE-YVES GLASS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
