<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880726-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-26-88 2345EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Nicaragua-Media     07-26 0256</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Nicaragua-Media,0263</SECOND>
<HEAD>Government Authorizes La Prensa to Reopen, Suspends Radio News
Program</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MANAGUA, Nicaragua (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Interior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> authorized the opposition newspaper <ORGANIZATION> La </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Prensa </ORGANIZATION> to resume publishing Wednesday following a 15-day suspension imposed for reporting violence at an anti-government protest. But a statement released Tuesday by the ministry said <ORGANIZATION> La </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Prensa </ORGANIZATION>'s directors at a meeting with government officials `` were admonished for constant disrespect for the laws of the nation.'' Also Tuesday, the ministry suspended for 48 hours the radio news program <ORGANIZATION> El </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nicaraguense </ORGANIZATION>. It accused the program directors of broadcasting `` false news'' but did not elaborate. The program is broadcast by the privately owned station <ORGANIZATION> Radio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mundial </ORGANIZATION>. The left-wing Sandinista government ordered the suspension of <ORGANIZATION> La </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Prensa </ORGANIZATION> on July 12, one day after the newspaper reported a violent police crackdown at a July 10 demonstration in the southern city of <LOCATION> Nandaime </LOCATION>. More than three dozen opposition leaders were detained by police during the demonstration. In ordering the shutdown, the government accused <PERSON> La </PERSON> <PERSON> Prensa </PERSON> of `` flagrant abuse of the freedom of expression to the detriment of the public order and the interests of the people.'' Also on July 12 the government ordered an indefinite suspension of <ORGANIZATION> Radio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Catolica </ORGANIZATION>, the station operated by the Nicaraguan Roman Catholic church, for its reporting of the Nandaime demonstration. <PERSON> Cristiana </PERSON> <PERSON> Chamorro </PERSON> <PERSON> Barrios </PERSON>, deputy director of <ORGANIZATION> La </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Prensa </ORGANIZATION>, told The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> Tuesday night the newspaper rejected the <ORGANIZATION> Interior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION>'s claims it had violated laws. She said Wednesday's editions would include a special section covering events that occurred during the suspension.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880726-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-26-88 0026EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--Italy-TunnelFire     07-26 0099</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Italy-Tunnel Fire,0102</SECOND>
<HEAD>Train Burns In Tunnel; One Dead, 20 Injured</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ORVIETO, Italy (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A train stalled in a tunnel after catching fire and one man suffocated while 20 other passengers were treated for smoke inhalation, railroad officials reported. They said the train was en route to <LOCATION> Bolzano </LOCATION> from <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION> and was carrying more than 150 passengers when the incident occurred Monday. The officials said the cause of the fire has not been determined. Area residents alerted authorities when they saw smoke pouring from the tunnel. Officials said <PERSON> Romeo </PERSON> <PERSON> Ascioni </PERSON>, 64, of <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION>, died of suffocation.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880726-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-26-88 0026EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--Italy-Speed     07-26 0127</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Italy-Speed,0131</SECOND>
<HEAD>Report Fewer Killed on First Day of Reduced Speed Limits</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ROME (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Lower speed limits helped reduce the number of highway fatalities on the first day new summer regulations went into effect, according to police. They said 19 people perished in highway accidents Sunday compared to 25 deaths on the corresponding day last year. The regulations went into effect Sunday and reduced speed limits from 87 mph to 68 mph on major highways and from 68 mph to 56 on secondary roads. Public Works Minister <PERSON> Enrico </PERSON> <PERSON> Ferri </PERSON> anounced the lower limits last week following a weekend in which 95 people were killed in highway accidents. The limits are to be in force until Sept. 11. Police said 6,000 speeding tickets were issued Sunday.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880726-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-26-88 0032EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     07-26 0805</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0841</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names In The News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CAPE CANAVERAL, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Former astronaut <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shepard </PERSON> has announced plans for a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Astronaut Hall of Fame that he hopes will offer a look at the heavens from an astronaut's perspective. <PERSON> Shepard </PERSON>, the first American to fly in space, said the museum will feature personal mementos of <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s seven original Mercury spacemen and will be displayed in complex to be built near this spaceport. The Hall of Fame `` will explain space travel from the astronauts' point of view'' with photographs, displays of training equipment, personal log books, clothing and souvenirs of the nation's first corps of astronauts, <PERSON> Shepard </PERSON> said Monday. He said the attraction, to be opened in 1990, will share an 18-acre complex with the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Space Camp of <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> and a 200-room hotel located in <LOCATION> Titusville </LOCATION>, just outside the gates of the Kennedy Space Center. Besides <PERSON> Shepard </PERSON>, the Mercury astronauts, named in 1959, were <PERSON> Scott </PERSON> <PERSON> Carpenter </PERSON>, <PERSON> Gordon </PERSON> <PERSON> Cooper </PERSON>, <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON>, <PERSON> Gus </PERSON> <PERSON> Grissom </PERSON>, <PERSON> Wally </PERSON> <PERSON> Schirra </PERSON> and <PERSON> Deke </PERSON> <PERSON> Slayton </PERSON>. <PERSON> Grissom </PERSON>, as a member of the Apollo 1 crew, died in a launch pad fire in 1967. The others are active in the <ORGANIZATION> Mercury </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Seven </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION>, which operates the <ORGANIZATION> Florida </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Space </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Camp </ORGANIZATION> and funds college scholarships in science and technology.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>BUENOS AIRES, Argentina (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actor <PERSON> Gregory </PERSON> <PERSON> Peck </PERSON> was treated to an impromptu tribute with a celebration of song and dance when he visited the colorful <LOCATION> La </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Boca </LOCATION> neighborhood. `` It was a spontaneous performance _ singing, the tango _ as a little homage to me,'' <PERSON> Peck </PERSON> said of the weekend fanfare. `` It touched my heart.'' <PERSON> Peck </PERSON>, 72, was in town to promote his latest movie, `` The Old Gringo,'' adapted from the 1985 book by <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Fuentes </PERSON>. The movie co-stars <PERSON> Jane </PERSON> <PERSON> Fonda </PERSON> and is to be released at the end of this year. The film was shot in <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> and directed by Argentine <PERSON> Luis </PERSON> <PERSON> Puenzo </PERSON>, who won an Academy Award for `` The Official Story.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>MILAN, Italy (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 American folk singer <PERSON> Joan </PERSON> <PERSON> Baez </PERSON> has become an honorary citizen of <LOCATION> Milan </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Baez </PERSON>, 47, was honored in a ceremony Monday and thanked Mayor <PERSON> Paolo </PERSON> <PERSON> Pillitteri </PERSON> by singing some of the song `` Swing Low, Sweet Chariot.'' <PERSON> Baez </PERSON> noted that her trip to <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION> coincides with the 40th anniversary of the declaration of human rights. `` It is very important to remember and celebrate this date, especially for young people,'' she said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>BERLIN (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Katarina </PERSON> <PERSON> Witt </PERSON>, <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>'s two-time Olympic figure skating champion, will become a special envoy for <ORGANIZATION> UNICEF </ORGANIZATION>, according to the state-run news agency ADN. <PERSON> Witt </PERSON>, who retired from competition after winning her second gold medal at the <LOCATION> Calgary </LOCATION> Winter Olympics in February, will `` help <ORGANIZATION> UNICEF </ORGANIZATION>'s efforts to improve the situation of children in the world,'' the East German agency said Monday. <PERSON> Witt </PERSON> will take part in an exhibition tour staged by the <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Skating </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION> in August, <ORGANIZATION> ADN </ORGANIZATION> said. She also will make guest appearances with the Holiday on Ice show in <LOCATION> Zurich </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Switzerland </LOCATION>; Dortmund, <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Stockholm </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> ADN </ORGANIZATION> said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>PEPIN, Wis. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 It's hardly a big fish story but two glorified guppies barely 6 inches long were enough to make <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Rudy </PERSON> <PERSON> Perpich </PERSON> the victor in fishing contest with Gov. <PERSON> Tommy </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON>. <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON> did n't catch anything Monday as the governors fulfilled a good-natured challenge made several weeks ago as to which state has the better fishing. `` I really did n't expect to win,'' <PERSON> Perpich </PERSON> said, describing himself as the worst fisherman in <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION>. `` I want to apologize to everyone from <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON> said. The governors had their states' natural resources departments work out joint fishing regulations for the spot on <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Pepin </LOCATION>. After the contest, <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON> gave <PERSON> Perpich </PERSON> a case of <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION> beer, a box of <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION> cheese and a necktie made to look like a fish. <PERSON> Perpich </PERSON> responded with a <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION> fishing cap and a case of apple cider. `` That's almost as good as beer,'' <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>SPRINGFIELD, Mass. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actress <PERSON> Jane </PERSON> <PERSON> Fonda </PERSON> told a packed synagogue that working on behalf of Soviet Jews, and one refusenik in particular, has `` changed my life forever.'' Ms. <PERSON> Fonda </PERSON> told the nearly 1,000 people at <LOCATION> Mount </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sinai </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Temple </LOCATION> on Monday night that her late father, actor <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> Fonda </PERSON>, inspired her efforts. `` Part of the fabric of my growing up and part of what he taught me as an actor and a human being was that it is important to stick up for people in situations where they ca n't stick up for themselves,'' she said. Ms. <PERSON> Fonda </PERSON> spoke about her successful three-year campaign on behalf of refusenik <PERSON> Ida </PERSON> <PERSON> Nudel </PERSON>, who was allowed to emigrate to <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> last year from the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. The actress said she traveled to the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> to visit Ms. <PERSON> Nudel </PERSON> and appealed to Soviet and <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> officials to secure her release.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880726-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-26-88 0054EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-SpaceShuttle     07-26 0242</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Space Shuttle,0249</SECOND>
<HEAD>Shuttle Test-Firing Delayed 24 Hours</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CAPE CANAVERAL, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A critical test-firing of space shuttle Discovery's three main engines on the launch pad has been put off 24 hours, until Sunday, to give crews more time to seal the engine compartment. A practice countdown, the first of two leading to the firing, was halted Monday when the launch team decided it could not close out the compartment work in time to conduct the test on Saturday as intended. The postponement was announced as engineers assessed two major candidates for fixing a small shuttle gas leak without having to take Discovery off the launch pad, a move that could delay the planned early September launch by as much as two months. <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aeronautics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Space </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> officials believe that even if the leak can be fixed on the pad, the launch will be delayed past the middle of September. The two most promising approaches for reaching the inaccessible leak for a launch pad fix are: _ Cutting a hole through the rear wall of the shuttle cargo bay and clamping a clamshell-shaped device over the leak, filling it with a sealant _ Running a flexible tube topped by a badminton-like shuttlecock through the 20-foot gas line, filling in the area behind the shuttlecock with a sealant Tests of both systems have been promising, <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> officials said. Shuttle managers were scheduled to meet again Thursday to consider the latest test findings.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880726-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-26-88 0059EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FinancialPlanners     07-26 0654</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Financial Planners,650</SECOND>
<HEAD>Fraud, Abuse Increase with Number of Financial Planners</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVE SKIDMORE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The explosion in the number of financial planners in the 1980s has been matched by a surge in fraud and abuse, state securities regulators told <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> today. The <ORGANIZATION> North </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Securities </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administrators </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, in a report to the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Banking </ORGANIZATION> subcommittee on consumer affairs, said losses to fraud and abuse totaled $ 397 million between mid-1986 and mid-1988. The losses were suffered by 22,100 investors in 79 separate cases pursued by officials in 30 states. That compares with $ 91 million lost in 31 cases between mid-1983 and mid-1985, the association said. `` The absence of effective national oversight of the financial planning industry has created an enormous opportunity for con artists and ... -LRB- others -RRB- who have few scruples about how they earn their living,'' the association said. The group, which represents regulators in all 50 states, said an `` alarming rise'' in large swindles contributed to the increase. It also said more aggressive enforcement probably led to more cases being uncovered. `` Most disturbing is that we are seeing a substantial surge in the number of ` big ticket' cases with investor losses in the eight-figure range,'' said <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Meyer </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION>'s top securities regulator and president of the association. A 1985 association survey turned up only one case where investors lost more than $ 10 million, while the latest check found five cases where losses totaled more than $ 30 million. With the proliferation of investment options in recent years, millions of <LOCATION> Americans </LOCATION> have turned to financial planners for advice on saving for retirement, college education or buying a house. The <ORGANIZATION> Securities </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Exchange </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> requires companies offering advice concerning securities to register as investment advisers. But, in contrast to stock brokers, who are required to pass an exam, there are no educational standards. Also, financial planners offering advice that does not involve buying securities do not have to register. Neither do lawyers and accountants whose advice is incidental to their work. And, individuals can work for a registered planner without registering themselves. Another contentious issue is how financial planners, who are supposed to offer independent advice, are paid. Some work only for fees paid by their customers. But, according to an <ORGANIZATION> SEC </ORGANIZATION> study in February, 85 percent are compensated at least in part through commissions on what they sell. In May, the <ORGANIZATION> SEC </ORGANIZATION> censured and suspended a <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> firm for failing to disclose it received commissions for the securities it recommended. The <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Financial </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Planning </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, based in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>, says its membership has tripled from the end of 1982 to about 25,000. It estimates there are as many as 150,000 financial planners overall. About 13,000 firms have registered with the <ORGANIZATION> SEC </ORGANIZATION> as investment advisers. <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Finn </PERSON>, a financial planner in <LOCATION> Hartford </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Conn. </LOCATION>, and chairman-elect of the association, said his group has been pushing for more federal regulation, including the creation of a self-regulatory organization similar to the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Securities </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dealers </ORGANIZATION>, which oversees brokers who trade over-the-counter stocks. `` We're talking here about rotten apples and my feeling is we should get those rotten apples out of the barrel,'' he said. `` One of the things I'm concerned about in this business is that somebody can call himself a financial planner with impunity.'' In a related matter, the <ORGANIZATION> SEC </ORGANIZATION> is scheduled to consider a rule Thursday which would require investment advisers to keep records for five years to back up performance claims made in their advertising. The 30 states included in the most recent <ORGANIZATION> NASAA </ORGANIZATION> survey were: <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Arkansas </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION> were not included in the 1985 survey. <LOCATION> Delaware </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION> were part of the earlier study, but not the 1988 survey.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880726-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-26-88 0108EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Navy-Blacks Bjt   07-26 0584</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Navy-Blacks, Bjt,570</SECOND>
<HEAD>Promotion of Blacks Lags in Navy</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BRYAN BRUMLEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> is studying why the promotion of blacks in its ranks lags behind that of the other services, 40 years after President <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Truman </PERSON> ordered the nation's military to integrate. The <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> has launched an intensive two-month study to report to Chief of Naval Operations Adm. <PERSON> Carlisle </PERSON> <PERSON> Trost </PERSON> on why the service has so few black officers and why so many blacks are subject to disciplinary action. The study was initiated at the suggestion of Vice Admiral <PERSON> L.A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Edney </PERSON>, chief of naval personnel. `` Progress has slowed. We need to find out why,'' <PERSON> Edney </PERSON> said at a convention of the mostly black Naval Officers' Association earlier this month in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>. The review coincides with the 40th anniversary today of <PERSON> Truman </PERSON>'s Executive Order 9981 for `` equality of treatment and opportunity for all persons in the armed forces without regard to race, color, religion or national origin. The road has been slow, especially in the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>. The number of black officers in the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> has grown from 254 in 1965 to 2,518 today. But that means that only 3.4 percent of the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>'s officers are black, far behind the <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>'s rate of 10.3 percent, and the 6.6 percent in the military as a whole. In the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION>, 5.4 percent of the officers are black, and in the <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corps </ORGANIZATION>, 5.4 percent. The <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> goal is to reach 6 percent by 1996. That would be quite a change for a service which declared as recently as 1933 that blacks would be accepted only as mess stewards and which did not name its first black admiral, <PERSON> Samuel </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gravely </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, until 1971, according to the weekly <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> rolls now list six black admirals, two of them promoted this year. The highest ranking black in the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> is two-star Rear Adm. <PERSON> Benjamin </PERSON> <PERSON> T. </PERSON> <PERSON> Hacker </PERSON>, commander of the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> base and naval training center at <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Diego </LOCATION>, a major port for the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> fleet. `` While we have experienced significant growth in numbers and opportunities for minority personnel, we have clearly not met all of our challenges,'' <PERSON> Edney </PERSON> said in his speech, given July 8. `` Despite our best efforts, the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> still suffers from shortages in minority officer accessions, officer promotions, enlisted advancement and _ while lower than past years _ slightly higher minority involvement with uniform code of military justice violations,' he said. The <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> has ordered a separate report, due by the end of the year, to determine why the court-martial rate for blacks last year was 1.65 percent compared to 1.34 percent for all naval personnel. Within two months, a task force is to report to <PERSON> Edney </PERSON> and <PERSON> Trost </PERSON> on ways to improve the promotion of blacks in the service. <PERSON> Edney </PERSON> proclaimed a commitment to `` keep equal opportunity on the front burner as a top priority. It is the right thing to do. Equal opportunity is fundamental to good leadership, morale and discipline.'' The white majority of <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> officers, he said, have `` a natural tendency to be less sensitive to the perceptions and human needs of minorities, be they minorities of race, religion or gender.'' `` Top leaders must recognize this tendency and not tolerate such insensitivity. We must have checks and balances to make sure the chain of command is responsive,'' <PERSON> Edney </PERSON> said. The admiral promised that `` this will not be just another study of equal opportunity programs. It will be a hard, introspective look.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880726-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-26-88 0033EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Drought-Ducks Bjt   07-26 0763</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Drought-Ducks, Bjt,750</SECOND>
<HEAD>Drought Cuts Duck Population</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GUY DARST</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Government biologists are discussing a 25 percent cutback in duck hunting seasons this fall, saying drought has produced `` the worst habitat conditions'' biologists have ever seen. Reduced hunting is one suggestion that advisory committees are being asked to consider before the Fish and <ORGANIZATION> Wildlife </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> holds hearings early next month on guidelines for states to use in adopting actual hunting regulations. Also put up for discussion, spokeswoman <PERSON> Megan </PERSON> <PERSON> Durham </PERSON> said Monday, are a three-bird bag limit _ the typical recent limit has been four _ and an early closing of the period when hunting is permissible, Jan. 1 instead of Jan. 20. In other drought-related activity in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> wrote key members of agriculture committees in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> on Monday that some features of a bipartisan drought relief bill for farmers might violate principles he believes should be followed. The president did not say specifically what troubled him, but during a tour of drought-stricken corn and soybean producing areas in southern <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> earlier this month, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> voiced concern that the relief package might take on the appearance of a `` Christmas tree,'' in which lawmakers attach favored amendments on legislation they know will pass the <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. The advisory committees' discussion is beginning with a prediction by the Fish and <ORGANIZATION> Wildlife </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> that the fall duck migration will total 66 million ducks, second lowest behind only the 62 million of 1985. All the reduction from last year's 74 million will come in the <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> and Central flyways. The migration on the <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> flyways is expected to be unchanged. The service has warned several times that hunting most likely would have to be restricted this fall, not only because of this year's drought but also because of drought throughout most of the 1980s in the marshy breeding areas of <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> and the northern plains states. The early-season guidelines for blue-winged teal hunting in September call for canceling the season outright in 13 states and for major reductions elsewhere. Last week, the service released population counts showing the breeding populations of 10 major duck species down 3.7 percent from 1987 and 17 percent below the long-term 1955-1987 average. The Northern pintail duck is at a record low of 2.58 million, 18 percent fewer than in 1987 and 54 percent below average. `` Biologists are beginning to worry that continued low water conditions in the areas waterfowl use for migration stopovers and wintering will concentrate the birds and make them more vulnerable to disease later this year,'' the service said in a survey of drought problems as seen by its biologists around the country. There are fewer statistics on non-duck species, but the service reported the <LOCATION> Platte </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION> has been turned into a `` river of sand,'' exposing the nesting piping plover and the interior least tern to threats of predators and death of aquatic food species. Pheasant, quail and grouse may not be affected until next spring, when they'll have less cover during nesting season. Some other highlights from the survey: _ Geese are faring better than ducks, since they nest on more permanent wetlands and are better able to protect their young from predators _ Federal hatcheries in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION> report rising water temperatures are increasing mortality of young trout and on Monday, <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> state hatcheries were reported rushing 600,000 fish to the state's cooler streams a month earlier than usual _ Fish and <ORGANIZATION> Wildlife </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> biologists on the Great Lakes report flows on tributaries are so low they can not safely apply chemicals to control lamprey, which prey on lake trout, and that dredging necessitated by low water will spread contaminated bottom sediment, threatening other aquatic life _ Without significant rain soon, a near-total failure of the acorn crop from oak trees in the <LOCATION> Midwest </LOCATION> and South will occur, spelling problems for deer, squirrels and wild turkey dependent on acorns for food _ All 750 seedlings of the green pitcher plant, an endangered species planted by the service in <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION> this spring, have been killed The duck population surveys recorded increases and in some cases record numbers of ducks in northern <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>. This means they could n't find suitable wetland areas further south, and may not have the energy left to breed at all after their longer flights. <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Dunkle </PERSON>, director of the Fish and <ORGANIZATION> Wildlife </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>, said last week he expects increased emphasis on habitat management. He said marshland managed specifically for waterfowl has provided the only relief for ducks and other species dependent on prairie wetlands.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880726-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-26-88 0114EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-DefenseProbe Bjt   07-26 0659</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Defense Probe, Bjt,650</SECOND>
<HEAD>Carlucci Orders Changes in Bid Rules</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BRYAN BRUMLEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Carlucci </PERSON> says he hopes to curb <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> purchasing abuses by ordering new limits on the number of `` final offers'' that defense contractors can make on a single deal. <PERSON> Carlucci </PERSON> said at a news conference Monday that he was surprised to learn how frequently companies were allowed to revise supposedly final bids, although he described it as `` the exception'' rather than the rule. In the past, contractors have been allowed to amend their final offers in consultation with the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> to change prices or technical specifications to meet military needs. The Pentagon has been rocked in recent weeks by allegations that private consultants working for defense contractors bribed top military purchasing officials for secret contract information. Many of the alleged abuses disclosed in the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> investigation involve contractors who, through the consultants, learned the price or other specifics of bids by competing companies, and then submitted a new `` best and final offer'' tailored to win contracts, some of them worth billions of dollars. `` It is the ` best and final offer' that seems to us to create the most intensive point in the competitive cycle. And that means that information is at a premium,'' <PERSON> Carlucci </PERSON> said. `` We intend to continue with our competitive process. But when you repeat it once, twice, or three times, then it can readily become subject to abuse,'' <PERSON> Carlucci </PERSON> added. <PERSON> Carlucci </PERSON>, who was scheduled to testify before the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Armed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> today, also said his aides had drawn up a `` protocol'' for the military to follow as more information is disclosed from the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> investigation. <PERSON> Carlucci </PERSON> said the department has: _ Required that 17 companies implicated in the investigation certify they did not engage in `` illegal or improper activity'' to obtain a defense contract; _ Required those 17 to agree, in any new contract greater than $ 100,000, to include a clause allowing the government to recover profits or 10 percent of the contract value if the deal is tainted; _ Started procedures to lift the security clearances of six people, including one suspended without pay from the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> and five others transferred to other duties pending results of the investigation; _ Sent letters to the top 200 defense contractors urging them to implement strong internal ethics programs, `` stringent management controls, and asking them to report back to us on their self-governance programs;'' _ Reviewed federal acquisition regulations to tighten controls on consultants employed by defense contractors; _ Formed an audit task force to review the cost imposed on the military budget by consultants <PERSON> Carlucci </PERSON> said the certification requirement was being applied only to the 17 implicated companies to avoid penalizing contractors who were not under suspicion. `` This is a rifle action. It is not a shotgun action,'' he said. `` We are directing this at certain contractors. We do not intend to apply it indiscriminately, because it does impose a burden on people. `` And where there are burdens, there are costs, and those costs may come back to the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> and the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> taxpayer,'' he said. `` It is only where we have reason to believe that people are under suspicion that we are doing this.'' <PERSON> Carlucci </PERSON> declined to identify people whose security clearances were being lifted, saying only that `` we are taking steps to revoke the security clearances of individuals who have been involved in illegal or improper actions.'' In a related development, the White House announced that President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> intends to nominate <PERSON> Milton </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Lohr </PERSON> to the new position of deputy undersecretary of defense for acquisition. Since 1983, <PERSON> Lohr </PERSON> has been president of the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> La </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jolla </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>. Before that, he was executive vice president of <ORGANIZATION> Flight </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Systems </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, from 1969-83 <PERSON> Lohr </PERSON>, a 63-year-old native of <LOCATION> Revere </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mass. </LOCATION>, graduated from the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION> in 1949 and the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION> at <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> in 1964.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880726-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-26-88 0115EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-US-CanadaTrade     07-26 0566</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-US-Canada Trade,530</SECOND>
<HEAD>Reagan Pays Tribute To Mulroney On Trade Pact</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto WX8</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Prenoon lede unlikely</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By MERRILL HARTSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> is praising Canadian Prime Minister <PERSON> Brian </PERSON> <PERSON> Mulroney </PERSON> at a time when <PERSON> Mulroney </PERSON> is encountering opposition to a sweeping U.S.-Canadian free-trade pact. At the same time, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> had kind words Monday for a <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> that often has come in for his criticism, saying lawmakers had put the agreement `` on a fast track'' _ just as he asked. The setting for the president's remarks was a Roosevelt Room ceremony at which <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> signed letters transmitting to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> legislation to implement the agreement. `` Throughout North American history, whenever and wherever trade barriers have been lowered, we've seen our economies bloom like mountain meadows after a spring rain,'' the president said. `` This agreement is a sun rising on a new morning of economic vitality,'' he said. `` It will save <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> consumers up to $ 3 billion a year. It will help keep the <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> economy growing for a generation to come.'' On Jan. 2, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and <PERSON> Mulroney </PERSON> signed an agreement that provides for the elimination of all tariffs in the two countries' $ 150 billion-a-year trade. It also would reduce many non-tariff barriers, liberalize investment practices and provide new rules covering cross-border trade in services. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> did not allude to the political situation in <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>, where <PERSON> Mulroney </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> Liberal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> opposition has threatened to stall legislation implementing the accord there until <PERSON> Mulroney </PERSON> calls new elections. But <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> quoted his Canadian counterpart as saying, `` The choice could n't be more clear-cut _ the voices of the past against a vision of the future.'' `` I asked the <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to put this on a fast track, which it did, and then some,'' he said. -LRB- Auto racing driver -RRB- <PERSON> Rick </PERSON> <PERSON> Mears </PERSON> could n't have driven it any faster, which shows what we can do when Democrats and Republicans work together.'' The accord ran into trouble last week in <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> when the opposition <ORGANIZATION> Liberal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> vowed to block ratification until <PERSON> Mulroney </PERSON> calls a general election. But <PERSON> Mulroney </PERSON>, in a heated <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commons </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> exchange </ORGANIZATION>, rejected demands for an immediate election to settle the free-trade issue _ a debate that has divided Canadians for a century. `` At an appropriate time, there will be an election,'' <PERSON> Mulroney </PERSON> said last Wednesday. White House spokesman <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said he did not believe <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials would comment `` on the internal affairs of <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> in terms of their elections.'' However, he said, `` we're still hopeful that they proceed with the Free Trade Agreement and that they'll be able to get that passed up there as well.'' <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> also said he hoped <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> would not amend or modify the agreement. He said he did not know whether such a move would require a renegotiation of the treaty. The Free Trade Agreement is scheduled to go into effect Jan. 1, 1989, provided <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and the Canadian <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION> pass implementing legislation. The changes will be phased in during a 10-year period. The House of Commons approved it in principle July 6 and has scheduled a third and final reading in mid-August after committee hearings. The legislation then goes to the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>, which has a large <ORGANIZATION> Liberal </ORGANIZATION> majority. <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>'s two opposition parties, the Liberals and socialist <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democrats </ORGANIZATION>, have accuse <PERSON> Mulroney </PERSON> of sacrificing the nation's sovereignty But <PERSON> Mulroney </PERSON> claims the deal will create prosperity and shield <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> from <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> protectionism.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880726-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-26-88 0036EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Shultz Bjt   07-26 0648</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Shultz, Bjt,640</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHINGTON WIRE: For Shultz, Patience Pays Off</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GEORGE GEDDA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Secretary of State <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> completed his sixth year in office just a few days ago, and it's hard to recall a time during that period when things looked better for him. East European nations are showing an increasing tendency to diversify their diplomatic contacts, reflected in planned visits to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> this week by <ORGANIZATION> Hungarian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> leader <PERSON> Karoly </PERSON> <PERSON> Grosz </PERSON> and <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>'s Foreign Minister <PERSON> Tadeusz </PERSON> <PERSON> Olechowski </PERSON>. Years have passed since either of these Soviet allies sent high-level visitors to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. In southwestern <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>, prospects have never seemed brighter for the withdrawal of Cuban and South African troops from <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION> and for Namibian independence from South African colonial rule. Pushed along by a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> mediation effort, <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION> have agreed to a statement of principle governing future negotiations and are to meet next week to discuss a timetable for the withdrawal of all foreign forces from the region. As <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> sees it, the withdrawal of Cuban forces from <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION> will free the area of superpower competition for the first time since the Cubans began arriving there in 1975. In addition, a South African pullback from <LOCATION> Namibia </LOCATION> would create conditions for independent rule in <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>'s last colony. Perhaps the best news for <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> lately is <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'s decision to accept the terms of a <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> resolution aimed at ending the 20th Century's longest major war. The administration has been working hard to encourage negotiated settlements in both southwestern <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION>. And administration officials in recent days have been feeling heady about the progress in both areas. But it's difficult to say whether these gains are the result of administration policy or just plain war weariness among the combatants. The fighting in <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION> dates back to the early 1960s; the war in the gulf has claimed more than 1 million lives. Even <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> is showing a far friendlier face to the outside world these days. Vietnamese forces have occupied neighboring <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION> for more than nine years, but <LOCATION> Hanoi </LOCATION> has promised to withdraw 50,000 troops this year and the rest in two years. It also has demonstrated a far more forthcoming attitude toward the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> on such issues as accounting for the nearly 2,400 American servicemen still listed as missing from the Vietnam War and its treatment of former officials identified with the former U.S.-backed regime in <LOCATION> Saigon </LOCATION>. An American team of technical experts is in <LOCATION> Hanoi </LOCATION> for discussions on arrangements for joint on-site inspections to help resolve the fate of the missing Americans. All this raises the possibility of eventual diplomatic ties with <LOCATION> Hanoi </LOCATION> for the first time since North <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> became independent more than 30 years ago. For now, however, the administration refuses even to discuss that possibility, waiting instead for a complete Vietnamese withdrawal from <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION> and a satisfactory accounting of <ORGANIZATION> MIA </ORGANIZATION>'s. On at least two issues, <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> is unable to claim progress. His efforts to promote Arab-Israeli peace talks have not borne fruit. In <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>, although a fragile cease-fire remains in place, the peace process is at an impasse and there is talk once again of renewed American military aid to the Contras. Still, the world seems like a far less contentious place to <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> than it was at the time of the last presidential election. In those days, <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> was able to cite the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> victory over the <ORGANIZATION> Grenadan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> as an achievement but not much else. That was before the rise of Soviet leader <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>, a time when Democrats were criticizing President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> for being the first <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> president in more than 50 years who had not met with a <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION> leader. That was four Soviet-American summits ago.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Gedda </PERSON> has covered foreign affairs for <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> since 1968.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880726-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-26-88 0015EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Canada-Election Bjt   07-26 0645</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Canada-Election, Bjt,0680</SECOND>
<HEAD>Political Debate Over Free Trade Has Parallel In 1911 Election</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto WX8</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JEFF BRADLEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>TORONTO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 For the second time this century, political furor over free trade with the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> could force a <LOCATION> Canadian </LOCATION> government out of office. The precedent was set in 1911 when long-serving Liberal Prime Minister Sir <PERSON> Wilfred </PERSON> <PERSON> Laurier </PERSON> proposed free trade but was pressured into an early election and defeated by the Conservatives. The roles are reversed this time. A Conservative prime minister, <PERSON> Brian </PERSON> <PERSON> Mulroney </PERSON>, has negotiated the U.S.-Canada Free Trade Agreement with <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, while the Liberal opposition claims the deal will turn <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> into little more than a resource base for the Americans. The agreement to dismantle duties and non-tariff barriers over a 10-year period is scheduled to take effect Jan. 1. President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> presented final legislation Monday to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and the Canadian <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commons </ORGANIZATION> is expected to approve the deal in August. In a bid to halt the ratification process, <ORGANIZATION> Liberal </ORGANIZATION> leader <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Turner </PERSON> played his final card last week. The Commons member asked the Liberal-dominated <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>, an appointed chamber that can delay and amend legislation, not to consider the bill until <PERSON> Mulroney </PERSON> calls an election on the issue. <PERSON> Mulroney </PERSON> accused Turner of hijacking the authority of elected members of <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION> _ meaning the Commons where Conservatives hold 207 of the 282 seats. <PERSON> Turner </PERSON>'s argument is that <PERSON> Mulroney </PERSON> has no mandate for entering a treaty that radically changes the future of <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>. In 1983, <PERSON> Mulroney </PERSON> spoke against free trade and the issue was not part of the Conservative election platform in 1984. `` The agreement should not go into effect until the people of <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> have had the opportunity to vote -LRB- on it -RRB-,'' said <PERSON> Turner </PERSON>, who maintains that such a pact would make <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> subservient to its giant neighbor. He urged <PERSON> Mulroney </PERSON> to call a September election, one year before his five-year term expires. That would provide enough time to implement the agreement if voters return <PERSON> Mulroney </PERSON> to office. The Liberals would tear up the deal if they win, <PERSON> Turner </PERSON> said. Polls show Canadians divided 50-50 on the issue and in favor of an election. But <PERSON> Mulroney </PERSON> reacted calmly to what he termed <PERSON> Turner </PERSON>'s `` act of desperation'' and said he has a full legislative agenda to complete before an election. He got a political boost Monday when a prominent Liberal, <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> van </PERSON> <PERSON> Roggen </PERSON>, resigned as chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Affairs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> so he could speak out in favor of free trade. <PERSON> Mulroney </PERSON>'s camp hoped more Liberals would break ranks. `` There's a lot bubbling around here and we'll have to wait and see what kind of stew comes out of the pot,'' <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Phillips </PERSON>, a top <PERSON> Mulroney </PERSON> aide, said. `` <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Turner </PERSON> has put a helluva lot of pressure on a lot of senators.'' <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>'s second opposition party, the socialist <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democrats </ORGANIZATION>, dislikes free trade. But party leader <PERSON> Ed </PERSON> <PERSON> Broadbent </PERSON> has accused Turner of abandoning democracy by using the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> to impede the will of the elected <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION>. The Conservatives have climbed steadily in the polls this year, while the other two parties have slumped. For <PERSON> Turner </PERSON>, deploying the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> is a gamble because he gave the Conservatives two diversionary election issues: his judgment in defying elected legislators and the need for <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> reform. `` The election outcome may very well be determined more by people's feelings about the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> than about free trade,'' columnist <ORGANIZATION> Orland </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> French </ORGANIZATION> wrote Monday in The Globe and Mail, the national newspaper. The situation has many parallels with 1911. The Conservatives then stirred up public opinion with the slogan `` No truck nor trade with the <ORGANIZATION> Yankees </ORGANIZATION>'' and filibustered for five months to force <PERSON> Laurier </PERSON> into an early election. Then, as now, the government had not included free trade in its election platform. But in 1911, the Conservatives did not use the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> to stop the treaty.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880726-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-26-88 0120EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-SuddenAcceleration     07-26 0340</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Sudden Acceleration,340</SECOND>
<HEAD>Mercedes Sudden Accleration Probe Expanded</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TIM BOVEE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 More than 300,000 <ORGANIZATION> Mercedes-Benz </ORGANIZATION> automobiles are under investigation to determine if hundreds of reports of unintended acceleration are true, the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Highway </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Traffic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> says. The agency said Monday it had broadened its probe into allegations that the vehicles speed up without the operator's intervention to encompass 309,000 cars made by Mercedes from 1984 through 1988 The cars are all equipped with gasoline engines and automatic transmissions. <ORGANIZATION> NHTSA </ORGANIZATION> in October had begun an investigation into 42,353 1986-1987 Mercedes Model 124 300E cars. The new engineering analysis broadens the regulatory case to include the Mercedes models 107 SL, 126 SE, SEL and <ORGANIZATION> SEC </ORGANIZATION>, and 201 190E. <ORGANIZATION> NHTSA </ORGANIZATION> said it has received reports of 301 instances of sudden acceleration in the Mercedes cars. The agency said 217 of the instances reportedly resulted in accidents that injured 92 people and killed one person. <ORGANIZATION> Mercedes-Benz </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> will cooperate fully with the <ORGANIZATION> NHTSA </ORGANIZATION> investigation, said A.B. <PERSON> Schuman </PERSON>, a spokesman for the company in <LOCATION> Montvale </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.J </LOCATION>. He said in the company's investigation of 283 sudden-acceleration reports, `` our technicians have never found any electrical, electronic or mechanical defect in our cars that could cause unintended acceleration.'' The Mercedes case is among six <ORGANIZATION> NHTSA </ORGANIZATION> investigations into alleged sudden acceleration involving at least 4.8 million vehicles. Other makers and the number of vehicles involved are <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Motor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, 3.2 million; <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Motors </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, 800,000; <ORGANIZATION> Audi </ORGANIZATION>, 255,000; <ORGANIZATION> Nissan </ORGANIZATION>, 183,000; and <ORGANIZATION> Honda </ORGANIZATION>, 62,500. The Mercedes investigation was opened at the request of the Center for Auto Safety, a consumer group often at odds with the auto industry and its regulators. `` The steady increase in sudden acceleration incidents in numerous Mercedes models other than the 1986-87 300E demonstrates that Mercedes' entire line of recent-year gasoline engine cars with automatic transmissions is affected by this defect,'' the center said. The center said it had received 164 reports of sudden acceleration in Mercedes cars, resulting in 125 accidents, 46 injuries and one death.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880726-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-26-88 0104EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FarmScene     07-26 0859</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Farm Scene,820</SECOND>
<HEAD>USDA Says Peanut Program Hikes Prices But Keeps Quality High</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DON KENDALL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Farm Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The government's peanut program restricts production and causes `` somewhat higher retail prices,'' says an <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> economist. But the program also helps provide `` a steady, high-quality supply of peanuts for consumers'' through a two-tiered price support system, says <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Schaub </PERSON> of the department's <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>. The two-tier system is scheduled to continue at least through the 1990 peanut marketing year. It involves a support rate for peanuts grown under a national quota, and a much lower rate for peanuts grown in addition to the quota. Quota peanuts are sold for domestic food and related uses, while the `` additional'' peanuts are used for export or crushing into oil and meal. <PERSON> Schaub </PERSON>, whose analysis is in the current <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Food </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Review </ORGANIZATION>, said net outlays by the department's <ORGANIZATION> Commodity </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Credit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> averaged $ 10 million annually between 1982 and 1986, well below the average of $ 30 million during the 1960s and the $ 61 million of the 1970s. `` The current program is expected to keep costs to <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> taxpayers to a minimum because the program is designed for quota production to equal domestic food and related demand,'' he said. However, <PERSON> Schaub </PERSON> acknowledged that the peanut program could cost substantially more if the national marketing quota greatly exceeded what processors want to buy at the quota rate. Should that happen, the government would wind up buying the unwanted peanuts and hold them as surplus. The 1988 price support, or loan rate, is $ 615.27 per ton for peanuts grown within a farmer's quota. The support for additional peanuts is $ 149.75 per ton. Farmers put their crop in storage arranged by grower associations. The peanuts then are pooled and controlled by the associations and the CCC. If the association sells the peanuts at a profit, growers participating in that pool are eligible for dividend payments. If the peanuts can not be sold on the market at the quota price, the CCC is obligated to buy them at the quota rate. <PERSON> Schaub </PERSON> said the peanut program does raise consumer prices and lower supplies by supporting farmers' prices and setting quota. But it's difficult to say what prices would be without the program. `` We do know that the break-even price for peanuts _ the longrun average price needed for growers to recover all production costs _ was about $ 420 -LRB- per ton -RRB- in 1986,'' he said. `` Therefore, a free market price would likely be closer to $ 420 than the $ 607-a-ton quota loan rate set for that year.'' But <PERSON> Schaub </PERSON> added that even these numbers can be questioned because the peanut programs _ which go back to 1934 _ have existed so long that farmers have altered production and marketing practices accordingly. Americans consume an average of about 8.5 pounds of peanuts a year, on a per capita basis, including peanut butter and candy, as well as roasted, salted and from the shell. <PERSON> Schaub </PERSON> said the government programs probably have not had a significant impact on peanut demand, at least partly because there are few good, comparably priced substitutes. In other words, he said, lower prices would not necessarily mean substantially greater consumption.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A 26-mile stretch of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Highway 64 in southeastern <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> is the first segment of a new National Forest Scenic Byways system set up by the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> chief <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Dale </PERSON> <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> said Monday the byway is located in the <ORGANIZATION> Cherokee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> and passes through scenic areas dominated by rock bluffs, mountain peaks and <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ocoee </LOCATION>. The byway also offers ready access to white-water rafting, boating, swimming and historical sites related to the Civil War and the Cherokee Indian culture, he said. The program was begun this summer `` to increase the scenic enjoyment of the millions of people who drive through national forests each year,'' <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> said. Despite a variety of more active recreational activities, driving for pleasure remains the most popular in the nation's 156 national forests located in 43 states, he said. Various groups are working with the <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> agency to place interpretive signs, develop brochures and provide facilities designed to make a drive through the forests more enjoyable, <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> said. A spokesman for the agency, <PERSON> Jay </PERSON> <PERSON> Humphreys </PERSON>, said he expected `` probably three or four more'' scenic byways will be designated by the end of summer. He said nominations are due by Oct. 1. The <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> byway was the first to be nominated and the first to be approved, <PERSON> Humphreys </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The nation's hens worked a little harder last month, but because of fewer birds the extra effort fell short of the year-ago production mark, according to an <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> report. June output was estimated at 5.52 billion eggs, down 2 percent from June 1987, the department's <ORGANIZATION> Agricultural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Statistics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> said Monday. Meanwhile, the number of hens in laying flocks declined 3 percent during the month to an average of 269 million birds. Individually, however, the fewer hens shelled out more eggs _ an average of 2,054 eggs per 100 birds during June, up from 2,033 a year earlier, the report said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880726-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-26-88 0126EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Bentsen-Finances     07-26 0711</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bentsen-Finances,680</SECOND>
<HEAD>Democratic Campaign Funds Held Up By Complaint Over Dual Bentsen
Race</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDs: No PMs lead likely; FEC meeting in mid-afternoon</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By JIM DRINKARD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Some $ 46 million in public money to finance <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' Democratic presidential campaign is being held up temporarily by a tangle over running mate <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>'s dual campaigns for vice president and the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Senatorial </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> filed a complaint with the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Election </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> alleging that any money <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> spends on his <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> re-election bid in <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> will directly benefit the party's presidential ticket and give it an unfair advantage over the Republicans. The <ORGANIZATION> FEC </ORGANIZATION> was considering the matter today. Commission spokeswoman <PERSON> Sharon </PERSON> <PERSON> Snyder </PERSON> said the commission has 10 days to decide how to handle the unprecedented issue. The <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> campaign filed its request for the money late Friday, and the existence of the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> complaint will add to the time it takes to release the federal campaign funds, she said. <PERSON> Jann </PERSON> <PERSON> Olsten </PERSON>, executive director of the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> committee, said at a news conference Monday that <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> is poised to spend more than $ 4 million on his <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> re-election campaign at the same time he is running for vice president. An unusual <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> law permits <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> to seek both offices simultaneously. `` There is no denying that one -LRB- race -RRB- is going to impact the other,'' <ORGANIZATION> Olsten </ORGANIZATION> said. `` A dollar spent by Senator <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, whether for the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> or the vice presidential campaign, is going to directly and immediately benefit both ... It just is n't fair.'' The 1976 law that created public financing for presidential campaigns stipulates that candidates who receive the federal money can not accept private funds for their campaigns. The $ 46 million each for the Democratic and Republican tickets comes from a $ 1 check-off on individual income tax returns. The <ORGANIZATION> NRSC </ORGANIZATION>, in a complaint filed Friday with the <ORGANIZATION> FEC </ORGANIZATION>, asked that the government withhold the federal campaign funds until it either bars the spending of <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> campaign chest or determines to count any <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> campaign spending against the $ 46 million limit. <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> opponent, Rep. <PERSON> Beau </PERSON> <PERSON> Boulter </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Texas </LOCATION>, said at a <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION> news conference that <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> intends to circumvent the law and should either bow out of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> race or not spend money raised for the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> race. `` Nobody expects him to do either,'' <PERSON> Boulter </PERSON> said. `` He wants it both ways.'' <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> spokesman <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> DeVore </PERSON> said <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>'s legal advisers had researched the issue and believed there was no problem with conducting and financing both campaigns, and said the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> was trying to win a free ride for <PERSON> Boulter </PERSON>. `` They know the <ORGANIZATION> Bentsen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> campaign would help the national ticket whether Sen. <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> was part of the ticket or not,'' <PERSON> DeVore </PERSON> said. `` What they're really saying is they're scared silly.'' <ORGANIZATION> FEC </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman <PERSON> Snyder </PERSON> noted that the only other case involving a similiar, but not parallel situation, was in 1976 when <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> ran for president and for the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>. The commission at that time was asked to rule on whether he could spend the legal limit for both his <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> and presidential primary race. The decision was that he could not because he would gain a ` ` significant publicity advantage'' over his rivals by spending more money overall throughout <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> But that ruling is not a good precedent for this case because there are no limits on <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> campaign spending any more and the issues are different, said <PERSON> Snyder </PERSON>. `` It was a different legal situation,'' she said. The current case is more likely to revolve around how various campaign expenses are paid for _ such things as whether <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> campaign photos of <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> with <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> could be paid out of his <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> fund or would be considered presidential expenditures. Another potential gray area might involve which campaign would pay for signs stating `` Vote Bentsen'' without any further indication of what office was being referenced. <ORGANIZATION> Olsten </ORGANIZATION> said if the <ORGANIZATION> FEC </ORGANIZATION> should rule against the Republican complaint it was likely that the party would seek a federal court injunction to halt the flow of federal campaign money. <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>'s latest <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> campaign report shows he has $ 3.9 million in cash on hand for his <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> race. Since the beginning of 1987, he has raised more than $ 6 million.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880726-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-26-88 0126EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-BoxOffice     07-26 0561</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Box Office,0583</SECOND>
<HEAD>`Roger Rabbit' on Top</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JEFF WILSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>HOLLYWOOD (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Business is booming at the nation's movie theaters this summer with hits like `` Who Framed Roger Rabbit'' producing revenues running well ahead of last year's record $ 4.2 billion take. `` The business is really rolling along. It's got momentum because there's variety, a selection for every taste,'' <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Krier </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> Exhibitor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Relations </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> said Monday. With the completion of eight weeks of the traditionally rich summer season, more than $ 934 million worth of tickets have been sold, 13 percent more than for the period last year. The industry trade paper <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Variety </ORGANIZATION> said when all the receipts are tallied the summer box office may reach $ 1.7 billion compared with $ 1.59 billion a year ago. Analysts attributed the revenue gains to the diversity of this summer's films _ ranging from mindless comedies, animated and partially-animated films and violent, action-packed fare. `` When you have many popular films, you have a great summer,'' said Variety's <PERSON> Art </PERSON> <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON>. `` You notice there are no films that did $ 10 million or more. That's because there is competition. It's the quality of product.'' <PERSON> Steven </PERSON> <PERSON> Spielberg </PERSON>'s collaboration with <ORGANIZATION> Disney </ORGANIZATION>, `` Who Framed <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> Rabbit </PERSON>,'' featuring the technological wizardry of live and animated characters, regained the No. 1 position at the nation's box offices last weekend with a take of $ 8.9 million. It nudged out last week's top film `` Coming to <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>.'' The second-place <PERSON> Eddie </PERSON> <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON> film earned $ 8.8 million, just $ 33,000 shy of the leader. <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Willis </PERSON>' `` Die Hard'' was third, <PERSON> Clint </PERSON> <PERSON> Eastwood </PERSON>'s `` Dead Pool'' was fourth, the <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> DeNiro-Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Grodin </PERSON> comedy `` Midnight Run'' was fifth and the re-release of the 46-year-old Disney classic `` Bambi'' was sixth. The mindless `` Big Top Pee-wee'' faired poorly in its debut, bringing in $ 4.6 million to place seventh, and `` Caddyshack II'' was eighth with $ 4.4 million. The <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Hanks </PERSON> hit `` Big,'' placing ninth, maintained its stature after eight weeks of release by adding $ 3.9 million in receipts for a total gross of $ 75.2 million. `` Bull Durham'' rounded out the top 10 with $ 2.4 million. Here are the top films for the weekend as tallied by Exhibitor Relations, with distributor, weekend gross, number of theater screens, average per screen, total gross, number of weeks in release and estimated production costs when available. 1. `` Who Framed <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> Rabbit </PERSON>,'' Disney, $ 8.92 million, 1,402 screens, $ 6,362 per screen, $ 84.1 million, five weeks, $ 40 million. 2. `` Coming To <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>,'' Paramount, $ 8.89 million, 2,064 screens, $ 4,305 per screen, $ 81.2 million, four weeks, $ 20 million. 3. `` Die Hard,'' 20th Century <PERSON> Fox </PERSON>, $ 7.1 million, 1,276 screens, $ 5,569 per screen, $ 10.1 million, two weeks, n-a. 4. `` The Dead Pool,'' <ORGANIZATION> Warner </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bros. </ORGANIZATION>, $ 6.0 million, 1,831 screens, $ 3,285 per screen, $ 23.1 million, two weeks, $ 18 million. 5. `` Midnight Run,'' Universal, $ 5.5 million, 1,158 screens, $ 4,775 per screen, $ 7.1 million, one week, n-a. 6. `` Bambi,'' <ORGANIZATION> Disney </ORGANIZATION>, $ 5.3 million, 1,489 screens, $ 3,570 per screen, $ 18.3 million, two weeks, $ 2 million -LRB- in 1942 -RRB-. 7. `` Big Top Pee-wee,'' Paramount, $ 4.6 million, 1,256 screens, $ 3,682 per screen, $ 4.6 million, one week, n-a. 8. `` Caddyshack II,'' <ORGANIZATION> Warner </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bros. </ORGANIZATION>, $ 4.4 million, 1,556 screens, $ 2,851 per screen, $ 4.4 million, one week, n-a. 9. `` Big,'' 20th Century <PERSON> Fox </PERSON>, $ 3.9 million, 1,276 screens, $ 3,060 per screen, $ 75.3 million, eight weeks, $ 15 million. 10. `` Bull Durham,'' <ORGANIZATION> Orion </ORGANIZATION>, $ 2.4 million, 1,019 screens, $ 2,371 per screen, $ 36.3 million, six weeks, $ 12 million.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880726-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-26-88 0127EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Dukakis     07-26 0351</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Dukakis,350</SECOND>
<HEAD>Dukakis Sticking To Statehouse Duties</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN KING</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BOSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> is maintaining his hybrid schedule of Statehouse duties and presidential campaigning by tending to gubernatorial tasks today, including a law-and-order event. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> was spending most of today at the office, with a visit to a new police post at a downtown subway stop to swear in six new members of the state transit authority police force. The <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> governor spent all of Monday at the <ORGANIZATION> Statehouse </ORGANIZATION>, putting aside state business for an hour-long meeting with Hungarian Prime Minister <PERSON> Karoly </PERSON> <PERSON> Grosz </PERSON> before the communist leader headed to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> to meet President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>. Wednesday also was to be a Statehouse day for <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, who kicks off an eight-state campaign swing Thursday. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> kept a low profile Monday, refusing to comment as he walked <PERSON> Grosz </PERSON> out of his office to an elevator surrounded by reporters. <PERSON> Grosz </PERSON> is the first East European communist party leader to come to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> in 10 years and the first <LOCATION> Hungarian </LOCATION> leader to visit this country in more than 40 years. At the top of <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' state agenda is legislative unrest with some of the $ 138 million in planned spending <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> vetoed from the state's fiscal 1989 budget. Some lawmakers, irate over the slashing of $ 91 million in local aid, have asked the legislative leadership to halt a summer recess so they can attempt to override the vetoes. `` Not to worry _ all is well,'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> said when asked Monday afternoon to discuss a meeting between the administration's top budget officer and <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Speaker <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Keverian </PERSON>. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' schedule this week fits with his primary season practice of spending Monday through Wednesday at the <ORGANIZATION> Statehouse </ORGANIZATION> before heading out to campaign. He is expected to continue that pattern through much of the general election campaign. The tentative schedule for this week's trip includes stops in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' running mate, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> Sen. <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>, took a weekend campaign trip with <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> but was not scheduled to campaign with the governor this week.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880726-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-26-88 0046EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-CounterfeitIndictment     07-26 0332</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Counterfeit Indictment,0341</SECOND>
<HEAD>Counterfeit Indictment Names Former Police Chief, Supremacist
Leader</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PITTSBURGH (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A one-time police chief, a former white supremacist leader and three other men have been charged in what prosecutors say was a scheme to pass $ 100,000 in counterfeit money to raise money for paramilitary organizations. The federal indictment revealed Monday accuses <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Wickstrom </PERSON>, 45, with attempting to buy conterfeit $ 20 and $ 50 bills through <PERSON> Victor </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Rizzo </PERSON>, a chiropractor in <LOCATION> Cambria </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, about 70 miles east of <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Wickstrom </PERSON>, who was arrested June 24, is a former leader of the supremacist group, Posse Comitatus. At a hearing June 29, <ORGANIZATION> Secret </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> agent <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Reddington </PERSON> said <PERSON> Wickstrom </PERSON> planned to pass the fake bills for genuine currency overseas to help support right-wing, paramilitary organizations. Also named in the six-count indictment was <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gardner </PERSON>, 44, who was police chief in <LOCATION> Youngstown </LOCATION>, about 35 miles southeast of <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION>, from 1980 to 1983; and <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Ryan </PERSON>, 29, of <LOCATION> Dublin </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION>, who was staying with <PERSON> Rizzo </PERSON> and was identified as his driver. The indictment charges them with conspiracy, counterfeiting and firearms violations. The fifth man named in the indictment, <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> Luttner </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Latrobe </LOCATION>, is in <LOCATION> Westmoreland </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> prison on state burglary charges. He is accused of providing paper for the production of phony bills. <PERSON> Gardner </PERSON> now works as a paramilitary instructor, according to documents prepared for his appearance before a federal magistrate after his arrest Monday. He was released on $ 5,000 bond. He is accused of agreeing to provide armed protection when the phony money was purchased. <PERSON> Rizzo </PERSON> and <PERSON> Ryan </PERSON> were arrested June 22 when <PERSON> Rizzo </PERSON> took delivery of counterfeit bills from an undercover <ORGANIZATION> Secret </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> agent. They are free on $ 10,000 bond. <PERSON> Wickstrom </PERSON>, who has been in custody since his arrest June 24, served a 13-month prison sentence in <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION> for Posse-related activities. He lives in <LOCATION> Homer </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, about 45 miles east of <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION>. Authorities claim he began a branch of the white-supremacist <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Identity </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> in that town.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880726-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-26-88 0058EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-PrisonDisturbance 4thLd-Writethru a0667 07-26 0436</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Prison Disturbance, 4th Ld - Writethru, a0667,0443</SECOND>
<HEAD>Injuries Reported in Maryland Penitentiary Disturbance</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: LEADS with 4 grafs to UPDATE with number of injured guards
now put at eight, sted seven; governor meeting with prison
officials, picking up 4th graf pvs, `Shipley said...'. SUBS grafs
10 and 11, `Two guards...,' to update with detail on injuries to
guards and psychologist. Picks up 12th graf pvs, `The problem...'.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By ANNE FITZHENRY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BALTIMORE (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Disturbances broke out among inmates at a maximum-security prison, injuring eight guards, a prison psychologist and three inmates, authorities said. `` It appears to be under control,'' <PERSON> Luther </PERSON> <PERSON> Starnes </PERSON>, assistant press secretary to Gov. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Schaefer </PERSON>, said about an hour after ambulances were sent to the <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Penitentiary </LOCATION> in downtown <LOCATION> Baltimore </LOCATION>. State Police spokesman Cpl. <PERSON> Greg </PERSON> <PERSON> Shipley </PERSON> said no prisoners escaped. <PERSON> Schaefer </PERSON> met Monday night with the prison warden and state prison officials, and said afterward that he was satisfied with their handling of the disturbance. <PERSON> Shipley </PERSON> said the disturbance began in the recreation yard shortly before 1 p.m, spread to a crisis clinic where the psychologist was having a session with inmates, and erupted again in another section of the yard. He said a minor fire also was set in the clinic. <LOCATION> Baltimore </LOCATION> police carrying shotguns immediately surrounded the perimeter of the prison, and a police helicopter flew overhead. Several downtown streets were blocked off, causing traffic backups. Prison officials did not know the reason for the three incidents and do not think they were organized, <PERSON> Shipley </PERSON> said. Two homemade knives were recovered, and several gunshots also were fired, he said. Officials said the prison immediately was `` locked down,'' with inmates locked in their cells. Two inmates, one in critical condition and one in fair, were being treated for gunshot wounds, said <PERSON> Anita </PERSON> <PERSON> Hisley </PERSON>, spokeswoman for <PERSON> Johns </PERSON> <PERSON> Hopkins </PERSON> <PERSON> Hospital </PERSON>. The third inmate was being treated at the prison hospital, which handles less-serious injuries, officials said. One of the eight injured guards suffered a gunshot wound to the neck, but authorities believe he may have been wounded by another officer during the melee. He and two other guards were hospitalized, while the others were treated and released. The psychologist was treated for facial injuries and released. The problem apparently resulted from an altercation that possibly followed an aborted escape attempt, said <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Bowlander </PERSON>, executive director of <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> 92 of the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Municipal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Employees </ORGANIZATION>, which represents correctional officers. The penitentiary, which opened in 1811, ordinarily holds 700 to 800 men, but Monday's inmate count was 1,270. Eighteen of its inmates are on death row.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880726-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-26-88 0129EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Salvador     07-26 0575</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Salvador,0596</SECOND>
<HEAD>Duarte Lauds Peace Plan; Rebels Attack Bowling Alley In San
Salvador</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DOUGLAS GRANT MINE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SAN SALVADOR, El Salvador (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Napoleon </PERSON> <PERSON> Duarte </PERSON> called a Central American peace plan a regional `` declaration of independence'' but accused <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> of not fulfilling obligations under the year-old effort. Also Monday, guerrillas set fire to a bowling alley in the capital to retaliate after police dispersed an anti-government march, the manager said. No one was reported hurt and no group claimed responsibility for the attack. <PERSON> Duarte </PERSON>, 62, appeared energetic Monday during his first news conference since he returned to <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION> July 11 after six weeks of medical treatment in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. He is suffering from terminal liver cancer and doctors give him six to 18 months more to live. <PERSON> Duarte </PERSON> accused <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>'s leftist Sandinista government of not adhering to terms of the peace plan signed Aug. 7 in <LOCATION> Guatemala </LOCATION> by the five Central American presidents. The plan calls for negotiations between governments and insurgents to end civil wars in <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Guatemala </LOCATION>. It also calls for amnesties for politically motivated crimes, moves toward democratization and a ban on outside support for guerrilla movements. The plan `` has fulfilled many of its objectives and must be considered a declaration of principles and, for me, it has been a second declaration of independence for <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Duarte </PERSON> said. `` In the short term, some of the plan's objectives have been fulfilled, and some have not been fulfilled,'' he said, without elaborating. `` <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>, in signing -LRB- the accord -RRB-, made an appearance of trying to put it into practice, but obviously that put it into confrontation with democracy,'' he added. <PERSON> Duarte </PERSON> accused the Sandinistas of supporting leftist Salvadoran guerrillas battling his U.S.-backed government. <PERSON> Duarte </PERSON>'s government declared an amnesty for political crimes and lifted a state of emergency to comply with the peace initiative. But there have been no talks between the government and rebels since October. The foreign ministers of <LOCATION> Guatemala </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Costa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rica </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION> meet Aug. 1 in <LOCATION> Guatemala </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> with <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Secretary of State <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> to discuss the plan's achievements and shortcomings. <PERSON> Duarte </PERSON> said there are no plans for a meeting of presidents to mark the initiative's first anniversary. Meanwhile, 10 to 12 masked men with pistols and at least one submachine gun set fire to a bowling alley after taking money from about 30 patrons and identifying themselves as `` urban commandos'' of the <ORGANIZATION> Faribundo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Marti </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION>, said <PERSON> Guillermo </PERSON> <PERSON> Castro </PERSON>, manager of the <PERSON> Bolerama </PERSON> <PERSON> Jardin </PERSON>. The front, a coalition of five guerrilla groups, has waged an 8-year-old war against the government. <PERSON> Castro </PERSON> said the guerrillas took `` money they said was a ` contribution' to the cause. They said the attack was in reprisal for the government's repression of Thursday's march.'' The guerrillas then doused several pool tables in a room adjoining the main bowling area with gasoline and set them afire, <PERSON> Castro </PERSON> said. Firefighters arrived within 15 minutes and extinguished the blaze. <PERSON> Castro </PERSON> said none of the bowling alley's owners has any connection with the government and that he did not understand why the business was targeted. On Thursday last week, police used tear gas and fired shots in the air to break up an anti-government demonstration in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>. Protesters then burned at least nine vehicles. Human rights groups estimate more than 65,000 people have been killed in <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION> since the civil war began in October 1979.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880726-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-26-88 0130EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-VoodooMayor-Impeach     07-26 0256</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Voodoo Mayor-Impeach,0265</SECOND>
<HEAD>Judge Scheduled Impeachment Trial For `Voodoo Mayor'</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ANDALUSIA, Ala. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A judge has scheduled an impeachment trial for an 85-year-old mayor who last week donned a turban and rubber snakes while declaring `` National Voodoo Week.'' But an attorney for Florala Mayor H.T. <PERSON> Mathis </PERSON> said the trial is moot because the mayor's four-year term ends Oct. 3. `` Really I think he is more interested in clearing his name than anything else,'' said attorney <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Prestwood </PERSON>. <LOCATION> Covington </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> Circuit Judge <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Baldwin </PERSON> on Monday refused to dismiss charges of neglect of duty, corruption and incompetency, and set an Aug. 29 trial date. Last week, while clad in a turban and rubber snakes, <PERSON> Mathis </PERSON> proclaimed `` National Voodoo Week'' at a midnight news conference on the steps of the county courthouse. The mayor said `` National Voodoo Week'' was aimed at promoting publicity for the town and peace among the residents. Attorney General <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Siegelman </PERSON> has accused <PERSON> Mathis </PERSON> of mismanagement and improperly pardoning about two dozen drunken drivers in <LOCATION> Florala </LOCATION>, a town of about 2,200 residents on the <LOCATION> Alabama-Florida </LOCATION> border. <PERSON> Mathis </PERSON> has said he has pardoned numerous DUI convictions because of what he calls overzealous police officers. <PERSON> Siegelman </PERSON> said <PERSON> Mathis </PERSON>' `` voodoo antics'' may be an issue at the trial. <PERSON> Mathis </PERSON> said <PERSON> Siegelman </PERSON> had no right to ask a judge to empanel the county grand jury that returned the impeachment recommendation. <PERSON> Prestwood </PERSON> said he was `` absolutely optimistic'' that <PERSON> Mathis </PERSON> would be found innocent at the impeachment trial, but may seek a delay to prepare for the trial.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880726-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-26-88 0147EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Philippines-AmericanShot     07-26 0278</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Philippines-American Shot,280</SECOND>
<HEAD>US Serviceman Killed While Jogging Near Base</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A soldier who was jogging in a neighborhood near <LOCATION> Clark </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Air </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Base </LOCATION> became the first <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> serviceman to be killed in the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION> in nine months when gunmen shot him from a speeding car, authorities said. A <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> statement identified the victim as Technical Sgt. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Blackmer </PERSON>, 31, of the <LOCATION> Cleveland </LOCATION> suburb of <LOCATION> Brook </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Park </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Blackmer </PERSON> was assigned to the 1961 <ORGANIZATION> Communications </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Group </ORGANIZATION>. The statement said he was shot while jogging in the Mountain View subdivision of <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, less than a mile from the base's main gate <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> is 50 miles northwest of <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION>. A <PERSON> Clark </PERSON> base spokeswoman, Capt. <PERSON> Maryellen </PERSON> <PERSON> Jadick </PERSON>, said `` initial reports indicate the shooting was criminal in nature and not politically motivated.'' Ms. <PERSON> Jadick </PERSON>, interviewed by telephone from the <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> bureau in <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION>, would not elaborate on how <PERSON> Blackmer </PERSON> was killed. Police Lt. <PERSON> Federico </PERSON> <PERSON> Naguit </PERSON> said a car sped by <PERSON> Blackmer </PERSON> as he jogged in Mountain View and gunmen in the vehicle sprayed the man with automatic gunfire. It was the first slaying of a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> serviceman in the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION> since Oct. 28, 1987, when gunmen killed two active-duty American servicemen and a retired <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military man outside <PERSON> Clark </PERSON>. Leftist guerrillas claimed responsibility for the October attacks. The <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> said the <ORGANIZATION> Clark </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Special </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Investigations </ORGANIZATION> and local authorities are conducting a joint probe of the shooting. Nearly 40 people have been killed in <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> and other communities around <LOCATION> Clark </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Air </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Base </LOCATION> since Jan. 1. Police say most of the slayings are politically motivated, and consider the district around the base a communist stronghold.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880726-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-26-88 0100EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-InsulationDanger     07-26 0415</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Insulation Danger,0427</SECOND>
<HEAD>Agency Investigating Wiring Insulation at Nuclear Plants</HEAD>
<DATELINE>FORT WORTH, Texas (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Nuclear Regulatory Commission is re-evaluating the use of a wiring insulation found in most <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> nuclear power plants after discovering damaged electrical circuits at several facilities, according to a published report. <PERSON> Uldis </PERSON> <PERSON> Potapovs </PERSON>, chief of the commission's unit that inspects vendor-supplied plant equipment, said the insulating material known as <PERSON> Kapton </PERSON> appears to damage easily under mechanical stress and even in routine handling by plant maintenance crews, the <ORGANIZATION> Fort </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Worth </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Star-Telegram </ORGANIZATION> reported in Tuesday's editions. Worn or damaged <PERSON> Kapton </PERSON> has been discovered on electrical wires that connect reactor containment buildings with main-plant control circuits located outside the reactor, <PERSON> Potapovs </PERSON> told the newspaper. He said such damage is a `` significant concern'' because it could cause erroneous equipment readings or failure of equipment, but there has never been a failure serious enough to produce a fire. <PERSON> Kapton </PERSON> can be found on wiring in most of the nation's 104 operating nuclear power plants, <PERSON> Potapovs </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Kapton </PERSON>, made by E.I. du <ORGANIZATION> Pont </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> de </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nemours </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ; </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, is a thin, lightweight insulation often used to wrap wiring in high-performance aircraft. It has been cited as a factor in dozens of aircraft fires and is suspected of contributing to dozens more, the Star-Telegram has reported in a series of stories this week. <PERSON> Du </PERSON> <PERSON> Pont </PERSON> has long maintained that its insulation does not crack or break any sooner than other insulation. The <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>, which has banned <LOCATION> Kapton </LOCATION> in its aircraft, says the material deteriorates prematurely, cracks easily and even explodes under certain conditions. But other <LOCATION> Kapton </LOCATION> users, including the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> and most commercial aircraft builders, say the insulation is the best on the market for the job. Asked if the <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION> might call for a ban on <LOCATION> Kapton </LOCATION> in nuclear plants, <PERSON> Potapovs </PERSON> said, `` That certainly would be a possibility.'' But <PERSON> Potapovs </PERSON> added that it seems more likely that the agency will issue a non-binding notice to plant operators recommending that <PERSON> Kapton </PERSON> wires be reinforced with a sleeve or coating and that maintenance crews be instructed in how to best handle the material. The <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION> has already issued one notice dealing with <PERSON> Kapton </PERSON> problems at nuclear power plants, agency records show. The agency reported Feb. 4, 1987, that wires wrapped with <PERSON> Kapton </PERSON> had shorted out because of `` insulation degradation'' on two occasions at separate plants. The wires were in small electric motors that regulated the opening and closing of steam supply valves at the plants.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880726-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-26-88 0154EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-CancerLinks Bjt   07-26 0562</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Cancer Links, Bjt,0577</SECOND>
<HEAD>Cancer Gene Linked To Breast And Lung Cancers</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PAUL RAEBURN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Science Editor</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BAR HARBOR, Maine (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
