<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880825-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-25-88 0031EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-APArts:ProfessorGumshoe     08-25 0683</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AP Arts: Professor Gumshoe,0701</SECOND>
<HEAD>Professor Turns Gumshoe</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By JAMES O. CLIFFORD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SAN FRANCISCO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Professor <PERSON> Josiah </PERSON> <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON> is an expert on such noted philosophers as <PERSON> Kierkegaard </PERSON>, <PERSON> Nietzsche </PERSON> _ and <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> <PERSON> Spade </PERSON>. <PERSON> Spade </PERSON>? What in the name of <PERSON> Humphrey </PERSON> <PERSON> Bogart </PERSON> is going on here? A career change, that's what. In 1976, <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON>, driven by a `` thirst for experience,'' left his tenured position as professor of philosophy at <ORGANIZATION> Haverford </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> _ a prestigous Quaker school in <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION>, came to <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> and became a private detective. He could n't have picked a better city in which to set up shop. <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION>'s hills are steeped in the lore of <PERSON> Dashiell </PERSON> <PERSON> Hammett </PERSON> and his legendary sleuth, <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> <PERSON> Spade </PERSON>, the `` blond Satan'' whose hair darkened when brought to the screen by <PERSON> Humphrey </PERSON> <PERSON> Bogart </PERSON> in `` The Maltese Falcon.'' There's even a bronze plaque on a <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> street, recalling a murder that took place only in <PERSON> Hammett </PERSON>'s mind: `` On approximately this spot Miles <PERSON> Archer </PERSON>, partner of <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> <PERSON> Spade </PERSON>, was done in by <PERSON> Brigid </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Shaughnessy </PERSON>.'' <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON>, whose previous writings were mostly limited to the academic world, has recounted his metamorphosis in a book appropriately called `` Gumshoe: Reflections in a Private Eye'' -LRB- Little, <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>, $ 17.95 -RRB-. He was born 53 years ago in <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Liverpool </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, where his father sold dishes. During World War I, his father took a pair of field glasses from a dead German and gave them to the youngster. <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON>, whose nickname is Tink, still uses the glasses on cases. He keeps them hanging over his desk and has used them on stakeouts. Even though slightly built, he played halfback in high school, closing his eyes `` on every play.'' Later, he was under fire in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> as an ensign with a <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Underwater </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Demolition </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Team </ORGANIZATION>, the elite Frogmen. Why did he become a professor in the first place, going from football bruises and the sound of warfare to the safety of a college campus? `` I had plenty of money when I got out of the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>, with demolition and combat pay,'' he said. `` I was a good student in high school so I went to <LOCATION> Oxford </LOCATION> and from there took the line of least resistance.'' When that line became a cul-de-sac, he took a sabbatical and grabbed a job with an established detective agency in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION>. During his apprenticeship and as his own boss, <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON> has worked on such headline cases as the defense of <PERSON> Black </PERSON> <PERSON> Panther </PERSON> <PERSON> Huey </PERSON> <PERSON> Newton </PERSON> on assault and murder charges, and the defense of <PERSON> William </PERSON> and <PERSON> Emily </PERSON> <PERSON> Harris </PERSON> in the <PERSON> Patty </PERSON> <PERSON> Hearst </PERSON> case. There were also other, less publicized capers, ranging from recovering $ 30,000 from under the floorboards of an attic in a drug case to retrieving a kidnapped child from <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON>'s wife, <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON>, sells real estate. They have two adult daughters and a son who plays soccer in college. He never carries a gun and he thinks the most dangerous part of his job is `` mistaken identity.'' `` I was taken for a spy on a case in <LOCATION> Morocco </LOCATION>,'' he said. `` And one time in <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>, while working on a drug case, word got around that a hit man was being brought in. When people heard I was from <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, some of them thought I was the guy. The bars would clear when I came in.'' While honing his skills as a gumshoe, <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON> has become fascinated by <PERSON> Hammett </PERSON> and <PERSON> Spade </PERSON>, so much so that on one case he took the time to interview some of <PERSON> Hammett </PERSON>'s relatives. <PERSON> Hammett </PERSON>, through <PERSON> Spade </PERSON>, was a bit of a philosopher, he says. `` In order to love, one must put off hardness and shiftiness,'' <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON> said. `` The ability to lie effectively, to appear different than one really is, all the disguises essential in the world of power, become, in the world of love, temptations, artful excuses to avoid the nakedness love requires, to avoid love.'' <PERSON> Hammett </PERSON> knew this, he said. `` That's why in the last line of The Maltese Falcon he makes <PERSON> Spade </PERSON> ` shiver' as he looks down the cold barrel of his future.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880825-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-25-88 0003EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-WildfiresRdp 1stLd-Writethru a0717 08-25 0867</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Wildfires Rdp, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0717,0881</SECOND>
<HEAD>Yellowstone's North Fork Fire Threatens Canyon Area</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto CKCX5</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Subs 3rd graf to UPDATE with fire within a mile from Canyon
area. Subs grafs 15 through end bgng `Just over' to add growth of
fires in Oregon and Idaho, and containment effort in Washington. No
pickup.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By ED ANDRIESKI</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>YELLOWSTONE NATIONAL PARK, Wyo. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A fire that has charred a 35-mile swath across the heart of <ORGANIZATION> Yellowstone </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Park </ORGANIZATION> threatened one of the park's most picturesque areas and forced out hundreds of visitors, officials said Wednesday. The rapidly burning North Fork fire, which started July 23 in <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Targhee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION>, grew to nearly 100,000 acres and forced the closure Wednesday morning of the Canyon area. Winds expected to reach 50 mph Wednesday in the park failed to materialize, and by nightfall the fire remained one mile to the west of the area, which is located a bit north of the center of the 60-mile-square park. Elsewhere, crews southeast of <LOCATION> Helena </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mont. </LOCATION>, said they expected to contain the 37,600-acre <LOCATION> Warm </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Springs </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Creek </LOCATION> blaze by Friday evening; and in <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION>, air tankers and fire crews fought a surging, 1,000-acre blaze on the slopes of <LOCATION> Hells </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Canyon </LOCATION>, the nation's deepest gorge The closure of Canyon, <ORGANIZATION> Yellowstone </ORGANIZATION>'s largest development with 600 cabins and 280 campsites, sent more than 700 visitors and employees to other parts of the park. `` My children are all excited about it,'' said tourist <PERSON> Allen </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>, of <LOCATION> Staffordshire </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>. `` It did n't detract from our visit at all.'' By midmorning Wednesday, only firefighters and reporters remained at Canyon, and the buzzing of chain saws filled the air as crews hurriedly removed downed trees and undergrowth. Smoke in the air partially obscured the view of the 308-foot Lower Falls and 109-foot Upper Falls. Fire officials said they hoped to keep the North Fork fire burning to the north of the Canyon area, but feared that embers could bring the blaze right into Canyon. <PERSON> Michelle </PERSON> <PERSON> Rotter </PERSON>, a park service public information officer, said the North Fork fire could then conceivably burn from Canyon and into the area blackened by the Clover Mist fire some miles to the east, in effect cutting the park virtually in two. Although not the biggest of the 10 fires that have burned more than 354,000 acres in <LOCATION> Yellowstone </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Fork </LOCATION> blaze has become the most dangerous to structures. Firefighters previously had come near to containing the fire, but the lack of rainfall combined with winds gusting to 60 mph repeatedly have fanned it out of control. The 156,500-acre Clover Mist fire earlier this week swung into the Shoshone National Forest east of <LOCATION> Yellowstone </LOCATION>. In the national forest, 635 Army regulars were working with professional firefighters to halt the advance. The so-called Snake Complex of fires, which includes the Red, Shoshone and Falls fires in southern Yellowstone, spread over 80,000 acres by Wednesday. While forcing the closure of the <LOCATION> Grant </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Village </LOCATION> area and the park's south entrance, the fires were not threatening any structures. Fires also posed threats both north and south of the park. To the south in Grand Teton National Park and the <ORGANIZATION> Bridger-Teton </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION>, firefighters dwarfed by 150-foot walls of flame battled to keep the 12,600-acre <PERSON> Huck </PERSON> fire from crossing into <ORGANIZATION> Yellowstone </ORGANIZATION> about 1 -LCB- miles away. The fire had more than doubled in size from Tuesday to Wednesday. Just over the <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION> line north of the park, nearly 600 additional firefighters and a top-level fire-management team from <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> arrived Wednesday to take over the 27,000-acre Storm Creek fire. The blaze is burning out of control in a wilderness area seven miles north of <LOCATION> Cooke </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, a town near the northeast corner of the park. Near <PERSON> Helena </PERSON>, crews had expected to contain the 37,600-acre Warm Springs Creek blaze Wednesday night, but pushed the deadline back two days because of one troublesome area along the fire lines, fire information officer <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Krepps </PERSON> said. The 2-week-old fire has burned more than a dozen structures. `` Once that's done and held, there's nothing much left to cause us any problem,'' <PERSON> Krepps </PERSON> said Wednesday. `` We're getting close. The noose is tightening.'' In <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION>, more than 400 firefighters were committed to the Eagle Bar blaze in <LOCATION> Hells </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Canyon </LOCATION>, which was burning out of control with no containment target in sight. The blaze made two significant runs Wednesday, moving into the <LOCATION> Deep </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Creek </LOCATION> drainage containing 12 million board feet of timber and toward the base camp at <LOCATION> Kinney </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Point </LOCATION>. In southern <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION>, a fire in Crater Lake National Park that charred 85 acres Tuesday grew to more than 1,000 acres Wednesday, burning across the park boundary into neighboring <ORGANIZATION> Winema </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION>. In central Oregon, firefighters nearly contained a blaze that charred 110 acres and forced the brief evacuation of three homes, but several lightning-caused blazes elsewhere in the state were reported out of control. In southwestern <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, calmer winds and cooler temperatures allowed firefighters to cut a containment line around 75 percent of a 500-acre fire 30 miles southwest of <LOCATION> Mount </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rainier </LOCATION> <LOCATION> National </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Park </LOCATION>, officials said. The fire grew from 60 acres to 500 on Tuesday thanks to gusty wind, 100-degree air and low humidity.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880825-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-25-88 2334EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p AM-Quayle-Resume     08-25 0502</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Quayle-Resume,490</SECOND>
<HEAD>Consumer Division Work Was Overstated, Report Says</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CLEVELAND (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Sen. <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>'s version of duties he handled as a consumer watchdog when he worked for the <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION> attorney general in 1970-71 appear to be exaggerated, an <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> newspaper reports in its Friday editions. The -LRB- <LOCATION> Cleveland </LOCATION> -RRB- Plain Dealer reported that state records in the <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION> archives reveal that <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>, 41, was a research assistant _ an entry-level job _ in the attorney general's office for most of that time, and held the consumer watchdog job for only 2 -LCB- months, from July to mid-September in 1971. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> biography, which is being distributed as official background of the Republican vice-presidential nominee, says: `` He was chief investigator for the Consumer Protection Division of the <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION> Attorney General's Office from 1970-1971.'' The Plain Dealer reported that the division was just being organized at the time. `` He just helped set it up,'' said <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Lybrook </PERSON>, a lawyer in <LOCATION> Martinsville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ind. </LOCATION>, who became the chief investigator in September 1971, when the division officially opened for business. State personnel records show <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> was already working for then-Gov. <PERSON> Edgar </PERSON> <PERSON> Whitcomb </PERSON> as an administrative assistant when the consumer division was officially launched. The consumer division had been created earlier in 1971 by the <ORGANIZATION> Indiana </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Legislature </ORGANIZATION>. The division was empowered to help resolve consumer complaints over such things as defective products, false advertising, odometer tampering and mail-order fraud. `` I do n't remember when <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> first started out,'' said <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, an <LOCATION> Indianapolis </LOCATION> lawyer who was the consumer division's first director <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> said <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> was assigned to his staff for a brief time before leaving to work in the governor's office. Said <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Stanton </PERSON> <PERSON> Evans </PERSON>, an editor at the <ORGANIZATION> Indianapolis </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> who arranged <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>'s job interview with then-Attorney General <PERSON> Theodore </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Sendak </PERSON>: `` He sure did n't start in that -LRB- consumer -RRB- job. He was n't chief of anything when he went over there. <PERSON> Evans </PERSON> worked for <PERSON> Eugene </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Pulliam </PERSON>, publisher of <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION>'s largest newspapers and <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>'s grandfather State records show that <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>, who graduated from <ORGANIZATION> DePauw </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> in May 1969 with a political science degree, went to work in the attorney general's office as a `` legal assistant'' in January 1970. The job is similar to that of a law clerk. It involved drafting legal memoranda, performing research for opinions and writing letters, according to other employees who worked in the attorney general's office at the time. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> was attending night school at <ORGANIZATION> Indiana </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Law </ORGANIZATION> at the same time. The office's annual report, filed in the <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION> state archives, shows <PERSON> Sendak </PERSON> did n't have a consumer division in 1970. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>'s picture was in the report with those of seven other research assistants <PERSON> Sendak </PERSON>'s 1971 annual report, which he was required to file under state law, has the pictures of the three staffers in the new consumer division. The three included <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, as the director, <PERSON> Roland </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Mather </PERSON> as assistant director and <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Lybrook </PERSON> as chief investigator. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> was not even listed as being on the attorney general's staff.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880825-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-25-88 2344EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-SpyRing 2ndLd-Writethru a0662 08-25 0899</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Spy Ring, 2nd Ld-Writethru, a0662,0921</SECOND>
<HEAD>Former U.S. Sergeant Sold Secrets To Soviets For Decade, Officials
Say</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: INSERTS 1 graf after 5th pvs `Clyde Lee ...' UPDATING with
some specific secrets reported stolen. PICKS up 6th graf pvs,
Conrad was...</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By KEVIN COSTELLOE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>FRANKFURT, West Germany (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A former <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> sergeant arrested in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> headed an international spy ring that sold <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> defense secrets to the Soviets at high prices for a decade, officials said Thursday. `` We ca n't exclude the possibility that millions of dollars are involved,'' said <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON> <PERSON> Prechtel </PERSON>, spokesman for the chief federal prosecutor's office. A second American soldier who was not identified received a `` five-figure sum'' of money for supplying the ring with military secrets, said Chief Federal Prosecutor <PERSON> Kurt </PERSON> <PERSON> Rebmann </PERSON>, and <PERSON> Prechtel </PERSON> said two Hungarian-born brothers arrested Tuesday in <LOCATION> Sweden </LOCATION> with cipher keys, coded messages and radios were a part of the ring. It was too early to know how much damage was caused to the <ORGANIZATION> North </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Atlantic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Treaty </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Prechtel </PERSON> said in an interview, but the ring is believed to have stolen documents concerning <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> defense plans for <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> and <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> contingency plans for a ground war with the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Clyde </PERSON> <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Conrad </PERSON>, the former sergeant, was arrested Tuesday, and a statement from the prosecutor's office said he was charged with `` compelling suspicion of espionage activities in an especially grave case.'' The <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> in its Friday editions quoted officials as saying <PERSON> Conrad </PERSON> gave away information on rocket bases and a secret <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> oil pipeline in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> to resupply tanks. The report from <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> did not identify the officials. <PERSON> Conrad </PERSON> was born in 1947 in <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> and worked for the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military for 20 years, <PERSON> Prechtel </PERSON> said. Army records list his hometown as Sebring, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>. He worked as an infantryman and then as an `` administration specialist'' during his active duty, according to his service records released in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Conrad </PERSON> received the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medal </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Vietnam </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medal </ORGANIZATION>, five Army Commendation medals, the Army Achievement Medal, three <ORGANIZATION> Meritorious </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> medals and seven Good Conduct medals. <PERSON> Prechtel </PERSON> said <PERSON> Conrad </PERSON> worked with classified military defense plans for seven years at a <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> base in <LOCATION> Bad </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kreuznach </LOCATION>, in central <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, and had access to a wide array of secret documents. <PERSON> Conrad </PERSON> allegedly continued espionage work after he left the service in 1985, <PERSON> Prechtel </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Rebmann </PERSON> said <PERSON> Conrad </PERSON> turned over the most recent batch of information to his Soviet bloc contact in <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION> just last month. Cable News Network on Thursday quoted unidentified West German sources as saying <PERSON> Conrad </PERSON> systematically photographed files between 1980 and 1985. The <ORGANIZATION> CNN </ORGANIZATION> report said investigators believe he may have transferred material onto a personal computer, which was seized at his home. Espionage cases are common in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, where Soviet bloc agents are active and sometimes are caught. But allegations of deep involvement by an <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> citizen in a West German-based ring are extremely rare. An official at the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, speaking on condition of anonymity, called the case `` a serious encroachment on our national security.'' White House spokesman <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> had been kept informed about the investigation `` on a continuing basis.'' But he added, `` We wo n't have any response or reaction at this point. We're looking into it.'' A special panel of <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> ordered <PERSON> Conrad </PERSON> held in prison pending further investigation, <PERSON> Rebmann </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Prechtel </PERSON> said the West German-based spy ring started in the late 1970s and used couriers from <LOCATION> Sweden </LOCATION>. In <LOCATION> Goteborg </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Sweden </LOCATION>, authorities said they detained two Hungarian-born brothers who confessed to working for the Hungarian secret service. The two men, physicians who immigrated to <LOCATION> Sweden </LOCATION> in the 1960s, were detained with radios, cipher keys and coded messages, authorities said. Their names were not released. The <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> reported Thursday that eight people were arrested by Swedish and West German in the ring operating through a German-Hungarian connection. The report said investigators believe the spy ring provided <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION>, West German and <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> secrets to the <LOCATION> Hungarian </LOCATION> intelligence agency. The Hungarians then shared the secrets with the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, officials told the Times. <PERSON> Prechtel </PERSON>, speaking from his office in the city of <LOCATION> Karlsruhe </LOCATION>, confirmed virtually all of the Times report. But he said `` several'' people were taken into custody or arrested and could not confirm that the number was eight. The Times said the network was uncovered by West German and <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials, including agents from the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>. The Army has about 250,000 military personnel in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> at more than 200 installations and frequently warns its personnel to beware of Soviet bloc spies. <PERSON> Rebmann </PERSON> said <PERSON> Conrad </PERSON> `` is under compelling suspicion of having delivered ... documents to a Soviet bloc secret service by means of a command officer and couriers living abroad in return for high payments.'' He did not identify the command officer but said the two last met in <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION> last month when <PERSON> Conrad </PERSON> allegedly again handed over secret documents for payment. After his retirement, <PERSON> Conrad </PERSON> tried to recruit other soldiers for espionage, <PERSON> Rebmann </PERSON> said. `` He recruited another member of the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> for espionage work and paid him a five-figure sum for the delivery of military documents,'' <PERSON> Rebmann </PERSON>'s statement said. The type of currency was not disclosed. The prosecutor's spokesman declined to release any further information about the second soldier.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880825-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-25-88 2358EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p AM-PoliticalRdp 2ndLd-Writethru a0732 08-25 1064</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Political Rdp, 2nd Ld-Writethru, a0732,1000</SECOND>
<HEAD>Vice Presidential Candidates Hit Rough Seas</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: INSERTS graf after 6th pvs, Quayle said...White House, to
update with published report about his resume; INSERTS two grafs
after 16th graf, Bush made...behind him, to update with Bush quotes
on SDI.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By DAVID ESPO</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Political Writer</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrat <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> said Thursday that cocaine imports have tripled in seven years and charged the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration with permitting a `` drug cancer'' to take root. <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said he represents `` proven tested leadership'' and likened his presidential rival to <PERSON> Jimmy </PERSON> <PERSON> Carter </PERSON>. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> and <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> sparred long distance as their vice presidential running mates encountered turbulence on their own campaign rounds. Democrat <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> was booed repeatedly when he praised <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> before the Veterans of Foreign Wars meeting in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>. `` The simple truth is, Gov. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> is a veteran, a patriot and an advocate of American strength and steadiness,'' the <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> senator said. Republican vice presidential candidate <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> was greeted in <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mo. </LOCATION>, by competing groups of supporters and demonstrators and a few signs that read, `` War Wimp'' and `` <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>'s a Chicken.'' That was a reference to the furor over his <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> service at the height of the Vietnam War. The <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION> senator told reporters the public was `` getting a little sick'' of the controversy, and at a meeting later with farmers, he added, `` I wo n't take any questions'' about the subject. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> said he was qualified to assume the presidency `` if that situation arises.'' He added that at 41, he is nearly as old as <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> was when he won the White House. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> faced new questions on his resume, however. The -LRB- <LOCATION> Cleveland </LOCATION> -RRB- Plain Dealer reported in its Friday editions that <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> held an entry-level job in the <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION> attorney general's office for most of the time he claimed to be `` chief investigator'' for the office's Consumer Protection Division The candidates spoke as the debate over campaign debates continued in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Neuman </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> League </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Women </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Voters </ORGANIZATION>, said she was encouraged that aides to <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> would meet next week to begin negotiations on debates for the fall. Democratic chairman <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Kirk </PERSON> criticized <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> for indicating on Wednesday that he wanted to wait until at least Sept. 20 before meeting <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> in debate. `` ... He's not going to be able to refuse to debate,'' <PERSON> Kirk </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> leveled a sharp attack on the drug policies pursued by President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, and said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> had failed in his task as a leader in the administration war on drugs. He said the administration was `` actively in business with -LRB- <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> -RRB- General <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> while <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> was involved in drug activity. `` My friends, that's criminal. That's criminal,'' he said. `` Why after seven years of task forces and policy boards and grandiose claims have cocaine imports tripled, drug-related deaths doubled and heroin imports risen by 50 percent?'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> added in a speech in <LOCATION> Cleveland </LOCATION>. He said the `` drug cancer'' was undermining governments overseas and was the `` single greatest cause of violence in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> today.'' An upbeat <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said the campaign momentum belonged to him as he opened a four-day campaign swing through his adopted home state of <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>. He said the country needs `` proven, tested leadership'' in the White House. The vice president compared <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> to former President <PERSON> Carter </PERSON>, adding he did not want to return to the `` malaise'' that occurred `` the last time a governor came out of nowhere and became president of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>.'' <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> won the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> in 1976 campaigning as a former governor of <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION>. Standing in the late-summer heat in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Antonio </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> told a riverfront rally that he would revive the faltering oil industry, create a better climate for small business, fight against federal gun control and provide jobs for the state's large minority population. `` I want to help these minorities who have n't really had a shot at the starting line,'' he said. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> made no mention of <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> in his remarks, but said, `` Yes, I do,'' when asked if he thought the controversy was behind him. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, meanwhile, appeared to be softening his stance on the Strategic Defense Initiative. The <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> quoted <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> in its Friday editions as saying a decision on whether to deploy a full or partial Star Wars defense system must await more research into its capabilities and costs. `` I do n't think we yet know what the price tag will be,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said. `` If you went to a full deployment of a full strategic defense, it would be very expensive. What I want to do is to continue reserach at the levels of funding, essentially, that we have requested.'' <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> was wearing his VFW cap as he defended <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> before a hostile audience. `` The simple truth is this: Gov. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> is a veteran, a patriot and an advocate of American strength and steadiess,'' he said. `` He can be trusted as a defender of <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> security _ and as a champion of <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> values.'' But the <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> senator and World War bomber pilot was interrupted four times by booing, including once when he said that <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> had begun the much-heralded defense buildup. The booing appeared to be led by <ORGANIZATION> VFW </ORGANIZATION> members from <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION>, and at one point the organizations's national commander, <PERSON> Earl </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Stock </PERSON><PERSON> , </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, appealed for quiet. `` I had a tough assignment and I fulfilled it,'' <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> said. `` Obviously some of them did n't want to hear it.'' <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> campaigned through the <LOCATION> Midwest </LOCATION>, telling his audiences it was time to `` talk about the future'' and not his controversial past. Referring to questions about his Vietnam-era stint in the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> said the public is `` getting a little bit sick'' of that issue. `` I've answered questions for seven days now,'' he told reporters as he arrived in <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mo </LOCATION>. `` We're going to talk about the future. We're going to talk about jobs. We're going to talk about other issues that the American people are interested in.'' <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> said he was qualified to be elected to a job placing him first in line for the presidency. `` I am qualified if that situiation arises,'' the <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION> senator said. `` I'm very close to the same age as <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> was when he was elected.'' <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> was 43 in 1960 when he won the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and had been in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> for eight years, compared to 12 for <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880825-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-25-88 0059EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-TeacherPay     08-25 0674</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Teacher Pay,0690</SECOND>
<HEAD>Dade Teacher Salaries Bring Flood Of Applications</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By MICHAEL WARREN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MIAMI (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Dade </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>'s approval of a whopping 28 percent teacher salary increase and a larger role for teachers in school decision-making has brought a flood of applications from around the country, officials say. News of the new contract approved by the <LOCATION> Dade </LOCATION> school board last month has `` spread like wildfire,'' said <PERSON> Terence </PERSON> <PERSON> Garner </PERSON>, director of teacher recruitment in <LOCATION> Dade </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>. `` My desk is literally covered with messages from people calling and wanting applications or copies of the contract sent,'' said <PERSON> Garner </PERSON>. `` We have enough candidates so principals can look at five to eight people for every one position,'' <PERSON> Garner </PERSON> said. `` We promised the school board we're going to hire the cream of the crop and now we're getting it.'' Last-minute hiring is under way and is expected to continue even after classes begin Monday in the <LOCATION> Dade </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>'s system, which includes the city of <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION>. With about 255,000 students and more than 15,200 teachers, it's the nation's fourth-largest. There's also an avalanche of applications in <LOCATION> Rochester </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION>, where the city school district attracted national attention last fall with a contract that boosted salaries and gave teachers more responsibility. `` When we go to college recruiting fairs, we have lines of people waiting to talk to us,'' said <PERSON> Ed </PERSON> <PERSON> Delaney </PERSON>, director of teacher personnel for the district. The three-year contract in <LOCATION> Rochester </LOCATION> raised salaries an average 40 percent over three years and offered some teachers who accept difficult assignments and work longer hours the chance to make $ 70,000 a year by the third year of the contract. In <LOCATION> Dade </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, average teacher pay will rise to $ 33,066 the first year of the contract, 9 percent above last year's pay of $ 30,000. Veteran teachers with doctorates could earn up to $ 64,000 a year. By the third year of the contract, the average pay would rise to $ 39,646, 28 percent above last year's pay. The contract also calls for expanding teachers' say in school decision-making. Teachers, principals and union stewards will sit together on faculty councils and make shared decisions, and teacher committees will help design schools and hire principals. Teachers are expected to approve it overwhelmingly when they vote Thursday and Friday. Dade's $ 33,066 average salary will be the highest in the state, nearly $ 8,000 above <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>'s statewide average in 1987-88 and more than $ 5,000 above the 1987-88 national average of $ 28,031, as calculated by the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Education </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>. `` I think many other districts will have to follow what we've done in order to be competitive,'' <PERSON> Garner </PERSON> said `` Teacher salaries all over will have to continue to rise.'' But state school officials say it could be some time before districts elsewhere in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> follow <PERSON> Dade </PERSON>'s lead. `` I think <LOCATION> Dade </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> has unique characteristics. The cost of living is more in <LOCATION> Dade </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, the union-administration relationship is extremely strong and cooperative, the emphasis on local solutions is greater there than anywhere else,'' said <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Voss </PERSON>, spokesman for Education Commissioner <PERSON> Betty </PERSON> <PERSON> Castor </PERSON>. `` We probably have the best labor-management relationship in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>,'' said <PERSON> Annette </PERSON> <PERSON> Katz </PERSON>, spokeswoman for the <LOCATION> Dade </LOCATION> teachers' union. `` That happened over a number of years, and it happened because of trust.'' <PERSON> Katz </PERSON> said <PERSON> Dade </PERSON>'s contract could encourage frustrated teachers elsewhere in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> to flock to the <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> area, although other spokesmen say <PERSON> Dade </PERSON>'s real competition is other large urban districts nationwide, not other <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> districts. `` We're not trying to raid people, but yes, people are interested,'' <PERSON> Katz </PERSON> said. `` We have to recruit the best teachers we can find.'' <PERSON> Laurie </PERSON> <PERSON> Murray </PERSON>, executive vice president of the teachers union in <LOCATION> Duval </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, which includes the city of <LOCATION> Jacksonville </LOCATION>, agreed that things are better in <LOCATION> Dade </LOCATION>. `` We've made some of the same proposals that <PERSON> Dade </PERSON> has but there's been no interest at the administrative level in shared decision-making,'' she said. `` Teachers have only a minimal input in every area.'' Management's latest offer in <PERSON> Duval </PERSON> is for a 4 percent pay hike, she said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880825-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-25-88 0105EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lites     08-25 0415</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lites,0429</SECOND>
<HEAD>On The Light Side</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CARMEL, N.Y. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Sybil </PERSON> <PERSON> Ludington </PERSON> wo n't be beheaded after all _ but she might be scalped. Both suggestions might have appealed to the British troops who were bedeviled by the 16-year-old heroine of the Revolutionary War. But local officials who made the suggestions insist they mean <PERSON> Sybil </PERSON> no harm _ they just want to help her overcome an embarrassing problem. It seems that <PERSON> Sybil </PERSON> _ a statue of her, that is _ has begun to foam at the mouth. Last month, <LOCATION> Putnam </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> officials were nearly ready to remove the head of the statue to clean out the mold causing the foam. But Tuesday night, a committee of the <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Legislature </ORGANIZATION> heard an alternate remedy. By slicing a small hole in the statue's head, legislator <PERSON> Lynn </PERSON> <PERSON> Greenwood </PERSON> said, workers might be able to remove the growth. Ms. <PERSON> Greenwood </PERSON> said she opposed decapitation, preferring a `` scalp job, which will be done at a more reasonable cost and -LRB- be -RRB- less dramatic to the people who see her every day.'' The bronze statue on the shore of <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gleneida </LOCATION> depicts the 16-year-old girl riding a horse in 1777, when she dashed through the countryside warning colonists that British forces were burning nearby <LOCATION> Danbury </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Conn </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>BEATRICE, Neb. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 While they know the guest of honor wo n't attend, residents of this southeastern <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION> community are planning a celebration to mark the birth of the newest member of <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>'s royal family The birth of Princess <PERSON> Beatrice </PERSON>, pronounced BEE-a-tris, gives the community of nearly 13,000, pronounced Bee-AT-tris, a reason to display pride in the name they share. `` It's a unique opportunity,'' said <PERSON> Randy </PERSON> <PERSON> Baynes </PERSON>, a member of the <ORGANIZATION> Gage </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Visitors </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>. Plans call for a Sept. 1 baby shower at the <ORGANIZATION> Chamber </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> to honor the princess, born Aug. 8. She is the daughter of Prince <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> and his wife, <PERSON> Sarah </PERSON>, the <PERSON> Duke </PERSON> and Duchess of <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, and is fifth in line to the throne. `` We're planning on serving iced tea and cake, but maybe tea and crumpets might be more appropriate,'' said <PERSON> Diane </PERSON> <PERSON> Schwenke </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> Chamber </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION>. While residents will be able to drop off cards and gifts for her royal highness, the town's official presents will include a T-shirt, mug, honorary <PERSON> Beatrice </PERSON> citizenship papers, a <ORGANIZATION> Beatrice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Library </ORGANIZATION> card, a bib cross-stitched with her name, and a deed giving her one square inch of land at the Homestead National Monument near here, Mrs. <PERSON> Schwenke </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880825-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-25-88 0657EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--CowDeaths     08-25 0179</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Cow Deaths,0184</SECOND>
<HEAD>Cow Deaths Prompt Dumping Of 32,000 Gallons Of Milk</HEAD>
<DATELINE>DAVIE, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Officials have dumped more than 30,000 gallons of milk at a dairy farm following the recent deaths of more than 20 cows, possibly from something they ate, authorities said. The milk apparently was not contaminated but was dumped as a public health precaution until the cause of the cow deaths is determined, according to officials from the farm and the state agriculture department. `` I do not believe there is any contaminant or toxicant causing the cattle deaths,'' <PERSON> Jay </PERSON> <PERSON> Boosinger </PERSON>, director of the division of dairy industry for the <ORGANIZATION> Florida </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Consumer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION>, said Wednesday. `` But it's better to err on the side of public health and safety and recommend that they not market the milk.'' <PERSON> Boosinger </PERSON> said milk, water, and feed samples, as well as tissue samples from one of the cows that died during the past two weeks, were collected from the 967-acre Imagination Farms, which milks 1,100 cows. Test results were not expected until later this week.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880825-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-25-88 0207EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     08-25 0791</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0825</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names In The News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MINNEAPOLIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Rock star Prince ca n't be faulted for lack of hard work. <PERSON> Prince </PERSON> will barely be back from his European concert series next month when he will begin his first <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> tour in four years with a pair of concerts in his home state of <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Prince </PERSON>, who lives and records in suburban <LOCATION> Chanhassen </LOCATION>, is scheduled to play Sept. 14 and 15 at the Met Center in <LOCATION> Bloomington </LOCATION>. Then, he'll hit the road through at least Oct. 19, taking his 90-member entourage to suburban <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Cincinnati </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION>. More dates will be added, said <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Merlis </PERSON>, vice president of publicity for <ORGANIZATION> Warner </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bros. </ORGANIZATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Records </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>. And after concluding the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> tour, <PERSON> Prince </PERSON> might just jet off for a <LOCATION> Far </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> tour early next year, <PERSON> Merlis </PERSON>
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>HONOLULU (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 One day in <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION> is not <PERSON> Thaao </PERSON> <PERSON> Penghlis </PERSON>' idea of a vacation, but the actor is happy that television work is cutting into his holiday. <PERSON> Penghlis </PERSON>, who will play disguise and dialect expert <PERSON> Nicholas </PERSON> <PERSON> Black </PERSON> in the new `` Mission: Impossible'' television series this fall on <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, said <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION> has finally accepted him as more than a `` mysterious foreigner'' playing terrorists and dignitaries. `` I've never been in this extreme a role. I'll be playing so many characters, because this man is a master of disguise,'' <PERSON> Penghlis </PERSON> said Wednesday from the condominium where he spent a day relaxing before heading to <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION> for rehearsals, publicity work and four months of filming. Born in <LOCATION> Sydney </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION>, to Greek parents, <PERSON> Penghlis </PERSON> is best known as <PERSON> Victor </PERSON> <PERSON> Cassadine </PERSON> in the soap opera `` General Hospital'' and as Count <PERSON> Antony </PERSON> <PERSON> DiMera </PERSON> on `` Days of Our Lives.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW RICHMOND, Ohio (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Country singer <PERSON> Johnny </PERSON> <PERSON> Paycheck </PERSON>, who faces up to 9 -LCB- years in prison for his 1986 conviction in a barroom shooting, will perform this weekend in his native state. The bearded performer is to sing in this southwestern <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> town and in <LOCATION> Dayton </LOCATION> on Saturday, and then at a benefit concert Sunday near <LOCATION> Chillicothe </LOCATION>. Paycheck, 49, faces a prison sentence of 4 -LCB- to 9 -LCB- years for his conviction on charges he shot and wounded another bar patron, <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Wise </PERSON>, on Dec. 19, 1985, at a <LOCATION> Hillsboro </LOCATION> tavern. According to Wise, Paycheck apparently took offense when <PERSON> Wise </PERSON> offered him a meal of turtle soup and venison, to which Paycheck responded, `` I'm no country hick.'' Paycheck, best known for the 1978 hit `` Take This Job and Shove It,'' claimed self-defense in the shooting. He has been free on bond for two years while he appealed. But the 4th <ORGANIZATION> Ohio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appeals </ORGANIZATION> this week upheld his conviction. <LOCATION> Highland </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> Prosecutor <PERSON> Rocky </PERSON> <PERSON> Coss </PERSON> said the singer could start serving his prison term within three months.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>BATON ROUGE, La. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An attorney for <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> <PERSON> Rollins </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> entered innocent pleas on the actor's behalf to charges of cocaine possession, drunken driving and speeding. State Judge <PERSON> Freddie </PERSON> <PERSON> Pitcher </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> agreed to waive the presence of the 37-year-old actor and allowed attorney <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Boren </PERSON> to enter the pleas Wednesday. No trial date was set. <PERSON> Rollins </PERSON> was arrested in March while he was in <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION> filming the <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> television series `` In the Heat of the Night.'' A state trooper reported <PERSON> Rollins </PERSON> was driving more than 100 mph on Interstate 12, and police said they found two bags of a substance that turned out to be cocaine. <PERSON> Rollins </PERSON>, who lives in <LOCATION> Baltimore </LOCATION>, had leading roles in the films `` Ragtime'' and `` A Soldier's Story.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Lorimar </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Telepictures </ORGANIZATION> tried to characterize <PERSON> Valerie </PERSON> <PERSON> Harper </PERSON> as a greedy, insane star going through menopause, the actress' attorney says. <PERSON> Barry </PERSON> <PERSON> Langberg </PERSON> confronted <ORGANIZATION> Lorimar </ORGANIZATION> television president <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Salzman </PERSON> with the accusation during cross-examination Wednesday in <PERSON> Lorimar </PERSON>'s breach-of-contract lawsuit against Ms. <PERSON> Harper </PERSON> and her countersuit against the company. <PERSON> Salzman </PERSON> adamantly denied that the production company sought to paint such an image of the 48-year-old actress. `` You do n't agree with the fact that she was greedy?'' asked <PERSON> Langberg </PERSON>. `` I do n't agree,'' said <PERSON> Salzman </PERSON>. `` Do you agree with the fact that she was insane?'' asked the attorney. `` She said she was insane,'' he replied. <PERSON> Langberg </PERSON> then repeated the question and <PERSON> Salzman </PERSON> answered, `` I think at times ... she acted as if she was going insane.'' `` What about going through a change of life?'' asked <PERSON> Langberg </PERSON>. `` No,'' replied <PERSON> Salzman </PERSON>. But he acknowledged that he had written the words, `` Change of life'' at the top of a page of notes he took on negotiation meetings with Ms. <PERSON> Harper </PERSON> over her series, `` Valerie.'' <PERSON> Lorimar </PERSON> ultimately replaced Ms. <PERSON> Harper </PERSON> with <PERSON> Sandy </PERSON> <PERSON> Duncan </PERSON> and changed the name of the series to `` The <PERSON> Hogan </PERSON> Family.'' Ms. <PERSON> Harper </PERSON> says she was wrongfully fired. <PERSON> Lorimar </PERSON> says she broke her contract.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880825-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-25-88 0026EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-Deaths 1stLd-Writethru a0788 08-25 0259</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Deaths, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0788,0262</SECOND>
<NOTE>Eds: ADDS Frey; An AMs separate moved as a0630 on Stuckey.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Nat Stuckey</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NASHVILLE, Tenn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Nat </PERSON> <PERSON> Stuckey </PERSON>, who wrote and recorded the country hit `` Sweet Thang,'' died Wednesday of lung cancer. He was 54. <PERSON> Stuckey </PERSON> was a radio announcer for <ORGANIZATION> KWKH </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Shreveport </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> La. </LOCATION>, when he wrote his first No. 1 hit, `` Waitin' In Your Welfare Line,'' recorded by <PERSON> Buck </PERSON> <PERSON> Owens </PERSON>. He then began appearing on the `` <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION> Hayride'' country music show in <LOCATION> Shreveport </LOCATION> before moving to <LOCATION> Nashville </LOCATION> in 1968. <PERSON> Stuckey </PERSON> also wrote the `` Pop A Top,'' recorded by <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Ed </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>. `` Sweet Thang,'' recorded by <PERSON> Stuckey </PERSON> 20 years ago, also was a hit as a duet by <PERSON> Ernest </PERSON> <PERSON> Tubb </PERSON> and <PERSON> Loretta </PERSON> <PERSON> Lynn </PERSON>. He most recently had recorded commercial jingles.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>Leonard Frey</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Leonard </PERSON> <PERSON> Frey </PERSON>, who received an Oscar nomination as best supporting actor for the role of Motel the tailor in the 1971 movie version of `` Fiddler on the Roof,'' died Wednesday of AIDS at age 49. <PERSON> Frey </PERSON> made his <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> professional debut as Yellow Feather in the off-Broadway musical `` Little Mary Sunshine.'' His theatrical breakthrough came with his performance as <PERSON> Harold </PERSON> in <PERSON> Mart </PERSON> <PERSON> Crowley </PERSON>'s `` Boys in the Band. He later re-created the role for the 1970 film. <PERSON> Frey </PERSON> also played leading roles in `` The Time of Your Life,'' `` Twelfth Night'' and <PERSON> Athol </PERSON> <PERSON> Fugard </PERSON>'s `` People Are Living Here.'' He acted in several operas, including `` Die Fledermaus.'' <PERSON> Frey </PERSON>'s last appearance was in an episode of the television series `` Murder, She Wrote.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880825-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-25-88 0035EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-CommunistRanks     08-25 0268</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Communist Ranks,0276</SECOND>
<HEAD>Party Membership Declines For First Time In Two Decades</HEAD>
<DATELINE>STANFORD, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The number of people throughout the world who belong to the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> declined slightly from 1986 to 1987, according to the <ORGANIZATION> Hoover </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institution </ORGANIZATION>. Total membership decreased from 89.8 million in 1986 to 88.6 million the following year, the conservative think tank at <ORGANIZATION> Stanford </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> reported in its 1988 Yearbook on Communist Affairs. That compares with a 7.6 percent increase in party membership from 1985 to 1986, the yearbook reported. The publication also has recorded a leap of more than 70 percent in international Communist membership since the early 1970s, when the total was about 50 million. The small drop from 1986 to 1987 indicates that Communists around the world are fed up with the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, said yearbook editor <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Staar </PERSON>. `` -LRB- It -RRB- can be attributed to several factors. ... Most important is the openly admitted failure of the politico-economic system in the <ORGANIZATION> U.S.S.R. </ORGANIZATION>,'' he said. `` The system has failed. It no longer serves as a model, even for <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>,'' <ORGANIZATION> Staar </ORGANIZATION> added. Another factor is the increased exposure of young people living in Communist countries to `` the success of capitalist governments around the world,'' <ORGANIZATION> Staar </ORGANIZATION> said. But while there may be fewer Communists throughout the world, there are more in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, the party said. `` We have found a tremendous renewed interest in Marxism and the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> in the last year,'' said <PERSON> Kendra </PERSON> <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON>, chairwoman of the <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> Communist Party. `` Our own membership, while admittedly not very large, has climbed by about 250 members to about 1,000 people,'' she said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880825-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-25-88 0227EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Justice-Ethics     08-25 0601</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Justice-Ethics,600</SECOND>
<HEAD>Justice Department's Ethics Program Faulted</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOAN MOWER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Congressional investigators are faulting the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> for not routinely evaluating its ethics program or providing enough training on ethics. The <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Accounting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION>, in a report released Wednesday, also said the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> is the only federal agency that does not require many of its employees to file confidential financial disclosure forms. `` Other agencies have found such reports to be a necessary part of their ethics program,'' the <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION> said. High-ranking Justice employees, like those at other agencies, must submit public financial disclosure forms under the 1978 Ethics in Government Act. But every agency except Justice requires civil servants with significant duties and responsibilities to file the confidential forms listing assets, investments and a spouse's job. `` This deviation from the practice elsewhere in the government is based on <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION>'s view that there has been no legal authority to require confidential reports since January 1979 when the Ethics in Government Act of 1978 took effect,'' said the <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>' auditing arm Justice officials have said they will ask for the confidential forms when the Office of Government Ethics, which monitors the act, submits final regulations, possibly this fall. An official at the ethics office said Justice was the only agency that has balked at the confidential forms. `` We have recognized for years that they -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> officials -RRB- desperately need a confidential system,'' said the official, who spoke on condition of anonymity. `` They are the main law enforcement branch; they should have it.'' The <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION> said the overall Justice ethics program `` contains many of the basic elements required by law and regulations. ... However, certain required elements are missing.'' Ethics programs are handled by the various divisions of the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>. Allegations of ethical misconduct are reported to the <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Professional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Responsibility </ORGANIZATION>, which reports to the attorney general. As a result of the decentralization, procedures on how to implement ethics programs differ at the department. `` For example, some components' procedures for reviewing public financial disclosure reports were more comprehensive than others,'' the report said. Moreover, <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> `` has not periodically evaluated the ethics program and not all of the Justice components have provided formal ethics training.'' Without proper evaluation, department officials are unable to determine if various divisions are `` properly reviewing and certifying public financial disclosure reports,'' the <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION> said. The report suggests periodic evaluations of the department's ethics programs, and a new program to train Justice employees in ethics and standards of conduct matters, including post-employment The report was released as Attorney General <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON> assumes command of the department with a promise to review the department's operations thoroughly. <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON> succeeded <PERSON> Edwin </PERSON> <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>, whose ethical conduct is still under review by the department's Office of Professional Responsibility. The report was requested last December by Reps. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Ford </PERSON>, D-Mich., and <PERSON> Gerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Sikorski </PERSON>, D-Minn. <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> is chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Civil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> Sikorski </PERSON> chairs a subcommittee on human <PERSON> Sikorski </PERSON> said at the time that his panel observed that <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> `` has failed to maintain an effective system of preventing ethics violations by <ORGANIZATION> DOJ </ORGANIZATION> -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> -RRB- employees.'' He cited questions about <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>'s stock holdings in seven regional telephone companies, and a June 1987 letter by <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>'s wife <PERSON> Ursula </PERSON> to a federal judge in <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> requesting leniency for a family friend who was awaiting sentencing <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>'s activities were investigated by independent counsel <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> McKay </PERSON>, who concluded that <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> probably broke tax and conflict-of-interest regulations, but said there was not enough information to prosecute. <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> said <PERSON> McKay </PERSON>'s report vindicated him.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880825-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-25-88 0232EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--France-Parking     08-25 0151</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--France-Parking,0155</SECOND>
<HEAD>25 Paris Workers Arrested in Parking Meter Theft</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PARIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Police arrested 25 city parking authority workers in breaking up a ring that bilked <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> out of up to $ 3.1 million in parking meter receipts over two years, authorities said. Police said Wednesday they discovered nearly two tons of one-franc and two-franc coins, worth about 15 and 30 <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> cents, hidden in a house in the <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> region on Tuesday. The arrests were made Tuesday and Wednesday, and more may come later, authorities said. <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> has had pay parking since 1971. The individual meters, however, have been phased out and replaced by about 6,000 coin-operated machines that provide timed cards which drivers display inside the windshield of their vehicles. Policemen then ticket violators. Police did not say how the money collectors managed to skim off coins from the machines without drawing the attention of the city's accountants
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880825-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-25-88 0235EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-EPA-Dumps     08-25 0664</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-EPA-Dumps,660</SECOND>
<HEAD>EPA Calls For Strict Dumpsite Regulations to Protect Groundwater
Supplies</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID GOELLER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The long arm of the <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> is reaching out to the local town dump _ and the huge metropolitan landfill as well. <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION>, in its first major effort to regulate the land disposal of household trash and garbage, is proposing rules that officials say would force nearly every municipal dump to take steps to protect the environment. Announced Wednesday, the plan would require all of the nation's municipal solid waste landfills to install often-expensive monitoring equipment to detect pollution of groundwater supplies The proposal, not expected to be popular with local governments, would require the cleaning up of dumps found to be leaking contaminants into underground aquifers. The draft regulations would force operators to put waterproof covers over dumps when they are closed and would set restrictions on where a new dump can be located. Many dumps that open after the rules take effect, probably not before 1991, would have to install bottom liners to prevent leakage and have systems to collect the polluting liquids found in dumps. `` It's a very strong protective rule,'' said <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Winston </PERSON> <PERSON> Porter </PERSON>, assistant <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> administrator for solid waste and emergency response. `` In some cases, people are going to have to spend a lot of -LRB- compliance -RRB- money.'' The plan would leave many compliance details up to states, so long as a dump did not impose any greater danger to humans than a 1-in-10 ,000 chance of contracting cancer from water contaminated by a dump's leachate <PERSON> Porter </PERSON> told a news conference that states would have flexibility to operate their own compliance programs with an underlying proviso: `` We do n't care what you do, but you can not leak.'' The proposal would apply to an estimated 6,000 solid waste landfills _ 78 percent of them owned by local governments _ that handle about 80 percent of the 160 million tons of household refuse produced each year, he said. At least one of every four municipal dumps is believed to be violating one or more state groundwater-protection standards, he said. <PERSON> Porter </PERSON> said the dangers posed by municipal dumps can be seen in the `` Superfund'' priority cleanup list, where nearly one of every five facilities awaiting decontamination was once a municipal solid waste landfill. Around the nation, less than a third of the operating dumps have groundwater monitoring systems, only 15 percent have bottom liners and only 5 percent have leachate collection systems, according to <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION>. `` Almost all landfills will have to do something,'' <PERSON> Porter </PERSON> said. `` There are very few landfills that meet all these requirements.'' He said he could not estimate precisely how much cost would be added to the nation's annual $ 4 billion to $ 5 billion bill for dumping, burning and recycling its trash and garbage. One EPA control scenario estimated the extra cost could reach $ 800 million a year, or about $ 11 per household. `` It will add something to the homeowner's bill,'' <PERSON> Porter </PERSON> said. `` We do n't think it will be dramatic.'' He said he expects positive reaction from states because they will have flexibility to structure their dump-control programs to meet particular hydrogeologic and topographical conditions. `` I think we'll get two other reactions: local governments will say this is too expensive and environmental groups will say it is n't strong enough,'' <PERSON> Porter </PERSON> said. He said the higher dump operating costs under the proposed rules could nudge local governments to make greater efforts to recycle trash, a move that could aid <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION>'s national goal of recycling 25 percent of all household refuse. <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> expects to take a year to obtain public comment on the proposal before making it final, <PERSON> Porter </PERSON> said. Dumps would then have 18 more months before they had to comply with the requirements. He said some dumps might close to evade the proposed rules, a move he acknowledged would leave them without leakproof covers unless they are in one of the handful of states that now require them.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880825-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-25-88 0236EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FarmScene     08-25 0422</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Farm Scene,420</SECOND>
<HEAD>Poultry Production Up Worldwide</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DON KENDALL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Farm Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 World output of poultry meat is up 3 percent this year and is expected to gain further in 1989, according to the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>. A survey of 51 major producing countries by the department's <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agricultural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> released Wednesday showed 1988 poultry meat production at 30.12 million metric tons, up from 29.21 million last year The forecast for 1989 is for 31.09 million tons. The <ORGANIZATION> European </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Community </ORGANIZATION> and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> account for most of this year's increase, while <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION> will be a major contributor in 1989, the report said. Six countries in addition to the 12-nation EEC account for 23.1 million tons of this year's poultry meat total and 23.8 million tons of the 1989 forecast. Looking at the 1989 forecast, the report showed <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> production at 9.79 million tons; <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION>, 2 million; <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>, 700,000; <ORGANIZATION> EEC </ORGANIZATION>, 6.01 million; <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>, 500,000; <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, 3.3 million; and <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, 1.5 million. Other countries, not listed, are expected to account for 7.29 million tons of the 1989 forecast of 31.09 million tons. World egg production is expected to be up 1 percent this year, with the largest increase in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. Production is expected to grow more slowly in 1989, the report said. In a related report, the department said <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> egg production in July dropped 2 percent from a year earlier to 5.68 billion eggs. The total number of laying hens declined to 268 million birds, down 3 percent from July 1987. However, July production per hen was up, averaging 2,118 eggs per 100 birds, compared with 2,097 a year earlier.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> says commercial flower growers will have a new, genetically engineered dwarf version of the long-stemmed lisianthus next spring. <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Lawson </PERSON> of the department's <ORGANIZATION> Agricultural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> said Wednesday the deep-purple lisianthus may be the first commercial flower developed through biotechnology research. The dwarf lisianthus will be sold as a potted plant, rather than seed, and will be available in April 1989, he said. It will be made available by the <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Florists </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Lawson </PERSON>, who heads up a new floral crops program funded jointly by <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> and the floral society, said the new plant bears several tulip-sized blooms at once, is a 6 - to 10-inch mutation of a 2-foot-tall lisianthus that is popular in many parts of the world as a cut flower Wild lisianthus grows throughout the American prairie region, he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880825-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-25-88 0240EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-SeatBelts     08-25 0579</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Seat Belts,570</SECOND>
<HEAD>Lawyer Says NHTSA Seat Belt Probe Is `Back Burner' Maneuver</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TIM BOVEE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Federal regulators hope to put on `` the back burner'' claims that some <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Motor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> seat belts can cause crippling injuries, an attorney representing a paraplegic child's family alleges The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Highway </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Traffic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> opened an investigation Wednesday into 1.7 million Ford Escort and Mercury Lynx cars to determine if the rear seat belts are safe. The agency turned down a request by the child's family that the cars be recalled immediately. `` Everything I know tells me that study on top of study means finesse,'' said <PERSON> Harold </PERSON> <PERSON> Sakayan </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> attorney for the family of <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Garrett </PERSON>, who was crippled at age 11 in the 1985 crash of a Ford Escort. `` It puts it on the back burner for awhile.'' He accused the agency of seeking to placate congressional critics while deferring action on the issue until after the next president is inaugurated. <PERSON> Garrett </PERSON> in January filed a petition for recall of the 1984-1988 cars on behalf of the child's parents, <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> and <PERSON> Patricia </PERSON> <PERSON> Garrett </PERSON> of <LOCATION> La </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Plata </LOCATION>, Md. The couple alleged a strap retainer caused the seat belt to ride around their child's waist rather than the hips. When the car in which they were riding smashed head-on into a tractor-trailer, the seat belt cut through the soft tissue to their son's spine, they said. The Garretts in January won a $ 3.3 million judgment against <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> for their child's injuries. <ORGANIZATION> NHTSA </ORGANIZATION> said in a letter to the <ORGANIZATION> Garretts </ORGANIZATION>' attorneys that a limited technical review had left the agency `` unable to conclude that the strap retainer has had an adverse effect on the performance of the system.'' The agency said the Lynx and Escort seat belts met federal safety standards, but added, `` Testing did indicate that the ... rear safety belts with and without the strap retainer fit differently on test subjects compared to rear safety belts in some other cars.'' The agency ordered a mid-level investigation, an engineering analysis, to probe the safety effects of the belts' fit. <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> said it believes the belts are safe. `` They meet or exceed all federal motor vehicle safety standard performance requirements, including those for location, fit, strength and ease of use,'' <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> said. `` We are confident that the agency, too, will conclude that no safety-related defect is involved,'' <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> said. In the 1985 accident, near <LOCATION> Annapolis </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Md. </LOCATION>, a second back-seat passenger, 14-year-old <PERSON> Christopher </PERSON> <PERSON> Gaboury </PERSON>, was killed. The two front-seat occupants were hospitalized after the accident but escaped crippling injury, even though the passenger compartment crumpled in the collision. The accident and subsequent lawsuit prompted public questioning of the safety of rear-seat safety belts, particularly those with the unusual design found in the Escort and <ORGANIZATION> Lynx </ORGANIZATION>. Belts that ride against the hips are braced on a large mass of bone in an accident, keeping the passenger anchored while avoiding damage to the spine. Belts that ride above the hip under the impact of a crash can slice through the body's soft tissue to the spine, resulting in paralysis or death. <ORGANIZATION> NHTSA </ORGANIZATION> said its strong recommendation that seat belts be used remains unchanged. `` Whether it be at the front or the rear, ... you are far better off wearing any kind of belt than no belt at all, and that is based on studies of hundreds of thousands of accidents and fatalities and injuries,'' said <PERSON> Ron </PERSON> <PERSON> DeFore </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> NHTSA </ORGANIZATION> spokesman.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880825-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-25-88 0243EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-CryingPlants Bjt   08-25 0478</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Crying Plants, Bjt,480</SECOND>
<HEAD>Plants `Crying' Out for Water</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DON KENDALL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Farm Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 This summer's drought has caused plants literally to `` cry'' out for water as they wither, and scientists are trying to determine if their sounds _ too highly pitched for the human ear _ are attracting destructive insects. Department researchers have been using electronic gadgets for more than four years to hear corn and other drought-stressed plants make noises as cell structures, or water tubes, break down from a lack of water traveling from roots to the leaves. When there is adequate water in the soil, the water and nutrients flow upward in the tubes under tension. If the soil lacks enough water, the tension becomes too great and the tubes fracture. One potential benefit from this kind of research would be new ways of letting irrigation farmers know precisely when to water their fields. Also it could aid in developing new plant varieties, which would be better equipped to move water and nutrients from roots to leaves. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Haack </PERSON>, an entomologist at the department's North Central Forest Experiment Station, <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lansing </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mich. </LOCATION>, and a colleague, <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Mattson </PERSON>, think there might be a connection between the noises and flocking of some insects, such as bark beetles, to drought-damaged trees. The noises are called ultrasonic acoustic emissions, and are in the 100-kilohertz range, while sound heard by humans is no more than about 20 kilohertz. While the ultrasonic emissions have been documented, their role in attracting insects remains only an educated guess. <PERSON> Haack </PERSON>, the research leader, said in a telephone interview Wednesday from his East Lansing office, that he thought it was `` a neat idea'' that the noises of stricken trees might attract insects. `` We're just starting up'' on the tree-insect project, he said. `` We do n't have enough to make any speculation on what we might find.'' <PERSON> Haack </PERSON> said insects have been known for a long time to be attracted by certain influences such as color and scent. But <PERSON> Haack </PERSON> said that to the best of his knowledge there has not been conclusive work linking the ultrasound of trees to insect behavior. The project only got under way three weeks ago, he said. A lot of time has been spent rounding up necessary equipment, part of it borrowed from other laboratories near <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION> State University, where the <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> operation is located. `` It could turn out that these sounds do attract insects,'' <PERSON> Haack </PERSON> said. `` Or it might not ... or it might be a combination of things.'' In any case, <PERSON> Haack </PERSON> is starting by depriving potted white pine seedlings of water and recording their ultrasounds. The next step will be to see if the recorded sounds attract beetles. Eventually, <PERSON> Haack </PERSON> hopes to see what role the tree sounds play in the choice of sites for beetles to mate and lay eggs.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880825-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-25-88 0245EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Reagan     08-25 0461</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Reagan,460</SECOND>
<HEAD>Reagan Says Quayle Experienced on Military Issues</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By SUSANNE M. SCHAFER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> came to the defense of <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> vice presidential candidate <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> by claiming that the junior senator from <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION> has more experience on military issues than Democrat <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, appearing Wednesday at a rally with Vice President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, offered his lengthiest comments to date about <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> since the vice president tapped the 41-year-old last week as his running mate. Since the announcement was made, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> have been dogged by questions about the conservative senator's use of family connections to help him join the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> and avoid the draft when many young Americans were being sent into combat in the Vietnam War. Although <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> made no mention of the flap, he opened his remarks by praising <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and adding, `` I like your running mate, too. `` He has had many more years of experience dealing with national security affairs than the head of the other ticket,'' <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said. The president lauded <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>'s work on a major job training bill without mentioning that Sen. <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, D-Mass., co-sponsored the measure `` <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> stands for the same principles as <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and I do,'' the president said. `` And he has the most important qualification of all for a co-pilot _ he wo n't be trying to turn the plane in one direction while the pilot is flying it in the other.'' <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> argued that <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> is well-prepared for the presidency after eight years in the co-pilot's seat. `` I once said that he is a great vice president, but I know and I've seen that it did n't come easily. <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> is a man of action _ a man accustomed to command,'' <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said. The president offered no examples of duties he'd handed the vice president, but said that `` day in, day out, I've sought <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s counsel.'' <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, as he has in several campaign appearances here amidst his annual August vacation in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, poked fun at the Democratic ticket, calling it `` a three-headed ticket that does n't know left from center. The president has often referred to the Democrats as running a triumvirate for the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, attempting to paint <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> as an unseen but powerful force in the campaign of <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> and his running mate Sen. <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Texas </LOCATION>. The president, who is scheduled to undergo a battery of annual eye, ear, nose and throat exams during his week-long stay in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>, has no public events until Saturday, when he is scheduled to take part in two fund-raisers for the <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> GOP and Rep. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Lagomarsino </PERSON>, R-Calif. Afterwards, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and his wife, <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON>, are to return to their <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Barbara </LOCATION> ranch until after Labor Day.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880825-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-25-88 0246EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-BeatsTicket     08-25 0201</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Beats Ticket,0206</SECOND>
<HEAD>Man Beats Traffic Ticket After Two-year Fight</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BIRMINGHAM, Ala. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Patrick </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kelly </PERSON> spent hundreds of dollars to beat a traffic ticket for running a red light, but said he is glad to have his name cleared, even if it took 2 -LCB- years and 11 court appearances. The 35-year-old house painter said his battle cost him more than $ 2,000, of which he expects to get back only $ 171.50 from the city in repayment of the fine and court costs. A <ORGANIZATION> Jefferson </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Circuit </ORGANIZATION> jury Tuesday acquitted <PERSON> Kelley </PERSON> after less than 10 minutes deliberations. `` I almost broke into tears,'' he said. `` I guess it shows truth will prevail. The system does work, if you fight it long enough.'' <PERSON> Kelley </PERSON>, who received the citation in March 1986, was convicted in Municipal Court two months later. He appealed, saying the citation contained several errors, including identifying him as black rather than white. On Tuesday, Judge <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> McCormick </PERSON> offered to dismiss that case, but <PERSON> Kelley </PERSON> said he wanted his name cleared by a jury. Officer A.W. <PERSON> Ellis </PERSON> testified the mistakes he made on the citation probably occurred when carbon paper in his ticket book accidentally transferred information from another ticket.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880825-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-25-88 0246EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-TreasuryAuction     08-25 0099</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Treasury Auction,90</SECOND>
<HEAD>Yields on Five-Year Notes Hit 9.04 Percent</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Yields on five-year <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> notes rose in the latest auction to the highest level since late 1985. The average yield Wednesday was 9.04 percent, up from 8.77 percent at the last auction on May 26. It was the highest rate since five-year notes averaged 9.13 percent on Nov. 27, 1985. The notes will carry a coupon interest rate of 9 percent, with each $ 10,000 in face value selling for $ 9,975.90. A total of $ 7.27 billion in notes was sold out of bids totaling $ 21.57 billion.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880825-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-25-88 0247EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-PresidentialDebates     08-25 0464</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Presidential Debates,460</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush Campaign Gives No Definite Date For Debate</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DONALD M. ROTHBERG</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Political Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Rival presidential candidates <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> are saying they want to debate this fall but sound far from agreement on when or where or how often they will meet. `` Vice President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> will debate his opponent this fall,'' said a brief statement Wednesday from the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> campaign. But the announcement also said it was `` unlikely that a debate can occur prior to Sept. 20.'' That brought an outraged reaction from <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> campaign chairman <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Brountas </PERSON>, who accused the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> campaign of `` seeking to unilaterally reject'' debates scheduled for Sept. 8 in <LOCATION> Birmingham </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ala. </LOCATION>, and Sept. 14, in <LOCATION> Annapolis </LOCATION>, Md. <PERSON> Brountas </PERSON> said the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> campaign decision not to accept the earlier dates `` threatens the full schedule of debates anticipated for the fall. It is a transparent effort to limit the number of debates.'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, during a stop in <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION>, said flatly, `` I'm going to be in <LOCATION> Annapolis </LOCATION> on the 14th with or without him.'' The <LOCATION> Birmingham </LOCATION> debate is being sponsored by the League of Women Voters, the <LOCATION> Annapolis </LOCATION> forum by the bipartisan <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> on Presidential Debates. A <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> spokesman said that while the Republican presidential nominee had said long ago he would debate his Democratic opponent, he had never agreed to any specific events. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> campaign chairman <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON> is expected to meet with <PERSON> Brountas </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> next week to negotiate the debate format. The campaign statement said they would discuss `` sponsorship, timing, ground rules and other related matters.'' The announcement said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> aides were confident `` the two campaigns would be able to work out the details of the debate schedule between themselves.'' It also said the campaign `` thanked the groups and organizations which had offered to help expedite the process.'' <PERSON> Brountas </PERSON> retorted: `` Mr. <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> stated that the campaign is not prepared for a debate prior to Sept. 20. This is inexcusable. The presidential commission debates have been scheduled for over a year and the vice president has known he would be his party's nominee for more than five months. ... `` The <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> people have a right to the full schedule of these debates as agreed upon by the two national political parties.'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> added during a campaign stop in <LOCATION> Cleveland </LOCATION>: `` After seven years of on-the-job training, it seems to me that he ought to be able to go to work and debate the issues. ... The vice president has been saying a lot about defense and national security, and I'm ready to debate him. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> campaign spokesman <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Goodin </PERSON> said: `` There were never any commitments made on specifics of a debate schedule. We've been very specific in saying the vice president wants to debate Governor <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880825-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-25-88 0249EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-AFL-CIO-Dukakis     08-25 0745</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AFL-CIO-Dukakis,720</SECOND>
<HEAD>AFL-CIO Hopes to Deliver Huge Margin of Union Votes to Dukakis</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MATT YANCEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Labor Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> AFL-CIO </ORGANIZATION> is gearing up a drive to deliver Democrat <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> a margin of at least 2 -LCB- million votes among its 14 million members on Election Day. Presidents of 87 of the labor federation's 91 affiliated unions gave the <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> governor an unqualified endorsement Wednesday. Union political operatives said the first step in their campaign for <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> is to make sure that 85 percent to 90 percent of union members and other voters in their families are registered, compared with 72 percent of the voting age population as a whole in the last presidential election. `` You need about six weeks in most states to have an effective drive,'' said <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Perkins </PERSON>, the labor federation's political director. <PERSON> Perkins </PERSON> will head the effort using computers at <ORGANIZATION> AFL-CIO </ORGANIZATION> headquarters here. The next step will use computers to track individual members' concerns on various issues, with letters sent to them on <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' position on those The aim is to obtain at least 65 percent to 70 percent turnout Nov. 8. <ORGANIZATION> AFL-CIO </ORGANIZATION> President <PERSON> Lane </PERSON> <PERSON> Kirkland </PERSON> estimated the federation's endorsement of <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> Mondale </PERSON> in 1984 was worth a net 2 million votes despite exit polls showing that as many as 47 percent of voters from union households cast their ballots for President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> `` Our rule of thumb is that we have to do two-thirds or better in order to be successful in the election,'' <PERSON> Kirkland </PERSON> said. `` We fell short of that. I'm reasonably confident that the results this time will be improved.'' <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Steel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Workers </ORGANIZATION> President <PERSON> Lynn </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> said winning passage of a law requiring employers to give 60 days advance notice of plant closings and layoffs has renewed labor's confidence going into the campaign's final 11 weeks. `` In the primaries, we had our members running -LRB- as potential delegates to national conventions -RRB- on behalf of every <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> candidate, but we have a very united position now in the <ORGANIZATION> Steel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Workers </ORGANIZATION>, and my sense is it's that way across the labor movement,'' <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Owen </PERSON> <PERSON> Bieber </PERSON>, the president of the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Auto </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Workers </ORGANIZATION>, said a poll of his members by the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Arbitration </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> showed a 96.9 percent level of support for <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>. `` And that was before <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>,'' <PERSON> Bieber </PERSON> said, referring to the <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION> senator tapped last week as the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> vice presidential nominee and the controversy since then on his use of family connections to help him avoid the Vietnam War draft. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> led the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration's opposition on <LOCATION> Capitol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION> to the plant closing notices law and has one of the lowest pro-labor voting records _ 9 percent _ in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>. Labor leaders acknowledged that an overwhelming majority of their rank-and-file probably are unaware of <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>'s role in defeating union-sought labor legislation over the past seven years. One of their missions between now and Election Day, they said, is to educate their members on <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>'s votes. `` At this point I just hope he's not forced off the ticket,'' <PERSON> Rachelle </PERSON> <PERSON> Horowitz </PERSON>, political director for the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Teachers </ORGANIZATION>, said of <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>. `` I want him out there campaigning.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> campaign spokesman <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Goodin </PERSON> called the <ORGANIZATION> AFL-CIO </ORGANIZATION>'s endorsement of <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> `` a classic dog bites man story. `` Every four years the <ORGANIZATION> AFL-CIO </ORGANIZATION> trots out what has become an obligatory endorsement of a Democratic presidential candidate and 1988 is obviously no exception,'' <PERSON> Goodin </PERSON> said. Among those unions abstaining in Wednesday's endorsement was the largest, the 1.6 million-member Teamsters, which endorsed <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> in 1980 and 1984 after making no presidential endorsement in 1976. Newly installed Teamster President <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> McCarthy </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>, who according to union sources dislikes <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, said he is withholding an endorsement until a mail poll of his members is completed Sept. 16. Asked if the Teamsters might endorse <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, a union official said, `` I just do n't see it.'' `` If the poll comes back strong for <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, we'll probably endorse him,'' said the Teamster official, who spoke on condition of anonymity. `` If it's close, we'll probably remain neutral.'' The 30,000-member <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Line </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pilots </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> said it was delaying an endorsement until after its convention next month. The 40,000-member <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Engineers </ORGANIZATION> union also voted to abstain, reaffirming its decades-old policy of making no presidential endorsements. The Newspaper Guild qualified its endorsement, voting 4,000 of its 25,390 members as abstaining primarily because of opposition by its 1,000-member <ORGANIZATION> Wire </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guild </ORGANIZATION> local to taking sides in the election.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880825-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-25-88 0249EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-US-SovietGrain     08-25 0314</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-US-Soviet Grain,310</SECOND>
<HEAD>US, Soviets Agree to Extend Grain Deal</HEAD>
<BYLINE>BY BARRY SCHWEID</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Diplomatic Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
