<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880405-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-05-88 2334EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-AfghanElection 1stLd-Writethru a0899 04-05 0577</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Afghan Election, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0899,0591</SECOND>
<HEAD>Report Thousands of Afghans Participate in General Elections</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Subs 4th graf bgng: It said photographs... with 4 grafs
report of rebels shooting at some polling places and turnout. Pick
up 5th pvs: One fourth ...</NOTE>
<DATELINE>ISLAMABAD, Pakistan (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Tens of thousands of Afghans went to the polls Tuesday on the first day of general elections that will be held over 10 days, <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>'s official <ORGANIZATION> Radio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Kabul </ORGANIZATION> reported. They are the first general elections in <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> since pro-Soviet military officers seized power ten years ago. Radio <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION>, monitored in <LOCATION> Islamabad </LOCATION>, said President <PERSON> Najib </PERSON> and other <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> officials cast their ballots in the elections for the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION>. In its first reports, <ORGANIZATION> Radio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Kabul </ORGANIZATION> said voters participated with `` enthusiasm and happiness'' and Tuesday's balloting ended in an orderly manner. But in later broadcasts monitored by the <ORGANIZATION> British </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Broadcasting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp </ORGANIZATION>, the government station in <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION>, the Afghan capital, said rebels fired at some polling stations in four provinces and other areas. The night broadcast said `` in some provinces the elections are taking place in difficult conditions.'' It did not say if there were any casualties. It reported that 147,300 people out of the 955,000 registered voters cast their ballots Tuesday. The broadcast also said there were as many as eight candidates for some legislative seats, and 70 per cent of the candidates were independents. One fourth of the 62 seats in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> and 229 in the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION> are set aside for representatives of anti-communist rebel groups, even if they do not participate. In a message to the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Najib </PERSON> said the elections were `` universal, secret, direct and democratic.'' `` The Republic of <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> invites a delegation of the <ORGANIZATION> Human </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rights </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> the </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> to visit the Republic of <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> in order to see the process of elections,'' his message said. In a separate message to the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> High Commissioner for Refugees, <PERSON> Najib </PERSON> said Afghans and Afghan political forces inside and outside the country were welcome to participate in the elections. About 5 million Afghans have fled the war and live in refugee camps in neighboring <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>, where rebel groups also have headquarters. <PERSON> Najib </PERSON> said if the return of the refugees is delayed, `` We are also ready to keep a necessary number of seats in both houses of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION> until their final return.'' The elections are being held while U.N.-sponsored peace talks are under way in <LOCATION> Switzerland </LOCATION>. The key issue in those negotiations is the withdrawal of an estimated 115,000 Soviet military personnel from <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>. Marxist military officers seized power in an April 1978 coup and Soviet forces intervened in December 1979 to help the government battle the anti-communist guerrillas. In <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION>, negotiators representing <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> completed five weeks of talks on an Afghan peace settlement. `` There is a constructive atmosphere. I am hopeful that we can in fact succeed shortly,'' said <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Peck </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> diplomat who consults regularly with <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> mediator <PERSON> Diego </PERSON> <PERSON> Cordovez </PERSON>. A diplomatic source who spoke on condition of anonymity said <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>'s ambassador to the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Shahid </PERSON> <PERSON> Amin </PERSON>, held talks with Soviet Deputy Foreign Minister <PERSON> Yuli </PERSON> <PERSON> Vorontsov </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Vorontsov </PERSON>'s portfolio includes the Afghan conflict. The Soviets have announced they plan to withdraw their troops from <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> wants the Soviets to either cut off aid to the Afghan government or allow <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> to continue supporting the insurgents.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880405-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-05-88 2359EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Hijack 6thLd-Writethru   04-05 0990</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Hijack, 6th Ld-Writethru,a0893,1021</SECOND>
<HEAD>Jet Hijackers Demand Release of Pro-Iranian Prisoners</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: INSERTS 2 grafs after 5th graf pvs, ``The Kuwaiti ... with
details on women freed; picks up 6th graf pvs, ``After an ...</NOTE>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto LON3, LaserGraphic NY19</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MONA ZIADE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NICOSIA, Cyprus (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Arab hijackers Tuesday forced a <ORGANIZATION> Kuwait </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airways </ORGANIZATION> jumbo jet to land in northeastern <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>, threatened to blow it up and demanded that <LOCATION> Kuwait </LOCATION> release 17 pro-Iranian prisoners. They later released 25 of the 112 people on board. <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'s official <ORGANIZATION> Islamic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> said without elaboration that the 24 women were released early Wednesday after negotiations with <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'s deputy prime minister, <PERSON> Ali </PERSON> <PERSON> Reza </PERSON> <PERSON> Moayyeri </PERSON>. A man in poor health was freed Tuesday. Among the other passengers were three members of <LOCATION> Kuwait </LOCATION>'s royal family and a passenger with a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> passport, on a flight from <LOCATION> Bangkok </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Kuwait </LOCATION>. The gunmen warned the Kuwaiti royals would be `` in imminent danger'' if <LOCATION> Kuwait </LOCATION> refused to free the prisoners, <ORGANIZATION> IRNA </ORGANIZATION> reported. The hijackers, brandishing pistols and hand grenades, identified themselves only as Arabs. But their demands echoed those of Iranian-backed Shiite Moslems holding American hostages in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>. The Kuwaiti government rejected the hijackers' demand to release 17 prisoners, calling it `` blackmail,'' but said it would listen to other demands, the <ORGANIZATION> Kuwait </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> reported. <ORGANIZATION> IRNA </ORGANIZATION> said the 24 freed women included five stewardesses, and identified them as 10 Britons, three Thais, three Egyptians, a Philippine citizen, a Palestinian, a Singaporean, an Irishwoman, a German, an Austrian, a Syrian and a Pakistani. The agency said the women were driven to a hotel in <LOCATION> Mashhad </LOCATION> after being questioned by security officers at the airport. After an emergency session, <LOCATION> Kuwait </LOCATION>'s government said it will send a three-man delegation on Wednesday morning `` to help Iranian authorities'' secure the passengers' release. <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> asked <LOCATION> Kuwait </LOCATION> to send a high-ranking delegation to <LOCATION> Mashhad </LOCATION> in northeastern <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> for direct talks with the hijackers. The hijackers earlier demanded fuel for the aircraft and threatened to blow it up if the Iranians approached. <ORGANIZATION> IRNA </ORGANIZATION> initially said the Iranians refueled the plane, but then said the gunmen were still requesting fuel. Iranian security forces surrounded the plane at <LOCATION> Mashhad </LOCATION> airport to keep it from taking off, <ORGANIZATION> IRNA </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Tehran </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Radio </ORGANIZATION> said. <LOCATION> Kuwait </LOCATION> urged <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> to handle the incident `` wisely'' and requested that the aircraft not be allowed to leave. <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> said it would try to resolve the crisis peacefully but said the plane would have to leave if it was not resolved quickly. The plane was commandeered three hours after it took off from <LOCATION> Bangkok </LOCATION> with 97 passengers and 15 crew members. <ORGANIZATION> IRNA </ORGANIZATION> reported that the hijackers told the control tower at <LOCATION> Mashhad </LOCATION> airport: `` We ask you Iranian officials to mediate between us and the <LOCATION> Kuwaiti </LOCATION> government if you want. `` Our rights have been usurped ... We have 17 prisoners in <LOCATION> Kuwaiti </LOCATION> jails who are under the worst kind of torture ... `` If you do not want to mediate, we ask for fuel and other needs and then we will take off.'' <ORGANIZATION> IRNA </ORGANIZATION>, monitored in <LOCATION> Nicosia </LOCATION>, said a <LOCATION> Jordanian </LOCATION> passenger with a heart condition was freed several hours after the plane landed at <LOCATION> Mashhad </LOCATION> at 7:30 a.m. -LRB- midnight EDT -RRB-. The passenger, businessman <PERSON> Mustafa </PERSON> <PERSON> Issa </PERSON>, 42, later appeared on <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION> television, also monitored in <LOCATION> Cyprus </LOCATION>, and said five or six hijackers were demanding to fly on to an undetermined location. The passenger list included 30 Kuwaitis, 22 Britons, eight Thais, various other nationalities and one person with a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and an Egyptian passport identified only as <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Attiaallaali </PERSON>. But the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> said it believed no Americans were aboard. In <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, spokeswoman <PERSON> Phyllis </PERSON> <PERSON> Oakley </PERSON> said the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government urged <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> to see that the hijackers are caught and tried. Airline sources, speaking on condition of anonymity, said the pilot was an <LOCATION> Iraqi </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Elias </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shiber </PERSON>, the airline's manager in <LOCATION> Bangkok </LOCATION>, said the three members of <LOCATION> Kuwait </LOCATION>'s ruling family aboard were <PERSON> Ibtesam </PERSON> <PERSON> Khaled </PERSON> <PERSON> Al-Sabah </PERSON>, <PERSON> Fadil </PERSON> <PERSON> Khaled </PERSON> <PERSON> Al-Sabah </PERSON> and the wife of <PERSON> Khaled </PERSON> <PERSON> Anwar </PERSON> <PERSON> Al-Sabah </PERSON>. Hundreds of Kuwaitis are related to <LOCATION> Kuwait </LOCATION>'s emir, <PERSON> Sheik </PERSON> <PERSON> Jaber </PERSON> <PERSON> Al-Ahmed </PERSON> <PERSON> Al-Sabah </PERSON>, the target of an assassination attempt by pro-Iranian extremists in 1986. <PERSON> Frances </PERSON> <PERSON> Watson </PERSON>, the wife of British passenger <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Watson </PERSON>, said she was waiting by the phone for more news about her husband, an engineering teacher from <LOCATION> Guisborough </LOCATION> in northern <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> who was returning from <LOCATION> Bangkok </LOCATION>. `` He is a very calm and cool-headed person and I am sure he will take it all in his stride,'' she said. `` But I am terrified of what could happen to him.'' The 17 prisoners demanded by the hijackers were jailed in the 1983 bombings that targeted <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and French embassies in <LOCATION> Kuwait </LOCATION>. Shiites holding foreign hostages in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> also have demanded the prisoners' release. Nine Americans are among the 22 foreigners missing and believed kidnapped in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>. The overwhelming majority of <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'s population is Shiite. In the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arab </LOCATION> <LOCATION> states </LOCATION>, Sunni Moslems dominate the government. <LOCATION> Kuwait </LOCATION> is the closest Arab nation to <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>, which are locked in a 7 -LCB- - year-old war <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> often accuses <LOCATION> Kuwait </LOCATION> of actively aiding <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>'s military effort. The <ORGANIZATION> Kuwait </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> quoted a spokesman for the airline as saying contact was lost with the aircraft while it flew over <LOCATION> Muscat </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Oman </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> first denied the plane permission to land, but reversed its decision when the pilot said the jet was running out of fuel, <ORGANIZATION> IRNA </ORGANIZATION> said. Prime Minister <PERSON> Hussein </PERSON> <PERSON> Musavi </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> told <ORGANIZATION> Tehran </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Radio </ORGANIZATION> that hijackings were `` against humanitarian and Islamic principles and unacceptable as a political tactic.'' Diplomatic relations between <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Kuwait </LOCATION> have been strained since August when Iranians stormed the embassies of <LOCATION> Kuwait </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Saudi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arabia </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Kuwait </LOCATION> closed its embassy in <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION> and brought its diplomats home. Pro-Iranian gunmen hijacked a <ORGANIZATION> Kuwait </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airways </ORGANIZATION> jetliner to <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION> in December 1984 and demanded the release of pro-Iranian Kuwaiti prisoners. They killed two American passengers before Iranian commandos stormed the aircraft, ending the six-day ordeal.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880405-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-05-88 0546EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--BusJoyride     04-05 0171</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Bus Joyride,0175</SECOND>
<HEAD>Police Charge Man In Theft Of Greyhound Buses</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BOSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Venanda </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> is charged with stealing two buses, but he ca n't be accused of inattentiveness. En route to <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> on Saturday, <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>, 21, reportedly changed a flat tire on a Greyhound bus he allegedly stole from a <LOCATION> Springfield </LOCATION> station. After arriving, he pulled the bus into a maintenance area and dutifully filled out a form noting the bus did n't seem to be running well. And <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> was upset when police on Sunday seized a second bus he allegedly drove from the <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> garage to a home in <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Mattapan </LOCATION> section where he spent the night `` I was told he yelled at the cops, ` Hey, where are you going with my bus?''' <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Gravley </PERSON>, a spokesman for <ORGANIZATION> Greyhound </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bus </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lines </ORGANIZATION> at company headquarters in <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION>, said Monday. <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> resident, faces auto theft charges in connection with an elaborate ruse that officials say included a bus driver's uniform and a deep knowledge of Greyhound operations.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880405-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-05-88 0547EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--U.S.-SovietFestival     04-05 0170</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--U.S.-Soviet Festival,0174</SECOND>
<HEAD>U.S.-Soviet Music Festival Ends With Emotional Finale</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BOSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The chief organizer of the `` Making Music Together'' festival says plans are already under way for a repeat performance of the Soviet-American cultural exchange in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> next October. `` It's meant to be pretty much a mirror image of this one,'' said <PERSON> Sarah </PERSON> <PERSON> Caldwell </PERSON>, director of the <ORGANIZATION> Boston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Opera </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Company </ORGANIZATION>. `` It's meant to continue to expose us to both American and Soviet life. The three weeks of ballet, chamber music, ballads and poetry ended Saturday night. During the five-hour finale, almost all the Soviet performers who were still in <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> took part. At its end, <LOCATION> Bolshoi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ballet </LOCATION> prima ballerina <PERSON> Maya </PERSON> <PERSON> Plisetskaya </PERSON> released a white dove from the crowded stage. Tears rolled down <PERSON> Plisetskaya </PERSON>'s face as the Soviet and Anerican anthems played. The American audience cheered, many shouting `` spasebo,'' Russian for `` thank you,'' to the Soviet performers. The festival included 285 Soviet and American artists from the Bolshoi, the <ORGANIZATION> Opera </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Company </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Boston </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Boston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Symphony </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Orchestra </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880405-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-05-88 0106EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p AM-Dukakis 1stLd-Writethru a0664 04-05 0708</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Dukakis, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0664,680</SECOND>
<HEAD>Dukakis Criticizes Jackson, Gore</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDs: INSERTS grafs 3-6 with late appearance, arrival back in
Boston; edits 4th graf pvs for transition, pick up 5th graf pvs,
bgng: Polls indicate</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By DAVID ESPO</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MILWAUKEE (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> cautiously criticized <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s involvement in the Panamanian standoff and expressed irritation with Sen. <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> on Monday as he struggled to pull out a victory in the critical <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION> primary. In a long, final day of campaigning around the state, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> repeatedly likened himself to <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, who scored an important primary victory in <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION> in his 1960 presidential campaign. Campaigning before students in <LOCATION> Stevens </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Point </LOCATION>, in his last appearance of the night, he urged that those who support him try to round up a little last-minute help. `` When you go home tonight, make a few phone calls, get a hold of your neighbors. Believe me, your work will make the ... difference,'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> said. Arriving back in <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> Monday night, he was asked about his prospects in <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION>. `` We've worked hard. It looks good. But you never know until the votes come in,'' he said. Earlier, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> recalled <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>'s success in reversing a round of steel industry price hikes in 1962, and said he would summon <ORGANIZATION> Chrysler </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>. President <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Iacocca </PERSON> to the White House `` fast'' and demand that he drop plans to close a plant in <LOCATION> Kenosha </LOCATION> Polls indicate <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> are locked in a tight race in <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION>, just as they are running neck and neck nationally in the chase for national convention delegates. The <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> governor said it was a `` bad idea'' for his Democratic presidential rival to suggest taking on the role of mediator between the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration and Panamanian strongman <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>. But he softened his criticism when he said he thought <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> had acted out of good intentions, and again when he said he understood that <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> had issued a clarifying statement on the subject. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> said he had asked <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> to leave the country, not offered to mediate. Even so, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> said, `` I think it's a bad idea for a private citizen to try to inject himself'' into the situation. Asked about <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s much-heralded trip to <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION> in 1984 when he won the release of captured <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> flyer <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Goodman </PERSON>, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> replied, `` I think the principle is the same.'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> was less charitable toward <PERSON> Gore </PERSON>, who rays the governor has been `` absurdly timid'' in criticizing <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> for fear of offending black voters. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> cut off one reporter who began to ask about the subject, and said, `` Sen. <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> ought to start campainging for the presidency.'' He noted that he and <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> disagree on the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION>, proposals for an oil import fee and other subjects. Asked later if he thought <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> were serious about winning the party's nomination, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> said, `` I do n't know what he's serious about.'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> noted that <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> has n't won any contests outside the South except the <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION> caucuses. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' criticism of <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> came at a time when aides said the <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION> race appeared extremely tight. While a weekend poll in the <ORGANIZATION> Milwaukee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Journal </ORGANIZATION> gave <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> an eight-point lead over <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> governor and his aides portrayed Tuesday's primary as a much closer match-up. `` It's too close to call,'' said <PERSON> Will </PERSON> <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON>, deputy political director for the campaign. `` We'll take any kind of win we can get.'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> told reporters, `` I do n't have to win'' in <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION>. `` I just have to win a good plurality of delegates by June 9,'' the end of the primary season. <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION> is regarded as a critical test of <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' candidacy, following losses in earlier industrial state contests in <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION>. He and <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> are running neck and neck in the race for delegates to the Democratic National Convention, and many party leaders have expressed concern that <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, a black liberal contender with roots in the civil rights movement, would lead Democrats to a crushing defeat in the fall. Thus, a defeat in <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION> would seriously damage <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' chances for winning the nomination, and would almost certainly rekindle talk of a draft-Mario <PERSON> Cuomo </PERSON> movement in the two weeks remaining before the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> governor's home state primary on April 19
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880405-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-05-88 0123EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w Dole-Dirksen Bjt   04-05 0612</FIRST>
<SECOND>Dole-Dirksen, Bjt,620</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHINGTON WIRE: Bush Defeat Could Hand Dole New Platform</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LAWRENCE L. KNUTSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 If Vice President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> stumbles on his way to the White House this November, erstwhile rival <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> could wind up as the nation's top <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> spokesman. The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> minority leader under a Democratic administration could find himself playing the lead in a 1980s version of the 1960s Ev and <PERSON> Charlie </PERSON> <PERSON> Show </PERSON>. It might well be called the <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> and <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> show, with <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> being joined by <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Minority Leader <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Michel </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> to counter a <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> president's programs and present alternatives to them. The Ev of Ev and <PERSON> Charlie </PERSON> was <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Minority leader <PERSON> Everett </PERSON> <PERSON> McKinley </PERSON> <PERSON> Dirksen </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION>. Dirksen teamed with <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Minority Leader <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Halleck </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION> in a regular series of televised news conferences, <PERSON> Dirksen </PERSON> became the undisputed `` Mr. Republican'' of his era. <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>, crowded out of the 1988 Republican field by <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, has returned to his leadership position in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>, serving notice he intends to prod the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> into opening its arms to a wider constituency. Republicans should, <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> says, address issues of concern to the homeless and the poor and embrace programs to deal with narcotics, day care, education, long-term health care, Medicaid and <ORGANIZATION> Medicare </ORGANIZATION>. `` We must, above all, give more Americans a reason to come our way and at the same time strengthen the commitment of our staunchest supporters,'' <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> said last week. With a sense of humor that can be dark and biting, <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> will have his own distinct style and image if he emerges as national spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Dirksen </PERSON> was `` full of fun and thunder,'' said <ORGANIZATION> Dirksen </ORGANIZATION> biographer <PERSON> Neil </PERSON> <PERSON> McNeil </PERSON>. <PERSON> McNeil </PERSON>, in his 1970 `` Dirksen: Portrait of a Public Man,'' said the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> minority leader became a television superstar despite a complete lack of the veneer said to be essential to a politician in the age of television. `` His tousled hair, long his trademark, was an easily recognizable ensign,'' <PERSON> McNeil </PERSON> wrote. `` His deep-throated husky voice, his flamboyant manners and his often astonishing use of a rococo vocabulary all tickled the viewing millions.'' <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> cartoonist <PERSON> Herblock </PERSON> caricatured <PERSON> Dirksen </PERSON> as a melancholy clown, <PERSON> Halleck </PERSON> as a buffoon and straight man. <PERSON> Halleck </PERSON> resented the Ev and Charlie tag. He took his partisanship seriously. But <PERSON> Dirksen </PERSON> said he liked the name, said it reminded him of such other all-American duos as corned beef and cabbage and ham and eggs. Some Republicans said they thought the two stood in poor contrast to <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, the nation's new, youthful and handsome Democratic president. One complained about <PERSON> Dirksen </PERSON>'s `` fuzzy hair'' and <PERSON> Halleck </PERSON>'s `` big red nose. `` None of this troubled Dirksen,'' <PERSON> McNeil </PERSON> wrote, `` for even as the criticisms were being made, he and <PERSON> Halleck </PERSON> were getting television and press coverage to make the opposition's case against the <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> administration. In time, he sensed, the criticism would wane and he would be better off for the national notoriety he was now receiving.'' Dirksen and <PERSON> Halleck </PERSON> used the Ev and <PERSON> Charlie </PERSON> routine to showcase criticism of the Kennedy domestic program. `` It may be called the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Frontier </ORGANIZATION>, but the Kennedy program is the old New Deal taken out of an old warming oven,'' <PERSON> Dirksen </PERSON> said. He scored the administration for `` deficit spending, increased government controls, increases in the government payroll, more welfare statism and that inevitable price which we must pay the piper, more taxes.'' By mid 1962 the Ev and <PERSON> Charlie </PERSON> show was fully launched and obviously effective in stating the Republican case. The ridicule evaporated. No Republican leader since has had anything quite resembling his disheveled flair, rumpled charm and widespread appeal.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880405-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-05-88 0123EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lites     04-05 0557</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lites,0577</SECOND>
<HEAD>On the Light Side</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SAN DIEGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 In laid-back <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, a little levity has been a hallmark at PSA. But the commuter airline's new parent, <ORGANIZATION> USAir </ORGANIZATION>, is lowering the curtain on one PSA feature: stand-up routines by flight attendants. For example, on a recent flight from <ORGANIZATION> San </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Jose </ORGANIZATION> to <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> PSA </ORGANIZATION> flight attendant <PERSON> Marka </PERSON> <PERSON> McDougall </PERSON> went into her act as the engines revved up. `` Ladies and gentlemen,'' Ms. <PERSON> McDougall </PERSON> said, `` We'd like to welcome you aboard Flight 1733 on our way to <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION>.'' Following a panicky gasp in the cabin, Ms. <PERSON> McDougall </PERSON> added: `` Just kidding. I wanted to see if you were listening.'' Ms. <PERSON> McDougall </PERSON>, who says about 10 percent of her colleagues go for such laughs, was on a roll. `` If you are traveling with infants or small children, or anyone resembling a small child, place your mask on first, then assist the child _ providing they've been good,'' she said. `` And now, for those of you who have not been in a car since 1962, we're going to show you how to fasten your seat belts.'' But the managers of <LOCATION> Arlington </LOCATION>, Va.-based <ORGANIZATION> USAir </ORGANIZATION> are not amused, and this week is Ms. <PERSON> McDougall </PERSON>'s last as a kidder. <ORGANIZATION> USAir </ORGANIZATION> is completing a $ 385 million takeover of PSA. `` Our policy is that we discourage that sort of thing because the information is very serious and should be delivered in that vein,'' said <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Shipley </PERSON>, assistant vice president for public relations at <ORGANIZATION> USAir </ORGANIZATION>. PSA, which has smiles painted on the noses of its jets, believes that a light touch is helpful, said <PERSON> Sherry </PERSON> <PERSON> Hendry </PERSON>, division vice president for the airline's in-flight and dining services. `` As long as the safety announcements are done in the right manner, we think a sense of humor is appreciated at a time that is perceived to be a hassle,'' she said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Ben </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON>, those irrepressible <LOCATION> Vermont </LOCATION> ice cream makers, found out that it's easier to make Coffee Heath Bar Crunch than to make a <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> subway station shine. About a year ago, <PERSON> Ben </PERSON> <PERSON> Cohen </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Greenfield </PERSON>, whose <ORGANIZATION> Ben </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON>'s ice cream has become a favorite of the upscale ice cream set, proposed to spruce up and maintain a subway station on <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION>'s upscale <LOCATION> Upper </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Side </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Cohen </PERSON>, just down from <LOCATION> Vermont </LOCATION>, found the station `` really disgusting.'' Many New Yorkers would say it's better than most. <PERSON> Cohen </PERSON> and <PERSON> Greenfield </PERSON> offered to spend their <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> advertising budget for the year _ $ 200,000 to $ 250,000 _ cleaning, painting and maintaining the station. The Transit Authority said yes. The <ORGANIZATION> Transport </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Workers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION> said no because <PERSON> Cohen </PERSON> and <LOCATION> Greenfield </LOCATION> wanted to use some non-union workers on the project. Negotiations dragged on and <ORGANIZATION> Ben </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON> finally set a March 31 deadline. That passed too; the matter went before an independent arbitrator who is expected to rule soon. So on Monday, <ORGANIZATION> Ben </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON> set up an ice cream wagon and a van at a park across the street from the station, and began doling out free ice cream as a consolation prize for passengers emerging from the filthy subway stop. <PERSON> Cohen </PERSON> and <LOCATION> Greenfield </LOCATION> were there to promise that they'd keep trying to spruce it up. Nobody seemed to care about the station, though _ not while there was free ice cream to be had.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880405-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-05-88 0126EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Households     04-05 0654</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Households,640</SECOND>
<HEAD>Average U.S. Household Size Half Civil War Level</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RANDOLPH E. SCHMID</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 American households have shrunk to their smallest size ever, containing just half as many people as at the start of the Civil War. The <ORGANIZATION> Census </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> reports that the average household contained 2.64 people as of last July 1, continuing a long-term decline. By comparison, the 1860 census found an average household of 5.28 people. While the household size has declined, the number of households has continued to climb, topping 90 million for the first time in 1987, the bureau said Monday. Household size is shrinking because the number of households is increasing faster than the overall population. This is occurring, said bureau population expert <PERSON> Campbell </PERSON> <PERSON> Gibson </PERSON>, because of changes in the country's age structure. The many Americans born in the post-World War II baby boom are now in their 20s and 30s, when they are most likely to set up households on their own, he said. The number of households rose from 80.4 million in 1980 to 88.8 million in 1986 and is now past the 90 million mark. At the same time the average number of persons per household declined from 2.75 in 1985 to 2.65 in 1986 and now to 2.64, <PERSON> Gibson </PERSON> said. By comparison, the 1970 Census found the average household contained 3.14 people. In 1930 households averaged more than 4 people, and they averaged more than 5 in 1880. The nation's first census in 1790 found an average household size of 5.79 people. While the growing number of ever smaller households continues a trend, <PERSON> Gibson </PERSON> pointed out that household growth is n't outpacing population increases as fast as in the 1970s. The same age factors that are increasing households now also occurred then, <PERSON> Gibson </PERSON> said. But in addition, in the 1970s the proportion of households in each age group was also growing. That has not continued in the 1980s, he said. `` This could be occurring for a number of reasons,'' <PERSON> Gibson </PERSON> said. For example, in this decade more young people have chosen to remain home with their parents instead of setting up housekeeping on their own, as many had done in the 1970s. This could be caused by the increasing cost of housing, he said. Delays in marriage, while young people pursue careers and school, have also been widely reported as a factor, but <PERSON> Gibson </PERSON> cautioned that it is too simplistic to attribute all of the household changes to this. `` There's a whole bunch of things'' that affect the rates, he said. For example, the elderly tend to have high household rates because a fair number are widowed, resulting in many one-person households. Continued low birth rates in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> are also a factor. The presence of children increases household size, while populations with a larger share of adults tend to have smaller households. Asked what the future holds, <PERSON> Gibson </PERSON> said he expects to see households continue to lead population in growth rates over the next few years. `` But that should change at some point'' as the smaller `` baby bust'' generation born following the baby boom comes into the household formation ages. While the national trend was reflected in most parts of the nation, <PERSON> Gibson </PERSON> cited two states that differ. In <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION>, household growth rates were only slightly different from those for population, he said. In <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, the increasing number of Hispanic and Asian residents likely is the reason, <PERSON> Gibson </PERSON> said, since those groups tend to have more people per household. <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Gibson </PERSON> said, has larger households because it maintains higher fertility than other states, largely because of the influence of the Mormon religion. Households are defined as occupied housing units containing one or more people. The number of households is, on average, smaller than the number of families because the definition of a family requires at least two people, while there are many one-person households.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880405-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-05-88 0126EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-EggRoll     04-05 0186</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Egg Roll,200</SECOND>
<HEAD>23,000 Turn out for White House Easter Egg Roll</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto WX6</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Some 23,000 children and their parents turned the White House south lawn into a kiddie carnival, celebrating an Easter Egg Roll that has been a tradition for 110 years. The children were entertained by an Uncle <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> on stilts, by tiny actor <PERSON> Emmanuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON> of the `` Webster'' TV show, and by all sorts of cartoon characters from the comic strip `` Peanuts.'' Monday's crowd filled the White House's south grounds where normally helicopters deliver VIPs, bands march and presidents speak. Vice President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> brought his wife, three children and five of his 10 grandchildren. He seemed to have a good time autographing wooden Easter eggs. The rolling was only a small part of the festivities. It consisted of eight youngsters lining up and using wooden spoons to urge their respective eggs toward the finish line. The winners each got a brightly colored wooden egg. So did the losers. On the grounds also were hidden eggs autographed by hundreds of movie stars ranging from Ann-Margret to <PERSON> Efrem </PERSON> <PERSON> Zimbalist </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880405-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-05-88 0130EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-ScotusRdp     04-05 0679</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Scotus Rdp,650</SECOND>
<HEAD>Major Precedent Unlikely in Libel Case</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JAMES H. RUBIN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A record $ 3 million libel award against <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> that the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> has refused to disturb is not likely to have widespread impact on the news media, says an authority on libel law. <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> Kaufman </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Libel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Resource </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> said the case does not establish a significant precedent because the facts involved are unique. But <PERSON> Kaufman </PERSON> did say that the case, stemming from a broadcast on a CBS-owned television station in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>, changes the psychological landscape. `` This is the first libel award that has broken through the psychological $ 1 million barrier on appeal, the first that has been able to make it through the process intact,'' he said. <PERSON> Kaufman </PERSON>, whose organization is funded by the news media, expressed disappointment along with <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> officials that the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> on Monday left the libel judgment intact. News organizations had hoped the case could be used to mount a First Amendment attack against punitive damages in libel cases, <PERSON> Kaufman </PERSON> said. `` That opportunity has passed for the time being,'' he said. `` We're disappointed,'' said <PERSON> Doug </PERSON> <PERSON> Jacobs </PERSON>, associate general counsel for <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> `` We believed these issues were important enough for review.'' The case stems from a suit by <ORGANIZATION> Brown </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <ORGANIZATION> Williamson </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tobacco </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Louisville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ky. </LOCATION>, which makes Viceroy cigarettes. It accused CBS and <ORGANIZATION> WBBM-TV </ORGANIZATION> anchorman <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> Jacobson </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> of libeling it in a Nov. 11, 1981, broadcast. <PERSON> Jacobson </PERSON>, in a nightly feature called `` <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> Jacobson </PERSON>'s Perspective,'' said there was a Viceroy advertising strategy to attract young people to smoking by relating cigarettes `` to pot, wine, beer and sex. He said the idea was to present cigarette smoking as `` an initiation into the adult world ... as an illicit pleasure.'' A federal jury awarded the cigarette company $ 5 million. The 7th U.S. <ORGANIZATION> Circuit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appeals </ORGANIZATION> upheld $ 3 million of the award against <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> and $ 50,000 against <PERSON> Jacobson </PERSON>. The $ 3 million award _ plus some $ 400,000 in interest _ is about four times the largest previous damage judgment against a news organization upheld on appeal. Awards upheld on appeal average between $ 100,000 and $ 150,000. In the <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> case, the appeals court rejected arguments that the broadcast was intended as opinion and thus could not be libelous. The appeals court said the remarks about Viceroy were intended to be factual, even if the tone of the broadcast made it sound like something else. The appeals court also rejected <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>'s claim that the broadcast was truthful. There was insufficient evidence that the cigarette company actually adopted a strategy of attracting young smokers by relating cigarettes `` to pot, wine, beer and sex,'' the appeals court said. Finally, the appeals court ruled that <PERSON> Jacobson </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> acted with `` actual malice'' in broadcasting the commentary. For a public figure to win a libel suit, it must be shown there was actual malice _ that statements were made with knowledge they were false or with reckless disregard for the truth. The cigarette company was held to be a public figure. In other action, the court: _ Left intact rulings in a case from <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Louis </LOCATION> that public airports may not ban all demonstrations, soliciting and distribution of political and religious literature at their terminals _ Agreed to review rulings that limited <ORGANIZATION> Korean </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lines </ORGANIZATION>' financial liability for a 1983 disaster in which 269 people died _ the shooting down of a KAL passenger jet over Soviet _ Reinforced the right of hospitals to challenge federal regulations limiting the amount of money they are reimbursed for treating <ORGANIZATION> Medicare </ORGANIZATION> patients The unanimous court was led by Justice <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, writing his first opinion since joining the court Feb. 18. _ Rejected a challenge to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>'s rent-control law that limits yearly increases for affected apartments to 7.5 percent _ Agreed to decide whether <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>'s powerful <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Estimate </ORGANIZATION> _ the city's mayor, city council president and comptroller and the president of each of the city's five boroughs _ must be reapportioned to meet equal-voting standards
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880405-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-05-88 0128EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FarmScene     04-05 0953</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Farm Scene,950</SECOND>
<HEAD>Carriers Report Low Benefit Payout Per Premium</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DON KENDALL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Farm Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The providers of all-risk crop insurance last year paid out the lowest amount of benefits per premium dollar since a new program went into effect in 1981, according to the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Crop </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Insurers </ORGANIZATION>. Farmers carried $ 6.07 billion worth of `` multiple peril'' crop insurance in 1987 on a record 62 million acres of production. <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Eugene </PERSON> <PERSON> Gantz </PERSON>, executive vice president of the association, said Monday that farmers paid $ 274 million in 1987 premiums and received $ 335 million in loss payments for the year. Nationally, that meant for each $ 1 paid in premiums, farmers received $ 1.22 in indemnities. The multiple peril crop insurance program includes commercial companies that are reinsured against catastrophic loss by the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Crop </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Insurance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, an agency of the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> FCIC </ORGANIZATION> also handles insurance directly through master marketers, who account for about 20 percent of the total. Up to 30 percent of a farmer's all-risk insurance premium is subsidized by the <ORGANIZATION> FCIC </ORGANIZATION>. When the federal subsidies are included, the 1987 premiums totaled $ 365 million, compared with the benefits of $ 335 million. Thus, the 1987 loss ratio was 0.92, or 92 cents paid out for each $ 1 of premium. <PERSON> Gantz </PERSON> said that was the lowest ratio since the multiple peril crop insurance program began in 1981. Under the program, farmers can buy varying levels of coverage for a variety of crops to insure them against loss from floods, drought, insects and other natural causes. `` As we look forward to 1988, we hope for another good loss ratio performance,'' <PERSON> Gantz </PERSON> said. `` But we're concerned with dry conditions already cropping up in the West and <LOCATION> Midwest </LOCATION>.'' The deadline for farmers to sign up for 1988 crop insurance is April 15 in most areas of the country -LRB- it was March 31 in some of the early planting areas of the South -RRB-, he said. Farmers who produce spring-planted crops also should keep in mind that without crop insurance they are not eligible for <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> disaster assistance, such as low-interest loans from the <ORGANIZATION> Farmers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Home </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Gantz </PERSON> said. The 1987 coverage on 62 million acres of crops compared with 60.7 million acres in 1986 and 46.5 million acres when the program began in 1981. A low point was reached in 1983 when plantings were cut sharply by drought and government acreage programs. Only 31.3 million acres of crops were insured that year. However, the mix of crops and variations in kinds of coverage have resulted in wide variations of coverage value. Last year's $ 6.07 billion in coverage was down from more than $ 6.22 billion in 1986, for example, despite the record acreage And in 1985, coverage totaled nearly $ 7.17 billion on $ 59.1 million.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> has been given the go-ahead by the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> to buy an additional 1 million metric tons of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> wheat at subsidized prices. Acting Undersecretary <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> O. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kay </PERSON> said Monday that since April 1987, the subsidized sales of wheat to the Soviets have totaled more than 11.8 million tons under previously announced allocations of the department's Export Enhancement Program, or EEP. More than 7.6 million tons of the 11.8 million tons of subsidized wheat bought by the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> has gone to fill its commitment under the fifth and final year of a long-term grain agreement with the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. The pact, which expires Sept. 30, calls on <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> to buy at least 9 million tons of grain annually and specifies that the purchases include a minimum of 4 million tons each of wheat and corn. The Soviets have the option of buying the remaining 1 million tons as wheat, corn or soybeans, with every ton of beans counting as two tons of grain _ up to a maximum of 1 million tons of grain equivalent. If more than 12 million tons are wanted in a year, the Soviets are required to seek <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> approval. The Soviets have been given approval to exceed the 12 million tons in the final year. A metric ton is about 2,205 pounds and is equal to 36.7 bushels of wheat or soybeans. If <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> buys all of the new authorization, that would push wheat sales in the last year of the agreement to more than 8.6 million tons. All of the wheat has been subsidized. In addition, the Soviets have bought 4.1 million tons of non-subsidized corn; 818,400 tons of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> soybeans; and 1.3 million tons of soybean meal. Under <ORGANIZATION> EEP </ORGANIZATION>, private exporters are given surplus commodities owned by the department's <ORGANIZATION> Commodity </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Credit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> so they can sell a foreign buyer wheat or another authorized commodity at competitive world prices. The subsidies, or bonuses, have run between less than $ 20 to more than $ 40 per ton, roughly 54 cents to $ 1.09 per bushel.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 More of the <ORGANIZATION> Farmers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Home </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>'s rural development loans may be targeted to areas of high unemployment <ORGANIZATION> FmHA </ORGANIZATION> administrator <PERSON> Vance </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Clark </PERSON> said Monday a proposed rule change would direct a higher proportion of the agency's business and industrial loan guarantees to smaller companies where there is high unemployment. The `` B & amp; I'' program involves guarantees by FmHA on loans made by commercial lenders to provide jobs through new or expanded businesses in rural areas. Loan guarantees would range from 70 percent to 90 percent of the loan value, with the higher guarantee reserved for smaller loans. A spokesman, <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Neill </PERSON>, said <ORGANIZATION> B </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; I loan guarantees range up to $ 10 million per project. Those of up to $ 2 million would carry the 90 percent guarantee; $ 2 million to $ 5 million, 80 percent; and $ 5 million to $ 10 million, 70 percent, he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880405-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-05-88 0140EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FDA-AgingCreams     04-05 0461</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-FDA-Aging Creams,450</SECOND>
<HEAD>Cosmetics Firms Warned To Stop Making Anti-Aging Claims</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JERRY ESTILL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Food </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Drug </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> says it is time for cosmetic companies to stop talking and start changing labels that claim skin creams can retard or reverse aging of the skin. The federal agency wrote 22 companies on Monday that it will take another look at the labels in 30 days _ and then crack down on any that persist in misleading claims. `` We believe that <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> has clearly stated its views regarding the types of claims that can appropriately be made on cosmetic skin care products and the types of claims that make skin products unapproved new drugs,'' wrote <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON>, associate commissioner for regulatory affairs. `` Accordingly, we do not believe that a detailed review or a prolonged discussion regarding individual product labeling is necessary. We hope that you will make the changes in your labeling that are necessary to bring it into compliance with the act and with <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION>'s stated views.'' The Food, Drug and Cosmetic Act defines cosmetics, which can be sold without pre-approval by the <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION>, as products intended to cleanse or to beautify superficially. In written warnings to the cosmetic industry last year, the agency said that when a product is said to counteract, retard or control the aging process or to rejuvenate, repair or renew the skin, then those statements put the product in the drug category _ with all its stringent scientific review requirements. That is so, the letter said, because such claims indicate that a `` function of the body, or that the structure of the body, will be affected by the product.'' The <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> said then it was `` unaware of any substantial scientific evidence that demonstrates the safety and effectiveness'' of the so-called anti-aging skin care products. Implicit in the latest letter was the <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> view that talks started with the companies last spring intended to lead to voluntary changes in labeling claims have gone on long enough. Some companies have modified their labels since last spring, but the <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> said last November it could not accept the labeling claims continuing to appear on many products. The latest letter said the agency will examine the labeling and promotions of the creams in 30 days and that a product still in `` substantial violation'' may be subject to immediate regulatory action. This can include seizure of products on shelves and court injunctions against further distribution. The <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> action does not involve Retin-A, a prescription acne medication that was widely publicized recently after a study suggested it was effective in removing small wrinkles caused by sun damage to the skin. The <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> did not release the names of the companies that received the letter.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880405-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-05-88 0143EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Candidates-Labor     04-05 0696</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Candidates-Labor,680</SECOND>
<HEAD>Some Labor Favorites Not Holding Up Well In Presidential Race</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MATT YANCEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Labor Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 One by one, the favorite presidential candidates of some of the nation's union leaders are falling by the wayside. Eight days ago it was <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION> Rep. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON>, the personal choice of <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Auto </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Workers </ORGANIZATION> President <PERSON> Owen </PERSON> <PERSON> Bieber </PERSON>. <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> finished a distant third in <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION>'s caucuses and withdrew last Monday. Today, in <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION>'s primary, leaders of the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Steel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Workers </ORGANIZATION> union expect their preferred choice, <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> Sen. <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Simon </PERSON>, to be weeded from the Democratic field. `` Quite sadly, tomorrow is going to show <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> to be yesterday's tomatoes,'' <PERSON> Joel </PERSON> <PERSON> Vattendahl </PERSON>, director of <ORGANIZATION> USW </ORGANIZATION>'s 14,000-member District 32 headquartered in <LOCATION> Milwaukee </LOCATION>, said on the eve of the primary While the union was abiding by <ORGANIZATION> AFL-CIO </ORGANIZATION> guidelines to encourage their members to support any candidate of their choice, <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> had clearly become the choice by default of the <ORGANIZATION> USW </ORGANIZATION>'s leaders. The first choice of <ORGANIZATION> USW </ORGANIZATION> President <PERSON> Lynn </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> had been <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Mario </PERSON> <PERSON> Cuomo </PERSON>, whom he has served as an adviser on industrial policy. <PERSON> Vattendahl </PERSON> now believes that <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> will edge out <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> among the union's members in <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION>, who are mostly foundry workers, with <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> Sen. <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> also finishing ahead of <PERSON> Simon </PERSON>. `` I would have thought <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> would have caught on better; he's been with us for 30 years and we've been with him,'' <PERSON> Vattendahl </PERSON> said `` But it's not happening that way.'' Going into today's votes, <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> actually has more delegates to the Democratic National Convention in July among union members than any of the other candidates, all from his victory in the <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> primary March 15. The latest <ORGANIZATION> AFL-CIO </ORGANIZATION> tabulations show him with 20 elected labor delegates, followed by <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> with 15, <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> with 10, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> with six and <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> with two. The steelworkers were instrumental in persuading <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> to stay in the race through the <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> primary and had hoped he would do well enough in <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION> to remain a candidate through the April 26 primary in <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION>, where the union has its biggest political strength. But <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Hubbard </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> USW </ORGANIZATION> spokesman, said <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> have been on the phone with steelworkers union members around the country who had been supporting <PERSON> Simon </PERSON>, offering them delegate slots for their support. `` So far it's being resisted,'' he added. Leaders of <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION>'s biggest union, the 48,000 teachers who belong to the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Education </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, also believe <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> will edge out <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> among their members today. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, however, has endeared himself to <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION> union members facing the greatest strife: 5,500 workers at a <LOCATION> Kenosha </LOCATION> Chrysler plant to be closed next summer and striking meatpackers at <LOCATION> Cudahy </LOCATION> and paper workers at <LOCATION> DePere </LOCATION>. `` <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> visited us and <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> showed up at the <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Temple </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Green </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION>,'' said <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> Murphry </PERSON>, one of 370 mostly white Paper Workers on strike the past 10 months against <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Paper </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>'s De Pere mill. `` But they're just reading off the script <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> wrote,'' <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Rosenbaum </PERSON>, president of <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Food </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commercial </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Workers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Local </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> P-40 </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Cudahy </LOCATION>, which is striking the <ORGANIZATION> Smithfield </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foods </ORGANIZATION>' meatpacking plant, has made trips to <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> to raise campaign money on <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s behalf `` The picket line is white, the strikebreakers are black,'' said <PERSON> Allen </PERSON> <PERSON> Zack </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> UFCW </ORGANIZATION> spokesman. `` The company orchestrated letters to <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> from scabs saying that he was selling them out. And he replied: A scab is a scab. Our Cudahy people are big <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> fans.'' <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> also has won the endorsement of <ORGANIZATION> UAW </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Local </ORGANIZATION> 72 in <LOCATION> Kenosha </LOCATION>, which represents the <ORGANIZATION> Chrysler </ORGANIZATION> workers, after appearing with them in protest rallies in January when the company announced its intention to close the plant next summer. Both <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> and <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> in the past week have denounced <ORGANIZATION> Chrysler </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Iacocca </PERSON> in campaign appearances, but labor leaders view those actions as too little and too late. `` The problem is people who are striking or are in trouble are the ones who vote, and those who are working do n't,'' said <PERSON> Joan </PERSON> <PERSON> Baggett </PERSON>, political director for the bricklayers union and a <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> supporter. `` That raises a real question about us getting a November-electable candidate.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880405-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-05-88 0152EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Jackson-Polls     04-05 0754</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Jackson-Polls,720</SECOND>
<HEAD>Pollsters Say Wisconsin Crucial in Jackson's Effort</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GARY LANGER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s showing in today's <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION> primary will be a key measure of his emergence as a candidate who could have sufficient support to win the Democratic nomination and the presidency, pollsters say. As <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> has improved his ability to win votes, the poll analysts noted Monday, the expectations for his campaign have increased. If he has done well, they said, he now needs to do better still. `` It may be a constantly moving target,'' said <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> pollster <PERSON> Keating </PERSON> <PERSON> Holland </PERSON>. `` The frontier is moving. Twenty percent of the white Democratic vote and all the black vote is not going to win the election in November.'' <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> gained co-frontrunner status when he upset Gov. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> in the <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION> caucuses March 26. No polls were done there to indicate the demographics of <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s support. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> then beat <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION>'s primary, where <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> got about 20 percent of the white vote. In <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION>, a <ORGANIZATION> Milwaukee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Journal </ORGANIZATION> poll last week put <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s white backing at 30 percent. `` In this state certainly he's a viable candidate,'' said <PERSON> Jeff </PERSON> <PERSON> Browne </PERSON>, the Journal editor who ran the poll. Though it gave <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> a slim lead, he said, it probably understated <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s support by underestimating black turnout. Blacks have been the most reliable of <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s supporters throughout the primary season, voting for him with near-unanimity. At the same time, `` You have to have white voters to be a viable candidate,'' said <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Klett </PERSON>, poll analyst for <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION>. `` There are some white voters going his way. But it will have to be much larger before he could get the nomination.'' <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> primary April 19 are crucial to indicate that vote-getting ability, <PERSON> Klett </PERSON> said. `` What happens in <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION> is going to be pivotal in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>,'' she said. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, she suggested, `` has to win one of those states or both.'' `` I would n't put a number on it; it's the number of Democrats that are voting for him,'' <PERSON> Klett </PERSON> said. `` When he gets most of them voting for him, that's when he becomes viable.'' There are other measures as well. In <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION>, the Journal poll last week showed Vice President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> leading <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> in a hypothetical general election race by 50 percent to 36 percent. `` That strikes me as extremely close for <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> in this state, considering how well known <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> is and how well liked -LRB- President -RRB- <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> is,'' <PERSON> Browne </PERSON> said. He noted that <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> and Sen. <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> both fared even better in matchups against <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. Another issue in gauging <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s strength is in the nature of the white votes he is attracting. Exit polls in <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION> said he did best with liberals and lost the blue-collar vote _ critical in the general election _ by 2-1. An analysis of the <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION> caucus results also indicated that <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> was not particularly strong in blue-collar precincts, <PERSON> Holland </PERSON> said. Still another measure is the share of voters who have a favorable opinion of <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>. Although his rating has improved, the last national survey by <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION>, done March 19-22, said more white Democrats had an unfavorable opinion of him _ 39 percent _ than the 31 percent favorable. <PERSON> Holland </PERSON> said. Among all white voters it was 46 percent unfavorable to 22 percent favorable, he said. `` You say to yourself, very few white Republicans are going to vote for him. You then write off half the <ORGANIZATION> Democrats </ORGANIZATION> as well, and you're not looking at much of an electoral base,'' said <LOCATION> Holland </LOCATION>. `` You can see why people will be putting increasing hurdles in front of him.'' `` He is increasing his white vote,'' the <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> analyst said. `` If that's the case it may be acceptable to say, Let's see how far you can go with this. Can you reach the point where you can win in November? Twenty percent is not there. I would guess it's not 30 percent.'' I.A. <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON>, chief of polling for the <ORGANIZATION> Los </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Angeles </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION>, said he retained his view that <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> is able but unlikely to win the nomination and unable to win in November. He cited <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s liberal positions as well as `` an element of racism that exists in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> today. Nonetheless, ` There's already been a profound change. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> has been to a certain extent legitimized by his very impressive victories,'' said <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON>. In turn, he said, whatever the outcome, `` <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> is legitimizing blacks as legitimate presidential contenders.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880405-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-05-88 0157EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-MeeseProbe     04-05 0627</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Meese Probe,620</SECOND>
<HEAD>Mrs. Meese to Be Questioned About Own Job</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Meese-Replacements Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PETE YOST</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Attorney General <PERSON> Edwin </PERSON> <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>'s wife, <PERSON> Ursula </PERSON>, will undergo questioning shortly in the criminal investigation of her husband about her own $ 40,000-a-year job, say sources familiar with the case. The office of independent counsel <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> McKay </PERSON> is trying to determine whether longtime <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> friend <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Wallach </PERSON> in effect helped supplement the Meeses' income by recommending Mrs. <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> for jobs, said sources familiar with the probe, speaking on condition of anonymity. Mrs. <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> has retained the same <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> law firm representing her husband, said <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Rocap </PERSON>, one of <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>'s lawyers. She will either make a federal grand jury appearance or be questioned by investigators from <PERSON> McKay </PERSON>'s office. <PERSON> McKay </PERSON> said last week that his investigation of <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>, also encompassing an examination of the circumstances surrounding Mrs. <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>'s job, would continue at least until the end of April. <PERSON> McKay </PERSON> last month subpoenaed records relating to Mrs. <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>'s post with the <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> chapter of the <ORGANIZATION> Multiple </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sclerosis </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION>, said a lawyer for the chapter, <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Bierbower </PERSON> A lawyer for <PERSON> Wallach </PERSON>, <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Walker </PERSON>, has told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> that <PERSON> Wallach </PERSON> had suggested Mrs. <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> for a job with a local radio station owned by the <PERSON> Bender </PERSON> family of <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. Mrs. <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> took the position with the <ORGANIZATION> MS </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION> instead. However, <PERSON> Bierbower </PERSON> said the <ORGANIZATION> Bender </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, controlled by the same family that owns the radio station, is contributing the $ 40,000 a year that constitutes Mrs. <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>'s salary with the MS group Calls to the <ORGANIZATION> Bender </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION> seeking its reasons for paying Mrs. <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>'s salary were not returned. Mrs. <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> has been a volunteer for the <ORGANIZATION> MS </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION> since 1981 and for the past two years has been in charge of a program called Operation Job Match, matching MS victims with employers. Mrs. <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> also was questioned in an earlier independent counsel's investigation of <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> in 1984. In that investigation, independent counsel <PERSON> Jacob </PERSON> <PERSON> Stein </PERSON> probed <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>'s failure to include in his financial disclosure statements a $ 15,000 loan by <PERSON> Edwin </PERSON> <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> to Mrs. <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>. <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> later became <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>'s assistant counselor at the White House. The independent counsel found no connection between the loan and federal jobs obtained by <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON>, his wife and his son. In another development Monday, <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> sources said <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> will face an ethics investigation by his own department's Office of Professional Responsibility if <PERSON> McKay </PERSON> does n't seek an indictment Such an inquiry ultimately could lead to a recommendation to President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> that <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> be fired. Former Assistant Attorney General <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Weld </PERSON>'s files on the attorney general's dealings with <PERSON> Wallach </PERSON> were moved to <ORGANIZATION> OPR </ORGANIZATION> last Friday, the sources said. Material collected by <PERSON> Weld </PERSON>'s criminal division last year led to <PERSON> McKay </PERSON>'s criminal investigation of <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>. <PERSON> McKay </PERSON> said Friday he has insufficient evidence to date to warrant seeking an indictment of <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> in connection with his involvement with a $ 1 billion Iraqi oil pipeline touted by <PERSON> Wallach </PERSON> or his involvement with the regional <ORGANIZATION> Bell </ORGANIZATION> telephone companies at a time when he held $ 14,000 in <ORGANIZATION> Baby </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bell </ORGANIZATION> stock. In December, <PERSON> McKay </PERSON> said he did n't have sufficient evidence at that time to warrant seeking an indictment of <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> in connection with his assistance to scandal-plagued <ORGANIZATION> Wedtech </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> McKay </PERSON> said that if he decides not to seek a criminal indictment of <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>, the independent counsel's office `` will refer all of those matters for review and action by the appropriate administrative authorities,'' a reference to OPR <ORGANIZATION> OPR </ORGANIZATION>'s chief, <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Shaheen </PERSON>, denied assertions by <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> sources, speaking on condition of anonymity, that his office had begun examining <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>'s ties to longtime friend <PERSON> Wallach </PERSON> last year. That review was halted when <PERSON> McKay </PERSON> launched his criminal investigation of <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> last May 11, the sources said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880405-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-05-88 0201EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Jackson-Money     04-05 0514</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Jackson-Money,490</SECOND>
<HEAD>Jackson Brings In $2 Million Plus in March</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RITA BEAMISH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s once-impoverished presidential campaign is showing new fund-raising strength, collecting an impressive $ 2.2 million in donations during March _ more than he raised during all of last year. The sum, coming mostly in contributions of $ 50 or less, represents a dramatic upswing for what <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> frequently boasts is the `` poor campaign with the rich message.'' <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Farmer </PERSON>, finance chairman for the Democratic field's consistent fund-raising leader, <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, was laudatory when told Monday about <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s money `` That's a tremendous achievement for Rev. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>,'' he said. `` Anybody that can raise $ 2 million in a month is a hero to me.'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, the <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> governor, collected donations totaling more than $ 2.5 million during March, <PERSON> Farmer </PERSON> said. Sen. <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> raised about $ 1.5 million during March, his campaign said last week. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> has been picking up most of his money in small contributions through an aggressive direct-mail and telemarketing program. The program banked $ 1 million during March, said <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s mail consultant, <PERSON> Mal </PERSON> <PERSON> Warwick </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Berkeley </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif </LOCATION> He said the returns are the most impressive of any campaign he has ever conducted in 10 years of fund-raising. Farmer said <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> has gotten contributions averaging $ 135 each over the past 90 days. During all of 1987, <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> raised just under $ 2 million, while <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> raised $ 10.8 million. `` He has emerged as a significant player and that's reflected in his financial performance,'' <PERSON> Farmer </PERSON> said of <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>. `` You're beginning to see this as a two-man race and the fund raising is the first benchmark of success. He said <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> `` should be very proud'' of his mail returns. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> campaign spokeswoman <PERSON> Pam </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> said <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s March receipts surprised even campaign manager <PERSON> Gerald </PERSON> <PERSON> Austin </PERSON>, who had projected contributions of about $ 1 million. In all, <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> collected $ 3 million, including about $ 800,000 in federal matching funds. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> took in about $ 3.4 million, including $ 875,000 in federal matching funds. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s fund-raising boost is timely as the expensive <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> primary approaches on April 19. `` They're really banking for <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> said, noting that television ad time in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> is particularly expensive. By contrast, she said, the campaign spent a total of $ 100,000 on today's <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION> primary, with about half going to TV ads. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> generally relies on a grassroots network of volunteers, eliminating the large payroll common to more wealthy campaigns. <PERSON> Warwick </PERSON> said <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s mail returns `` have picked up since Super Tuesday,'' when <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> polled first in popular vote and second in delegates across 20 state primaries and caucuses on March 8. In addition to the direct mail campaign, <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> said <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> raised about $ 140,000 during a two-day fund-raising swing through <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, where national campaign chairman <PERSON> Willie </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> put on a series of fund-raising events. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> also collected about $ 120,000 at events in <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION> prior to the March 26 caucuses where he won a landslide victory. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> got about half his March donations from three days of big-ticket fund-raising events in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Farmer </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880405-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-05-88 0205EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-WISCONSINAt-A-Glance     04-05 0198</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-WISCONSIN At-A-Glance,160</SECOND>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
</TEXT>
<HEAD>DEMOCRATS</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Method: Primary Date: Tuesday, April 5 Pledged delegates: 81 Super delegates: 7 TOTAL: 88 Delegates allocated: Tuesday, April 5 Selection of delegates: Sunday, May 22 and Saturday, June 11 All of <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION>'s 81 pledged delegates to the Democratic National Convention will be allocated among presidential candidates in proportion to the results of the primary on April 5.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>REPUBLICANS</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Method: Primary Date: Tuesday, April 5 Delegates: 47 Delegates allocated: Tuesday, April 5 Selection of delegates: Dates not yet determined. All of <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION>'s delegates to the Republican National Convention will be allocated among presidential candidates based on the results of the primary. The presidential candidate receiving a plurality of votes in a congressional district will get all three of the national convention delegates from that district. The remaining 20 delegates at large will go to the presidential candidate receiving a plurality of the statewide vote. After the primary, the state committee will submit a list of national convention delegates for approval by the winning presidential candidates.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880405-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-05-88 0212EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Nofziger     04-05 0521</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nofziger,520</SECOND>
<HEAD>Nofziger Supporters Urge Leniency In Friday Sentencing</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JAMES ROWLEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Two Cabinet secretaries and the <ORGANIZATION> Secret </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> director have attested to <PERSON> Lyn </PERSON> <PERSON> Nofziger </PERSON>'s character in letters to the judge who will sentence the former presidential aide for illegal lobbying. Letters signed by <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Herrington </PERSON>, Labor Secretary <PERSON> Ann </PERSON> <PERSON> McLaughlin </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> Secret </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> Director <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Simpson </PERSON> are among 62 attached to a defense brief that urges a short term of unsupervised probation for <PERSON> Nofziger </PERSON>. In a three-page letter, <PERSON> Herrington </PERSON> urged <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Flannery </PERSON> to show `` compassion and understanding'' for <PERSON> Nofziger </PERSON>. `` Society has been paid by what he has gone through in this trial and the effect that it has had on him as an individual,'' <PERSON> Herrington </PERSON> said. Rep. <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-N.Y. </LOCATION>, one of four members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> who sent letters, urged <PERSON> Flannery </PERSON> to consider `` balancing the requirements of justice with the quality of mercy.'' <PERSON> Simpson </PERSON> wrote about <PERSON> Nofziger </PERSON>'s role as White House spokesman on March 30, 1981, after President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> had been shot and taken to <ORGANIZATION> George </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION>. `` Once Mr. <PERSON> Nofziger </PERSON> took the podium,'' <PERSON> Simpson </PERSON> recalled, he quickly became aware `` of the rapport and the trust the press had for any statements he made.'' <PERSON> Nofziger </PERSON>, 63, is scheduled to be sentenced Friday on three counts of illegally lobbying former <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> colleagues on behalf of <ORGANIZATION> Wedtech </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, the manufacturer of the A-10 anti-tank plane, and a maritime engineers union. He could receive a two-year prison term and a $ 10,000 fine for each of the three felony violations of the Ethics in Government Act. Last week, independent counsel <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> McKay </PERSON> urged a prison term of unspecified length and a fine, arguing that <PERSON> Nofziger </PERSON> flouted the law and was unrepentant following his conviction Feb. 11. <PERSON> Nofziger </PERSON> had likened his crime to `` running a stop sign.'' The defense brief that was filed Monday said imprisonment `` would unnecessarily add to the degradation and humiliation Mr. <PERSON> Nofziger </PERSON> has already suffered as a result of his indictment and trial.'' Accusing <PERSON> McKay </PERSON> of making a `` vindictive'' and `` mean-spirited'' sentencing request, defense lawyers <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Plotkin </PERSON> and <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> <PERSON> Barcella </PERSON> said `` it is inconceivable that a sentence other than probation is appropriate under these circumstances.'' Former Sen. <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Laxalt </PERSON>, R-Nev., said <PERSON> Nofziger </PERSON> `` has been deeply wounded and punished _ physically, emotionally and financially. Rep. <PERSON> Helen </PERSON> <PERSON> Delich </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentley </PERSON>, R-Md., called <PERSON> Nofziger </PERSON> `` a man of impeccable character and integrity'' who would `` never do anything which he understood to be morally wrong. Others who signed letters were Sen. Chic Hecht, R-Nev., Rep. <PERSON> Mervyn </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Dymally </PERSON>, D-Calif., and former <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Human </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Heckler </PERSON>, now <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> ambassador to <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION>; Former <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Treasurer <PERSON> Angela </PERSON> <PERSON> Buchanan </PERSON>; <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Rodgers </PERSON>, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> ambassador to <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>; and <PERSON> Carol </PERSON> <PERSON> Boyce </PERSON> <PERSON> Hallett </PERSON>, the ambassador to the The defense brief repeated a longstanding contention that <PERSON> Nofziger </PERSON> did n't intend to violate the post-employment lobbying restrictions, a point hotly disputed by <PERSON> McKay </PERSON>'s sentencing memo. <PERSON> Nofziger </PERSON> `` does not dispute the need for fair, clear and balanced post-employment restriction'' but, his lawyers contended, if the statute were clearer he `` likely would not be before the court for sentencing.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880405-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-05-88 0221EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w BC-JacksonLetter-Text     04-05 0348</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Jackson Letter-Text,320</SECOND>
<HEAD>With PM-Jackson and PM-US-Panama</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here is the text of <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s letter to Panamanian strongman <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>, dated March 23, 1988. It was released by the <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> campaign.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>Dear General Noriega:</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 On behalf of all those around the world who see and feel the agony of the Panamanian people, I am writing to appeal to you _ for all of us _ to pursue peace and to put an end to this crisis. The whole forest is being set afire to smoke you out, and the strategy is causing great suffering in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> _ a suffering seen around the world. The livelihood, health and safety of Panamanians are threatened. It is time to put these considerations in the proper perspective for the country's good. A judgment for a greater good must be made. A judgment for <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> and for the region must be made! By us working together for peace, we can help heal the sick, feed the hungry and put your country back together. I have been to <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> several times and have a great feeling, sensitivity and respect for the people of <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>. I agonize daily as I watch the suffering. I have talked with people in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> who now have desperation added to their destitution. I make this appeal reluctantly because I know the history of our country with your country has been a complex one. But suffice it to say that the <ORGANIZATION> Panama </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Canal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Treaty </ORGANIZATION> brought us closer together in harmony. I am appealing for us to relieve the people of the suffering and the bloodshed that may occur. I am anxious to do whatever I can to help alleviate the suffering, but we must act decisively and quickly. I appeal to you for us to find a way to end the crisis now. I am therefore asking <PERSON> Cirilo </PERSON> <PERSON> McSween </PERSON>, my dear friend who has accompanied me to your country on my visits, to see you immediately so that these dialogues surrounding this moral appeal may begin. Repectfully and in Peace, Reverend <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Louis </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880405-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-05-88 0224EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-InternationalPay     04-05 0455</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-International Pay,470</SECOND>
<HEAD>Mexico Cheapest, Norway Most Expensive In US Dollars</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CARL HARTMAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> had the lowest labor costs last year and <LOCATION> Norway </LOCATION> had the highest as measured in dollars, the <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> says. Average hourly costs in <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> went down to $ 1.37 from $ 1.49 in 1986, the department said in its report, released Monday. Though wages more than doubled in Mexican pesos, the exchange value of the peso dropped so far that the dollar cost declined. Brazilian workers saw their wages and benefits rise when measured in cruzados, but in dollar terms there was a decline to $ 1.49 from $ 1.60 an hour because of the low value of the domestic currency. <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> are the Third World's two biggest debtors, a situation that tends to drive down the price of their currencies. They were the only countries where the dollar cost of labor was reported to have dropped in the year. The figures take account of the fall in the price of the dollar, and of changes in local pay rates. The costs of social insurance and other benefits are also figured. But the figures do not consider whether some workers are more efficient than others. <LOCATION> Norway </LOCATION>'s average compensation of $ 17.58 an hour was nearly 13 times <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>'s dollar amount. The <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> average of $ 13.46 dollars was almost 10 times <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>'s. Low wage costs in other countries have long been used by politicians as the reason for protecting <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> industry from imports. Labor unions also have complained against `` exporting jobs,'' arguing that low labor costs in other countries encourage <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> employers to set up production there rather than at home. Labor in the newly-industrialized countries of <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Latin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> remained less than a fifth as costly as in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. Of 22 countries surveyed, seven had costs higher than the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> rate here. They were, in addition to <LOCATION> Norway </LOCATION>: <LOCATION> Switzerland </LOCATION>, $ 17.06; <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, $ 16.83; <LOCATION> Sweden </LOCATION>, $ 15.14; <LOCATION> Netherlands </LOCATION>, $ 15.11 dollars; <LOCATION> Belgium </LOCATION>, $ 15.08 and <LOCATION> Denmark </LOCATION> $ l4 .49 dolllars All 23 countries for which the <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> had statistics showed an increase of compensation in their own currency, including the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. `` <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s relative cost level in 1987 -LRB- of 84 percent of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> costs -RRB- greatly exceeded the previous peak of 72 percent reached in 1986,'' said the report from the <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Statistics </ORGANIZATION>. It noted that <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s level was now close to <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>'s. The increase was due largely to the rise of the yen against the dollar. The high value of the domestic currency against the dollar was also the reason for most of the rise in European costs, though they were also raised in <LOCATION> Norway </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Denmark </LOCATION> by cuts in working hours, the report said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880405-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-05-88 0226EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w BC-NoriegaLetter-Text     04-05 0856</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Noriega Letter-Text,800</SECOND>
<HEAD>With PM-Jackson and PM-US-Panama Rdp</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here is the text of Gen. <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>'s letter to <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, as released Monday by the <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> campaign. It was written in response to a March 23 letter from <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>. The text, as released by the campaign, contained several fragmentary sentences, misspellings, and other irregularities.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>Dear Reverend Jackson:</HEAD>
<TEXT>
