<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880727-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-27-88 0000EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-PhelanProfile     07-26 0489</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Phelan Profile,0506</SECOND>
<HEAD>Chicago Attorney Named to Investigate House Speaker</HEAD>
<HEAD>With AM-Wright-Ethics, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By F.N. D'ALESSIO</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CHICAGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> attorney <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Phelan </PERSON>, named Tuesday to investigate the ethical conduct of <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Speaker <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>, has raised money for Democratic Sen. <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> and was elected a delegate to the Democratic National Convention. But some of <PERSON> Phelan </PERSON>'s associates took issue with <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> claims that the <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> lawyer is a <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> activist who could n't impartially investigate <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>, also a Democrat. Although he was a delegate to the Democratic convention last week, <PERSON> Phelan </PERSON> decided not to go. <PERSON> Phelan </PERSON>, 51, was elected as a delegate pledged to the failed presidential bid of <PERSON> Simon </PERSON>, D-Ill., but resigned before the convention, said <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> spokeswoman <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> <PERSON> Stephan </PERSON> Ms. <PERSON> Stephan </PERSON> did not indicate why <PERSON> Phelan </PERSON>, who had served as a <ORGANIZATION> Simon </ORGANIZATION> fund-raiser, had resigned. <PERSON> Phelan </PERSON>'s selection Tuesday drew criticism from Citizens for <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, which sent a Mailgram message to the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Ethics committee saying, `` The appointment of liberal Democrat activist <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Phelan </PERSON> as outside counsel in the <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> case certainly calls into question the independence of the ethics committee inquiry.'' But <PERSON> Amy </PERSON> <PERSON> Zisook </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Simon </PERSON>'s national finance director, took issue with characterizing <PERSON> Phelan </PERSON> as an `` activist.'' `` I assume he's been active locally, but I've been involved in Democratic politics at the statewide level for six years and this year was the first time I ever met Mr. <PERSON> Phelan </PERSON>,'' Ms. <PERSON> Zisook </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Phelan </PERSON> is a 1958 graduate of the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Notre </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dame </ORGANIZATION>, and received his law degree from <ORGANIZATION> Georgetown </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> in 1961, the same year he was admitted to the <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> bar. He is the author of numerous articles on litigation and was president of the <ORGANIZATION> Chicago </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bar </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> in 1985-86. Last year, <PERSON> Phelan </PERSON> successfully defended <ORGANIZATION> Jewel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Companies </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, in a lawsuit in which attorneys sought $ 100 million in punitive damages for hundreds of people sickened in the nation's largest outbreak of salmonella. The outbreak in 1985 had been traced to milk from a Jewel dairy in suburban <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>. The company ended up compensating those who fell ill for their actual losses but not paying extra punitive damages. Attorneys at <PERSON> Phelan </PERSON>'s firm said the case was the largest personal injury product liability class action yet settled. <PERSON> Phelan </PERSON> also defended the city of <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> in a case brought by a black patrolmen's association which contended the police force had discriminated against black officers. <PERSON> Phelan </PERSON> and his wife, <PERSON> Carol </PERSON>, an architect, have three children. They live in a northern <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> suburb. <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Ethics <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Julian </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Dixon </PERSON>, D-Calif., said Democratic and <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> members of the evenly divided 12-member panel had agreed on <PERSON> Phelan </PERSON>'s selection Members of both parties were satisified that he could do an impartial job, <PERSON> Dixon </PERSON> said. The contract with <PERSON> Phelan </PERSON>'s <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> firm, <PERSON> Phelan </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Pope </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> John </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Ltd. </ORGANIZATION>, will be for no more than $ 300,000, he said. <PERSON> Dixon </PERSON> said he could not estimate how long the investigation would take.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880727-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-27-88 0007EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Korea-Strike 1stLd-Writethru a0776 07-27 0507</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Korea-Strike, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0776,0516</SECOND>
<HEAD>Police Arrest Locomotive Engineers in Move to Break Strike</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: LEADS throughout with train service partially restored as
some drivers end strike; edits to conform. No pickup. </NOTE>
<BYLINE>By C.W. LIM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SEOUL, South Korea (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Partial train service was restored Wednesday as striking locomotive drivers began returning to work after police arrested hundreds of strikers and supporters. Hundreds of locomotive drivers and assistants demanding higher pay and shorter hours walked off the job Tuesday after refusing to accept a compromise deal on allowances and working hours. The <ORGANIZATION> Korean </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Railroad </ORGANIZATION> said services were operating at about 30 percent of normal levels after being virtually crippled Tuesday. Railroad officials said they hoped to restore almost full service by Thursday as strikers returned to work. Surburban train service around <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION>, which was affected by the strike, was back to normal early Wednesday, railroad officials said. Police officials, who declined to be named, said 420 people were still being held Wednesday after about 1,460 striking drivers and members of their families were arrested the day before for blocking stations and other railroad facilities. The others had been released with reprimands, police said. Of the ramaining 420 still in custody, officials said about 20 were strike leaders facing charges of conducting an illegal strike. The others would probably be handed over to summary courts to face minor charges, they said. The government moved to crush the strike and thousands of riot police were sent to stations and railway yards to stop peaceful protests by the strikers and their families. The Cabinet held an emergency session Tuesday to oversee handling of the affair. Those arrested defied police orders to disperse, but there were no reports of violent clashes, police said. Railroad officials said strikers were returning to work, but they had no overall figures on how many of the some 4,400 drivers and assistants had joined the strike. They said they expect most strikers to resume work Wednesday. But reports in <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION> newspapers Wednesday said some strikers said they would not return to work until all strikers arrested by police had been freed. The officials said the strike cost the KNR an estimated $ 2.5 million Tuesday alone and that there was no estimate yet as to losses suffered by other industries. <PERSON> Choi </PERSON> <PERSON> Ki-duk </PERSON>, head of the railroad authority, said the strike was illegal because it had not been approved by the railroad union. Strikers said a compromise deal worked out by the union failed to satisfy demands for shorter work hours and a 100 percent raise in allowances paid on top of normal salaries. Under the rejected deal, the railroad would raise allowances from about $ 100 to $ 138 a month and cut workloads from 245 hours to 224 hours a month. The strikers wanted work hours cut to 144 hours. <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>'s train drivers with about 10 years's expereince earn about $ 1,200 a month in regular salary and various allowances, which include overtime, holiday allowance, locomotive drivers allowance, according to the railroad.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880727-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-27-88 0017EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Nielsens     07-27 0511</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nielsens,0527</SECOND>
<HEAD>Democratic Convention a Turn-Off for Networks</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Democratic National Convention would have been a big ratings hit last week if only one network had showed up. With three sharing the coverage, however, the convention drove millions of viewers to other channels. The three-network share of the viewing audience fell to 49 percent in the <ORGANIZATION> A.C. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nielsen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> ratings last week, meaning that fewer than half the sets in use during prime time were tuned to a network. That compares to a 68 percent share for the three networks this season. During convention week in 1984, the three-network share was 54 percent, according to <PERSON> Gerald </PERSON> <PERSON> Jaffe </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s vice president for research, who said last week's share was the worst ever for the networks. During the four days of the convention in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>, the networks' prime-time share this year was 40 percent <PERSON> Jaffe </PERSON> estimated that perhaps another 1 percent of the audience was watching the convention on <ORGANIZATION> Cable </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Network </ORGANIZATION>. The best finish for campaign coverage was 26th for <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> on Tuesday night, with a rating of 8.7, while <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> had the low on Monday night with a 5.7 for 52nd place. However, the three-network total for Tuesday night's coverage was a rating of 23.2, compared with 15.6 for `` Golden Girls,'' the week's top-rated show. Cumulative totals for the other nights were 20.1 for Monday, 20.1 for Wednesday and 21.1 on Thursday. The rating is a percentage of the nation's estimated 88.6 million households with televisions. The share is a percentage of sets in use. Because of the lack of suspense at this year's Democratic Convention and the expectation that the Republican National Convention also will be largely a scripted media event, <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> News President <PERSON> Roone </PERSON> <PERSON> Arledge </PERSON> has said his network might pare its coverage of the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> gathering. The two other networks have said they will give the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> as much time as the Democrats got. <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> had the biggest convention audience with a 7.4 average rating for the four nights. <PERSON> Jaffe </PERSON> said <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> was the only network to have better convention ratings than in 1984. <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> was second with 6.9 and <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> was third with 6.5. <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> won the week with an average rating of 9.4, more than a third less than its season average. CBS was second at 7.9 and <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> had 7.8. For the 44 weeks of the season, <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> leads with an average prime-time rating of 15.0, followed by <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> at 12.6 and <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> at 12.5. News ratings also were down last week. CBS was the winner with an 8.6 rating, half a point lower than its winning number a week earlier. <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> was second at 8.6, down 0.6, and <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> was in third at 7.8, down 0.9. <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s reruns again dominated the week. Here is the top 10: `` Golden Girls,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>; `` The Cosby Show'' and `` Hunter'' -LRB- tie -RRB-, both <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>; `` 60 Minutes,'' CBS; `` Deliberate Stranger'' part 1, the <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> Sunday Night Movie; `` Murder She Wrote,'' CBS; `` Amen,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>; `` Sin of Innocence,'' the `` CBS Sunday Movie,'' and <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` 20-20'' -LRB- tie -RRB-; `` <PERSON> Alf </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880727-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-27-88 0018EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-NielsensList     07-27 0591</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nielsens List,0660</SECOND>
<HEAD>List of Week's Top-Rated TV Shows</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Nielsens</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the prime-time television ratings as compiled by the <ORGANIZATION> A.C. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nielsen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> for the week of July 18-24. Top 20 listings include the week's ranking, with full season-to-date ranking in parentheses, rating for the week, and total homes. An `` X'' in parentheses denotes one-time-only presentation. A rating measures the percentage of the nation's 88.6 million TV homes. 1. -LRB- 4 -RRB- `` Golden Girls,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 15.6 rating, 13.8 million homes. 2. -LRB- 27 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Hunter </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 15.3, 13.6 million homes. 2. -LRB- 1 -RRB- `` The Cosby Show,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 15.3, 13.6 million homes. 4. -LRB- 7 -RRB- `` 60 Minutes,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 14.5, 12.8 million homes. 5. -LRB- 21 -RRB- `` Deliberate Stranger,'' Part 1, _ `` <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> Sunday Night Movie,'' 14.3, 12.7 million homes. 6. -LRB- 10 -RRB- `` Murder, She Wrote,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 13.8, 12.2 million homes. 7. -LRB- 17 -RRB- `` Amen,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.7, 12.1 million homes. 8. -LRB- 52 -RRB- `` 20-20,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.4, 11.9 million homes. 8. -LRB- 20 -RRB- `` Sin of Innocence'' _ `` CBS Sunday Movie,'' 13.4, 11.9 million homes. 10. -LRB- 14 -RRB- `` ALF,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.5, 11.1 million homes. 11. -LRB- 38 -RRB- `` Moonraker'' _ `` <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> Sunday Night Movie,'' 12.1, 10.7 million homes. 12. -LRB- 28 -RRB- `` 227,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.7, 10.4 million homes. 13. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Heart and Soul,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.1, 9.8 million homes. 14. -LRB- 49 -RRB- `` <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> Vice,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 10.8, 9.6 million homes. 14. -LRB- 6 -RRB- `` Who's the Boss?'', <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 10.8, 9.6 million homes. 16. -LRB- 71 -RRB- `` Full House-Tuesday,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 10.7, 9.5 million homes. 17. -LRB- 69 -RRB- `` Mr. <PERSON> Belvedere </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 10.4, 9.2 million homes. 18. -LRB- 8 -RRB- `` Growing Pains,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 10.1, 8.9 million homes. 19. -LRB- 81 -RRB- `` I Married Dora,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 9.9, 8.8 million homes. 19. -LRB- 22 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Matlock </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 9.9, 8.8 million homes.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 21. -LRB- 26 -RRB- `` Head of the Class,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 9.8. 22. -LRB- 30 -RRB- `` Family Ties,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 9.6. 23. -LRB- 43 -RRB- `` Facts of Life,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 9.4. 24. -LRB- 15 -RRB- `` My Two Dads,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 9.2. 25. -LRB- 60 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Jake </PERSON> and The Fatman,'' CBS, 9.0. 26. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Democratic Convention-Tuesday,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 8.7. 27. -LRB- 104 -RRB- `` TV Bloopers and Practical Jokes,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 8.6. 27. -LRB- 73 -RRB- `` Full House-Friday,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 8.6. 29. -LRB- X -RRB- `` <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> Vice Special,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 8.5. 30. -LRB- 48 -RRB- `` Perfect Strangers,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 8.4. 31. -LRB- 64 -RRB- `` Beauty and the <LOCATION> Beast </LOCATION>,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 8.3. 31. -LRB- 91 -RRB- `` Blue Skies,'' CBS, 8.3. 33. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Democratic Convention-Thursday,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 8.0. 34. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Democratic Convention-Tuesday,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 7.8. 35. -LRB- 83 -RRB- `` Tour of Duty,'' CBS, 7.5. 36. -LRB- 109 -RRB- `` West 57th,'' CBS, 7.0. 36. -LRB- 64 -RRB- `` MacGyver,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 7.0. 36. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Why on <LOCATION> Earth </LOCATION>,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 7.0. 39. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Democratic Convention-Wednesday,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 6.9. 40. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Democratic Convention-Tuesday,'' CBS, 6.7. 40. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Democratic Convention-Wednesday,'' CBS, 6.7. 40. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Democratic Convention-Thursday,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 6.7. 40. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s Most Wanted,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 6.7. 44. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Democratic Convention-Wednesday,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 6.5. 45. -LRB- 91 -RRB- `` Educating Rita'' _ `` CBS Friday Movie,'' 6.4. 45. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Democratic Convention-Thursday,'' CBS, 6.4. 47. -LRB- 96 -RRB- `` Supercarrier,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 6.3. 48. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Democratic Convention-Monday,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 6.2. 49. -LRB- 107 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Ohara </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 6.1. 49. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` Married ... With Children,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 6.1. 51. -LRB- 102 -RRB- `` Rags To Riches,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 5.9. 51. -LRB- 42 -RRB- `` Kate & amp; <PERSON> Allie </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 5.9. 53. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Democratic Convention-Monday,'' CBS, 5.8. 54. -LRB- 106 -RRB- `` Hotel,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 5.7. 54. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Down <LOCATION> Delaware </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Road </LOCATION>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 5.7. 54. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Democratic Convention-Monday,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 5.7. 57. -LRB- 89 -RRB- `` Young <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> Houdini </PERSON>,'' Part 2 _ `` Disney Sunday Movie,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 5.4. 58. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` 21 Jump Street,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 5.3. 59. -LRB- 117 -RRB- `` Johnsons Home-Ltd. Partnership'' _ `` Summer Playhouse,'' CBS, 5.0 60. -LRB- 64 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Frank </PERSON>'s Place,'' CBS, 4.9. 60. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` <PERSON> Garry </PERSON> <PERSON> Shandling </PERSON> Show,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 4.9. 62. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Divided We Stand,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 4.8. 63. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` <PERSON> Tracey </PERSON> <PERSON> Ullman </PERSON> Show,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 3.4. 64. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` Duet,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 3.0. 65. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` Family Double Dare,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, -LRB- 8 p.m. -RRB- 2.4. 66. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` Family Double Dare,'' FOX -LRB- 8:30 p.m. -RRB- 2.0. 67. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` Dirty Dozen,'' 1.4. 67. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` Werewolf,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 1.4.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880727-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-27-88 0033EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--Germany-PlaneCrash     07-27 0147</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Germany-Plane Crash,0151</SECOND>
<HEAD>Ultralight Crashes After Encounter With West German Fighter</HEAD>
<DATELINE>EGGENFELDEN, West Germany (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The pilot of an ultralight airplane was killed after his craft apparently struck a West German Tornado jet fighter in flight and crashed, police said. Police said a preliminary investigation indicated the light plane nicked the fighter before Tuesday's crash. But officials did not rule out the possibility that turbulence from the jet's engine sent the ultralight down. The dead pilot was not identified. The crash occurred near <LOCATION> Eggenfelden </LOCATION>, about 60 miles east of <LOCATION> Munich </LOCATION>. The jet was not damaged and returned to its base near <LOCATION> Munich </LOCATION>, officials said. Police did not say whether the Tornado was on a low-level training flight. A series of <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> warplane crashes in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> in recent weeks has resulted in a growing demand that low-level military training flights be banned or sharply reduced.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880727-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-27-88 0117EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Soviet-Layoffs     07-27 0226</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Soviet-Layoffs,0234</SECOND>
<HEAD>Economic Reforms Lead To 1 Million Layoffs</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MOSCOW (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s drive to modernize industry and trim fat from management forced nearly 1 million Soviet factory workers out of work in the first half of the year, <ORGANIZATION> Radio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Moscow </ORGANIZATION> reported. But those laid off are sure to get other jobs `` since the government has undertaken to redistribute the labor force in a planned manner,'' the state-run radio said Tuesday. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>, named <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> chief in March 1985, has waged a campaign to reform the country's economy, increase productivity and prune the size of the state bureaucracy. In January, the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> daily Pravda estimated that 16 million Soviets would be laid off in the next 12 years as efficiency increases. Radio <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> said: `` The number of workers in Soviet industries has gone down by almost 1 million in the first half of the year, compared with the same period last year.'' `` The national statistical service attributes the fact to the current economic reform, which is introducing more automatic systems and streamlining management,'' the radio said. Radio <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> did not provide the size of the labor force in the country's factories last year or today. In 1986, 82.1 million of the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>'s 276 million citizens were officially classified as `` workers,'' as distinguished from white-collar service or management personnel and collective farmers.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880727-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-27-88 0139EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     07-27 0744</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0776</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names In The News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MONTCLAIR, N.J. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Rock' n' roll star <PERSON> Mick </PERSON> <PERSON> Jagger </PERSON> got satisfaction from seeing his long-time girlfriend, model <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Hall </PERSON>, make her acting debut in a production of `` Bus Stop.'' Hall played the starring role of <PERSON> Cherie </PERSON>, a woman who is stranded at a bus stop with a cowboy who abducted her. About 850 people attended Tuesday night's performance that started a two-week run for the play at <ORGANIZATION> Montclair </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION>. Singer <PERSON> Neil </PERSON> <PERSON> Young </PERSON> accompanied <PERSON> Jagger </PERSON>. Both remained backstage until the lights dimmed for the opening act. Some in the audience tried to get the autographs of <PERSON> Jagger </PERSON> and Young but were blocked by bodyguards. The audience appeared to enjoy the show throughout and applauded loudly at ts end. <PERSON> Jagger </PERSON>, <PERSON> Young </PERSON> and the bodyguards left immediately after the show and went into a limousine.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 `` Wheel of Fortune'' letter-turner <PERSON> Vanna </PERSON> <PERSON> White </PERSON> says mystery spells success and has turned down an offer to be host of the daytime version of the show when <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Sajak </PERSON> leaves. `` I think <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> likes what I do,'' <PERSON> White </PERSON> said Monday. `` I'm a mystery to people. They want to know more.'' The show's producer says she discussed the idea of White taking over as host, but <PERSON> White </PERSON>, 31, says she does n't want a bigger role. `` I think the fact that I do n't do more has made me what I am,'' said <PERSON> White </PERSON>, whose largely non-speaking role on the popular game show turned her into a star. <PERSON> Sajak </PERSON> will remain as host of the nighttime version, the nation's top-rated syndicated show But he will leave the <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> daytime version at the end of the year to be host of a late night talk show.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>VADUZ, Liechtenstein (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>'s longest-reigning head of state, Prince <PERSON> Franz </PERSON> <PERSON> Josef </PERSON> <PERSON> II </PERSON>, has marked his 50th anniversary ruling the tiny, 62-square-mile principality of <LOCATION> Liechtenstein </LOCATION>. Parliament honored the 81-year-old monarch with a special session Tuesday and unveiled a portrait of the prince etched onto <LOCATION> Liechtenstein </LOCATION> marble in the government building in the capital, <LOCATION> Vaduz </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Franz </PERSON> <PERSON> Josef </PERSON> is the second-longest ruling head of state in the world, behind <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s Emperor <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON>, 87, who has reigned for 62 years. He oversees a principality with a homogeneous population of 27,000. Four years ago, <PERSON> Franz </PERSON> <PERSON> Josef </PERSON> turned over administrative duties to his eldest son, <PERSON> Hans </PERSON> <PERSON> Adam </PERSON>, and since then his role largely has been ceremonial.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> let the parade pass him by once, when he dropped out of high school. Now, as editor of Parade magazine, he has a message for others who missed the academic boat. <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> has signed on as a spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Educational </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION> program, which allows dropouts to take a test to gain the equivalent of a high school diploma. `` It was in the Marines that I was able to develop my self-esteem and a sense of pride,'' <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> said at a news conference Tuesday. `` After passing the GED exam, I was able to get into <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corps </ORGANIZATION> schools and grow with more confidence.'' Other former dropouts who are GED spokesmen include Rep. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Florio </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.J. </LOCATION>; warden <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Vasquez </PERSON> of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Quentin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Prison </LOCATION>; and cookie king <PERSON> Wally </PERSON> `` Famous'' <PERSON> Amos </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The estranged wife of <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Redskins </ORGANIZATION> owner <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Kent </PERSON> <PERSON> Cooke </PERSON> says she was stunned to learn that comments she made during an intimate conversation with biographer <PERSON> Kitty </PERSON> <PERSON> Kelly </PERSON> were published in a magazine. August's issue of Washingtonian magazine offers a revealing account of the <ORGANIZATION> Cookes </ORGANIZATION>' tumultuous marriage based on two interviews between Miss <PERSON> Kelly </PERSON> and <PERSON> Suzanne </PERSON> <PERSON> Cooke </PERSON>. The interviews were conducted two years apart. Among the revelations is Mrs. <PERSON> Cooke </PERSON>'s account of her two abortions after getting pregnant by <PERSON> Cooke </PERSON>, and how the billionaire football team owner only agreed to marry her on condition that she end a third pregnancy by him. Mrs. <PERSON> Cooke </PERSON>, 31, never got the third abortion and is the mother of <PERSON> Jacqueline </PERSON> <PERSON> Kent </PERSON> <PERSON> Cooke </PERSON>, born Jan. 25. <PERSON> Cooke </PERSON>, 76, has never seen the baby. Mrs. <PERSON> Cooke </PERSON> said Tuesday she objects to the use of the intimate details she gave <PERSON> Miss </PERSON> <PERSON> Kelly </PERSON> in 1986. `` I was stunned by the quotations that were printed from the early interviews,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Cooke </PERSON> said. But Miss <PERSON> Kelly </PERSON> said that Mrs. <PERSON> Cooke </PERSON> knew during both interviews that she was being taped. Mrs. <PERSON> Cooke </PERSON> said her marriage to <PERSON> Cooke </PERSON> is over and has sued him for $ 15 million for a trust fund for her daughter.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880727-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-27-88 0609EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--ColorConversion     07-27 0140</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Color Conversion,0143</SECOND>
<HEAD>`Felix the Cat,' `Abbott and Costello'' Go Color</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MARINA DEL REY, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Ninety colorized vintage films, the cartoon series `` Felix the Cat'' and the `` <PERSON> Abbott </PERSON> and Costello'' TV series will be distributed worldwide by <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pictures </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Television </ORGANIZATION>, it was announced. <ORGANIZATION> Color </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Systems </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Technology </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> said Tuesday that its library was part of the long-term, worldwide distribution agreement, which also provides for <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION> to finance the colorization of 12 black-and-white movies owned by Color Systems. Financial terms were not disclosed. Color Systems titles being colorized for <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION> distribution within eight months include `` The <ORGANIZATION> Corsican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Brothers </ORGANIZATION>,'' `` Kit <PERSON> Carson </PERSON>,'' `` The Man in the Iron Mask'' and `` Black Beauty.'' The colorization process has drawn fire from such Hollywood figures as <PERSON> Jimmy </PERSON> <PERSON> Stewart </PERSON>, <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Huston </PERSON> and <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Capra </PERSON>, who have said the process violates the original films' artistic integrity.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880727-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-27-88 0200EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Congress-200Years Bjt   07-27 0702</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Congress-200 Years, Bjt,700</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHINGTON WIRE: But Did He Leave a Tip?</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LAWRENCE L. KNUTSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 On an evening in 1856, Rep. <PERSON> Philemon </PERSON> <PERSON> T. </PERSON> <PERSON> Herbert </PERSON> of <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, one of the more obscure members of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, was waiting for service in the dining room of the capital's preeminent hotel, The <PERSON> Willard </PERSON> Growing hungrier _ and angrier _ by the minute, he was resolutely ignored by a haughty waiter. According to a new history of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Representatives </ORGANIZATION>, `` Losing his patience, and perhaps feeling the snub more acutely than he had a right to do, <PERSON> Herbert </PERSON> pulled his pistol and shot and killed the man.'' <PERSON> Herbert </PERSON>'s rather extreme reaction to this unacceptable affront to his congressional dignity is recounted by <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> historian <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> T. </PERSON> <PERSON> Currie </PERSON>, who adds: `` The <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> did not censure Rep. <PERSON> Herbert </PERSON> for his act, thereby giving a certain justification to it.'' This was, perhaps, not a high moment in the history of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> or of its members. But <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> waiters ever since have been closely observant of the needs of hungry <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> members. The temper tantrum of the ignored congressman and its fatal result is but a minor low point in a new volume sketching the 199-year history of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, most of which is devoted to far more consequential affairs of state. <PERSON> Currie </PERSON>'s work, and a companion history of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> by its official historian, <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON>, have been issued to mark next year's celebration of the bicentennial of the <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. They set out the milestones of the nation's legislative history, with an occasional side look at some of the more unusual, and eccentric, people and events along the way. For the most part, <PERSON> Baker </PERSON>'s history of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> ignores the existence of the House. <PERSON> Currie </PERSON>'s history of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> mostly ignores the history of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>. But not entirely. At the very beginning, the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> historian notes, the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> proposed that the nation's president be addressed as `` His Highness, President of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and Protector of the Rights of the Same.'' <PERSON> Currie </PERSON> calls this `` an awful appellation'' and records that the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> would have none of it. The president has been `` Mr. President'' ever since. <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> recalls how <PERSON> Alexis </PERSON> <PERSON> DeTocqueville </PERSON>, the French observer of American institutions, was struck in 1831 by the `` vulgar demeanor'' of the popularly elected <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> compared to the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>, whose members were elected by state legislatures. The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>, said <PERSON> De </PERSON> <PERSON> Tocqueville </PERSON>, `` is composed of eloquent advocates, distinguished generals, wise magistrates and statesmen of note, whose arguments would do honor to the most remarkable parliamentary debates in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>.'' The <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, he sniffed, was composed of men of far lower qualifications and standing in society. `` In a country in which education is very general, it is said that the representatives of the people do not always know how to write correctly.'' In fairness, <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> notes that Sen. <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Hart </PERSON> <PERSON> Benton </PERSON> took exception to this, branding <PERSON> DeTocqueville </PERSON> and his opinions as `` elitist.'' `` The <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION> senator observed that most senators had originally been House members.'' <PERSON> Currie </PERSON> notes that <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Jefferson </PERSON> is said to have asked <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Washington </PERSON> why the Constitutional Convention had created a two-house legislature. Why was n't one house enough? `` Why did you pour your tea into that saucer? asked <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. `` To cool it,'' replied <PERSON> Jefferson </PERSON>. `` Just so,'' responded <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. `` We pour <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> legislation into the senatorial saucer to cool it.'' <PERSON> Currie </PERSON> notes that 200 years after that purported discussion, the situation is at times reversed. `` The House has begun to act as a check on the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>,'' he concludes. `` It has now become in many instances the saucer into which <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> legislation is poured to cool it.'' The two volumes lay out the benchmarks of congressional history, high and low, triumph and scandal: The burning of the Capitol by the British in 1814, the expansion of the nation, the march toward Civil War in the 1860s, the end of slavery, the era of reconstruction, the impeachment trial of President <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>, investigations, the rivalry with the presidency, the depression, world wars, the ethics of congressmen, Watergate. ... Says historian <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> of his volume: `` It's a hop, skip and a jump over the mountain tops.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880727-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-27-88 0204EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Nutrition&amp;Health Bjt   07-27 0830</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nutrition &amp; Health, Bjt,810</SECOND>
<NOTE>For release 11 a.m. EDT; time set by Source</NOTE>
<HEAD>Americans Eating Their Way to Early Graves, Surgeon General Says</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PAUL RECER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Science Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Americans are eating their way to early graves, bite by bite and meal by meal, consuming too much fat, seasoning it with too much salt and washing it down with too much alcohol, according to a report issued today by the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> surgeon general. `` Overconsumption of certain dietary components is now a major concern for Americans,'' the report said, noting that `` diseases of dietary excess and imbalance'' are among the leading causes of death in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. Many Americans are overweight, do n't eat enough fruit, vegetables and whole grains, and often fail to get required nutrients such as calcium and iron. Of the 2.1 million Americans who died last year, the surgeon general's study said that nearly 1.5 million succumbed to diseases associated with diet. `` What we eat may affect our risk for several of the leading causes of death for Americans, notably, coronary heart disease, stroke, atherosclerosis, diabetes, and some types of cancer,'' the report said. `` These disorders together now account for more than two-thirds of all deaths in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>.'' Though malnutrition is a problem in several parts of the world and for certain Americans, the report said, `` for most of us the more likely problem has become one of overeating _ too many calories for our activity levels and an imbalance in the nutrients consumed along with them.'' In a forward to the report, Surgeon General <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Everett </PERSON> <PERSON> Koop </PERSON> said that although many foods are involved, the chief factor affecting health `` is the disproportionate consumption of foods high in fats, often at the expense of foods high in complex carbohydrates and fiber _ such as vegetables, fruits, and whole grain products.'' He said he is convinced that through `` a concerted effort'' by policy makers and the public, `` our daily diets can bring a substantial measure of better health to all Americans.'' The 712-page report cites more than 2,000 scientific studies from around the world and was compiled with the advice of more than 200 doctors, nutritionists and biochemists. The report makes recommendations ranging from the amount of fat that should be included in the diet, to the advisability of taking vitamin supplements. Among the major findings: _ Most people should reduce the consumption of fat, especially saturated fats, such as from eggs, butter or untrimmed red meat It suggests more vegetables and fruits, fish, poultry, lean meats and low-fat dairy products. _ More whole grain foods, cereal products, vegetables and fruits should be in the diet The report recommends that dried beans and peas be used as a source of protein to replace some animal products. _ Sodium consumption should be reduced by limiting the use of salt in food preparation and at the table _ Alcohol intake should be reduced to two drinks a day `` if at all. Pregnant women should avoid any alcohol, it said. The report estimates that about 9 percent of the <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> population has two or more drinks a day. _ Fluoride should be added to community water systems to prevent tooth decay, and that the consumption of sugar be limited to avoid dental cavities _ Adolescent girls and women should increase consumption of foods high in calcium, such as low-fat dairy products _ Children, adolescents and women of childbearing age should consume more iron-rich foods, such as red meat, fish, cereals, beans and whole-grain cereals `` This issue is of special concern for low-income families,'' the report said. Dietary fat, the report said, increases risks for obesity, some types of cancer, gallbladder and heart disease. `` Dietary fat accounts for about 37 percent of the total energy intake of Americans, well above the upper limit of 30 percent recommended by the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Heart </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cancer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION>,'' the report said. It said excess cholesterol levels, strongly associated with heart attacks, should be reduced by limiting consumption of foods of animal origin, such as eggs, dairy products, meat, poultry and fish. The report warned against fad diets or `` magical'' foods that often are promoted with unsubstantiated claims. It said Americans spend about $ 2.7 billion a year for nutritional supplements that are `` of unproven benefit.'' Over-the-counter vitamins and minerals, alone, represent a huge business of questionable value, the report said. `` An estimated 40 percent of Americans consume supplemental vitamins, minerals, or other dietary components at an annual cost of more than $ 1.5 billion,'' even though such supplements are not needed by most customers, the report said. Americans also spend extra money for products labeled as `` natural'' or `` organic'', even though the study said special benefits of these products `` are not generally demonstrated.'' `` ` Natural' vitamins, for example, often sell at twice the price of synthetic products even though they are chemically identical,'' the report said. `` In some such products labeled as ` natural', only a minor fraction of the vitamin is actually derived from natural sources.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880727-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-27-88 0205EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Congress-Drought Bjt   07-27 0752</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Congress-Drought, Bjt,750</SECOND>
<HEAD>Boon for Dairymen Tacked Onto Drought Bill</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MIKE ROBINSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Critics of a $ 145 million milk price support increase tacked onto the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> drought-relief bill say it could invite a presidential veto, but the amendment's chief sponsor says it's needed because `` cows do n't drop from the sky.'' Rep. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Jeffords </PERSON>, R-Vt., says that without the 50-cent price support increase, dairy farmers in his state and elsewhere will reduce the size of their herds, eventually leading to milk shortages Critics produced two studies saying the chances of such shortages are slight, but the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> approved the milk price-support increase anyway on a 15-12 vote and then sent the drought-relief bill to the full House. `` This amendment makes the whole bill more vulnerable,'' said Rep. <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Glickman </PERSON>, D-Kan. He said the amendment makes the measure subject to criticism that it treats `` one segment of agriculture more favorably than other segments of agriculture.'' The committee action also came despite a warning from President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> against special benefits for favored segments of agriculture. `` Creating windfalls for some will mean less for the truly deserving,'' <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said in a letter sent Monday to <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> Chairman E. `` Kika'' de la <PERSON> Garza </PERSON>, D-Texas. `` To put it very simply, we must not bust the budget,'' <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said. As the bill was written two weeks ago, it would have canceled an expected price-support cut of 50 cents for each hundred pounds of milk. The new plan adopted at <PERSON> Jeffords </PERSON>' urging would not only cancel the reduction but would increase the price-support level by 50 cents per hundredweight to $ 11.10. `` It is the duty of this committee to assure that there is an adequate supply of milk,'' said <PERSON> Jeffords </PERSON>, whose home state is a major source of the <ORGANIZATION> East </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION>'s milk. He said that without additional help, dairy farmers will reduce their herds and the lost production capability could not be restored overnight. `` Cows do n't drop from the sky,'' <PERSON> Jeffords </PERSON> said. He said that if milk shortages set in, `` you're going to hear screams from consumers that you wo n't believe.'' Rep. <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Olin </PERSON>, D-Va., presented one study by the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> and another by private agricultural economists that saw no milk shortage in the offing if the system remains as it is Proponents of the measure, however, shrugged off such studies. Rep. <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Stenholm </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Texas </LOCATION>, said that because of the drought a 50-cent increase in the price-support level actually is in keeping philosophically with the 1985 farm program, even though it calls for successive 50-cent cuts in supports. <PERSON> Steinholm </PERSON> said higher feed prices, caused by a hay shortage, have been tantamount to a drastic cut in price supports, and that fairness would actually call for a $ 1 increase in supports. At the outset of the committee's session, Deputy Agriculture Secretary <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Myers </PERSON> told lawmakers the administration already disapproved of provisions of the bill that would expand feed programs for dairy and livestock producers. He also said the administration opposes a provision that would require farmers to buy federal crop insurance in the next two years as a condition of receiving disaster payments now. The measure would provide disaster payments for growers of all crops equal to 65 percent of losses in excess of 35 percent of expected yield. For farmers who lost their entire crops, there would be additional payments. The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> already has approved its own version of the bill but is struggling to come up with a similar plan to aid farmers whose crops have been all but entirely burned away by the blazing sun and shortage of rainfall that has plagued the midcontinent. Farm senators had planned to meet late Tuesday to work out a formula but canceled the session at the last minute. They still are aiming for floor action this week. Feed benefits for livestock producers would be capped at $ 50,000 for each individual. Payments for crop producers would be limited to $ 100,000 per person. As it was putting the finishing touches on the bill, the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> demonstrated compassion for cotton growers in the district of Rep. <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Combest </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Texas </LOCATION>, whose crops were damaged last year by hail. The panel approved a $ 24 million amendment that would provide disaster payments to those farmers. Proponents acknowledged that the damage had nothing to do with the drought but noted that there was a similar disaster relief bill in 1986 but none in 1987. They said <PERSON> Combest </PERSON>'s plan would `` fill in the gaps.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880727-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-27-88 0206EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Hostages-List     07-27 0274</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Hostages-List,0283</SECOND>
<HEAD>American Hostages Believed Held In Lebanon</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Iran-Hostages, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 The following is a list of the nine Americans believed held by kidnappers in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>, with the dates they were reported seized: _ <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON>, chief <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> correspondent of <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>, March 16, 1985 The Iranian-backed Islamic Jihad, or Holy War, claims to hold him. _ <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Sutherland </PERSON>, Scottish-born acting dean of agriculture at the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Beirut </ORGANIZATION>, June 9, 1985 Islamic Jihad claims to hold him. _ <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Herbert </PERSON> <PERSON> Reed </PERSON>, director of the private <ORGANIZATION> Lebanon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>, Sept. 9, 1986 A pro-Libyan group called <ORGANIZATION> Arab </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Revolutionary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cells-Omar </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Moukhtar </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forces </ORGANIZATION> claimed responsibility. _ <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Cicippio </PERSON>, acting comptroller of the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Beirut </ORGANIZATION>, Sept. 12, 1986 <ORGANIZATION> Revolutionary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> claimed responsibility. _ <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Austin </PERSON> <PERSON> Tracy </PERSON>, author of children's books Date of kidnapping unclear, but the <ORGANIZATION> Revolutionary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> claimed responsibility Oct. 21, 1986. _ <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Turner </PERSON>, visiting professor of mathematics and computer science at <ORGANIZATION> Beirut </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION>, Jan. 24, 1987 Kidnapped from university campus along with <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Polhill </PERSON>, <PERSON> Alann </PERSON> <PERSON> Steen </PERSON> and <PERSON> Mithileswar </PERSON> <PERSON> Singh </PERSON>, by gunmen posing as policemen. Islamic Jihad for the <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Palestine </ORGANIZATION> claimed responsibility. _ <PERSON> Alann </PERSON> <PERSON> Steen </PERSON>, journalism professor at <ORGANIZATION> Beirut </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION>, Jan. 24, 1987 _ <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Polhill </PERSON>, assistant professor of business and lecturer in accounting at <ORGANIZATION> Beirut </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION>, Jan. 24, 1987 _ Marine Lt. Col. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Higgins </PERSON>, head of a 75-man observer group attached to the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Interim </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>, Feb. 17, Kidnapped near Tyre. Claimed by the Organization of the Oppressed on <LOCATION> Earth </LOCATION>, a <ORGANIZATION> Shiite </ORGANIZATION> faction. The group said last April 21 that <PERSON> Higgins </PERSON> would be put on trial for spying.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880727-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-27-88 0211EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FarmScene     07-27 0899</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Farm Scene,890</SECOND>
<HEAD>Drought To Have Long-Term Effect On Livestock Production</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DON KENDALL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Farm Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 This summer's heat and drought have hurt livestock producers now and for some time in the future, an Agriculture Department analysis says. Meat production in the second half of 1988 will be greater than it otherwise would have been without the drought. And prices received by livestock producers will be down, reflecting the thinning out of herds. `` As producers sell off some breeding stock, the long-term capacity of the industry will be lowered,'' the report said. `` The increased slaughter in 1988 will lower production in 1989 and prices will rise again.'' The report was prepared by <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Ginzel </PERSON> and <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Stillman </PERSON> of the department's <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>. It was included in a forthcoming issue of Agriculture Outlook magazine. Beef production will be affected by this year's drought in two ways, the report said. First, cattle feedlot operators, who depend on corn and other feed grains, are seeing higher production costs. Second, cow-calf operators, who provide calves to feeders, will be hit the hardest. `` Calves are the major cost in the cattle feeding industry,'' the report said. `` As the price of feed rises, cattle feedlot operators will decrease the price they are willing to pay for feeder cattle.'' Meanwhile, the cow-calf producer's major feed is forage such as pasture and hay. Drought has reduced the forage supply, just as it has the grain inventory. As production of forage is reduced, cow-calf operators are forced to reduce their herds or supplement grazing with hay. `` The first cattle to move off drought-stressed pasture usually are the yearling cattle that normally go into feedlots,'' the report said. `` The next to move are replacement heifers, which were intended to go into the breeding herd, and older, less-productive cows.'' Finally, the last to go are the mature, most productive cows, the basic breeding stock for future beef production. Drought affects hog producers mostly through higher feed costs, the report said. Many hog farmers produce some or all of their feed grains. But as corn yields are reduced, producers will have to buy additional grain or send their hogs to slaughter early. `` Increased culling of the -LRB- hog -RRB- breeding herd boost short-term production and reduces prices received,'' the report said. `` It will also reduce production in 1989. Feeder pig producers are squeezed more than farrow-to-finish hog farmers, much like the cow-calf producers in the beef industry.'' Drought has hit the poultry industry in similar ways, with higher grain and soybean meal prices raising production costs. Broiler production may drop in the second half of 1988 and in 1989, relative to normal output. `` Because broilers have a short production cycle, the broiler industry can respond more quickly to the higher feed costs and can decrease production more quickly than either the cattle or hog industries,'' the report said. It added: `` As with previous droughts, if next year's grain and forage crops are near normal and if grain prices drop and livestock prices soar because production is down, meat production will then become further depressed as profitability improves and as producers hold animals from slaughter to rebuild their breeding herds.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> has scheduled a referendum among hog producers and importers to determine whether a national pork promotion and research program will continue. The vote will be held Sept. 7-8 at county extension offices, <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Patrick </PERSON> <PERSON> Boyle </PERSON>, administrator of the department's <ORGANIZATION> Agricultural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Marketing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>, announced Tuesday. `` All pork producers or persons importing hogs, pork or pork products between Nov. 1, 1986, and Sept. 6, 1988, will be entitled to vote in the referendum,'' <PERSON> Boyle </PERSON> said. `` A simple majority -LRB- one vote more than half the number cast -RRB- will determine if the ... program will continue.'' The 1985 farm law authorized the pork program, which is paid for by an assessment of one quarter of 1 percent of the market value of all hogs sold in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, and an equivalent amount on imported hogs, pork and pork products. A final regulation setting up the program was issued by <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> on Sept. 5, 1986, and the assessments began that fall on Nov. 1. <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> stipulated that for the program to continue in effect a referendum must be held between 24 months and 30 months after the department issued the final regulation.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Rains have `` relieved drought stress'' in parts of the Corn Belt, but crops have shown little improvement, reports the government's Joint Agricultural Weather Facility. `` The precipitation gave most crops a boost in the central and southern <LOCATION> Great </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Plains </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Delta </ORGANIZATION> and Southeast,'' the report said Tuesday. `` Soil moisture improved but was still mostly short in the eastern half of the nation.'' In the central and eastern Corn Belt, rain during the week of July 18-24 may have come too late to improve corn harvest prospects, the report said. Soybeans were reported in `` mostly fair'' condition but showed little improvement as a result of rain in the central and eastern Corn Belt areas, the report said. However, soybeans continued to improve in the <LOCATION> Great </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Plains </LOCATION>, where the crop was reported in `` good to fair'' shape. Livestock was reported in `` mostly fair'' condition and recent rains have helped pastures, although forage was still in short supply. The facility is operated jointly by the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Oceanic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Atmospheric </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880727-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-27-88 0215EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Wright-Ethics     07-27 0677</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Wright-Ethics,670</SECOND>
<HEAD>Outside Counsel To Look Into Matters In Ethics Panel Complaint</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JIM DRINKARD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> ethics committee says a new outside counsel named to probe allegations against <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Speaker <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> will be `` free to investigate in any manner he deems appropriate.'' But the counsel, <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> lawyer <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Phelan </PERSON>, will be restricted to looking into the six counts in a complaint adopted by the panel on June 9 and public release of any findings will be controlled by the ethics panel, said chairman <PERSON> Julian </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Dixon </PERSON>, D-Calif. `` If any other evidence comes to his attention, he is directed to report that to us,'' <PERSON> Dixon </PERSON> said in an interview Tuesday The committee would then decide whether to broaden the investigation, he added. <PERSON> Dixon </PERSON> said he expects <PERSON> Phelan </PERSON> and his staff will do independent investigative work, including the taking of large numbers of depositions. The ethics panel, formally known as the <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> on </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Standards </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Official </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conduct </ORGANIZATION>, will pay <PERSON> Phelan </PERSON>'s law firm up to $ 300,000 plus expenses, he said. `` He is free to investigate in any manner he deems appropriate, whatever he feels is necessary,'' said <PERSON> Dixon </PERSON>. `` I'm like any other professional lawyer,'' <PERSON> Phelan </PERSON> told reporters in a brief introduction outside the closed door of the committee room. `` I'm going to exercise my own judgment within the parameters of the inquiry. ... I've been told to investigate the allegations fully, fairly, completely and thoroughly, and that's what I intend to do. <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>'s chief accuser, Rep. <PERSON> Newt </PERSON> <PERSON> Gingrich </PERSON>, R-Ga., complained about the selection of <PERSON> Phelan </PERSON>, noting that he has been an active Democratic fund-raiser in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> and had been a delegate to last week's Democratic National Convention, although he sat out the convention and let an alternate take his place <PERSON> Gingrich </PERSON> said he also would have preferred selection of someone with a prosecutorial background. <PERSON> Phelan </PERSON>'s 60-lawyer firm handles mostly corporate law and civil litigation. `` It seems to me for this investigation to have any legitimacy it has to be able to follow the leads wherever they lead,'' <PERSON> Gingrich </PERSON> told reporters. `` The independent counsel has to be truly independent. He can not be on a short leash held by the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> chairman of the committee.'' <PERSON> Dixon </PERSON> said the 12-member ethics panel, made up of six Democrats and six Republicans, agreed to seek an outside counsel at the same time it opened its <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> inquiry on June 9, but chose not to make that decision public until someone was found to take the job. `` We believed the <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> public would feel more comfortable, when the speaker of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Representatives </ORGANIZATION> is being investigated, with someone that is not an employee of the Capitol,'' he said. <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> repeated to reporters his contention that he would be exonerated by the probe and said he hoped it would be conducted quickly. `` I think they will conclude I have not violated any commonly accepted ethics rules, and the sooner that happens, the better,'' <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> said. But <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> said the matter is being used as a political weapon by <PERSON> Gingrich </PERSON>, who is laying the groundwork to cry foul if the probe turns up nothing critical of the speaker. `` Failing to have any substance on which to rely, they are trying to lay the impression that the inevitable result of a clear bill of health is somehow a whitewash,'' <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> said. At the same time, Vice President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, who has used <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>'s ethics problems as grist on the campaign trail, was speaking across the street from the Capitol at the Library of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and advocating conflict-of-interest laws for <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> that are as tough as those that now apply to the executive branch, including provisions for a fully independent counsel to investigate ethics cases. The six counts now pending against <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> include charges of using his office to lobby federal officials and others on matters in which he had a financial interest, and alleged improprieties in the publication of a book by a campaign contractor for which <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> received unusually high royalties, among other charges.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880727-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-27-88 0036EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-YellowstoneFire 2ndLd-Writethru a0801 07-27 0846</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Yellowstone Fire, 2nd Ld - Writethru, a0801,0863</SECOND>
<HEAD>Fire Burning Near Old Faithful; 1,000 Firefighters Summoned</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: LEADS with 8 grafs to UPDATE acreage total, add background on
varying estimates for size, distance of fire. Picks up 9th graf
pvs, `A fire...'.</NOTE>
<HEAD>LaserPhotos DX2,4; LaserColor DX3</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MIKE DENNISON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>YELLOWSTONE NATIONAL PARK, Wyo. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Fire-spitting helicopters were dispatched to <ORGANIZATION> Yellowstone </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Park </ORGANIZATION> on Tuesday to help protect the Old Faithful geyser area from a 6,000-acre blaze, part of the worst series of fires in the park in nearly a century. Almost 1,000 firefighters were summoned to the scene, but officials had not decided as of early Tuesday evening whether to actively fight the fire, one of a dozen burning in the oldest national park. The fires have charred more than 70,000 acres in the 2.2 million-acre park, the nation's oldest national park. One fire, the 47,000-acre blaze dubbed `` Clover Mist'' on the eastern edge of <LOCATION> Yellowstone </LOCATION>, made two jumps into <ORGANIZATION> Shoshone </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION>. Interior Secretary <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Hodel </PERSON> made plans to tour <ORGANIZATION> Yellowstone </ORGANIZATION> by helicopter Wednesday to get a first-hand view of the devastation. Winds were pushing the Old Faithful fire away from the geyser complex, which includes an historic inn and several other buildings. But fire managers decided as a safeguard to call in `` heli-torches'' that can spew a napalm-like substance. If officials decide to use them, the copters will be used to start `` backfires'' to burn away brush in the main fire's path. The fire, which started Friday in the adjacent <ORGANIZATION> Targhee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION>, burned roughly 10 miles west of <LOCATION> Old </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Faithful </LOCATION>, and about 10-15 miles south of <LOCATION> Madison </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Junction </LOCATION>, said Fire Information Officer <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Fox </PERSON>. Later estimated differed on how far the fire was from Old Faithful, ranging from about 6 miles to 10 miles, but officials agreed that it was still burning toward the northeast, a direction would bypass the geyser. Spokesmen stressed that their figures on total acreage burned also were estimates. Officials said they did n't believe firefighters could ever douse the flames. `` These fires are going to burn until the weather puts them out,'' said <PERSON> Fox </PERSON>. A fire camp was established 13 miles north of <LOCATION> Old </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Faithful </LOCATION> in an open field, where resting firefighters relaxed in tents or simply stretched out on the ground. Other firefighters were at Old Faithful picking the area clean of downed trees, piles of firewood, twigs and pine needles that could feed embers carried by winds to the area. They also cleared the ground around a microwave tower that provides Old Faithful's communications with the rest of the park Plans were made to burn a five-mile-long meadow, possibly on Wednesday, to clear out the dry vegetation and thus slow the fire if it turned toward Old Faithful, said <PERSON> Fox </PERSON>. `` With the worst-case weather scenario -LRB- strong winds out of the west -RRB-, that probably would n't hold it. But it would definitely slow it down,'' he said. `` If all else fails, we'll backfire Old Faithful.'' Eighty firefighters were sent to an area near <LOCATION> Frost </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION>, located 10 miles north of <LOCATION> Yellowstone </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Entrance </LOCATION>, where flames had blackened about 200 acres since the fire moved into the national forest during the weekend, said forest spokesman <PERSON> Dave </PERSON> <PERSON> Damron </PERSON>. Another 60 were 10 miles farther to the north where the `` Canoe Lake'' fire had burned about 50 acres, he said. Unusually hot and dry conditions this summer have left <ORGANIZATION> Yellowstone </ORGANIZATION> and the rest of northwestern <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION> tinder-box dry. `` The last time they had this much fire in the park was in the late 1800s,'' said Incident Commander <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Caplinger </PERSON>. `` The fuel conditions, and the weather conditions, lend themselves to extreme fire potential. `` The outlook is we probably got at least three long months of fire season ahead of us in this part of the country,'' he added. `` We could be in for the beginning of the siege of'88.'' Although no closures of services or accommodations at Old Faithful had been ordered, park visitors were advised such closures may eventually be necessary. Fires have forced the closure of <LOCATION> Grant </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Village </LOCATION> and the road from there south to the <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Entrance </LOCATION>. At <LOCATION> Grant </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Village </LOCATION>, about 500 firefighters were continuing to fight flames from the the Shoshone and Red fires that had spread to 20,200 acres. The village includes a small hotel and some trailers and apartments for park service personnel. Hot embers shooting ahead of the fires Monday night burned through power lines at the area of the village and set one building on fire. Officials said the structure was n't seriously damaged. Flames also had burned around the <LOCATION> Lewis </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> campground, torching trees along the perimeter of the area, according to fire officials. In the Teton Wilderness that borders <ORGANIZATION> Yellowstone </ORGANIZATION> on the south, some 690 firefighters worked Tuesday along the northern edge of the 24,400-acre Mink Creek fire. While good progress was made during the day on the southern end of the fire, thunderstorms packing some erratic winds were creating a problem on the northern end, which had burned about 1,200 acres into <ORGANIZATION> Yellowstone </ORGANIZATION>'s remote backcountry.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880727-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-27-88 0222EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Wilderness     07-27 0647</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Wilderness,630</SECOND>
<HEAD>Forest Lands Being `Loved To Death' By Campers, Forest Service
Says</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVE GOELLER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Americans looking for a pristine wilderness experience on remote <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> lands increasingly are finding trashy campsites, unsafe trails, unhealthy water and pollution. And forest service officials recounting these problems also are warning that because of tight money and growing land use, conditions are likely to worsen among the 32 million acres of official wilderness under their control. `` We're falling behind,'' <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Leonard </PERSON>, associate <ORGANIZATION> USFS </ORGANIZATION> chief, told the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Interior </ORGANIZATION> public lands subcommittee on Tuesday in what chairman <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Vento </PERSON>, D-Minn., said was the first-ever congressional review of the condition of wilderness areas protected from development under a landmark 1964 law `` Wilderness areas are now literally being loved to death'' by burgeoning numbes of backpackers, some of them ignorant of backcountry etiquette and hygiene, said <PERSON> Greg </PERSON> <PERSON> Hansen </PERSON>, a ranger from the Superstition Wilderness in <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Tonto </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> LaBorde </PERSON>, supervisor for two areas in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Inyo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION>, said that overuse there has been countered by setting trailhead quotas and requiring campers to obtain permits. But he said the areas' two rangers are able to contact only 7 percent of the visitors to brief them on backcountry manners and that trail reconstruction is eight years behind schedule, causing safety and erosion problems. <PERSON> LaBorde </PERSON> said all visitors are told to purify water before drinking it. And to combat improper sanitation practices by campers, there are now two solar toilets on the popular Mt. <PERSON> Whitney </PERSON> trail, he said. <PERSON> Anne </PERSON> <PERSON> Fege </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> explains that such toilets are portable enclosures that have solar collectors to generate heat to dry out and compost human waste. <PERSON> LaBorde </PERSON> said grazing by pack animals owned by commercial outfitters is nearing the land's grazing capacity and that concentrated use of some campsites `` has left many barren scars on the landscape.'' `` Our efforts to regain some sort of natural condition to these areas have been weak,'' testified <PERSON> LaBorde </PERSON>, adding that he's `` had very little success'' in getting forest service support for revegetation efforts. <PERSON> Leonard </PERSON> and the six rangers at the hearing said more money is needed to manage the wilderness areas. <PERSON> Vento </PERSON> agreed, saying that only 32 cents a year is being spent on each wilderness acre, compared to $ 6.39 per acre for general forest service lands. Since 1984, <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> has doubled the number of wilderness areas to 352. It also has doubled the wilderness budget to about $ 15 million. <PERSON> Leonard </PERSON> said, however, that this `` does n't give us the resources to get ahead.'' The rangers from the field continually emphasized one point: beyond one headquarters job in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, there are no full-time jobs as wilderness rangers and no forest service career track in wilderness management. As a result, there is little overall management planning, considerable turnover among skilled field people and little time for rangers to do much more than keep a cursory watch on the remote acreage under their domain. `` The reality of a person only working five months is that there is little planning time available,'' said <PERSON> Linda </PERSON> <PERSON> Merigliano </PERSON>, the ranger responsible for the 116,500-acre <ORGANIZATION> Jedediah </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Smith </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wilderness </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION>. She said that because of tight money, 63 percent of her trail system is substandard and deteriorating. She estimated it would cost $ 162,295 for labor and materials to repair the trails. `` Most of the impacts occurring in the <ORGANIZATION> Jedediah </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Smith </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wilderness </ORGANIZATION> result from visitor ignorance of appropriate camping and traveling behavior,'' said <PERSON> Merigliano </PERSON>, adding that she could n't get $ 50 to put together a slide show about proper camping techniques. She said that despite the requirements of the Targhee National Forest Plan, her area lacks an assessment of its campsites. <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Kirsch </PERSON>, the ranger for three areas in <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> San </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Isabel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION>, said such assessments in her areas found 85 percent of the campsites violating wilderness regulations.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880727-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-27-88 0228EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-WeaponsTests     07-27 0705</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Weapons Tests,700</SECOND>
<HEAD>Congress, Pentagon Spar Over Weapons Testing</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto WX6</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TIM AHERN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Pentagon has ignored congressional orders to do a better job of testing weapons before it invests in multimillion-dollar programs, says the watchdog arm of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. As a result, the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION>'s 5-year-old weapons testing program still can not adequately assess whether weapons would work in combat, the <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Accounting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> says. The <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION> review deals with the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION>'s Office of Operational Test and Evaluation, which was created by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> in 1983 in an attempt to do a more realistic job of testing weapons. The legislation was triggered by the discovery of serious flaws in several major weapons systems after they were well into development. The <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION> report was released Tuesday by the <ORGANIZATION> Congressional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Military </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reform </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Caucus </ORGANIZATION>, a group of 140 legislators who banded together in 1981 to seek management changes in the federal government's largest single agency. Rep. <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Fla </LOCATION>., a caucus member, told <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Carlucci </PERSON> the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> had ignored <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>' orders to test weapons `` <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> can not depend on the realism of the weapons tests, or the independence of the testing reports we receive,'' said <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON>. <PERSON> Carlucci </PERSON>, appearing at a <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Armed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> hearing, said he had n't seen the report and could n't comment on its specifics. But he then went on to criticize what he said is `` an increasing tendency on the part of members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>'' to seek <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION> reviews without giving the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> a chance to review the reports before they are released. <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Howard </PERSON>, <PERSON> Carlucci </PERSON>'s spokesman, was even more critical. `` The difficulty is that those -LRB- members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> -RRB- who do not wish to inform themselves, who very carefully guard their ignorance, obviously are not going to learn about the details of our testing programs,'' he said. Sen. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Pryor </PERSON>, D-Ark., a co-sponsor of the 1983 legislation, said: `` I am disappointed, but hardly surprised I have never seen evidence of any desire by the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> or this administration to make this office work as we in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> intended it to work.'' The <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION> reviewed the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION>'s test of six major weapons, including the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>'s Aegis air defense. That is the sophisticated tracking system involved in the July 3 shootdown by the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> cruiser <LOCATION> Vincennes </LOCATION> of an Iranian jetliner in the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION>. The Pentagon says the ship thought it was firing at an Iranian F-14 and is investigating the incident. The other weapons in the <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION> study were the <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Aquila </ORGANIZATION> drone plane; the <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>'s helicopter improvement program; <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> Tomahawk conventional cruise missile; the newest targeting system for the Air Force Maverick missile; and the Air Force LANTIRN system for night-time targeting. The <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION> concluded that there were `` significant problems and limitations in the planning, execution, realism, analysis, and service test agency reporting of the six'' programs. Some of these problems and limitations `` were unavoidable due to time, resource or safety constraints, although numerous others were not.'' The <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION> study said the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> had n't followed congressional orders to make the tests as realistic and combat-like as possible. For example, `` the prevailing problem for operational users was that they were selected from an operator pool that was atypically high in skill or experience level _ that is, so-called ` golden crews,''' the review said. Another example: In some instances contractors were permitted to help military crews maintain the weapons `` although that contractor support would not be available in the field.'' The problem was compounded by the fact that test data was often misread, the <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION> said. `` In five of six cases, we found problems with the various assumptions underlying the analyses of the test data. In at least two cases, such assumptions led to overly optimistic estimates of the system's capability, one of which was contracted by available data.'' There were other `` questionable practices'' in interpreting data and their impact `` was significant,'' the <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION> said. `` They frequently allowed a system to appear to meet its performance requirements.'' Flaws cited by the report included the fact that crews used for both the <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> helicopter tests and Maverick tests were specifically trained for the tests, rather than being normal crews; and tests of the Tomahawk occurred only over pre-tested flight routes.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880727-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-27-88 0045EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-Mecham-Fund 1stLd-Writethru a0412 07-27 0410</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Mecham-Fund, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0412,0415</SECOND>
<HEAD>Former Governor Says He Won't Turn Over Fund to State</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: SUBS 8th graf, `Mrs. Mofford's...', to CORRECT that Manager
is spokesman sted spokeswoman.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By LARRY LOPEZ</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>TUCSON, Ariz. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Former Gov. <PERSON> Evan </PERSON> <PERSON> Mecham </PERSON> on Tuesday rejected a demand by Gov. Rose Mofford that he turn over to the state a `` protocol fund'' that figured in his impeachment trial. Instead, <PERSON> Mecham </PERSON> said he planned to return the roughly $ 80,000 to those who contributed to it in the first place. The money was raised through ticket sales to <PERSON> Mecham </PERSON>'s January 1987 inaugural ball and was originally intended to help pay off some of his campaign debts. But corporations had bought some of the tickets, and state law bars corporate campaign contributions. So <PERSON> Mecham </PERSON> aides later agreed to treat the money as a kind of `` protocol fund'' to pay for gifts to visitors and similar expenses that state budgets normally do n't cover Mrs. <PERSON> Mofford </PERSON> and Attorney General <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Corbin </PERSON> contend that the agreement turned the fund into state property, and they told <PERSON> Mecham </PERSON> last week that he had until the close of business Tuesday to turn over the money or face a civil suit. But <PERSON> Mecham </PERSON> said in a speech Tuesday that he believed his solution was a better one, and spokesmen for Mrs. <PERSON> Mofford </PERSON> and <PERSON> Corbin </PERSON> said the officials were willing to negotiate further before suing. `` We are not champing at the bit to file this suit,'' said <PERSON> Corbin </PERSON> spokeswoman <PERSON> Maria </PERSON> <PERSON> Khan </PERSON>. `` We want to discuss it with people in the governor's office and Mr. <PERSON> Mecham </PERSON>'s lawyers.'' Mrs. <PERSON> Mofford </PERSON>'s spokesman, <PERSON> Vada </PERSON> <PERSON> Manager </PERSON>, said the governor `` still is following the advice of the attorney general.'' <PERSON> Mecham </PERSON> was convicted April 4 by the state <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> on impeachment charges, including one that he had misused the state funds when he loaned much of the protocol fund to his car dealership. <PERSON> Mecham </PERSON> maintained that the money was a private account even though it was being used for state purposes. And he said lending the money to his dealership allowed the fund to garner higher interest than a regular bank account would have earned. On Tuesday, <PERSON> Mecham </PERSON> said he would fight any suit but would hold off on making refunds for `` a couple of weeks'' to let <PERSON> Corbin </PERSON> file suit. <PERSON> Khan </PERSON> declined to say why <PERSON> Corbin </PERSON> did n't accept the idea of returning the money to the contributors or what compromise his office might approve.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880727-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-27-88 0246EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-China-Trade     07-27 0395</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-China-Trade,0408</SECOND>
<HEAD>US, Hong Kong Deals Help Increase Foreign Trade 20 Percent</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Sharp increases in trade with the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> helped push <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s foreign trade up nearly 20 percent in the first half of 1988, officials said today. Spokesman <PERSON> Liu </PERSON> <PERSON> Xiangdong </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Relations </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Trade </ORGANIZATION> told a news conference that trade for the period totaled $ 35.85 billion, 19.5 percent above last year's figure He said exports were up 16.1 percent to $ 20.22 billion and imports climbed 24.3 percent to $ 15.63 billion. <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s foreign trade is `` stable and healthy'' and `` demonstrated good prospects of a smooth transition from the old system to the new,'' <PERSON> Liu </PERSON> said. <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> is decentralizing controls over its foreign trade and trying to develop export industries while confining imports to machinery and high technology items that will help in the nation's modernization drive `` The unchecked importation of production lines and high durable consumer goods was basically controlled,'' <PERSON> Liu </PERSON> said. He said that through May, <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s trade with the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> was $ 2.89 billion, up 26.3 percent from the first five months of 1987. Trade with the <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> region totaled $ 7.54 billion, up 35.5 percent. Trade with <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> was $ 5.49 billion, up 8 percent; with the <ORGANIZATION> European </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Community </ORGANIZATION> $ 3.775 billion, up 3.5 percent; and with the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> $ 1 billion, up 32.1 percent, <PERSON> Liu </PERSON> said. The ministry's figures differed from those released this month by the Customs Office, which showed <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> with a trade deficit of slightly more than $ 1 billion on total trade of $ 43.2 billion. <PERSON> Liu </PERSON> said the two offices have different ways of calculating goods imported and then processed for export. He said his ministry does not include imports of equipment by foreign-funded enterprises that will be used to produce goods for export. <PERSON> Liu </PERSON> also said 2,109 foreign-funded enterprises were approved in the first half of the year, an increase of 186 percent over January-June 1987. He said the value of those contracts was $ 2 billion, up 130 percent. Projects funded by investors in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> jumped from 34 last year to 85 this year, <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> from 39 to 85, <LOCATION> Singapore </LOCATION> from 20 to 36, <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> from three to 13 and <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> from three to 10. <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> continued to lead foreign investors with 79 percent of projects and 67 percent of money invested.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880727-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-27-88 0248EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a BC-Opera     07-27 0308</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Opera,0320</SECOND>
<HEAD>NY City Opera Has New `Rigoletto'</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: No PMs Planned</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By MARY CAMPBELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Opera </LOCATION>'s new production of `` Rigoletto'' made a favorable first impression Tuesday night at the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Theater </ORGANIZATION>, helped by a high caliber of singing. Tenor <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Leech </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Binghamtom </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION>, who played the Duke, has a golden voice and thrilled the audience as he held the last note of his biggest aria. His Duke was more like a heedless college man than a hardened womanizer. It was easy to understand how <PERSON> Gilda </PERSON> could stay in love with him even after two betrayals. <PERSON> Leech </PERSON> made his <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Opera </LOCATION> debut in 1984 and this year won the <ORGANIZATION> Richard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tucker </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Award </ORGANIZATION> and will make his Metropolitan Opera debut. <PERSON> Faith </PERSON> <PERSON> Esham </PERSON>, whose voice is clear and whose presentation is much more lyric than coloratura, was an exceedingly pure but human and agreeable <PERSON> Gilda </PERSON>. <PERSON> Frederick </PERSON> <PERSON> Burchinal </PERSON>, whose baritone is clear and interesting, played a middle-range Rigoletto. His characterization was not passionate, and one did not feel enormously sorry for this Rigoletto when his troubles began, then compounded. <PERSON> Tito </PERSON> <PERSON> Capobianco </PERSON> devised and directed the production. Some staging innovations work well: Rigoletto's patio in Scene 2 is upstairs on the bedroom level of his house; Act 3 has <PERSON> Sparafucile </PERSON>'s Inn near the front of the stage, which places singers forward, where they can project A bridge indicates the river into which Rigoletto intends to dump the <ORGANIZATION> Duke </ORGANIZATION>'s body after <PERSON> Sparafucile </PERSON> murders him. The bridge connects to upstairs rooms in the inn. The Duke not only sings from his inn bedroom, making Rigoletto realize he's alive, but casually walks away across the bridge, right in front of Rigoletto, a nice touch. <PERSON> Elio </PERSON> <PERSON> Boncompagni </PERSON> conducted the Verdi melodies that dance even while the plot turns tragic.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880727-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-27-88 0250EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--Britain-Arts     07-27 0129</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Britain-Arts,0131</SECOND>
<HEAD>Britain's Arts Generate $17 Billion A Year</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The arts are a $ 17 billion-a-year sector of the British economy and one-fourth of the country's tourist income is spent on cultural activity, a non-profit institute reported today. The report by the <ORGANIZATION> Policy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Studies </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> says the arts account for 2.5 percent of all spending on goods and services in <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> and directly employ 496,000 people, or 2.1 percent of the work force. `` The Economic Importance of the Arts in <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'' says 27 percent of the $ 9.2 billion spent annually by overseas visitors in <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> is connected to arts attractions. The three-year, four-volume study is being sent to the government, local councils, private business, tourism authorities, arts organizations and private foundations that helped to fund it.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880727-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-27-88 0251EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Drought-Casinos Bjt   07-27 0632</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Drought-Casinos, Bjt,0654</SECOND>
<HEAD>Nevada's Tourism Industry Turns Down Taps as Drought Deepens</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TOM GARDNER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>RENO, Nev. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Most restaurants in this desert resort serve water on request only, towering hotel-casinos have reduced the flow from thousands of showerheads and a showroom elephant waits longer for her bath to be changed. The drought has come home to <PERSON> Reno </PERSON>, but its slot machine bells still jangle and chips still fly across its felt gambling tables. In fact, the drought that has stunned the nation's midsection with its severity has n't surprised hotel owners here. After two consecutive years in which the area has received half its scant 7.5-inch annual precipitation, <PERSON> Reno </PERSON> is in a Stage One drought alert, calling for voluntary cutbacks in water use. Stage Two, which mandates some unenforced reductions, is expected by mid-August. Unlike <LOCATION> Las </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vegas </LOCATION>, where the <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> provides more than enough water to the casinos and their shimmering fountains, <PERSON> Reno </PERSON> depends almost solely on runoff from winter snow in the <LOCATION> Sierra </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION> for its summer water. And the snow is gone. Restaurants, hotel-casinos and other businesses here typically have been watchful of their water use, partly because they pay for every drop. `` Our per-person use is half that of residential consumption,'' said <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON> <PERSON> McCormick </PERSON>, chief engineer at the Peppermill Hotel Casino. <PERSON> McCormick </PERSON> estimates that water-saving conversions at the year-old hotel tower have produced a minimum savings of 3 million to 4 million gallons of water annually for little more than the cost of the time it took to make them. While some hotels here and at <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Tahoe </LOCATION> have installed restricted-flow shower heads and water-saving toilets, <PERSON> McCormick </PERSON> opted to modify the existing fixtures. `` You do n't have to spend a lot of money,'' he said. `` People go out and buy a lot of gadgets they do n't need.'' He cut back the Peppermill's water use by putting smaller washers in shower heads and reducing pressure in the taps. Lower water levels in hotel toilets cut consumption from 6 gallons per flush to 4, he said. Outdoor watering was decreased by replacing thirsty plants with decorative rocks or vegetation better suited to the desert. At <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Ascuaga </PERSON>'s Nugget in nearby <PERSON> Sparks </PERSON>, all outside plants are watered by drip irrigation installed during the past year, according to spokesman Art Long. The Nugget, like other local hotels, recycles water in air conditioning cooling towers and loads dishwashers completely before starting them. Conservation even has affected <PERSON> Bertha </PERSON>, the Nugget's trained elephant who warms up showroom crowds for entertainers like <PERSON> Red </PERSON> <PERSON> Skelton </PERSON> and <PERSON> Shirley </PERSON> <PERSON> MacLaine </PERSON>. `` We used to clean and drain her pool twice a week. Now it's down to once a week And the water that's pumped out is used to water the lawn and foilage around <PERSON> Bertha </PERSON>'s Elephant Palace,'' <PERSON> Long </PERSON> said. Homeowners, however, successfully fought efforts to require water meters. They pay a flat monthly fee regardless of how much water they use. New homes are required to have water meters, but there still are nearly 50,000 with virtually unlimited water use. `` Hotel-casinos are not the biggest users. I think they take a bad rap,'' said <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Firth </PERSON>, water resources manager for <ORGANIZATION> Westpac </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Utilities </ORGANIZATION>. Businesses use only 22 percent of the 90 million gallons or so his company pumps out daily, <PERSON> Firth </PERSON> said. By comparison, he said, 47 percent of the daily summertime use goes for watering lawns and hedges. The Reno area's last prolonged dry spell was in 1976-77, and even though those years were a little wetter than the past two, `` we got through kind of by the skin of our teeth,'' <PERSON> Firth </PERSON> said. `` The difference between now and 1976-77 is that we've had a 33 percent growth rate,'' <PERSON> Firth </PERSON> said. `` Measures may have to be a lot more drastic than they were at that time.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880727-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-27-88 0255EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Dukakis     07-27 0601</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Dukakis,600</SECOND>
<HEAD>Dukakis Criticizes Reagan, Bush on Meese, Iran-Contra, Other
Issues</HEAD>
