<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880325-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-25-88 2331EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p AM-Bush 2ndLd-Writethru a0824 03-25 0776</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Bush, 2nd Ld-Writethru, a0824,760</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush Sticks To Game Plan; Says It Is Too Soon To Consider Running
Mates</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDs: Subs 9th graf bgng: He mentioned ... to CORRECT spelling of
Deukmejian.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By DEBBIE NEWBY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>DENVER (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Vice President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, far ahead of Sen. <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> in the race for the Republican presidential nomination, said Friday he will stick to his game plan in the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> campaign and declared, `` It's too early for me to start thinking about any running mates.'' With the latest <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> tally showing <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> with 788 delegates to <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>'s 178, <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> was downbeat as he told the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chamber </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, `` I think it's probably a foregone conclusion what's happening on the Republican side.'' The <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> senator, telling reporters, `` I can read the numbers and I know probably what's going to happen,'' suggested he was re-evaluating his campaign, but his spokesman said the candidate is n't ready to abandon the race. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, after a speech at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Denver </ORGANIZATION>, said, `` I do n't see any reason to change any game plan that we have.'' The vice president added: `` This does n't say it's over. So I'm going to just keep going right down to the wire and not speculate on somebody else's campaign or on the Democratic side.'' Asked whether he would consider <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> as a running mate, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said, `` It's too early for me to start thinking about any running mates. That would project a certain arrogance or presumption that I do n't want to do.'' He commented after addressing an estimated 1,000 supporters who went to a fieldhouse to see <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and his family and have a lunch of chili, crackers, brownies, iced tea and lemonade. Meanwhile in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> chief of staff <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> was asked on <ORGANIZATION> Cable </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Network </ORGANIZATION>'s `` <ORGANIZATION> Evans </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> Novak </PERSON>'' if he would accept the vice presidency if <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> turned to him. `` It's not just going to happen. That is n't going to occur,'' <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> said. `` <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> needs to find someone who will bring strength to the ticket on a regional and political basis, and I think that is not going to be me.'' He mentioned former <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Lamar </PERSON> <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON>, <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Deukmejian </PERSON>, and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Kean </PERSON> as good choices for the vice presidential slot. Despite this, when pressed as to whether he would refuse the position if it was offered, <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> said, `` I did n't say that. Nobody says that who spent 20 years in politics. `` You know, most of my adult life I've spent in public service, and if someone asked me to do it, I would have a very difficult time trying to figure out what I was going to say,'' he said. `` But I do not wish that to happen. I do not think that will happen, and I do not expect it.'' Earlier in the day, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> arrived at the <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Springs </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Municipal </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION> where he spoke briefly to about 300 people before flying to <ORGANIZATION> Buckley </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Base </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Aurora </LOCATION> and going by motorcade to <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> stopped in <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION> in a search for support in the state's April 4 <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> caucuses The Democratic and Republican presidential nominees will represent the `` difference between night and day,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said at the university. `` The country does not want to swing left to that Democratic gloom-and-doom liberal philosophy, and we're not going to do it,'' he said. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> told reporters he is unsure whether the cease-fire agreement in <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> will work. `` I am skeptical,'' he said. `` I hope it works. I hope peace can come and with it, democracy and freedom. Those two have to be together.'' `` You ca n't have a peace that ends up with the Soviets ending up with a base in <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>. The <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> people are not as supportive of our initiatives with the Contras as I'd like to think the facts dictate. But they are strongly supportive of the concept, overwhelming so, that the Soviets should not have another stronghold in this hemisphere,'' he said. In <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Springs </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> pledged strong support for the Strategic Defense Initiative or `` Star Wars'' space defense program, which is being developed in that city. `` Is n't it better to put weapons at risk rather than human lives at risk?'' he asked. `` We can do it technologically.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> also brushed aside questions involving the Iran-Contra affair and what impact it would have on his political future, saying Americans are not concerned about that issue. `` The Democrats are short of real issues, bringing it up over and over again. No one is even suggesting I have done anything wrong,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880325-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-25-88 0214EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-US-Australia     03-25 0501</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-US-Australia,500</SECOND>
<HEAD>Linkletter Preparing for Brisbane Expo</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GENE KRAMER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The top American representative at <LOCATION> Brisbane </LOCATION>'s Expo'88 will be one of the few Americans who can claim to be a specialist in both world's fairs and in <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION> <PERSON> Art </PERSON> <PERSON> Linkletter </PERSON> is preparing to travel Down Under to play his new role of commissioner general of the American pavilion, with the rank of ambassador. `` I have a background of half a dozen years in world's fairs, which is really very unusual, because it's not what you might call a regular profession,'' the veteran radio and television entertainer said at a news conference Thursday. A half century ago, he said, he left a comfortable job at a <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> radio station to spend `` a very happy seven or eight months'' organizing radio events at the San Diego-Pacific International Exposition. That led to a similar job at the <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> Centennial in <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION> and finally to more than two years at the <ORGANIZATION> San </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Francisco </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION>'s Fair on the eve of World War II. <PERSON> Linkletter </PERSON> started acquiring his Australian expertise with a `` great fiasco,'' he said, participating in a rice-growing venture in the bush near <LOCATION> Darwin </LOCATION> that became a kitchen for millions of crop-devouring geese. But he stayed on to operate sheep and cattle stations that took him to <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION> annually for the past 30 years. `` I know <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION> quite well,'' he said, `` I am very, very fond of Australians and the whole country.'' The April 30-Oct. 30 <LOCATION> Brisbane </LOCATION> exposition will `` give a fresh look to world's fairs'' with its theme of leisure and technology, he said This is especially appropriate, since Australians spend the most of any country on sports, equipment `` and the fun of sports,'' <PERSON> Linkletter </PERSON> said. The theme of the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> pavilion is sports and sports science. <PERSON> Linkletter </PERSON>, 75, said his own devotion to fitness and daily exercise further qualifies him for the <LOCATION> Brisbane </LOCATION> post. He said he skis six weeks a year, swims and plays tennis but has not yet taken up golf because `` I'm not old enough.'' In show business he directed or appeared in a series of successful radio and tv programs including `` People are Funny,'' `` Art <PERSON> Linkletter </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>,'' and `` Kids Say the Darndest Things.'' He has written several books, including `` Linkletter Down Under,'' about <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION>, and the most recent, `` Old Age is Not for Sissies.''' In addition to sports industry exhibits, and daily demonstrations of gymnastics and smaller team sports at <LOCATION> Brisbane </LOCATION>, `` we are going to have such things as deaf basketball players and wheelchair'' athletes in demonstrations of sports for the handicapped plus continuous workshops in many areas of amateur and professional sports and recreation, he said. Arrangements may be made for some <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> stars of the <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION> Olympics to appear at <LOCATION> Brisbane </LOCATION> on their way home from <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Linkletter </PERSON> said. Also there will be a modern health club, along with marching bands and many <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> groups `` who are raising their own money and paying their way,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880325-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-25-88 0222EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FarmScene     03-25 0986</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Farm Scene,980</SECOND>
<HEAD>`Real' Price Of Wheat Lowest Since Revolution</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DON KENDALL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Farm Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> economist says farmers could be forced to accept the squeeze between costs and prices as a permanent way of life if wheat price trends are an indicator of how the farm economy may develop in the future. <PERSON> Clark </PERSON> <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON> of the department's <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> says farmers `` make more money when they become more efficient, they expand, or their terms of trade improve.'' Advances in technology have boosted yields of crops and livestock. Farms have gotten larger because of people leaving the land. But prices farmers get in relation to costs have tended downward over the years. Thus, <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON> said, two of the three ingredients for profitability have been working for farmers. But the third _ prices _ has worked against them. That results in the `` cost-price squeeze'' that has chewed on the farm economy for generations. <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON>, who is economics editor of Agricultural Outlook magazine, examined the price history of a single commodity _ wheat _ since 1800. Rising prices reflected growth in domestic and export demand from the beginning of the 19th century through the Civil War, which included inflated prices triggered by shortages during the 1861-65 war years. `` From then on, for more than a century, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> agriculture has shown a capacity to grow faster than its markets, and the trend in real wheat prices has been downward, with cycles from wars and depressions,'' <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON> said. In economic parlance, the `` real'' price of a commodity includes an adjustment for inflation. The `` nominal'' price does not include an inflation adjustment. During World War I, wheat prices spiked higher, but still were below the Civil War peak. In the 1920s, wheat prices declined as a farm depression took hold. Further downward pressure came in the Great Depression of the 1930s. Wheat prices rose again in World War II but were still below the levels of World War I. `` The real price -LRB- of wheat -RRB- fell from its World War II high throughout most of the 1950s and 1960s,'' <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON> said. `` There was a gradual downtrend in the nominal price, and inflation picked up, particularly since 1965.'' But prices received by farmers in the'50s and'60s were steadied by `` massive government programs'' which boosted the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> domestic price of wheat above the world price, he said. As fears of global hunger and grain shortages developed in the early 1970s, wheat prices were driven up to record levels and heralded a return to wide annual fluctuations, <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON> said. Even so, the real price of wheat at its 1973 peak was below the World War II high point. Wheat prices dropped in 1986, reflecting changes in federal supports authorized by the 1985 farm law, he said. That allowed lower market prices to induce more export and domestic use, while maintaining farm income through direct payments to growers. `` The price is edging up a little this year,'' <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON> said. `` Even so, the real price of wheat is well below what it was at the depth of the depressed 1930s, and the lowest it has been since Revolutionary times. At the same time, wheat yield per acre now is about three times what it was in the 1930s, and the wheat acreage per farm growing wheat is 10 times what it was.'' <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON> acknowldged that wheat accounts for `` a small percentage of total food outlays'' by American consumers and that the margin between the farm value of wheat and the final food product has been growing as a result of higher transportation, processing, packaging and other costs. `` Therefore, a stable consumer price is consistent with a decreasing wheat price,'' he said. `` Even so, wars, depressions and food crises are reflected in the price of wheat, and the price of wheat may be a useful proxy for long-run farm and food price trends.'' If that is the case, <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON> said those who think that farm prices in the coming decades will rise relative to costs `` are calling for a fundamental change in the long-run trend.'' He added: `` It would appear more reasonable to expect farmers -LRB- and help them when necessary -RRB- to continue to find ways to make a living in the face of prospective long-run cost price squeeze, as they have done for the last century.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Existing organizations and private funds could help the federal government move ahead in rural development, says <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Bergland </PERSON>, executive vice president and general manager of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Electric </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cooperative </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>. A partnership between private and public interests is necessary because rural communities must not be left behind as the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> economy continues to change and grow, he told the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Budget </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> on Thursday. `` Unfortunately, many of these communities have experienced rapid declines during the last several years,'' <PERSON> Bergland </PERSON> said in his statement. Loss of population, sluggish job growth, high unemployment or underemployment, poverty and an education gap were cited as major problems. <PERSON> Bergland </PERSON>, who was secretary of agriculture in the <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> administration, said the association he represents is an example of existing networks that can be used to help with rural development. The <LOCATION> NRECA </LOCATION>, he said, provides service to 25 million people in 2,600 counties in 46 states. `` Today, the problems facing many rural communities have spurred electric cooperatives to increase their initiatives and activities in community and economic development,'' he said. <PERSON> Bergland </PERSON> recommended that the <ORGANIZATION> Rural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Electrification </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> in the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> be authorized to make financing available to REA borrowers for rural development of business, industry and public works. <PERSON> REA </PERSON> is the federal government's chief lending agency for the rural electric and telephone cooperatives. The financial assistance could take the form of guarantees, loans, grants and the ability to create private revolving funds, he said. REA borrowers then could be encouraged to put together financial packages that would `` leverage federal funds with private capital.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880325-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-25-88 0221EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-AlienBoxcars     03-25 0284</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Alien Boxcars,0293</SECOND>
<HEAD>Border Patrol Finds Dehydrated Aliens In Sealed Boxcars</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOEL WILLIAMS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>HARLINGEN, Texas (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A special sweep of railroad traffic is credited with rescuing illegal aliens from possible suffocation in airtight boxcars, <ORGANIZATION> Border </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Patrol </ORGANIZATION> agents say. `` We feel that at least some of them would not have made it to <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Silvestre </PERSON> <PERSON> Reyes </PERSON>, chief of the <ORGANIZATION> Border </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Patrol </ORGANIZATION>'s <PERSON> McAllen </PERSON> <PERSON> Sector </PERSON>, said Thursday. The 46 aliens, some of them dehydrated, had been crouched in a four-foot-high space in the boxcar about seven hours when discovered with the aid of dogs, <PERSON> Reyes </PERSON> said. `` Many of them were happy that they were finally out of that place, and said they were concerned that they were going to die in there,'' he said. Agents this week have been searching nearly every train car at a stop about six miles north of <LOCATION> Harlingen </LOCATION>. By Thursday the crackdown had netted 370 undocumented aliens and 120 pounds of marijuana, the patrol said. `` We identified three particular -LRB- smuggling -RRB- organizations out of this,'' <PERSON> Reyes </PERSON> said. In discovering the dehydrated group in the sealed car, along with 16 more in two other cars, he said agents probably averted a tragedy similar to the incident last summer in the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> town of <LOCATION> Sierra </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Blanca </LOCATION>. Agents there found 18 aliens suffocated to death inside a sealed boxcar. Although temperatures in the lower <LOCATION> Rio </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Grande </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION> have ranged in the 50s this week, the temperature inside the boxcar with 46 people in it was around 90 degrees, and would have become hotter, <PERSON> Reyes </PERSON> said. The group rescued Monday was dehydrated, but did not require hospitalization, <PERSON> Reyes </PERSON> said. More than 100 aliens escaped during the train raids, agents reported.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880325-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-25-88 0221EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-People-Garagiola     03-25 0168</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-People-Garagiola,0175</SECOND>
<HEAD>Pressed for Security Gate, Now Home Is Robbed</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PARADISE VALLEY, Ariz. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Garagiola </PERSON> lost his 1946 World Series ring and other jewelry in a break-in at his home two days after the baseball announcer pressed the <ORGANIZATION> Town </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> to allow security gates. <PERSON> Garagiola </PERSON>, 62, and his family were home at the time Wednesday night but heard nothing, they said. The burglar got in by breaking a window in the closet of the master bedroom and took $ 200,000 in jewelry from a chest in the closet, said police Sgt. <PERSON> Ron </PERSON> <PERSON> Warner </PERSON>. The items stolen included the former <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Louis </LOCATION> catcher's Series ring from 1946, the year the <ORGANIZATION> Cardinals </ORGANIZATION> beat the <ORGANIZATION> Boston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sox </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Warner </ORGANIZATION> said. On Monday night, <PERSON> Garagiola </PERSON> pressed officials of this affluent <LOCATION> Phoenix </LOCATION> suburb to amend rules against security gates at subdivision entrances. <LOCATION> Paradise </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION> and two unincorporated luxury communities within it have been hit by at least 15 similar burglaries since January, police said. The Council agreed to study the proposal.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880325-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-25-88 0738EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Dukakis-Advantage     03-25 0814</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Dukakis-Advantage,820</SECOND>
<HEAD>Dukakis Working To Lay To Rest Talk Of Brokered Convention</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID ESPO</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Democratic presidential contender <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, with a widening edge in the delegate race, is working to lay to rest talk of a brokered Democratic National Convention. As the campaign for the Democratic presidential nomination moves into a springtime series of Northern and Midwestern state contests, aides to the <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> governor are laying plans to drive the rest of the Democrats out of the race. `` It's conceivable we could have a nominating majority by the day after <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>,'' which is among the states to vote on the last day of the primary season June 8, says <PERSON> Tad </PERSON> <PERSON> Devine </PERSON>, a senior campaign aide. More optimistic aides paint a scenario that would effectively clinch the nomination earlier. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' rivals concede his superior organization, finances, fresh endorsements and other advantages. `` There's no state that's life and death for <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>,'' says <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> <PERSON> Michael </PERSON>, a spokesman for Sen. <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Simon </PERSON>, adding that most of the other contenders face make-or-break elections in the next few weeks But, they quickly add, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> and his message of managerial competence in the <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> statehouse have yet to stir the emotions of Democrats around the country, and a few bumps might be all it takes to shatter his candidacy. `` I think his lack of a message of what a <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> administration would do is catching up with him,'' says <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>, spokesman for Rep. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON>. `` They have n't captured the hearts of Democrats. All they've been able to do is convince many that they're a safe bet,'' says <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> aide <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> `` They have been moving along picking up delegates on tactics, not on message.'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' aides insist their candidate has a sound campaign message. But they also argue tactics, saying that Vice President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s apparently secure Republican nomination is cooling the enthusiasm for a brokered Democratic convention. `` The fear of giving <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> a head start is eventually going to help somebody, and if we do our job right, that person is going to be <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>,'' says <PERSON> Leslie </PERSON> <PERSON> Dach </PERSON>, communications director. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' blueprint for the nomination calls for defeating <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> in Saturday's <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION> caucuses and driving him from the race. Next, aides seek a victory over <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION> on April 5, driving him from the race. They hope to follow up with victories in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> or <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> that cripple Sen. <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, even if he remains a candidate. That would leave <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, but <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' aides believe he is n't likely to win more than 900 or so delegates, out of 2,082 needed to gain the nomination. They say <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> is prepared to outline differences over policy issues with <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> later in the year, particularly over the <LOCATION> Mideast </LOCATION> and defense spending. During the period between <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>'s primary on April 19 and <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> a week later, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' aides hope that many of the 645 `` super delegates'' to the convention _ the party leaders, members of members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and governors _ will swing to their side. There is no disputing the strides <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> has made since he fell to third place in <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION>: _ He has 533.55 delegates according to a count by The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>, an increase of 69 in the past week. <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, his nearest pursuer, has 511.55, an increase of 51. But <PERSON> Gore </PERSON>, who has 360.8 overall, has added only six in that time, while <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON>, at 154, has added only nine. <PERSON> Simon </PERSON>, the <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> winner, has 171.5 delegates, 141 of them from <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION>. _ <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> has been endorsed since the <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> primary by five senators, 10 congressmen and a governor. The biggest prize, Sen. <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON> of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION>, has been mentioned prominently as a possible compromise candidate in case of a deadlocked convention this summer. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> and the other contenders continue to vie for support from <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Mario </PERSON> <PERSON> Cuomo </PERSON>. _ Recent national public opinion polls show <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> running strongly against <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. A nationwide survey conducted for <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> showed <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> leading the vice president 50 percent to 45 percent. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> led <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> and <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> in similar matchups. _ He won the <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> caucuses a few days after <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> voted, his first triumph in a predominantly agricultural state. However, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' rivals say his finish in <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> _ where he got 17 percent of the vote behind favorite sons <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, and no delegates _ is symptomatic of a failure to attract widepsread support to his candidacy. They say he has particularly failed to demonstrate appeal among blue collar workers and conservative Democrats who will be essential to Democratic chances of capturing the White House. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> also stands accused of flip-flopping on a key issue, belatedly embracing trade legislation to make himself more appealing to the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Autoworkers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION> members who will participate in Saturday's <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION> caucuses.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880325-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-25-88 2354EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p PM-US-Deleg-Sum     03-25 0577</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-US-Deleg-Sum,100</SECOND>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here is the current breakdown of the presidential preference of the delegates to the Democratic and Republican National Conventions. The preferences are based on actual delegate's public statements or binding state laws or party rules. The first column shows the total number of delegates for each candidate; subsequent columns show the delegates gained or lost during the last 30 days.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>DEMOCRATIC</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Total Changes Friday 7days 30days <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> 548.55 +15 +67 +504 <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> 154 0 +9 +115 <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> 362.8 +2 +5 +352 <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> 520.55 +9 +51 +511 <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> 171.5 0 0 +139 Uncommitted 354.6 +7 +82 +81 Others 0 0 0 -4
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 Needed to nominate 2,082 Total Delegate Votes 4,163
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 Chosen thus far 2,112 Yet to be chosen 2,051
</TEXT>
<HEAD>REPUBLICAN</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Total Changes Friday 7days 30days <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> 788 0 +14 +727 <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> 178 0 0 +118 <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> 17 0 0 +9 Uncommitted 72 0 0 +62 Others 0 0 0 0
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 Needed to nominate 1,139 Total Delegate Votes 2,277
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 Chosen thus far 1,055 Yet to be chosen 1,222
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880325-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-25-88 2355EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Panama 3rdLd-Writethru a0828 03-25 0823</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Panama, 3rd Ld-Writethru, a0828,0848</SECOND>
<HEAD>Panamanian Military Reportedly Unpaid; Shops Ordered To Open</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: SUBS grafs 19-20 pvs, `It did not ...' with 1 graf to CORRECT
that only one decree issued, sted of two as sent. PICKS up 21st
graf pvs bgng, It said store...</NOTE>
<BYLINE>REID G. MILLER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PANAMA, Panama (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The armed forces that keep Gen. <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> in power went unpaid Friday and the broke and beleaguered government ordered businesses closed in the general strike to reopen. In a decree issued under a week-old state of emergency, the civilian government that does <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>'s bidding said it would take away the commercial licenses of any businesses `` offering goods and services to the public'' if they remained closed. The decree specifically mentioned grocery stores, pharmacies, transportation companies and gasoline stations. An estimated 90 percent of <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s industry and businesses have shut down in the strike that began Monday in an effort to force <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>'s removal as the head of the 15,000-member Defense Forces that includes the military and police. The government's inability to pay the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forces </ORGANIZATION> kindled hopes in the opposition that loyalty for him will wane. Several members of the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forces </ORGANIZATION>, including a secretary at military headquarters, said army, <ORGANIZATION> navy </ORGANIZATION>, police and air force personnel did not receive their semi-monthly paychecks as scheduled Friday. `` We did not receive our wages and we were not told when we would receive them,'' said the secretary, who declined to give her name. Soldiers questioned by reporters also said they had not been paid. In mid-March, most of the 130,000 public employees were given partial payment of at least $ 75 on their salaries. Those employees whose monthly salaries are $ 1,000 or more were not paid. Social security checks have been postponed. Demonstrators at the Roman Catholic cathedral protested the church's failure to issue a denunciation of <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> as expected. Pilots who guide ships through the <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Canal </LOCATION> and claimed they had been harassed by soldiers in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> demanded protection and met with the <ORGANIZATION> Panama </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Canal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION>. Some pilots had spoken of a strike, but commission spokesman <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Castrellon </PERSON> said the situation was resolved at the meeting. He did not elaborate. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Maher </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> Panama </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Canal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pilots </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, said: `` There is no problem now.'' <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> remained obstinate. He was asked at a military ceremony about President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s renewed call for his departure and he replied: `` My president is called -LRB- <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> -RRB- <PERSON> Solis </PERSON> <PERSON> Palma </PERSON> and my geographic space is called <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> I do n't take orders from extra-terrestrials.'' <PERSON> Solis </PERSON> <PERSON> Palma </PERSON> was named chief executive by the legislature when President <PERSON> Eric </PERSON> <PERSON> Arturo </PERSON> <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON> was ousted on Feb. 26, the day after he tried to fire <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>. Two members of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Affairs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, Reps. <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Ackerman </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.Y. </LOCATION>, and <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kostmayer </PERSON>, D-Pa., ended a two-day visit Friday and told a news conference they thought the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration should increase economic pressure on <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> is under indictment in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> on narcotics charges. The <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration has cut the flow of money to <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>, which uses the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> dollar as its currency. The order for businesses to reopen was in Decree No. 16 issued under the state of emergency that enables the government to act as it deems necessary `` to secure public order,'' including suspending civil liberties. The decree also said any establishment that had been closed for the past five days and sold food, meats or canned goods `` can not reopen unless it is first inspected by the <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION>.'' It said store owners who do not comply face `` temporary suspension of their licenses or, in case of repeated violations, the cancellation of their commercial licenses.'' The strike began Monday and was called by the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Civic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Crusade </ORGANIZATION>, a broad alliance of <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>'s opposition. Crusade leaders said it would continue until <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> was ousted. <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Canal </LOCATION> employees have worked throughout protests and general strikes against <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> that began last June. The canal continues to operate normally while the nation around the waterway is at a virtual standstill. Most of the canal's 230 pilots are American citizens. Soldiers man roadblocks around the capital and they demand identification from drivers, search cars and rummage through personal belongings. Some pilots complained about those actions. About 100 people stalked out of the cathedral after Archbishop <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> McGrath </PERSON> opened a special Mass by telling worshipers and observers the church would not issue the anticipated anti-Noriega statement. `` We do n't know how this mistaken rumor originated,'' <PERSON> McGrath </PERSON> said. `` We are sorry, but it is not our fault.'' Civic Crusade leaders and <PERSON> Ackerman </PERSON> had said they had been assured the church would issue a strong condemnation of <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>. Those who walked out stood on the steps of the gray stone cathedral chanting, `` Justice! Justice!'' and `` <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> must go!'' <PERSON> McGrath </PERSON> told those remaining inside that he and <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> had a `` preparatory meeting'' Thursday. He did not explain and said he could not discuss the conversation.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880325-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-25-88 0237EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-ArmsTreaty     03-25 0656</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Arms Treaty,640</SECOND>
<HEAD>Administration, Lawmakers Remain Divided Over Future
Interpretation</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TIM AHERN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats and Republicans on the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Relations </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> are trying to settle the one major dispute left before the panel approves the U.S.-Soviet treaty eliminating medium-range nuclear missiles. `` I think we'll be able to agree on something,'' said Sen. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Lugar </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Ind </LOCATION>., leader of a group of Republicans who are seeking a compromise on the issue of how treaties are legally intepreted `` That is the only major question left and I would expect that we can solve it by next week,'' Sen. <PERSON> Claiborne </PERSON> <PERSON> Pell </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-R.I. </LOCATION>, chairman of the committee, said Thursday. The panel spent three days this week rejecting a series of challenges by conservative Republicans to the Intermediate-range Nuclear Forces treaty and has set Tuesday afternoon for a final vote on the pact. <PERSON> Pell </PERSON> and other Democratic leaders have predicted overwhelming approval, both in the committee next week and by the full <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> next month when the Democratic-controlled chamber returns from an Easter recess. Ratification requires the approval of 67 of the 100 senators. The remaining fight centers on the dispute between the legislative and executive branches over the authority to interpret treaties. The disagreement arises from President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s assertion that his administration can unilaterally change the intepretation of the 1972 Anti-Ballistic Missile treaty, a contention the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> disputes. <PERSON> Pell </PERSON> and other Democrats want some type of condition on the INF treaty that would block a future administration from changing the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> interpretation of the pact. <PERSON> Lugar </PERSON> said one compromise being considered is attaching an amendment to the ratification resolution which says the INF treaty can not be reinterpreted by a future administration without prior consent of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>. `` That is one ay to solve it and remove the fight from this treaty without coming to a final answer on the intepretation issue,'' said <PERSON> Lugar </PERSON>. The treaty was signed Dec. 8 by <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and Soviet leader <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>. It requires the elimination within three years of all missiles with a range of 300 to 3,400 miles. Anti-cheating provisions _ the strictest in arms control history _ include provisions for on-site inspections by each superpower in the other country. In the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>, the treaty has been criticized chiefly by conservative Republicans, including Sens. <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Helms </PERSON> of <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Pressler </PERSON> of <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> officials are preparing for an unusual secret session of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> early next week to examine sensitive intelligence information about the number of SS-20 medium-range missiles possessed by the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. A total of 650 were declared by the Soviets and those will be destroyed after the treaty takes effect. But <PERSON> Helms </PERSON> claims there are conflicting estimates by <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> intelligence agencies about the number of missiles, including one report by the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Intelligence </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> that the Soviets may have up to 300 more SS-20s than they have declared. The Foreign Relations panel voted 15-2 Thursday to reject <PERSON> Helms </PERSON>' amendment requiring new intelligence analyses of the SS-20 question Only <PERSON> Helms </PERSON> and <PERSON> Pressler </PERSON> supported his proposal which would have required <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> to certify the accuracy of the Soviet claims that they only have 650 SS-20s. The closed-door session will take place in the Capitol's Old Senate Chamber, according to <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Majority Leader <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON>, D-W. The small, historic room is normally maintained as a museum, but <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON> said it is better for the meeting than the current <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> chamber. The new <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> is laced with a variety of cables that make it more difficult to protect security, <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON> explained. Later, the committee also rejected, 15-2, <PERSON> Pressler </PERSON>'s plan to block implementation of the treaty until <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> certifies that <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> wo n't be jeopardized by the Soviets' advantage in a variety of non-nuclear weapons. <PERSON> Helms </PERSON> originally had 36 amendments, but dropped the majority of them after only <PERSON> Pressler </PERSON> supported his proposals. <PERSON> Pressler </PERSON> also dropped some of his challenges in the face of widespread rejection.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880325-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-25-88 0240EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-S&amp;LLosses     03-25 0689</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-S&amp;L Losses,680</SECOND>
<HEAD>Industry Says Southwestern Thrifts Have Caused Heavy Losses</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVE SKIDMORE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The heaviest savings institution losses since the Great Depression underscore the need for federal regulators to begin cleaning up the mire of insolvent institutions in the <ORGANIZATION> Southwest </ORGANIZATION>, savings and loan lobby groups say. The <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Home </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Loan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> said Thursday that the nation's 3,147 savings institutions lost $ 3.2 billion in the fourth quarter of 1987, pushing red ink for the year to $ 6.8 billion, the worst loss since the agency began keeping track in 1934 `` I hope it's the worst we'll ever see,'' said <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Christian </PERSON>, chief economist of the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> League </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Savings </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Insitutions </ORGANIZATION>, the industry's largest trade group. The bank board said S & amp; L losses were heavily concentrated in states like <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION>, which are dependent on the ailing oil and gas industry. The worst 20 institutions _ most of them in the <ORGANIZATION> Southwest </ORGANIZATION> _ lost a total of $ 2.1 billion in the final quarter of last year, accounting for two-thirds of the overall industry loss. `` The No. 1 item on the agenda is to stop the bleeding in the <LOCATION> Southwest </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Christian </PERSON> said. `` That's in the bank board's lap. ... And we hope they do it sooner rather than later.'' Until recently, the bank board has been forced to keep insolvent institutions open because it lacked the money to pay off depositors or entice a healthier S & amp; L into merging with the sick institution. The bank board said 345 S & amp; Ls were insolvent at the end of the year, 109 in <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> alone. An S & amp; L is considered insolvent when its loans and other assets are worth less than what it owes to depositors and other creditors. By the tougher accounting standards the bank board will be using next year, 510 would be considered insolvent. Yet, regulators closed only 17 institutions in 1987 and provided assistance for the merger of 26 others. Now that money has begun flowing from a three-year, $ 10.8 billion recapitalization enacted in August, bank board Chairman <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Danny </PERSON> <PERSON> Wall </PERSON> has pledged to pick up the pace. Last month, he announced a plan to spend $ 6 billion to $ 7 billion in <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> over the next several years, but the bank board said Wednesday it expected no announcements on specific institutions before early April. <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> A. Regalia, chief economist of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Savings </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institutions </ORGANIZATION>, warned that the bank board must move swiftly. `` On balance, next year will be not quite as bad, but that depends on how quickly you get rid of these institutions'' in the <LOCATION> Southwest </LOCATION>, he said. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Barth </PERSON>, chief economist of the bank board, said he believed the industry's problems have `` plateaued out'' and that `` there is some light at the end of the tunnel'' in the <LOCATION> Southwest </LOCATION>. Industry losses in 1987 were nearly 50 percent greater than the previous post-Depression record of $ 4.6 billion, set in 1981, when the prime lending rate soared above 20 percent. <ORGANIZATION> Insured </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> S </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; Ls lost $ 1.8 billion in the third quarter of last year and $ 1.9 billion in the spring. They earned $ 100 million in the first three months of the year and had a modest $ 132 million profit for all of 1986. In contrast, the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Deposit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Insurance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> said earlier this month that the nation's 13,700 federally insured commercial banks earned $ 3.7 billion in 1987. Still, it was their lowest profit since 1933. Despite the overall loss for the S & amp; L industry, 66 percent of the <ORGANIZATION> S </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; Ls earned money in the fourth quarter. The $ 1.3 billion earnings of 2,089 S & amp; Ls partly offset the $ 4.5 billion losses of the remaining 1,058 institutions. The percentage of institutions earning a profit has declined steadily for two years, from 81 percent in the first quarter of 1986 to 66 percent at the end of last year. <PERSON> Barth </PERSON> said part of the overall industry loss in 1987 can be attributed to a decrease in the corporate tax rate. He said some S & amp; Ls decided to push profits into 1988, when the top tax rate is 34 percent, rather than take them in 1987, when the rate was 40 percent.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880325-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-25-88 2358EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Israel Bjt   03-25 0761</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Israel, Bjt,0785</SECOND>
<HEAD>Troops Storm Hospital And Mosque, Two Palestinians Killed</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto covering</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By SERGEI SHARGORODSKY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>JERUSALEM (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Israeli troops stormed a <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> hospital and a mosque and killed two Palestinian demonstrators and wounding 18 in a new outbreak of clashes in the occupied lands. Most media coverage was barred. Prime Minister <PERSON> Yitzhak </PERSON> <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON> met with <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. Ambassador <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Pickering </PERSON> to express his `` dissatisfaction'' about today's scheduled meeting in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> between Secretary of State <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> and two members of the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION>'s legislative arm Also Friday, an Arab-American advocate of non-violent resistance to occupation called for the establishment of a `` parallel'' Palestinian government in <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s occupied territories. The army closed key areas of the occupied <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strip </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> to the media, including the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Hebron </LOCATION> area, where the most of Friday's violent clashes occurred. In <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, meanwhile, the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> urged Americans to stay away from the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION>. Easter and Passover are approaching, <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> and Jewish holidays that usually attract tourists to the Holy Land. About 50 Israeli troops fired tear gas and rubber bullets into <LOCATION> Hebron </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Alia </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION> compound Friday to subdue about 100 protesters who were hurling stones and bottles, hospital officials and <PERSON> Arab </PERSON> reports said. Later, soldiers stormed the hospital to arrest six <PERSON> Arab </PERSON> youths who barricaded themselves on the roof, the army said. Reporters saw troops surround <LOCATION> Hebron </LOCATION>'s <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> Haras </PERSON> mosque after Friday's Moslem prayers, firing live ammunition and tear gas from the rooftops of nearby houses at several dozen stone-throwing Arab youths on the mosque's roof. Four Palestinians were wounded, hospital officials and <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> radio reported. After a two-hour confrontation, soldiers stormed the mosque, yanked down <LOCATION> Palestinian </LOCATION> flags raised by the protesters and lined up dozens of <PERSON> Arab </PERSON> teenagers against a wall. The army said 50 Arabs were arrested. The army said it was forced to break in when the stone-throwers refused to surrender. Television said it was the first time soldiers had stormed a mosque since unrest began Dec. 8 in the territories <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> seized in the 1967 <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> war. Another Arab was wounded in the village of <LOCATION> Idna </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Israel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Radio </ORGANIZATION> said. In the village of <LOCATION> Tarqumia </LOCATION> near <LOCATION> Hebron </LOCATION>, troops killed two Palestinians and wounded 13, witnesses and the radio said. The army said it was checking the reports but could not confirm them because relatives took the bodies. Troops entered <PERSON> Tarqumia </PERSON> at about 4 a.m. and took over the school, said <PERSON> Naim </PERSON> <PERSON> Odeh </PERSON>, a 52-year-old teacher. The army has converted a number of schools into military bases since the unrest began and is using about half a dozen as temporary detention centers. `` Then about 500 youths marched out to the school and started throwing rocks and broken bottles,'' <PERSON> Odeh </PERSON> said in an interview. <PERSON> Khaled </PERSON> <PERSON> Hassan </PERSON> <PERSON> Ahmed </PERSON> <PERSON> Murktan </PERSON>, 18, died of a gunshot wound to the stomach and <PERSON> Walid </PERSON> <PERSON> Abdul </PERSON> <PERSON> Fatatta </PERSON>, 18, was shot in the heart, villagers and <LOCATION> Alia </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION> officials said. Friday's fatalities brought to 111 the number of Palestinians killed by <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> count in the anti-occupation unrest since Dec. 8. One Israeli soldier has been killed. Meanwhile, 72 percent of the Israelis questioned said they want harsher measures in the occupied territories. The Dahaf nstitute poll published in the daily <ORGANIZATION> Yediot </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ahronot </ORGANIZATION> said 7 percent of the 606 Israelis questioned this week supported less severe measures while 21 percent did not want policy changes. Also, 49 percent of those questioned said <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON>' <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> peace plan _ essentially an exchange of land for piece with the <LOCATION> Arabs </LOCATION> _ should be accepted. Forty-three percent were against it and 8 percent had no opinion. Israeli officials, however, reacted angrily to <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON>' plans to discuss the peace initiative with two <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> citizens who belong to the <ORGANIZATION> Palestine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION>'s parliament-in-exile. <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON> expressed his `` dissatisfaction'' during Friday's meeting with <PERSON> Pickering </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> TV said. <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON>'s spokesman <PERSON> Avi </PERSON> <PERSON> Pazner </PERSON> said <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON>'s meeting with <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Said </PERSON>, a professor at <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, and <PERSON> Ibrahim </PERSON> <PERSON> Abu-Lughod </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Northwestern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> professor, violates a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> commitment not to talk to the <ORGANIZATION> Palestine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION>. In another development, <PERSON> Mubarak </PERSON> <PERSON> Awad </PERSON>, an Arab-American advocate of non-violent resistance to <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> occupation, called for forming a `` parallel'' government in the occupied territories. `` We should start thinking what kind of a <LOCATION> Palestinian </LOCATION> state we are going to have, what to do with <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION>, where are the borders,'' he told <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> TV. Israeli authorities confiscated <PERSON> Awad </PERSON>'s <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> passport and Israeli identity card last year and ordered him expelled last November when his tourist visa expired. <PERSON> Awad </PERSON> stayed following strong <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> pressure.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880325-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-25-88 0244EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Panama-Politics     03-25 0699</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Panama-Politics,0721</SECOND>
<HEAD>A Noriega Departure Could Mean Political Free-for-All</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Panama, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ELOY O. AGUILAR</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PANAMA CITY, Panama (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 If Gen. <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> leaves, it could start a political free-for-all in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>, where 20 years of military rule with a civilian facade have given opposition parties little chance to mature. `` No dictatorship ever prepared a people for democracy,'' said editor <PERSON> Winston </PERSON> <PERSON> Robles </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> La </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Prensa </ORGANIZATION> newspaper, which the Noriega-controlled government shut down last month. Many political observers, including opposition party leaders, predict a `` free-for-all, no holds barred'' if <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> goes. The general, who heads the 15,000-strong <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forces </ORGANIZATION>, says he is n't leaving. He has defied a huge opposition campaign and crippling <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> economic pressure and even indicated he might run for president. The government-controlled news media have started referring to <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> as `` the undisputed leader of the political majorities'' of <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>. His predecessor, Gen. <PERSON> Omar </PERSON> <PERSON> Torrijos </PERSON>, abolished political parties in 1968 after taking power in a coup. In 1977, when he and then-President <PERSON> Jimmy </PERSON> <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> signed the Canal Treaties, <PERSON> Torrijos </PERSON> founded his own party. He let other parties campaign in 1984, but his <ORGANIZATION> Revolutionary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> won in what the opposition called robbery. Most parties here revolve around a single personality _ like 87-year-old <PERSON> Arnulfo </PERSON> <PERSON> Arias </PERSON> <PERSON> Madrid </PERSON> of the Authentic Panamanian Party, deposed three times as president by the military, and the leader of the <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Ricardo </PERSON> <PERSON> Arias </PERSON> <PERSON> Calderon </PERSON>, who returned Thursday from exile. Others parties are what Panamanians call `` stationery.'' They exist on paper, issuing statements and communiques, but have no popular following. Political parties have not been in the forefront of the campaign against <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>. The drive has been led by the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Civic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Crusade </ORGANIZATION>, a coalition of business, private organizations and professional groups and some labor unions. `` We do not have any political leadership. We are being led by businessmen,'' said a young man collecting food for residents of a <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> slum. While the Civic Crusade was organizing national strikes and issuing calls for <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> to resign, most politicians applauded from the sidelines. <PERSON> Arias </PERSON> <PERSON> Calderon </PERSON> and some other <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> officials have been an exception. Last month, the Civic Crusade and most of the opposition parties formed an alliance and agreed that if <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> goes, they will work under a transitional government with deposed President <PERSON> Eric </PERSON> <PERSON> Arturo </PERSON> <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON> as its head. The next election is scheduled for May 1989. The Authenic Panamanian Party, however, refused to join the alliance. Party leaders say they will never recognize <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON> because the party he represents robbed them of victory in the 1984 election. <PERSON> Arias </PERSON> <PERSON> Madrid </PERSON> is a populist first elected in 1940 and first deposed late the following year. He was elected again in 1950 and deposed in 1951. He was elected president a third time in 1968 and deposed after 11 days in office. The Authentic Panamanians see <PERSON> Arias </PERSON> <PERSON> Calderon </PERSON> _ <ORGANIZATION> Arias </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Madrid </ORGANIZATION>'s vice presidential running mate in 1984 _ as a threat The Christian Democrats, the nation's largest opposition party, gave <ORGANIZATION> Arias </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Madrid </ORGANIZATION> the top spot on the 1984 coalition ticket because <PERSON> Arias </PERSON> <PERSON> Calderon </PERSON> was seen as something of an egghead with little popular appeal. But since then, <PERSON> Arias </PERSON> <PERSON> Calderon </PERSON>'s close cooperation with the Civic Crusade has positioned him for a presidential bid in a post-Noriega <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>. When <PERSON> Arias </PERSON> <PERSON> Calderon </PERSON> returned Thursday, <PERSON> Aurelio </PERSON> <PERSON> Barria </PERSON>, the head of the <ORGANIZATION> Panamanian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chamber </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Industry </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> and a founder of the Civic Crusade, stood next to him as he greeted cheering well wishers. <PERSON> Arias </PERSON> <PERSON> Calderon </PERSON> has also been busy building bridges with other political parties, particularly the <ORGANIZATION> Liberal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nationalist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Movement </ORGANIZATION>, in what is seen as an attempt to forge a new coalition. Some politicians say they do not expect the Crusade to survive long after <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> because its leaders are mostly business people without political affiliation. Typical of the Crusade leaders are <PERSON> Ernesto </PERSON> <PERSON> Gonzalez </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> la </PERSON> <PERSON> Lastra </PERSON>, general manager of an insurance company, and <PERSON> Barria </PERSON>. Neither is affiliated with a political party. Other politicians, however, say the strong role people like <PERSON> Barria </PERSON> and <PERSON> Gonzalez </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> la </PERSON> <PERSON> Lastra </PERSON> have assumed in the Crusade could make them forces to be reckoned with if they remain active in public life.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880325-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-25-88 0248EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Robertson     03-25 0589</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Robertson,550</SECOND>
<HEAD>Pat Robertson Says He'll Do Some Muscle-Flexing At GOP Convention</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CHRISTOPHER CONNELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>FALLS CHURCH, Va. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> says his lagging campaign for the Republican presidential nomination is being revived in caucus states that will strengthen conservatives' hand at the party convention in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION>. Beyond that goal, <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> said Thursday night, he is looking not only to lay the groundwork for another presidential campaign in 1992, but to help build <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> strength in state houses and <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> for the 1990s. Although <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> was beaten by <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> in his home state's non-binding primary on Super Tuesday, he told 700 supporters at <ORGANIZATION> Falls </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> High </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> that they can still capture most of the state's delegates by turning out in force at local precinct meetings `` A few days from now we're going to be celebrating the most important event in the entire Christian calendar,'' said the former religious broadcaster, referring to Easter, which falls on April 3. He said the press wrote his candidacy off as dead after Super Tuesday, `` but I do n't think they're aware of the resurrection.'' He said his campaign swept county convention delegates in <LOCATION> Wake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.C. </LOCATION> on Tuesday, and had picked up other delegates in <LOCATION> Charleston </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> S.C. </LOCATION>, as well as <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> and elsewhere. `` All over this country, when June comes around and it's all over ... our people should be in significant places of responsibility in something like 15 or 20 of the state Republican parties,'' he said. `` We are going to put together a coalition that will go to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION> strong, speaking with one voice, and having enough political weight to make sure that some of the things we hold very dear ... are embodied in the platform of the Republican party,'' he said. `` In the next few weeks, as these caucuses unfold in <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>, we are going to win the majority in the <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>,'' he predicted. Asked as he left the rally if he was giving up in <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION>, a caucus state where his campaign pulled the plug on a bank of 32 phones, <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> said, `` We're going from paid phone banks to volunteer phone banks. The operation is still under way. I'm going out there for a series of meetings a week from Saturday.'' In his speech, <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> attacked the Civil Rights Restoration Act that <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> passed Tuesday over President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s veto, as `` a horrible bill. It was a federal power grab ... a blot on the <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>.'' Many of <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s worst problems, including crime and drugs, stem from erosion of morals, he said, adding, `` If we're going to restore the greatness of <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, we've got to go back to a sense of personal, individual responsibility.'' `` We must be No. 1 in our ethics, No. 1 in our morals, No. 1 in our lifestyles, No. 1 in our adherence to freedom, No. 1 in our trust and faith in God almighty,'' he said. `` We can not allow the radical Democrats to institutionalize aberrant behavior which is part of the destruction of <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>,'' he said. A <ORGANIZATION> Falls </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> High </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> freshman, <PERSON> Debbie </PERSON> <PERSON> Weisshaar </PERSON>, 14, of <LOCATION> Annandale </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, said afterwards that she was discomfited by <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON>'s repeated references to God and Christianity. `` I was n't sure if he meant freedom for everyone, or freedom for the people who believed in what he believed in,'' said the teen-ager, who is Jewish. <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> has just 17 delegates in the latest <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> count to 788 for <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and 178 for <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880325-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-25-88 0249EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Lebanon-Haven     03-25 0740</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lebanon-Haven,0766</SECOND>
<HEAD>Southern Town Is What Lebanon Used to be</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By HASAN MROUE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>RMEILEH, Lebanon (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 In the chaos and intolerance that is <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Rmeileh </PERSON> is an oasis of liberty, a haven for people fleeing political and social persecution and assassination. This coastal town, 19 miles south of <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>, is what <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> used to be before 13 years of civil war, sectarian hatreds and religious fanatacism turned it into a wilderness. Leftists and other refugees from <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> and the south have fled to <PERSON> Rmeileh </PERSON> following a campaign of assassinations by Shiite Moslem fundamentalists against communists, pro-Iraqi Baath socialists and other leftists. One of the things that makes <PERSON> Rmeileh </PERSON> different from just about everywhere else in <LOCATION> south </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> is that alcohol is sold openly at the side of the road. Alcohol is banned in most areas of the region, dominated by Shiite Moslem factions, and in <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>'s southern slums, the <ORGANIZATION> Shiite </ORGANIZATION> stronghold in the capital. Islamic religious laws also ban mixed parties, mixed bathing and the consumption of pork. But in the summer, <PERSON> Rmeileh </PERSON>'s eight restaurants and three miles of <LOCATION> Mediterranean </LOCATION> beaches and hillside picnic areas are packed with males and females having a good time. Pork also is sold. <PERSON> Hamza </PERSON>, 35, comes from the staunchly <ORGANIZATION> Shiite </ORGANIZATION> town of <LOCATION> Nabatiyeh </LOCATION> in the south. `` We ca n't buy drinks in <LOCATION> Nabatiyeh </LOCATION> any more, so we come to <PERSON> Rmeileh </PERSON>,'' he said. `` In summer women have to come here to swim because it's the one of the very few places they can do that.'' Because he lives in a Shiite area, where such activities are forbidden, <PERSON> Hamza </PERSON> declined to disclose his full name. <PERSON> Rmeileh </PERSON> was a mainly Christian town, with about 5,000 <ORGANIZATION> Maronite </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Catholics </ORGANIZATION>, until 1985, when Moslem forces overran the coastal plain. Now only about 60 Maronite families are left. But <PERSON> Rmeileh </PERSON> now is protected by <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> militiamen, most of them Christians, who are allied to neighboring Druse and Sunni Moslem forces who help keep the Shiites out. The Syrian army also has a checkpoint just south of <LOCATION> Rmeileh </LOCATION> on the <LOCATION> Awali </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> which also acts as a deterrent for <ORGANIZATION> Shiite </ORGANIZATION> gunmen. <PERSON> Abu </PERSON> <PERSON> Rim </PERSON>, a leftist official in the town, said 500 refugee families _ Moslems, <ORGANIZATION> Christians </ORGANIZATION> and Palestinians _ live in <LOCATION> Rmeileh </LOCATION> with the local Christians. `` Our aim is to get rid of the sectarian atmosphere and implement co-existence,'' he said. <PERSON> Elias </PERSON> <PERSON> Tabet </PERSON>, director of the town's government school, said ethnic mix gives <PERSON> Rmeileh </PERSON> a non-sectarian nature, where people from different areas and religions `` feel safe and free.'' <PERSON> Samih </PERSON> <PERSON> Germanos </PERSON>, 57, a Christian who fled <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>'s Shiite-controlled southern slums, said: `` We're very happy and hope things will stay this way. Acting Mayor <PERSON> Halim </PERSON> <PERSON> Kleib </PERSON>, said the tourist influx last summer was even better than pre-war times. `` People in the south prefer <PERSON> Rmeileh </PERSON> to other places because it's the closest resort to them that provides restaurants and private beaches as well as drinks,'' <PERSON> Kleib </PERSON> added. <PERSON> Ali </PERSON> <PERSON> Hujeiri </PERSON>, 40, a father of nine, who works at a <ORGANIZATION> Pepsi </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cola </ORGANIZATION> plant in a nearby town, said he sells alcohol on the street to earn extra money and that most of his customers are from the Shiite south. `` I'm the only one to sell pork in this area,'' said <PERSON> Abu </PERSON> <PERSON> Elie </PERSON>, a 32-year-old shopowner. `` I started bringing it from <LOCATION> Mount </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> last week and in four days, I sold around 40 kilograms -LRB- 88 pounds -RRB-. Justice Minister <PERSON> Nabih </PERSON> <PERSON> Berri </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> Amal </ORGANIZATION> movement and the Iranian-backed <ORGANIZATION> Hezbollah </ORGANIZATION> -LRB- Party of God -RRB- have been blamed for many of the assasinations of leftists in south <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>. But since many of those who have fled to <PERSON> Rmeileh </PERSON> _ `` self-deportees,'' <ORGANIZATION> Amal </ORGANIZATION> calls them _ are skilled or professional people, the <ORGANIZATION> Amal </ORGANIZATION> recently asked them to return to their villages. <PERSON> Wafiq </PERSON> <PERSON> Rihan </PERSON>, a 33-year-old Shiite school teacher, did n't sound as though he is ready to return. He said that after he fled <LOCATION> Nabatiyeh </LOCATION> last year the Communists and the leftist <PERSON> Druse </PERSON> `` helped us find places to stay and in the beginning we relied on Red Cross supplies.'' `` I'm teaching at the school now,'' he added. `` I was originally a teacher. But most of the other deportees here are also working in their particular fields, medicine, the law, and so on. `` One doctor who fled <LOCATION> Nabatiyeh </LOCATION> even has some of his old patients come here to see him for treatment.'' <PERSON> Rihan </PERSON> said he wants to go back to his own village but only when it's safe.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880325-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-25-88 0250EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Israel-Guards     03-25 0810</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Israel-Guards,0835</SECOND>
<HEAD>Arabs Stand Overnight Watch for Soldiers and Settlers</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By MASHA HAMILTON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ARURA, Occupied West Bank (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Two Palestinians on night guard duty, masked and armed with clubs, sprinted down the main village road passing the word: `` Israeli soldiers are coming!'' Behind them, about 20 more moved in the dark with the speed of practice to block the road in a half-dozen places. They dragged stockpiled boulders and twisted metal onto the pavement to slow the 12 jeeps in the Israeli patrol. Palestinians whose faces were hidden by checkered keffiyeh headdresses whistled shrilly to each other across the rocky hills, tracking the army's progress on the narrow road. The overnight citizen patrol was in action, witnessed in this case by a journalist. The patrol at <LOCATION> Arura </LOCATION> was one of dozens organized after the army started nighttime raids, arresting hundreds of alleged agitators in an effort to quell nearly four months of violent anti-Israeli protests. <PERSON> Jamal </PERSON>, 30, stood watch atop a ridge on the outskirts of <LOCATION> Arura </LOCATION>, a village of 2,200 Palestinians that sprawls over hills of the occupied <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> about 20 miles north of <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION>. `` Because of these patrols, we are ready for an attack from anywhere,'' he said. `` But there is more than that. The guard duty makes us unified as a people. Everyone feels he has a part in the uprising.'' Arab patrols are clandestine and all those interviewed would agree only to the use of their first names. Riots began Dec. 8 in the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strip </LOCATION>, which <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> has occupied since capturing them from <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION> in the 1967 <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> war. More than 100 Palestinians and an <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> soldier have been killed. The patrols are a sign of the changing nature and steady escalation of the `` intefadeh,'' Arabic for uprising. They illustrate growing sophistication in a rebellion that began spontaneously and, for that reason, worry Israeli officials. `` Illegal local organization could lead to illegal regional organization, all of it directed against us,'' a military man said privately. On this night the army jeeps stopped short of <LOCATION> Arura </LOCATION>, parked for about half an hour, then drove away. Why the soldiers approached and left in the latest cat-and-mouse game was not clear, but the villagers viewed called it a retreat by the enemy and a victory for themselves. Residents said soldiers had approached <PERSON> Arura </PERSON> on three occasions since the patrols began, but stopped each time when guards alerted villagers and about 1,000 people gathered in the streets, chanting and throwing stones. Patrolling in <LOCATION> Arura </LOCATION>, as witnessed on two evenings, is a methodical and sometimes tense business. Men carrying clubs and rocks, their faces covered, stop each passing car. Strangers are ordered out of their vehicles until they are determined to be friends and not <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> soldiers in plainclothes or Jews from the nearby <LOCATION> Ateret </LOCATION> settlement. Between cars and sightings of soldiers, the sentinels often engage in mutual pep-talk. They encourage each other to continue the fight against <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>, make optimistic predictions about the uprising and sometimes ward off the night cold with a shared glass of sweet herb tea. <PERSON> Tahir </PERSON>, 23, said he would stand guard until 5 a.m. then leave for his job in an <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> factory, where he packs oranges. `` I'm one person at night and another in the day,'' he said. `` In <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>, they have no idea that I am taking my turn, once a week, on patrol.'' Nightly patrols were organized in <LOCATION> Arura </LOCATION> about a month ago after the army had made four raids in a six-week period, arresting 21 young men. <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> soldiers have rounded up more than 700 Palestinians in the past week in an effort to end the rebellion, and about 3,000 have been detained since the violence began. Soldiers are ordered to make arrests overnight, when most people are sleeping, to avoid causing violent protests. `` They wo n't catch us sleeping here and they wo n't be able to arrest us. We are watching for them every night,'' said <PERSON> Salah </PERSON>, 22, one of 250 men of Arura aged 16 to 45 who take turns on guard duty from about 8 p.m. until dawn. Boys under 16 are not taken for the patrols, but many children are eager to do their part. Four boys huddled for warmth over smoldering embers in a small, smoky cave beside the road to the village. They said they would remain until 2 a.m., and if a man came running with word of approaching soldiers they would race through the rocky hills helping wake the villagers. `` I feel like a man because I am doing something to resist the Israelis,'' <PERSON> Yassin </PERSON> told a reporter with a solemnity far beyond his 11 years. `` This is in the interest of our homeland. It is the duty of everyone to help.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880325-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-25-88 0250EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-LaRoucheTrial     03-25 0435</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-LaRouche Trial,0444</SECOND>
<HEAD>Witness: Fund-Raisers Ordered To Demand Money To Head Off Global
Crisis</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN KING</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BOSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Fund-raisers for <PERSON> Lyndon </PERSON> <PERSON> LaRouche </PERSON> were ordered to tell people they owed the political extremist money because he was preventing Soviet aggression and global economic collapse, a former <PERSON> LaRouche </PERSON> aide testified. The fund-raisers also were told that <PERSON> LaRouche </PERSON> needed the money to pay for security to protect him from assassins, former aide <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Tate </PERSON> testified Thursday at the federal trial of <PERSON> LaRouche </PERSON>, six aides and five <PERSON> LaRouche </PERSON> political groups. <PERSON> Tate </PERSON> said <PERSON> LaRouche </PERSON> followers were treated as soliders and warned repeatedly that falling short of daily quotas was `` the moral equivalent of treason'' and would result in the immediate collapse of Western civilization. <PERSON> Tate </PERSON> testified that <PERSON> LaRouche </PERSON>'s top fund-raising operative, <PERSON> Will </PERSON> <PERSON> Wirtz </PERSON>, said prospective donors should be told <PERSON> LaRouche </PERSON> prevented a Soviet takeover, was the only Democratic presidential candidate not under <ORGANIZATION> KGB </ORGANIZATION> influence and the only man on earth who could prevent global economic disaster. The warnings were given in late 1983 and 1984, when <PERSON> LaRouche </PERSON> followers were under stringent fund-raising quotas because of his campaign and the pending move of organization headquarters from <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Leesburg </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Tate </PERSON> said. <PERSON> LaRouche </PERSON>, a candidate for the 1988 Democratic presidential nomination, is charged with conspiring to obstruct a federal grand jury investigation into allegations that his followers raised more than $ 2 million through credit card and loan fraud. Four LaRouche organizations, including his two 1984 campaign committees, are charged with fraud. Those organizations and a fifth LaRouche group are charged in the alleged obstruction, as are the six aides. Prosecutors, through <PERSON> Tate </PERSON>, are attempting to show that intense pressure from <PERSON> LaRouche </PERSON> led followers to solicit loans by falsely promising they would be repaid and by submitting unauthorized charges to the credit card accounts of past donors to <PERSON> LaRouche </PERSON> causes. <PERSON> LaRouche </PERSON> and defense lawyers have conceded some <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> fund-raisers might have committed credit card fraud but contend <PERSON> LaRouche </PERSON> and top aides relieved those fund-raisers of their duties when allegations of impropriety surfaced. <PERSON> LaRouche </PERSON> contends the allegations of nationwide fraud were concocted as part of a <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration plot to ruin him because he opposed Contra aid and because his fund-raising competed with former <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> aide <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> <PERSON> North </PERSON>'s private effort to resupply the Nicaraguan rebels at a time when <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> had halted government aid. The 125-count indictment against <PERSON> LaRouche </PERSON> and the other defendants, however, charges that three <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> fund-raisers were ordered by <PERSON> LaRouche </PERSON> to destroy records and flee the country to avoid being called before the grand jury. The three were indicted but are fugitives.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880325-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-25-88 0252EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-ChemicalWeapons     03-25 0815</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Chemical Weapons,0842</SECOND>
<HEAD>Chemical Warfare Threat Mounts In Gulf War</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By ED BLANCHE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NICOSIA, Cyprus (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The slaughter of Kurdish civilians in Iraqi poison gas attacks and Iranian warnings of retaliation underscore the growth of the chemical warfare arsenals of major <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> powers. Despite efforts to curb such weapons, their spread has added a dangerous new dimension to conflicts in the volatile <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION>. Their use, but not their production, is banned under a 1925 <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> agreement. The London-based <PERSON> Jane </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Weekly </ORGANIZATION> noted in a recent study that the use of poison and nerve gases since 1984 in the 7 -LCB- - year-old Iran-Iraq war has `` changed the rules of war in the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION> charges that <LOCATION> Iraqi </LOCATION> warplanes have dropped chemical bombs on several villages in northwestern <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> after Iranian forces overran the Kurdish area in a round offensive. Western correspondents in <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> have reported evidence to substantiate Iranian claims that 5,000 Iraqi Kurds were killed and another 5,000 injured when <LOCATION> Iraqi </LOCATION> warplanes dropped chemical bombs on towns captured by the Iranians in northeast <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> last week. <PERSON> Nicholas </PERSON> <PERSON> Beeston </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> London </ORGANIZATION> reported from <LOCATION> Halabja </LOCATION>, one of the towns, that `` hundreds and possibly thousands'' of the Kurds, who have been rebelling against <LOCATION> Baghdad </LOCATION> for years, were killed. <PERSON> Hashemi </PERSON> <PERSON> Rafsanjani </PERSON>, speaker of <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION> and <PERSON> Ayatollah </PERSON> <PERSON> Ruhollah </PERSON> <PERSON> Khomeini </PERSON>'s representative on the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>, warned Thursday that <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> will be forced to use chemical weapons in retaliation if the <LOCATION> Iraqi </LOCATION> attacks continue. The intensity of <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION>'s accusations against <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> in recent days has heightened fears that the Iranians may be seeking to justify using chemical weapons of their own. <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> Spokesman <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Redman </PERSON> said Wednesday there was evidence <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> may already have fired chemical artillery shells into <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>. He declined to elaborate. `` It's entirely likely that the Iranians could do so,'' said <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Kerr </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Strategic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Studies </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> in a telephone interview. `` They've had these weapons used against them for a long time.'' <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>, a signatory to the 1925 agreement, has been condemned by the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Nation </LOCATION> four times since 1984 for using chemical weapons. The Iranians claim the Iraqis have launched around 100 chemical attacks in that period, mainly against Iranian troops. Iranian-backed Kurdish guerrillas fighting the <LOCATION> Baghdad </LOCATION> regime for autonomy have claimed scores of such attacks on their villages in the last year. But last week's bombing appears to have been the worst chemical attack in the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> conflict. Germ warfare dates back to the 14th Century, when the Tartars catapulted the rotting corpses of plague victims into the besieged Crimean city of <LOCATION> Kaffa </LOCATION> in a bid to spread disease. Modern chemical warfare began at on April 22, 1915, at 5 p.m. when the Germans released 180 tons of chlorine gas at <LOCATION> Ypres </LOCATION> on the <ORGANIZATION> Western </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION> in World War I. Within an hour, 5,000 French soldiers were dead or dying from the wind-blown gas rolling a few fet above their trenches. By the end of the war, gas had killed 100,000 men and affected more than 900,000 others. Modern nerve gases are far more lethal. <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> has the biggest chemical weapons armory in the region, with sizable stocks of poison and nerve gases produced at three top-secret plants, Western military analysts told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>. The sources, speaking on condition of anonymnity, said <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> is now producing <PERSON> Sarin </PERSON>, a highly lethal nerve gas that can kill in less than 10 minutes. They said there are indications that the Iraqis are also working on germ warfare weapons. The sources estimated that <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> can now produce 60 tons of mustard gas a month and four tons each of Sarin and <LOCATION> Tabun </LOCATION>, another highly lethal nerve agent. <LOCATION> Tabun </LOCATION>, first developed by <ORGANIZATION> Nazi </ORGANIZATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> before World War II but never used, is a colorless gas that attacks the body's muscular centers and causes asphyxiation within 15 minutes. The sources said the Iraqis' main production plant is at <LOCATION> Samarra </LOCATION>, a heavily guarded 10-square-mile complex ringed by Soviet-supplied Sa-2 anti-aircraft missiles 70 miles north of <LOCATION> Baghdad </LOCATION>. On the other side, <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'s chief military spokesman, <PERSON> Kamal </PERSON> <PERSON> Kharrazi </PERSON>, has said his country is producing chemical weapons. The analysts and diplomatic sources, who spoke on condition of anonymity, said Iranian chemical weapons are believed to be mainly mustard and phosgene gases. <PERSON> Kerr </PERSON> noted: `` These are relatively simple to manufacture from readily available industrial components, as is hydrogen cyanide. Only the more complex nerve gases are likely to pose a chemical challenge to the Iranians.'' The Syrians, <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>'s main Arab ally, also have developed their own chemical weapons industry over the last few years, intelligence and diplomatic sources said. The Israelis allege the Syrian chemical warfare capability is a serious threat and say <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION> has the means to deliver nerve agents with Soviet-supplied SS-1 Scud-B missiles and combat aircraft.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880325-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-25-88 0753EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-TreatyObstacles Bjt   03-25 0603</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Treaty Obstacles, Bjt,600</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHINGTON WIRE: New Treaty May Not Be Ready For Reagan To Sign</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BARRY SCHWEID</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Diplomatic Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 In the uphill climb to the <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> summit, the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> this week made a couple of proposals to the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> on a new treaty to sharply reduce long-range nuclear weapons. One was the exemption of spy satellites from treaty restrictions. The other was that <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and Soviet negotiators make a supreme effort to define space-based testing and deployment. The Soviets seemed taken with the satellite proposal, but sharpening definitions of space tests and space deployments could be very difficult. There's always been a question whether technology sent into space is part of a permissible test or is a tricky step toward an illicit anti-missile deployment. In any event, with the <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> summit meeting only nine weeks away, the outlook for completing the new U.S.-Soviet treaty is not bright. The biggest problem is verification _ making sure cutbacks are carried out. Two types of long-range weapons are especially hard to monitor. One is the land-based mobile missile. The other is the sea-launched cruise. Experts assisting Secretary of State <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> and <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> Foreign Minister <PERSON> Eduard </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shevardnadze </PERSON> were unable to resolve the problem during three days of talks here. And yet, the two sides apparently still intend to try to include the weapons in the accord with all bombers, submarines and missiles having a range in excess of 3,000 miles. The Soviets proposed a joint experiment next month to see whether monitors could determine if an American ship was carrying nuclear-tipped cruise missiles. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> rejected the proposal as unlikely to solve the detection problem. On another front, a little headway was made. The <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Strategic Defense Initiative, probably the biggest obstacle to the treaty, and the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> space defense program will be dealt with separately by the negotiators. The Soviets claim the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> program, known popularly as Star Wars, violates the 1972 Anti-Ballistic Missile Treaty. They have threatened at various times to hold up a new accord to reduce strategic nuclear weapons unless the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> program to develop a defense against ballistic missile were curbed. That `` linkage'' has not been removed. <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> told reporters Wednesday night `` the two things move in parallel.'' In other words, the Soviets are retaining the right suddenly to halt progress on arms reductions unless the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> slows down SDI. `` Both sides have worked hard and some progress has been realized in a number of areas, but much more needs to be done,'' the two sides said in a communique winding up three days of talks. <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> and <PERSON> Shevardnadze </PERSON> will meet again in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> on April 21. Meanwhile, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and Soviet negotiators will keep trying to agree on three drafts for the treaty. One deals with the elimination of weapons, another with verifying the cutbacks and the third with the size and location of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and Soviet strategic arsenals. Before flying home, <PERSON> Shevardnadze </PERSON> called the rejected Soviet proposal to verify sea-launched cruise missiles a breakthrough in verification. He said the Soviets had similar ideas for monitoring mobile intercontinental ballistic missiles and air-launched cruises. `` I hope that at the April round we will find solutions for a number of these problems,'' the Soviet foreign minister said. But he was not all that optimistic about concluding a treaty before the June 29 summit meeting. `` I ca n't guarantee that a treaty will be signed in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>, but it is a possibility, given enough effort,'' he said.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Barry </PERSON> <PERSON> Schweid </PERSON> has covered six U.S.-Soviet summits for <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880325-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-25-88 0253EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-WellRescue-Movie     03-25 0585</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Well Rescue-Movie,0601</SECOND>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</NOTE>
<HEAD>Two Rival Associations Fighting Over Movie Rights</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MIDLAND, Texas (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
