<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880414-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-14-88 2337EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-Fetuses-Research     04-14 0335</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Fetuses-Research,310</SECOND>
<HEAD>Administration Bars NIH From Experiments On Aborted Fetal Tissue</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The National Institutes of Health may not conduct experiments using tissue from aborted fetuses _ considered promising in early work on Parkinson's disease _ under a ruling by the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration, according to a published report. `` This is a very difficult process,'' Dr. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Windom </PERSON>, assistant secretary of health at the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Human </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION>, said Thursday about his decision last week. The <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> reported the decision in Friday's editions. `` The morality and science are all mixed together,'' <PERSON> Windom </PERSON> said. `` They need to be evaluated before we rush ahead. We just ca n't afford to move too hastily on this.'' <PERSON> Windom </PERSON>'s decision was prompted by an <ORGANIZATION> NIH </ORGANIZATION> proposal to implant fetal tissue into patients with <ORGANIZATION> Parkinson </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION>, the newspaper reported. <PERSON> Windom </PERSON>, in a letter to <ORGANIZATION> NIH </ORGANIZATION> Director <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Wyngaarden </PERSON>, said he was `` withholding my approval of the proposed experiments'' due to `` ethical and legal'' questions that had not been addressed satisfactorily. He directed <PERSON> Wyngaarden </PERSON> to create an outside advisory committee to examine such questions, the <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> said. <PERSON> Windom </PERSON> wrote that he does not oppose the use of fetal tissue from miscarriages or stillbirths, but researchers contacted by the <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> said proper planning is necessary to retrieve the tissue while it is useful and that it is rarely possible to use fetuses that have been aborted spontaneously. Researchers contacted by the newspaper expressed dismay over the decision, with Dr. <PERSON> Bernard </PERSON> <PERSON> Liebel </PERSON>, professor of medicine at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Toronto </ORGANIZATION>, saying: `` <ORGANIZATION> NIH </ORGANIZATION> sets the pace, and this will cripple fetal research in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> ... It is an extraordinarily valuable research tool with immense potential. Depriving research scientists of this material is a great disservice to humanity.'' But abortion opponents praised the decision. `` If the parents were a part to the killing, they have no right to assign organs to another person,'' said Dr. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Willke </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Right-to-life </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>. `` that is desecration of a corpse.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880414-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-14-88 2350EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Italy-USOExplosion 5thLd-Writethru   04-14 0790</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Italy-USO Explosion, 5th Ld - Writethru,a0902,0812</SECOND>
<HEAD>Explosion at USO Club Kills Navy Servicewoman, Four Italians</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: LEADS with 6 grafs to INCLUDE fourth injured American,
CORRECT spelling of Capodanno; picks up 7th graf pvs, ``Italian
media ...; SUBS grafs 18-19, ``Navalta is ... with 22 grafs to
identify American.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By STEPHEN WILSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NAPLES, Italy (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A car bomb blew up in front of a club for <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military personnel in <LOCATION> Naples </LOCATION> on Thursday, killing a <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> enlisted woman and four Italians and wounding at least 17, officials said. There was no immediate claim of responsibility for the blast that happened shortly after 8 p.m. -LRB- 2 p.m. EDT -RRB- at the USO club. A <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman said the <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> woman was stationed at <ORGANIZATION> Naval </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Communications </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Area </ORGANIZATION> Master Station in <LOCATION> Naples </LOCATION>. Lt. <PERSON> Janet </PERSON> <PERSON> Mescus </PERSON>, the spokeswoman, said the woman's identity was being withheld pending notification of next of kin. Italian media quoted officials as saying four Italians were also killed. One of the bodies at the club's entrance was draped in a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> flag. Lt. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Morris </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> spokesman in <LOCATION> Naples </LOCATION>, said an undetermined number of crewmen from the frigates USS Capodanno and USS <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> were injured but that no sailor from either ship was killed. <PERSON> Morris </PERSON> said three sailors from the Capodanno and one from the <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> were admitted to the <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. Naval Hospital in <LOCATION> Naples </LOCATION>. He said one crewman from the Capodanno was treated and returned to his ship. Italian media said the bomb exploded during a reception at the club for the commander of the USS Paul, a torpedo boat destroyer docked in <LOCATION> Naples </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Morris </PERSON> and a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Consulate official could not confirm the report. Passers-by screamed and ran when the explosion occurred outside the club, which is in one of <LOCATION> Naples </LOCATION>' busiest areas. `` I was in the store and we were getting ready to lower the shutters when the world exploded around us,'' said <PERSON> Valeria </PERSON> <PERSON> Spinetti </PERSON>, 22, an employee in a nearby shop. A spokesmen for <PERSON> Pellegrini </PERSON> <PERSON> Hospital </PERSON> said 14 of the wounded, including four Americans and eight Italians, were sent to the hospital. The spokesman, who asked not to be identified, said the Americans were moved to a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military hospital. RAI, the state-run television network, said a 27-year-old Italian woman was in grave condition. <PERSON> Morris </PERSON> said the <LOCATION> Capodanno </LOCATION>, based in <LOCATION> Newport </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> R.I. </LOCATION>, and the <PERSON> Paul </PERSON>, based in <LOCATION> Mayport </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>, were on routine deployment with 6th Fleet. Antonio Barrel, the inspector general of public security in <LOCATION> Naples </LOCATION>, told the Italian news agency <ORGANIZATION> ANSA </ORGANIZATION> that authorities do not yet know if the car bomb was set by foreigners or Italians. But <ORGANIZATION> ANSA </ORGANIZATION> quoted an unidentified police official as saying `` the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> connection seems most likely.'' Italian news media noted the blast occurred almost exactly two years after <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> warplanes bombed <LOCATION> Tripoli </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Benghazi </LOCATION> in retaliation for alleged <LOCATION> Libyan </LOCATION> involvement in the bombing of a night club in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> that killed an American soldier. Investigators said the Thursday blast destroyed the inside of the club and wrecked cars on the street. The bomb apparently was hidden in a Ford Fiesta that was destroyed by the blast. Mescus identified three of the injured <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> servicemen as Chief Petty Officer <PERSON> Francisco </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Navalta </PERSON>, 39, of the USS <PERSON> Paul </PERSON>, and Petty Officer 3rd Class <PERSON> Craig </PERSON> <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Trent </PERSON>, 22, and Senior Chief Petty Officer <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Fifer </PERSON> <PERSON> Roberts </PERSON>, 38, both assiged to the USS Capodanno. <PERSON> Morris </PERSON> identified a fourth injured sailor as <PERSON> Stanley </PERSON> <PERSON> Lawson </PERSON>, 27, an electronics technician on the Capodanno. He was in stable condition. <PERSON> Navalta </PERSON>, from <LOCATION> Castillejos </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Zambales </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION>, and <PERSON> Trent </PERSON>, from <PERSON> Gaither </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Md. </LOCATION>, were also in stable condition. <PERSON> Roberts </PERSON>, from <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Louis </LOCATION>, Ill, was treated and released. `` Our sympathy goes out to the families and friends of those who were killed or injured in this brutal act,'' said World USO President <PERSON> Chuck </PERSON> <PERSON> Hagel </PERSON> from <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. The bombing was the fourth attack in seven years aginst <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> installations or personnel in <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>. In December 1981, <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Brigade </ORGANIZATION> terrorists disguised as plumbers kidnapped <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Brig. Gen. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Dozier </PERSON> from his home in <LOCATION> Verona </LOCATION>. He was freed 42 days later by a special police unit in <LOCATION> Padua </LOCATION>. In February 1984, terrorists in <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION> fatally shot <PERSON> Leamon </PERSON> <PERSON> Hunt </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> diplomat and director-general of the <ORGANIZATION> Multinational </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> and Observers in the Sinai. The Red Brigades claimed responsibility. In June 1987, a car bomb exploded near the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Embassy in <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION> and at least two rockets were fired at the embassy. There were no injuries. The <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> has a major presence in <LOCATION> Naples </LOCATION>, headquarters for <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION>'s southern command and the support center for the 6th Fleet An average of 45 ships, 200 aircraft and over 23,000 people comprise the fleet, which is deployed in the <LOCATION> Mediterranean </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880414-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-14-88 2351EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-Clanton 5thLd-Writethru a0907 04-14 0601</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Clanton, 5th Ld - Writethru, a0907,0614</SECOND>
<HEAD>URGENT</HEAD>
<HEAD>Va. Inmate Executed For Strangling</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: LEADS with 6 grafs to UPDATE with no final statement, ADD
previous murder and CORRECT in 2nd graf pvs that two jolts sted
three were administered. PICK UP 6th graf pvs, `The execution ...'</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By JOE TAYLOR</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>RICHMOND, Va. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Earl </PERSON> <PERSON> Clanton </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> went quietly to his death in the electric chair Thursday night for strangling a neighbor during a 1980 robbery. <PERSON> Clanton </PERSON>, 33, was pronounced dead at 11:07 p.m., six minutes after the first of two, one-minute jolts of 2,500 volts each was administered, said state <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corrections </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Wayne </PERSON> <PERSON> Farrar </PERSON>. <PERSON> Clanton </PERSON>, who had escaped from death row in 1984, had no final statement and showed little emotion as he went to his death. The prison chaplain, <PERSON> Russ </PERSON> <PERSON> Ford </PERSON>, turned his back on the electric chair as the sentence was carried out. A three-judge panel of the 4th U.S. <ORGANIZATION> Circuit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appeals </ORGANIZATION> earlier in the day had set the stage for the seventh execution in <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> since 1982 when it unanimously overturned a stay granted Tuesday by a federal judge. Later Thursday, the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>, in a 7-2 vote, denied a stay, and Gov. <PERSON> Gerald </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Baliles </PERSON> refused clemency an hour before <PERSON> Clanton </PERSON> went to his death. <PERSON> Clanton </PERSON> was convicted by a <LOCATION> Petersburg </LOCATION> jury in 1981 of murdering 38-year-old <PERSON> Wilhemina </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, a school librarian who lived in his apartment building. He was on parole at the time for a 1972 murder conviction in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION>. The execution was the 98th in the nation since the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> in 1976 allowed states to resume use of the death penalty. Besides his mother, a sister, two aunts and lawyers, <PERSON> Clanton </PERSON>'s last visitors included <PERSON> Jay </PERSON> <PERSON> North </PERSON>, the 1960s child TV star of `` <PERSON> Dennis </PERSON> the Menace. North has been working on a movie about the 1984 escape of <PERSON> Clanton </PERSON> and five other <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> death row prisoners. `` We became extremely close friends,'' said <PERSON> North </PERSON>. `` We've been in contant communication, wrote and called. We became like brothers.'' About 50 death penalty opponents conducted a vigil and prayer service outside the prison. A single supporter of capital punishment shouted, `` Pray for the woman that died.'' The appeal to the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> had centered on abuse <PERSON> Clanton </PERSON> contended he suffered as a child but did not disclose until after being sentenced to death. The appeal cited a psychiatric report saying <PERSON> Clanton </PERSON> suppressed memories of his violent childhood, thus hampering defense efforts to present mitigating evidence that could have resulted in a life sentence. However, the federal appeals court said that <PERSON> Clanton </PERSON>'s case had been given least 10 reviews in state and federal courts and that his sentencing had been found constitutional. In addition, the court said, <PERSON> Clanton </PERSON>'s attorney had failed during a previous federal appeal to raise the issue of abuse. <PERSON> Clanton </PERSON> was one of six death row inmates who escaped from the <ORGANIZATION> Mecklenburg </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Correctional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in 1984. He was recaptured a day later while eating cheese and drinking wine with another escapee at a coin laundry in <LOCATION> Warrenton </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.C. </LOCATION>. At his 1981 trial, <PERSON> Clanton </PERSON> refused his lawyer's request to submit to a psychiatric examination, and the only mitigating evidence presented to the jury at his sentencing hearing was that he attended Bible classes while in jail awaiting trial After the trial, <PERSON> Clanton </PERSON> said he was beaten as a child by his father and was sexually abused by his stepmother. After leaving his father, he moved to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> to live with his mother and was convicted of a murder. He was later paroled.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880414-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-14-88 0817EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--AlcoholBan     04-14 0147</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Alcohol Ban,0151</SECOND>
<HEAD>Students Rally Against Alcohol Ban</HEAD>
<DATELINE>AMHERST, Mass. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A rally of nearly 1,000 students at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Massachusetts </ORGANIZATION> to protest a ban on alcohol at outdoor events was the largest demonstration in recent memory, a school spokeswoman said. The spokeswoman, <PERSON> Jeanne </PERSON> <PERSON> Hopkins </PERSON>, said the demonstrators Wednesday outnumbered recent protests against the <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION>, apartheid and in support of minority students who occupied a campus building for six days. The alcohol ban was ordered last week by Chancellor <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Duffey </PERSON>. Several students at Wednesday's hourlong rally carried beer cans and chanted `` <PERSON> Joe </PERSON>'s got ta go!'' Half the crowd, some singing `` Give beer a chance,'' marched on the administration building, but protest leaders said <PERSON> Duffey </PERSON> refused to meet with them. Administrators, however, said he was having lunch elsewhere. Ms. <PERSON> Hopkins </PERSON> said the demonstration was orderly but probably would not change <PERSON> Duffey </PERSON>'s mind about the ban.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880414-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-14-88 0818EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--Nut&amp;HoneyProtest     04-14 0176</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Nut &amp; Honey Protest,0178</SECOND>
<HEAD>Won't Change Ads, Kellogg Says</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BATTLE CREEK, Mich. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Kellogg </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> has refused to change or cancel one of its TV commercials for <ORGANIZATION> Nut </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; Honey Crunch cereal, despite claims by an activist group that the ad promotes violence against homosexuals. In the commercials, cereal eaters play off the <ORGANIZATION> Nut </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; Honey name by answering the question of what they are eating with the reply, `` Nothing, honey.'' The Chicago-based <ORGANIZATION> Coalition </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Against </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Media-Marketing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Prejudice </ORGANIZATION> called `` offensive'' one version that shows a western chuck wagon cook being threatened by gun-toting cowboys who believe he has called them `` honey.'' The commercials `` send a serious and dangerous message _ that gays and lesbians or anyone perceived as sexually or behaviorally different are easy and acceptable targets for trivialization,'' the group said Wednesday outside <PERSON> Kellogg </PERSON> headquarters. <PERSON> Kellogg </PERSON>, however, said it would be overreacting to change the commercial or pull it off the air. The company refused to accept evidence from experts on psychology, advertising and violence who backed the group's claim, said spokesman <PERSON> Arthur </PERSON>
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880414-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-14-88 0032EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-RiceStatue     04-14 0268</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Rice Statue,0277</SECOND>
<HEAD>Pranksters Make Statue Do About-Face</HEAD>
<DATELINE>HOUSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The one ton bronze statue of <ORGANIZATION> Rice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> founder <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Marsh </PERSON> <PERSON> Rice </PERSON> has been festooned with such things as hats, coats and military regalia since it was placed on campus 58 years ago. But on Tuesday, it was facing south instead of north. Just before dawn, a campus police officer spotted about 20 people around the statue and noticed a spotlight that usually illuminates it was dark. As he approached, the group scattered, said <ORGANIZATION> Campus </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION> Chief <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Voswinkel </PERSON>. Ms. <PERSON> Voswinkel </PERSON> said the officer was able to stop one student, who was driving a pickup truck away from the quadrangle. The officer took the student's name and let him go, then sped back to the statue to investigate. The statue appeared intact _ but was facing the <LOCATION> Fondren </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Library </LOCATION> to the south instead of the Lovett Building to the north. It took 3 -LCB- hours for a crew of professional movers using a crane to fix the statue. `` It was a student prank,'' said <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Noblitt </PERSON>, <PERSON> Rice </PERSON>'s director of university relations. `` It was a rite-of-spring type thing.'' <PERSON> Noblitt </PERSON> said the vandalism could have had serious consequences because students apparently used an A-frame built from 4-by-6 beams to lift the statue. The devices that were found had cracked, and the statue could have fallen. The pranksters apparently climbed to the roof of the Architecture Building to disconnect the spotlight and had painted the A-frame black to help conceal it. The student who was questioned will face disciplinary action from the university, but officials did not release further details.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880414-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-14-88 0033EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-APArts:StandandDeliver     04-14 1068</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AP Arts: Stand and Deliver,1095</SECOND>
<HEAD>Teacher Hopes Hollywood Spotlight Inspires Others to Excel</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By BARBARA METZLER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>EAST LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Jaime </PERSON> <PERSON> Escalante </PERSON> focuses on the blackboard with absorbed frustration. Reporters and photographers have invaded his classroom, and he's concerned his students are losing their concentration. Although his life and unorthodox teaching methods are the subject of the critically acclaimed film `` Stand and Deliver,'' <PERSON> Escalante </PERSON> has more important things on his mind _ like mathematics and helping his <ORGANIZATION> James </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Garfield </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> High </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> students to learn as much as they can. `` We have so many people working at <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> in the Box -LRB- fast-food restaurants -RRB- and pumping gas,'' he said. Like the movie teacher portrayed by actor <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Olmos </PERSON>, <PERSON> Escalante </PERSON> wants more for his students, and pushes them to excel in math and use it as their ticket out of menial jobs. `` It's like a sport,'' he said. `` You have to practice every day to be in shape.'' His scrapbooks chronicle the victories of his mathematical athletes. Photos show beaming students holding banners heralding their achievements. Each year the number of <PERSON> Escalante </PERSON> students passing the Advanced Placement calculus test, given by the <ORGANIZATION> Educational </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Testing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> for college credit, has grown tremendously. In 1979, five students took the test and all had a passing mark of 3 or better. By last year, 87 <PERSON> Garfield </PERSON> students passed the test, higher than any other school in <LOCATION> Southern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>. The movie concerns an incident in 1982, when 18 students took the exam and all passed. Surprised that the predominantly Hispanic class had performed so well in a school that was about to lose its academic accreditation, the <ORGANIZATION> ETS </ORGANIZATION> accused the students of cheating. Twelve took the retest and passed with either perfect scores of 5 or near perfect scores of 4. Last year, scores made by <PERSON> Garfield </PERSON> students taking the Advanced Placement calculus test placed <PERSON> Garfield </PERSON> second in the nation out of the 4,197 schools with students taking the tough exam, said <PERSON> Janice </PERSON> <PERSON> Gams </PERSON> with the <ORGANIZATION> Educational </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Testing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>. Just 2 percent of American students even attempt the test. This year, a record 160 <PERSON> Garfield </PERSON> students are expected to take the test, and <PERSON> Escalante </PERSON> has set his sights on attracting even more students to calculus classes in the 10 more years he plans to continue teaching. `` He's your friend, he's your mentor and he's your father,'' said former student <PERSON> Josie </PERSON> <PERSON> Richkarday </PERSON>, who was one of the 18 students suspected of cheating. `` He just did n't teach,'' said <PERSON> Richkarday </PERSON>, 23, who is studying to be a math teacher herself. `` He brought something out of me. If you're willing to go 50 yards, he'll go 100.'' <PERSON> Escalante </PERSON> has seen `` Stand and Deliver'' four times and likes it, although he says 90 percent is true and 10 percent is hype because the <ORGANIZATION> Warner </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bros. </ORGANIZATION> release depicts more gang activity than really exists and portrays the families and neighborhoods as more destitute than they really are. His students have become doctors and engineers. They work at the <ORGANIZATION> Jet </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Propulsion </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Laboratory </ORGANIZATION>, which does work for <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION>, and for <ORGANIZATION> TRW </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, and <ORGANIZATION> Atlantic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Richfield </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Armando </PERSON> <PERSON> Islas </PERSON>, a 1976 <PERSON> Garfield </PERSON> graduate and an oral surgeon with two offices in the <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> area, credits <PERSON> Escalante </PERSON> with challenging him to be more than a C student with athletic talent `` He was a fantastic instructor,'' <PERSON> Islas </PERSON> said. `` He kept you motivated, and his method of teaching was kind of unorthodox but I think in that particular environment that's what you needed.'' In the 14 years <PERSON> Escalante </PERSON> has been at <LOCATION> Garfield </LOCATION>, he has watched the gang influence dissipate, due mostly to a tough line by school administrators and teachers. The graffiti is more or less gone. And, thanks in part to the reputation of <PERSON> Escalante </PERSON>'s math achievers, the school is respected within the mostly Hispanic barrio, where neatly kept stucco homes reflect community pride. The days when students did n't want to go to <LOCATION> Garfield </LOCATION> are over, said <PERSON> Principal </PERSON> <PERSON> Maria </PERSON> <PERSON> Tostado </PERSON>, who grew up in the area. `` There's no longer the defeatist attitude that no matter what you do you're not going to get ahead,'' she said. Today, the school is well-known for academic prowess. <PERSON> Escalante </PERSON>, a 57-year-old father of two sons, was a respected teacher in <LOCATION> Bolivia </LOCATION> for 11 years before coming to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> at his wife's urging in 1964. Once here, he tried a career in computers but the work lacked the spirit of teaching. `` I got real tired,'' he said in an interview. `` I did n't want to deal anymore with the printouts or schematics.'' Now he spends his days in a stage-like arena before as many as 52 students who sit on tiered rows, and demands that late comers get `` The Chair,'' a tot's seat meant to embarrass tardy students into promptness. His classroom is plastered with posters designed to motivate. A foot-high banner curls around the room's corners, greeting students with: `` Calculus need not be made easy; it is easy already.'' Another poster tells students what they can expect to feel if they master math: `` Feel ready to attend any college or university. Feel prepared to go into real estate, business, engineering. Feel really good about myself.'' The students do feel good about themselves. Boredom is replaced with laughter, smiles and friendly jests, as <PERSON> Escalante </PERSON> tries to reach them through cheers, swats them with a battered and faded pillow, practices an imaginary ski swish and does practically anything to promote learning. He was given the nickname `` <PERSON> Kimo </PERSON> <PERSON> Sabe </PERSON>'' by four gang toughs in his class. The name translates loosely from <LOCATION> Spanish </LOCATION> as `` the one who knows.'' He's accepted the nickname, but shakes off such glorious titles as `` American hero,'' which <ORGANIZATION> Newsweek </ORGANIZATION> dubbed him in a recent story about the movie and teacher behind it. `` What I tried to do is improve things in my school,'' he said. `` He's a master,'' said <PERSON> Tostado </PERSON>, describing <PERSON> Escalante </PERSON>'s teaching `` He's a genius at it.'' News crews file in and out of his classroom almost daily now, but while the media intrusion disturbs him, <PERSON> Escalante </PERSON> believes the rewards from the movie's exposure will offset the <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION> glare. `` It's going to motivate parents to control, to help ... because the schools alone can not educate,'' he said. `` It's going to motivate the students. The teachers are going to see it's better to teach the way this guy does and and not from the desk.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880414-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-14-88 0036EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-APArts:Olmos     04-14 0560</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AP Arts: Olmos,0575</SECOND>
<HEAD>`Miami Vice' Star Goes Home to Make Movie</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By DONALD W. SWINTON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NORTH MIAMI BEACH, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The working class neighborhood that taught <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Olmos </PERSON> respect for humanity and watched the `` Miami Vice'' star mature into an acclaimed actor is home to his latest movie. <PERSON> Olmos </PERSON> returned to an <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> high school last spring to make `` Stand and Deliver,'' a movie about a magnetic, demanding math teacher who led an unruly Hispanic class to academic triumph in 1982. The 41-year-old actor was no stranger to the halls of <ORGANIZATION> Garfield </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> High </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION>. His cousin teaches computer science there. Only 1 -LCB- miles from his childhood home, it is ethnically mixed, like the neighborhood he remembers. `` Stand and Deliver'' was a smash when it opened in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>. It brought in $ 411,000 during its first week last month, averaging $ 14,000 at each of 30 theaters, he said. <PERSON> Olmos </PERSON>, an actor of <PERSON> Mexican-American </PERSON> heritage who won an Emmy Award for his role as Lt. <PERSON> Castillo </PERSON> on the <ORGANIZATION> NBC-TV </ORGANIZATION> series `` Miami Vice,'' was delighted with the movie and its reception in his home area. `` This film is probably the most inspirational film I've done to date,'' he said of the <ORGANIZATION> Warner </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bros. </ORGANIZATION> release. `` Stand and Deliver'' is about overcoming racial stigmas. It advances the humanities, something <PERSON> Olmos </PERSON> said he holds close to his heart; something he learned in a family of eight living in a neighborhood crowded with <LOCATION> Russian </LOCATION>, Mexican, Jewish and American Indian families. <PERSON> Olmos </PERSON>, who co-produced and helped write the movie, claims he is not making a political point. `` I'm not a political animal,'' he said. It's the advancement of the humanities through acting that inspires <PERSON> Olmos </PERSON>. `` It's always been that way. It serves me well and makes me stronger,'' he said. `` That does n't mean I have to make message movies. I think that art forms, especially films, should be used to entertain. Now if by chance your entertaining and allowing -LRB- your audience -RRB- to experience an event that has some value and some substance and some awareness to it, well even better. `` The criterion, No. 1, is the story. If that story happens to be socially relevant, well that's wonderful, but if it is n't, that's OK too.'' `` Stand and Deliver'' is about an event that drew national attention to <ORGANIZATION> Garfield </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> High </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION>'s 1982 calculus class. The predominantly Hispanic class took and passed an Advance Placement calculus test, in stark contrast to the rest of the school, which faced loss of accreditation. The 18 students, who were badgered and inspired by computer specialist-turned-teacher <PERSON> Jaime </PERSON> <PERSON> Escalante </PERSON>, were stripped of their honors when the <ORGANIZATION> Educational </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Testing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>, which tests <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> students and provides their scores to colleges and universities, accused the entire class of cheating. In the movie, <PERSON> Olmos </PERSON>, in his role as <PERSON> Escalante </PERSON>, accuses the Educational Testing Service of racism. Students from wealthy <PERSON> Beverly </PERSON> <PERSON> Hills </PERSON> would not be questioned if they passed an Advance Placement calculus test, but students with Hispanic names from a barrio high school were suspect, he says in the movie. Eventually, the students are vindicated with a second test. The movie is not meant to be manipulative, <PERSON> Olmos </PERSON> said. It presents an event `` that allows you to experience with your own values.'' `` We do n't give results,'' he said. `` We only give the facts.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880414-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-14-88 0037EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Scotch&amp;Water     04-14 0226</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Scotch &amp; Water,0230</SECOND>
<HEAD>Whisky-Maker Says San Francisco Water Not Good Enough</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SAN FRANCISCO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The drought-threatened <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION> region is getting a little help from an unlikely quarter _ the makers of Famous Grouse Scotch whisky. The manufacturers of the liquor, <ORGANIZATION> Matthew </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Gloag </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; Sons of <LOCATION> Perth </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Scotland </LOCATION>, kicked off their latest <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> sales campaign, but decided they could n't bear the thought that <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Franciscans </LOCATION> might mix their prized whisky with local tap water. `` The fact is that <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> tap water does not taste very good,'' said local Famous Grouse spokesman <PERSON> Ed </PERSON> <PERSON> Schwartz </PERSON>. So this month, it started selling a $ 14 package containing the scotch and a bottle of water from <LOCATION> Great </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Strathmore </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION>, a combination the company says is necessary to bring out the best features of the liquor. `` Serious scotch drinkers in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> have been loath to mix Famous Grouse with the infamous chlorinated city water,'' read several hundred invitations to a scotch and bagpipe bash Wednesday at a chic watering hole. Famous Grouse, stung by the mere 1.5 gallon-per-capita consumption of distilled spirits in this country, is trying to heighten the figure with a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> campaign initially targeting <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> D.C </ORGANIZATION>. In the Bay region, a fringe benefit will be to ease ever so slightly the water shortage threatened by an exceptionally dry winter.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880414-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-14-88 0039EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Afghan-Chronology     04-14 0831</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Afghan-Chronology,0857</SECOND>
<HEAD>A Chronology of the War in Afghanistan</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Afghan-Signing, Bjt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ISLAMABAD, Pakistan (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here is a chronology of some some of the main events in the war in <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>: April 1978 _ The <ORGANIZATION> Marxist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Afghanistan </ORGANIZATION> overthrows the Afghan republic headed by <PERSON> Mohammad </PERSON> <PERSON> Daoud </PERSON> and installs <PERSON> Nur </PERSON> <PERSON> Mohammad </PERSON> <PERSON> Taraki </PERSON> as president. <PERSON> Daoud </PERSON>, his family and hundreds of his supporters are killed. The armed, non-communist resistance begins. Feb. 14, 1979 _ <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> ambassador <PERSON> Adolph </PERSON> <PERSON> Dubs </PERSON> is kidnapped and killed in <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> blames `` enemies of the government'' trying to `` destroy friendship between <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>.'' March 12, 1979, the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION>, a Moslem group, calls for a Jihad, or Holy War, against the <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION> government. July 1979 _ The Soviets deploy their first combat unit in <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>, a 400-man airborne battalion sent to <LOCATION> Bagram </LOCATION>, just north of <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION>. September 1979 _ Prime Minister <PERSON> Hafizullah </PERSON> <PERSON> Amin </PERSON> gains control of the government after a shootout at the presidential palace. Official media announce <PERSON> Taraki </PERSON>'s resignation and <PERSON> Amin </PERSON>'s appointment as president. October 1979 _ Official <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION> media announce <PERSON> Taraki </PERSON>'s death. December 1979 _ During the last week of the month, a massive Soviet airlift occurs with 300 transports and 5,000 troops. Soviet commandos attack the presidential palace. <PERSON> Amin </PERSON> is killed and <PERSON> Babrak </PERSON> <PERSON> Karmal </PERSON> becomes president. January 1980 _ Soviets deploy 40,000 more troops in <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION> votes 104-18 for a resolution demanding an `` immediate, unconditional and total withdrawal of foreign troops'' from that country. February 1980 _ Soviet troop strength increases to 75,000, and eventually to 115,000, by Western estimates. April 1982 _ The <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> High Commissioner for Refugees says the number of Afghan refugees in <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> has passed 2.5 million. June 182 _ In <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION>, U.N. Undersecretary for Political Affairs <PERSON> Diego </PERSON> <PERSON> Cordovez </PERSON> conducts the first indirect peace talks between officials of <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION> represents the Soviets and <LOCATION> Islamabad </LOCATION> speaks for the Afghan resistance. January 1984 _ Guerrillas gain temporary control of <LOCATION> Kandahar </LOCATION>, the second-largest city in <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>. April 1984 _ Soviets, for the first time, conduct saturation bombing of guerrilla strongholds and villages, using TU-16 Badger heavy bombers. August 1984 _ <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> lodges a series of protests with the <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION> government over repeated aerial bombing and cross-border shelling in which 51 Afghans and Pakistanis were killed and 33 injured. May 1985 _ The <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Strategic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Studies </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> estimates the Soviets have suffered 20,000 to 25,000 casualties in the 5-year-old war. In <LOCATION> Peshawar </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>, an alliance of fundamentalist Moslem guerrillas joins a grouping of moderates to form the seven-party <ORGANIZATION> Islamic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Unity </ORGANIZATION> of Afghan group. June 1985 _ Mutinous Afghan air force officers blow up 20 Afghan air force planes at an air base in western <PERSON> Farah </PERSON> province. May 1986 _ <PERSON> Karmal </PERSON> steps down, reportedly for health reasons. Western observers claim it is due to <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>'s dissatisfaction at his failure to defeat the armed resistance. He is succeeded by <PERSON> Najib </PERSON>, a physician and former chief of state security. July 1986 _ Soviet leader <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> announces plans to withdraw six regiments from <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> later says the forces mainly were unnecessary anti-aircraft units, and were replaced by armored regiments. September 1986 _ Guerrillas reportedly receive their first <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Stinger and British Blowpipe anti-aircraft missiles. Within months, they reportedly shoot down an average of one enemy aircraft a day. January 1987 _ <PERSON> Najib </PERSON> declares a unilateral cease-fire as part of a new program of national reconciliation. It is ignored by both sides, and the guerrillas reject any power-sharing with the Communists. October 1987 _ A survey conducted by <ORGANIZATION> Geneva </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> Professor <PERSON> Marek </PERSON> <PERSON> Sliwinski </PERSON> for Gallup <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> estimates that more than 1.2 million Afghans have died in the war. The <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> High Commissioner for refugees estimates that 2.9 million Afghans have fled to <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> and 2.3 million to <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>. December 1987 _ One of <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s chief advisers tells reporters he expects the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> to pull out of <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> in 1988. January 1988 _ <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> President <PERSON> Mohammad </PERSON> <PERSON> Zia </PERSON> <PERSON> ul-Haq </PERSON> declares his acceptance for some Communist involvement in a future Afghan government as the price for a Soviet withdrawal. <PERSON> Cordovez </PERSON> begins a 20-day diplomatic shuttle mission between <LOCATION> Islamabad </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION>. February 1988 _ <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> offers to withdraw Soviet troops beginning May 15 and ending 10 months later, if a <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> accord is signed by March 15. <PERSON> Cordovez </PERSON> meets for the first time with Afghan guerrilla leaders. He concludes his shuttle mission in <LOCATION> Islamabad </LOCATION>, announcing near-agreement on terms of a Soviet pullout and a new round of <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> talks starting March 2. March 1988 _ Indirect talks between <LOCATION> Islamabad </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION> resume with <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and Soviet delegations standing by. Agreement is reached that Soviet troop withdrawal must be completed within nine months once it starts. But negotations continue past <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s March 15 target date. April 1988 _ Agreement is reached and April 14 date set for signing in <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> the accord on Soviet troop withdrawal, return of refugees and other issues.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880414-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-14-88 0016EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-Farrakhan-Penn 1stLd-Writethru a0841 04-14 0651</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Farrakhan-Penn, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0841,0666</SECOND>
<HEAD>Opposition, But No Violence A Farrakhan Speaks On Penn Campus</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: New throughout to UPDATE with quotes from speech as
delivered, add that university disputes number of people at rally.
No pickup.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By LEE LINDER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PHILADELPHIA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Nation of Islam leader <PERSON> Louis </PERSON> <PERSON> Farrakhan </PERSON> told a cheering audience at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pennsylvania </ORGANIZATION> `` you should thank God <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> has emerged'' as a leading presidential candidate. The black Muslim minister, whose appearance set off a week of controversy and a protest rally by up to 1,000 people, brought most of the 2,000 in the auditorium to their feet when he said, `` <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> is running to save a people; he is running to save the nation. `` <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> is growing up to respect men of wisdom in black skins, but it has n't grown up yet,'' <PERSON> Farrakhan </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, during his 1984 presidential campaign, accepted <PERSON> Farrakhan </PERSON>'s support, leading to harsh criticism, particularly from Jews. <PERSON> Farrakhan </PERSON> has been reported to have praised <PERSON> Hitler </PERSON> and called Judaism a gutter religion, but he denied Wednesday ever making the statements. During this campaign, <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> has had no contact with <PERSON> Farrakhan </PERSON>. The Muslim minister, whose visit was guarded by strict security measures that cost the university $ 6,000, insisted that those opposing <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, especially in the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> primary next week in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, are using `` me to galvanize Jews against <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>.'' `` They are using me to try to derail him,'' he added. The comments came in two-hour speech in which he predicted, without being specific, that `` a very dark and tragic day is coming to <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, to <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> and to humanity.'' Over and over <PERSON> Farrakhan </PERSON> told how whites dominate the western world. Referring to the days, more than 125 years ago, when blacks were slaves in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Farrakhan </PERSON> said he was joining `` my dear Jewish friends in saying ` never again,''' referring to the phrase Jews use in condemning the Nazi Holocaust. `` I am considered a hater, but I am a reminder to the black people of what has happened to us,'' he said. `` For if we forget it will happen again.'' Before his evening speech, the black Muslim minister said the community would benefit by the controvery his visit has generated. `` Even though the atmosphere is charged, I did not charge it,'' he said at a news conference. `` My presence hopefully will help the students to judge me better.'' Students gathered for an hour-long demonstration before the speech, waving signs saying: `` Unity, Yes. Anti-Semitism, No.'' and `` Free Speech, Yes. Hatred, No.'' `` No matter what <PERSON> Farrahkan </PERSON> says, it does n't erase what he said in the past,'' said <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Genulka </PERSON>, the rally organizer and chairman of the Council of Jewish Students. `` We must work together as a community instead of being at odds.'' Last week, university officials refused a Jewish group's request to cancel the visit, saying they respected <PERSON> Farrakhan </PERSON>'s right to free speech. A letter condemning <PERSON> Farrakhan </PERSON> and signed by more than 700 students and teachers appeared in the Wednesday student paper. The visit comes in the wake of the 18-month suspension of a predominantly Jewish fraternity for hiring two black women to perform as strippers at a party. Party-goers reportedly shouted racial epithets. University President <PERSON> Sheldon </PERSON> <PERSON> Hackney </PERSON> defended the Farrakhan visit. `` In an academic community, open expression is the most fundemental value. We ca n't have free speech just some of the time for some of the people,'' he told the rally. Security officers estimated the number of protesters at 1,000, but university spokesman <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> White </PERSON> said no more than 400 attended the rally and the others were waiting to clear the tight security into the auditorium where <PERSON> Farrakhan </PERSON> was speeking. The sell-out crowd of 2,000 paid $ 4 apiece to see <PERSON> Farrakan </PERSON>, who received $ 10,000 plus travel expenses from the two groups sponsoring the appearance: the <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Black </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Consciousness </ORGANIZATION> and the predominantly white <ORGANIZATION> Penn </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Political </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880414-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-14-88 0043EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Afghan-Accord-Glance     04-14 0136</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Afghan-Accord-Glance,0144</SECOND>
<HEAD>Provisions of Afghan Agreement</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Afghan-Signing, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here, at a glance, are the main features of the agreement to withdraw Soviet troops from <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>. The provisions, outlined before the signing today in <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION>, include: _ Withdrawal of all Soviet troops within nine months starting May 15, with half the total gone by Aug. 15 _ Pledges by <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> of non-interference in each other's affairs _ Voluntary return of about 5 million Afghan refugees from <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> _ Supervision of the settlement and the return of refugees by the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> _ Guarantees from the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>'s future non-alignment In addition, a U.S.-Soviet understanding will allow <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> to continue military aid to the Afghan guerrillas, and <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> to continue sending arms to the Afghan government.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880414-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-14-88 0049EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lites     04-14 0445</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lites,0461</SECOND>
<HEAD>On The Lite Side</HEAD>
<DATELINE>FORT MADISON, Iowa (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 There's not much you can buy for a penny these days. But with 1,000,131 of them, you can make your way into the Guinness Book of World Records. This weekend, a local group trying to raise money for a $ 40,000 playground will try to lay down at least that many coins in a high school gymnasium to set a world record in length for a line of pennies. Volunteers plan to begin creating 58 lanes 3 feet wide and 44 feet long on the gym floor Friday night. When they are finished sometime Saturday, they hope to have 1,540,500 pennies set down in rows an inch apart, creating a line 13.66 miles long. The Guinness-recognized record is 1,000,130 one-cent coins put down in a 12.29-mile line Nov. 15, 1985, by students at <ORGANIZATION> Blacktown </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Girls </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ' </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> High </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Wales </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION>. `` We figured out that, in order to accomplish the whole thing in a 12-hour period, we would have to lay down something like 30 pennies a second,'' volunteer coordinator <PERSON> Carolyn </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> said. Coordinators have lined up 30 people for each two-hour shift of penny-laying. The group also has planned ahead how to get the pennies picked up after the record attempt. `` We'll start vacuuming them up on Sunday morning,'' said volunteer <PERSON> Martha </PERSON> <PERSON> Wolf </PERSON>. The group received donations for the effort from children, businesses and service groups. One problem, however, was that the three banks in <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Madison </LOCATION> only keep about $ 300 each in pennies at one time. The banks arranged for 800,000 pennies to be shipped in by armored car from <LOCATION> Davenport </LOCATION>, and paid $ 1,000 to have the pennies wrapped and shipped, which took about three weeks.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>TALLAHASSEE, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 State officials are n't quite ready to file for a patent, but they're definitely taking a `` pro-pie-tary'' interest in Key lime pie. Under a bill approved in committee Wednesday, the creamy concoction would be designated the official state pie. Key lime pie, legislators explain, is `` properly'' made only with limes from the <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Keys </LOCATION>. State symbols are serious business in identity-conscious <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>, which already has a state tree, beverage, shell, stone, gem, animal, freshwater and saltwater fish, marine and saltwater mammal, air fair, festival and litter control symbol. In 1987, lawmakers designated the American alligator as the official state reptile. According to a committee staff analysis, `` by being officially designated, the Key lime pie would be in greater demand, thereby promoting this fruit unique to <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>.'' The Intergovernmental Relations Subcommittee of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Community </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Affairs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> voted 5-0 for the bill, which must be now be approved by the full House.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880414-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-14-88 0059EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Afghan-Questions     04-14 0468</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Afghan-Questions,0484</SECOND>
<HEAD>Q &amp; A on Afghan Settlement</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Afghan-Signing, Bjt</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By TONY CZUCZKA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>GENEVA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here in question and answer form is a discussion of the <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> agreement: Q: Who is involved in the settlement? A: Signing the documents were the Soviet-supported Afghan government in <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION> and neighboring <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>, in which 3 million Afghan refugees live, with the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> signing as guarantors. The mujahedeen gurrellias who have been fighting the Afghan government and the Soviet troops in <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> have not signed and have vowed to carry on their struggle to establish an Islamic government. <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>, which shelters about 2 million Afghan refugees, did not participate in the <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> talks. Q: What is in the four-part accord? A: The text of the accord was being published only after the signing, but <ORGANIZATION> U.N </ORGANIZATION> mediator <PERSON> Diego </PERSON> <PERSON> Cordovez </PERSON> and spokesman for the parties involved outlined the provisions. The documents include Afghan-Pakistani agreements for non-interference and non-intervention in each other's affairs and for the safe and voluntary return of Afghan refugees. Another part are <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and Soviet declarations guaranteeing <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>'s future non-alignment and the rest of the settlement. A fourth document sets the timetable for the withdrawal of Soviet troops and ties the other three together. Soviet leader <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> has said the pullout of an estimated 115,000 Soviet troops will begin May 15. The process is to be completed within nine months but <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> has indicated it hopes to bring the last soldier home early. Q: How will compliance be monitored? A: An annex sets up a <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> supervisory role for the settlement. About 50 <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> officers in <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> will monitor implementation until two months after all refugees return. The repatriation will be overseen by the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> high commissioner for refugees. Q: Will the settlement stop the civil war? A: The mujahedeen alliance of Moslem guerrillas says it will continue fighting until Soviet troops leave and the Marxist <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION> government is overthrown. The <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION> government has said it will continue to exercise power. Both sides are well armed and believed capable of carrying on the fighting. <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> is convinced the bloodshed will not end, and the refugees will not return, until the creation of an interim Afghan government. The <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> says <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>'s political future is for its people to decide. Q: What about superpower support of the rivals? A: The accords say nothing about that. But the superpowers have reached an understanding allowing both to continue aid _ the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> to the <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION> government and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> to the mujahedeen. Diplomats have said the understanding is that arms shipments will be phased out, with each superpower reserving the right to resume arms supplies if the other does so.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880414-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-14-88 0019EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-DEAGuns     04-14 0328</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-DEA Guns,0338</SECOND>
<HEAD>DEA Agents Will Carry More Firepower</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MIAMI (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Federal agents fighting <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s war against drugs got a hefty boost of firepower Wednesday with the announcement here that they will carry semi-automatic submachine guns. Each of <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>'s 341 <ORGANIZATION> Drug </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Enforcement </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> agents will be issued a 9mm Colt semi-automatic submachine gun that will fire three bursts every time an agent pulls the trigger, officials said. The increased firepower was welcome news for <ORGANIZATION> DEA </ORGANIZATION> agents who until now had to go into battle carrying six-shot, .38 - caliber handguns and shotguns against drug dealers firing 50 and 100 rounds a pop from fully automatic <PERSON> Uzi </PERSON> and Mac-10 machine <ORGANIZATION> DEA </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Hook </PERSON> called it parity. `` It gives you a sense of confidence we never had in <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> in the last 10 years with the .38 revolver. Anybody who levels a gun at a <ORGANIZATION> DEA </ORGANIZATION> agent now is going to have some problems,'' said Hook. All 3,000 <ORGANIZATION> DEA </ORGANIZATION> agents will be issued submachine guns as quickly as possible, officials said, but <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> was chosen to be first because it is a mecca for drug dealers. From October to January, the <ORGANIZATION> DEA </ORGANIZATION> seized 31 machine guns nationally. Of those, 11 were seized in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>. The Colt <ORGANIZATION> SMG </ORGANIZATION> weighs 5.75 pounds and is nearly 29 inches long. <ORGANIZATION> DEA </ORGANIZATION>'s version is modified to carry a clip of 32 rounds of 9mm ammunition. The <ORGANIZATION> DEA </ORGANIZATION> is not using fully automatic guns because of concerns about the safety of bystanders, <PERSON> Hook </PERSON> said. Automatic guns tend to spray wildly and have muzzles that are difficult to control, he said. The <ORGANIZATION> DEA </ORGANIZATION> is the first federal agency to routinely issue submachine guns. Customs and <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> still carry .38 - and .357 - As of Wednesday, all <ORGANIZATION> DEA </ORGANIZATION> agents were also issued 15-shot 9mm automatic sidearms as their primary, personal weapons. The submachine gun is considered secondary firepower. The price of the guns was not disclosed. <PERSON> Hook </PERSON> said that was a government secret.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880414-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-14-88 0133EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--Niger-Condoms     04-14 0141</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Niger-Condoms,0145</SECOND>
<HEAD>Government Authorizes Use of Contraception</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NIAMEY, Niger (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The government authorized the use of contraceptives to help control population growth and the spread of disease. The move was regarded as significant in a predominantly Moslem country of 7 million people, where the use of contraceptives has been illegal without a doctor's prescription since independence from <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> in 1960. The government said on Wednesday the use of condoms, diaphragms and spercmicides would no longer require a doctor's prescription. The communique did not say if the government also would begin distributing contraceptives. <LOCATION> Niger </LOCATION>, located in the arid <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> African </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sahel </LOCATION>, suffers from recurring serious food shortages related to drought and poor farm land. Its population is growing at an annual rate of 2.9 percent. The government has predicted the population will grow to 10 million by the year 2000.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880414-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-14-88 0133EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--Britain-Smell     04-14 0113</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Britain-Smell,0115</SECOND>
<HEAD>Gas-Like Smell Causes Evacuation Of Busy Shopping Street</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Thousands of people were evacuated from one of <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>'s busiest shopping districts after an odor thought to be caused by a gas leak permeated the area, police said. Three hours after clearing a 1 square mile area of <LOCATION> Oxford </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Street </LOCATION> on Wednesday, city gas officials determined a gas leak had not occurred. The cause of the smell was not determined, a police spokesman said. The spokesman, who was not named in keeping with <LOCATION> British </LOCATION> custom, said `` some theories were that it was sewage, another theory said it was diesel -LRB- fuel oil -RRB- leaking from a bus, but no one knows.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880414-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-14-88 0218EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-People-Hepburn     04-14 0187</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-People-Hepburn,0193</SECOND>
<HEAD>Actress Audrey Hepburn Campaigns Against World Hunger</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actress <PERSON> Audrey </PERSON> <PERSON> Hepburn </PERSON>, who visited drought-stricken <LOCATION> Ethiopia </LOCATION> recently, joined <ORGANIZATION> UNICEF </ORGANIZATION> officials in calling for help in the battle against world hunger. `` To save a single child is a blessing ... to save millions of children is a God-given opportunity presented to us by <ORGANIZATION> UNICEF </ORGANIZATION>,'' the 58-year-old actress said Wednesday at a news conference. <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON>, the international children's fund president and chief executive, announced <ORGANIZATION> UNICEF </ORGANIZATION>'s latest drive to raise $ 22 million for medicine, vaccines and other non-food relief. `` We have the means of cutting by half the present global death rate of 38,000 children each day ... and I find it unconscionable that these children should die of preventable causes,'' <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Hepburn </PERSON>'s eyes glistened with tears as she described the poor, starving children she saw in <LOCATION> Ethiopia </LOCATION> while accompanying <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> for five days in mid-March. She noted that as an adolescent in <LOCATION> Holland </LOCATION> after World War II, she was the recipient of food from a <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> relief agency. `` Without that nutrition, my health might well have been impaired for life,'' she said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880414-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-14-88 0133EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--Nigeria-Corrupt     04-14 0109</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Nigeria-Corrupt,0111</SECOND>
<HEAD>14 Traffic Officers Arrested For Corruption</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LAGOS, Nigeria (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Detectives arrested 14 police officers working at police checkpoints around <LOCATION> Lagos </LOCATION> for allegedly demanding bribes from motorists, a <LOCATION> Lagos </LOCATION> newspaper reported. The detectives raided several checkpoints Tuesday on a 20-mile span of highway between <LOCATION> Lagos </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Ogun </LOCATION> state, the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Concord </ORGANIZATION> reported. One of the officers arrested was an assistant police superintendent. The equivalent of $ 75 in Nigerian currency was found under the floor mat of a squad car at one checkpoint, the newspaper reported Wednesday. Authorities began a crackdown on police corruption because of complaints from the public and recent violent anti-police demonstrations in <LOCATION> Lagos </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880414-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-14-88 0031EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-Iran-Embargo     04-14 0392</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Iran-Embargo,0404</SECOND>
<HEAD>2 Companies Accused Of Violating Embargo With Defense-Related
Sales</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SAN DIEGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> authorities unsealed three indictments Wednesday involving two companies accused of selling radar navigational equipment to <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> in violation of a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> embargo. The companies named in the indictments are <ORGANIZATION> Marsh </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aviation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, of <LOCATION> Mesa </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ariz. </LOCATION>, and <ORGANIZATION> Beechcraft </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Vertrieb </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Und </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> company of <LOCATION> Munich </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, said <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Attorney <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Nunez </PERSON> at a news conference. <PERSON> Marsh </PERSON>'s owner, <PERSON> Floyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Stilwell </PERSON>, 61, of <LOCATION> Phoenix </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ariz. </LOCATION>, was arrested Wednesday in <LOCATION> Phoenix </LOCATION> and arraigned on charges of exportation of defense articles, conspiracy to export items to <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>, and making false statements to authorities, <PERSON> Nunez </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Hans </PERSON> <PERSON> Schneider </PERSON>, 57, who owns <ORGANIZATION> Beechcraft </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Vertrieb </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Und </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>, is charged with conspiracy to export equipment to <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>, exportation of defense articles, and making false statements to authorities, he said. The indictments were the result of an investigation prompted by a tip from <ORGANIZATION> Teledyne </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ryan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Electronics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> San </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Diego </ORGANIZATION> and aided by two West Germans who have pleaded guilty to related charges, he said. The charges against both companies and their owners stem from the alleged diversion of U.S.-made equipment from <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>, which shops around the world for military equipment for its war with <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>. An export embargo on U.S.-made equipment was first placed on <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> by President <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> during the height of the American hostage crisis. <PERSON> Stilwell </PERSON> allegedly submitted false export information to <PERSON> Teledyne </PERSON> <PERSON> Ryan </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, and the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Customs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>, in an attempt to conceal that the equipment's final destination was <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Stilwell </PERSON>, who was arraigned in <LOCATION> Phoenix </LOCATION> on Wednesday, is scheduled to be extradited to <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Diego </LOCATION> to appear in court Monday. The Sept. 25, 1987, indictment against <PERSON> Schneider </PERSON> accuses him of directing his managing director, <PERSON> Bernd </PERSON> <PERSON> Pleuger </PERSON>, to continue negotiating and servicing Iranian contracts with the illegal diversion of equipment through their company. <PERSON> Schneider </PERSON>'s company sells service and distributes parts for <ORGANIZATION> Beechcraft </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aircraft </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Wichita </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Kan. </LOCATION>, and other aircraft part manufacturers. <PERSON> Nunez </PERSON> said he doubted that <PERSON> Schneider </PERSON> will be extradited to stand trial in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Diego </LOCATION> because the offenses he faces do not warrant extradition under the West German extradition treaty. <PERSON> Pleuger </PERSON>, 51, of <LOCATION> Stuttgarde </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, and <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Juergen </PERSON> <PERSON> Zimmermann </PERSON>, 37, of <LOCATION> Augsberg </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, have pleaded guilty to conspiracy charges in the case and have been cooperating in the investigation, <PERSON> Nunez </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880414-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-14-88 0219EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-BabyDonors     04-14 0345</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Baby Donors,0356</SECOND>
<HEAD>Effort To Get Organs From Doomed Babies Continues Under New Policy</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOMA LINDA, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A hospital will continue to harvest organs for transplant from babies born with most of their brains missing, despite a prior announcement that the program had been suspended, officials said. <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Schaefer </PERSON>, a spokesman for <ORGANIZATION> Loma </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Linda </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>, said Wednesday he was mistaken when he announced earlier in the week that the hospital's program of keeping such babies alive had been temporarily halted until new guidelines could be issued. On Tuesday night, hospital spokeswoman <PERSON> Anita </PERSON> <PERSON> Rockwell </PERSON> issued a statement saying the program to admit anencephalic babies `` is to continue without interruption.'' The hospital's policy was slightly revised, however, so that such babies will be placed on respirators only if their heart rates slow or they have trouble breathing, <PERSON> Schaefer </PERSON> said from the hospital 60 miles east of <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>. Anencephalic babies _ those missing most of their brains _ inevitably die within days to weeks. <PERSON> Loma </PERSON> <PERSON> Linda </PERSON>'s experimental and so-far unsuccesful program is aimed at using such infants as organ donors to save the lives of babies who otherwise would die of fatal heart defects or other deadly ailments. Previously, the hospital's policy was to place the anencephalic babies on respirators as soon as they were admitted to the hospital so their organs would n't deteriorate as they died. A seven-day limit for keeping them on the respirators was established to counter criticisms that the doomed anencephalic babies were suffering only to benefit infants who need transplants. The revised life-support policy, which still maintains the seven-day limit, apparently is aimed at increasing the proportion of babies who can be declared brain-dead. <PERSON> Schaefer </PERSON> said Wednesday his earlier statement `` was a misunderstanding on my part. I assumed that the program would n't be started until the statement -LRB- of revised policy -RRB- was released.'' Only one of the first six anencephalic babies admitted to <LOCATION> Loma </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Linda </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Hope </PERSON> <PERSON> Lovette </PERSON> <PERSON> Mount </PERSON>, of <LOCATION> Knoxville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Tenn. </LOCATION>, remained alive Wednesday. She was taken off life-support Monday and will be allowed to die, <PERSON> Schaefer </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880414-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-14-88 0220EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     04-14 0823</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0854</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names In The News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ATLANTA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An Atlanta-based organization for terminally ill children has given out 100 tickets to pop star <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s concert here tonight, but needs a few more tickets to meet the number they were asked to get `` Once the word came out that we had tickets, the phone was ringing off the hook,'' <PERSON> Linda </PERSON> <PERSON> Dozoretz </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Children </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wish </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION> said Wednesday. Ms. <PERSON> Dozoretz </PERSON> said the organization needs 24 more tickets to fulfill every request it got. `` We're trying to see what we can do,'' she said. `` It would be a wonderful experience.'' The group, which grants wishes to terminally ill children, was awaiting confirmation from <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s staff on whether he will be able to meet some of the children, Ms. <PERSON> Dozoretz </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> brought his solo tour to <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> on Wednesday for three sold-out shows.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>MEXICO CITY (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Cuban </LOCATION> leader <PERSON> Fidel </PERSON> <PERSON> Castro </PERSON> has been honored by the <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> for giving up his famous cigar and setting a smoke-free example for his countrymen, <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION>'s official news agency says. <PERSON> Castro </PERSON> was given two medals by <PERSON> Carlyle </PERSON> <PERSON> Guerra </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Macedo </PERSON>, director general of the Geneva-based organization, in a ceremony Tuesday at <LOCATION> Havana </LOCATION>'s Palace of the Revolution, said <PERSON> Prensa </PERSON> <PERSON> Latina </PERSON> in a dispatch received here Wednesday. The WHO announced the honor on April 7, the first worldwide `` No Tobacco Day.'' <PERSON> Castro </PERSON>, whose cigars were almost as much a trademark as his beard, was cited for pledging in 1981 never to smoke in public and subsequently quitting.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>TUCSON, Ariz. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Counterculture journalist <PERSON> Hunter </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON> canceled tonight's scheduled speaking engagement at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Arizona </ORGANIZATION> because of alleged death threats, his agent says. <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON>, 48, who lives near <LOCATION> Aspen </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Colo. </LOCATION>, has received numerous telephone threats in the past week, agent <PERSON> Greg </PERSON> <PERSON> Werckman </PERSON> said Wednesday in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON>, creator of so-called `` gonzo'' journalism, has written several books, including `` Fear and Loathing in <LOCATION> Las </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vegas </LOCATION>'' and `` The Great White Shark Hunt.'' <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON> has developed a reputation for rowdy behavior and drinking on the speaking tour, and his appearance initially had been opposed by student leaders. <PERSON> Werckman </PERSON> said <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON> was disappointed at having to cancel, but has taken the threats seriously. <PERSON> Werckman </PERSON> said he did not know the source of the threats, but that the writer previously had been threatened by someone in <LOCATION> Tucson </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Singer <PERSON> Deborah </PERSON> <PERSON> Harry </PERSON>, songwriter <LOCATION> Irving </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION>, jazz musician <PERSON> Lionel </PERSON> <PERSON> Hampton </PERSON>, and transsexual tennis coach <PERSON> Renee </PERSON> <PERSON> Richards </PERSON> are among dozens of celebrities who owe back taxes to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> state </LOCATION>, a newspaper says. Miss <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> owes $ 241,354 for record royalties and <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> owes $ 5,500, according to state records cited by the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> on Wednesday. <PERSON> Richards </PERSON>, an ophthalmologist, owes nearly $ 33,000 and master vibraphonist <PERSON> Hampton </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> Lionel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hampton </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Enterprises </ORGANIZATION> owes $ 10,500 in withholding taxes, the paper said. The records also showed the state was seeking almost $ 289,000 from the estate of jazz great <PERSON> Duke </PERSON> <PERSON> Ellington </PERSON> and more than $ 91,000 from the estate of singer <PERSON> Brook </PERSON> <PERSON> Benton </PERSON>, who died Saturday. On Monday, movie reviewer <PERSON> Rex </PERSON> <PERSON> Reed </PERSON> pleaded guilty to evading more than $ 20,000 in state income taxes. A secretary for <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> denied that the 99-year-old songwriter owed taxes. <PERSON> Hampton </PERSON>'s manager, <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Titone </PERSON>, said the tax problem was cleared up in 1987. A secretary for <PERSON> Richards </PERSON> said the issue was being handled by <PERSON> Richards </PERSON>' lawyer, according to the <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION>. Miss <PERSON> Harry </PERSON>'s lawyer, <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Kurfirst </PERSON>, said the singer was repaying her debt in installments and would owe no money by the end of the year.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 P.D. <PERSON> James </PERSON>, one of <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s top detective fiction writers, has been named to the government-funded <ORGANIZATION> Arts </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> to lead a campaign to stimulate interest in literature, particularly in schools. `` We have a wonderful, almost miraculous literary heritage,'' Ms. <PERSON> James </PERSON> said Wednesday. `` Now we need to stimulate our writers and poets in the future.'' Ms. <PERSON> James </PERSON>, whose books include `` Cover Her Face'' and `` Death Of An Expert Witness,'' will preside over the council's literature panel. The council, one of <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s main sources of public support of the arts, also is commissioning English translations of foreign works, a television series about poetry, and subsidizing black British authors.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Former network executive <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> Silverman </PERSON> says he figures that since he's become an independent producer he's committed about 100 murders <PERSON> Silverman </PERSON> is the executive producer of <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Matlock'' and `` In the Heat of the Night'' and <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>' `` <PERSON> Jake </PERSON> and the Fatman.'' He also produces the `` <PERSON> Perry </PERSON> <PERSON> Mason </PERSON>'' series and is planning two more series, including a revival of `` <PERSON> Burke </PERSON>'s Law'' with <PERSON> Gene </PERSON> <PERSON> Barry </PERSON>. `` But no more mysteries for me,'' said <PERSON> Silverman </PERSON>, formerly head of programming at <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, former president of <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Entertainment </ORGANIZATION> and former president of <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>. `` I feel like I've earned a law degree with all these lawyers,'' he said Wednesday. `` I think <PERSON> Dean </PERSON> <PERSON> Hargrove </PERSON>, my co-executive producer, and I have committed about 100 murders so far.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880414-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-14-88 0047EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-PenaRecall 1stLd-Writethru a0818 04-14 0494</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Pena Recall, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0818,0501</SECOND>
<HEAD>URGENT</HEAD>
<HEAD>Mayoral Recall Group Delivers Insufficient Petitions</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: New throughout to UPDATE with petitions falling short of
required numbers. No pickup.</NOTE>
<HEAD>With AM-Mofford-Mecham, Bjt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>DENVER (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A months-long recall effort to oust Mayor <PERSON> Federico </PERSON> <PERSON> Pena </PERSON> failed Wednesday when an elections official announced that petitions submitted fell more than 2,000 names short of the number required by law. The backers of the drive delivered 21 bundles of petitions to the <ORGANIZATION> Denver </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Election </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> Wednesday afternoon, beating a 5 p.m. deadline by several hours. They said they believed there were enough valid signatures to support calling a new mayoral election. But late Wednesday, <PERSON> Felicia </PERSON> <PERSON> Muftic </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> Denver </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Election </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION>, said that even without checking for validity, the number of signatures was only 36,960. For a recall, the petitions would have to bear the valid signatures of 39,091 registered <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION> voters, which is 25 percent of the number of votes cast in the last mayoral election, said <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> <PERSON> Tarkington </PERSON>, executive director of the <ORGANIZATION> Election </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION>. `` It appears that unofficially there's just not enough signatures to continue,'' <PERSON> Muftic </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Pena </PERSON>, 41, one of the first Hispanics to be mayor of a major <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> city, reacted immediately with pleasure. `` The time for negativism and doubt is behind us. To those people who opposed the recall I thank you. To those who supported the recall I urge you to join with the city to help move the city forward. These are critical times facing our city and we ca n't afford to have disunity,'' he said at a news conference at his office late Wednesday Recall organizer <PERSON> Marge </PERSON> <PERSON> Doty </PERSON> said earlier Wednesday that she had no exact count on the number of signatures, but said she was confident there were `` more than enough'' to continue the recall process. <PERSON> Doty </PERSON>, who launched the recall effort in January, requested a police escort to and from the <ORGANIZATION> Election </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> office after she reported receiving threats. The recall drive was started by a group angry over what its members claimed was fiscal mismanagement by the <PERSON> Pena </PERSON> administration. The group gathered support among residents stranded for several days by a major holiday snowstorm when maintenance crews plowed only major traffic arteries while <PERSON> Pena </PERSON> was vacationing out of state. While there is some dispute about precise procedures, <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION>'s charter calls for an entirely new, nonpartisan election if the petitions are validated to recall <PERSON> Pena </PERSON>, a second-term Democrat Any candidate who collected 300 names on a nominating petition could run, and if no candidate mustered a clear majority, a run-off would be held next. There have been hints of illegalities in the petition campaign. <PERSON> Pena </PERSON> appeared on a <ORGANIZATION> KOA </ORGANIZATION> radio call-in show Wednesday morning, and one caller informed him her daughter had been approached by petitioners. The daughter said she was told she `` had to sign,'' and when she said she was not a <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION> resident, she was allegedly told, `` We'll give you a <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION> address.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880414-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-14-88 0238EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Hijack-Bombers     04-14 0835</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Hijack-Bombers,0860</SECOND>
<HEAD>Jailing Of 17 Bombers In Kuwait Has Left Trail Of Violence</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Hijack, Bjt</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ED BLANCHE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NICOSIA, Cyprus (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The hijacking of a <ORGANIZATION> Kuwait </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airways </ORGANIZATION> jumbo jet is the latest in a series of terrorist attacks in the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> that began when <LOCATION> Kuwait </LOCATION> convicted 17 pro-Iranian bombers in 1984. Since those men _ all but one of them Shiite Moslems _ were put behind bars, their comrades have hijacked airliners, kidnapped Americans and other foreigners and carried out bombing attacks and assassinations. The Shiites who hijacked <ORGANIZATION> Kuwait </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airways </ORGANIZATION> Flight 422 on April 5 have one demand: the release of the 17 men convicted of a series of bombings in <LOCATION> Kuwait </LOCATION> in December 1983 that killed five people and wounded 61. <LOCATION> Kuwait </LOCATION> refuses. The bombings were part of an Iranian-inspired campaign to destabilize <LOCATION> Kuwait </LOCATION>, which has a substantial <ORGANIZATION> Shiite </ORGANIZATION> minority, and which <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION> accuses of helping <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> in their 7 -LCB- - year-old war Dozens of other Shiites have been jailed in <LOCATION> Kuwait </LOCATION> for bombings, but no one has demanded their release. `` There's a thread running through all these events that began with the 1983 bombings,'' <PERSON> Ian </PERSON> <PERSON> Geldard </PERSON> of the London-based Institute for the Study of Terrorism said in a telephone interview. He and other specialists traced the chain of violence to one mastermind, <PERSON> Imad </PERSON> <PERSON> Mughniyeh </PERSON>, 36, a Lebanese Shiite who is a security chief of Iranian-backed <ORGANIZATION> Hezbollah </ORGANIZATION>, an umbrella organization whose name means Party of God. Among the 17, three have been sentenced to death. One of the three is <PERSON> Elias </PERSON> <PERSON> Saab </PERSON>, whose real name is <PERSON> Mustapha </PERSON> <PERSON> Youssef </PERSON> <PERSON> Badreddin </PERSON>. He is <PERSON> Mughniyeh </PERSON>'s cousin and brother-in-law. `` At the end of the day, it's <PERSON> Mughniyeh </PERSON> who's been responsible for most of this violence,'' <PERSON> Geldard </PERSON> said. Some passengers freed by the hijackers of the Kuwaiti jet said a man boarded the plane last week when it landed at <LOCATION> Mashhad </LOCATION> in northeast <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> shortly after being seized. Palestinian negotiatiors in <LOCATION> Cyprus </LOCATION>, where the plane flew next, said the hijackers' leader, who they called `` experienced,'' never showed himself and they speculated that he might be <PERSON> Mughniyeh </PERSON>. The plane later flew to <LOCATION> Algeria </LOCATION> where the hijackers refused to free their 32 remaining hostages. <PERSON> Mughniyeh </PERSON> disappeared in <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>, where he has his headquarters, several weeks ago after returning from <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>, informed souces said on condition of anonymity. Another leading Shiite militant in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Hussein </PERSON> <PERSON> Musawi </PERSON>, leader of <ORGANIZATION> Islamic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Amal </ORGANIZATION> which is linked to <ORGANIZATION> Hezbollah </ORGANIZATION>, also has been involved in the violence, <PERSON> Geldard </PERSON> said. One of <PERSON> Musawi </PERSON>'s cousins, <PERSON> Hassan </PERSON> <PERSON> Youssef </PERSON> <PERSON> Musawi </PERSON>, is among the 17 held in <LOCATION> Kuwait </LOCATION> and is serving a life sentence. `` The family connections involved here are the reason there's been such a passionate intensity involved in this campaign,'' <PERSON> Geldard </PERSON> said The 17 are members of the Iranian-based al-Dawaa, or The Call, a movement of dissident Iraqi Shiite fundamentalists opposed to the <LOCATION> Baghdad </LOCATION> government of President <PERSON> Saddam </PERSON> <PERSON> Hussein </PERSON>. <PERSON> Al-Dawaa </PERSON> is closely linked with <ORGANIZATION> Hezbollah </ORGANIZATION>. In <LOCATION> Baghdad </LOCATION> in 1980, <PERSON> Hussein </PERSON> publicly beheaded the movement's founder <PERSON> Mohammed </PERSON> <PERSON> Bakr </PERSON> <LOCATION> al-Sadr </LOCATION>, a <ORGANIZATION> Shiite </ORGANIZATION> cleric and close friend of <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'s spiritual leader, <PERSON> Ayatollah </PERSON> <PERSON> Ruhollah </PERSON> <PERSON> Khomeini </PERSON> <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and Lebanese intelligence officials said <PERSON> Mughniyeh </PERSON> and his clan were behind the kidnappings of Americans and Frenchmen in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> that began in 1984. Intelligence organizations consider <ORGANIZATION> Hezbollah </ORGANIZATION>, al-Dawaa and <LOCATION> Islamic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jihad </LOCATION>, or Islamic Holy War, one and the same, part of an increasingly potent terrorist network that leads to <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION>. Here are some of the events that stemmed from the conviction of the 17 bombers. _ Dec 4, 1984: Five Arabs hijack a Kuwaiti airliner and demand the release of the 17. They fly the plane to <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION> and kill two <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> passengers. Iranian security men storm the plane after five days and capture the hijackers, who later vanish. Western intelligence believes the Iranians let them go. _ March 16, 1985: <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON>, chief <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> correspondent for <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> is kidnapped in <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> by <LOCATION> Islamic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jihad </LOCATION> Twenty-two foreigners, including nine Americans, are now held in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>. _ May 4, 1985: Islamic Jihad warns there will be `` catastrophic consequences'' if <LOCATION> Kuwait </LOCATION> does not free the 17 _ May 25, 1985: The emir of <LOCATION> Kuwait </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Sheik </PERSON> <PERSON> Jaber </PERSON> <PERSON> Al-Ahmed </PERSON> <PERSON> Al-Sabah </PERSON>, narrowly escapes assasination when a Shiite suicide bomber rams a car loaded with explosives into his motorcade in <LOCATION> Kuwait </LOCATION> Two of the emir's bodyguards and the bomber were killed. Islamic Jihad claimed responsibility. _ June 14, 1985: Shiites hijack a <ORGANIZATION> TWA </ORGANIZATION> airliner and fly it to <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>, demanding the release of the 17 and more than 700 Arabs held by <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> A <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> diver is killed and 39 Americans held hostage for 17 days before being freed after Syrian intervention. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> authorities name <PERSON> Mughniyeh </PERSON> as one of the suspected hijackers. _ July 24, 1987: After a string of bombings in <LOCATION> Kuwait </LOCATION>, a 21-year-old Lebanese Shiite member of <ORGANIZATION> Hezbollah </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Hussein </PERSON> <PERSON> Hariri </PERSON>, hijacks an <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Afrique </ORGANIZATION> jetliner to <LOCATION> Zurich </LOCATION>, demanding the release in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> of another <ORGANIZATION> Shiite </ORGANIZATION> held there for the <ORGANIZATION> TWA </ORGANIZATION> hijacking The plane's crew overwhelm <PERSON> Hariri </PERSON> after he kills a French passenger.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880414-0025 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-14-88 0240EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-CitySmelters Bjt   04-14 0629</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-City Smelters, Bjt,0654</SECOND>
<HEAD>Annual Spawning Brings Smelt And Fish Stories To Chicago Lakefront</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto CX1</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By F.N. D'ALESSIO</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CHICAGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 On spring nights, pearls of light from lanterns and campfires sparkle along <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>'s dark seawalls and breakwaters as thousands of people wait for tiny silvery fish to wander into their nets. The smelt are spawning again, a decades-old rite of spring that is part social event, part business and part recreation along the <LOCATION> Great </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lakes </LOCATION> during the six-week season from April 1 to May 15. Smelting is almost a way of life. `` I've been doing it for 30 years, and I've run through friends, family, my kids _ nobody loves it quite as much as I do,'' said <PERSON> Herman </PERSON> <PERSON> Telkamp </PERSON>, who staked out his spot four hours before he could legally lower his net at 7 p.m. `` My wife wo n't clean fish anymore, so I spend all night smelting and all day cleaning.'' Rainbow smelt, 6 - to 8-inch members of a family resembling the trout, have been eaten in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> for centuries In the <LOCATION> Midwest </LOCATION>, the rite began after 1912, when the smelt, orginally a salt-water fish, escaped into the Great Lakes from a small lake in <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION> where they had been stocked. The best smelting at <LOCATION> Montrose </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Harbor </LOCATION> was on the breakwater, which was lined with Vietnamese, <LOCATION> Cambodian </LOCATION> and Korean families, and a few <LOCATION> Polish </LOCATION> immigrants. Fathers lower and raise the nets, children pull the fish from the mesh and mothers gut and clean. `` A lot of those fish are going to <LOCATION> Argyle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Street </LOCATION>,'' said one onlooker, referring to a nearby neighborhood with Vietnamese and <LOCATION> Cambodian </LOCATION> restaurants. With the right water temperature, current and wind, the smelt head in from open waters in great numbers. <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> smelters run their square gill nets out on anchored ropes, raising the nets several times an hour. Nightly yields can reach 5,000 fish a person, but on nights when the fish are fewer, it's time for six-packs and smelt stories. Like the one <PERSON> Rob </PERSON> <PERSON> Ohagan </PERSON>, 24, of <LOCATION> Darien </LOCATION>, tells about the tipsy smelter who weighted his net with his keys. `` A lot of guys fish without licenses and just abandon their nets when the wardens come by,'' <PERSON> Ohagan </PERSON> said. `` They figure it's cheaper to lose a $ 35 smelt rig than to pay a $ 50 fine `` This guy remembered that his keys were on the net, and he could n't get into his car, so he had to take the fine,'' <PERSON> Ohagan </PERSON> said. There's also the matter of upholding a tradition observed by younger smelters: biting the head off the first smelt of the season. <PERSON> Ed </PERSON> <PERSON> Flowers </PERSON>, 25, of <PERSON> La </PERSON> <PERSON> Grange </PERSON>, pulled up his first net of the spring and saluted the four dangling fish with a beer, but he would n't take the bite. `` Now you wo n't have any more luck,'' said <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Falduto </PERSON>, 25, of Park Ridge. <PERSON> Chuck </PERSON> <PERSON> Roth </PERSON> and his wife, <PERSON> Laurie </PERSON>, had set up a net, a fire and a tent for their two young daughters, <PERSON> Nicole </PERSON> and <PERSON> Chris </PERSON>. `` We've been smelting about five years _ always at this very same spot,'' <PERSON> Roth </PERSON> said. `` We only ran out of last year's frozen smelt last month.'' The Roths, of Park Forest, like their smelt marinated in home-made hot sauce, but <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Wolfgang </PERSON>, also casting his net along the breakwater, cooks his in a beer batter. `` I keep a couple of gallons for myself and give the rest away _ to friends or in the tavern,'' <PERSON> Wolfgang </PERSON> said. `` They're a lot easier to give away than zucchini or tomatoes.'' <PERSON> Wolfgang </PERSON>, 45, said this night he was catching a wedding present. `` My sister's getting married tomorrow in <ORGANIZATION> Eau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Claire </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION>,'' he said. `` She likes smelt, but they're hard to come by that far from the lakes.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880414-0026 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-14-88 0241EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-PresidentialWords     04-14 0665</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Presidential Words,670</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHINGTON WIRE: When a President's Words Are Not His Words</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By W. DALE NELSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
