<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880426-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-26-88 2355EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p BC-PA-GOP-Pres-Sum     04-26 0048</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-PA-GOP-Pres-Sum,400</SECOND>
<HEAD>04-26-88 23:41</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the latest, unofficial results in the Republican presidential primary in <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> on Tuesday.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 6,992 of 9,406 precincts reporting - 74 percent <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, 456,054 - 79 percent <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON>, 54,143 - 9 percent <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>, 69,908 - 12 percent
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880426-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-26-88 2355EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p AM-PrimaryRdp 7thLd a0914 04-26 1002</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Primary Rdp, 7th Ld, a0914,990</SECOND>
<NOTE>Eds: Updates with delegates; addl Dukakis reax.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By DONALD M. ROTHBERG</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Political Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PHILADELPHIA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> certified his status as the Democratic presidential front-runner on Tuesday with a thumping 2-1 triumph over <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> in the <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> primary. <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> won a resounding <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> victory and predicted the state would deliver the final delegates needed to clinch the nomination. By their victories, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> emerged as almost certain opponents in the fall general election campaign _ survivors of a campaign marathon that once featured seven Democratic candidates and six Republicans. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> was gaining 65 percent of the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> and said his victory would be `` very very helpful'' in his quest for the White House. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> was gaining 30 percent of the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> vote, and said he intended to compete through the last primary on June 7. `` I'm a long-distance runner,'' he said. `` It's too close now to turn around.'' Vice President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> campaigned across <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> during the day, declaring, `` We're almost getting down to the main event. According to the <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION>, this evening I'll capture enough delegates in the <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> primary to exceed the 1,139 -LRB- Republican -RRB- convention delegates needed for the nomination.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was gaining 79 percent of the vote to 12 percent for dropout Sen. <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> and 9 percent for former television evangelist <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON>. President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> agreed to drop his studied show of neutrality and bestow his blessings on his vice president in a White House meeting on Wednesday. The <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> delegate count was far slower than the popular vote. He needed to win 58 of the 78 delegates at stake to clinch his majority in the <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> delegate count, and he seemed certain to get them. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> won all of the first 14 tallied, with the rest of the races still being counted. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> won a separate landslide in election of delegates, leading for 165 to 12 for <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>. One was uncommitted. That would bring <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' national delegate total to 1,266, compared to 850 for <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>. It takes 2,081 to clinch nomination. Network polling place interviews contained news that was as good for <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> as his vote totals. Though <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> gained more than 90 percent support from blacks, <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> polling analyst <PERSON> Doug </PERSON> <PERSON> Muzzio </PERSON> said that for the first time in the campaign season, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> was winning a majority of voters who cited the poor and elderly as their chief concerns _ voters <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> won in prior contests. He said <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> also was winning voters who cited strong leadership and ability to make a change, groups that <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> usually won in earlier races. `` He's emerging as the consensus candidate,'' pollster I.A. <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Los </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Angeles </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> said of <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>. `` The next step is going to be binding the wounds, pulling the party together and getting it directed against the Republicans.'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> was cautious, as ever. Asked if the big win meant the nomination is now his, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> refused to claim the crown yet, refering to Democratic nominee <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> Mondale </PERSON>'s problems in 1984. `` I reminded you several time that <PERSON> Fritz </PERSON> <PERSON> Mondale </PERSON> won <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> and then lost a string of primaries,'' he said. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> achieved his status as odds-on favorite to win the nomination far faster than <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, routing the Republican eld on a single Super Tuesday on March 8. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> gained the upper hand week by week. Even so, both men fared better than seemed possible when the nominating wars opened in <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> last February _ and both men wound up third in the state's lead-off caucuses. On Tuesday, both <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> already were pointing their campaigns toward the fall. With 73 percent of the <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> vote in, the Democratic vote was: <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, 745,930, or 65 percent. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, 344,284, 30 percent. On the Republican side, it was: <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, 447,504, 79 percent. <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>, 68,402, 12 percent. <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON>, 53,166, 9 percent. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> said his <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> victory was a `` very big boost ... particularly in a state that has been a bellwether state in the general election.'' He said he would `` campaign as hard as I can'' in the remaining primaries. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> made clear he has the same intentions. `` The contest will be determined on June 7 in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION>,'' he said from <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, which holds one of three primaries on next week's calendar `` We have every reason to be hopeful, if we keep winning every urban center. Our coalition is broad, it is strong, it is deep, and we're inspired to run on.'' The outline of <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s campaign against <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> was taking shape. The vice president said the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> front-runner lacks foreign policy experience and added, `` That will be a major issue in the fall.'' The vice president also arranged to meet Wednesday with President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>. Spokesman <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> `` will see him first thing in the morning, and I am sure the president will offer his congratulations and discuss how he can help in the campaign.'' On the Democratic side, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> was scarcely more than halfway toward a nominating majority, but party officials were beginning to talk aloud about a first-ballot victory for the man from <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Larryann </PERSON> <PERSON> Willis </PERSON>, an uncommitted superdelegate from <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION>, said, `` If the voting goes the way it's going -LRB- in upcoming primaries -RRB-, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> will get it -LRB- the nomination -RRB- on the first ballot.'' <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Ruvolo </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Ohio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> chairman, agreed that <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> enters his state with campaign momentum. `` What I worry about is <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> insiders trying to end the race before it's over,'' he said. <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION> Mayor <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> <PERSON> Goode </PERSON> had this advice for <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>: `` hang in there.'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> forged his early <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> lead after a week-long campaign that looked and sounded more like a mutual admiration society than the typical 1988 Democratic primary brawl. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> had scant hopes for a victory in <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION>, where his campaign failed to file a complete slate of delegate candidates. He already was looking ahead to next week's primaries in the <LOCATION> District </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>. In <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION>: pickup 11th graf a0854
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880426-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-26-88 2359EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-GovernmentTrips     04-26 0187</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Government Trips,180</SECOND>
<HEAD>Ethics Panel Clears Couple At HHS Of Taking Unauthorized Trips</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A government review panel has cleared a married couple at the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Human </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> of violating federal travel rules or taking unauthorized trips at government expense, according to a published report Wednesday. The department's ethics review board found that the trips by <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> and <PERSON> Paget </PERSON> <PERSON> Hinch </PERSON> had been authorized and did involve government business, <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> reported. The panel said in a written report that Mrs. <PERSON> Hinch </PERSON> apparently had arranged three legitimate business trips so that she could be near her husband at the resort area of <LOCATION> Orlando </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>, and over Thanksgiving near his family's home in the <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Franciso </LOCATION> area. The board said arranging the trips for `` the personal convenience of the Hinches'' raised an `` appearance of impropriety,'' and noted that it had sought and received voluntary reimbursement of $ 3,264 for some costs related to the trips. However, the report added, `` The board does not believe that any disciplinary action is warranted by the evidence relating to the official travel by <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> and <PERSON> Paget </PERSON> <PERSON> Hinch </PERSON>.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880426-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-26-88 0025EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     04-26 0961</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,1000</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names In The News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Emperor <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON> held a rare news conference to talk of his health and his fabled past as the world's longest-reigning monarch The annual news conference, to be broadcast Friday on his 87th birthday, came as some Japanese already were preparing for the death of the emperor, who has been on the throne since Dec. 25, 1926. Medical equipment has been moved from a hospital on palace grounds into <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON>'s living quarters so he can die at home, said sources who spoke on condition of anonymity. However, they said, there was no indication his health is failing. At Monday's news conference for 30 Japanese reporters, <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON> talked of World War II and its aftermath, said the sources. It has been 13 years since his last news conference with foreign reporters, when he denied planning the attack on <LOCATION> Pearl </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Harbor </LOCATION> but left many other questions unanswered.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Squinting in the bright <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> sun, the King and Queen of <LOCATION> Sweden </LOCATION> landed in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> for the last stop of their 17-day, 15-city American tour celebrating the 350th anniversary of Swedish immigration to <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>. A beaming King <PERSON> Carl </PERSON> <PERSON> XVI </PERSON> <PERSON> Gustaf </PERSON> and Queen <PERSON> Silvia </PERSON> were welcomed Monday by dignitaries including Mayor <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON> and <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> Secretary of State March <PERSON> Fong </PERSON> <PERSON> Eu </PERSON>, as the 55-member Swedish <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Band </ORGANIZATION> played the Swedish national anthem. The couple have meetings planned with celebrities including <PERSON> Mickey </PERSON> <PERSON> Mouse </PERSON>. Their visit ends Wednesday.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 British producer <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Puttnam </PERSON>, bidding farewell to <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION> after a stormy two years, has offered a sobering view of <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>. `` There is a disillusionment wafting through the heady winds of the <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> dream as more and more people come to feel that they've had the experience but somehow, somewhere, missed out on the meaning of it,'' <PERSON> Puttnam </PERSON> said Saturday in a speech to the 34th annual Entertainment Law Symposium at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION>. The movie-industry maverick rode into <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION> on the reputation of his successful `` Chariots of Fire,'' but his job as chairman of <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pictures </ORGANIZATION> went up in smoke 14 months later. During his tenure at <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Puttnam </PERSON> had fallouts with many stars, agents and such filmmakers as influential producer <PERSON> Ray </PERSON> <PERSON> Stark </PERSON>. <PERSON> Puttnam </PERSON> argued that successful films can be made without highly paid actors and directors.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Trade Representative <PERSON> Clayton </PERSON> <PERSON> Yeutter </PERSON> joked that he probably was the subject of the first and last `` Meet the Press'' appearance from <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Yeutter </PERSON> appeared on the <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> program Sunday via a satellite hookup from <PERSON> Lincoln </PERSON> to present the administration's opposition to the trade bill in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. Midway through <PERSON> Yeutter </PERSON>'s first answer, the satellite feed broke up and for the rest of the show the program's panelists could direct questions only to Sen. <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Texas </LOCATION>, the show's other guest and a key supporter of the legislation `` It was frustrating, sitting there in that little studio in <LOCATION> Lincoln </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION>, having to watch and listen to that biased explanation of the plant closing amendment,'' <PERSON> Yeutter </PERSON> said. `` That was probably the first time in history that they have ever done a ` Meet the Press' feed out of <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION> and probably the last time in history they will do one,'' <PERSON> Yeutter </PERSON> joked Monday during an appearance before farm editors.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>Eds: A version of the following item is moving on sports wires.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 After watching <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Lou </PERSON> <PERSON> Retton </PERSON> pitch practically everything from batteries to breakfast cereal, Olympic teammate <PERSON> Greg </PERSON> <PERSON> Louganis </PERSON> has one thing to tell the gymnast: I'd love to have your problems. `` I saw <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Lou </PERSON> <PERSON> Retton </PERSON> on <PERSON> Ted </PERSON> <PERSON> Koppel </PERSON>'s -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s -RRB- ` Nightline' recently, and she was complaining that she was n't prepared to be thrust into the limelight after the'84 Olympics,'' <PERSON> Louganis </PERSON> told Gentleman's Quarterly magazine in its May issue `` I do n't feel sorry for her. She's made $ 5 million! Give me her problems, please!'' the gold-medal-winning diver said. <PERSON> Louganis </PERSON> also revealed that although he appears confident and in command on the diving platform, `` I'm not in control of my diving.'' `` I get disoriented in a dive and lose the water. It's terrifying,'' he said `` Diving has been my only distinction in life, but I'm not afraid to leave it.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actor <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Garner </PERSON> is continuing his recovery from quintuple bypass heart surgery, eating his first solid food in a hospital room overflowing with cards and flowers, a spokesman said. <PERSON> Garner </PERSON>'s popularity with his fans, and now with the <ORGANIZATION> Cedars-Sinai </ORGANIZATION> staff, is unparalleled, said hospital spokesman <PERSON> Ron </PERSON> <PERSON> Wise </PERSON>, describing the bags of mail and gardens of flowers sent by well-wishers. Asked if the spokesman for the beef industry's $ 30 million `` Beef, <ORGANIZATION> Real </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Food </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Real </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION>'' ad campaign was eating meat, <PERSON> Wise </PERSON> said, `` I do n't know what he's eating.'' <PERSON> Garner </PERSON>, 60, earlier blamed his heart problem on 45 years of cigarette smoking.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>PLANTATION, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Express </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> stockholder says he believes former Secretary of State <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> Kissinger </PERSON> and other big-name directors and consultants at the company do n't deserve their hefty pay. <PERSON> Kissinger </PERSON>'s consulting firm pocketed $ 420,000 in fees last year in addition to his $ 48,000 salary as an <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Express </ORGANIZATION> director, stockholder <PERSON> Benedict </PERSON> <PERSON> Toth </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Coral </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gables </LOCATION> said Monday at the company's annual meeting here. But Chairman <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON> said <PERSON> Kissinger </PERSON>'s contacts have proven valuable. <PERSON> Kissinger </PERSON> brought $ 508 million in capital to the company last year and helped lure Japanese investors, <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> said. That led to <ORGANIZATION> Nippon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Life </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Insurance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> buying a 13 percent voting interest in <ORGANIZATION> Shearson </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lehman </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hutton </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Express </ORGANIZATION>' brokerage arm, he said. Other directors or consultants at the meeting were former President <PERSON> Gerald </PERSON> <PERSON> Ford </PERSON>, former <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Drew </PERSON> <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON> and former <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Urban </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> League </ORGANIZATION> President <PERSON> Vernon </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Jordan </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880426-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-26-88 0025EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--Malaysia-Refugees     04-26 0156</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Malaysia-Refugees,0161</SECOND>
<HEAD>More Than 226,000 Vietnamese Refugees Have Arrived In Malaysia</HEAD>
<DATELINE>KUALA LUMPUR, Malaysia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 From 1975 to this March, 226,091 Vietnamese boat people have landed in <LOCATION> Malaysia </LOCATION>, an official said today. The influx of Vietnamese refugees began in 1975 after <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> forces withdrew from <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> and it fell to communist forces from <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>. Of the 226,091 refugees, 217,812 resettled in other countries, including 128,000 in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, said <PERSON> Eric </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Morris </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> High </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commissioner </ORGANIZATION> for Refugees for <LOCATION> Malaysia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Brunei </LOCATION>. In the first three months of this year, 2,921 boat people reached <LOCATION> Malaysian </LOCATION> shores, higher than the 1,702 for the same period last year, he said. <PERSON> Morris </PERSON> told reporters the increase was due, in part, to <LOCATION> Thailand </LOCATION>'s decision to forbid boats of refugees to land on its shores. The boat people generally land on the east coasts of <LOCATION> Malaysia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Thailand </LOCATION> by cutting across the <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sea </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880426-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-26-88 0027EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Israel-Martyr     04-26 0770</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Israel-Martyr,0792</SECOND>
<HEAD>Young Electrician Became Bethlehem's First Martyr In Uprising</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By JOCELYN NOVECK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BETHLEHEM, Occupied West Bank (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Salim </PERSON> <PERSON> Shaar </PERSON> always liked fixing things. He spent the last afternoon of his life laying new tiles on the family porch and wiring new lights. He planned to finish the job the next day, after a morning of throwing stones at <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> soldiers. But a soldier thought he saw a firebomb in <PERSON> Salim </PERSON>'s hand, and the next time <PERSON> Salim </PERSON> crossed the porch he was carried, with a bullet hole in his head. On an afternoon two weeks later, members of the family sat at home sipping strong Arab coffee and talking about the shy, 23-year-old electrician, <LOCATION> Bethlehem </LOCATION>'s first martyr of the Arab rebellion that began nearly five months ago in the Israeli-occupied lands. `` This uprising changes everyone,'' said <PERSON> Salim </PERSON>'s father, <PERSON> Khalil </PERSON>. `` It turns a sane man into a crazy man. It turns a shy man into an angry man.'' The clearest evidence of the change in <LOCATION> Salim </LOCATION> is in his diary, a frayed notepad from a souvenir shop lovingly preserved by his family. It speaks of his growing desperation. `` I do n't dream about toys anymore, mother,'' <PERSON> Salim </PERSON> wrote in an entry directed to his mother, <PERSON> Fatmah </PERSON>, several weeks before his death. `` When they killed my friends I grew up a thousand years.'' When the violence began Dec. 8, <PERSON> Salim </PERSON> was a good-natured young man devoted to his job, who often stopped at the homes of neighbors after work to see if anything needed fixing, his family says. `` People appreciated him, and his work made him happy,'' said his brother <PERSON> Mohammed </PERSON>, 21. `` He did n't have any great ambitions.'' <PERSON> Salim </PERSON> was happy at his family's home, and had added a room to it where he could settle one day with a wife. He filled the new closets with books on electricity, and moved into the room only weeks before he died. His possessions do not seem those of a man driven to die for a cause. They reveal instead a young man who liked music _ Turkish singers and traditional Arab tunes _ and was an amateur photographer who filling albums with pictures of his friends. Friends and family said <PERSON> Salim </PERSON> began to change when the `` intefadah,'' Arabic for uprising, came to the towns and refugee camps near <LOCATION> Bethlehem </LOCATION>, taking the lives of young Palestinians like himself. `` <PERSON> Salim </PERSON> was affected by what was going on,'' said a cousin, <PERSON> Mussa </PERSON>. `` He had many friends who went to prison and it became obvious to him that one day he, too, would go to jail. So he wanted to prepare himself.'' He began spending free time at the nearby Dheishe refugee camp, talking to Palestinians who had been in jail and visiting the families of prisoners to offer emotional support. In the diary, <PERSON> Salim </PERSON> sounds alternately desperate and defiant. `` What's a human being worth without a homeland, without a flag, without an address?'' he wrote, and later: `` The enemy planes can raid our camps and kill our children, but can not kill our will to fight.'' The entry for Friday, April 1, the night before his death, was the most striking: `` If my friends come back without me, mother, do n't cry. Every tear in your eyes is oil to light a lamp of freedom.'' <PERSON> Salim </PERSON> was in a good mood that Saturday morning, his family said. He took a shower, donned khaki trousers and a sweater, kissed his mother and said: `` If I come back, I wo n't be late.'' He and his brother, <PERSON> Mohammed </PERSON>, set off to join friends in <LOCATION> Bethlehem </LOCATION>'s market, gathering stones along the way. They became part of a group in central <LOCATION> Manger </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Square </LOCATION>, where Israeli soldiers were stationed. `` When it's over, you go back home. I'll go to a friend's house,'' <PERSON> Salim </PERSON> told <PERSON> Mohammed </PERSON>, anticipating the house-to-house search that often followed protests According to the army account of the morning's events, a soldier thought he saw a firebomb in <PERSON> Salim </PERSON>'s hand, but the family called that `` absurd.'' What no-one disputes is that <PERSON> Salim </PERSON> was killed instantly by a bullet that went through his right cheek and out the back of his neck. His parents, still in mourning clothes two weeks later, became defiant in their grief when asked if they would stop their seven other children from joining protests. `` We all have the right to demonstrate for what we believe in,'' <PERSON> Fatmah </PERSON> said. `` I will never take that from my children.'' <PERSON> Khalil </PERSON> nodded and added: `` Besides, <PERSON> Salim </PERSON> is not really dead. He lives on as a hero for our town.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880426-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-26-88 0028EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Contras     04-26 0614</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Contras,0640</SECOND>
<HEAD>Contras In `Liberated Zone' Say They Won't Lay Down Arms</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs.</NOTE>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 The writer, a photographer for <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Managua </LOCATION>, accompanied the Contra rebels for two days. Here is his account:
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>By MAURICIO OROZCO</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PUNTA GORDA, Nicaragua (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Commander <PERSON> Halcon </PERSON> and his band of Nicaraguan rebels move freely around what they call their `` liberated zone'' in the jungles near the <LOCATION> Caribbean </LOCATION> coast. They are willing to talk peace but wo n't lay down their arms. `` We have received orders from our high command to stop shooting,'' <PERSON> Halcon </PERSON> said as he sat under a tree while his men rested nearby. `` But we are not dropping our guard. The enemy can not be trusted.'' A peasant widow provided food and coffee to his company of young rebels, including several women. <PERSON> Halcon </PERSON>, a former Sandinista who fought against the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> of late strongman President <PERSON> Anastasio </PERSON> <PERSON> Somoza </PERSON>, and his troops are in the jungles of <LOCATION> Southern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Zelaya </LOCATION> province near the <LOCATION> Caribbean </LOCATION> coast. They are part of the <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> the </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nicarguan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION>, or <ORGANIZATION> FDN </ORGANIZATION>, the main Contra force which has fought to overthrow the Sandinista government. The area is one of seven set up under a 60-day cease-fire agreement between the U.S.-backed Contras and the Sandinista. Under the agreement, the <ORGANIZATION> Sandinistas </ORGANIZATION> have promised not to attack Contra troops congregating in the areas. `` They do n't come here anyway,'' <PERSON> Halcon </PERSON> said. `` We liberated this zone a long time ago.'' Looking around at his troops, <PERSON> Halcon </PERSON> said, `` There is no one here among us against his will.'' `` The people know we are not mercenaries,'' he said. Journalists traveled with the group for a day, visiting different camps where they met groups of rebels. <PERSON> Halcon </PERSON> said he commands three companies of 100 men each in the rugged eastern zone. Sandinista army troops evacuated many of the residents from the mountainous region two years ago in an effort to remove the rebels' `` social base'' but some people refused to leave They often help the Contras and provide food. They do the same for the Sandinista army when it moves in. Some cattle still roam the area and <LOCATION> Contra </LOCATION> groups use abandoned farms. <PERSON> Halcon </PERSON> and his men appeared to be well-armed and in good spirits. They had enough medicine and beef and plenty of U.S.-made candy to eat. At night they danced to tapes of Mexican `` ranchera'' music, then slept in hammocks made of silky parachute cloth. The commander said the last air drop of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> supplies to the group came a month ago. Under the cease-fire that took effect April 1, rebels may receive humanitarian aid through neutral international organizations once they are settled in the designated zones. Details of the truce are still being worked out in talks which will resume Thursday. <PERSON> Halcon </PERSON> said he had received two letters from the regional commander of the Sandinista army asking him to meet with the government represntatives `` in an effort to achieve peace.'' He said he was waiting for further instructions from Contra headquarters. There have already been several meetings of army and rebel groups on the field since the cease-fire went into effect. `` We will do whatever our leaders tell us,'' <PERSON> Halcon </PERSON> said. `` If we had a complete cease-fire, it would be the most beautiful thing. We have been fighting among Nicaraguans for too long. But we are armed campesinos and we are willing to fight ... and we are not going to lay down our arms unless there is a definitive cease-fire.'' `` We will lay down our arms when the <ORGANIZATION> Sandinistas </ORGANIZATION> lay down theirs, when there is a democratic government in <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880426-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-26-88 0032EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-ManilaVice     04-26 0691</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Manila Vice,0710</SECOND>
<HEAD>Police Crack Down On Manila's Red Light District</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By CLARO CORTES</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MANILA, Philippines (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The police chief is vowing to close down <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION>'s honky-tonk district, which he claims had made it the `` Sin Capital of <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION>.'' His targets are nightspots in the neighborhood known as the city's `` tourist belt,'' where scantily clad girls bump and grind to disco music and _ for a price _ go out with male customers. Although the <LOCATION> Ermita </LOCATION> district pumps millions of dollars each year into the city's economy, authorities have called for replacing the nightspots with more wholesome family entertainment. `` Now, we are known internationally as the center of the flesh trade, the <LOCATION> Sin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION>,'' Brig. Gen. <PERSON> Alfredo </PERSON> <PERSON> Lim </PERSON>, the capital's police chief, said recently. `` When we hear of this reference, all of us feel a furious sense of outrage, for we all know that we do n't deserve such notoriety.'' However, bar owners say the crackdown will cause worse problems, add to economic hardship and advance the spread of sexual disease. Last month, police began raiding bars and discos in the city's <LOCATION> Ermita </LOCATION> district They have rounded up more than 2,000 barmaids, known as `` hospitality girls,'' and detained dozens of foreigners who operate some of more than 505 bars, restaurants, discos, nightclubs and brothels in <LOCATION> Ermita </LOCATION>'s 10-block strip. President <PERSON> Corazon </PERSON> <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON> has backed the raids, saying `` what we should guard against is sacrificing the dignity and honor of the Filipino woman.'' But in a country with many economic problems, sex is big business. <PERSON> Lim </PERSON> said he expects bar owners _ mostly Americans, Australians, West Germans, Japanese and Filipinos _ to fight back by waging a smear campaign against him and his police force. `` They are employing all tricks to stop us so they can earn bundles and bundles of money,'' <PERSON> Lim </PERSON> said. `` They are capitalizing on our women.'' Indeed, an typical Ermita bar earns about $ 715 dollars on a regular day. The bigger establishments average about $ 1,666 daily. But <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON> <PERSON> Compuesto </PERSON>, general manager of the <ORGANIZATION> Hollywood </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Show </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Palace </ORGANIZATION>, said the raids have been hurting the once-thriving entertainment industry, cutting daily earnings by as much as 70 percent. Moreover, <PERSON> Ronnie </PERSON> <PERSON> Rueda </PERSON>, operations manager of a leading club called Firehouse, said closing bars will force tens of thousands of <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION> prostitutes to go underground. She says that will make it difficult to trace carriers of acquired immune deficiency syndrome and venereal diseases. <PERSON> Lim </PERSON> said 80 percent of 2,000 women picked up in the raids have been found suffering from venereal disease. The <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> said at least 50 Filipinos, mostly hospitality girls, have been infected with the AIDS virus, but none has developed its active symptoms. `` The problem of venereal disease will spread out because the women will become freelancers. They will hang around hotels and restaurants,'' <PERSON> Rueda </PERSON> said. `` Who will manage them and check them for diseases?'' <PERSON> Compuesto </PERSON> said his group has offered to help police by closing some establishments and ridding the area of free-lance prostitutes. But he says their offer has been ignored. `` If they are really trying to cure the problem of morality, this campaign should be nationwide,'' Compuesto said. `` How can they solve immorality, prostitution or drug abuse if they are only concentrating on Ermita?'' Other critics say closing <PERSON> Ermita </PERSON>'s seedy establishments would force some displaced workers into a life of crime. `` If you're starving and you're the only breadwinner in the family, I think there is nothing else to do,'' said <PERSON> Kit </PERSON> <PERSON> Samson </PERSON>, a disc jockey <PERSON> Compuesto </PERSON> said most bar girls are earning more than the $ 3 minimum daily wage of factory workers, not counting what they earn once they leave the bars with customers. `` Thousands of people do n't have jobs. We have jobs that we enjoy, but now they want to get it from us,'' Compuesto said. `` What kind of logic is that?'' `` It's really a hypocrisy of people to say that when tourists come to the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION>, they just want to see the sights in <LOCATION> Tagaytay </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Baguio </LOCATION> or some other part of the country,'' Compuesto said. `` They need entertainment.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880426-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-26-88 0038EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-ScotusRdp Bjt   04-26 0803</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Scotus Rdp, Bjt,650</SECOND>
<HEAD>Court Takes Own Initiative And Reopens Civil Rights Ruling</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JAMES H. RUBIN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Civil rights groups are worried that a <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> decision to reconsider a 12-year-old ruling on race discrimination could be the beginning of an effort to reverse basic legal advances for minorities. Conservatives see it as signaling the possible end of an era where they believe legal principles were bent to favor minorities. `` The message is there's a new court now that <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> -LRB- <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> -RRB- </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> is on board and previous rulings are up for grabs,'' said <PERSON> Ira </PERSON> <PERSON> Glasser </PERSON>, executive director of the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Civil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberties </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION>. `` It is an ominous development.'' By a 5-4 vote Monday, the justices took the unusual initiative of broadening the scope of a <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> racial-harassment case so that they could consider limiting the ability of minorities to sue private citizens for monetary damages. <PERSON> Arthur </PERSON> <PERSON> Spitzer </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> ACLU </ORGANIZATION>'s legal director here, said the court's action will have `` enormous psychological impact'' by indicating `` basic civil rights decisions now may be considered open to attack. A conservative constitutional lawyer, hailing the action, said it comes from a court `` no longer willing to say, as it has in the past, that any statutory interpretation that is a victory for minorities automatically wins even if you've got to bend legal principles.'' The lawyer, <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Fein </PERSON>, visiting fellow in constitutional studies at the conservative think tank <ORGANIZATION> Heritage </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION>, said the action could lead the court to take another look at other cases which represent `` really almost absurd efforts to rewrite intent and legislative history.'' `` This indicates to me,'' <PERSON> Fein </PERSON> said, `` that the court is going to take a hard look at statutory civil rights and be willing to overturn decisions where they were based on really flawed reasoning, even if the results are politically unpopular.'' <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, who joined the court in February, provided a fifth vote Monday to re-examine the 1976 ruling that expanded the right of minorities to sue over alleged discrimination. The other four are Chief Justice <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Rehnquist </PERSON> and Justices <PERSON> Byron </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> White </PERSON>, <PERSON> Antonin </PERSON> <PERSON> Scalia </PERSON> and <PERSON> Sandra </PERSON> <PERSON> Day </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Connor </PERSON>. <PERSON> Scalia </PERSON>, <PERSON> O'Connor </PERSON> and <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> were appointed to the court by President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, a frequent critic of rulings he regards as too liberal. Justice <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Stevens </PERSON>, in a sharply worded dissent, said minorities may feel betrayed by the court's willingness to consider discarding an important civil rights precedent. He said the action is unwise activism and will `` have a detrimental and enduring impact on the public's perception of the court as an impartial adjudicator.'' He was joined by Justices <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Brennan </PERSON>, <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Blackmun </PERSON> and <PERSON> Thurgood </PERSON> <PERSON> Marshall </PERSON>. Their views were echoed by <PERSON> Glasser </PERSON>, who said the five in the majority `` have made careers of extolling the virtue of judicial restraint.'' <PERSON> Glasser </PERSON> continued, `` In this case they have reopened a major strand of the civil rights enforcement infrastructure when neither party in the case has asked to do so and when there is no ferment in the courts below.'' The court majority, in an unsigned order, said, `` It is surely no affront to settled jurisprudence to request argument on whether a particular precedent should be modified or overruled.'' The <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> case, argued last Feb. 29, now will be held over until the court's next term beginning in October. A ruling is likely in 1989. In the case, <PERSON> Brenda </PERSON> <PERSON> Patterson </PERSON>, a black woman, wants to use a post-Civil War law to force her employer, <ORGANIZATION> McClean </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Credit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION>, to pay actual and punitive damages for alleged harassment. Lower federal courts said the law, the Civil Rights Act of 1866, is designed only to ban racial discrimination in hiring, firing and promotion _ not racial harassment. Ms. <PERSON> Patterson </PERSON> still could charge racial harassment under a 1964 civil rights law. But the more recent law provides that those who win their cases in court may collect back pay, not potentially big awards as compensation for emotional and mental suffering. Civil rights groups say the more limited 1964 law may not be a sufficient deterrent to harassment. The court agreed to use Ms. <PERSON> Patterson </PERSON>'s appeal to reconsider a 1976 ruling, called <PERSON> Runyon </PERSON> vs. <PERSON> McCrary </PERSON>, that held that racially segregated private schools violate the 1866 law. The statute was enacted to ensure that recently freed slaves would enjoy all the rights of citizenship. The 1976 decision has given civil rights groups an important legal weapon to fight racial bias by permitting them to use the law as a basis for lawsuits against private individuals. In other action, the court: _ Turned away the first `` dial-a-porn'' case ever to reach it, letting stand a ban on sexually explicit telephone message services in <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION> _ Agreed to decide whether wardens of federal prisons should have sweeping power to say what publications inmates may read
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880426-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-26-88 0043EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-US-Gulf Bjt   04-26 0767</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-US-Gulf, Bjt,750</SECOND>
<HEAD>Reagan Administration Reversing Field on Extent of U.S. Role in
Gulf</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TIM AHERN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 New declarations that the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> does n't want a `` serious shooting war'' with <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> come amid signs that the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration is backing away from earlier proposals to broaden the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> role in the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION>. The new suggestions by top administration officials come after a week-long review of Persian Gulf policy triggered by the April 18 clash between the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> and <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>, in which six Iranian ships were damaged or sunk. Last week, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials had said the policy was under review, specifically the rules of engagement which permitted the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> only to protect itself and 11 reflagged Kuwaiti tankers. But on Monday, administration officials suggested that there may be no change in that policy. Secretary of State <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> stressed that no final decision had been made, but said `` we will not get tied up in any serious shooting war with the Iranians.'' Presidential spokesman <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> reflected the new line, telling reporters that `` everybody acknowledges that we need to move back to some more limited set of rules.'' For the past 10 months, <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> ships have been escorting the 11 reflagged Kuwaiti tankers through the gulf, which is one of the venues for the long Iran-Iraq war. <LOCATION> Kuwait </LOCATION> is an ally of <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has previously attacked Iranian forces and facilities in retaliation for Iranian mine-laying activities. Last week's clash was in revenge for an April 14 incident in which a <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> frigate hit a mine the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> claimed was laid by <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>. Administration officials had suggested last week that the rules might be changed to let the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> aid other merchant ships should those vessels come under attack. `` Right now the rules of engagement are essentially the same as they were last week, reflecting the emergency nature of the situation,'' <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said Monday. `` But the question is, where do we move back to? ... I ca n't discuss specifics.'' <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON>, appearing on <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Today'' program from <LOCATION> Belgium </LOCATION> where he was meeting with other <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> officials, said `` as far as our rules of engagement are concerned, what the right ones are for this stage of the game in the gulf is being considered in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, and there is a process of consultation going on, and I think it's premature to describe them in any particular way. On April 18, <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said, <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> vessels were given wider latitude. `` You'll recall at that point that our ships were engaging hostile forces in any number of areas. And we now want to move back to our conservative set of rules. And so that decision has to be made about where to move back to ...'' One change may be the addition of up to six 110-foot <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> boats to help patrol the shallow gulf waters. That proposal was criticized on <LOCATION> Capitol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION>, where senators noted that the <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> is already cutting back its anti-drug patrols and some routine search and rescue missions because of budget cuts. But the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> has offered to pay for the <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION>'s <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> patrols `` Ridiculous, harebrained, absolute utter nonsense,'' said Sen. <PERSON> Alfonse </PERSON> <PERSON> D'Amato </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-N.Y. </LOCATION>, a critic of administration anti-drug policies. Sen. <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Hatfield </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION>, ranking Republican on the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appropriations </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, said, `` I do n't know what the rationale for that would be. We've put a lot of additional burdens on the <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> in the last few years and I'd think they have a full plate.'' The committee will meet later this week to consider shifting money to the <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> to meet a $ 100 million budget shortfall. The lightly armed `` Island'' class patrol boats would be pulled off anti-drug patrols in the <LOCATION> Caribbean </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> officials said Monday. The boats would be replaced by new <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> cutters now under construction. Adm. <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Yost </PERSON>, commandant of the <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION>, said `` if the president, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Joint </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chiefs </ORGANIZATION>, think those boats would be a help over there, I'm more than delighted to send them and my <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> personnel are ready to go. Really raring and ready to go.'' The <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> is part of the <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, but the agency also falls under <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> jurisdiction for national security purposes. The boats which would be used in the gulf operations have a maximum speed of more than 26 knots and carry a crew of 16. The vessels are armed with one 20mm machine gun in the front, and two 7.62 mm machine guns elsewhere Another 20mm machine gun can be added.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880426-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-26-88 0045EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-BarefootElectrocution     04-26 0280</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Barefoot Electrocution,0290</SECOND>
<HEAD>Barefoot Teen-Ager Electrocuted On Hot Steel Plate</HEAD>
<DATELINE>FORT LAUDERDALE, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A teen-ager walking barefoot along a busy street was electrocuted when she stepped on a steel plate that covered wiring for a light post, authorities said. Sunday morning's accident that killed 17-year-old <PERSON> Veronika </PERSON> <PERSON> Beatriz </PERSON> <PERSON> Feria </PERSON> `` was just a death waiting to happen,'' said <PERSON> Ott </PERSON> <PERSON> Cefkin </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lauderdale </LOCATION> police spokesman. The street and wiring had been moved to make way for the entrance of a new shopping center. It was badly rewired and set the grating alive with 480 volts, said police and a <ORGANIZATION> Florida </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Power </ORGANIZATION> and Light spokesman. Had the victim been wearing shoes, she probably would have been insulated from the current, said <ORGANIZATION> FPL </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Ostberg </PERSON>. <PERSON> Feria </PERSON>, who moved to <LOCATION> Oakland </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Park </LOCATION> from <LOCATION> Peru </LOCATION>, had been celebrating the 18th birthday of her best friend, <PERSON> Lina </PERSON> <PERSON> Torres </PERSON>, on Saturday. They had gone to the beach with another friend, <PERSON> Beatriz </PERSON> <PERSON> Lopez-Aguirre </PERSON>, 29, and were on their way to her apartment shortly before 5 a.m. <ORGANIZATION> Feria </ORGANIZATION>'s friends received mild shocks when they tried in vain to revive her. A motorist, <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Spector </PERSON>, stopped to help and pulled her body off the plate using a towel for insulation, authorities said. <PERSON> Cefkin </PERSON> said city workers investigating the accident told police a poorly insulated wire had been improperly positioned on the lip of the box beneath the steel plate. When the lid was placed on the box, the insulation was severed. `` It turned that cover into a hot plate,'' <PERSON> Cefkin </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Ostberg </PERSON> said he'd never heard of that happening. <PERSON> Cefkin </PERSON> said it was unclear who was responsible for the wiring, but the investigation was continuing.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880426-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-26-88 0053EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-PentagonVeep Bjt   04-26 0756</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Pentagon Veep, Bjt,750</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHINGTON WIRE: A Double-Duty Vice President for the Democrats</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LAWRENCE L. KNUTSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Imagine it: newspaper stories next year that begin with the words, `` Vice President and Secretary of Defense <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> <PERSON> Nunn </PERSON> said today that ...'' There would be a lot of ifs to be surmounted if <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION>'s senior Democratic senator were in a position to assume such a jawbreaking and unprecedented dual title. <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> would have to win the Democratic presidential nomination, ask <PERSON> Nunn </PERSON> to be his running mate, offer him the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> as an inducement to accept, and then win the fall campaign. But the idea is being floated _ apparently seriously _ by such leading Democrats as former <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Robb </PERSON>. Others say <PERSON> Nunn </PERSON> as a prominent Southerner and respected defense expert would so strengthen a <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> ticket that he should be promised he could be secretary of state or national security adviser _ if he also agrees to run for vice president. <PERSON> Nunn </PERSON> has said that no matter what inducements might be offered, his interest in the vice presidency is just about one on a scale of 10. But he has never said never. No vice president has ever served simultaneously as secretary of defense. No vice president has ever served simultaneously as a member of a president's <ORGANIZATION> Cabinet </ORGANIZATION>. But a number of people who became vice president had previously served in presidential cabinets. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Calhoun </PERSON> served as vice president in one period and as secretary of state at another. Presidents have appointed vice presidents to task forces on one subject or another. President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> named Vice President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> to head a task force on drugs and narcotics. President <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> named his vice president, <PERSON> Lyndon </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>, to head a task force on space exploration. Other vice presidents have had a strong influence on their administrations. But that has been the rare exception rather than the rule. While not barred by the Constitution, a vice president simultaneously serving as secretary of defense might well discover a thicket of unexpected conflicts. While the vice president has his job by election, a cabinet officer must be confirmed by the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>. The only job specifically assigned the vice president by the Constitution is to serve as president of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>. Unexpected strains might arise if the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> were asked to confirm its own presiding office to serve as well in a Cabinet post. In the role of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>'s presiding officer, the vice president's only real power is his ability to cast tie-breaking votes at moments of legislative impasse. Some senators might demand that a vice president who was also the secretary of defense abstain from breaking a tie on closely divided defense issues directly affecting his department. Such a decision would deprive the administration of its ability to decide the issue in its favor by breaking the tie. Since 1981 <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has broken seven ties, five of them on defense issues. Secretaries of defense routinely testify before congressional committees in defense of military budgets. There is some potential awkwardness in a situation when the witness is also president of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>. Concern might also be triggered if it became necessary for an elected vice president also serving as secretary of defense to travel with a president to an overseas conference. That would place both the president and vice president out of the country at the same time. And that might become a more worrisome situation if the country they were visiting were the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. Naming <PERSON> Nunn </PERSON> the national security adviser might create fewer such problems since the person who fills that post is not confirmed by the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>. The vice presidency has not always been a happy post for the person who held the job. Many have complained it consists of little more than attending the funerals of foreign leaders. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Adams </PERSON>, the nation's first vice president, had some thoughts on his job which he shared with his colleagues on the eve of a visit to their chamber by President <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. `` Gentlemen, I feel great difficulty -LRB- in -RRB- how to act,'' <PERSON> Adams </PERSON> said. `` I am possessed of two separate powers. I am vice president. In this I am nothing, but I may be everything. `` But I am president also of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>. When the president comes into the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>, what shall I be?'' Some politicians are still thinking about what a vice president shall be, at least when <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> <PERSON> Nunn </PERSON>'s name comes up for discussion.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880426-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-26-88 0054EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Soviet-Summit Bjt   04-26 0772</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Soviet-Summit, Bjt,750</SECOND>
<HEAD>Soviets Worry That Reagan Backing Away</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BRYAN BRUMLEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Soviet officials are giving up hopes of sharp cuts in strategic nuclear arsenals before President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> leaves office and fear he may be returning to Red-baiting as he prepares to make his exit. `` The problem is that the American position is moving not forward but backward,'' said <PERSON> Valentin </PERSON> <PERSON> Falin </PERSON>, chairman of the semi-official <ORGANIZATION> Novosti </ORGANIZATION> news agency. `` As far as I can see, we do n't have enough time to prepare any formal treaty'' before the <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> summit May 29-June 2, <PERSON> Falin </PERSON> said in an interview on Monday. <PERSON> Falin </PERSON>, a non-voting member of the policymaking <ORGANIZATION> Soviet </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> and former <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> ambassador to <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, blamed the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration and the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> political process for what he called wasted time since the summit in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> last December. `` Certainly we can not accomplish in the following four weeks what we have failed to do in four months,'' said <PERSON> Falin </PERSON>. `` Certainly, we can not expect miracles.'' <PERSON> Falin </PERSON> also criticized a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> intelligence report saying the Soviet economy has not improved despite economic reforms by Soviet leader <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>. He said the joint report by the <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Intelligence </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> analysts might have been done `` to show the president that the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> is almost on its deathbed and it needs just another push, that he should not talk with the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, but push it.'' <PERSON> Falin </PERSON> contested the pessimistic <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> intelligence report, and said that under <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> industrial production rose more than 4 percent last year and agricultural production was up 9 percent, `` higher than any rate in a decade.'' The <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> intelligence studies said the production of goods and services last year in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> grew by only 0.5 percent, after a 4 percent jump in 1986. <PERSON> Falin </PERSON> said the gloomy <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> intelligence report and recent speeches by the president may signal a return to the harsh anti-Soviet rhetoric of <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s first years in office, when he called the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> an `` evil empire.'' `` I would say that in his most recent speech, as well as his speeches in March and February, the president was preoccupied with rhetoric,'' said <PERSON> Falin </PERSON>. `` Bearing in mind that he will not remain in office for a long time, he is trying to say in his last speeches what he lost the chance to say in 1981 and 1982. `` We have already passed the time when we could tolerate such rhetorical escapades.'' <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> complained after meeting with Secretary of State <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> last week that the administration was `` marking time'' in arms control negotiations. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> has said that he will not tailor his arms control positions to meet political deadlines, and does not expect the meeting in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> to wrap up the proposed Strategic Arms Reduction Treaty to cut strategic nuclear arsenals by 30 to 50 percent. Previously, Soviet officials were more optimistic in public assessments of the summit. <PERSON> Falin </PERSON>'s comments reflected what has become public pessimism by the Kremlin. <PERSON> Falin </PERSON> also accused the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration of dragging its heels in negotiations for an international convention to curb chemical weapons and on <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION> Pact proposals for cuts in non-nuclear forces in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>. But whatever the prospects for the summit, said <PERSON> Falin </PERSON>, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> `` will be accorded our very warm and very deep hospitalities.'' `` As we look at summits, we think they are convened not to express sentiments, but to become milestones in the development of bilateral and international relations,'' said <PERSON> Falin </PERSON>. `` This is a problem for the president, because it is important for him how he finishes his political career.'' At best, said <PERSON> Falin </PERSON>, the meeting may produce a `` framework ... for the development of future negotiations. This will make negotiations easier.'' But no START accord is likely by the end of the year, and it is doubtful that <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> would meet again for what would be their fifth summit, he said. After <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>, said <PERSON> Falin </PERSON>, `` I do not think that your president will have enough authority to make obligations which would have to be fulfilled by his successor.'' The Soviets, he said, are frustrated by the American political process. `` In your country, it is a dead political season,'' said <PERSON> Falin </PERSON>. `` Every four years in your political life, one year is wasted.'' He declined to say whether the <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION> would prefer to deal with Vice President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, who has virtually clinched the Republican presidential nomination, or with the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> front-runner, <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>. `` The Soviet leadership would prefer to negotiate with the person who will be elected to the White House by your people,'' said <PERSON> Falin </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880426-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-26-88 0111EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Bush Bjt   04-26 0620</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bush, Bjt,610</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush Set To Lock In Nomination With Delegates Picked Today</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TOM RAUM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has had a virtual lock on the Republican presidential nomination since late March, but today's <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> primary should make it a mathematical certainty The contest, in which <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> only faces token opposition from former television evangelist <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON>, should raise his delegate total to more than the 1,139 needed for nomination at the GOP convention in August in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION>. Savoring the situation on the eve of that vote, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> told an airport rally in <LOCATION> Scranton </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION>, on Monday: `` We got a break in this primary process. ... I'm glad it's gone my way.'' The vice president noted that due to his overwhelming lead in the race for the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> nomination, the campaign spotlight has been mostly on the Democratic contenders. But he said he was n't complaining `` The news is being dominated by the Jackson-Dukakis fight. That's the way it should be,' said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. `` I would n't trade places.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> predicted that the general election `` is going to be hard fought; it's going to be close.'' The vice president was campaigning today in <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION>, both of which hold primaries a week from today. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was attending a rally in <LOCATION> Lima </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, addressing the <ORGANIZATION> Ohio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Broadcasters </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Cincinnati </LOCATION> and holding an airport rally in <LOCATION> Evansville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ind </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> tells audiences he'll still campaign through to the end of the primary season and `` ca n't wait'' to debate the Democratic nominee, who he has predicted will be <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>. Even so, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> remains vague on the terms for such events. `` I'm not going to let some outside group, even within my own party, set the agenda,'' he told reporters in <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION>. `` I'll appoint somebody who knows about setting up debates'' and who could work with Democrats in coming up with a process agreeable to both parties, he said. On another subject, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said in <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION> that he fully backs President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s vow to veto trade legislation nearing a final congressional vote. However, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said he hoped that some other way could be found to notify workers of impending plant closings. The bill _ which <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> has said he would sign if he were president _ contains a provision requiring 60 days advance when plants are to be shut down. `` Maybe there's a compassionate way to give notice to a worker and his family. But it has nothing to do with the trade bill,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said. `` I know it's an emotional issue but -LRB- the bill -RRB- interferes with our ability to compete.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> did acknowledge that there were still areas of <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> and elsewhere that had not shared fully in the economic recovery that is now in its sixth year. But he criticized Democrats, saying they `` talk about despair and agony.'' `` You're going to see a clear choice'' in the general election, he said. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has had a huge lead for the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> nomination since his remarkable 17-state sweep in the March 8 Super Tuesday contests, a lead he solidified with the withdrawal from the race on March 29 of Sen. <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>, his only remaining major rival. <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> is still technically a candidate but has ceased active campaigning, saying there is no way <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> can be denied the nomination. He has a scant 31 delegates, to <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s 1,081. At his campaign appearance Monday at the Scranton-Wilkes-Barre airport, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was confronted by about two dozen protesters. `` I'm glad to see the -LRB- <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> -RRB- <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> supporters here, or maybe the <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> supporters,'' he said. Of the Democrats, he said: `` I will welcome them in debate, I will welcome taking on their ticket and we will beat them in the fall.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880426-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-26-88 0112EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Scotus-Kennedy'sRole     04-26 0550</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Scotus-Kennedy's Role,550</SECOND>
<HEAD>An AP News Analysis</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Scotus Rdp</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RICHARD CARELLI</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> Justice <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, two months on the job, has given liberals their first real cause for concern that he will help forge a solid conservative court majority. <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> was part of a 5-4 majority that said Monday it is thinking about overturning a 1976 decision considered a key civil rights victory. The ruling 12 years ago, never undone by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, interpreted a Civil War era law as allowing lawsuits for monetary damages against private businesses and individuals over alleged racial discrimination. The decision in <PERSON> Runyon </PERSON> vs. <PERSON> McCrary </PERSON>, adopted in hundreds of lower court cases since, has become what one civil rights lawyer called `` a major strand of the civil rights enforcement infrastructure.'' Monday's announcement sparked sharp criticism and dire predictions. Four justices said it could shake minorities' faith in the court. `` Time alone will tell whether the erosion of faith is unnecessarily precipitous,'' said Justice <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Stevens </PERSON>, a swing vote who most often sides with the court's liberals. `` But in the meantime some of the harm that will flow from today's order may never be completely undone.'' <PERSON> Ira </PERSON> <PERSON> Glasser </PERSON>, executive director of the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Civil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberties </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION>, agreed. `` The message is there's a new court and previous rulings are up for grabs,'' he said. `` If this decision possibly can be overturned, perhaps a lot more are endangered.'' The court's three <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> appointees _ Kennedy and Justices <PERSON> Sandra </PERSON> <PERSON> Day </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Connor </PERSON>, <PERSON> Antonin </PERSON> <PERSON> Scalia </PERSON> _ joined Chief Justice <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Rehnquist </PERSON> and <PERSON> Byron </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> White </PERSON> in voting to restudy the 1976 decision. Joining <PERSON> Stevens </PERSON> in dissent were Justices <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Brennan </PERSON>, <PERSON> Thurgood </PERSON> <PERSON> Marshall </PERSON>, the court's leading liberals, and Justice <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Blackmun </PERSON>, another swing vote. Will there be five votes to overturn the 1976 precedent? <PERSON> Rehnquist </PERSON>, long the court's most conservative member, and <PERSON> White </PERSON>, a conservative with a generally liberal voting record in civil rights cases, dissented from the 1976 decision. Two likely votes to overturn. <PERSON> Scalia </PERSON> is considered as conservative as <PERSON> Rehnquist </PERSON>. A third vote. The keys may be the votes of <PERSON> O'Connor </PERSON>, who in recent years has shown greater independence from the court's conservative bloc, and <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, who joined the court last Feb. 18. <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> won <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> confirmation only after <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s nomination of <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bork </PERSON> was rejected. <PERSON> Bork </PERSON>'s critics in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> and among the civil rights organizations who opposed him said they feared his replacing centrist <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Powell </PERSON> on the court could threaten 30 years of civil rights precedents. In its first seven years, the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration has had little success persuading the court to adopt the president's conservative agenda: outlawing abortion, restoring prayers in public schools and curtailing affirmative action <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, whose views on such matters are unknown, is viewed as a staunch conservative less ideological than <PERSON> Bork </PERSON>. Some liberals voiced the hope that he would assume <PERSON> Powell </PERSON>'s role as the court's voice of judicial restraint But the concerns voiced during the <PERSON> Bork </PERSON> nomination fight were echoed Monday. Calling <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> the key to a `` new court,'' the <ORGANIZATION> ACLU </ORGANIZATION>'s <PERSON> Glaser </PERSON> said: `` <PERSON> Bork </PERSON> had an extensive record of civil rights animus and <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> did not. But this is n't encouraging.''
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 EDITOR'S NOTE: <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Carelli </PERSON> has covered the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> for <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> since 1976.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880426-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-26-88 0113EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-NukeInvestigation     04-26 0457</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nuke Investigation,450</SECOND>
<HEAD>Report Says Nuclear Agency Should Improve Its Internal
Investigations</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID GOELLER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Nuclear </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Regulatory </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Lando </PERSON> <PERSON> Zech </PERSON> says he agrees with a congressional study recommending that the agency improve its internal investigations. He made the statement Monday as his agency released a study by the <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Accounting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> that said the <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION> needs to ensure that its investigations are done professionally and competently. `` The commission will give careful consideration to -LRB- the -RRB- entire report in our continuing efforts to assure that we carry out our investigative responsibilities fairly and efficiently,'' <PERSON> Zech </PERSON> said. In the study, <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION> said `` the important mission and critical safety role of the <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION> require that it possess a first-rate investigative capability.'' <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION>, the investigative wing of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, said the study was based on review of three investigations made within the nuclear agency. <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION> said that in two cases, the work done by the <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION>'s Office of Inspector and Auditor was not thorough enough One case involved allegations by an <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION> inspector that superiors had pressured him to change findings in 1986 about safety conditions at the <ORGANIZATION> Comanche </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Peak </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Steam </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Electric </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Station </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>. The other involved alleged improper discussions in 1986 between <PERSON> Victor </PERSON> <PERSON> Stello </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION>'s executive director of operations, and <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> White </PERSON>, head of the <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Authority </LOCATION>'s NRC-regulated nuclear program. <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION> said its review supported the findings of <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION> investigators who said neither matter was improper. But in both cases <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION> said that <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION> investigators had not interviewed individuals with key roles. The third case looked into <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION>'s probe of how a copy of an internal <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION> document turned up in 1985 in the files of the <ORGANIZATION> Louisiana </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Power </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Light </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Company </ORGANIZATION>'s Waterford III plant _ along with a memo from <ORGANIZATION> LPL </ORGANIZATION>'s holding company saying the document had been `` received from sources inside'' the <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION>. <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION> said notations on the copy indicated it was duplicated from the file copy in the office of <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION> Commissioner <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Roberts </PERSON>, who was in charge of investigating the alleged leak. <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION> was critical of the `` very limited'' investigation made by <PERSON> Roberts </PERSON>, but <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION> said it was unable to determine how the copy reached the regulated utility. `` A properly conducted investigation might have provided <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION> with the identity'' of the leaker, according to <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION>. The case, <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION> said, `` demonstrated that a regulated utility secured unauthorized access to <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION> documents. The ability to obtain such materials could impact on the <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION>'s enforcement program, licensing functions and regulatory procedures.'' `` The <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION> should assure that its investigators conduct their work in a competent manner using professional standards,'' said <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION>, adding that there is a lack of coordination between the <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Investigations </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> of Inspector and Auditor
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880426-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-26-88 0113EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-ArmsTreaty     04-26 0331</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Arms Treaty,330</SECOND>
<HEAD>GOP Leaders Try To Find Way To Assure May INF Ratification</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto WX8</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LAWRENCE L. KNUTSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Republicans are trying to make sure the medium-range missile treaty is ratified before President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> meets Soviet leader <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> on May 29, but the majority leader says Democrats wo n't be rushed. Senate Minority Leader <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>, R-Kan., appealed on Monday for swift action on the treaty He said the president deserves to be accommodated on his wish not to go to <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> empty-handed. President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> has said it is important for the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> to ratify the treaty before he meets <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> because there is little chance the two sides will make further arms control progress unless the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> has acted favorably. But Majority Leader <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON> of <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> said he refused `` to be rushed or harried'' on the matter before remaining problems are cleared away. <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON> said he will not call up the treaty for debate before May 9. He added he may not do so then unless it can be shown the Soviets agree with the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> position that the pact bans medium-range `` futuristic'' weapons such as those using laser rays or particle beam generators. <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> and other Republicans huddled Monday with White House chief of staff <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> and national security adviser <PERSON> Colin </PERSON> <PERSON> Powell </PERSON> to devise a strategy to deal with <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON>'s concerns and get the treaty debate started. <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON> replied: `` I want to accommodate the president too, and will accommodate the president where I can. ... But that is not my first responsibility. ... That is not my first objective. `` I'm going to accommodate the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> and our responsibilities under the Constitution first, before the accommodation of anybody else or any other office.'' The treaty is silent on future weapons, but <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> negotiators contend the pact bans all weapons with ranges of from 300 miles to 3,400 miles, no matter how they are armed.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880426-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-26-88 0113EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--BrazilOilFire     04-26 0187</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Brazil Oil Fire,0190</SECOND>
<HEAD>Oil Rig Fire Cuts Brazilian Production By 11 Percent</HEAD>
<DATELINE>RIO DE JANEIRO, Brazil (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Three ships were fighting a fire on <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION>'s largest offshore oil rig, and the state oil company, <ORGANIZATION> Petrobas </ORGANIZATION>, said the blaze has caused an 11 percent drop in the nation's petroleum output. <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Pinto </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Petrobras </ORGANIZATION> spokesman, said the fire broke out Sunday when gas leaked from the Enchova platform in the <LOCATION> Campos </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Basin </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION>'s richest oil-producing region, 120 miles east of <LOCATION> Rio </LOCATION> <LOCATION> De </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Janeiro </LOCATION>. The 250 workers on the oil rig were safely evacuated to a ship, he said. Three ships on Monday continued to spray the platform with water in an effort to put out the fire, the spokesman said. <PERSON> Enchova </PERSON> and four connected fields were shut down, halting the production of 71,000 barrels of oil and 2 million cubic meters of gas per day, <PERSON> Pinto </PERSON> said. The campos basin offshore fields produce 60 percent of the nation's oil output of 615,000 barrels a day and 40 percent of the 17 million cubic meters of gas. <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION> imports about 45 percent of the oil it uses.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880426-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-26-88 0114EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-AtomicVeterans     04-26 0455</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Atomic Veterans,450</SECOND>
<HEAD>Veterans Of Atomic Testing, WWII To Get Benefits Under Senate Vote</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TIM AHERN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The quarter-million `` atomic veterans'' exposed to radiation during World War II and open-air nuclear tests in the two decades that followed would receive new health benefits under a bill before the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>. The Democratic-controlled chamber is expected to vote on the bill this week. The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> passed it Monday by a 48-30 vote. House passage would send the measure to President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, who has threatened to veto the legislation because of its high costs and because administration officials claim there is no scientific basis for the bill. The measure would cost an estimated $ 36 million in its first year to pay for extra medical benefits. The 250,000 surviving atomic veterans are <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> service personnel who took part in the occupation of <LOCATION> Hiroshima </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Nagasaki </LOCATION> after <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> atomic bombs were dropped on those two Japanese cities in August 1945, or who took part in open-air tests of atomic weapons in the southern <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ocean </LOCATION> or <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION>. Many of the servicemen wore little or no protective gear during the tests, and some have claimed that their exposure to radiation caused cancer. The bill would make a presumptive finding that 13 different cancers are related to their radiation exposure during the tests or the Japanese service. Existing law provides that veterans who have cancer can be compensated or receive health benefits, but they must show in each case that the cancer is related to the military service. Only 28 of the nearly 5,000 veterans who have filed radiation-related claims with the <ORGANIZATION> Veterans </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> have been approved for disability benefits. The bill now before the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> began as an amendment to a much larger health and compensation bill for the nation's 27.4 million military veterans. But the `` atomic veteran'' provision was dropped after the White House said <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> would veto a measure containing the amendment. Sen. <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Cranston </PERSON>, D-Calif., chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Veterans </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Affairs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, supported the measure because, he told his colleagues, `` it is time to be fair to these men. But Sen. <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Simpson </PERSON>, R-Wyo., said the bill `` just ignores sound, medical scientific evidence ... It's just an absurd approach toward compensation.'' Sen. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> McClure </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Idaho </LOCATION>, said that `` scientists are still unsure about how much level ionizing radiation causes cancer.'' Sen. <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Simon </PERSON>, D-Ill., agreed _ up to a point `` We do not yet know the full relationship between low-level radiation and latent illness,'' he said. `` But it is crystal clear that many of those responsible for setting policies that affect thousands of our citizens are intent upon making the facts fit their theories and decisions instead of the other way around.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880426-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-26-88 0118EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-BlackKidneyDisease     04-26 0543</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Black Kidney Disease,520</SECOND>
<NOTE>For release at noon EDT; time set by source</NOTE>
<HEAD>Possible Genetic Basis for Kidney Disease Among Blacks</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PAUL RECER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Science Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Black people may have a gene that gives their kidneys the unique ability to function well on very limited amounts of salt, but which also can cause high blood pressure and disease when too much salt is consumed, a researcher suggested today. Dr. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Luke </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cincinnati </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> said the existence of this unique kidney gene is suggested by the mixed results of efforts to prevent disease by controlling high blood pressure among black people. Speaking at a <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Kidney </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION> seminar, <PERSON> Luke </PERSON> said controlling high blood pressure, or hypertension, has resulted in a reduction in stroke and heart disease. But it has not caused a reduction in the rate of a kidney disease caused by hypertension. And striking differences between the races suggest there may be a genetic-based difference in the cause of high blood pressure. `` All kidney disease is more common among blacks than whites,'' said <PERSON> Luke </PERSON>, the chairman of the department of internal medicine at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cincinnati </ORGANIZATION>. `` End-stage renal disease -LRB- terminal kidney failure -RRB- is three times more common in blacks than in whites.'' He said that at a <LOCATION> Birmingham </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ala. </LOCATION> transplant center, which performs about half its transplants on black patients, there have been many instances where kidneys transplanted from a white donor to a black patient with high blood pressure has resulted in the recipient becoming `` normotensive,'' or achieving a normal blood pressure. `` This suggests that the cause of the original high blood pressure was the patient's own kidneys,'' he said. <PERSON> Luke </PERSON> said hypertension among laboratory animals also has been controlled by the transplant of kidneys from `` normotensive'' rats to ones with high blood pressure. Studies also have shown, he said, that black people tend to retain more salt, excreting less of the mineral in their urine than white people. All of this suggests, said <PERSON> Luke </PERSON>, `` that a hereditary kidney abnormality may actually cause high blood pressure.'' He said there is speculation that this kidney characteristic developed through evolution in central <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> where salt is naturally very limited. In that environment, the kidney characteristic represented a `` Darwinian advantage'' for people who lived there, he said. `` In very hot and dry climates in inland areas of low availability of -LRB- salt -RRB-,'' he said, `` an ability of the kidney to carefully and quickly conserve salt may confer a survival advantage in evolution.'' That advantage, however, becomes a disadvantage and eventually leads to disease if there is an overabundance of salt in the diet, said <PERSON> Luke </PERSON>. `` Chronic but subtle salt retention may lead over long periods to high blood pressure possibly as a complication of the body's response to try to force the kidney to excrete more salt,'' he said And high blood pressure, in turn, often leads to kidney disease, heart attack and stroke. Medication can control the high blood pressure and reduce heart attack and stroke, but there is no similar reduction in kidney disease, he said. But a genetic basis for high blood pressure is still speculation, <PERSON> Luke </PERSON> said in an interview, `` and a puzzle that we are still trying to understand.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880426-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-26-88 0120EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Dukakis     04-26 0612</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Dukakis,570</SECOND>
<HEAD>Dukakis Appeared Relaxed Heading Into Today's Pennsylvania Contest</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By EVANS WITT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Political Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>HARRISBURG, Pa. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 It was story time for 28 toddlers and the choice was an old favorite, `` The Very Hungry Caterpillar.'' But the storyteller was a newcomer to the Discovery School _ <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, the front-runner in today's <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> primary. He was a hit with the preschool set. Monday was a day of big crowds and loud cheers for <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, and the <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> governor was trying out a relaxed campaign style. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> held a big lead over rival <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION>, and about all aides had to wonder about was how big a delegate victory he could win in the state. `` I look forward to working with you and to winning with you tomorrow,'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> told about 500 people in <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION> on the eve of the primary. In his final day of campaigning before the <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> vote, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> was at ease and ready to quip. `` I saw a Bush sign around here some place,'' he asked 1,000 gathered on the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Scranton </ORGANIZATION> campus. `` You know, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> is the only guy who had a baseball league named after him. Then he asked if the crowd held any fans of the <ORGANIZATION> Baltimore </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Orioles </ORGANIZATION> _ the team with the worst record in baseball at the moment. `` Where are the <ORGANIZATION> Orioles </ORGANIZATION> fans around here? You know if you're an Orioles fan you have to be headed for a career in social work or something. You have to be very charitable,'' he said. But <LOCATION> Scranton </LOCATION> brought <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> face-to-face with some of the most strident demonstrators of the campaign thus far. Fifty anti-abortion protesters sought to form a gantlet for the candidate outside the hall at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Scranton </ORGANIZATION>. `` Stop <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>! Stop abortion!'' they chanted. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> was escorted to the car by a group of aides and police officers, amid much pushing and shoving. From <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION>, from Erie to <LOCATION> Harrisburg </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> took his message of jobs and party unity. `` There is no more important challenge facing the president of <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. Make no mistake about it. I'm a dyed-in-the-wool, true-blue full-employment Democrat,'' he said in <LOCATION> Erie </LOCATION>. He repeatedly urged his supporters to ignore the polls and to get out the vote _ `` Pollsters do n't vote,'' he said. A win in the complicated election Tuesday would boost his lead for the 1988 Democratic presidential nomination in both delegates and momentum. `` It is n't enough just to vote for me,'' he told 2,000 cheering supporters at a park in Erie. `` This is one election where you've got to vote more than once and it's legal I need your vote as a candidate. Our delegates need your votes. ... We must do both.'' The crowd was enthusiastic, often interrupting <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> with applause and cheers. After the speech, many in the crowd pressed forward to touch <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> and to shake his hand. Several babies were handed to him. Smiling, he kisssed them. `` With your help, we can leave <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> with the kind of enthusiasm and the kind of energy and the kind of momentum that a victory will give,'' he told them. At his first stop in <LOCATION> Phildelphia </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> reached out to the black community that is the core of <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s support. `` We have too much to do in this country to divide ourselves,'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> told about 60 people gathered a black church in <LOCATION> Northeast </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION>. `` I'm someone who believes that one of the jobs of a governor and a president _ perhaps the most important job _ is to bring this country together, brown, black and white, business and labor. These past seven years have been a divisive seven years.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880426-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-26-88 0120EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--Iceland-Strike     04-26 0120</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Iceland-Strike,0125</SECOND>
<HEAD>Clerical Strike Closes Many Businesses In Iceland</HEAD>
<DATELINE>REYKJAVIK, Iceland (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A strike by 15,000 clerical workers interrupted domestic airline service and forced many shops and businesses to close. The workers began their strike on Friday in an attempt to win a 27 percent increase for the lowest paid among them. <ORGANIZATION> Icelandair </ORGANIZATION> halted local flights because of the strike, and clerical workers were expected to walk out of <LOCATION> Keflavik </LOCATION> international airport on Wednesday. Hotels in <LOCATION> Reykjavik </LOCATION> were nearly empty on Monday, and hotel managers said their financial loss will be considerable if the strike continues. The workers struck after the employers' organization turned down a demand by the unions that minimum wages be increased by 27 percent.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880426-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-26-88 0442EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--CardinalHospitalized     04-26 0135</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Cardinal Hospitalized,0137</SECOND>
<HEAD>Retired Roman Catholic Cardinal Treated For Lung Congestion</HEAD>
<DATELINE>DETROIT (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
