<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880729-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-29-88 2326EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-HotelFire     07-29 0299</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Hotel Fire,0307</SECOND>
<HEAD>Fire Breaks Out At Retirement Hotel</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DENNIS GEORGATOS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SAN DIEGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Fire broke out at a downtown retirement hotel Friday, forcing the evacuation of about 150 residents as flames shot out of the top floor and roof of the six-story building, authorities said. Nine of the elderly occupants of the <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION> Hotel were taken to hospitals for treatment of minor symptoms ranging from smoke inhalation to chest pains, said fire Capt. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> McDowell </PERSON>. Hotel resident <PERSON> Wayne </PERSON> <PERSON> Huffman </PERSON>, 60, said he was standing in the lobby shortly before 5 p.m. when he heard a hotel employee shout a warning. `` The desk clerk came running up, yelling ` The building's on fire! The building's on fire!''' `` It was such a small fire,'' said <PERSON> Huffman </PERSON>. `` No one took it seriously until we saw the smoke. Now here we are, out on the street.'' The blaze broke out during the commuter rush hour, drawing a large crowd of spectators and snarling traffic. Hotel residents were among the onlookers, some sitting in wooden chairs across the street from the burning building. More than 75 firefighters were called to the scene and several city blocks were cordoned off. They remained closed at 7 p.m. as firefighters mopped up the blaze, which was confined to the sixth floor. `` We do n't have anything on cause or point of origin yet,'' <PERSON> McDowell </PERSON> said. He estimated 150 people were evacuated, including two people who were rescued from the top floor by an aerial-platform atop a firetruck ladder. `` Structurally, the building is sound,'' <PERSON> McDowell </PERSON> said. `` A wing of the sixth floor was gutted,'' <PERSON> McDowell </PERSON> said, but firefighters hoped residents of unaffected floors might return home later Friday night, he said. <ORGANIZATION> Salvation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> officials were arranging hotel rooms for those who needed them.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880729-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-29-88 2328EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Mexico-Well 1stLd-Writethru a0764 07-29 0231</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Mexico-Well, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0764,0234</SECOND>
<HEAD>Oil Well Fire Put Out</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: LEADS with 3 grafs to UPDATE with fire put out. PICKS up 3rd
graf pvs bgng, The well is ...</NOTE>
<DATELINE>MEXICO CITY (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Special emergency crews managed to put out a fire Friday in an oil rig on the <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> that had been blazing out of control, the state petroleum monopoly <ORGANIZATION> Pemex </ORGANIZATION> said in a statement. `` The fire was put out by special crews at midday today at the <ORGANIZATION> Puerto </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ceiba </ORGANIZATION> 113 well and work continues to bring the well under complete control,'' the statement said without giving details. No injuries have been reported since a fire to burn off natural gas went out of control about dawn Thursday at the Puerto Ceiba 113 well, <ORGANIZATION> Pemex </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Emilio </PERSON> <PERSON> Matar </PERSON> said. The well is about 300 yards off the Tabasco state coast and three miles from <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Paraiso </LOCATION>, a town of 26,000 people. <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Paraiso </LOCATION> is 400 miles southeast of <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. Drilling had reached 19,000 feet when the well went out of control. In addition to cooling the oil rig with water, emergency crews placed a series of dams around the well to contain any oil spills, the spokesman said. <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> is the world's sixth largest producer of crude oil and exports about 1.3 million barrels a day, about half of it to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880729-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-29-88 2328EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-People-Cher     07-29 0260</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-People-Cher,0268</SECOND>
<HEAD>Photographer Sues Actress, Her Boyfriend</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JEFF WILSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SANTA MONICA, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actress <PERSON> Cher </PERSON> and her 24-year-old boyfriend, <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Camilletti </PERSON>, were sued Friday by a free-lance photographer who alleges <PERSON> Camilletti </PERSON> tried to run him down with <PERSON> Cher </PERSON>'s sports car. The lawsuit, filed in <ORGANIZATION> Los </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Angeles </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Superior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>, alleges <PERSON> Cher </PERSON> was negligent by entrusting her Ferrari to <LOCATION> Camilletti </LOCATION>, and accuses him of assault and battery on photographer <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Brandt </PERSON>. In addition, <PERSON> Brandt </PERSON> is suing for emotional distress from the accident Wednesday in front of <PERSON> Cher </PERSON>'s <LOCATION> Benedict </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Canyon </LOCATION> home. The sports car driven by <PERSON> Camilletti </PERSON> hit <PERSON> Brandt </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> Honda </ORGANIZATION> Accord, damaging both vehicles. `` He chased him and said he was going to kill him,'' said <PERSON> Brandt </PERSON>'s attorney, <PERSON> Ron </PERSON> <PERSON> Carpol </PERSON>. <PERSON> Cher </PERSON> and <PERSON> Camilletti </PERSON> have blamed the accident on the tabloid press and the frustration of dealing with paparazzi who incessantly stake out their home. <PERSON> Camilletti </PERSON> was arrested Wednesday and booked for investigation of felony assault with a deadly weapon. He has denied allegations that he was trying to run down <PERSON> Brandt </PERSON>. <PERSON> Camilletti </PERSON> said in a statement prepared by his lawyer that he had hoped to avoid the photographer's stakeout by swerving the car into the Cher's driveway. The Oscar-winning actress, 42, and <PERSON> Camilletti </PERSON> have been companions since meeting at a <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> nightclub on her 40th birthday. Marriage plans have been denied repeatedly by <PERSON> Cher </PERSON>'s publicist <PERSON> Lois </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> A former bagel maker, pizza chef and bartender, <PERSON> Camilletti </PERSON> is now pursuing an acting career and he recently completed shooting of `` Loverboy'' with <PERSON> Kate </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> and <PERSON> Kirstie </PERSON> <PERSON> Alley </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880729-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-29-88 2339EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-Obit-Berlin     07-29 0342</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Obit-Berlin,0354</SECOND>
<HEAD>Novelist, Wife Of Songwriter</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Ellin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION>, the novelist wife of songwriter <PERSON> Irving </PERSON> <PERSON> Berlin </PERSON>, died Friday after the last of a series of strokes. She was 85. Mrs. <PERSON> Berlin </PERSON> died at <LOCATION> Doctors </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION>, where she was taken from her <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION> home. The last of Mrs. <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION>'s four novels, `` The Best of Families,'' was published in 1970. She was also a prolific short-story writer. In one article for The New Yorker, she defended her generation's abandonment of the <ORGANIZATION> Junior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> League </ORGANIZATION> and `` polite society'' for the wilder life of cabarets and dancing the <LOCATION> Charleston </LOCATION> `` It is not because fashionable young ladies are picturesquely depraved that they go to cabarets,'' she wrote. `` They go to find privacy.'' Her marriage to <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> on Jan. 4, 1926, drew headlines as the famous songwriter, an Orthodox Jew, wed the former <PERSON> Ellin </PERSON> <PERSON> Mackay </PERSON>, a Roman Catholic debutante who spurned her multimillionaire father's fortune for love When her father reportedly threatened to disinherit his daughter, <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> reportedly replied, `` In that case, I'll probably have to make her a wedding gift of a couple of million dollars.'' `` It could be the greatest love affair of the century,'' said composer and cabaret performer <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Wallowitch </PERSON>, a neighbor. `` It really is a tragedy.'' <PERSON> Wallowitch </PERSON>, who leads a group in serenading <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> on his birthday, recalled that Mrs. <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> could frequently be seen walking in the neighborhood and went to Mass each Sunday at <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Patrick </ORGANIZATION>'s Cathedral until about 10 years ago. During 62 years of marriage, <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> wrote several songs just for his wife, including `` Always'' and `` The Song Is Ended.'' Mrs. <PERSON> Berlin </PERSON> was born on her father's $ 6 million estate in <LOCATION> Roslyn </LOCATION>. She and <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> had three daughters. Mrs. <PERSON> Berlin </PERSON> was a major supporter of the Girl Scout movement. She is survived by her daughters, <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Ellin </PERSON> <PERSON> Barrett </PERSON> of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>; <PERSON> Linda </PERSON> <PERSON> Louise </PERSON> <PERSON> Emmett </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> Irving </PERSON> <PERSON> Peters </PERSON> of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>; a brother, <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Mackay </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Locust </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION>, nine grandchildren and one great-grandchild. A funeral was scheduled for Tuesday at <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Patrick </ORGANIZATION>'s Cathedral.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880729-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-29-88 2354EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Japan-Markets 1stLd-Writethru a0773 07-29 0260</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Japan-Markets, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0773 ,0265</SECOND>
<HEAD>Japanese Stocks Rise for Fifth Day</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: LEADS thruout to UPDATE with closing stocks</NOTE>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Share prices surged Saturday on the <ORGANIZATION> Tokyo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Stock </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Exchange </ORGANIZATION> for the fifth straight day of gains and a closing level that topped 28,000 points for the first time since mid-July. The Nikkei Stock Average of 225 selected issues, a 115.54-point winner Friday, advanced 288.31 points, or 1.02 percent, to close Saturday's half-day session at 28,199.94. The Nikkei index, the most widely followed market barometer, briefly hovered above 28,000 points in early trading Friday. But Saturday's closing represented the first time the index has finished above the 28,000 level since July 15. Volume on the first section was a heavy 700 million shares. <PERSON> Shinji </PERSON> <PERSON> Shihara </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> Okasan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Securities </ORGANIZATION> said the <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION> market was taking a cue from sharp advances on Wall Street overnight. `` It's the fifth straight day of gains, but the market is really moving up in reaction to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> trading.'' The upsurge in shares prices has also been attributed to a strong <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> currency and reduced concern over growing inflation. `` It's not just the bullish <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> market, but we've got positive economic factors here -LRB- in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> -RRB- along with a strong dollar and less concern about inflation,'' said an analyst with <ORGANIZATION> Nikko </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Securities </ORGANIZATION>, speaking on condition of anonymity. <PERSON> Shihara </PERSON> said light electricals like <ORGANIZATION> Sony </ORGANIZATION> were being sought along with heavy electricals, financials and automakers on the first section of the <ORGANIZATION> Tokyo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Stock </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Exchange </ORGANIZATION>. The <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION> foreign exchange market is closed on Saturdays.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880729-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-29-88 2357EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-ArabFunk Bjt   07-29 0765</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Arab Funk, Bjt,0783</SECOND>
<HEAD>Paris Swings To Them Ole' Bedouin Blues</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By SYDNEY RUBIN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PARIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> is swinging to those old Bedouin blues. Songs that once were chanted by Algerian shepherds to their sheep are now drawing flocks of hip Parisians to dance in city clubs. The music is called `` rai.'' Pronounced `` rye,'' like the bread, it is the latest sound rocking on French radio, a hard-driving electrified wail that makes it hard to stay still. By fall, the pulsing <PERSON> Arab </PERSON> pop likely will be rolling from radios across <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> as record companies, already cashing in on the worldwide popularity of ethno-new wave, begin promoting the music of northwestern <LOCATION> Algeria </LOCATION>. Bedouin sheep herders were the first to sing rai, punctuating langorous melodies and improvised lyrics on Algerian angst with the refrain `` ya rai, ya rai'' _ the nomad equivalent of `` oh yeah.'' During World War II, the music shifted from fields around the western town of <LOCATION> Oran </LOCATION> to bars and brothels in <LOCATION> Algiers </LOCATION>, where rai singers borrowed American jazz riffs learned from black soldiers, just as they had taken Flamenco passion and the paso doble from Spanish settlers in <LOCATION> Oran </LOCATION> decades before. In 1981, an Algerian record producer realized it was cheaper to synthesize drums than pay a drummer. Adding the drum machine was the birth of rai pop, traditional minor-keyed melodies with a rock n' roll beat. Big hits followed, like `` Ana Ma H'lali Ennoum'' -LRB- `` Personally, I Do n't Appreciate Sleeping Anymore'' -RRB- and `` N'sel Fik'' -LRB- `` You Belong to Me'' -RRB-. Who cares if the Arabic slang belted out by the young rai stars is incomprehensible to the average Parisian? The melodies are haunting and the driving 4-4 beat swings. `` <PERSON> Rai </PERSON> is not poetry,'' <PERSON> Cheb </PERSON> <PERSON> Khaled </PERSON>, the charismatic <PERSON> Elvis </PERSON> of Arab funk told the daily newspaper <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION>, which has two reporters writing exclusively about Arab culture. `` <PERSON> Rai </PERSON> speaks directly to people about what is happening in their lives. The things I sing about, I have lived,'' said <PERSON> Khaled </PERSON>. <PERSON> Khaled </PERSON>'s new album, `` Kutche,'' was released June 7 in <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>. It is the first top-quality, high-tech rai disk produced by a Western record company, <ORGANIZATION> EMI-Pathe </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Marconi </ORGANIZATION>, based here. In August three other rai albums by a major British record company are scheduled for release in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> and continental <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, including one by <PERSON> Chaba </PERSON> <PERSON> Fadela </PERSON>, a female vocalist with a rough, sensual voice who has sung duets with <PERSON> Khaled </PERSON>. The three disks will be marketed by <ORGANIZATION> Virgin </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Records </ORGANIZATION>. All have attracted the attention of American disk jockeys, said <PERSON> Jumbo </PERSON> <PERSON> Van </PERSON> <PERSON> Renen </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> Mango </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Records </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>, a division of <PERSON> Virgin </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> Island </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Records </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Van </PERSON> <PERSON> Renen </PERSON> first heard rai in obscure <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> clubs four years ago. He was fascinated by the freshness of the sound and saw its commercial potential. `` There is a growing interest in global excellence and language is no longer a barrier,'' <PERSON> Van </PERSON> <PERSON> Renen </PERSON> said in a telephone interview from <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>. `` <PERSON> Rai </PERSON> is part of the new trend toward world music, it is a sound that, in the tired world of rock' n roll, is good and new.'' <PERSON> Rai </PERSON> is the latest trend in the globalization of pop. <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Simon </PERSON>'s Grammy-winning `` Graceland'' owed much of its uniqueness to the a capella South African male choir Ladysmith Black Mambazo, which opened singer <PERSON> Joan </PERSON> <PERSON> Baez </PERSON>' sold-out <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> gig in June. Musicians from <LOCATION> Antigua </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Zaire </LOCATION> are finding new fans around the world. A festival in 1986 that marked the debut of a several rai singers in <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> attracted 5,000 people a day during the three days of concerts. The music quickly began attracting audiences of non-North Africans, the target market for <PERSON> Khaled </PERSON>'s new release. `` Kutche'' takes its name from the Algerian version of the Spanish word for car, `` coche,'' reflecting the multi-cultural roots of the music. The record's instrumentation is a cultural melange as well. <PERSON> Khaled </PERSON>'s mellifluous, passionate voice pours over synthizers, accordions, violins, traditional North African flutes, Algerian bendirs -LRB- tamborines -RRB-, Arabic derboukas -LRB- drums -RRB- and several African percussion instruments. <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Meissonier </PERSON>, who produced <PERSON> Khaled </PERSON>'s album, launched Nigerian bandleader King Sunny Ade and is credited with introducing African music to the developed world. He called rai lyrics apolitical. But Algerian authorities banned rai from the radio until three years ago, saying lewd lyrics on wine, women and life in <LOCATION> Algeria </LOCATION>'s fast lane had no place on Moslem airwaves. They since have changed their minds and see the music as a way to reach the young. `` Rai touches people because it is more than simply music,'' <PERSON> Meissonier </PERSON> said. `` Like reggae, it is an attitude. <PERSON> Rai </PERSON> is a way of life.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880729-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-29-88 0046EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a BC-AIDS-Stats     07-29 0221</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-AIDS-Stats,0218</SECOND>
<HEAD>CDC Statistics On U.S. AIDS Cases</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ATLANTA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the latest statistics on acquired immune deficiency syndrome in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, as reported this week by the national Centers for Disease Control:
</TEXT>
<HEAD>Number of Cases</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Total cases reported since June 1981: 69,085. Cases, year to date: 18,663. Total deaths: 38,897, or 56 percent of all cases.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>Transmission Categories</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Homosexual or bisexual males: 42,689, or 62 percent. Intravenous drug abusers: 12,929, or 19 percent. Homosexual male and drug abusers: 5,014, or 7 percent. Heterosexual cases: 2,859, or 4 percent. Transfusion or blood cases: 1,848, or 3 percent. Hemophilia patients: 717, or 1 percent. Children of parents with AIDS or at risk: 849, or 1 percent. Undetermined transmission cause: 2,180, or 3 percent.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>Age and Race</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Childhood cases -LRB- under age 13 -RRB-: 1,095, or 2 percent. Cases among whites: 40,329, or 58 percent. Cases among blacks: 18,027, or 26 percent. Cases among Hispanics: 10,084, or 15 percent. Cases among other: 645, or 1 percent. -LRB- NOTE: These statistics are through July 25 and have been rounded to the nearest whole percent. Cumulative totals are for AIDS cases reported since June 1981, and include 75 cases subsequently found to have occurred prior to that date. The `` other'' classification under Age and Race includes Asians, American Indians and native Alaskans. -RRB-
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880729-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-29-88 0048EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-HooverBall     07-29 0477</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Hoover Ball,0490</SECOND>
<HEAD>`Hoover-Ball,' Invented By Former President, Is Not for Wimps</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GREG SMITH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WEST BRANCH, Iowa (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Presidential athletics often makes people think of touch football in the <ORGANIZATION> Kennedy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, but <PERSON> Herbert </PERSON> <PERSON> Hoover </PERSON> invented a sport that makes those games look like tea parties, say devotees of `` Hoover-ball.'' `` Hoover-ball is not a sport for wimps,'' said <PERSON> Scott </PERSON> <PERSON> Sailor </PERSON>, who is organizing the 1988 Hoover-Ball National Championship Aug. 7 in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Branch </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Hoover </PERSON>'s birthplace. `` Hoover-ball'' is like volleyball played with a six-pound medicine ball, except players must catch the ball and heave it back over the eight-foot net. The hardest play may be serving, from 33 feet away, or receiving serve, where the ball comes crashing down faster than the stock market in October 1929. `` One of the reasons for the tournament is that <PERSON> Hoover </PERSON> has had a bad reputation in history. People think of the Depression when his name is mentioned,'' said Sailor, part-time special events coordinator for the <ORGANIZATION> Hoover </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Presidential </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Library </ORGANIZATION> and Museum here. `` We want to show there is more to <PERSON> Hoover </PERSON>, we want to show a more personal side,'' he said. A medicine ball is constructed with a bag of sand at its core, which is wrapped in cotton matting and covered by leather. Used primarily by boxers, whose trainers bash them in the stomach with it while they do situps, the ball is heavy and difficult to catch when it comes flying down. When <PERSON> Hoover </PERSON>, the nation's 31st president, took office in 1929, he carried a portly 210 pounds on a 5-foot-11-inch frame. His physician, Admiral <PERSON> Joel </PERSON> <PERSON> T. </PERSON> <PERSON> Boone </PERSON>, was concerned and advised excercise. The <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> president strung up a net on the south lawn of the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and ordered Cabinet members and other dignitaries to divide into two teams. Except for Sundays, <PERSON> Hoover </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Cabinet </ORGANIZATION> members and <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> justices played the game every day _ national holidays included _ from 7 a.m. to 7:30 a.m., regardless of weather. Teams of two to four players must catch the ball on the fly and return it without passing. A point is won when the opposing team fails to catch the ball or throws it out of bounds. `` It required less skill than tennis, was faster and more vigorous, and therefore gave more exercise in a short time,'' <PERSON> Hoover </PERSON> wrote in his memoirs. `` Stopping a six-pound ball with steam back of it, returning it with similar steam, is not pink-tea stuff.'' <PERSON> Hoover </PERSON> lost 25 pounds playing the game. But, like his hopes for a second term, the game faded away. Sailor and members of the <ORGANIZATION> Hoover </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Library </ORGANIZATION> are reviving it, however, with the tournament held in observance of <PERSON> Hoover </PERSON>'s birth in 1874. Sailor said two teams from <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mo. </LOCATION>, including a writer from Sports Illustrated, will participate, as will about a dozen other rag-tag squads.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880729-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-29-88 0100EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Eastern-Machinists     07-29 0258</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Eastern-Machinists,0265</SECOND>
<HEAD>Union Files Suit to Block Eastern Cutbacks in Service, Workers</HEAD>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MIAMI (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A union representing 12,000 <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> employees seeks to block the carrier from eliminating service in 14 cities in a lawsuit that contends the cutbacks will eventually destroy the company. The suit requests a preliminary injunction or temporary restraining order against the cutbacks in service, scheduled to take effect Aug. 31. Eastern announced the changes, along with a work force reduction of 4,000, last Friday. Unless the cutbacks are blocked, the suit says, <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION> will `` embark on a program that will significantly increase its recurring losses and lead to the ultimate destruction of the carrier.'' The <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Machinists </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aerospace </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Workers </ORGANIZATION> filed the suit Thursday in <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> for the <LOCATION> District </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION>. The union represents Eastern mechanics and ground workers. <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Bryan </PERSON>, president of the Machinists local in <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION>, said the union will argue that <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION>'s reduction in service benefits <ORGANIZATION> Continental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION>. Both companies are subsidiaries of <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION>. `` This is an act of self-help,'' <PERSON> Bryan </PERSON> said at a news conference. `` It's not too different from a lockout, quite frankly.'' Eastern spokesman <PERSON> Robin </PERSON> <PERSON> Matell </PERSON> said the airline has `` taken these actions because they're in the best interests of the company, and we expect that the court will agree with us.'' Eastern's cutbacks mean an 11.4 percent reduction in daily flights. The financially struggling company said the move would permit it to concentrate on serving cities where it is strongest.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880729-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-29-88 0012EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Leonardo Bjt   07-29 0510</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Leonardo, Bjt,0525</SECOND>
<HEAD>Computers Explore Art And Science Of Leonardo da Vinci</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GRAHAM HEATHCOTE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Experts are using computer graphics to explore in three dimensions the revolutionary artistic and scientific work of Italian Renaissance genius <PERSON> Leonardo </PERSON> <PERSON> da </PERSON> <PERSON> Vinci </PERSON>. The results will be shown in the Hayward Gallery Jan. 26-April 16, said <PERSON> Rosalie </PERSON> <PERSON> Cass </PERSON>, an organizer of the exhibition. `` If <PERSON> Leonardo </PERSON> was around today there is no doubt he would be using computers and what we are doing is to show that there was no division in his mind between his science and his art,'' Miss <PERSON> Cass </PERSON> said Thursday. She said the exhibition will combine the artistic and scientific interests of da <PERSON> Vinci </PERSON> and display the greatest range of his drawings ever assembled. `` Unlike photography, which records surface patterns of light and color, computer graphics build realistic, three-dimensional images,'' said <PERSON> Philip </PERSON> <PERSON> Steadman </PERSON>, who is directing the sequences. `` Leonardo's drawings are being plotted into a computer and the sequences will make clear to visitors the spatial thinking and development in his ideas on architectural projects, light in space and geometrical bodies,'' he said. Participants will use the technique to analyze the perspective of <PERSON> Leonardo </PERSON>'s wall painting `` The Last Supper.'' The painting of <PERSON> Jesus </PERSON> <PERSON> Christ </PERSON>, portrayed at the moment when he tells his disciples that one of them will betray him, marks a turning point in art. It presents questions on perspective that art historians and scientists still have not completely solved since the work was completed in 1497. `` Everything comes together in only one spot, but that varies from different viewpoints and from some positions there appear to be different vanishing points,'' Miss <PERSON> Cass </PERSON> said. The tempera painting, damaged by dampness, is on a refectory wall in the church of <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Maria </LOCATION> <LOCATION> delle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Grazie </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Milan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>. In his `` Treatise on Painting'' <PERSON> Leonardo </PERSON> wrote: `` Painting encompasses the surfaces, colors, and forms of anything created by nature, and philosophy penetrates those same bodies, considering their properties, but is not satisfied with the truth as shown by the painter.'' <PERSON> Steadman </PERSON> said: `` It is striking how many of <PERSON> Leonardo </PERSON>'s remarks in his treatise, whether on human anatomy, optics or the structure of plants, go well beyond the limits of what is strictly relevant to the painter's needs, and how often a section ends with a remark that he will pursue the subject elsewhere in one of his projected scientific works.'' The exhibition will have 119 drawings, 88 of them from the royal collection at <ORGANIZATION> Windsor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Castle </ORGANIZATION>, and Italian and British models built recently from <PERSON> Leonardo </PERSON>'s drawings of mechanical inventions. They include a construction of his flying machine with a 36-foot wingspan, ball bearings, a tank and a multibarreled gun. <PERSON> Leonardo </PERSON>, who lived from 1452 to 1519, worked for <PERSON> Duke </PERSON> <PERSON> Lodovico </PERSON> <PERSON> Sforza </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Milan </LOCATION>. He entered the duke's service after writing a celebrated letter saying he believed he could give `` complete satisfaction'' in military engineering, constructing buildings and sculpture in marble, bronze or clay. `` In painting I can do as much as anyone, whoever he may be,'' he wrote.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880729-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-29-88 0012EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-MissingNewlyweds     07-29 0480</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Missing Newlyweds,0492</SECOND>
<HEAD>`Missing' Newlyweds Thankful, Family Forgiving</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DENNIS GEORGATOS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SAN DIEGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Chicago-area newlyweds who surfaced here after dropping out of sight for nearly four months said Thursday they understand why a lot of people are upset with them but are thankful their relatives are forgiving. `` What can you say? We're prodigal children,'' said <PERSON> Scott </PERSON> <PERSON> Swanson </PERSON>, 23, referring to the Biblical parable of a wayward youngster who returns to his family in repentance and is welcomed back. <PERSON> Swanson </PERSON> and his bride, <PERSON> Carolyn </PERSON> <PERSON> Swanson </PERSON>, 22, were reunited Wednesday with her parents, <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> and <PERSON> Kathy </PERSON> <PERSON> MacLean </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Haddonfield </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.J </LOCATION>. The elder MacLeans flew to <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Diego </LOCATION> after receiving a letter from the couple Tuesday and talking to them by telephone later that night. `` We did n't come out thinking we would be welcomed with open arms -LRB- but -RRB- that's what happened with our families and that's the most important thing,'' <PERSON> Swanson </PERSON> said. `` We came out really thinking that we were going to be scorned for the rest of our lives.'' The <ORGANIZATION> Swansons </ORGANIZATION>, students at <ORGANIZATION> Wheaton </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> in a suburb of <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>, disappeared April 2 without a word to relatives or friends. The vanishing act led to fears the couple met with foul play. It provoked a massive and costly police investigation and search that principally involved <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> police but also included law enforcements agencies from other states. The couple said Thursday they do n't believe they should have to make restitution for the police expenditures. `` It seems fairly unrealistic for them to try to prosecute us in the sense that they want the money back,'' said <PERSON> Swanson </PERSON>. He said he believes it's the police rank-and-file, rather than department officials, who want to see some kind of payment because they feel `` really gypped.'' `` It's like ` Here are some yuppie kids from <ORGANIZATION> Wheaton </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION>. They just took off and we have no clues and we did n't know what to do.' And they look silly, so they might want to retaliate,'' <PERSON> Swanson </PERSON> said. `` Nobody cares, it's over with,'' said an officer in the <ORGANIZATION> Chicago </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>'s missing persons bureau who would not give his name. The couple said they intend to remain in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Diego </LOCATION> and pursue their education. <PERSON> Swanson </PERSON> said he will pursue his goal of going into the military reserve and wants to teach, while his wife said she plans to write books. The <ORGANIZATION> Swansons </ORGANIZATION>, who eloped in late March, said their love for each other grew while they toiled at jobs at separate delicatessens in the upscale beachfront community of <LOCATION> La </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jolla </LOCATION>, 10 miles north of downtown <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Diego </LOCATION>. The two have been in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Diego </LOCATION> since shortly after their disappearance. <PERSON> Swanson </PERSON> said Wednesday night that they came here because they `` did n't know anyone, and no one knew us. It has a climate that is conducive to living outdoors if we needed to bum it for a while.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880729-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-29-88 0021EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-WestfieldPresident 1stLd_Writethru a0820 07-29 0427</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Westfield President, 1st Ld _ Writethru, a0820,0432</SECOND>
<HEAD>College President Resigns Over Use Of Funds</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Subs 8th graf `The Union-News' to fully identify newspaper.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By TRUDY TYNAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WESTFIELD, Mass. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A state college president resigned Thursday after his use of trust funds for personal expenses came under scrutiny and criticism. `` I can no longer offer the leadership which the college requires and deserves, as a result of the intense publicity that has come about in the wake of charges of inaccuracy in the expenditures of general trust funds,'' <ORGANIZATION> Westfield </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> President <PERSON> Irving </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Buchen </PERSON> said in a letter. College trustees accepted the resignation unanimously after a nearly three-hour private session, which <PERSON> Buchen </PERSON> did not attend. Trustees Chairman <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> St. </PERSON> <PERSON> Clair </PERSON> said there was no settlement negotiated with <PERSON> Buchen </PERSON>, who had been paid $ 77,000 a year. `` Effective today, he is no longer a member of the faculty and will receive no benefits except for any accrued vacation time,'' <PERSON> St. </PERSON> <PERSON> Clair </PERSON> said. `` It's sufficient to say that in a light most favorable to the president, this could be viewed as careless attention to detail, poor record keeping and mistakes in judgment relative to the use of trust funds, which this board finds unacceptable,'' he said. <PERSON> St. </PERSON> <PERSON> Clair </PERSON> said the board would have no specific comment on the results of its investigation into <PERSON> Buchen </PERSON>'s expense accounts until after submitting reports on the findings to the <LOCATION> Hampden </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> district attorney and a legislative subcommittee investigating the use of state college trust funds. The <ORGANIZATION> Union-News </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Springfield </LOCATION> reported that <PERSON> Buchen </PERSON> billed college trust funds for $ 3,400 in expenses by submitting allegedly inaccurate or questionable vouchers for travel and dinners. He later paid back $ 1,259. <PERSON> St. </PERSON> <PERSON> Clair </PERSON> said the trustees will appoint an interim chief executive officer within a week. In the meantime, the board and the four college vice presidents will run the 3,000-student institution, he said. <PERSON> Buchen </PERSON>, 57, has been under fire for his use of college trust funds for personal expenses and waiving entrance requirements for his 16-year-old daughter. She attended the college and lived in a dormitory during the fall semester last year, although she had not graduated from high school. In January, <PERSON> Buchen </PERSON> apologized to trustees and withdrew her from classes. <PERSON> Buchan </PERSON> had succeeded <PERSON> Francis </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Pilecki </PERSON>, who left amid charges of sexual misconduct with male students and a furor over a $ 10,000 payment by trustees to one of the students. The 150-year-old college, founded by <PERSON> Horace </PERSON> <PERSON> Mann </PERSON>, was one of the first coeducational public teachers colleges in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880729-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-29-88 0028EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p AM-Clinton 2ndLd-Writethru a0416 07-29 0682</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Clinton, 2nd Ld - Writethru, a0416,0700</SECOND>
<HEAD>Governor Getting Mileage out of Publicity Over Bad Speech</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Inserts one graf after 7th graf `The governor' to add that
Clinton played sax with orchestra.</NOTE>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto LA11</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 As sand trickled through an hourglass on <PERSON> Johnny </PERSON> <PERSON> Carson </PERSON>'s desk, <LOCATION> Arkansas </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Clinton </PERSON> admitted to `` Tonight Show'' viewers that his comically savaged speech at the Democratic convention did not go as planned. `` My sole goal was achieved, however. I wanted so badly to make <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> look great, and I succeeded beyond my wildest dreams,'' said <PERSON> Clinton </PERSON>, to the laughter and applause of the show's studio audience. <PERSON> Clinton </PERSON> delivered the nominating speech for <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> at last week's Democratic National Convention in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>. Allotted 15 minutes, <PERSON> Clinton </PERSON> spoke for 32 minutes, ignoring flashing red lights and other attempts to cut him off. Finally, <PERSON> Clinton </PERSON>'s line `` I want to say, in closing'' drew applause. <PERSON> Carson </PERSON> told the audience in his monologue that <PERSON> Clinton </PERSON> was to be a guest, and added: `` Not to worry we have plenty of black coffee and extra cots in the lobby.'' <PERSON> Carson </PERSON> introduced <PERSON> Clinton </PERSON> with a satirical, long-winded speech of his own that included details ranging from the governor's educational background After <PERSON> Clinton </PERSON> sat on the couch, <PERSON> Carson </PERSON> said, `` My first question is, how are you?'' then turned over the hourglass. The governor said that while his speech was ridiculed, his constituents continued to support him. He said the speech was a `` good idea that did n't work.'' <PERSON> Clinton </PERSON> tried a different approach to win over <PERSON> Carson </PERSON>'s audience, playing a tenor saxophone with the show's orchestra <PERSON> Clinton </PERSON>'s appearance on the <PERSON> Carson </PERSON> show was his latest attempt to use humor to keep the disastrous speech from ruining his image as a rising star in the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>. The governor, who previously had a reputation as a good orator, began polishing his quips in Little Rock shortly after the convention speech was over: `` It was n't my finest hour,'' went one line. `` It was n't even my finest hour and one-half.'' During a speech this week to about 150 educators, <PERSON> Clinton </PERSON> had trouble with his microphone. Without skipping a beat, he said, `` Have the networks taken control of the mikes?'' On Wednesday at the Capitol, <LOCATION> Little </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rock </LOCATION> activist and restaurateur <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> `` Say'' <PERSON> McIntosh </PERSON> dished up food for anyone willing to dish out criticism for the <PERSON> Clinton </PERSON> bashers. Diners earned a free meal with lines such as: `` <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Clinton </PERSON> may be a blabbermouth, but he's the best thing to happen to <LOCATION> Arkansas </LOCATION>.'' `` I appreciate my governor even if he is boring.'' On Thursday, the <LOCATION> Arkansas </LOCATION> Democrat carried <PERSON> Clinton </PERSON> and <PERSON> Carson </PERSON> in its editorial page comic strip `` Spanks.'' The first frame shows <PERSON> Carson </PERSON> introducing <PERSON> Clinton </PERSON> with, `` Now here's a man who was a miniseries unto himself _ `` Gone with the windbag'' _ <ORGANIZATION> Arkansas </ORGANIZATION>' TALK of the town _ Governor <PERSON> Clinton </PERSON>.'' <PERSON> Clinton </PERSON> appears in the second frame in the image of comedian <PERSON> Rodney </PERSON> <PERSON> Dangerfield </PERSON> saying, `` Hey, <PERSON> Johnny </PERSON>, I tell yuh, I do n't get no respect.'' The last frame shows <PERSON> Clinton </PERSON> finishing his monologue, `` When I was speaking at the convention, one delegate accidentally hit another delegate with his sign. `` Oh excuse me!'' said the first delegate. `` I hit you with my sign.'' `` Hit me again,'' said the second delegate. `` I can still hear him.'' The <ORGANIZATION> Arkansas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Gazette </ORGANIZATION>, on its op-ed page, carried a 13-paragraph story by a retired newspaper editor who urged <PERSON> Clinton </PERSON> not to let TV people get under his skin. `` If they were all as smart as they sometimes pretend to be, surely some of them would be out there where the really big money is _ selling red neckties to the people who are on television,'' wrote <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Pruniski </PERSON>. <PERSON> Clinton </PERSON>, first elected governor in 1978 at the age of 32, met <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> while serving as president of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Governor </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> last year and eventually landed a major role in <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' campaign as an adviser and sometime stand-in <PERSON> Clinton </PERSON>, who at one time flirted with the idea of running for president, was among those talked of as a possible <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> running mate.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880729-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-29-88 0142EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lottery     07-29 0039</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lottery,0044</SECOND>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the winning weekly state lottery numbers picked Thursday:
</TEXT>
<HEAD>DELAWARE</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Play 4: 2-2-3-1.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>NEW JERSEY</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Pick 6 Lotto: 03; 05; 09; 20; 21; 23. Bonus 42830.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>PENNSYLVANIA</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Big 4 Lottery: 1-3-4-0.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880729-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-29-88 0146EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-LotteryRdp     07-29 0075</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lottery Rdp,0079</SECOND>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the winning weekly state lottery numbers picked so far this week:
</TEXT>
<HEAD>DELAWARE</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Play 4: 2-2-3-1.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>MASSACHUSETTS</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Wednesday Megabucks: 05; 10; 12; 24; 32; 34.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>NEW JERSEY</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Pick 6 Lotto: 03; 05; 09; 20; 21; 23. Bonus 42830.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>NEW YORK</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Wednesday Lotto 54 Game: 01; 12; 15; 26; 30; 39. Supplementary 46.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>PENNSYLVANIA</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Big 4 Lottery: 1-3-4-0.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>RHODE ISLAND</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Grand Lot Game: 1-4-5; 8-7-2-0; 3-2-1-2-2; 9-9-0-7-2-0.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880729-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-29-88 0146EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-PersonalDiplomacy Bjt   07-29 0831</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Personal Diplomacy, Bjt,850</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHINGTON WIRE: Jackson's Campaign To Free Hostages Doesn't Take
Off</HEAD>
<BYLINE>An AP News Analysis</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>By BARRY SCHWEID</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Diplomatic Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> has a winning record in helping Americans in trouble abroad, but he failed to get the support of the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> and the Democratic and Republican presidential candidates for a private bid to spring the nine <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> hostages in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>. So <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> is backing off, saying `` no meeting has been set and no meeting has been sought'' for him to negotiate with Iranian officials. The best chance for the hostages remains recognition by <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION> that their confinement by pro-Iranian factions in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> is a humanitarian issue and not a card to play in foreign policy maneuvers. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> was quoted as saying on Wednesday that he was trying to reach the Iranian foreign minister, <PERSON> Ali </PERSON> <PERSON> Akbar </PERSON> <PERSON> Velayati </PERSON>, through `` third parties'' including Arab diplomats. `` I have continuously expressed my interest in doing whatever I could to make a humanitarian appeal to gain release of the Americans held hostage,'' he told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION>. `` Humanitarian appeals always help. They penetrate deeper than political tradeoffs.'' <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> had made the freeing of the hostages a theme in his unsuccessful pursuit of the Democratic presidential nomination. Like a number of his proposals, it has a sweet and simple ring to it. In January 1984, <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> negotiated the release of Lt. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> O. </PERSON> <PERSON> Goodman </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> airman who had been shot down by Syrian forces in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>. It was widely seen as an attempt by President <PERSON> Hafez </PERSON> <PERSON> Assad </PERSON>, whose government is listed by the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> as a supporter of terrorism, to boost <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s political stock. In June 1984, possibly with similar intentions, <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> worked out arrangements with <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Havana </LOCATION> for the release of 48 American and Cuban political prisoners. Despite this winning record, <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> was publicly discouraged by the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> from trying his hand at personal diplomacy in behalf of the hostages in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>. `` Reverend <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s sentiments concerning the hostages are those shared by all Americans,'' spokesman <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Redman </PERSON> said Thursday. `` But as for efforts to release the hostages, we believe that official channels offer the best chance of success.'' <PERSON> Redman </PERSON> said he meant working through the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON>, deputy issues director in the presidential campaign of <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, also voiced qualified disapproval. `` We do not know any of the facts about this matter. As a matter of general policy, Gov. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> has said that he does not favor private citizens independently conducting foreign policy.'' <PERSON> Kitty </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, the Democratic candidate's wife, said her husband would not sanction any attempt by <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> to negotiate for the hostages' release. `` My husband feels very strongly that individuals ca n't negotiate, but governments negotiate with each other,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> said. `` And he would discourage <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> from going to <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> and trying to do that.'' Vice President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, who will receive the <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> nomination next month in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION>, was more critical of <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s personal diplomacy. `` It should n't happen,'' he said. `` We're talking about very sensitive foreign policy. The administration is empowered to conduct those negotiations at the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION>. We do n't need any loose cannons rolling around the deck.'' The remark stung. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> criticized <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> on Thursday for describing him as a `` loose cannon.'' But he also appeared to back away from the idea of interceding with the Iranians. `` No meeting has been set, and no meeting has been sought,'' <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>. `` We've simply talked through -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> -RRB- Secretary-General -LRB- <PERSON> Javier </PERSON> <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> -RRB- <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Cuellar </PERSON>, who did meet with the <LOCATION> Iranian </LOCATION> foreign minister.'' Traditionally, private citizens are discouraged from conducting <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> foreign policy. There is even a law against it. In the case of <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>, the situation is particularly delicate. The <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration was embarrassed when it tried to gain freedom for the hostages by secretly selling missiles to <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, which did not support the fiasco, is engaged in a careful campaign of messages and public statements designed to draw <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> into a direct discussion of the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> war, the hostages and terrorism. So far, there has been no `` authorized'' response from <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION>. `` They know where to get hold of us,'' <PERSON> Redman </PERSON> said. An offer on Tuesday by <PERSON> Hojatolislam </PERSON> <PERSON> Hashemi </PERSON> <PERSON> Rafsanjani </PERSON>, the speaker of <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'s parliament, to help obtain the release of the American captives if the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> returned frozen assets was turned down. `` No deals,'' <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> spokesman, promptly retorted. If <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> agrees to talk with the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> the hostages will be high on the agenda. But the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration does not want to appear to be making another deal with <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION>. In the meantime, it is seeking release of the hostages through a separate diplomatic track. When it comes to <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> and to the hostages, a badly burned <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration prefers proceeding with extreme caution.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 EDITOR'S NOTE: <PERSON> Barry </PERSON> <PERSON> Schweid </PERSON> covers diplomacy for <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> from the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880729-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-29-88 0154EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Soviet-Israel     07-29 0406</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Soviet-Israel,0419</SECOND>
<HEAD>Israeli Delegation Makes First Trip Since Relations Broken In 1967</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Soviet-Reforms, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ANDREW KATELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MOSCOW (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Six Israelis on the first diplomatic mission to <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> since the <ORGANIZATION> Kremlin </ORGANIZATION> broke diplomatic relations with the Jewish state in 1967 say they want to review procedures for Soviet Jews who want to leave. The Israeli diplomats planned to pray in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>'s central synagogue on the Jewish Sabbath, which begins this evening. Officially, the Israelis came Thursday to inspect the embassy building on <LOCATION> Bolshaya </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ordynka </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Street </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> has been paying the Soviets $ 100,000 a year to rent the building and diplomats from the <LOCATION> Netherlands </LOCATION> have been taking care of it. But the focus of the Israelis' visit is another role the Dutch have been performing for the Israeli government _ the processing of requests by Soviet Jews for Israeli visas. <PERSON> Meron </PERSON> <PERSON> Gordon </PERSON>, head of the delegation and a counselor at his country's embassy in <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION>, said his group might meet with prominent Jewish refuseniks who have been denied permission by Soviet authorities to leave the country. From January to June, 6,017 Soviet Jews emigrated, but only a small fraction went to <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>. Last year, the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> allowed 8,011 Jews to emigrate. Four of the diplomats were born in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Gordon </PERSON> left in 1957 at the age of 10. `` I think you have an expression _ butterflies in the stomach,'' he said at Sheremetyevo airport after the group arrived from <LOCATION> Amsterdam </LOCATION>. `` The ones I have in my stomach are very big.'' <PERSON> Gordon </PERSON> said he hopes the visit is `` the first step in developing the process of improving relations between the states of <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>.'' But Kremlin officials stress that the visit is not a precursor to the restoration of diplomatic relations, broken off after <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> seized lands from <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION> during the 1967 Middle East War. The Soviet visas the delegation received in the <LOCATION> Netherlands </LOCATION> entitle them to a two-month stay in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. The <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION> says it wo n't restore relations until <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> withdraws from the occupied territories and agrees to an international <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> peace conference. <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> insisted the <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION> allow its representatives to visit in exchange for permission for a Soviet consular delegation to visit the Jewish state. Eight Soviet diplomats have been in <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> since last July to survey Russian Orthodox Church property and meet with Soviet citizens living there.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880729-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-29-88 0157EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-DrugSmuggling Bjt   07-29 0849</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Drug Smuggling, Bjt,820</SECOND>
<HEAD>Witness: North Wanted to Give Anti-Drug Money to Contras Instead</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LARRY MARGASAK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> drug enforcement official says former <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> staffer <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> North </PERSON> suggested in 1984 that $ 1.5 million designated for a drug sting operation be diverted to the Nicaraguan Contras instead. <PERSON> Ron </PERSON> <PERSON> Caffrey </PERSON>, now in charge of the <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> office of the <ORGANIZATION> Drug </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Enforcement </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>, told a <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> panel Thursday the <ORGANIZATION> DEA </ORGANIZATION> rejected the idea. <PERSON> Caffrey </PERSON> said he told North the suggestion would have compromised the chief operative in one of the agency's most significant undercover operations. As it turned out, according to <PERSON> Caffrey </PERSON> and other <ORGANIZATION> DEA </ORGANIZATION> witnesses, the investigation was compromised anyway _ and closed prematurely _ several weeks later when details were leaked to the <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> Times. The hearing was the first in a series by the Judiciary subcommittee on crime, which is trying to learn whether <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration officials condoned drug smuggling and other criminal activities to further its Central American policy _ especially winning aid for the Contra rebels. Chairman <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Hughes </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.J. </LOCATION>, said the panel has `` discovered many, many instances of persons in or associated with ... elements of our government attempting to convert, to divert, and to subvert the criminal justice process.'' North, who has been indicted in the separate diversionof millions of dollars from the administration's <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> arms sales to the Contras, figured prominently in Thursday's testimony. The testimony focused on a 1984 sting operation, in which <ORGANIZATION> DEA </ORGANIZATION> used convicted drug pilot <PERSON> Barry </PERSON> <PERSON> Seal </PERSON> to make contact with the Colombian cocaine cartel _ then operating in <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> _ and a purported Nicaraguan government official, <PERSON> Federico </PERSON> <PERSON> Vaughn </PERSON>. <PERSON> Hughes </PERSON> later said the committee has doubts about whether <PERSON> Vaughn </PERSON> was in fact part of the government. Nonetheless, four DEA witnesses said <PERSON> North </PERSON> was interested in exposing an alleged involvement of the marxist Nicaraguan government in drug smuggling, so the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration could win an upcoming congressional vote on Contra aid. <PERSON> Caffrey </PERSON>, who was in charge of the <ORGANIZATION> DEA </ORGANIZATION> cocaine desk in 1984, said he briefed North on the undercover operation in late June or early July 1984, after <PERSON> Barry </PERSON> <PERSON> Seal </PERSON> had brought cocaine back from <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. Seal at the time was functioning as a <ORGANIZATION> DEA </ORGANIZATION> operative, hoping his cooperation would bring him a lenient sentence. <PERSON> Caffrey </PERSON> said he told North that the <ORGANIZATION> DEA </ORGANIZATION> planned to send Seal back to <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> to make a $ 1.5 million payment for the drugs he brought back, with the money to be split between the <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION> drug kingpins in <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> and Nicaraguan officials. `` Col. <PERSON> North </PERSON> asked why we could n't land the plane outside <LOCATION> Managua </LOCATION> and turn the money over to the Contras,'' <PERSON> Caffrey </PERSON> said. The <ORGANIZATION> DEA </ORGANIZATION> official said he responded that such a plan would jeopardize Seal, who had won the trust of the Colombian drug cartel and of <PERSON> Vaughn </PERSON>, identified by the <ORGANIZATION> DEA </ORGANIZATION> witnesses as an official of the Nicaraguan <ORGANIZATION> interior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> ministry </ORGANIZATION>. Most of the hearing centered on the news leak to the <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> Times, which published its story on the Seal operation July 17, 1984. Seal then became a government witness rather than an operative, but was machine-gunned to death in early 1986 after declining federal protection. <PERSON> Caffrey </PERSON> said when he briefed North on the operation before the story was leaked, the then-National <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> staffer `` asked when the operation could go public.'' He added that <PERSON> North </PERSON> `` did indicate to me there was a vote coming up on an appropriation bill to aid the Contras. I told him public disclosure would come from the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> attorney or the attorney general ... but we had a lot of goals left in the investigation'' and did not want to compromise it. <PERSON> Ernst </PERSON> <PERSON> Jacobsen </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> DEA </ORGANIZATION> undercover agent who directed Seal, said that following the leak, `` I heard from my superiors the leak came from an aide in the White House.'' Still an undercover agent, <PERSON> Jacobsen </PERSON> testified from behind a screen. A former top <ORGANIZATION> DEA </ORGANIZATION> official, ex-assistant administrator <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Monastero </PERSON>, testified, `` I thought the leak came from the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> because of the Contra vote that was coming up.'' <PERSON> Monastero </PERSON> told the subcommittee that the day the news story appeared, an irate <PERSON> North </PERSON> called him to deny that he was responsible for the leak. North, he said, accused the <ORGANIZATION> DEA </ORGANIZATION> of telling a reporter that <PERSON> North </PERSON> was the source of the information. `` He called to say he did not leak the information and the proof was the facts -LRB- in the story -RRB- were not accurate,'' <PERSON> Monastero </PERSON> said. `` My response was, ` That's the standard way to cover your tracks.' I did n't accept that.'' Pages from <PERSON> North </PERSON>'s diary, released by the subcommittee, show the former <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> staffer made frequent references to the drug operation in the weeks before the leak. And the diary shows he was aware of photographs from the investigation showing cocaine being loaded at a Nicaraguan airstrip. <PERSON> Jacobsen </PERSON> said that shortly before the leak, a <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> agent in <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> told him the spy agency planned to leak the material to the news media to suggest Sandinista involvement in drug smuggling.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880729-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-29-88 0056EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-DrugTesting     07-29 0352</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Drug Testing,0360</SECOND>
<HEAD>Judge Rejects Air Controllers' Suit</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SAN FRANCISCO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A federal judge has upheld a <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration program of drug testing for air traffic controllers, saying they `` have the lives of thousands of people in their hands.'' <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Vukasin </PERSON>'s ruling was the first in favor of a drug testing program by a judge in the federal court here, where labor groups have filed most of their suits attacking the administration's plans for urine testing of federal employees. An appeal of the ruling is expected. Another federal judge in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> has struck down a testing program for all federal prison workers, and the 9th U.S. <ORGANIZATION> Circuit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appeals </ORGANIZATION>, which covers <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> and eight other Western states, has ruled against mandatory testing of railroad crews after accidents and rule violations. The latter decision has been accepted for review by the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Vukasin </PERSON> announced his ruling July 19 but has not yet issued it in written form. A transcript of his comments was made available to reporters Thursday. The lawsuit, like those against other drug programs, contended random drug testing is unconstitutional because it is not based on individual suspicion of impairment from current drug use. The suit also argued that drug testing was unreliable and would be ineffective in promoting safety. The judge said he was unimpressed by statistics showing that less than 1 percent of air traffic controllers had shown signs of drug use in testing so far. `` We are talking here about air traffic controllers who have the lives of thousands of people in their hands,'' <PERSON> Vukasin </PERSON> said. In response to arguments that drug testing does n't show whether an employee is currently impaired or under the influence, <PERSON> Vukasin </PERSON> said, `` Unfortunately, the state of the art has not reached that level. But that is not an argument of why what at least is available to the -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aviation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> -RRB- should not be exercised and utilized.'' Apparently referring to the ruling on railroad workers, he said he `` may be failing to follow precedents, but if so, it is not done out of disrespect.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880729-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-29-88 0157EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FarmScene     07-29 0794</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Farm Scene,800</SECOND>
<HEAD>Wheat Program to Remain Unchanged</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DON KENDALL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Farm Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 No major adjustments because of this year's drought are in the works for the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>'s 1989 wheat acreage program Winter wheat producers soon will be planting next year's crop, and the no-change announcement Thursday by <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Lyng </PERSON> helps clear the way. All they need now is rain. As it stands now, wheat farmers will have to idle 10 percent of their base acreage in 1989 to qualify for federal price supports, the same as announced last spring. The 10 percent acreage reduction for next year was announced on May 25, under 1985 farm law which requires a determination for the following year's crop prior to June 1. That was before the drought became so widespread and severe. `` Even though the severe drought has reduced wheat production, especially that of spring wheat, the prospective supply-demand balance -LRB- for the coming year -RRB- does not call for a change in the previously announced wheat acreage reduction program in 1989,'' <PERSON> Lyng </PERSON>, who was out of town, said in a statement. A crop projection issued on July 12 put the 1988 wheat crop at 1.84 billion bushels, down from 2.12 billion bushels forecast in June. The 1987 harvest was about 2.1 billion bushels. But <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> wheat inventories have been large, despite a heavy export drain, and totaled around 1.27 billion bushels on June 1, the beginning of the 1988-89 wheat marketing year. The smaller harvest will result in a further reduction in the stockpile to around 666 million bushels by June 1, 1989, according to the projections. Earlier, the June 1, 1989, wheat carryover was forecast at 781 million bushels. Winter wheat, which comprises about three-fourths of the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> total, will be planted this fall for harvest next year. Spring wheat, including durum used for pasta, is produced farther north and bore the brunt of this summer's drought damage to the wheat crop. In a related development, officials served notice that wheat export subsidies are continuing, despite the drought and reduction in wheat supplies. <PERSON> Melvin </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Sims </PERSON>, general manager for the department's <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agricultural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>, said <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> has bought an additional 400,000 metric tons of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> wheat at subsidized prices. The sales, equal to about 14.7 million bushels, were handled by two companies: <ORGANIZATION> Cargill </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, 200,000 tons, and <ORGANIZATION> Ferruzzi </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> USA </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, 200,000 tons. <PERSON> Sims </PERSON> said the sales were part of an authorized 2 million tons of wheat announced April 5 under the Export Enhancement Program, or <ORGANIZATION> EEP </ORGANIZATION>, and some left over from an earlier authorization. Although no selling prices or other details were announced, recent wheat prices at farm points have averaged around $ 3.46 per bushel, indicating a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> farm value of about $ 50 million. A metric ton is about 2,205 pounds and is equal to 36.7 bushels of wheat. Prior to the new authorization on April 5, <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> had bought 4.9 million tons of wheat under <ORGANIZATION> EEP </ORGANIZATION> subsidy arrangements. <PERSON> Sims </PERSON> said <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> has 610,000 tons still available for use. Under the program, exporters can sell <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> commodities at reduced prices in order to meet foreign competition and then collect free government surpluses of grain or other commodities as bonuses, or subsidies. <PERSON> Sims </PERSON> said the bonuses due the four companies averaged $ 9.84 per ton of wheat, or about 27 cents a bushel. The bonuses will be paid in the form of surplus commodities owned by the department's <ORGANIZATION> Commodity </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Credit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp </ORGANIZATION>
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Drought may be gnawing at the bank accounts of many farmers, but the hot, dry weather is n't expected to cut back on their spending for many production items this year, according to an <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> report. `` The drought is expected to have little impact on 1988 expenditures for seed, fertilizer and pesticides because most of these ... were applied at or before planting,'' the report by the department's <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> said Thursday. `` Farm machinery expenditures are projected to increase again in 1988 but could be slowed by the drought.'' Spending on the fuel and electricity needed to run farms will be affected significantly by the drought, however. `` Energy expenditures for irrigation will be up, but likely will be more than offset by decreased outlays for harvesting and drying,'' the report said, a grim reminder that reduced yields _ or none at all _ mean it will cost less to run grain combines and dryers. Spending on farm machinery increased $ 1.2 billion to $ 5.8 billion in 1987, ending seven years of decline, the report said. Net cash income of farmers _ the difference between gross cash receipts and cash expenses _ rose to a record $ 56 billion in calendar 1987. Current <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> forecasts put 1988 net cash income at $ 53 billion to $ 59 billion.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880729-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-29-88 0222EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-StrandedWorkers     07-29 0394</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Stranded Workers,400</SECOND>
<HEAD>Congressman Seeks Relief For Migrant Workers Unable To Travel Home</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JENNIFER DIXON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> is putting the finishing touches on an emergency aid package for thousands of migrant workers stranded in the drought-parched <LOCATION> Midwest </LOCATION>, a department spokesman said. <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Zachariasiewicz </PERSON> said Thursday the agency `` has a plan of action'' but it wo n't be unveiled until Labor Secretary <PERSON> Ann </PERSON> <PERSON> McLaughlin </PERSON>, who is overseas, gives it her final approval. An announcement is likely next week. A source said the package would total $ 4 million to $ 5 million but `` the final distribution is just not set on paper yet.'' The package follows appeals by Rep. <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Bustamante </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Texas </LOCATION>, for assistance to migrant and seasonal workers who were unable to earn a living this summer because of the drought. In his letter to Mrs. <PERSON> McLaughlin </PERSON>, <PERSON> Bustamante </PERSON> said: `` Migrant workers pinned their hopes on a successful harvest and invested their personal savings to search for field work. Drought conditions have dashed their hopes for employment and for recouping their financial losses. `` Because the president's emergency relief program is directed solely at the farmer level, migrant workers and their families have no safety net to relieve their conditions. Measures taken to date have allowed migrant laborers to fall through cracks.'' <PERSON> Bustamante </PERSON>, a migrant worker for 23 years and the son and grandson of Mexican-Americans who followed the crops, said he still has relatives who travel from <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION> to harvest sugar beets. <PERSON> Bustamante </PERSON> estimates the stranded migrant and seasonal worker population at about 10,000, but said it is difficult to get a true figure because `` they do n't have a high profile. ... They're not a voting bloc like some others that make a lot of noise.'' `` Exhausted of their personal financial resources, they have no money for temporary shelter and food,'' he wrote. `` Many would like to return home, but they can not. They are broke, indebted, stranded and dependent on the kindness and charity of local efforts.'' He said he is seeking funds to provide shelter, food and job-search assistance to migrants who want to stay in the <LOCATION> Midwest </LOCATION> to help farmers salvage crops, and to give others who want to return home money for travel. <PERSON> Bustamante </PERSON> also sent his appeal to President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Lyng </PERSON> and <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Clements </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880729-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-29-88 0223EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-GreenhouseEffect     07-29 0675</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Greenhouse Effect,680</SECOND>
<HEAD>Senators Prepare Legislation On Greenhouse Effect</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID GOELLER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Senators are using the closing weeks of the 100th <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to put the issue of global warming from the `` greenhouse effect'' at the top of their environmental agenda for next year. They got the ball rolling this week with the introduction of legislation prompted by a series of hearings over the last two years at which scientists warned that the greenhouse effect threatens the planet with higher temperatures, climate changes and rising oceans in the next century. Sixteen senators, including <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnston </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-La </LOCATION>., unveiled a comprehensive plan on Thursday that calls for a variety of steps, from developing safer nuclear power to slowing the destruction of forests in the Third World A day earlier, a group headed by <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Stafford </PERSON>, R-Vt., submitted a package to end <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> use of chlorofluorocarbons, the chemicals that contribute to global warming and destroy the Earth's vital ozone <PERSON> Johnston </PERSON>, who has been identified more with energy development and production than environmental protection, said he would hold a series of hearings in coming weeks to set the stage for 1989. Next year, he said at a news conference, `` we'll have to begin the serious process of legislating. We'll act as fast as the public's willing to support us.'' <PERSON> Johnston </PERSON> is a cosponsor of most elements in a package developed by Sen. <PERSON> Tim </PERSON> <PERSON> Wirth </PERSON>, D-Colo., that represents the broadest <LOCATION> Capitol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION> response yet to the greenhouse warnings `` The greenhouse effect is the most significant economic, political, environmental and human problem facing the 21st Century,'' <PERSON> Wirth </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Johnston </PERSON>, who recently held a hearing on the greenhouse effect, said: `` The evidence of global warming is virtually undeniable. It is so much more comprehensive, dangerous and life-changing than anything we've ever seen.'' Aides said <PERSON> Johnston </PERSON> has become convinced that global action is necessary to combat the production of carbon and other gases that scientists say trap heat in the atmosphere. <PERSON> Johnston </PERSON> stopped short of endorsing a key element of <PERSON> Wirth </PERSON>'s proposal: reducing carbon monoxide emissions by requiring new car fleets to average 55 miles per gallon by 2010, a doubling of the 1985 fuel efficiency standard The <PERSON> Wirth </PERSON> package would force this country to reduce carbon dioxide emissions by 20 percent by 2000. Scientists estimate that carbon dioxide, coming mostly from fossil fuel combustion, produces about half the world's greenhouse gases. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> is said to be responsible for 20 percent of the world's carbon dioxide emissions. The proposal would require administration officials to draft a national energy plan emphasizing the least expensive ways to reduce fossil fuel use and increase use of renewables such as solar energy. The package would authorize about $ 1 billion through 1992 for research and development of non-fossil energy sources and a new generation of safer and cheaper nuclear reactors. It also calls for greater reliance on cleaner-burning natural gas for heating and transportation. On the international front, the secretary of state would be urged to hold a meeting aimed at getting other nations to commit to a 50 percent cut in greenhouse gas production by 2015. The legislation also would authorize this country to spend more than $ 1.5 billion in the early 1990s to provide birth control information in an effort to slow the demand for fossil fuels in burgeoning nations. It also calls for the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> to work through international lending and development agencies to slow the destruction of forests, which consume carbon dioxide when alive but which emit huge amounts when they are cut down. <PERSON> Johnston </PERSON> said that to slow down polluting development in the Third World, `` we're going to have to pay for their non-development in some way, and it's going to be expensive.'' Joining as cosponsors were <PERSON> Max </PERSON> <PERSON> Baucus </PERSON>, D-Mont.; <PERSON> Jeff </PERSON> <PERSON> Bingaman </PERSON>, D-N.M.; <PERSON> Dale </PERSON> <PERSON> Bumpers </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Ark </LOCATION>.; <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Chafee </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-R.I. </LOCATION>; <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Danforth </PERSON>, R-Mo.; Wyche <PERSON> Fowler </PERSON>, D-Ga.; <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Gore </PERSON>, D-Tenn.; <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Heinz </PERSON>, R-Pa.; <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Inouye </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Hawaii </LOCATION>; <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Melcher </PERSON>; <PERSON> Claiborne </PERSON> <PERSON> Pell </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-R.I. </LOCATION>; <PERSON> Spark </PERSON> <PERSON> Matsunaga </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Hawaii </LOCATION>; <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> <PERSON> Sanford </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.C. </LOCATION>; and <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Stafford </PERSON>, R-Vt.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880729-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-29-88 0223EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-BlackPatriots     07-29 0231</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Black Patriots,230</SECOND>
<HEAD>Sites Approved For Black Patriots, Military Women Memorials</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Advocates of a proposed memorial to honor black Revolutionary War soldiers are concentrating on a design now that two federal commissions have approved its location on the National Mall. The <ORGANIZATION> Fine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Arts </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Capital </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Planning </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> on Thursday approved plans to build the memorial in Constitution Gardens, a grasy area close to the reflecting pool between the Lincoln Memorial and <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> Monument. The two panels also voted, at separate meetings, to approve a plan to build a memorial honoring women in military service at the entrance of the Arlington Cemetery. Advocates for both projects next must develop designs and win another round of approvals from the two panels and the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Capital </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Memorial </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION>, which approved the siting plans last month. <PERSON> Marshall </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Purnell </PERSON>, executive vice president of <ORGANIZATION> Devrouax </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> Purnell </PERSON>, one of three architectural firms involved with the project, said designers will meet with memorial supporters `` to get a feel for what they think it should look like.'' The designers will then draft plans to present to the memorial's foundation by early next year If approved, the design will be presented to the three agencies for their approval. <PERSON> Purnell </PERSON> estimated the project would be completed in about 2 -LCB- years. Private donations are expected to pay for the project, estimated at $ 4 million.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880729-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-29-88 0225EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-TexasTsunami     07-29 0603</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Texas Tsunami,620</SECOND>
<HEAD>Comet May Have Triggered Ancient Wave Which Smashed Texas</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PAUL RECER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Science Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A 66-million-year-old rock deposit in a <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> creek bed shows that the area was once smashed by a massive ocean wave, perhaps triggered by a large comet or asteroid that hit the <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ocean </LOCATION>, according to a study published today in the journal Science. <PERSON> Thor </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Hansen </PERSON>, a geologist at <ORGANIZATION> Western </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, said he and another researcher found evidence that a wave, perhaps as tall as 300 feet, scoured the floor of a primitive <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, picked up sand and shark teeth, then dumped the material in what now is in a bed of a tributary to the <LOCATION> Brazos </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>. `` It -LRB- the wave -RRB- was so big, we think the circumstantial evidence is very strong that it was caused by a bolide -LRB- meteorite -RRB- impact,'' said <PERSON> Hansen </PERSON>. The deposit, he said, was found in what is called the Cretaceous-Tertiary boundary. This is the name given a geologic formation that other researchers have identified as having been created during a time that meteorites were showering Earth, about 66 million years ago. <PERSON> Hansen </PERSON> said the formation he found in the <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> creek bed is rich in iridium, an element that is common in meteorites but rare on <LOCATION> Earth </LOCATION>. It is considered a universal mark of the Cretaceous-Tertiary -LRB- called K-T -RRB- boundary. At the time that the wave was created, <PERSON> Hansen </PERSON> said <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> and the whole Gulf coast area looked far different than now. The waters of the ocean were much higher and the coast was much farther inland. <PERSON> Hansen </PERSON> said the massive wave churned against the ocean floor, moving huge clay boulders, picking up sand, limestone and shark teeth, and leaving a path of great erosion. When the waters settled down, the debris was deposited again on the ocean floor, leaving a mark of the violence that occurred. Over many centuries, the sea water receded, dry land emerged and now the deposit left by the wave is seen in the wall of a creek bed in <LOCATION> Falls </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>. `` The thing that is remarkable about this deposit is that it was produced far offshore on a quiet water shelf,'' said <PERSON> Hansen </PERSON>. `` Above and below is just mud, quiet water sedimentation. There's no evidence of any disturbance at all Yet, in the middle of that, there is this quite large unit.'' Based on the force required to move the material left in the deposit, <PERSON> Hansen </PERSON> said he calculated that the wave had to be 150 to 300 feet high. Circumstantial evidence, he said, leads to the theory that a meteorite striking the ocean caused the wave because there is no geologic evidence suggesting that a volcano or an earthquake could have triggered the wave. `` There was no volcanic activity nearby at the time,'' he said. `` Also, we find no volcanic ash in the formation.'' The only other thing that could have created such a large wave of this type, said <PERSON> Hansen </PERSON>, is a meteorite about six miles in diameter that probably struck the west central <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ocean </LOCATION>. Other researchers, he said, have found K-T formations in <LOCATION> Arkansas </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Haiti </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> and offshore from <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>. All of these, said <PERSON> Hansen </PERSON>, help support the idea that a boulder from space swamped <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> with a splash some 66 million years ago. Co-investigators with <PERSON> Hansen </PERSON> in the study were <PERSON> Joanne </PERSON> <PERSON> Bourgeois </PERSON> and <PERSON> Patricia </PERSON> <PERSON> Wiberg </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION>, and <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kauffman </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Colorado </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Boulder </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Colo. </LOCATION>. Science is the journal of the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> for the Advancement of Science
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880729-0025 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-29-88 0226EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-AIDSAttack     07-29 0471</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AIDS Attack,480</SECOND>
<HEAD>Researchers Find AIDS Disrupts Key Immune Response In Cell</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PAUL RECER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Science Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Researchers have long known that the AIDS virus can kill the disease-fighting T-cells in the body, but research published today shows that the virus can also destroy the immune system simply by disrupting the inner mechanism of these cells. In a study published today in Science, a group of researchers said they have found that the AIDS virus is able to block a function of a key molecule in T-cells and prevent the immune response from taking place. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Hartzman </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Naval </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Bethesda </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Md. </LOCATION>, said he and his co-researchers made the finding by comparing the response of T-cells that were infected with the AIDS virus with T-cells that were uninfected. Normally, T-cells respond to an antigen by binding to it and then starting a process that leads to the production of antibodies. Part of this process is a signal by a molecule called the CD3 receptor which is on the outside of the T-cell. This signal crosses the cell wall and triggers production of calcium within the cell. This calcium then leads to the next step in producing an antibody against the disease. <PERSON> Hartzman </PERSON> said the study showed that in T-cells infected with HIV-1, which is an AIDS virus, the ability of the CD3 receptor to release calcium is blocked or retarded. `` This is a mechanism that can disrupt the immune response,'' said <PERSON> Hartzman </PERSON>. `` We knew that HIV can kill T-cells. Now this shows that it can also reduce the qualitative response of those cells.'' The study was conducted using T-cells from healthy donors. Part of the cells were infected with HIV and the rest were not. The cells were cultured for 60 days and then exposed to a antibody that would mimic the early response to an antigen. In the uninfected cells, the CD3 took the normal next step by releasing calcium into the interior of the cell. The T-cells infected with HIV, however, did not release the calcium, which stopped the immune response. <PERSON> Marvin </PERSON> <PERSON> Reitz </PERSON>, a researcher in an AIDS laboratory at the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cancer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION>, said the research `` would answer part of the question of how the immune response is messed up by the virus in a way that does n't kill the cell.'' He said it is not clear, however, if the experiment involved T-cells that were actively expressing the HIV virus. Such cells, said <PERSON> Reitz </PERSON>, are usually killed within a short time anyway. Co-researchers with <PERSON> Hartzman </PERSON> in the study were <PERSON> Carl </PERSON> H. June of the <ORGANIZATION> Naval </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Gerald </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Linette </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> Georgetown </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, and <PERSON> Jeffrey </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Ledbetter </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Oncogen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION>. Science is the journal of the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> for the Advancement of Science.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880729-0026 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-29-88 0107EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-IrishStowaway 2ndLd-Writethru a0803 07-29 0463</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Irish Stowaway, 2nd Ld - Writethru, a0803,0470</SECOND>
<HEAD>Irish Stowaway Tells Judge She Yearns for Home</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Subs 3rd graf to UPDATE with departure for Ireland. Picks up
4th graf pvs `The girl...'</NOTE>
<HEAD>LaserPhotos RA1, NY53</HEAD>
<DATELINE>RALEIGH, N.C. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An Irish girl who crossed the <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> as a stowaway on a <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> destroyer told a judge Thursday she yearns for her homeland, and her mother said the family might seek legal action against the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government. `` I just want to go home,'' 16-year-old <PERSON> Suzanne </PERSON> <PERSON> Twomey </PERSON> of <PERSON> Cork </PERSON> told <ORGANIZATION> Wake </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> Judge <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> Morelock </PERSON>. The judge put her in custody of two <ORGANIZATION> Naval </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Investigative </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> agents who were escorting her. Miss <PERSON> Twomey </PERSON> was put on a flight to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> John </LOCATION> <LOCATION> F. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kennedy </LOCATION> <LOCATION> International </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION>, and left from there at 10:45 p.m. on a flight to <PERSON> Shannon </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION>. The girl apparently slipped aboard the USS Conyngham while it was on a courtesy call in <LOCATION> Cork </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Harbor </LOCATION>. She was discovered aboard the guided missile destroyer Saturday when it returned to its <LOCATION> Norfolk </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, base. Three officers searched the ship after hearing a girl was aboard and found her in a 2 -LCB- - foot-wide, 15-foot-long, 3-foot-high compartment above a refrigeration unit Five sailors accused of helping the girl were being held at the <LOCATION> Norfolk </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Naval </LOCATION> base, authorities said. If charged and convicted, they face a maximum five years in prison and a fine of $ 2,000 for aiding an illegal entry into the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. Meanwhile, Miss <PERSON> Twomey </PERSON>'s parents said they are considering suing the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government. `` There is a lot more to this than meets the eye,'' said <PERSON> Christine </PERSON> <PERSON> Twomey </PERSON>. Mrs. <PERSON> Twomey </PERSON> said <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials had telephoned her in <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION> to apologize. They said her daughter could not have boarded the ship undetected without help from crew members, Mrs. <PERSON> Twomey </PERSON> said. In court Thursday, Miss <PERSON> Twomey </PERSON> listened intently as Assistant District Attorney <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Franklin </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> told the judge she was a runaway and would be considered an undisciplined child under the American court system. Assistant <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Attorney <PERSON> Rocco </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Grasse </PERSON> said no charges would be filed against Miss <PERSON> Twomey </PERSON>. After the hearing, deGrasse approached Miss <PERSON> Twomey </PERSON> and gave her a stern lecture. He said her status as a juvenile had protected her, but that she had committed a serious offense. A <ORGANIZATION> Delta </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> flight carrying the girl to <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> for a connecting flight home was diverted to <LOCATION> Raleigh </LOCATION> on Tuesday when she became sick. She was released Wednesday night from <ORGANIZATION> Rex </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION>, said <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> West </PERSON>, a nursing supervisor who did not know what the girl was treated for. <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Berry </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Delta </ORGANIZATION> spokesman in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>, said the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> had asked Wednesday night about booking the girl on another <ORGANIZATION> Delta </ORGANIZATION> flight to <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION>, but the airline refused her passage because of possible medical problems.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880729-0027 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-29-88 0226EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-US-Afghanistan     07-29 0426</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-US-Afghanistan,440</SECOND>
<HEAD>U.S. Pressing Soviets for Afghan Mine Maps</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RUTH SINAI</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
