<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880217-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-17-88 0240EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a BC-Awards     02-17 0514</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Awards,0538</SECOND>
<HEAD>National Board of Review Gives 1987 Film Awards</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: No PMs Planned</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By MARY CAMPBELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 `` Empire of the Sun'' was named best movie and its director, <PERSON> Steven </PERSON> <PERSON> Spielberg </PERSON>, and young star, <PERSON> Christian </PERSON> <PERSON> Bale </PERSON>, also received honors as the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Review </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Motion </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pictures </ORGANIZATION> presented its 1987 awards Tuesday night. A lifetime achievement award was given to <PERSON> Lillian </PERSON> <PERSON> Gish </PERSON>, who also was named best actress for her 105th film, `` The Whales of August'' _ an award shared with <PERSON> Holly </PERSON> <PERSON> Hunter </PERSON> for `` Broadcast News.'' <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON> was named best actor for his performance in `` Wall Street.'' The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> was founded in 1909 to oppose censorship and reward excellence on the screen. Its <PERSON> D.W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Griffith </PERSON> Awards have been given annually since 1917. Miss <PERSON> Gish </PERSON>'s first film, `` An Unseen Enemy,'' was directed by <PERSON> Griffith </PERSON> in 1912. Bale, 13, was given a special award, the first the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> has given to a child actor. Neither Miss Hunter nor Miss <PERSON> Gish </PERSON>, recuperating from a fall in January, was present. Miss <PERSON> Gish </PERSON>'s best friend, <PERSON> Helen </PERSON> <PERSON> Hayes </PERSON>, said, `` She was bullied into staying home. I'm sure that doctor has been dismissed.'' <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON>, accepting the best actor award from <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON> <PERSON> Close </PERSON>, his costar in `` Fatal Attraction,'' called his part in `` Wall Street'' `` the best I've ever had.'' He thanked <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> <PERSON> Stone </PERSON> and <PERSON> Stanley </PERSON> <PERSON> Wise </PERSON>, who wrote it. <PERSON> Spielberg </PERSON> said `` Empire of the Sun'' was `` the hardest movie any of us involved have ever made.'' He called <PERSON> Christian </PERSON> <PERSON> Bale </PERSON>, who did not attend, `` a regular kid _ I think a lot of that came out in the movie.'' `` If <PERSON> Christian </PERSON> <PERSON> Bale </PERSON> had n't existed, we had no second choice. He carried this movie really all by himself,'' <PERSON> Spielberg </PERSON> said. Host <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Ferrer </PERSON> called `` Empire of the Sun'' `` a powerful and richly human anti-war film.'' <PERSON> Spielberg </PERSON> said that if <PERSON> Griffith </PERSON> had made the movie, it would have cost `` about $ 175,000, in the early part of this century.'' <PERSON> Olympia </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, cousin of the <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> governor, was named best supporing actress for her role as <PERSON> Cher </PERSON>'s mother in `` Moonstruck.'' <PERSON> Sean </PERSON> <PERSON> Connery </PERSON>, who was n't present, was named best supporting actor for `` The Untouchables,'' in which he played a tough Irish cop. The two-part `` Jean de Florette'' - `` Manon of the Spring'' from <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> was named best foreign film. The award for best documentary went to `` Chuck Berry: Hail! Hail! Rock' n' Roll'' begins with <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Lennon </PERSON> saying, `` If you tried to give rock' n' roll another name, you might call it <PERSON> Chuck </PERSON> <PERSON> Berry </PERSON>.'' <PERSON> Lennon </PERSON>'s widow, <PERSON> Yoko </PERSON> <PERSON> Ono </PERSON>, presented the award to performer-songwriter <PERSON> Berry </PERSON>. <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Remick </PERSON> received a special television award. <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Rowley </PERSON>, who will choose vintage movies for the Biograph Theater, which will open Friday near <LOCATION> Carnegie </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hall </LOCATION>, also received a special award. Ceremonies were held at the Library for the Performing Arts in Lincoln Center. Recipients of the awards are known ahead of time. One of the presenters, actress <PERSON> Judith </PERSON> <PERSON> Ivey </PERSON>, drew applause when she said, `` We're not sitting here waiting for an envelope to be opened. Some people think that's entertaining. I think it's sick.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880217-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-17-88 0223EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-TradingIndictments     02-17 0310</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Trading Indictments,0320</SECOND>
<HEAD>Former Broker Pleads Guilty To Illegal Trading Scheme</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CHICAGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A former broker pleaded guilty Tuesday to charges that he defrauded his employer of more than $ 1 million in a scheme involving illegal trading at the <ORGANIZATION> Chicago </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mercantile </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Exchange </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Jeffrey </PERSON> <PERSON> Donnelly </PERSON>, 28, of <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>, a former trader in <ORGANIZATION> Standard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; Poor's 500 stock index-futures contracts, pleaded guilty to two counts of commodities fraud, said Assistant <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Attorney <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> <PERSON> Pearl </PERSON>. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Alesia </PERSON> set sentencing for April 7, <PERSON> Pearl </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Donnelly </PERSON>, a former employee of <ORGANIZATION> CRT </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, faces a maximum penalty of 10 years in prison and a $ 1 million fine. Under a plea agreement, <PERSON> Pearl </PERSON> said, the government reserves the right to grant <PERSON> Donnelly </PERSON> immunity from prosecution in return for his testimony. <PERSON> Donnelly </PERSON> was expelled by the <ORGANIZATION> Merc </ORGANIZATION> last March and fined $ 100,000 on charges of fraudulent trading. The charges to which he pleaded guilty were brought last week. The plea agreement states that he defrauded <ORGANIZATION> CRT </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> by diverting money from profitable S & amp; P futures trades to four accounts between January 1984 and July 1986. Authorities charged that <PERSON> Donnelly </PERSON> split the profits with four other people after diverting the money into their accounts. <PERSON> Donnelly </PERSON>'s share, 35 percent of the profits, amounted to $ 350,000, prosecutors said. <PERSON> Pearl </PERSON> said <PERSON> Donnelly </PERSON> already has paid back some of the money. `` He and the others have made substantial restitution,'' the attorney said. Pearl would not say whether the other four would be charged. But he said the investigation is continuing. <PERSON> Donnelly </PERSON> was among 10 men charged Feb. 9 with fraudulent trading in commodity futures. The men were accused in four separate schemes _ one of which, authorities said, involved the use of wigs, makeup and phony credentials to gain access to trading pits. But <PERSON> Donnelly </PERSON> was involved only in the scheme to which he pleaded guilty Tuesday.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880217-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-17-88 0312EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r e PM-APArts:Bacon-McGovern     02-17 0682</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AP Arts: Bacon-McGovern,0701</SECOND>
<HEAD>`Baby' Actors Enjoy Virtuous Roles</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY10 of Feb. 13</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CLAUDIA COATES</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Kevin </PERSON> <PERSON> Bacon </PERSON> and <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> McGovern </PERSON> did n't mind playing two squares in the comedy hymn to marital fidelity, `` She's Having a Baby. In fact, they liked the movie's emphasis on old-style morals. `` Old-fashioned is new-fashioned, let's face it,'' <PERSON> Bacon </PERSON> said. Director-writer <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Hughes </PERSON> `` is basically an old-values type of guy in all his movies,'' <PERSON> McGovern </PERSON> said. And his story of a young couple, <PERSON> Jake </PERSON> and <PERSON> Kristy </PERSON> <PERSON> Briggs </PERSON>, is `` a tribute to suburbia'' and to the virtue of commitment. Though the actors are young _ Bacon is 29, <PERSON> McGovern </PERSON> is 26 _ both are examples of another old-fashioned virtue: hard work. They recently talked about just how hard it was to bring out `` Baby.'' One scene _ the <PERSON> Briggs </PERSON>' wedding _ was shot over 26 consecutive hours. It was filmed in the <ORGANIZATION> Winnetka </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Congregational </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION>, which was available for only a limited time. Two versions of the scene were filmed: a straight-forward account of the wedding, and <PERSON> Jake </PERSON>'s hallucination about what his wedding vows really mean. `` <PERSON> Wilt </PERSON> thou listen to endless conversations about children's clothes and decorator checkbooks? the minister asks in the fantasy version. The marathon session demanded a lot of Bacon. `` I actually fell asleep on my feet,'' he said. <PERSON> Bacon </PERSON>, who previously appeared in `` Diner'' and `` Footloose,'' is on the screen in almost every frame of the film. In one scene, <PERSON> Jake </PERSON> sits outside the church with his best man, who tries to tempt him not to get married. The struggle, <PERSON> Bacon </PERSON> says, was to win the audience's sympathy, despite the fact that his character is on the brink of jilting the beautiful <PERSON> Kristy </PERSON>. `` I really wanted him to seem like a little boy in a monkey suit, and that was difficult,'' <PERSON> Bacon </PERSON> said. <PERSON> McGovern </PERSON>'s travails were more subtle. Her character, <PERSON> Kristy </PERSON>, appears bland. But she's not, said the actress. <PERSON> Kristy </PERSON> is `` very strong, although she does n't necessarily appear on the surface to be strong,'' said <PERSON> McGovern </PERSON>, who first drew attention in the industry with her portrayal of <PERSON> Timothy </PERSON> <PERSON> Hutton </PERSON>'s girlfriend in 1980 in the Academy Award-winning `` Ordinary People. The next year, she had a supporting actress <PERSON> Oscar </PERSON> nomination for her role in `` Ragtime.'' `` She's a person you would n't ever think twice about,'' <PERSON> McGovern </PERSON> said. But before the end of the movie, `` The door opens on her soul and you see how much there is she has to offer.'' Both actors lauded <PERSON> Hughes </PERSON>' direction. `` As strong and independent as I come off on the set, I need a director who will say, ` OK, that's good, you got it,''' <PERSON> Bacon </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Hughes </PERSON> did that for him. <PERSON> McGovern </PERSON> agreed. `` I always felt supported and I always knew that he would guide me.'' By the end of the filming, <PERSON> Hughes </PERSON> trusted <PERSON> Bacon </PERSON> to improvise. One touching and funny result has <PERSON> Jake </PERSON> trying natural childbirth methods _ massaging his abdomen and panting _ while <PERSON> Kristy </PERSON> gives birth in another room. `` By that point I'd been playing this character so many times and in so many different situations that I really felt that I knew him and <PERSON> John </PERSON> knew him. ... And he just kind of said, ` We'll turn the camera on and you just hang out in the room and do what you would do.'' The tension <PERSON> Bacon </PERSON> has felt in front of the camera in other movies did n't apply in this one, he said. `` <PERSON> John </PERSON> sort of blows all that tension right out of the water,'' by letting the camera roll during retakes instead of shouting, `` Action!'' or `` Cut!'' a lot. The atmosphere during filming was relaxed enough for <PERSON> Bacon </PERSON> to bring along his dog, <PERSON> Jane </PERSON>, whom he calls `` a <LOCATION> Labrador </LOCATION> deceiver'' _ a mutt that's part Lab. <PERSON> Bacon </PERSON> and <PERSON> McGovern </PERSON> are both accomplished on the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> stage, and are used to feeding on the energy of an audience. But in a way, <PERSON> McGovern </PERSON> said, the director filled that function. `` When he was looking at me he would see <PERSON> Kristy </PERSON>, he would n't see <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON>,'' she said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880217-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-17-88 0322EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Trantino     02-17 0760</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Trantino,0782</SECOND>
<HEAD>After 25 Years, Cop-Killer Case Still Stirs Emotions</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By JOEL SIEGEL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LODI, N.J. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The letters, phone calls and telegrams come from across the nation, but the message to police and state <ORGANIZATION> Parole </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> members is almost always the same: <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Trantino </PERSON> must not go free. Nearly 25 years after <PERSON> Trantino </PERSON> and an accomplice shot Sgt. <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Voto </PERSON> and officer <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Tedesco </PERSON> to death at point-blank range in a nightclub here, emotions still run high. From an accountant in nearby <LOCATION> Teaneck </LOCATION>: `` The courts and the parole system should start to recognize the danger which these criminals present to society. If he killed in cold blood two police officers who were in uniform, how can those of us who are citizens in plain clothes be safe?'' From a <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION> woman: `` I do n't want to hear that he is a model prisoner who is now a writer, a painter. ... They are forgetting he has one other glaring accomplishment, and that is that he committed a cold-blooded murder of two human beings.'' The prospect of release has sparked a petition drive, legislative proposals, a letter-writing campaign and a candlelight rally by more than 1,500 people to convince the <ORGANIZATION> Parole </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> that <PERSON> Trantino </PERSON> must remain behind bars. The case has also revived debate over an old question: When has a murderer finally paid his debt to society? <ORGANIZATION> Paramus </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION> Chief <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Delaney </PERSON>, a leader of the campaign against parole, said many feel `` the people who commit the violent acts are n't getting punishment that fits the crime.'' `` They want to see pure, unadulterated punishment,'' he added. `` Do n't say ` life in prison' for someone and then let him out 15, 20 or 25 years later.'' On Aug. 26, 1963, <PERSON> Trantino </PERSON> and <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Falco </PERSON> were at the Angel Lounge celebrating a robbery. When <PERSON> Voto </PERSON> and <PERSON> Tedesco </PERSON> arrived to investigate a disturbance, <PERSON> Trantino </PERSON> and <PERSON> Falco </PERSON> surprised them, partially stripped them and shot them. <PERSON> Falco </PERSON> was killed the next day by police trying to capture him. <PERSON> Trantino </PERSON> was caught, convicted and sentenced to die in the electric chair. The sentence was commuted to life when <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION>'s death penalty was ruled unconstitutional in 1972. In 1980, the full <ORGANIZATION> Parole </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> voted to release <PERSON> Trantino </PERSON>, provided that he make restitution to the families of his victims. The decision sparked an outcry, and in 1982 the board voted to keep <PERSON> Trantino </PERSON> locked up for 10 more years, a term that was cut almost in half through credits for good behavior and work. A two-member panel decided last month that he should be paroled March 15, but the full board has decided to review the decision. A Parole Board official, citing policy, declined to explain the decision. However, under state law <PERSON> Trantino </PERSON> can be paroled only if he shows `` no substantial likelihood of future criminal activity'' and proves he has `` made progression in rehabilitating himself.'' From 1978 to 1982 <PERSON> Trantino </PERSON> was granted regular furloughs from prison, which ended after the controversy over his parole. In 1980, he married the community college English professor who had edited his prison writings into a book. <PERSON> Trantino </PERSON>, 50, is now at the medium-security Riverfront State Prison in <LOCATION> Camden </LOCATION>, and declined an interview request. In a 1986 interview he said he had no recollection of the murders and believed his freedom was long overdue. He works in the prison canteen storeroom and participates in a program that tries to convince juvenile delinquents, in a `` low key'' way, to change their ways, said <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corrections </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Stabile </PERSON>. Victims' rights organizations, <PERSON> Delaney </PERSON> and <PERSON> Voto </PERSON>'s brother <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON>, now police chief in this small blue-collar community, have been at the forefront of efforts to block parole. Recently, <PERSON> Delaney </PERSON> and <PERSON> Voto </PERSON> appeared on <PERSON> Morton </PERSON> <PERSON> Downey </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>'s television talk show The next day about 1,000 people called the board from across the country to oppose <PERSON> Trantino </PERSON>'s release. `` He's a classic con artist,'' <PERSON> Delaney </PERSON> said. `` I have dealt with people in my many years as a cop and there's no question in my mind that if they release him he will kill again.'' The case has struck a chord among family members of crime victims. `` Most of the letters that come in to me thank me for picking up the fight against coddling prisoners. There's too much concern for these people,'' <PERSON> Voto </PERSON> said. `` Why should a man walk out when he was sentenced to death? There is rehabilitation, and I am for it, but not in these types of cases ... not an outright killer, a cold-blooded killer.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880217-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-17-88 0018EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p AM-NH-Robertson     02-17 0418</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-NH-Robertson,410</SECOND>
<HEAD>Finishing Last, Robertson Says He'll Shine in the South</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MICHAEL MOKRZYCKI</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CONCORD, N.H. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Former television evangelist <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> took in stride his bottom-of-the-pile finish in the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION> primary Tuesday, saying he was ready to shine in the <LOCATION> South </LOCATION>, `` in my backyard.'' With returns nearly complete in the Republican primary, <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> was last among the five contenders. `` We played in <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>'s backyard -LRB- in <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> -RRB- and I beat <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> there,'' <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> said. `` We played in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION>, which according to <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> is his backyard, and he won convincingly. `` Tomorrow morning, I go into the <LOCATION> South </LOCATION>, and they're going to be playing in my backyard,'' <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> said in a concession speech at a hotel ballroom as several hundred supporters cheered, stomped and chanted, `` We want <PERSON> Pat </PERSON>!'' <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON>, 57, with his wife, <PERSON> Dede </PERSON>, at his side, said: `` I'm throwing the gauntlet down to <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> and <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>: <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> is the first Super Tuesday state, and I'm going to beat you there convincingly.'' <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> Republicans actually vote the Saturday before Super Tuesday, when 20 states hold caucuses or primaries. The crowd cheered again when one supporter yelled out, `` You've got the biggest backyard, <PERSON> Pat </PERSON>! Earlier, <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON>'s national field director, <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Pinsky </PERSON>, acknowledged that after <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON>'s surprise second-place showing in the Feb. 8 <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> caucuses, `` We were hoping to do better here.'' <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> said in an interview on <ORGANIZATION> NBC-TV </ORGANIZATION>: `` Our polling showed we would have a strong third place. We came up very short on that.'' <PERSON> Pinsky </PERSON> blamed <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON>'s showing on two controversies in the past week: <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON>'s charges about allegations made by a group from which <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> distanced himself and <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON>'s claim during a <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> debate Sunday that the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> has `` nukes in <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION>.'' <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> was hounded Monday by questions on his statement during the debate, and subsequently said his was not `` a categorical statement per se.'' But in his concession remarks, <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> said he will meet with <LOCATION> Cuban </LOCATION> leaders in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> this week, and `` It may be that something happened in the debate here which may be the key to victory in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>.'' Later he said: `` We've got an issue that came out of here on the <LOCATION> Cuban </LOCATION> missiles. I was n't expecting it to play this way, but I'm getting reports from <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> that the people down there are with me on this issue So New Hampshire may have given me the key issue to win the two biggest states in the South.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880217-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-17-88 0323EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-VanishingOldJapan     02-17 0876</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Vanishing Old Japan,0904</SECOND>
<HEAD>Japan's `Last Frontier' Turning To High Technology</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</NOTE>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ELAINE KURTENBACH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SENDAI, Japan (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 It was once known as the Black Country because of its long winters, harsh terrain and hard life. Even at the dawn of this century, it still was a land of barbarian tribes and powerful feudal warriors _ one of <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s last frontiers. Warrior clans and impoverished peasants lived in isolation among its vast mountain ranges. But it had a bucolic tranquility and Japanese poured in from all over to enjoy what <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> once was _ volcanic hot springs and rugged seascapes, folk crafts and villages, old temples and teahouses, well-tended apple orchards and rice fields. This is <PERSON> Tohoku </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> Black </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Country </ORGANIZATION>'s formal name, and it takes up the entire northern end of <LOCATION> Honshu </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s main island. But <PERSON> Tohoku </PERSON>'s leaders are planning to catapult <PERSON> Tohoku </PERSON> into the 21st century, turning the region into a hub of technological progress, filled with high-tech factories, seaports and telecommunications centers. If that happens, some fear, <ORGANIZATION> Tohoku </ORGANIZATION>'s culture and way of life will vanish. Some of it already has. New highways and high-speed train lines have brought modern <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> closer to <LOCATION> Tohoku </LOCATION>. Thousands upon thousands come to its ski resorts and lakes, snowscapes and primieval marshes in three national parks, all offering a respite from the urban plain around <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION>, a little over 100 miles to the south. <LOCATION> Sendai </LOCATION> is now <ORGANIZATION> Tohoku </ORGANIZATION>'s largest city, with 700,000 residents. Devastated by World War II bombing, its broad tree-lined boulevards are a rare product of postwar city planning. Between <PERSON> Tohoku </PERSON>'s growing cities lie vast wooded mountains and cultivated plains, where people carry on a simpler, more traditional Japanese lifestyle. Most live in houses that are huge by comparison with those in <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION>, but they lack central heating and flush toilets. People's lives are suited to the seasons: The cold winter months are spend clustered around quilt-covered heaters called kotatsu, and observing the traditional festivals and rituals tied to the planting and harvesting of rice But in <LOCATION> Sendai </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Tohoku </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organizations </ORGANIZATION>, a powerful business alliance, is planning a leap into the 21st century. If the federation has its way, rustic northern <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> will become a network of technolopolises, marinopolises, teletopias and a `` magmapolis'' _ modern cities based on high technology, seaports, telecommunications and power generation and tourism tied to volcanic activity. Prime Minister <PERSON> Noboru </PERSON> <PERSON> Takeshita </PERSON>'s `` Furusato -LRB- Hometown -RRB- Concept'' _ a plan to establish centers of industry and culture in rural <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> _ is further encouragement for <ORGANIZATION> Tohoku </ORGANIZATION>'s planners. More than 34 foreign firms and some of <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s leading electronics companies already have moved their factories from <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION> to industrial parks in <LOCATION> Tohoku </LOCATION>, attracted by tax incentives, lower land costs and abundant water and energy. Real estate cost an average $ 9 a square foot in <LOCATION> Tohoku </LOCATION> in 1987, compared with $ 110.50 in suburban <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION>. Several company presidents said fresh, skilled labor drew their firms to <LOCATION> Tohoku </LOCATION>, where the people are known for their `` serious character and diligence.'' Federation officials maintain that high-tech industrial development poses little threat to the Tohoku's environment. But opponents claim the air already has become polluted around heavily used roads and that even `` clean'' semiconductor factories must use dangerous chemicals. About one-tenth of <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s 121 million people _ the same number that live in <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION> _ live in all of <LOCATION> Tohoku </LOCATION>, which makes up 20 percent of <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s land area. <PERSON> Toshio </PERSON> <PERSON> Tamakawa </PERSON>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Tohoku </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> federation </ORGANIZATION> and president of the region's largest corporation, <ORGANIZATION> Tohoku </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Electric </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Power </ORGANIZATION>, says <ORGANIZATION> Tohoku </ORGANIZATION> is an attractive alternative to <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION>'s congestion and high prices. `` People used to say <PERSON> Tohoku </PERSON> was a barbarian hinterland,'' he said. `` They certainly ca n't say that anymore.'' Nearby <PERSON> Matsushima </PERSON> -LRB- <LOCATION> Pine </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> -RRB- is still considered one of the most beautiful spots in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, but the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> coast to north and south is a mass of gray factories and shipyards. Modernization has brought flashy department stores and hotels to <LOCATION> Sendai </LOCATION>, along with subways, urban sprawl and traffic jams. But even in quieter, less developed areas, life is changing. A few hours north of <LOCATION> Sendai </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Hiraizumi </LOCATION>, taxi driver <PERSON> Kirio </PERSON> <PERSON> Aoyanagi </PERSON>, in blue uniform and white gloves, talks of how he returned to his native town from `` miserably lonely'' <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION> after living there almost 10 years, to marry and raise his family. <PERSON> Aoyanagi </PERSON> now guides tourists through ancient temples and describes the floods, wars and fires that destroyed most of <PERSON> Hiraizumi </PERSON>, a city built around 1100 by the powerful <PERSON> Fujiwara </PERSON> clan that was once a center of political power. <PERSON> Aoyanagi </PERSON> says he and others ca n't live by farming alone, and need factory jobs. But he worries that old traditions are disappearing as <ORGANIZATION> Tohoku </ORGANIZATION> grows more modern and less isolated. `` It's not like it used to be,'' he said. `` People are becoming self-centered just like in <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION>. The younger generation is completely different.'' A giant <PERSON> Buddha </PERSON>'s face loomed out of a nearby cliff in a quiet mountain valley. Below, a group of farmers, in traditional aprons and kerchiefs, worked at rethatching a farmhouse roof _ a picture of the past. `` I want to keep <PERSON> Tohoku </PERSON> a good place to live,'' <PERSON> Aoyanagi </PERSON> said, `` where people care about each other, and not just their money.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880217-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-17-88 0325EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Israel-Hospitals     02-17 0766</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Israel-Hospitals,0789</SECOND>
<HEAD>Arab Hospitals Overcrowded, Overwhelmed</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</NOTE>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARY SEDOR</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>GAZA CITY, Occupied Gaza Strip (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Hospitals in the occupied <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strip </LOCATION> are overcrowded and increasingly overwhelmed with victims of <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s policy of using beatings and blows to subdue Arab protesters. Last Wednesday at the <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strip </LOCATION>'s largest <LOCATION> Shifa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Palestinian </LOCATION> doctors set the broken limbs of 24 Arabs clubbed by <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> soldiers, then swiftly discharged them to make room for more. In the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Nablus </LOCATION> on Friday, troops fired rubber bullets and smashed windows with their rifle butts to break into <ORGANIZATION> Al </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ittihad </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION> and detain four Arabs suspected of throwing stones. A wall was smeared with blood where docors said the Arabs were beaten and six windows were broken, one punctured with a rubber bullet. Besides treating scores of victims, <LOCATION> Palestinian </LOCATION> hospitals have served as havens for Arab protesters trying to elude detention after anti-Israeli demonstrations. <LOCATION> Shifa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION> has been a staging ground for riots by hundreds of Palestinians who hurled firebombs and stones at soldiers. Troops stormed the hospital twice within two days in December and shot dead two Arabs. `` This is a situation worse than on the TV serial ` M-A-S-H,''' said Dr. <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Geiger </PERSON>, a member of a fact-finding team from the <ORGANIZATION> Boston-based </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Physicians </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Human </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rights </ORGANIZATION> that visited hospitals in the territories. `` People are stitching wounds without gloves and without anesthesia. These hospitals are completely inadequate for the treatment of this kind of trauma and do not meet an acceptable standard,'' <PERSON> Geiger </PERSON> said last Wednesday. As <PERSON> Geiger </PERSON> spoke at <LOCATION> Shifa </LOCATION>, a large ginger-colored cat wandered through wards that reeked with the smell of urine and feces. Thick fetid water filled clogged-up toilets and sinks in the bathroom and a pool of open sewage ran on the floor. At <LOCATION> Alia </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Hebron </LOCATION> last week, an <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> reporter watched doctors stitch up the wounds of <LOCATION> Palestinian </LOCATION> patients lying on blood-stained stretchers on the emergency room floor because all the beds were filled. A doctor stitched shut a deep gash on the head of a 20-year-old man shaking with pain, while in a stretcher beside him another doctor set a man's broken forearm. `` We work with the minimal medical standards,'' said Dr. <PERSON> Ahmed </PERSON> <PERSON> Yassih </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Shifa </LOCATION>, which like <LOCATION> Hebron </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Alia </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION> is Israeli-run. `` Every time we operate there is a shortage.'' `` One day there was no clean linen. Another day, no water. Then no towels, no sterile instruments. Sometimes we work without electricity or have no silk thread for stitches,'' said <PERSON> Yassih </PERSON>, one of four Palestinian surgeons who perform most operations at <LOCATION> Shifa </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Yassih </PERSON> said he discharged 45 Palestinians with beating injuries, including 24 with broken limbs, after only a few hours of treatment last Wednesday. `` There just are n't enough beds,'' <PERSON> Yassih </PERSON> said. `` We get more and more cases every day. I have to keep at least 15 beds free for emergencies.'' Lying in rows of narrow metal frame beds were dozens of Palestinians recovering from more serious beating injuries and gunshot wounds. One 17-year-old Palestinian student, Jihad <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> Achronz </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Rafah </LOCATION>, was paralyzed from the waist down from a bullet wound that punctured a spinal nerve. Another 14-year-old, <PERSON> Ahmed </PERSON> <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> Khalud </PERSON> of Jabaliya refugee camp, suffered epileptic seizures, incontinence and paralysis of his lower spine and upper leg from a bullet wound to the back. <PERSON> Youssef </PERSON> <PERSON> Hamad </PERSON>, 40, screamed as doctors lifted him to examine a swollen black bruise from his neck to lower back. Both <PERSON> Hamad </PERSON>'s arms and legs were in casts, his bandaged head had 12 deep gashes, and several ribs were fractured. <PERSON> Hamad </PERSON> said he was beaten by 10 soldiers who accused him of raising the outlawed <LOCATION> Palestinian </LOCATION> flag on a <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> street. <PERSON> Yasih </PERSON> said beating victims often were from the same family or section of a refugee camp and frequently were clubbed at night. He said he treated 12 members of the <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> Masri </PERSON> family from <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION>, six of whom had broken limbs. `` We find people injured in the same places over and over: the upper chest, legs, back, knees, arms, hands and elbows,'' <PERSON> Yassih </PERSON> said. He said about half the victims treated at <LOCATION> Shifa </LOCATION> had broken legs and 60 percent had broken hands. <PERSON> Yassih </PERSON> also said many Palestinians were reluctant to go to <LOCATION> Shifa </LOCATION> or other Israeli-run hospitals because hospital officials are required to give patients' names to the army, which patrols outside the hospital gate. Three days earlier, troops entered the hospital and took three <PERSON> Arab </PERSON> patients from their beds, reinforcing Palestinians' fears, the doctor said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880217-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-17-88 0326EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Nielsens     02-17 0534</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nielsens,0549</SECOND>
<HEAD>ABC News Wins, But Olympics Start Slow</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KATHRYN BAKER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Television Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 ABC only got a silver in the ratings the first week of Winter Olympics coverage, but <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` World News Tonight'' was golden for the first time since August, snapping <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>' 20-week win streak. The first two nights of the Olympics, Saturday and Sunday, varied widely in the <ORGANIZATION> A.C. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nielsen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> ratings, but according to <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> averaged higher than the first two nights of the 1984 games. An estimated 25 million viewers saw Sunday night's coverage, featuring pairs figure skating, putting it in the top 10 with a 19.7 rating and a 30 share. But Saturday's coverage of hockey was in the bottom 10 with a 9.9 rating and 17 share. The rating is a percentage of the 88.6 million households with televisions. The share is a percentage of sets in use that are tuned to that program. The first two nights of the 1984 games were a Tuesday and a Wednesday, and had a combined rating of 13.8 compared to 15.5 for this year, said <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>. <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s highest rated show of the week was n't the Olympics, but the conclusion of the two-part miniseries `` Elvis and Me,'' the highest-rated miniseries so far this season. But <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> handily won the week ending Feb. 14, with an average prime-time rating of 16.2. <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> was second with 14.9. <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> was third with 14.2. After winning 19 of the 21 weeks so far in the season, <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> has an average rating of 16.4, and <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> are tied with 13.6. The 10 top-rated shows of the week were: `` The Cosby Show'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, `` A Different World'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, `` Elvis and Me, Part 2'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, `` Cheers'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, `` Golden Girls'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, `` Growing Pains'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, `` Night Court'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, `` Who's the Boss?'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, `` L.A. Law'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> and the Winter Olympics Sunday coverage on <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>. <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s new `` <PERSON> Sonny </PERSON> <PERSON> Spoon </PERSON>,'' starring <PERSON> Mario </PERSON> <PERSON> Van </PERSON> <PERSON> Peebles </PERSON> as a chameleon private eye, premiered last Friday with so-so numbers, ranking 49th. The lowest rated shows of the week were: `` Our House,'' Winter Olympics Saturday coverage, `` West 57th,'' `` The Law and <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> McGraw </PERSON>,'' `` Decision'88 _ The <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Caucus </LOCATION>,'' `` Star Trek II: The Wrath of <PERSON> Khan </PERSON>,'' `` The Thorns,'' `` 48 Hours in <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>,'' `` Sledge Hammer!'' and `` The Charmings.'' For the week ending Feb. 12, <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` World News Tonight'' had an average rating of 11.8 and a 20 share. The `` CBS Evening News'' had an 11.1 and 19. `` NBC Nightly News'' had a 10.9 and 19. Network analysts had no immediate explanation for <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s showing. However, last week's ratings could have been affected by coverage of the <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> caucuses, the first results from the 1988 presidential race. `` We tend to do well with major stories, be it Challenger or coverage of <LOCATION> Chernobyl </LOCATION>, and with live programming like the <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> hearings and political coverage,'' said <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman <PERSON> Elise </PERSON> <PERSON> Adde </PERSON>. <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s prime-time special on <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> ranked a respectable 44 out of 68. It followed the conclusion of `` Elvis and Me.'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> coverage ranked 63rd. <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> delayed its coverage of <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> until 11:30 p.m. EST, after prime time. The last time <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> was first in news ratings was the week of Aug. 10, 1987.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880217-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-17-88 0336EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-NielsensList     02-17 0600</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nielsens List,0669</SECOND>
<HEAD>List of Week's Top-Rated TV Shows</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Nielsens</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the prime-time television ratings as compiled by the <ORGANIZATION> A.C. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nielsen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> for the week of Feb. 8-14. Top 20 listings include the week's ranking, with full season-to-date ranking in parentheses, rating for the week, and total homes. An `` X'' in parentheses denotes one-time-only presentation. A rating measures the percentage of the nation's 88.6 million TV homes. 1. -LRB- 1 -RRB- `` The Cosby Show,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 30.1 rating, 26.7 million homes. 2. -LRB- 2 -RRB- `` A Different World,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 26.9, 23.8 million homes. 3. -LRB- 31 -RRB- `` Elvis and Me,'' Part 2, _ `` <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> Monday Night Movie,'' 24.9, 22.1 million homes. 4. -LRB- 3 -RRB- `` Cheers,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 24.7, 21.9 million homes. 5. -LRB- 6 -RRB- `` Golden Girls,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 24.4, 21.6 million homes. 6. -LRB- 5 -RRB- `` Growing Pains,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 24.0, 21.3 million homes. 7. -LRB- 4 -RRB- `` Night Court,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 23.9, 21.2 million homes. 8. -LRB- 7 -RRB- `` Who's the Boss?'', <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 22.6, 20.0 million homes. 9. -LRB- 11 -RRB- `` <LOCATION> L.A. </LOCATION> Law,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 20.5, 18.2 million homes. 10. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Winter Olympics-Sunday,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 19.7, 17.4 million homes. 11. -LRB- 9 -RRB- `` Murder, She Wrote,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 19.5, 17.3 million homes. 11. -LRB- 10 -RRB- `` Moonlighting,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 19.5, 17.3 million homes. 13. -LRB- 15 -RRB- `` Hostage'' _ `` CBS Sunday Movie,'' 19.4, 17.2 million homes. 14. -LRB- 16 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Matlock </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 19.2, 17.0 million homes. 14. -LRB- 12 -RRB- `` ALF,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 19.2, 17.0 million homes. 16. -LRB- 8 -RRB- `` 60 Minutes,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 19.0, 16.8 million homes. 17. -LRB- 21 -RRB- `` 227,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 17.6, 15.6 million homes. 18. -LRB- 19 -RRB- `` <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION>,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 17.5, 15.5 million homes. 19. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Windmills of the Gods,'' Part 2, _ `` CBS Special Movie Presentation,'' 17.3, 15.3 million homes. 20. -LRB- 30 -RRB- `` Knots Landing,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 17.2, 15.2 million homes. 20. -LRB- 19 -RRB- `` Moving Target'' _ `` <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> Monday Night Movies,'' 17.2, 15.2 million homes.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 22. -LRB- 24 -RRB- `` Head of the Class,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 16.7. 23. -LRB- 43 -RRB- `` <PERSON> J.J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Starbuck </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 16.6. 24. -LRB- 27 -RRB- `` Perfect Strangers,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 16.4. 25. -LRB- 35 -RRB- `` Highway to Heaven,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 15.8. 26. -LRB- 13 -RRB- `` Family Ties,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 15.3. 27. -LRB- 34 -RRB- `` Facts of Life,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 15.2. 28. -LRB- 36 -RRB- `` Dynasty,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 15.0. 29. -LRB- 40 -RRB- `` thirtysomething,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 14.9. 30. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Growing Pains Special,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 14.7. 31. -LRB- 28 -RRB- `` Hooperman,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 14.5. 31. -LRB- 33 -RRB- `` Kate & amp; <PERSON> Allie </PERSON>,'' CBS, 14.5. 33. -LRB- 23 -RRB- `` The Dirty Dozen: Fatal Mission'' _ `` NBC Sunday Night Movie,'' 14.3. 34. -LRB- 36 -RRB- `` <LOCATION> Falcon </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Crest </LOCATION>,'' CBS, 14.2. 35. -LRB- 28 -RRB- `` Designing Women,'' CBS, 14.1. 36. -LRB- 36 -RRB- `` Magnum, P.I.,'' CBS, 14.0. 37. -LRB- 43 -RRB- `` Beauty and the <LOCATION> Beast </LOCATION>,'' CBS, 13.9. 37. -LRB- 26 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Newhart </PERSON>,'' CBS, 13.9. 39. -LRB- 45 -RRB- `` St. Elsewhere,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.7. 40. -LRB- 39 -RRB- `` <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> Vice,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.6. 41. -LRB- 24 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Hunter </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.4. 41. -LRB- 21 -RRB- `` My Two Dads,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.4. 43. -LRB- 47 -RRB- `` <ORGANIZATION> Simon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> Simon </PERSON>,'' CBS, 13.3. 44. -LRB- X -RRB- ``'88 Vote: <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> Caucus,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.9. 45. -LRB- 53 -RRB- `` A Year in the Life,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.8. 46. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Magic In-Magic Kingdom,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.5. 46. -LRB- 62 -RRB- `` Tour of Duty,'' CBS, 12.5. 48. -LRB- 46 -RRB- `` The Slap Maxwell Story,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.4. 49. -LRB- 56 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Sonny </PERSON> <PERSON> Spoon </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.0. 50. -LRB- 50 -RRB- `` 20-20,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.9. 50. -LRB- 51 -RRB- `` High Mountain Rangers,'' CBS, 11.9. 50. -LRB- 47 -RRB- `` The Equalizer,'' CBS, 11.9. 53. -LRB- 58 -RRB- `` Wiseguy,'' CBS, 11.7. 53. -LRB- 64 -RRB- `` Full House,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.7. 55. -LRB- 58 -RRB- `` Mr. <PERSON> Belvedere </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.3. 56. -LRB- 55 -RRB- `` Crime Story,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.0. 56. -LRB- 51 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Frank </PERSON>'s Place,'' CBS, 11.0. 58. -LRB- 70 -RRB- `` <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION> Knights,'' CBS, 10.1. 58. -LRB- 57 -RRB- `` Our House,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 10.1. 60. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Winter Olympics-Saturday,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 9.9. 61. -LRB- 79 -RRB- `` West 57th,'' CBS, 8.9. 62. -LRB- 68 -RRB- `` The Law and <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> MacGraw </PERSON>,'' CBS, 8.7. 63. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Decision' 88-Iowa Caucus,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 8.4 64. -LRB- 73 -RRB- `` Star Trek II: The Wrath of Khan'' _ `` <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> Thursday Night Movie,'' 8.1. 65. -LRB- 73 -RRB- `` Thorns,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 7.7. 66. -LRB- 69 -RRB- `` 48 Hours: In <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 7.6. 67. -LRB- 79 -RRB- `` Sledge Hammer!'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 6.8. 68. -LRB- 81 -RRB- `` The <PERSON> Charmings </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 6.3.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880217-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-17-88 0853EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--DipperDipped     02-17 0134</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Dipper Dipped,0138</SECOND>
<HEAD>Dipper Takes Dip, Is Dipped By Dippers</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CASTLE ROCK, Wash. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A smelt fisherman who fell into the <LOCATION> Cowlitz </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> learned what it's like to be netted when his fellow smelt dippers dipped him out. `` Before I realized it, I was in a very swift, icy stream, my waist-high wading boots were full of water and they were dragging me under,'' <PERSON> Elton </PERSON> `` <PERSON> Tommy </PERSON><PERSON> '' </PERSON> <PERSON> Krueger </PERSON>, who can not swim, said after his rescue Sunday. Five other smelt dippers held out their long-handled nets to <PERSON> Krueger </PERSON>, 72, of <PERSON> Wapato </PERSON>, after he slipped in from the muddy river bank. `` I grabbed and they dipped me out,'' he said. <PERSON> Krueger </PERSON> said he brought home a near-limit of smelt, not counting the four that he poured back into the river when he emptied his boots.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880217-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-17-88 0029EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-PLODeportees Bjt   02-17 0767</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-PLO Deportees, Bjt,0797</SECOND>
<HEAD>Deportees On Aborted Voyage Range From Pacifists to Militants</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN RICE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ATHENS, Greece (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The 130 Palestinian deportees whose voyage home was aborted by the bombing of their ship this week include prominent <PERSON> Arab </PERSON> proponents of peace with <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> as well as others who advocate violence. Most were expelled from their Israeli-occupied homeland without trial, under a process considered illegal by virtually every nation except <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> Palestine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> gathered the deportees and hundreds of observers in <LOCATION> Athens </LOCATION> for a trip back to <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> aboard a `` ship of return.'' Their goal was to focus attention on <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s policy of exiling Palestinians from the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strip </LOCATION>, which <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> seized in the 1967 <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> war. Participants said the voyage would have been probably the largest non-violent action attempted by the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION>. `` We have chosen to go back with no guns, no explosives, not even any stones,'' said <PERSON> Mohammed </PERSON> <PERSON> Milhem </PERSON>, deported mayor of the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> city of <LOCATION> Halhoul </LOCATION>. Israeli leaders had vowed to block the ship from reaching <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s shores. On Monday, before the deportees could fly from <LOCATION> Athens </LOCATION> to the port of <LOCATION> Limassol </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Cyprus </LOCATION>, to begin the protest voyage, an explosion left a hole below the waterline of the ferry bought for the trip. A day before, three <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> guerrillas were killed in a car bombing also in <LOCATION> Limassol </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> accused <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> of responsibility. The planned voyage carries echoes of the 1947 trip of the ship Exodus, in which Jewish refugees from Nazi death camps were turned back by British forces as they tried to reach <LOCATION> Palestine </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> Prime Minister <PERSON> Yitzhak </PERSON> <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON> had called the PLO-sponsored trip a `` declaration of war'' on <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> and branded participants as `` terrorists and those who want to kill us, every one of us.'' Defense Minister <PERSON> Yitzhak </PERSON> <PERSON> Rabin </PERSON> said in 1985 that deportations were effective `` for those who instigate and call for participation in terror, even though they themselves are not active.'' The same 1945 British Mandate laws used by <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> for many of the deportations were applied against <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON> and other <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> leaders who led guerrilla bands that assassinated and bombed British soldiers and Arabs in the 1940s. The <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> denounced the deportations in 1980 and again last month, saying they contravened the 1949 <ORGANIZATION> Geneva </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Convention </ORGANIZATION>. `` Their goal is to leave our people leaderless,'' said <PERSON> Abdul-Jawad </PERSON> <PERSON> Saleh </PERSON>, exiled in 1973, a year after his re-election as mayor of <LOCATION> Al-Bireh </LOCATION>. Among those listed for the trip are the president of <ORGANIZATION> Bir </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Zeit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, the president of the <ORGANIZATION> Jerusalem </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Higher </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Islamic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>, the <LOCATION> Jordanian </LOCATION> mayor of <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION>, the deputy mayor of <LOCATION> Jenin </LOCATION> and the assistant Anglican archbishop of <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Milhem </PERSON>, expelled in 1980 and elected to the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> Executive Committee in 1984, often has been suggested as a moderate <LOCATION> Palestinian </LOCATION> negotiator for <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> peace talks. <PERSON> Saleh </PERSON> described himself as `` a non-violent activist,'' and said he was never told specifically what triggered his deportation. He recalled that Israeli military officials had summoned him to warn against founding agricultural cooperatives and ordered him to stop protesting on behalf of villagers outside <LOCATION> Al-Bireh </LOCATION>. Like <PERSON> Milhem </PERSON> and many other exiles, <PERSON> Saleh </PERSON> said he favors acceptance of <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> alongside a <LOCATION> Palestinian </LOCATION> state. `` Two states to live in peace together in the same country,'' was the way Anglican Bishop <PERSON> Eliya </PERSON> <PERSON> Khoury </PERSON> put it. Not all deportees agree with that view. Four Palestinians expelled last month issued a statement shortly after arriving in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>, saying Islamic radicals there should `` threaten to execute'' three <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> hostages if <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> kept up its crackdown on Palestinians in the occupied lands. More than 50 Palestinians have been killed in rioting in the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strip </LOCATION> since Dec. 8, most of them by Israeli gunfire. According to Palestinian and <LOCATION> Jordanian </LOCATION> officials, <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> has deported up to 3,000 Palestinians. Many deportees say they want peace with Israelis, but within an Arab-dominated Palestinian state. `` My brother and my grandfather and his father and my children were born in <LOCATION> Palestine </LOCATION>,'' said <PERSON> Nashaat </PERSON> <PERSON> Labadeh </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Nablus </LOCATION> school principal. `` This is our land. <LOCATION> Palestine </LOCATION> belongs to us.'' He said he was deported largely for his involvement in a 1968 teachers' strike against <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s attempt to impose its school books on <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> pupils. <PERSON> Saleh </PERSON> said <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> should not close its doors to those who have attacked it in the past. `` Even if we were terrorists, and we are demanding a peaceful solution, I think we are the people to make peace with,'' he said. `` You do n't make peace with your friends. You make peace with your enemies.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880217-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-17-88 0353EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-TrainSabotage     02-17 0197</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Train Sabotage,0203</SECOND>
<HEAD>City Transit Executive Pledges To Catch Saboteurs</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CHICAGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A city official says transit agency employees are suspected sabotaging safety devices on train doors. `` This appears to be an insider problem, someone who obviously knows enough about cars to disable them,'' said <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> Chicago </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Authority </ORGANIZATION>'s senior deputy executive director in charge of maintenance. Inspectors at a rail yard discovered the vandalism, involving the air-filled rubber edges that prevent doors from closing on passengers, <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> said. Over the weekend, 25 doors on 18 cars were vandalized, he said. Air hoses either were disconnected or cut cleanly where they connect to a compressor, <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> said Monday. On Tuesday, crews found 11 new cases of apparent tampering, including five instances of damage to cars that had been repaired since the weekend, he said. There were no passenger injuries linked to the faulty doors. <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> has been very outspoken about the agency's problems since coming to <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> a month ago from a similar post in <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION>. Last fall, the transit authority suspected employee sabotage when fuses necessary for emergency brake systems were missing in 100 cars. An investigation failed to produce any suspects.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880217-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-17-88 0044EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p AM-NH-Republicans 8thLd-Writethru a0427 02-17 1006</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-NH-Republicans, 8th Ld-Writethru, a0427,990</SECOND>
<HEAD>URGENT</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: SUB grafs 6-7 with 100 percent vote bgng ``Bush led...; Will
stand for AMs</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By WILLIAM M. WELCH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CONCORD, N.H. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> got the win he so badly needed in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION>'s Republican presidential primary Tuesday and proclaimed `` reports of my death are greatly exaggerated.'' <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> fumed over what he called campaign distortions and told <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, `` Quit lying about my record.'' `` Thank you, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said, apt words of gratitude to the state that revived his presidential hopes. `` On to the <LOCATION> South </LOCATION>, where we're going to rise again.'' <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> accused <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s campaign of distorting his record in a flurry of late television commercials aired in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION>. The <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> senator said the ads unfairly accused him of backing an oil import fee and trying to raise taxes. After complaining for much of the evening, he was asked if he had anything to say to <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> during a live interview with both men on <ORGANIZATION> NBC-TV </ORGANIZATION>. `` Yeah, quit lying about my record,'' <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> said. `` I'm not for raising anybody's taxes and he knows that; I'm not advocating a $ 10 oil import fee, and he knows that _ but they were on the ads all weekend.'' <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> also said he regretted not answering <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> more forcefully during the waning days of the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION> campaign, saying he had been `` too kind.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> led with 38 percent to <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>'s 29 percent, with all precincts reporting. The remaining three <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> candidates lagged far behind _ <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> Rep. <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> at 13 percent, former <LOCATION> Delaware </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Pete </PERSON> <PERSON> du </PERSON> <PERSON> Pont </PERSON> at 10 percent and former television evangelist <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> at 10 percent A sixth candidate, <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON> <PERSON> Haig </PERSON>, dropped out of the race Friday and registered less than 1 percent. <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> claimed he was in third place and sought to make that sound like a victory. `` We won the contest for the conservative wing, and now we're going to contest fo the whole nomination of the <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>,'' <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> looked ahead to primaries in the <LOCATION> South </LOCATION>, saying he had competed in <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>'s backyard of <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION>. `` Tomorrow morning we go into the <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> and they're going to be playing in my backyard,'' <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> said. He pointed to <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>, which holds a <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> primary three days before the rest of the South votes on Super Tuesday March 8. `` I'm going to beat you there convincingly,'' he said to his rivals. <PERSON> Du </PERSON> <PERSON> Pont </PERSON> also contended he was in the running with <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> and <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> for third place. He called it `` a virtual tie'' among those three and said, `` That's got to be good.'' <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> said: `` It's better to win, and I congratulate the winner. I can stand here with my head held high.'' <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> had distorted his record by accusing him of backing tax increases. <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>, who was battling a reputation as a slashing campaigner earned in his 1976 vice presidential race, suggested he may come back at <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> as the campaign turns to the South in the coming three weeks. `` I think we should have answered the charges. I mean, I think you can be too kind to your opponent and we were,'' <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> said. `` They kept saying <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> wants to raise taxes. They know that was not accurate. ... We wanted to keep it positive and see if it worked. `` It's unfortunate that the vice president of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, who knows better, would sink to that level,'' <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> said. Asked later about <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>'s accusing remark, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said: `` I do n't know what he's talking about. But <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s campaign in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> issued a statement quoting <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> four times over the last six months saying he would support the oil tax. <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> has said he would consider the oil import fee but would rebate the fee to homeowners who use oil for heat. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s victory came after his once-strong advantage in the polls had evaporated following his dismal showing in <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> a week ago. <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> forces pointed to that comeback, even as it fell short. `` We were down more than 20 points eight days ago,'' said <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> campaign manager <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Brock </PERSON>. `` To have come this close is a tremendous commentary on <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> and also ... on the softness of the vice president's supporters. `` If he is going to have this kind of a problem in the South ... he's got a real problem,'' <PERSON> Brock </PERSON> said. Earlier in the day, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said `` things have dramatically turned around'' for him in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION>, just as they did for <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> in 1980. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> pointed cheerfully to the traditional first returns that were counted just after midnight in tiny Dixville Notch in the state's northern mountains. There he was a winner, with 11 votes to <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>'s 6. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s once-substantial lead in polls in the state evaporated following <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>'s two-to-one victory over him in <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>'s caucuses a week earlier. But daily polling by the television networks indicated the trend to <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> tailed off by the weekend and the race stabilized into a virtual dead heat. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> also found comfort in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION>'s history of rejecting <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> winners _ including himself in 1980. `` He did what I did in 1980,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said of <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>. `` He won in <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> and came in and talked about momentum. I did what Presidnt <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> did. He came in and started talking the issues'' after losing to <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> searched urgently following his <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> debacle for a way to better deliver his message _ that he is the logical heir to <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s conservative legacy. He was an insulated candidate who rarely made contact with reporters in <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>, a time when he was beset with questions over his role in sales of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> missiles to <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>. But with his politial future on the line after the <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> defeat, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> began asking for votes with apparent emotion and uncharacteristically climbed into the cab of a big truck and drove a forklift to try to display a common man's touch.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880217-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-17-88 0047EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p AM-NH-Democrats 6thLd-Writethru a0435 02-17 0673</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-NH-Democrats, 6th Ld-Writethru, a0435,720</SECOND>
<HEAD>URGENT</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: SUB grafs 6-7 with 100 percent returns bgng ``With...; Will
stand for AMs</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By EVANS WITT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Political Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CONCORD, N.H. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> claimed `` a great victory'' in the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION> presidential primary Tuesday, moving to the front of the Democratic field with the backing of his neighbors. Rep. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION> _ the winner last week in the <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> caucuses _ held onto the No. 2 spot, besting Sen. <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> for the second time in a row. `` It's really a great victory in many ways,'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> said, `` because these are the people who know me best and they had to test me, not as neighbor, but as a presidential candidate. `` It's just a terrific boost. Obviously, it's going to be very important as we go into the <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> West </LOCATION>,'' he said. But the <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> governor would not claim the front-runner's crown: `` I'm wary of that label.'' With all precincts reporting, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> had 36 percent, <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> 20 percent and <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> 17 percent. Further back were <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> at 8 percent, Sen. <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> at 7 percent, former <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Babbitt </PERSON> at 5 percent and former Sen. <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Hart </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION> at 4 percent. <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> said he did well across the state, exaggerating his showing a bit by claiming, `` The only thing we did n't carry was the <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> suburbs.'' `` About a week ago, they said we could n't compete in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> said. Now, he declared, `` It appears that we've got a Dukakis-Gephardt race in the rest of the country, but that could change.'' And the <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION> congressman said money is not a problem. `` We're raising money at a good clip,'' he said. `` We are going to be fine for Super Tuesday.'' That was not the case for <PERSON> Simon </PERSON>, whose campaign was alrady $ 500,000 in debt before the primary. `` This is not helping,'' <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> said. `` From the financial point of view, if I were 3 percentage points ahead instead of 3 points behind, it would make a huge difference in collecting money.'' <PERSON> Babbitt </PERSON> was next-to-last and <PERSON> Hart </PERSON> last, but both refused to end their campaigns. `` This nomination is not won in one week or 30 days, it's going to be a six-month campaign,'' said <PERSON> Hart </PERSON>, who won <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION> in 1984. <PERSON> Hart </PERSON>, who re-entered the race saying `` let the voters decide,'' admitted he would have to start doing better: `` It will take at least 30 to 60 days to determine whether or not I can put together a viable candidacy.'' Asked if he was going to withdraw, <PERSON> Babbitt </PERSON> said, `` No way. I'm going to move on to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> in a couple of days and call and talk to my supporters all over the country and ask them this question: how ... can we keep this reform movement alive Should I wage a guerilla campaign or should I withdraw or do something else?'' <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> said he was satisfied with his showing here. `` Our message has won ... They outspent me 10-to-1. And yet a poor campaign, a rich message has been successful in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION>,'' he said. <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> said he did better than anticipated in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION> and had no regrets about doing little campaigning there. `` We made a decision not to spent a million dollars on two or three delegates. We're saving that for the 1,400 delegates here in the Super Tuesday states,'' <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> said in <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION>. He was the only candidate who was n't in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION> Tuesday night. <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> and <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> had been concentrating their fire on each other until the final weekend, when both switched to ads attacking <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>. `` I have n't been watching a lot of television lately, but I'm told people have been saying some pretty nasty things about me,'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> said `` I assume that's going to take its toll.'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> was angered at <PERSON> Simon </PERSON>'s ad, which suggested he is a technocrat who does n't care about people. <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> `` obviously does not know what he's talking about,'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880217-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-17-88 0330EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Deaths 1stLd-Writethru a0819 02-17 0405</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Deaths, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0819,0411</SECOND>
<NOTE>Eds: ADDS Cohn; AMs separate moved as a0762 on Feynman.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Richard Feynman</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Feynman </PERSON>, a Nobel Prize winning physicist who helped shatter <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION>'s claim that cold weather did n't doom the shuttle Challenger, died Monday of cancer He was 69. <PERSON> Feynman </PERSON> earned a degree from the <ORGANIZATION> Massachusetts </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Technology </ORGANIZATION> in 1939 and a doctorate at <ORGANIZATION> Princeton </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> in 1942. He worked on the <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION> Project where he helped develop the atomic bomb during World War II. He moved to <ORGANIZATION> Cornell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> in 1945, where he did his Nobel-winning studies, then moved to <LOCATION> Caltech </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Pasadena </LOCATION> in 1950. In 1965, <PERSON> Feynman </PERSON> shared the Nobel Prize in physics with <PERSON> Julian </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Schwinger </PERSON> and <PERSON> Shinichero </PERSON> <PERSON> Tomonaga </PERSON> for developing an improved theory of quantum electrodynamics. The theory allowed scientists to predict the effects of electrically charged particles on each other in a radiation field. His best-selling autobiography in 1985 was entitled `` Surely You're Joking, Mr. <PERSON> Feynman </PERSON>!'' <PERSON> Feynman </PERSON> was a member of the presidential commission that investigated the Jan. 28, 1986, explosion of the shuttle Challenger in which all seven crew members died.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>Robert Brown</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LEXINGTON, Ky. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Vahey </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>, a retired veteran radio announcer and broadcast advertising executive, died Sunday at age 82. <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> began working in radio in 1925 at WGR in <LOCATION> Buffalo </LOCATION>, N.Y. He joined <ORGANIZATION> WLW </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Cincinnati </LOCATION> as chief announcer and special events director in 1928. In the 1930s and 1940s, as an announcer for <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>'s voice could be heard on the `` Ma Perkins'' serial, `` <PERSON> Vic </PERSON> and Sade'' and `` Backstage Wife.'' After World War II, <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> became a <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Coast </LOCATION> program manager for <ORGANIZATION> NBC-TV </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION>. He returned to <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> in the 1950s as a commentator, sports announcer, director, writer and producer of television shows and commercials for <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Leo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Burnett </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, a well-known advertising agency.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>Alvin Cohn</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>EAST STROUDSBURG, Pa. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Alvin </PERSON> `` Al'' <PERSON> Cohn </PERSON>, a jazz saxophonist whose career took off after he joined the big band of <PERSON> Woody </PERSON> <PERSON> Herman </PERSON> in 1948, died Monday of cancer. He was 62. <PERSON> Cohn </PERSON> played in bands led by <PERSON> Herman </PERSON>, <PERSON> Buddy </PERSON> <PERSON> Rich </PERSON> and <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Aulds </PERSON>. He also arranged and wrote for television, including the <PERSON> Ernie </PERSON> <PERSON> Kovacs </PERSON> and <PERSON> Sid </PERSON> <PERSON> Caesar </PERSON> shows and `` Your Hit Parade,'' and for the Broadway musicals `` Raisin'' and `` Sophisticated Ladies.'' Among his arrangements were `` Jazz Mission to <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>'' for the <PERSON> Benny </PERSON> <PERSON> Goodman </PERSON> <PERSON> Band </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880217-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-17-88 0313EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-LookingSouth Bjt   02-17 0879</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Looking South, Bjt,870</SECOND>
<HEAD>The Next Battleground: The South And Super Tuesday</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By WILLIAM E. SCHULZ</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ATLANTA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Leaving the snows of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION> behind, the presidential candidates set their sights today on the next big test _ the <LOCATION> South </LOCATION>, with its high-stakes Super Tuesday contests looming three weeks away. `` On to the <LOCATION> South </LOCATION>, where we're going to rise again,'' said Vice President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, fresh from his revival in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION>. Republican rival <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> threatened to shatter what his campaign called a `` myth of invincibility'' surrounding the vice president's organization in the South. The change in scenery could n't come too soon for <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> after his last-place finish in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON>, a Virginian, consoled his followers by saying, `` Tomorrow morning we go into the <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> and they're going to be playing in my backyard.'' <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, coming off a strong first-place finish in his neighboring state, was conceding nothing to <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> rivals <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, a Tennessean who is banking on his native Dixie, and <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, who has a strong base in the region's large black population. `` Some people have been asking how a New Englander can hope to do well on Super Tuesday,'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> said. `` The fact of the matter is, I do n't have a Southern strategy. I do n't have a Northern strategy. I have an American strategy.'' <PERSON> Gore </PERSON>, in <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION>, was the only one of the candidates not in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION> Tuesday night. `` We made a decision not to spend a million dollars on two or three delegates,'' he told supporters. After <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION>, several candidates were heading to <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION>, where lower-stakes contests are scheduled between now and March 8. But the big attention-grabber is Super Tuesday, March 8, when 20 states, most of them in the South, stage primaries or caucuses. The delegate prize: 1,307 Democrats, or more than half of the 2,082 needed to win the nomination, and 700 Republicans, also more than of the 1,139 needed to nominate. <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> has a favorite line about his decision to bypass <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> and run a limited campaign in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION>: `` If you're going to go duck hunting, you go where the ducks are. If you're hunting for delegates, you go where the delegates are.'' Super Tuesday, in a sense, is <PERSON> Gore </PERSON>'s first stand _ and without a strong showing, it could be his last. `` We must do well on Super Tuesday _ there's no ifs, ands or buts about it,'' said his campaign manager, <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> Martin </PERSON>. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, who has solid black backing, has taken the lead in some recent Southern surveys. In <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION>, both of which have only tiny black populations, <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> notched respectable fourth-place showings, indicating he has broadened his base of support. <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> has singled out <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> as his main opponent in the South. `` I think it will essentially become a two-person race,'' he said. He raised the `` electability'' of <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> on Tuesday, saying: `` Democrats in all parts of the country are really hungry for a victory in 1988 and interested in finding a nominee who can offer the best chance of beating the Republicans in the fall.'' <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> are displaying vastly differing campaign styles. <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> is racking up endorsements from key political leaders, and kicked off a massive media campaign last week. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> does n't have the money for big media buys, but his campaign manager, <PERSON> Gerald </PERSON> <PERSON> Austin </PERSON>, said that is n't important because <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> is already well-known. As for <PERSON> Gore </PERSON>'s support from the Democratic political establishment, <LOCATION> Austin </LOCATION> retorts: `` We're depending on the endorsement of the people, not the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> speakers and the like.'' The well-funded <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> was spending heavily in delegate-rich <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, and his organization is seen as strong, especially in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>. To mount a serious Super Tuesday television offensive, a candidate must buy air time in 20 or more separate television markets. That means big expenses _ a major factor for candidates like Democrats <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> and <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Simon </PERSON>, who are saddled with debt. Among Republicans, <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> was kicking off his Southern campaign with a news conference Thursday at the <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION> Capitol. Despite <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s strong Southern organization _ the best among the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> candidates, in the view of some _ <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> was banking on winning over a large undecided vote. `` It does n't surprise me when the people with the vice president say they've got an organization that ca n't be matched down here,'' said <PERSON> Clay </PERSON> <PERSON> Collins </PERSON>, <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>'s campaign director for <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION>. Nonetheless, he said, `` We have the thrust to break through that invincibility myth. I think we are going to make rapid gains.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, however, also was confident. `` We're going <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> and fight. It looks good there,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said. He was to campaign in <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION> on Thursday and in <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> through the weekend. <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON>, the former television evangelist, has also shown a strong Southern organization, and his church-backed following will be a formidable force in the Bible belt. But <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> also needs to regain momentum after his disappointing showing in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION>, so he's looking to <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> primary on the Saturday before Super Tuesday. An expected low turnout, combined with <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON>'s constituency of fundamentalist <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> voters, make that state a likely spot for an improved <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> performance heading into Super Tuesday.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880217-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-17-88 0410EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-BidenHealth Bjt   02-17 0745</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Biden Health, Bjt,730</SECOND>
<HEAD>Life-Threatening Illness First Thought To Be Just A Pain In The
Neck</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PAUL RECER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Science Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 When Sen. <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Biden </PERSON> experienced a pain in the neck, he was placed in a brace until it felt better. But last week when the pain came back suddenly, doctors found an aneurysm on the brain that required delicate surgery to save his life. The surgery, performed last Friday, was so successful that doctors at <ORGANIZATION> Walter </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> on Tuesday transferred the 45-year-old <LOCATION> Delaware </LOCATION> Democrat out of intensive care and into a regular hospital room. `` Physicians are pleased with his continued progress and his condition is listed as satisfactory,'' said <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Esker </PERSON>, a <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> Reed </PERSON> spokesman. A neurosurgeon familiar with the <PERSON> Biden </PERSON> case said many patients with cerebral aneurysms are not as lucky, particularly if there is rapid and serious bleeding. `` It can kill you in 10 minutes,'' said the surgeon, who asked not to be named. `` Most patients survive,'' he added, but for a serious medical condition, aneurysms on the brain are `` big time.'' The doctor said that <PERSON> Biden </PERSON> is in `` the lucky two-thirds'' who live through cerebral aneurysm surgery, and the senator's relatively quick release from intensive care probably means he avoided a long list of problems that can ambush such patients `` One third of these patients die,'' said the surgeon, while others may experience some loss of function, such as paralysis or decline of intellectual ability. `` But if everything is perfect and the surgery is within 24 hours -LRB- of serious bleeding -RRB-, they can be out of the hospital within seven days. Recovery can be absolutely normal.'' Dr. <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Laws </PERSON>, chairman of the neurosurgery department at <ORGANIZATION> George </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION>, said he had no details on the <PERSON> Biden </PERSON> case but that patients with successful surgery usually are released within a week or 10 days. `` It sounds like he -LRB- <PERSON> Biden </PERSON> -RRB- is doing better than that, though,'' said Laws. `` I think he's probably going to do great.'' An aneurysm is caused by a weakness in the artery wall that allows pressure to force the artery to swell outward, like a blister. The danger is that the aneurysm will burst. But in the brain, even a mild leakage can be dangerous and damaging. A leakage into the brain from a branch of the carotid artery can cause a neck pain, but both Laws and the other neurosurgeon said it is `` unusual'' for such a pain to be misdiagnosed. Laws suggested that <PERSON> Biden </PERSON>, in fact, may have had a neck problem earlier and that development of the aneurysm, which manifests a similar pain, was just coincidental. <PERSON> Biden </PERSON> first complained of the neck pain in late January. <PERSON> Jane </PERSON> <PERSON> Berman </PERSON>, an aide in <PERSON> Biden </PERSON>'s <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> office, said when the senator sought medical care, he was issued a brace. `` They thought he had a pinched nerve and a viral infection in the neck at the same time,'' she said. <PERSON> Biden </PERSON>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Judiciary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, wore a neck brace in late January during hearings on the nomination of <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> to the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>. A week later, the senator was too ill to vote on the confirmation. But last week, <PERSON> Biden </PERSON> felt well enough to take off the brace and accept several speaking engagements at <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Coast </LOCATION> colleges, Ms. <PERSON> Berman </PERSON> said. In <LOCATION> Rochester </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION>, the pain returned suddenly and powerfully, and <PERSON> Biden </PERSON> also experienced nausea. He went home to <LOCATION> Wilmington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Del. </LOCATION>, and immediately was admitted to <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francis </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION> `` for tests.'' One of these tests was a CAT scan, a sophisticated X-ray technique. The aneurysm was spotted and <PERSON> Biden </PERSON> quickly was transferred by ambulance early Friday morning to <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> Reed </PERSON> where surgery began only hours later. Laws said that typically in such a procedure an incision is made in the temple area of the head. Surgeons then cut a small window through the wall of the skull and the brain is raised slightly to gain access to the aneurysm site. To correct the flaw, surgeons use a clip, a small metal device with two tiny jaws that lock together. The clip is placed at the base of the aneurysm, parallel to the flow of blood. Left in place permanently, the clip isolates the weak spot and allows the artery to heal. The procedure, said Laws, is `` microsurgery'' because the artery, which he described as like `` a piece of wet spaghetti'' is so small. `` It is very difficult and delicate surgery,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880217-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-17-88 0411EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Reagan     02-17 0473</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Reagan,460</SECOND>
<HEAD>Reagan Returning to Washington; Mum on Political Race</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDS: Reagan leaving Pt. Mugu at 12:30 p.m. EST; may be led.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>SANTA BARBARA, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> is remaining mum on the battle for the Republican presidential nomination as he heads back to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> and his regular weekly meeting with Vice President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. White House spokesman <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> watched returns from the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION> primary on television on Tuesday as he wound up a three-day vacation at his ranch in the <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ynez </LOCATION> mountains north of here. `` We wo n't have any comment,'' <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said when asked about the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION> voting. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> has maintained a public stance of neutrality in the race for the nomination, although he has repeatedly praised <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s performance as vice president. In response to a question, <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> campaign, facing stiff competition from <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Majority Leader <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>, had made no requests that the president step up his commendation of the vice president. He said <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> had not talked with <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> in recent days. The two are scheduled to have lunch at the White House on Thursday, as they do each week. Also on Thursday, the president will meet with bipartisan negotiators in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> who worked out the $ 1.1 trillion budget compromise to be formally unveiled that day. <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> would tell them that `` it is a remarkable budget that ... includes more money for AIDS research, more money for housing and education, but makes cuts in other areas that will allow us to meet the budget reduction and keep the deficit on a downward path.'' Later Thursday, the president will attend the swearing in of Judge <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> of the 9th U.S. <ORGANIZATION> Circuit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appeals </ORGANIZATION> as a member of the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>. He nominated <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> after the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> rejected his nomination of <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Bork </PERSON> and his second nominee, Judge <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON> <PERSON> Ginsburg </PERSON>, withdrew in the face of reports of his marijuana use in earlier days. On Friday, the president will meet with West German Chancellor <PERSON> Helmut </PERSON> <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON> before leaving for Camp David to spend the weekend. At his final meeting with reporters in <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Barbara </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> was asked about a speech in which <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Rowny </PERSON>, the president's disarmament adviser, told a group of scientists in <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> that the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> is `` squandering time'' in arms talks and `` remains a brutal adversary. `` I think Ambassador <PERSON> Rowny </PERSON> was just giving them a little prod that says, ` Come on, fellows, let's get down to business here,''' <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said. `` We might not use those words, but we share his concerns.'' The spokesman also announced that the president was signing a bill by Sen. <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> K. </PERSON> <PERSON> Inouye </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Hawaii </LOCATION>, rescinding an $ 8 million appropriation for schools for North African Jews in <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Inouye </PERSON> was criticized after including the funds in a catch-all appropriations bill.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880217-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-17-88 0854EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--PlaneEngine     02-17 0115</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Plane Engine,0118</SECOND>
<HEAD>Jetliner Engine Fails</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PITTSBURGH (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> USAir </ORGANIZATION> and federal officials are investigating the failure of an engine from a <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> 737 jetliner en route from <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Newark </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.J. </LOCATION>, according to the airline. <ORGANIZATION> USAir </ORGANIZATION> Flight 264 returned to <LOCATION> Greater </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION> <LOCATION> International </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION> Monday morning after the jetliner's right engine compressor stalled and oil pressure dropped about 45 miles east of <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION>, said <ORGANIZATION> USAir </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Shipley </PERSON>. None of the 80 passengers and crew members aboard were injured, he said. The aircraft was taken out of service and was being checked by <ORGANIZATION> USAir </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aviation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> officials, <PERSON> Shipley </PERSON> said. The passengers and their luggage went to <LOCATION> Newark </LOCATION> aboard another <ORGANIZATION> USAir </ORGANIZATION> jetliner.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880217-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-17-88 0300EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-NewHampshireAnalysis Bjt   02-17 0705</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-New Hampshire Analysis, Bjt,670</SECOND>
<HEAD>Reports That the GOP Race is Over May Be Greatly Exaggerated</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP News Analysis</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By WALTER R. MEARS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Special Correspondent</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
