<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880331-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-31-88 2336EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p AM-Dukakis 1stLd-Writethru a0824 03-31 0547</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Dukakis, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0824,520</SECOND>
<HEAD>Dukakis Says Reagan Administration Deserted American Dream</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDs: SUBS 3rd graf pvs, His speech, to UPDATE with speech
delivered; new grafs 6-9 to UPDATE with new material from news
conference</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By DANIEL BEEGAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MILWAUKEE (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Democratic presidential candidate <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> said Thursday the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration has `` walked away from the <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> dream'' with policies to help the rich at the expense of working people. `` I'm running for president because during the past seven years I've seen too many people thrown out into the streets after decades on the job. ... I've talked to too many local leaders who've seen their communities become ghost towns of boarded up hopes and foreclosed dreams,'' the <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> governor said. His speech at Serb Hall, a traditional rallying spot for presidential hopefuls in <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION>, came with polls suggesting <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> is in a virtual dead heat with <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> heading into Tuesday's primary. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> has been making a strong pitch in <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION> to blue-collar workers, asking them to support him as he supported striking meatpackers and paperworkers as well as <LOCATION> Kenosha </LOCATION> autoworkers about to lose their jobs because of a plant closing. While hitting hard at the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> refrained from criticizing other Democratic candidates. One day earlier, he had spoken in general terms of his differences with <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> and then had criticized <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> for demanding he be more specific. At a news conference after the speech, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, responding to questions, said he felt he was better qualified than <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> to be president because of his experience as a governor of <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION>. But he stopped well short of criticizing <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> also called for the resignation of Attorney General <PERSON> Edwin </PERSON> <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>. Asked why he felt he was better qualified than <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> said: `` I think I am going to be a better president because I think I have the strength, the experience and the values to lead this country, because I am somebody who not only believes in good jobs and good wages for people, I've helped to create them.'' In his speech, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> reserved his criticism for the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> White House. `` This administration has walked away from the <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> dream,'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> said Thursday. `` They've walked away from the basic contract that says if you work hard and pay your taxes and live within the law, you have a right to a good job; and the right to a life where you do n't have to go to bed every night worried about whether that job will still be there in the morning.'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> said the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration has done nothing to move people from welfare to jobs, to fight adult illiteracy, to preserve good-paying jobs or to provide adequate health care to the needy. He said he is running for president `` because I believe that every American should have a house _ not a slab of concrete or a heating grate _ that they can call home.'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> also promised what he called a real war on drug and alcohol dependency and asked, `` How can we tell our children to say no to drugs when this administration ca n't say no to one of the largest drug peddlers in this hemisphere?'' _ an apparent reference to <LOCATION> Panamanian </LOCATION> strongman Gen. <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880331-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-31-88 2346EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p AM-Gore     03-31 0732</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Gore,1st Ld-Writethru, a0771,700</SECOND>
<HEAD>Gore Calls For Meese Removal, Defends Criticism of Jackson</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDs: LEADS with 7 grafs, Gore on Meese, picks up 3rd graf pvs,
bgng: ``Forty makes</NOTE>
<HEAD>With AM-Political Rdp Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By WILLIAM M. WELCH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrat <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> defended his criticism of rival <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> on Thursday and took issue with <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> for being `` afraid to say a single word about <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>.'' Later, he called for the removal of Attorney General <PERSON> Edwin </PERSON> <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>. At a <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> fundraiser, <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> said the attorney general should step down because it is `` time to remove the cloud over the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION>.'' `` How long will it take this administration to understand the importance of integrity in government?'' <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> asked a crowd at the posh Grove Isle resort. `` We can not tolerate a situation where the nation's chief law enforcement officer is constantly testifying as a suspect before grand juries, constantly operating under a cloud of suspicion.'' The <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> senator pointed to the departure of top <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> officials and reports that they had quit because they believed <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> was hurting the department by staying on. `` President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and Vice President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> say, ` Oh, it's no bid deal. There are resignations all the time.' What insensitivity! What contempt for the American people!'' said <PERSON> Gore </PERSON>. The <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> campaign raised about $ 108,000 at the <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> event, said <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON> <PERSON> Berger </PERSON>, one of the organizers. Earlier, <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> commented after a Capitol Hill celebration marking his 40th birthday, an event that came as a relief to the candidate who has grown weary of answering questions about running for president while still in his 30s. `` Forty makes all the difference,'' he said. <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> reacted to questions at a news conference about his remarks on Monday in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, when he criticized <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> as without experience and said he was dismayed by the candidate's associations with <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> leader <PERSON> Yasser </PERSON> <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON> and <LOCATION> Cuban </LOCATION> President <PERSON> Fidel </PERSON> <PERSON> Castro </PERSON>. <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> said that by his criticism he was holding <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, the civil rights activist, to the same standard as other candidates. `` I've said exactly the same thing I've said over the last year, and all of a sudden it's a big deal,'' <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> said. `` Well, the only reason it seems to some people like a big deal is that <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> is afraid to say a single word about <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>.'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, however, began cautiously speaking of differences between himself and <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> on the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> and domestic policy on Wednesday. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> said `` from time to time differences will arise ... and those will come out over time.'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> have won the most Democratic delegates so far, with <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> in third place. The <LOCATION> Tennesse </LOCATION> senator spoke to reporters in the sunshine in front of the Capitol after joining in a birthday celebration in a <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> office building. `` You know, <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Benny </PERSON> was perpetually 39,'' <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> said. `` I've been doing a kind of reverse <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Benny </PERSON> in this campaign _ I've been trying to turn 40 <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> planned to spend the next four days campaigning in <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION> before Tuesday's primary there. His campaign began airing a new television ad in that state attacking <ORGANIZATION> Chrysler </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>. Chairman <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Iacocca </PERSON> for closing the <ORGANIZATION> Chrysler </ORGANIZATION> assembly plant in <LOCATION> Kenosha </LOCATION> It shows <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> stating that <PERSON> Iacocca </PERSON> was paid $ 20 million in 1986. `` I'll make these corporations pay their share of the taxes and create jobs here in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> said in the ad. <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> was asked about his criticism of <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> a day after his rival said <PERSON> Gore </PERSON>'s comments amounted to a personal attack and canceled a meeting between the two. <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> called that characterization ridiculous, and he faulted <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> for what he termed a `` ludicrous'' hesitancy to engage <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> in debate or criticism. <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> is still trying to restart his campaign in the <LOCATION> North </LOCATION>, where he has failed to duplicate his Southern success _ or even to register in double-digits in the <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> primary and <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION> caucuses. He reacted strongly when asked by a questioner whether he has been privately encouraged to rop out of the presidential race in order to stop splitting the white vote _ a question that suggested <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> was profiting by the battle between <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> and <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>. <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> said the `` question has a racial if not racist premise.'' He said he had not been so urged and called it inappropriate to talk about such racial divisions.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880331-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-31-88 2347EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-Meese 2ndLd-Writethru a0831 03-31 1131</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Meese, 2nd Ld-Writethru, a0831,1,080</SECOND>
<HEAD>Thurmond Meets With Meese, Notes `Deep Concern' on Capitol Hill</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDs: Inserts 7 grafs after 4th graf bgng: Minutes after ... to
UPDATE with report on Fried asking Meese to resign and being
rebuffed. Inserts 3 grafs after 21st graf pvs bgng: The criminal
... to UPDATE with Rappaport now apparently not cooperating with
investigation. Deletes last few grafs to tighten.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By PETE YOST</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Republican Sen. <PERSON> Strom </PERSON> <PERSON> Thurmond </PERSON> met Thursday with Attorney General <PERSON> Edwin </PERSON> <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON> and expressed `` deep concern'' on behalf of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> about problems at the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> in the wake of the resignations of two of <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>'s top aides. <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>'s meeting with <PERSON> Thurmond </PERSON>, the ranking Republican on the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Judiciary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, was the strongest signal to date of growing bipartisan concern in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> over whether the attorney general, the focus of an 11-month criminal investigation, can continue to run the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>. `` A number of people on <LOCATION> Capitol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION> have expressed deep concern about the problems at the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>,'' <PERSON> Thurmond </PERSON> said in a statement after the meeting. `` I went today to talk to the attorney general to convey these concerns to him.'' Minutes after the meeting, <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> refused to answer reporters' questions about the resignations when he attended a news conference at <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> headquarters on a drug bust Meanwhile, <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> reported in Friday's editions that Solicitor General Charles Fried, the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>'s fourth-ranking official, this week urged <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> to resign but was rebuffed According to the newspaper, Fried told <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> in a meeting Wednesday that the attorney general's legal problems were creating turmoil within the department. After the meeting, <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> said he hoped and expected that the solicitor general would stay on. Department officials told the <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> that Fried had stressed that he was making no judgment on whether <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> was guilty of a crime. They said Fried told <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> that the mounting dispute over his leadership and ethical standards was hindering the department's work. `` <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> feels strongly that <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> has to go for the good of the department,'' one official told the Times. Fried, reached at home Thursday night by The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>, refused to discuss any aspect of the story. `` I'm not going to comment on that,'' he said. The Times also reported that <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Powell </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, the retired <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> justice, said Fried called him Monday evening `` very upset and concerned, and very perplexed about what he should do.'' <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>, who said Wednesday `` there's no reason'' for him to resign, said he would answer questions on the resignations of his aides `` within the next several days'' when `` I hope and I fully expect ... to be announcing various appointments to fill those vacancies.'' `` The business of law enforcement is going forward energetically and without interrupton,'' <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> said. `` Our strong management team is on the job.'' The attorney general, a longtime confidant of President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, stood somberly next <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> Director <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Sessions </PERSON> as the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> chief praised Deputy Attorney General <PERSON> Arnold </PERSON> <PERSON> Burns </PERSON> and Assistant Attorney General <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Weld </PERSON>, who quit Tuesday because they felt <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>'s continuing legal troubles were hurting <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> operations `` I think they're very fine gentlemen, served their government well, are to be commended for the service that they performed,'' Sessions said when asked about <PERSON> Burns </PERSON> and <PERSON> Weld </PERSON>, who oversaw all federal criminal investigations. <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>, in response to a reporter's question, said he had no plans to meet with <PERSON> Thurmond </PERSON> later in the day, neglecting to mention that he had already done so. After the news conference and after <PERSON> Thurmond </PERSON> already had issued his statement, <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> <PERSON> Eastland </PERSON> issued a clarifying statement confirming that the meeting had occurred before the news conference. <PERSON> Thurmond </PERSON> said at a <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Judiciary subcommittee meeting in the morning that he would n't `` countenance any corruption in any way, shape or form in the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> or any other department.'' The <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> reported Thursday, and <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> sources subsequently confirmed, that <PERSON> Weld </PERSON> had told <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> during a meeting Tuesday that the criminal investigation of the attorney general was a close call in terms of whether the attorney general should be prosecuted. <PERSON> Weld </PERSON> went on to say that if he were the independent counsel investigating <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>, he would present the case to a grand jury seeking indictment, according to the sources, who spoke only on condition of anonymity. Sen. <PERSON> Arlen </PERSON> <PERSON> Specter </PERSON>, R-Pa., said Thursday that <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> should meet with <PERSON> Weld </PERSON> and then reconsider whether <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> should stay on the job <PERSON> Specter </PERSON> said <PERSON> Weld </PERSON>'s reported remarks require a presidential inquiry and decision. On Wednesday, Sen. <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Packwood </PERSON>, R-Ore., said flatly that <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> should resign <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Democratic Leader <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON> of <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> also called for his resignation, saying <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> was `` the crown jewel of the sleaze factor in <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration history.'' Sen. <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Evans </PERSON>, R-Wash., told reporters Thursday that if <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> encounters difficulty in finding capable replacements for <PERSON> Burns </PERSON> and <PERSON> Weld </PERSON> and there is evidence the department is not functioning well, and `` he ought to step aside. But Sen. <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Simpson </PERSON>, R-Wyo., the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>'s deputy <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> leader, said he was `` appalled'' at the hue and cry over <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> `` They've never laid a glove on him yet,'' <PERSON> Simpson </PERSON> said, adding there is no indication <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> is guilty of anything. <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s press secretary, <PERSON> Elaine </PERSON> <PERSON> Crispen </PERSON>, said reports that the first lady was campaigning for <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>'s removal were `` absolutely not true.'' `` She has n't talked to anyone and no one has talked to her about the issue,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Crispen </PERSON> said by telephone from <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>, where Mrs. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> was visiting before joining the president at their <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> ranch Friday for an Easter vacation. The criminal investigation of <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> launched last May 11 by independent counsel <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> McKay </PERSON> is continuing, and so far has delved into his involvement through longtime friend <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Wallach </PERSON> with scandal-plagued <ORGANIZATION> Wedtech </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> and a proposed $ 1 billion Iraqi pipeline project. A partner in the pipeline project, Swiss financier <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Rappaport </PERSON>, had been scheduled to give a deposition about the case to <PERSON> McKay </PERSON> last month but backed out and has apparently decided not to cooperate with the investigation, <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> reported in Friday's editions. The newspaper, quoting unidentified sources in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> and abroad, said <PERSON> Rappaport </PERSON> was scheduled to give sworn testimony at a meeting in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> with <PERSON> McKay </PERSON> and his aides but changed his mind at the last minute because he was afraid he might not remember everything accurately. <PERSON> Rappaport </PERSON> was to have been given immunity from prosecution in the case. <PERSON> McKay </PERSON> widened the probe this week by subpoenaing payroll records and other documents of the <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> chapter of the <ORGANIZATION> Multiple </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sclerosis </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION> in connection with a $ 40,000-a-year job <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>'s wife, <PERSON> Ursula </PERSON>, got with the charity in 1985 Investigators are examining <PERSON> Wallach </PERSON>'s role in helping Mrs. <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> get the job.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880331-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-31-88 0129EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-CometAlterations     03-31 0321</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Comet Alterations,0328</SECOND>
<HEAD>Comets Not Unaltered Relics of Solar System's Birth, Analysis
Suggests</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MALCOLM RITTER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Science Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Comets do not deserve a reputation as pure samples of material from the birth of the solar system, because they have been altered in deep space, suggests an analysis published today. Heat from very bright stars and star explosions called supernovae has altered their characteristics, researchers from the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Colorado </ORGANIZATION> at <LOCATION> Boulder </LOCATION> propose. `` There's no such thing as a pristine comet,'' said <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Shull </PERSON>, who presented the analysis with colleague <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Stern </PERSON> in today's issue of the British journal Nature. Comets are essentially dirty snowballs that formed at the birth of the solar system. Scientists study them for clues to the conditions surrounding the formation of the sun and planets. Trillions of comets are thought to orbit the sun some 10,000 to 100,000 times as far away as the Earth's orbit, <PERSON> Shull </PERSON> said. Those comets have never been seen, but astronomers do spot comets that have left that orbit and swung in toward the sun. While still in their distant orbits, the analysis contends, the comets have been heated to differing extents by passing stars and by supernova explosions. That caused boiling that obliterated the original structure and chemical composition of the comet surfaces, the analysis says. <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Feldman </PERSON>, professor of physics and astronomy at <ORGANIZATION> Johns </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hopkins </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Baltimore </LOCATION>, called the proposal intriguing. Comets that return to view on a regular schedule have certainly been heated and modified by repeated trips near the sun, he said, but comets making their first trip to the inner solar system are thought to contain pristine material. `` Their hypothesis is not likely to be easily tested by remote observations from the ground or from earth-orbiting observatories, but will await future missions to comets which can actually measure the composition and structure of the ice directly'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880331-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-31-88 0134EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Africans-Marijuana     03-31 0469</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Africans-Marijuana,0483</SECOND>
<HEAD>Kenyan Ex-President's Nephew Fined $5,000 In Pot Importation
Scheme</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DANIEL J. WAKIN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEWARK, N.J. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The nephew of <LOCATION> Kenya </LOCATION>'s founding president has been fined $ 5,000 and credited for time served for his role in a 1,900-pound marijuana importation conspiracy. `` For your greed, you ... have failed your government and certainly your family,'' <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> Alfred </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Wolin </PERSON> said Wednesday in sentencing <PERSON> Samuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Muigai </PERSON>, 36, nephew of <LOCATION> Kenya </LOCATION>'s first president <PERSON> Jomo </PERSON> <PERSON> Kenyatta </PERSON>. <PERSON> Muigai </PERSON> walked away a free man after paying the fine and serving more than five months in jail since his arrest in October on charges of conspiring to import the marijuana. Three co-defendants were sentenced to prison. <PERSON> Muigai </PERSON> pleaded guilty to conspiring to import an unspecified quantity of the drug, which carries a maximum term of five years in prison. <PERSON> Wolin </PERSON>, who sentenced two Kenyan co-defendants to six years in prison and a third to nine years for their guilty pleas, found that <PERSON> Muigai </PERSON> played a `` truly passive'' role `` limited to greed,'' in the scheme. A fifth Kenyan, millionaire arms dealer and land developer <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> Mwangi </PERSON>, 49, was found innocent after a trial earlier this month. A Ugandan defendant, <PERSON> Mpigi </PERSON> <PERSON> Kabasha </PERSON> <PERSON> Mbogo </PERSON>, 39, is to be sentenced Monday. The six men were arrested after they traveled to <LOCATION> Gloucester </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, where the pot had just arrived aboard a ship. They were to be paid $ 1 million in the deal, negotiated through undercover agents in telephone calls to <LOCATION> Kenya </LOCATION>. Though <PERSON> Muigai </PERSON>'s crime was an `` affront to the people of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Wolin </PERSON> said he was satisfied <PERSON> Muigai </PERSON> was remorseful and had learned a `` bitter lesson.'' He also took note that <PERSON> Muigai </PERSON> was the first to plead guilty. <PERSON> Muigai </PERSON>, dressed in a gray pin-stripped suit and white loafers, apologized for his involvement in what he called an `` unfortunate incident.'' `` I would like to assure you, sir, that I do n't intend and I do n't think I will ever stand in another court of law for charges of any sort of criminal activity,'' he told the judge. <PERSON> Muiga </PERSON>'s his attorneys argued that <PERSON> Muigai </PERSON>'s co-defendants invited him to meet with wealthy <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> businessmen interested in developing some of his property. Even after learning the discussions with the `` businessmen,'' who turned out to be federal agents, concerned marijuana, <PERSON> Muigai </PERSON> went along, hoping still to discuss the land deal, the court papers said. The stiffest sentence, nine years, went to <PERSON> Steven </PERSON> <PERSON> Thuku </PERSON>, who <PERSON> Wolin </PERSON> determined was the principal in the deal for making the contacts with the sources of the marijuana and the other defendants. <PERSON> Wolin </PERSON> found that <PERSON> Geoffrey </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Tumbo </PERSON>, 45, and <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Githegi </PERSON>, 36, had less culpability and gave them six-year prison terms. They pleaded guilty to conspiring to import more than 110 pounds of marijuana, a charge carrying a 20-year maximum penalty.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880331-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-31-88 2351EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-Wallach-Chinn 1stLd-Writethru a0910 03-31 0638</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Wallach-Chinn, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0910,610</SECOND>
<HEAD>Meese Friend: Should Have Been More Sensitive To Appearance Of
Impropriety</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDS: Subs 2nd graf to show that interview published Thursday.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>SAN FRANCISCO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Attorney General <PERSON> Edwin </PERSON> <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>'s friend <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Wallach </PERSON> says he should have been more sensitive to an appearance of impropriety in helping <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> set up a financial partnership with an investment manager who wound up on the board of <ORGANIZATION> Wedtech </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp </ORGANIZATION>. In an interview published Thursday in the <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jose </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION> -RRB- Mercury News, <PERSON> Wallach </PERSON> said that he `` missed the boat completely'' on the potential conflict of interest in linking <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> with the investment manager, <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Franklyn </PERSON> <PERSON> Chinn </PERSON> of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> in May 1985. <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> knew at the time that <PERSON> Chinn </PERSON> was doing work for <ORGANIZATION> Wedtech </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Chinn </PERSON> subsequently become a member of <ORGANIZATION> Wedtech </ORGANIZATION> board of directors. <PERSON> Wallach </PERSON> and <PERSON> Chinn </PERSON> were indicted in December on racketeering charges for allegedly extracting payments from <ORGANIZATION> Wedtech </ORGANIZATION> as part of a scheme to influence <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> and other public officials to assist the defense contractor. In 1981 and 1982, <PERSON> Wallach </PERSON> wrote <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> a dozen memos urging the then-White House counselor's support for the <LOCATION> Bronx </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION> defense contractor. <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> interceded on <ORGANIZATION> Wedtech </ORGANIZATION>'s behalf in connection with the company's efforts to get a $ 32 million no-bid contract to build small engines for the army. <ORGANIZATION> Wedtech </ORGANIZATION> ended up wining the contract in 1982. `` I just missed the boat completely on the <ORGANIZATION> Wedtech </ORGANIZATION> connection,'' <PERSON> Wallach </PERSON> said, referring to the potential for a conflict of interest. `` <ORGANIZATION> Wedtech </ORGANIZATION> at the time was just an irrelevancy. `` I knew that my memos -LRB- to <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> -RRB- had had nothing to do with the award of the -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> Wedtech </ORGANIZATION> -RRB- contract in 1982. ... We -LRB- <PERSON> Wallach </PERSON> and <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> -RRB- were trapped by our own honest conduct. We never thought of <ORGANIZATION> Wedtech </ORGANIZATION>. ... Our state of mind in April'85 was, we had not played a major role in <ORGANIZATION> Wedtech </ORGANIZATION>.'' <PERSON> Wallach </PERSON> also insisted that neither he nor <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> was aware of memos in 1981 and 1982 from then <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> counsel Fred Fielding warning <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>'s top deputy and other administration officials not to intercede in <ORGANIZATION> Wedtech </ORGANIZATION>'s military contract discussions because of ethical and procedural considerations. `` On reflection, a more cautious approach on my part would have been wise,'' said <PERSON> Wallach </PERSON>. `` A more cautious approach on his -LRB- <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>'s -RRB- part would have been wise.'' In the interview with the <ORGANIZATION> San </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Jose </ORGANIZATION> newspaper, <PERSON> Wallach </PERSON> also said <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> had `` nothing absolutely'' to do with a $ 150,000 payment to <PERSON> Wallach </PERSON> in 1985 in connection with a $ 1 billion Iraqi oil pipeline deal. The $ 150,000 was a legal fee to <PERSON> Wallach </PERSON> by one of his clients, Swiss oilman <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Rappaport </PERSON>, a partner in the pipeline project. The $ 150,000 wound up in a stock trading account owned by <PERSON> Chinn </PERSON> and the money was, in effect, pooled with that of other investors, including <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>, to generate profits in highly speculative stock trading of brand new stock issues which were bought and sold on the same day. Under this arrangement, <PERSON> Chinn </PERSON> turned a $ 40,000 profit for <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> on a $ 50,000 investment in just 18 months. The pooling of money from <PERSON> Chinn </PERSON>'s various investors, including <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>, helped the financial manager obtain the funds to get new stock issues. It would have been difficult for <PERSON> Chinn </PERSON> to obtain the new issues of stock with <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>'s money alone. <PERSON> Wallach </PERSON> said that when all of the facts are known, his and <PERSON> Chinn </PERSON>'s handling of the $ 150,000 originally paid to <PERSON> Wallach </PERSON> will emerge as `` the classic bureaucratic error.'' He declined to elaborate. <PERSON> Wallach </PERSON> said the main reason he introduced <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> to <PERSON> Chinn </PERSON> was because <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> stood to make more money investing with <PERSON> Chinn </PERSON> than with more conventional institutions. `` I probably was influenced disproportionately by <PERSON> Frank </PERSON>'s offering a high return,'' <PERSON> Wallach </PERSON> said `` Should I have been more prudent and recommended him -LRB- <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> -RRB- to a more major investment firm?'' <PERSON> Wallach </PERSON> asked. `` In retrospect, yes.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880331-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-31-88 0139EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-CouchPotatoPoll     03-31 0464</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Couch Potato Poll,0476</SECOND>
<HEAD>Study Finds Couch Potato Label Doesn't Fit Most Americans</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BRIAN MURPHY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BOSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A recent survey shows that while about 70 percent of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> adults indicate they watch television during the evening hours, only 12 percent said it is their principal activity. `` We found that most people are not just simply couch potatoes, but do a number other things with their free time,'' said <PERSON> Carol </PERSON> <PERSON> Hess </PERSON>, a research consultant for Lexington-based <ORGANIZATION> Decision </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp </ORGANIZATION>. Most adults reported they combine television viewing with other activities, such as cooking, cleaning and doing crafts, <PERSON> Hess </PERSON> said Wednesday. The <ORGANIZATION> DRC </ORGANIZATION> survey, a follow-up to a previous leisure time poll released last year, asked 1,000 adults during October, November and December to describe how they spent the previous evening from 5 p.m. to 1 a.m. Reading was the second most popular activity, particularly among older respondents, with 22 percent reporting books or magazines as part of their evening. Men comprised the majority of the 18 percent saying they worked during the evening, while the 9 percent reporting they shopped were mostly women, according to the survey. Other top activities included dining out, 12 percent; with sports or exercising, going to a meeting or having sex each noted by 2 percent of the respondents. One percent went to a movie. `` We had a lot of other responses from knitting to spent last night in jail to skinning a raccoon,'' said <PERSON> Hess </PERSON>. Yet only 15 percent rated their evening as `` great,'' with satisfaction higher among older or married respondents or people with annual incomes above $ 50,000. The recent survey was launched after <ORGANIZATION> DRC </ORGANIZATION> researchers last year found that many respondents felt their leisure time was diminishing. `` We thought this was curious considering all the labor-saving equipment and that, in theory, people have a five-day work week,'' said <PERSON> Hess </PERSON>. <ORGANIZATION> DRC </ORGANIZATION> research, however, indicates that people perceive they have less leisure time because of the trend toward highly structured activities outside of work, said <PERSON> Hess </PERSON>. `` When I ask you what are your favorite leisure activities, you might say sailing or something,'' said <PERSON> Hess </PERSON>. `` You are not likely to say you love going swimming at the health club five mornings a week, although that is something you chose to do. It's not a question that people have less leisure time. It's that people are losing their discretionary time; time that is for myself.'' <PERSON> Hess </PERSON> noted that the low percentage of inveterate `` couch potatoes'' suggest people are seeking to gain more control over their free time. `` I think we are looking here at people exercising more freedom of choice,'' said <PERSON> Hess </PERSON>. `` It shows they can exercise their discretionary power to pick what gives them pleasure rather than accepting what's out there in a passive way.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880331-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-31-88 0141EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-RadarDetectors     03-31 0807</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Radar Detectors,0829</SECOND>
<HEAD>Maryland Insurance Ruling Helps Radar Detector Advocates</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By THOMAS GINSBERG</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BALTIMORE (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> James </PERSON> says he drove with a radar detector in his car for years without an accident. But his insurance company dropped him anyway and eventually hit a roadblock that forced it to restore his coverage. The <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION> insurance commissioner two weeks ago, citing data that drivers like <PERSON> James </PERSON> are no more likely to crash than drivers who do n't carry radar detectors, threw out <ORGANIZATION> Geico </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>'s rule against underwriting drivers who own radar detectors. It was under that rule that <ORGANIZATION> Geico </ORGANIZATION> canceled <PERSON> James </PERSON>' policy, but a trade association called RADAR won him reinstatement and filed a complaint with state officials. `` I've never had an accident,'' said <PERSON> James </PERSON>, 45, who commutes to work in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> from suburban <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION>. He said he bought the detector after speeding unintentionally and getting a ticket. `` I do n't speed anymore, I outgrew that years ago.'' An estimated 4 million people nationally use radar detectors, and advocates hope the ruling in <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION> will help keep them legal. `` This is the first ruling of its kind in the country,'' said <PERSON> Janice </PERSON> <PERSON> Lee </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> Cincinnati-based </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Radio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defending </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airwave </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rights </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, the trade group. The devices, which alert drivers that police may be tracking them by scanning for certain radar frequencies, are illegal in <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> D.C </ORGANIZATION>. Legislation to ban the detectors was introduced this year in 12 states and still has a chance of passing in <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION>, said Ms. <PERSON> Lee </PERSON>, whose organization represents about a dozen manufacturers with an estimated $ 300 million in yearly sales. `` Geico tried to make law, and the commissioner told them they had to play by everybody else's rules,'' Ms. <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> said. The ruling, written by Associate Deputy Insurance Commissioner <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Raimondi </PERSON>, criticized <ORGANIZATION> Geico </ORGANIZATION>'s `` vision -LRB- of -RRB- itself as the Good Witch of the North who, alone among the 800 property and casualty insurers, is pointing the magic anti-radar wand of the good corporate citizen in condemnation of the use of radar devices by the citizens of this state.'' Highway safety groups say the detectors ought to be illegal because they are used primarily to break the law. `` Speed is not a function of emotion or economics or politics,'' said <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Brien </PERSON>, spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>. `` Speed is a function of physics: The faster you go, the more likely it is that you'll have an accident.'' Companies such as <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Farm </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Insurance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, the nation's largest auto insurer, and <ORGANIZATION> Aetna </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Insurance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> said they have no detector rules because most states recognize the devices as legal. Insurers also cited the dearth of direct evidence. The insurance industry does not know how many accidents or how many claims are related to detectors, said <PERSON> Harvey </PERSON> <PERSON> Seymour </PERSON> of the industry-funded <ORGANIZATION> Insurance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Information </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION>. `` We oppose speeding and the use of radar detectors. -LRB- But -RRB- it's very hard to statistically support that people with radar detectors have more accidents,'' said <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Doran </PERSON>, director of automobile underwriting for <ORGANIZATION> Allstate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Insurance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, the nation's second-largest auto <ORGANIZATION> Allstate </ORGANIZATION> has concluded that, although it might lose money on drivers with radar detectors, its data would not support a ban in court, <PERSON> Doran </PERSON> said. `` -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> Geico </ORGANIZATION>'s -RRB- guideline was a little arbitrary,'' <PERSON> Doran </PERSON> said. <ORGANIZATION> Geico </ORGANIZATION>, based in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION>, last week failed to win an injunction against the <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION> order, but says it will appeal in <ORGANIZATION> Baltimore </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Circuit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>. And a study in <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> may show whether speeders are likely to be using radar detectors. The federally financed study by the <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> at <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> A & amp; M <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> is slated for completion late this year. It will use two radar units to clock car speeds in four states. One undetectable radar _ using a specially licensed frequency _ will observe speeds before and after a detectable signal is turned on. Using the same method last year in <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>, the industry-backed <ORGANIZATION> Insurance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Highway </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> found that 29 percent of cars going faster than 70 mph, and 19 percent going 66 mph to 70 mph, slowed down abruptly when they encountered the second radar. `` We know the effects of speed, and we know that these -LRB- radar detectors -RRB- cause drivers to go faster. Therefore, our conclusion is that people who use radar detectors would cause higher'' numbers of fatalities, said <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Cook </PERSON>, vice president of the institute. Arguing before the commission, <ORGANIZATION> Geico </ORGANIZATION> used that study and others to calculate that drivers using detectors are equal to drivers `` with two more more violations and would have 2.41 times as many accidents.'' RADAR, on the other hand, cited a survey showing that drivers using detectors were involved in fewer accidents and were more likely to wear seat belts than drivers as a whole.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880331-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-31-88 0141EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-OtherKillings     03-31 0588</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Other Killings,0603</SECOND>
<HEAD>Chambers Case Vs. Other Murders: A Tale Of Two Worlds</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By SAMUEL MAULL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 There are at least four men in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> prisons who have something in common with a new inmate, <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Chambers </PERSON>: They all killed somebody in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> on Aug. 26, 1986. But the similarities end there. Unlike the killer of <PERSON> Jennifer </PERSON> <PERSON> Levin </PERSON>, they are serving their time in obscurity. No camera-wielding mobs hounded them when they surrendered, no tabloids splashed their names in headlines. All four cases were in the impoverished <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bronx </LOCATION>, uptown from the grassy spot in Central Park where the former prep school student killed Miss <PERSON> Levin </PERSON>, from the bar on <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION>'s East Side patronized by Chambers, Miss <PERSON> Levin </PERSON> and other affluent young people. `` It is n't fair,'' said <PERSON> Angel </PERSON> <PERSON> Traverso </PERSON>, 16, a neighbor of one of the victims, <PERSON> Rosa </PERSON> <PERSON> Dueno </PERSON>, 44. `` They make such a big deal out of <PERSON> Jennifer </PERSON> <PERSON> Levin </PERSON>'s death and <PERSON> Rosa </PERSON>'s death means nothing.'' Chambers, 21, started a five - to 15-year sentence Saturday for killing Miss <PERSON> Levin </PERSON>, 18, during what he initially called an episode of `` rough sex. The day before, while a jury deliberated murder charges against him, he pleaded guilty to first-degree manslaughter. Chambers and the other defendants all killed people they knew, and they were arrested quickly. Three of the four <LOCATION> Bronx </LOCATION> killers pleaded guilty after bargaining with prosecutors, as <PERSON> Chambers </PERSON> did. But none went through the protracted litigation that <PERSON> Chambers </PERSON> did, and all but one are serving longer sentences. The one who received a lighter term was Ms. <PERSON> Dueno </PERSON>'s killer, <PERSON> Juan </PERSON> <PERSON> Enrique </PERSON>. He had a history of beating Ms. <PERSON> Dueno </PERSON>, who was his girlfriend, and on Aug. 26, 1986, he stabbed her to death. He was never charged with murder. He pleaded guilty to second-degree manslaughter and was sentenced May 19 to two-and-a-third to seven years in prison. In a city that averages about five homicides a day, the deaths of Ms. <PERSON> Dueno </PERSON> and the others were largely unnoticed. The disposition of the cases went unnoticed as well: _ <ORGANIZATION> Santos </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cuello </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Valdez </ORGANIZATION>, charged with second-degree murder for shooting <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Alvarez </PERSON> to death, pleaded guilty last May 14 to first-degree manslaughter. Justice <PERSON> Elbert </PERSON> <PERSON> Hinkson </PERSON> sentenced him on June 26 to seven to 21 years in prison. _ A grand jury charged <PERSON> Juan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quinones </PERSON> with second-degree murder in the stabbing of <PERSON> Rachel </PERSON> <PERSON> Pajooh </PERSON>, 48. She allegedly had shot at him once when he tried to rob her and had reported him to police. After a non-jury trial, Justice <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> <PERSON> Bernstein </PERSON> convicted <PERSON> Quinones </PERSON> of first-degree manslaughter and sentenced him on Oct. 7, 1987, to 12 -LCB- to 25 years in prison. _ <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Matthews </PERSON>, indicted on a charge of second-degree murder after he smashed his father's head with a sledgehammer, pleaded guilty to first-degree manslaughter and was sentenced by Justice <PERSON> Ivan </PERSON> <PERSON> Warner </PERSON> on Oct. 13 to six to 18 years in prison. There is no indication as to whether the families of the victims were consulted when the guilty pleas were negotiated; prosecutors gave the <PERSON> Levin </PERSON> family the right to veto their agreement with Chambers. And no news conferences were called when the <LOCATION> Bronx </LOCATION> cases were wrapped up. <PERSON> Ed </PERSON> <PERSON> McCarthy </PERSON>, a spokesman for the <LOCATION> Bronx </LOCATION> district attorney's office, said the assistant district attorneys who prosecuted the cases were not available to discuss them, or to compare them with the more celebrated case in <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION> `` It's apples and oranges,'' he said. `` What happened there, happened there. What happens here, happens here.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880331-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-31-88 0145EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-APArts:Babette'sFeast     03-31 0687</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AP Arts: Babette's Feast,0700</SECOND>
<HEAD>Feast for the Body Follows One for the Mind</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By MARY MacVEAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 For $ 2 or so, you can hungrily cradle a barrel of popcorn while watching characters in `` Babette's Feast'' ravish blini with black caviar, quail stuffed with foie gras and other magnificent morsels in what has to be one of the most inspiring meals ever shown on the screen. For $ 88 more, you can follow this feast for the eyes with one for the body. `` One thing will happen after you see this movie: You will be starving,'' said <PERSON> Dro </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Proudian </PERSON>, general manager at <ORGANIZATION> Petrossian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, whose restaurant is one of several around the the country serving the seven-course feast during the run of the movie, <LOCATION> Denmark </LOCATION>'s entry for an Academy Award as best foreign film. `` When you see the film, how complicated the meal is, how expensive, all the marketing,'' there will be a greater understanding of the art of preparing a great meal, said <PERSON> Yannick </PERSON> <PERSON> Cam </PERSON>, chef and owner at <ORGANIZATION> Le </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pavillion </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, which begins serving the feast in April. The movie, based on a story by <PERSON> Isak </PERSON> <PERSON> Dinesen </PERSON>, tells of two unmarried and pious sisters who take a <LOCATION> French </LOCATION> political refugee, <PERSON> Babette </PERSON>, into their home on the bleak coast of <LOCATION> Norway </LOCATION>, in return for housekeeping. Fourteen years later, when <PERSON> Babette </PERSON> wins 10,000 francs in the lottery, she repays them with a feast so strange to them that one sister, in anticipation, compares it to a witch's sabbath But <PERSON> Babette </PERSON> fills the hearts, as well as the bellies, of her 12 guests, mostly members of the sisters' religious community. `` It was a whole experience, that's why we did it,'' said <PERSON> Stella </PERSON> <PERSON> Geller </PERSON> of <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orange </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.J. </LOCATION>, who with her husband followed the film with dinner recently at <LOCATION> Petrossian </LOCATION>. `` I did n't leave a bite of anything. I ate every bite.'' So far, plans have been made for the feast at restaurants in <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Laguna </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Niguel </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, according to <PERSON> Alfred </PERSON> <PERSON> Rosenthal </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Orion </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Classics </ORGANIZATION>' gastronomic consultant for the dinners. Prices will vary slightly, with $ 80 the lowest, without wines, he said. That will buy: turtle soup; blini with black caviar; quail stuffed with foie gras baked in a pastry nest with truffle sauce; salad; cheeses; rum cake with candied fruit; fresh fruit; coffee. Add $ 35 for four wines. As the movie opens in more cities, theater owners and restaurateurs can use a guide written by <PERSON> Rosenthal </PERSON> to help them present the feast and find such ingredients as turtle meat. While the meal is expensive, <PERSON> Proudian </PERSON> called it a bargain, noting the normal prices of just three ingredients: 30 grams of fresh Russian Sevruga caviar -LRB- $ 21 -RRB-; 2 -LCB- ounces of fresh foie gras -LRB- $ 15 -RRB-; three-quarters of an ounce of black truffle -LRB- $ 30 -RRB-. `` The people who come here are adventurous, a lot of romantic people,'' <PERSON> Proudian </PERSON> said in a recent interview at <LOCATION> Petrossian </LOCATION>, a mirrored and marbled restaurant near <LOCATION> Carnegie </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hall </LOCATION>. To meet their expectations and recreate the sense of abundance evident on <PERSON> Babette </PERSON>'s table, he said, `` the caviar has to be heaping, you have to see the truffles, not just a speck here, a slice there. When you put your knife into the quail, you have to feel the foie gras.'' `` It was extraordinarily difficult, because we had to recreate a visual image on a plate,'' he said. <PERSON> Petrossian </PERSON>'s chef, <PERSON> Michel </PERSON> <PERSON> Attali </PERSON>, said he encountered one problem. In the film, the quail is served sitting in its pastry nest with the head on. Believing that would not be acceptable here, <PERSON> Attali </PERSON> fashioned pastry `` heads'' for the tiny game birds. But no matter how faithful, diners will not experience the same mood as in the film, <PERSON> Cam </PERSON> said: `` First the house in the film, and it was a little religious dinner. I do n't think we can reproduce that.'' Still, <PERSON> Proudian </PERSON> said, `` The star of the movie is the food. So if you are in this business, it's nice to see all of this dignity and respect given to the preparation of food.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880331-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-31-88 0107EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Reagan-Nicaragua Bjt   03-31 0634</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Reagan-Nicaragua, Bjt,630</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHINGTON WIRE: Reagan and Ortega Battle to a Draw</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By W. DALE NELSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 It looks more and more as though President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> will leave office without achieving his stated goal of making <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON> say `` Uncle.'' In the view of many Latin American experts, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s policy of keeping the pressure on <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON>'s Nicaraguan government to bring about peace and democracy has failed. `` You have peace, but you do n't have freedom,'' says <PERSON> Neil </PERSON> <PERSON> Pickett </PERSON>, an expert on national and international security affairs at the <ORGANIZATION> Hudson </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Indianapolis </LOCATION>. `` They're about to leave office, and they've got a Contra program that's falling apart on them,'' says <PERSON> Ed </PERSON> <PERSON> King </PERSON>, Latin American adviser to <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Majority Leader <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON>. As <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Pope </PERSON> <PERSON> Atkins </PERSON>, senior associate specializing in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> affairs at the <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Strategic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Studies </ORGANIZATION>, sees it, the stated goal of the policy has kept shifting. `` The first one was simply to interdict Nicaraguan arms to <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Atkins </PERSON> said. `` Then it was rather strongly implied that the idea was to bring down the regime. And now the idea is that if they -LRB- <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>'s leaders -RRB- will change, everything will be all right.'' <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON>, the president's chief spokesman, says the administration's goal remains the same: `` The situation is that we need aid to the Contras in the worst way.'' But questions remain whether Wednesday's <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> vote to continue non-lethal aid and leave the door open for military aid, and the expected <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> vote today, will help further <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s objectives. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> has said his goal is to keep pressure on the <ORGANIZATION> Sandinistas </ORGANIZATION> so they will live up to the promises of democratic reform that they made when they took over from dictator <PERSON> Anastasio </PERSON> <PERSON> Somoza </PERSON> in 1979. At a news conference Feb. 21, 1985, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> was asked whether he was advocating the overthrow of the Nicaraguan government. His reply was: `` Not if the present government would turn around and ... say, ` Uncle. All right, come back into the revolutionary government, and let's straighten this out and institute the goals.''' Now that the two sides have agreed on a cease-fire, will <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>'s Marxist-led Sandinista government reform? And if it does n't, can the Contra rebels the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration has backed survive as an effective force? Many think not. `` I think it would be awfully difficult to reorganize them,'' said <PERSON> Atkins </PERSON>. `` I doubt if they would be particularly interested in that. I do n't think they would want to go through the convolutions of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> policy again.'' King added that `` it's over for the time being unless the <ORGANIZATION> Sandinistas </ORGANIZATION> back up on what they say they are going to do, and have done, and the Contras change their orientation from where they are, which is: let's get some kind of political opening going.'' <PERSON> Pickett </PERSON>, too, sees `` the end of the resistance'' in the latest developments, `` barring some miracle or barring some violation before the truce is signed.'' `` If the Sandinistas do something stupid before that, the Contras can be saved,'' he said. King, the adviser to <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON>, said: `` The objective of the whole exercise in the beginning was to protect <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> security concerns in the region. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> security concerns in the region are removal of the Soviet and the <LOCATION> Cuban </LOCATION> advisers, guarantees of no bases, reduction of Soviet weapons and guarantees of no border crossing. `` Now they are at a point where they do n't have any of those things arranged, they're about to leave office, and they've got a Contra program that's falling apart on them,'' <PERSON> King </PERSON> said. `` I think the whole thing is a disaster, frankly.'' The less partisan sources are not calling it a disaster, but they are n't proclaiming it a success either.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880331-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-31-88 0148EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FederalSpending     03-31 0387</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Federal Spending,360</SECOND>
<HEAD>Federal Spending: $3,433 Per Person</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RANDOLPH E. SCHMID</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> continues to lead the nation in per capita federal spending, but <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> is closing in, new federal figures show. The <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government spent about $ 5,421 per resident in <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> last year, making it the leading state in per capita spending. But second-place <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> _ which moved up from third a year earlier _ was n't far behind at $ 5,317 per capita, according to the <ORGANIZATION> Census </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION>. That $ 104 per capita difference in spending between the states was down from a $ 246 spread in 1986. <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION>, which had been second in 1986, dropped to third place with 1987 spending of $ 5,113. Both <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> benefit from their location adjacent to the nation's capital. Many federal agencies have offices in the suburbs, which also are home for consultants and suppliers of goods for the government. If it were a state, the <LOCATION> District </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION> would easily lead in per capita spending, averaging $ 23,360. Nationwide, federal spending averaged nearly $ 3,433 per American last year, about $ 41 more than the year before. The report, `` Federal Expenditures by State for Fiscal Year 1987,'' broke down spending totaling $ 848 billion, covering virtually everything except interest on the national debt. Direct payments to people was the largest share, totaling $ 384 billion. That includes Social Security, Medicare, food stamps and other such programs. Buying goods and services was second, with $ 196 billion spent. Salaries for federal employees totaled $ 127 billion, with $ 108 billion sent out to state and local governments and $ 33 billion spent on research grants, agriculture subsidies and various other purposes. Per capita, that amounts to $ 1,555 paid to individuals; $ 795 in procurement; $ 514 in salaries; $ 437 in grants to state and local government and other spending of $ 133. <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>'s top finish included high levels of aid to state and local governments as well as pay for federal employees, but it was way down the list in payments to individuals. <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> topped that category, with Social Security and <ORGANIZATION> Medicare </ORGANIZATION> benefits for its large elderly population raising the state's average <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> was easily the leader in total federal spending, with its large population, military bases and industry helping bring in $ 100.7 billion. Even so, the <ORGANIZATION> Golden </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> finished only 14th in per capita spending.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880331-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-31-88 0156EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-MilitaryPurchases     03-31 0409</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Military Purchases,410</SECOND>
<NOTE>For Release 6 a.m. EST, Time set by source.</NOTE>
<HEAD>GAO Cites Weaknesses in Military Purchasing Program</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JAMES HANNAH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Congressional investigators say the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Logistics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> should tighten controls over its `` fast-pay'' program to avoid paying for supplies that are never delivered. According to a <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Accounting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> report released today, one <ORGANIZATION> DLA </ORGANIZATION> purchasing office failed to take action to ensure collection of more than $ 7 million in overpayments. `` I'm appalled that <ORGANIZATION> DLA </ORGANIZATION> is paying money for supplies that it never received,'' said Sen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Ohio </LOCATION>, who, along with Sen. <PERSON> Pete </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON>, R-Calif., released the <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION> report `` We need sound business management at <ORGANIZATION> DLA </ORGANIZATION>.'' The agency purchases food, clothing, fuel oil and other supplies for the armed services. Under the fast-pay program, the agency pays vendors based on shipping invoices instead of verifying receipt of the supplies. The procedure is designed to expedite payments for small purchases. `` Internal controls established by the <ORGANIZATION> DLA </ORGANIZATION> purchasing offices do not prevent possible fast-pay program abuse,'' said the <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION>, the investigative arm of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. `` Potential missing depot shipments are not always detected for timely follow-up and resolution.'' The <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION> said that in 52 fast-pay shipments valued at $ 71,267 to the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Electronics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supply </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Dayton </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, the center could not document the receipt of 16 shipments valued at $ 18,618. In addition, the center failed to notify some of the vendors of the missing shipments within 90 days. It also said action had not been taken as of last May to collect more than $ 7 million in previously identified overpayments owed the Defense Personnel Support Center in <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION> also said that vendors with performance problems on previous contracts have continued to receive fast-pay awards and that controls have not been established to ensure the receipt of supplies sent directly from vendors to overseas locations. In 1985, the <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Management </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Budget </ORGANIZATION> issued instructions to limit the use of fast pay, saying it should not be used to replace stocks in depots or when timely payment can be made. The <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION> said <ORGANIZATION> DLA </ORGANIZATION> believes it is not required to follow the requirements until they are incorporated into the Federal Acquisition Regulations. However, <ORGANIZATION> DLA </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> said the agency plans to be in compliance with the <ORGANIZATION> OMB </ORGANIZATION> requirements by the end of the year even though it is expected to cost an additional $ 2.5 million to process the extra paperwork.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880331-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-31-88 0158EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-AirControllers     03-31 0407</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Air Controllers,400</SECOND>
<HEAD>House Votes To Rehire Some Controllers Fired In 1981</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By H. JOSEF HEBERT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Legislation calling for the rehiring of 1,000 air traffic controllers fired nearly seven years ago has won strong approval in the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, although the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> has yet to consider a similar bill. The <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration has steadfastly refused to rehire any of the 11,400 controllers who were fired after they walked off their jobs in 1981. The <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> has urged that such legislation be vetoed by President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> if it clears <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. The 234-180 <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> vote Wednesday calling for some of the fired controllers to return to the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aviation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> came two years after similar legislation was defeated by a 193-226 margin. Supporters of the legislation argued that there are too few controllers to handle air traffic needs, especially at some of the busiest towers and traffic control centers, and that the former controllers could become fully trained more quickly than trainees off the street. Rep. <PERSON> Guy </PERSON> <PERSON> Molinari </PERSON>, sponsor of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> resolution, said a selected number of fired controllers should be rehired by the <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> `` for the sake of safety and the convenience of the flying public.'' `` Today it's clearer than ever that the air traffic control system is still severely strained,'' <PERSON> Molinari </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-N.Y. </LOCATION>, said during floor debate. The legislation calls for selectively hiring 500 of the fired controllers this year and another 500 next fiscal year. The <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Accounting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION>, the investigative arm of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, has estimated that as many as 6,000 of the 11,400 former controllers still have an interest in returning to the <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION>. Under the legislation the <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> would be free to select the controllers it wants to rehire. The <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> has steadily been increasing its controller workforce and now has 14,450 controllers at various experience levels, compared with 16,375 before the 1981 strike. The <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> plans to hire another 1,350 over the next 1 -LCB- years. While support for rehiring at least some of the fired controllers was widespread, some congressmen continued to have deep concerns about such a move. `` Putting the strikers and their replacements in the same control tower is sure to create animosity between the two factions,'' suggested Rep. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Hammerschmidt </PERSON>, R-Ark. Rep. <PERSON> Gerald </PERSON> <PERSON> Solomon </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-N.Y. </LOCATION>, said the legislastion is `` sending the wrong message'' to government workers and their unions. `` The right to fire illegal strikers must not be compromised,'' <PERSON> Solomon </PERSON> declared.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880331-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-31-88 0200EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Ozone-CFCs     03-31 0612</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Ozone-CFCs,610</SECOND>
<HEAD>Subcommittee Witnesses Call For Quicker Action</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID GOELLER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration is being urged to lead the industrialized world into new, tougher action against the chemicals that scientists say are destroying the Earth's stratospheric ozone layer The call for strict international controls on chlorofluourocarbons, or CFCs, is coming from senators, scientists and two quarters that often are in deep disagreement: environmentalists and chemical companies. `` We need a massive diplomatic mission,'' Sen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Chafee </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-R.I. </LOCATION>, said Wednesday as two <ORGANIZATION> Environment </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> subcommittees heard renewed warnings that <ORGANIZATION> CFC </ORGANIZATION>'s are depleting the ozone that shields humans from the sun's cancer-causing ultraviolet rays. Committee members and witnesses took turns saying that the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> must take the lead to push other industrialized nations into taking stronger measures against CFCs than contained in last year's <LOCATION> Montreal </LOCATION> Protocol. That agreement could lead to a freeze on global CFC production in 1999 at a level of 50 percent of the CFCs manufactured in 1986. To take effect, the protocol needs ratification by nations representing two-thirds of <ORGANIZATION> CFC </ORGANIZATION> production. So far, only the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> have acted. CFCs are widely used as refrigerants and industrial solvents and in the production of foam products. They also serve as propellants in aerosol cans, although such use was banned in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> in 1977. Witnesses said the administration should not only be pushing for ratification but also be lobbying for an emergency international gathering to consider a larger production freeze or even a ban on CFCs. The protocol provides for a <ORGANIZATION> CFC </ORGANIZATION> review meeting sometime in 1990. <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON>, administrator of the <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION>, said Tuesday he would press to have that meeting very early in 1990. Sen. <PERSON> Max </PERSON> <PERSON> Baucus </PERSON>, D-Mont., called on President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> to make an accelerated schedule for <ORGANIZATION> CFC </ORGANIZATION> reductions a priority item this June when he and leaders of other industrialized democracies hold their annual economic summit Also calling for faster action was <PERSON> Sherwood </PERSON> <PERSON> Rowland </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> California-Irvine </ORGANIZATION> professor who in the 1970s was one of the first scientists to warn of dangers posed by CFCs. `` Clearly the protocol is not going to do much of anything for 10 years,'' <PERSON> Rowland </PERSON> said. `` We need more rapid action than that.'' <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Doniger </PERSON>, senior attorney for the environmentalist <ORGANIZATION> Natural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Resources </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>, said a swift international response is needed in light of the conclusion announced March 15 by a panel of 100 scientists convened by the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aeronautics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Space </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>. The panel said ozone depletion is occurring faster than previously thought. <PERSON> Doniger </PERSON> said the losses cited by the panel already are at levels <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> has projected for the year 2050 under the production cuts specified by the <LOCATION> Montreal </LOCATION> protocol. `` I think we can attain a new worldwide agreement in a year and end the use of these chemicals by the end of the century,'' <PERSON> Doniger </PERSON> said. Joining the call for a stepped-up diplomatic effort were representatives of two major <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> producers of CFCs, E.I. <ORGANIZATION> DuPont </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> De </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nemours </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ; </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, and <ORGANIZATION> Allied-Signal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> `` All of us need to work to get as many nations as possible to ratify the protocol as quickly as possible,'' said <PERSON> Marilyn </PERSON> <PERSON> Montgomery </PERSON>, vice president and general manager of <ORGANIZATION> Allied-Signal </ORGANIZATION>'s Genetron Products <PERSON> Elwood </PERSON> <PERSON> Blanchard </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> DuPont </ORGANIZATION>'s executive vice president, said his company believes that CFC-producing countries should be convened as soon as possible `` to review the scientific findings and to establish appropriate global responses to these findings.'' He and Ms. <PERSON> Montgomery </PERSON> said their companies have begun efforts to develop safe substitutes for CFCs, but neither could say when they might be available. <ORGANIZATION> DuPont </ORGANIZATION> announced last week it was phasing out production of CFCs.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880331-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-31-88 0201EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-HandgunBan     03-31 0386</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Handgun Ban,380</SECOND>
<HEAD>Coretta King Calls on Congress to Restrict Handgun Sales</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PHYLLIS MESSINGER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The widow of slain civil rights leader <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Luther </PERSON> <PERSON> King </PERSON> says <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> has `` acquiesced too long to the gun lobby'' and she is urging lawmakers to vote to restrict sales of handguns. Speaking on the seventh anniversary of the shooting of President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> outside a <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> hotel, <PERSON> Coretta </PERSON> <PERSON> Scott </PERSON> <PERSON> King </PERSON> cited the significantly lower murder statistics from countries that control handgun sales. Such restrictions, she said, `` are more effective than capital punishment'' in deterring killings. `` We need to end the needless sacrifices of men, women and children on the altar of congressional inaction.'' She later added: `` <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> has acquiesced to the gun lobby. The only thing that will bring an end to this inaction is an aroused citizenry.'' Mrs. <PERSON> King </PERSON> then signed a giant-size petition, sponsored by the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coalition </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> to </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ban </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Handguns </ORGANIZATION>, that calls for restrictions on the sale of handguns. She will be honorary chairwoman of the petition drive along with <PERSON> Ethel </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, the widow of Sen. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>. The petition drive, called `` A Time to Remember, A Time to End Handgun Violence,'' coincides with the 20th anniversary of the deaths of King and <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>. King was assassinated on April 4, 1968, and <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> on June 6, 1968. In a separate statement, <PERSON> Sarah </PERSON> <PERSON> Brady </PERSON>, wife of White House Press Secretary <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Brady </PERSON>, who was wounded in the attack seven years ago on <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, pleaded to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> for stronger handgun control laws. Mrs. <PERSON> Brady </PERSON> said she supports legislation that would require a seven-day waiting period for handgun purchases to allow police to conduct a background check. `` I'm firmly convinced that had such a proposal been in effect seven years ago, <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Hinckley </PERSON> would have been prevented from purchasing the handgun he used to shoot the president, my husband and two law enforcement officers,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Brady </PERSON> said. The National Coalition to Ban Handguns petition does not endorse any specific piece of legislation. But <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> K. </PERSON> <PERSON> Beard </PERSON> of the coalition said `` we hope it will stimulate this Congress to enact a national waiting period requirement before a handgun may be purchased, to ban the sale of non-detectable -LRB- plastic -RRB- handguns and to ban Saturday Night Specials, the kind of handgun used to kill <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880331-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-31-88 0203EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-CampaignNotebook     03-31 0481</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Campaign Notebook,480</SECOND>
<HEAD>On The Road With Bush: Tongue Twisters and Bowling Technique</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TOM RAUM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MILWAUKEE (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Audiences seem to know what he means, but Vice President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> does n't always get the words out exactly right as he campaigned this week in <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION>. During an appearance at <ORGANIZATION> Lawrence </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Univeristy </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Appleton </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wis. </LOCATION>, the Republican presidential candidate told his audience, `` I want to be the education president.'' `` There is a need for help at the federal level ... so you can afford to send your college to children,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> declared. At another time in the same speech, he meant to talk about the `` high cost of college,'' but it came out: `` the high cost of courage.'' Speaking to a rally in a <LOCATION> Milwaukee </LOCATION> suburb, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> appeared to invent a new federal tax on farmers, declaring he favored a lower `` capital grains tax.'' No doubt, he was referring to the capital gains tax. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has urged a partial repeal of the part of the 1987 tax overhaul law that taxes capital gains _ such as from the sale of a house, stocks or business assets _ at the same level as other income. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s verbal tongue-twisting seems to be catching. Introducing the vice president at another Milwaukee-area function, <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Tommy </PERSON> <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON> asserted: `` As the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> presidency ends, it's time for the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> pregnancy to begin.''
</TEXT>
<HEAD>___</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 As he campaigned in the area, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was repeatedly reminded by local reporters of a previous campaign visit here, when he went to a <LOCATION> Milwaukee </LOCATION> bowling alley _ and wound up sprawled on the lane. Questions like `` Plan to do any bowling this time?'' have abounded. `` You have a good memory,'' he told one inqusitor. `` I did fall down. But so did nine pins,'' he said in defense of his technique.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>___</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 At an aviation musuem in <LOCATION> Oshkosh </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was presented with a brown leather aviator's jacket and he climbed readily into the cockpit of a 1949 Bearcat fighter. The plane was billed as similar to one he had flown as a <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> pilot during World War II, a past his campaign strategists would like to have remembered as often as possible. Well, it was n't exactly like the kind of planes he used to fly, `` but it has the same engine,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said. Then <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, who frequently has posed on and in various kinds of heavy equipment during his campaign, held his right arm over his head and flashed a `` V'' sign for photographers. `` Is this the Red Baron look?'' he asked. Then <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was led to a full-scale replica of the Voyager, the lightweight plane that set a record for flying non-stop around the world. `` I'm anxious to learn about this,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said. `` This looks like it may be a little tough.'' He elaborated further. `` There's the inevitable question,'' he said. `` How does one go to the bathroom?''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880331-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-31-88 0106EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--AbominableSnowman     03-31 0122</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Abominable Snowman,0124</SECOND>
<HEAD>Climber Resumes Search For Abominable Snowman</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A British mountain climber set off for the Himalayas to find out whether the Abominable Snowman is myth or monster. <PERSON> Chris </PERSON> <PERSON> Bonington </PERSON>, who left <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> on Wednesday, intends to return to the 23,237-foot Menglungtse, where last year he found footprints from an unidentified creature on a failed attempt to climb the mountain. `` It would be fantastic if we could come back with some proof,'' he said during a visit to the Natural History Museum in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> before his departure. <PERSON> Bonington </PERSON> and a five-man team discovered 7-inch-by-4-inch footprints 16,000 feet up the mountain last year. Periodic sightings of the creature, also known as the yeti, have been reported for decades.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880331-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-31-88 0208EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-PresidentialYacht     03-31 0583</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Presidential Yacht,560</SECOND>
<HEAD>Presidential Yacht, Rescued from Oblivion, on National Tour</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto WX9</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RICHARD KEIL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The restored presidential yacht USS Sequoia is making a national tour before being returned once again to the president of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> after an 11-year hiatus. The Sequoia, which was sold in 1977 by President <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> as part of an austerity move, has been repaired by a private group. It was launched Wednesday on a 100-city, 22-state tour that will enable thousands to see the vessel before it is officially returned to the White House Nov. 15. `` What we have here is a Fourth of July celebration every weekend in cities throughout the country,'' said <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> McGehee </PERSON>, a member of the group that raised money to repair the 105-foot yacht. `` We're taking a piece of American history to the American people.'' Private and corporate funding paid for the Sequoia's restoration, and <PERSON> Josh </PERSON> <PERSON> Lanier </PERSON>, who chairs the nine-member <ORGANIZATION> Presidential </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Yacht </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Trust </ORGANIZATION>'s board of trustees, hopes the tour will raise money for an endowment to pay for the ship's upkeep `` This tour is a little like running a campaign,'' he joked. `` We have a good candidate, no opposition, and we're confident she wo n't screw up on the evening news.'' The Sequoia was built in 1925 and sold to the <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> in 1931. In 1933, after President <PERSON> Hoover </PERSON> wintered on it in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>, the Sequoia was acquired by the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> and became the president's official yacht. Over the next 44 years, the Sequoia served eight presidents. It was the site of talks on nuclear controls during the <PERSON> Truman </PERSON> administration, the venue of gala celebrations by President <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> and the place where President <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> told his family in 1974 that he would resign the presidency. In 1977, as part of a widespread retrenchment program, <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> directed that the vessel be sold. It was purchased for $ 286,000 by a group of private investors. Over the next four years, the craft changed hands three times and began to deteriorate. In 1981, a private trust was established to purchase and restore the boat. After reading news accounts in 1983 about the boat's dilapidated condition, <PERSON> Lanier </PERSON>, a former aide to Sen. <PERSON> Herman </PERSON> <PERSON> Talmadge </PERSON>, D-Ga., joined the effort to refurbish the craft `` I remember thinking it was a crying shame that this boat had fallen on such bad times, because I remember how it was used in the <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> administrations,'' he said. Minor repairs were made, and a little-publicized, 16-state tour during the summer of 1984 drew surprisingly large crowds. `` Everyone told us it was a mistake for the federal government to have sold the Sequoia,'' <PERSON> Lanier </PERSON> said. `` We then started raising money for a full restoration, with the intention of returning the vessel to the office of the president.'' In June 1986, a six-month, $ 3.5 million restoration was completed, and the Sequoia sailed to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> for the Statue of Liberty centennial celebration. Since then, the Sequoia has been moored in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> and used for government functions. The Sequoia's tour will include ports in <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> in April, and to <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Coast </LOCATION> cities in <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> in May. It then will sail up the <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> in June and July, stopping at ports in <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Arkansas </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION>. After visiting Great Lakes ports in August, the Sequoia will stop at cities between <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Baltimore </LOCATION> in September. The tour will end Oct. 30 in <LOCATION> Alexandria </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880331-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-31-88 0106EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--Kenya-Oil     03-31 0147</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Kenya-Oil,0150</SECOND>
<HEAD>Energy Minister Denies Big Kenyan Oil Strike</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NAIROBI, Kenya (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A newspaper said vast oil deposits have been found in northern <LOCATION> Kenya </LOCATION>, but the minister of energy downplayed the discovery. `` It is true that encouraging results have been achieved, but conclusions drawn by the paper are rather grossly exaggerated,'' <PERSON> Nicholas </PERSON> <PERSON> Biwott </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Biwott </PERSON> issued a statement Wednesday after the <ORGANIZATION> Kenya </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> reported the energy minister had confirmed the presence of vast oil deposits and had said that <LOCATION> Kenya </LOCATION> was ready to begin looking for pump sites. The newspaper of the governing <ORGANIZATION> Kenya </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> African </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> also quoted <PERSON> Biwott </PERSON> as saying two of five international companies prospecting in <LOCATION> Kenya </LOCATION> had struck oil. <PERSON> Biwott </PERSON> said test wells in the <LOCATION> northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Turkana </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Marsabit </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Isiolo </LOCATION> districts had confirmed the presence of gas and oil, but none of the wells had `` yielded hydrocarbons in commercial quantities.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880331-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-31-88 0106EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--NukeVisit     03-31 0132</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Nuke Visit,0133</SECOND>
<HEAD>Soviet Team Visits British Nuclear Plant</HEAD>
<DATELINE>COMBWICH, England (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Four officials from the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> made the first-ever visit by a <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> delegation to a British nuclear plant. The Soviet nuclear power officials, who are on an official four-day visit to <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> this week, have been discussing with their British counterparts methods of making nuclear power stations safer. The delegation, led by <PERSON> Vadim </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Malyshev </PERSON>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Soviet </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> on Supervision of Nuclear Power Safety, was given a tour Wednesday of <LOCATION> Hinkley </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Point </LOCATION> station near <LOCATION> Combwich </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Somerset </LOCATION>, in southwest <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Malyshev </PERSON> told reporters Monday the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> is designing new nuclear reactors since the April 1986 disaster at the Chernobyl plant in the <LOCATION> Ukraine </LOCATION>, which killed 31 people and sent radiation drifting over <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880331-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-31-88 0227EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--BurgerSlip     03-31 0125</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Burger Slip,0126</SECOND>
<HEAD>Policeman Blames Fall On Errant Burger; Court Agrees</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A police officer who was given the slip by a discarded hamburger has won a damage claim against the operators of the <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> subway. High Court Judge <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Lipfriend </PERSON> ruled on Wednesday that <ORGANIZATION> London </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Regional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transport </ORGANIZATION> was negligent in failing to clear up potentially dangerous litter at <ORGANIZATION> Earls </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> station. The amount of damages will be assessed later. <PERSON> Graham </PERSON> <PERSON> Blakely </PERSON>, 26, alleged he was chasing pickpockets in August 1982 when he leaped down some stairs and skidded on the remains of a hamburger and its container, breaking his right leg. `` I am very pleased with the outcome of the case, but I have lost my taste for hamburgers,'' said <PERSON> Blakely </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880331-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-31-88 0109EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     03-31 0937</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0979</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in The News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LANCASTER, Texas (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Jessica </PERSON> <PERSON> McClure </PERSON>, whose rescue from an abandoned well last year attracted international attention, is playing the role of a wee celebrity to help raise funds for a boy with serious lung problems. <PERSON> Jessica </PERSON>, who turned 2 on Saturday, is participating in a balloon release this evening to benefit 5-year-old <PERSON> Brennan </PERSON> <PERSON> Bolin </PERSON>, who needs a heart-lung transplant, benefit coordinator <PERSON> Bonnie </PERSON> <PERSON> Arnold </PERSON> said. The plans called for <PERSON> Jessica </PERSON> to release the first balloon, followed by children from <LOCATION> Lancaster </LOCATION> elementary schools, then `` a drawing among those children for two toys signed by <PERSON> Jessica </PERSON>,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Arnold </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Jessica </PERSON> got involved because the families of the children are acquainted, according to Mrs. <PERSON> Arnold </PERSON>. The boy's grandmother lives in <PERSON> Jessica </PERSON>'s home town of <LOCATION> Midland </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Brennan </PERSON> has idiopathic pulmonary hemosiderosis, a rare condition in which bleeding occurs within the lungs' lining.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Newfound fame has caused quite a stir at the <ORGANIZATION> Cammareri </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Brothers </ORGANIZATION> bakery in <LOCATION> Brooklyn </LOCATION>, where owner <PERSON> Gilberto </PERSON> <PERSON> Godoy </PERSON> uttered one line in the movie `` Moonstruck.'' Customers now greet <PERSON> Godoy </PERSON> with `` We saw you in the movie'' and ask him to autograph their bread bags. `` I go to buy a paper, people recognize me. I go to the bank, people recognize me,'' <PERSON> Godoy </PERSON> said Wednesday. <PERSON> Nicholas </PERSON> <PERSON> Cage </PERSON> played opposite <PERSON> Cher </PERSON> as baker <PERSON> Ronnie </PERSON> <PERSON> Cammareri </PERSON>, putting the tiny <LOCATION> Brooklyn </LOCATION> bakery and its owner on the silver screen. `` <PERSON> Ronnie </PERSON>, someone's looking for you over here,'' <PERSON> Godoy </PERSON> said in his brief movie debut. `` I told them, my part was too small,'' joked <PERSON> Godoy </PERSON>, who had to join the <ORGANIZATION> Screen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Actors </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guild </ORGANIZATION> to prepare for his big moment.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>BOSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Her famous split leap is now just a memory. But at 62, Bolshoi prima ballerina <PERSON> Maya </PERSON> <PERSON> Plisetskaya </PERSON> still dominates the rest of the troupe. She's three times the age of many of her co-dancers and the oldest ballerina of stature performing today. But <PERSON> Plisetskaya </PERSON> nonetheless is living up to the advance publicity generated by organizers of Making Music Together, the largest Soviet-U.S. cultural exchange ever staged. Although other artists also have drawn capacity crowds since the three-week festival opened March 11, <LOCATION> Plisetksaya </LOCATION> has reigned supreme among the 285 featured Soviet performers as crowd-pleasers go. A capacity audience of 4,100 crowded <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Wang </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> for the Performing Arts for a performance based on <PERSON> Bizet </PERSON>'s `` Carmen'' Tuesday, clearly enjoying the grace of <PERSON> Nina </PERSON> <PERSON> Ananiashvili </PERSON>, the strength of <PERSON> Adris </PERSON> <PERSON> Liepe </PERSON> and the near flawless mastery of other young principals. But the normally restrained <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> audience went wild over <PERSON> Plisetskaya </PERSON> as the title character. Many moved to the front for the curtain call to get a closer look amid bravos and sustained applause.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
