<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881229-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-29-88 2327EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Japan-Politics 4thLd-Writethru a0751 12-29 0804</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Japan-Politics, 4th Ld-Writethru, a0751,0829</SECOND>
<HEAD>Justice Minister Resigns</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: New grafs 1-5 UPDATE with Hasegawa quotes, report on
successor. Picks up 4th pvs pvs, Takeshita reshuffled ... DROPS
extraneous words from final graf</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By TETSUO JIMBO</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s newly appointed justice minister resigned Friday under a barrage of criticism for accepting political donations from a company at the center of a major scandal. `` There is nothing wrong with politicians accepting donations made from the good will of their supporters,'' <PERSON> Takashi </PERSON> <PERSON> Hasegawa </PERSON> told reporters at the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION>. `` However, as minister in charge of clearing up the Recruit problem in the <PERSON> Takeshita </PERSON> administration, which is trying to heighten trust in government, it is regrettable that I received donations from Recruit. `` I apologize deeply and resign from my post as justice minister.'' <ORGANIZATION> Kyodo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> said Prime Minister <PERSON> Noboru </PERSON> <PERSON> Takeshita </PERSON> accepted the resignation. Just Tuesday, <PERSON> Takeshita </PERSON> chose <PERSON> Hasegawa </PERSON> to handle a probe of a stock-profiteering scandal involving influential politicians and business leaders and the <ORGANIZATION> Recruit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co </ORGANIZATION>. The secretary general of <PERSON> Takeshita </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> Liberal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Shintaro </PERSON> <PERSON> Abe </PERSON>, said the administration may look outside government to replace <PERSON> Hasegawa </PERSON>. He said a new minister probably would be named before the weekend. <PERSON> Takeshita </PERSON> reshuffled his Cabinet on Tuesday in a move to rid his administration of any links to the scandal involving the purchase of unlisted stocks by a select number of individuals. On Thursday, <PERSON> Takeshita </PERSON> told Chief Cabinet Secretary <PERSON> Keizo </PERSON> <PERSON> Obuchi </PERSON> to look into the history of other new Cabinet members' ties to <ORGANIZATION> Recruit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, an information and publishing conglomerate at the center of the scandal. <ORGANIZATION> Kyodo </ORGANIZATION> said <PERSON> Obuchi </PERSON> also accepted donations from Recruit. Two other new Cabinet members have acknowledged that Recruit bought tickets for their fund-raising parties. Opposition party leaders had demanded <PERSON> Takeshita </PERSON> fire <PERSON> Hasegawa </PERSON> and said the prime minister should take responsibility for appointing <PERSON> Hasegawa </PERSON> without checking whether he had ties with Recruit. `` Appointing a person related to the Recruit scandal as justice minister, who is in charge of investigation into the scandal, is out of the question. It is not something they can get away by saying they did not know,'' said <PERSON> Mitsuhiro </PERSON> <PERSON> Kaneko </PERSON>, head of the <ORGANIZATION> Japan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>'s secretariat. Influential politicians and business leaders were offered bargain-priced shares in <LOCATION> Recruit-Cosmos </LOCATION>, a Recruit real estate subsidiary, before they were listed for public sale. Share prices rose sharply after their public offering, and some shareholders made more than $ 80,000 in tax-free profits. Former Finance Minister <PERSON> Kiichi </PERSON> <PERSON> Miyazawa </PERSON> heads the roster of 17 politicians and business leaders who resigned earlier in the scandal. A former Recruit official pleaded guilty to trying to bribe an opposition <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION> member to tone down his investigation. But <PERSON> Hasegawa </PERSON>'s and <PERSON> Obuchi </PERSON>'s reported links with Recruit differed from the other cases. The day after <PERSON> Hasegawa </PERSON>'s appointment, it was disclosed that his political support organization received $ 46,000 in membership dues from Recruit over 12 years. The latest donation of $ 3,800 came in October, about three months after the Recruit scandal erupted. On Thursday, <PERSON> Takeshita </PERSON> said <PERSON> Hasegawa </PERSON> told him that accepting membership fees from Recruit `` lacked prudence, and I fully agree with him.'' But <PERSON> Takeshita </PERSON> added, `` I believe his ability will allow him to fulfill his responsibility as justice minister.'' The prime minister said earlier <PERSON> Hasegawa </PERSON> would play a key role in promoting reform in political ethics and that <PERSON> Hasegawa </PERSON> was the best man for the job. <PERSON> Hasegawa </PERSON>, 76, told a news conference Thursday he was `` truly careless'' in not knowing about the donations, but `` as justice minister I do n't think this matter will be an impediment.'' <PERSON> Hasegawa </PERSON> first denied allegations about the donations, and then said they were made without his knowledge. But his son and secretary, <PERSON> Akira </PERSON> <PERSON> Hasegawa </PERSON>, said he told his father about the donations as early as October. In forming his new Cabinet on Tuesday, <PERSON> Takeshita </PERSON> sought to put the Recruit scandal behind him. But critics link <PERSON> Takeshita </PERSON> himself to the scandal since one of his aides profited from sales of bargain Recruit shares. The prime minister has denied any personal involvement. <ORGANIZATION> Kyodo </ORGANIZATION> said <PERSON> Obuchi </PERSON>'s support organization has been receiving $ 160 a month from Recruit, although it was not known for how long. It said <PERSON> Obuchi </PERSON>'s only comment was, `` We have been complying with the law in handling political donations.'' <PERSON> Tsutomu </PERSON> <PERSON> Hata </PERSON>, the new agriculture minister, acknowledged that Recruit bought tickets for his fund-raising party in 1986, but did not disclose the amount. Another new Cabinet official, <PERSON> Ken </PERSON> <PERSON> Harada </PERSON>, director general of the <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Planning </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION>, acknowledged he received donations from Recruit for more than 10 years and that Recruit has bought tickets for his fund-raising parties. Like the stock transactions, the political donations were legal. But critics contend the stock deals were unethical and were donations in disguise. <PERSON> Tsuruo </PERSON> <PERSON> Yamaguchi </PERSON>, general secretary of the largest opposition party, the Socialists, had demanded <PERSON> Hasegawa </PERSON>'s resignation.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881229-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-29-88 0045EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Italy-Flu     12-29 0221</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Italy-Flu,0227</SECOND>
<HEAD>Chinese Flu Sweeps Through Italy</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ROME (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A quick-spreading outbreak of Chinese flu has ruined the holidays for tens of thousands of Italians, filled hospitals and clinics, and left many doctors sick in bed, Italian newspapers report. The outbreak surprised health officials, who had predicted the annual flu season would begin in January, according to news reports Wednesday. While health officials do not consider this year's virus, which they think originated in Chinese pigs, to be more severe than recent types, its timing has caused numerous problems. Throughout <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>, family doctors, understaffed emergency rooms and clinics were unprepared for the onslaught of people seeking relief from the virus, which is considered dangerous only to infants and the elderly. There have been no reports of deaths in <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION> from the flu. In <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION>, weekend calls to the city's main emergency center poured in at almost twice the normal rate. An estimated 15 percent of the city's doctors and 35 percent of its nurses were unable to work, mostly due to the virus. Health officials in <LOCATION> Bologna </LOCATION> estimate that about 20,000 citizens remain in bed with symptoms of the flu, which include high fever, aching joints and the chills. Doctors have said the flu normally lasts three days and should be treated with rest, fluids, aspirin and vitamin C.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881229-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-29-88 0045EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--PicassoMuseum     12-29 0152</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Picasso Museum,0154</SECOND>
<HEAD>Picasso Museum To Close For Repairs</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PARIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Picasso </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Museum </ORGANIZATION>, home for the past three years to nearly 3,500 works by <PERSON> Pablo </PERSON> <PERSON> Picasso </PERSON>, is closing to the public for two months for repairs, a museum spokesman said. The refurbished 17th century mansion, known as the Hotel Sale after one of its former owners, opened as a museum in 1985 with the world's largest collection of works by the Spanish master who died in 1973. The 203 paintings, 158 sculptures and 3,000 drawings were taken by the French government from <PERSON> Picasso </PERSON>'s heirs in lieu of death taxes, along with works by <ORGANIZATION> Matisse </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Cezanne </PERSON>, <PERSON> Braque </PERSON> and <PERSON> Renoir </PERSON> in the artist's private collection. A spokesman said Wednesday that the repairs involved replacing the building's stone floors, which had proven `` too porous and fragile,'' to handle traffic from some 40,000 visitors monthly. The museum closes Saturday and reopens March 1.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881229-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-29-88 0054EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-APArts:Fisher     12-29 0932</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AP Arts: Fisher,0950</SECOND>
<HEAD>M.F.K. Fisher Continues Her Wondrous Gifts of Words and Wit</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.
^By JACK SCHREIBMAN</NOTE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>GLEN ELLEN, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Ignore the wheelchair and arthritis. Her 80 years weigh lightly upon the mind and wit of M.F.K. <PERSON> Fisher </PERSON>, whose gifts to the world of food and literature are still mounting. But shed a tear for the grand dame of gastronomy: <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Frances </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> <PERSON> Fisher </PERSON> denies herself the pleasure she gives her army of admirers in the 17 books and scores of magazine pieces that for 50 years set a lean and spicy standard few can match. `` I never read anything I've written,'' she snapped. `` I do n't care to go back I never read a word of print about me or by me.'' She would n't argue with going back to being able to use her hands for typing. Fate has ruled that she must dictate into a tape recorder. There's no question of her not doing it. Writing is as important to her as air. `` I am compulsive about it,'' admitted the Michigan-born author, who wrote such tasty morsels as `` How to <PERSON> Cook </PERSON> a Wolf,'' `` The Gastronomical Me,'' `` Consider the Oyster'' and her pungent `` Alphabet for Gourmets.'' Chafing among cushions in her little wine-country house, she added, `` But it's like pulling teeth. It's just awful. I ca n't dictate to a person so I dictate secretly I do n't make many mistakes, you know. It's my newspaper training. ... I do n't have any errors once I get it down on paper, thank God.'' In 1937, the world's food writers discovered a tough new kid on the block when they eyed this paragraph leaping from the pages of `` Serve It Forth,'' <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Frances </PERSON>' first book: `` The quails are an artful lure to the most refined of palates, and the rabbit stew, steaming, aromatic, is made just as tempting with an onion or two, pepper freshly ground, a little bacon and a dash of cheap, pure wine.'' A somewhat less literate reporter observed, `` It's a shame you do n't get to read your good stuff like that.'' She was not impressed. Others are. It was once said of her crisp prose: `` She writes about food as others do about love, but rather better. ... <PERSON> Fisher </PERSON> writes not as a specialist but as a whole human being, spiky with prejudices, charming, short-tempered, well-traveled and cosmopolitan. ... She is a person, not a gourmet masked as a writer. Her passion comes from inside her.'' That was 35 years ago. Except for such indignities as two hip replacements, a corneal implant and the arthritis, nothing has changed, and she remembers everything between times _ three husbands, magazine pieces, the books that `` never made me any money,'' the travels in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>. Of all her mates, said <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Frances </PERSON>, `` my real husband was <PERSON> Jimmy </PERSON> <PERSON> Parrish </PERSON> -LRB- <PERSON> Dillwyn </PERSON> <PERSON> Parrish </PERSON> -RRB-.'' They lived in a stone house surrounded by a vineyard and garden in <LOCATION> Vevey </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Switzerland </LOCATION>. It was there, she said, that she learned from her Italian Swiss neighbors to cook vegetables in their own juices `` with sweet butter or thick olive oil to encourage them a little; tomatoes and onions and sweet peppers and all the summer things.'' She credits her start in food-writing on an episode during prohibition when she was living in <LOCATION> Whittier </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, and her newspaperman father, <PERSON> Rex </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, was teaching at a nearby college. She was working in a postcard shop. One afternoon she had a half-day off and decided to go the public library, where she found an Elizabethan cookbook on a table. `` It smelled so good ... the binding. I started writing,'' she said. She showed her writing to <PERSON> Alfred </PERSON> <PERSON> Fisher </PERSON>, the man who became her first husband. She had just turned 21 when they married, and 11 days later they set off to <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> and three years in Dijon, where he got his doctorate and she earned a degree at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dijon </ORGANIZATION>. Back in the states, her writing started making the rounds. At 26, she sold her first magazine story, `` The Standing and the Waiting,'' and it conjured visions, full of verbs and wide swaths of color. The most scholarly of her work is her translation of legendary gastronomer <PERSON> Jean </PERSON> <PERSON> Anthelme </PERSON> <PERSON> Brillat-Savarin </PERSON>'s `` The Physiology of Taste,'' her favorite work. Smoothing her red polka-dot dress, she peered out the window of the small, busy house she has lived in for 18 years, craning to see who was coming to visit her next. They come all day long, for a few moments in her `` youthful'' presence. They come professionally or as friends, for interviews, a publisher's conference, a chat, advice or perhaps to drop off a particularly nice piece of cheese or share a plateful of the chincoteague oysters she loves so much. She calls her visitors `` strays and wayfarers.'' They sit with her near a large picture window in her <LOCATION> Sonoma </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> house on the edge of the old <LOCATION> Bouverie </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ranch </LOCATION>, in <LOCATION> Jack </LOCATION> <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> country. But in her eighth decade, <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Frances </PERSON> is not overwhelmed with the way things have gone with the world. `` We're suicidal,'' declared the mother of two daughters. `` Our doom is sealed. I take a very dim view of us as a human race, the only one that kills itself and everything around it. ... We've poisoned the earth and the land and the water What else is there to poison? ... I do n't have any hope for us at all.'' We looked out on her green meadow, rolling to the trees, peaceful, and the harsh pronouncement seemed a long way away.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881229-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-29-88 0107EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BorderCrossing     12-29 0171</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Border Crossing,0173</SECOND>
<HEAD>Environmentalists Stage Protest Inside East German Border</HEAD>
<DATELINE>HOF, West Germany (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A dozen environmentalists protesting East bloc air pollution erected two tents on the East German side of the border as Communist border guards watched without intervening, West German police said. Police said the activists staged the protest Wednesday just inside <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> near where <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Czechoslovakia </LOCATION> meet. The environmentalists contend East German and Czechoslovak authorities are too lax in enforcing air pollution laws, resulting in harmful emissions that affect air quality in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> as well. Twelve of them erected two tents just inside the East German frontier, but outside the fence that separates the two countries. They also released balloons with slogans such as `` Pollution knows no borders.'' West German police said East German border guards watched the developments from a distance, but did not intervene. Czechoslovak sentries also watched from their side of the border. Five other environmentalists stayed on West German territory as the protest continued late Wednesday.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881229-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-29-88 0113EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-TopTen-List     12-29 0102</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Top Ten-List,0113</SECOND>
<HEAD>With PM-Top Ten, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the top 10 stories of 1988 as selected by <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> member editors and broadcasters in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. -LRB- Note: The voting ended before the <ORGANIZATION> Pan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Am </ORGANIZATION> airliner crash in <LOCATION> Scotland </LOCATION>. -RRB- 1. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> defeats <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> in presidential election. 2. Earthquake levels Armenian cities. 3. Drought parches Midwestern farms. 4. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> warship downs Iranian airliner. 5. <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> re-enters space. 6. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> will open <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> talks. 7. <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> end eight-year war. 8. Nation's environment threatened. 9. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> announces Soviet troop reductions. 10. Forest fires scorch national parks.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881229-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-29-88 0113EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-TopTen-ForeignList     12-29 0146</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Top Ten-Foreign List,0155</SECOND>
<HEAD>With PM-Top 10, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the top 10 stories of 1988 as selected by foreign newspaper editors polled by The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>. -LRB- Note: The voting ended before the Armenian earthquake and the <ORGANIZATION> Pan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Am </ORGANIZATION> airliner crash in <LOCATION> Scotland </LOCATION>. -RRB- 1. The U.S.-Soviet summit in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>; first steps in implementing Intermediate Nuclear Forces treaty. 2. <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> end eight-year war. 3. Soviet party shake-up; <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> named president; reforms continue. 4. Afghan accords reached; Soviets begin troop pullout. 5. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> defeat <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> in <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> presidential election. 6. Palestinian unrest in the Israeli-occupied territories. 7. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> warship downs Iranian airliner. 8. Armenian-Azerbaijani unrest hits <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. 9. <LOCATION> Chile </LOCATION>'s Gen. <PERSON> Augusto </PERSON> <PERSON> Pinochet </PERSON> rejected in referendum on another eight-year presidential term. 10. Mysterious plane crash kills <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> President <PERSON> Mohammed </PERSON> <PERSON> Zia </PERSON> <PERSON> ul-Haq </PERSON>; <PERSON> Benazir </PERSON> <PERSON> Bhutto </PERSON> named prime minister after free elections.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881229-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-29-88 0115EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Quake-Survivors 2Takes   12-29 0619</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Quake-Survivors, 2 Takes,0637</SECOND>
<HEAD>Trapped Woman Gave Daughter Her Blood to Keep Her Alive</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</NOTE>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 The Dec. 7 earthquake that killed an estimated 55,000 people brought tragedy and sorrow to countless Armenians. But it also was a time for bravery. Here is one woman's story of her fight to save the life of her child, as they lay buried alive for eight days.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>By JOHN-THOR DAHLBURG</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>YEREVAN, U.S.S.R. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Mother and daughter were entombed in eternal night and their only food, a jar of jam, was gone. Tons of smashed concrete around them had become their prison. `` Mommy, I'm so thirsty, I want to drink,'' cried the 4-year-old girl <PERSON> Susanna </PERSON> <PERSON> Petrosyan </PERSON> said she was trapped flat on her back. A prefabricated concrete panel 18 inches above her head and a crumpled water pipe above her shoulders kept her from standing. She wore only a slip, and it was horribly cold. Beside her in the darkness lay the lifeless body of her sister-in-law, <PERSON> Karine </PERSON>. She had been crushed by falling walls, and died pinned beneath rubble one day after the Dec. 7 earthquake leveled much of <LOCATION> Leninakan </LOCATION> and other towns in northwestern <LOCATION> Armenia </LOCATION>. `` Mommy, I need to drink,'' sobbed Mrs. <PERSON> Petrosyan </PERSON>'s daughter, <PERSON> Gayaney </PERSON>. `` Please give me something.'' `` I thought my child was going to die of thirst,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Petrosyan </PERSON>, 26, recalled. `` I had no water, no fruit juice, no liquids. It was then I remembered that I had my own blood.'' Although she was trapped in darkness, she could slide on her back from side to side. Her groping fingers, numb from the cold, found a shattered glass. She sliced open her left index finger with a shard and gave it to her daughter to suckle. The drops of blood were n't enough. `` Please, Mommy, some more. Cut another finger,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Petrosyan </PERSON> remembers her daughter saying. The woman made more cuts in her flesh, feeling nothing because of the bitter cold. She put her hand to her child's mouth, squeezing her fingers to make more blood come. `` I knew I was going to die,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Petrosyan </PERSON> said. `` But I wanted my daughter to live.'' Many stories of courage have emerged from the earthquake in <LOCATION> Armenia </LOCATION>, but few, if any, are as touching or harrowing as the tale <PERSON> Susanna </PERSON> <PERSON> Petrosyan </PERSON> told this week in a soft voice from her <LOCATION> Yerevan </LOCATION> hospital bed. Around 11:30 a.m. on the day of the quake, she said the two were driven by Mrs. <PERSON> Petrosyan </PERSON>'s husband, <PERSON> Gerkham </PERSON>, a shoemaker, to the apartment building on <LOCATION> Leninakan </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Kamo </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Street </LOCATION> where <PERSON> Karine </PERSON> lived. Mrs. <PERSON> Petrosyan </PERSON>, a petite woman with thick black hair and curving eyebrows, wanted to try on a black dress with puffed shoulders that <PERSON> Karine </PERSON> had for sale. It fit her perfectly. As she took it off at 11:41 a.m., the fifth-floor apartment began to tremble, then shake violently. Dressed only in a slip and her underwear, she grabbed <PERSON> Gayaney </PERSON>, wearing a heavy winter sweater, and ran to the door. Then the floor opened up and the 36-unit building collapsed. The three fell into the basement, with the nine-story building crumbling around them. Although trapped on her back, Mrs. <PERSON> Petrosyan </PERSON> found a 1 -LCB- - pound jar of blackberry jam that had fallen to the basement from <PERSON> Karine </PERSON>'s On the second day of their captivity _ the day <PERSON> Karine </PERSON> died of her injuries _ she gave the entire jar to <LOCATION> Gayaney </LOCATION> to eat. Mrs. <PERSON> Petrosyan </PERSON> said she found a skirt, perhaps the one she had tried on, and made a bed for <LOCATION> Gayaney </LOCATION> to lie on. Despite the bitter cold, she took off her stockings, and wrapped them around her daughter to keep her warm.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>MORE</NOTE>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881229-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-29-88 0120EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Quake-Survivors-1stAdd     12-29 0618</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Quake-Survivors - 1st Add,0636</SECOND>
<HEAD>YEREVAN: her warm.</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 As the days passed, and <PERSON> Gayaney </PERSON>'s pleas for something to drink become more pressing, her mother remembered something she had seen on television. `` It was a program about an explorer in the Arctic who was dying of thirst. His comrade slashed open his hand and gave his friend his blood,'' she said. Losing track of time because of the unchanging darkness, Mrs. <PERSON> Petrosyan </PERSON> does n't know what day she cut open her fingers, or how many times she used the method to feed her daughter. Her thoughts wandered. She saw scenes of her life pass before her eyes, and she hallucinated. `` When I closed my eyes and opened them again, I could see boxes full of apples and bottles of lemonade,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Petrosyan </PERSON> recalled. `` I told my daughter, ` My child, there are so many things to eat and drink.' But when I reached out to touch them, they were gone.'' <PERSON> Gayaney </PERSON> cried that she wanted to go home. `` I want to be back in my bed again, and see my daddy,'' she said. `` I lost all hope,'' the mother said. `` I was just waiting for death.'' On Dec. 14, the eighth day of their captivity, rescue workers opened a small hole that let in a shaft of light. `` We're saved!'' Mrs. <PERSON> Petrosyan </PERSON> cried. `` There's a child in here, be careful not to hurt her!'' she screamed as they got closer. Her husband, a shoemaker, was uninjured by the quake. He was with the rescuers and the two tearfully embraced. Mrs. <PERSON> Petrosyan </PERSON> was placed on a stretcher. Mother and daughter were flown to <LOCATION> Yerevan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Armenia </LOCATION>'s capital, 60 miles away. <PERSON> Gayaney </PERSON> was taken to Children's Hospital No. 3, Mrs. <PERSON> Petrosyan </PERSON> to the Armenian national hospital. <PERSON> Gayaney </PERSON> was in intensive care for four days, hooked up to intravenous bottles that dripped liquids into her parched body. Her temperature was dangerously low, her blood alarmingly thick and she was in shock, said Dr. <PERSON> Silva </PERSON> <PERSON> Nersesyan </PERSON>, her physician. The girl also was in a deep state of depression, and would n't talk or smile. Mrs. <PERSON> Petroysan </PERSON>, also dehydrated, was given intravenous fluids and placed in a coffin-like box so that pressurized oxygen could be pumped around her as a treatment against exposure. It was then that doctors discovered that the woman, who also has a 7-year-old son who was not hurt in the earthquake, is two months' pregnant Doctors say both mother and daughter could be released from their hospitals in as little as a week, but differ about whether Mrs. <PERSON> Petrosyan </PERSON>'s blood helped keep <PERSON> Gayaney </PERSON> alive. `` For a child, the concentration of liquids in the body is much more important than for an adult,'' <PERSON> Nersesyan </PERSON> said. `` For <PERSON> Gayaney </PERSON>, her mother's blood played an important, perhaps decisive role.'' Dr. <PERSON> Ripsime </PERSON> <PERSON> Parsadanyan </PERSON>, who treated Mrs. <PERSON> Petrosyan </PERSON>, disagrees. `` <PERSON> Susanna </PERSON> lost a very little, even insignificant amount of blood. What saved them was that they were together. The mother did n't have time to panic. She had to think of her child.'' <PERSON> Gayaney </PERSON> is still weak and has a light case of pneumonia. But the girl with the big, dark eyes has started to talk again and to smile. In her hospital bed, she strings colored yarn through cardboard dolls and plays with a teddy bear _ Christmas gifts that <PERSON> Jeb </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, the son of President-elect <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, gave her when he visited the hospital Sunday. <PERSON> Gayaney </PERSON> is too young to understand what happened to her the day she was buried alive. `` Bad people pulled down the house where we were, and we could n't get out,'' she said `` I wanted my father to come and defend us from those bad people. But he did n't come. Not for a long time.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881229-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-29-88 0121EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-China-Dissent     12-29 0767</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-China-Dissent,0790</SECOND>
<HEAD>One Man Launches Crusade For Democracy</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By KATHY WILHELM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 As <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> enjoys a marked thaw in restrictions on cultural debate, an intense, voluble man with no political stature and little fame has launched a one-man crusade to open up debate on democracy and communist rule. Sexual themes now can be portrayed on canvas and the screen, and economists can question the wisdom of state ownership of factories. But suggestions for limits to the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>'s power are an invitation for arrest. <PERSON> Ren </PERSON> <PERSON> Wanding </PERSON>, a thin, shaggy-haired accountant who rarely laughs, knows it. He spent 1979-83 in prison for having advocated multiparty democracy, and after a long silence renewed his call last month with an open letter to the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Human </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rights </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> and a 22-page essay on freedom. This week, he began distributing among foreign journalists four new essays denouncing the ruling <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> as a narrow-minded bully and appealing to the world at large to show concern for human rights in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>. `` If one just thinks about things and does n't have the freedom to speak out, then there's no freedom,'' <PERSON> Ren </PERSON> wrote in one essay, explaining his motivation. Aware that his own arrest now would prove the point, <PERSON> Ren </PERSON> wrote in another, `` I appeal to the power of international society for protection.'' <PERSON> Ren </PERSON>, an accountant, said in an interview that he spends most of his non-working hours writing essays and plans to distribute batches of them each month to foreign and <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> media. He said he does not expect to persuade the government to change, but wants to stimulate public debate and make <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s political prisoners better known abroad, as are the dissidents in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Ren </PERSON> also is indignant that, as <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> celebrates the 10th anniversary of its opening to the outside world and economic reform under senior leader <PERSON> Deng </PERSON> <PERSON> Xiaoping </PERSON>, activists who advocated many of the same reforms remain in jail. Those jailed, like himself, were leaders of the 1978-79 Democracy Wall Movement. During those few heady months, intellectuals debated politics in home-mimeographed journals and posters pasted on a wall in central <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>, dubbed Democracy Wall. <PERSON> Ren </PERSON> insisted they had an impact, despite their eventual silencing. `` If one says that <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> society has progressed over 10 years and the economy has grown greatly, all of this is because Chinese social reformers paid the painful price of sacrificing their freedom and fortune,'' he wrote. `` Without their brave spirit, could Chinese have as much freedom of discussion and modernization as they have today? Would the ruling authorities have voluntarily granted this?'' Such Democracy Wall themes as the need for multicandidate elections, greater contact with the outside world and policies to end <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s backwardness have since been adopted by the government. `` Where then is the crime?'' <PERSON> Ren </PERSON> wrote. Despite thick glasses and a solemn manner, <PERSON> Ren </PERSON> looks younger than his 44 years. His work at as an accountant at a <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> equipment installation company is not demanding, he said, but he has been given no chances for promotion. Officials have refused to transfer his wife's residence permit from <LOCATION> Tianjin </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>, 75 miles away. She lives illegally in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> with him, making it impossible for her to find work. <PERSON> Ren </PERSON> said he has not told his 12-year-old daughter that he was in prison. His essays are closely argued outpourings of personal frustration and outraged principles. In one, he denounced communist authorities as `` narrow-minded ... They fear the general public but bully small groups of people.'' He also denounced the practice of bypassing the courts for misdemeanor cases and allowing police to hand out sentences for `` labor education.'' `` There is no way to appeal in court, and covzr-ups, false arrests and illegalities are hidden,'' he wrote. `` Why does n't <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> even respect its own regulations?'' <PERSON> Ren </PERSON>, who never was tried, was ordered to undergo labor education but actually spent his four years in jail `` without labor and without education,'' he said. Newly emerged from his long silence and without a wall or journal to proclaim his views, <PERSON> Ren </PERSON> seems uncertain how to proceed. He said he has no plans to go to campuses and address <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s most volatile and receptive sector _ the students _ or to start up a publication. So far, neither his employers nor police have questioned him about his new political activity. `` I'm not alone. Many people agree with me,'' he said. But he is at a loss to explain why he is the only one stepping into the dangerous limelight. `` I've always been a free-thinker,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881229-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-29-88 0123EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-US-Trade Bjt   12-29 0898</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-US-Trade, Bjt,880</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHINGTON TODAY: Bush Has Powerful Weapon To Negotiate Trade
Accords</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CARL HARTMAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A little-known deal between the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> should make it easier for President-elect <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> to reach agreements with the rest of the world on tough trade issues such as the current dispute over hormones in <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> beef. Beginning Sunday, the 12 countries of the European Economic Community are banning all imports of meat treated with hormones _ including <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> beef and veal worth about $ 100 million a year. The <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration promised to retaliate by raising duties on European food shipped here. Counterretaliations and counter-counterretaliations are threatened, in what some see as a potential trade war. Over the long run such conflicts can be limited by the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> using the `` fast track'' for making trade agreements. A series of agreements is being drafted by 96 governments in the current `` <LOCATION> Uruguay </LOCATION> round'' of trade talks. Despite its name, the fast track is less important for its speed than for the power its gives the president. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> signed the latest version into law last August as part of a major trade bill. On Wednesday he issued an executive order on regulations to implement the new law. It associates key members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> closely with trade talks, though not as actual negotiators. After an agreement is reached, <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> is pledged to vote it up or down in 90 days _ no exceptions or conditions, no internal bargaining over details. That differs from the usual relations between the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and <LOCATION> Capitol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION>. Often the administration and <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> bargain for months or even years over what goes into an important bill before it becomes law _ or fails. The fast track allows the administration to make promises that are bound to be unpopular in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, such as ending protection for a small industry against foreign competition. Under the fast track system the negotiators can gamble that <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> will accept the entire agreement, even if many members dislike parts of it. Governments of other countries long have complained that they can not get firm commitments from a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> negotiator. They can make firm promises themselves because the French or Japanese prime ministers, for example, can threaten to dissolve parliament and force members to fight a new election unless his promises are supported. A <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> president ca n't do that. <PERSON> Raymond </PERSON> <PERSON> Vernon </PERSON>, who negotiated for presidents from <LOCATION> Franklin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Roosevelt </LOCATION> to <PERSON> Jimmy </PERSON> <PERSON> Carter </PERSON>, tells a story about <PERSON> Lord </PERSON> <PERSON> Keynes </PERSON>, the famous economist who came to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> to get more aid for <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> in World War II. <PERSON> Keynes </PERSON> was annoyed to hear one official after another explain how <PERSON> Roosevelt </PERSON> favored many measures but <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> would not approve them. <PERSON> Keynes </PERSON> dropped his usual politeness when one American, more pompous than the others, began by saying: `` My government _ `` `` You know,'' Kenyes interrupted, `` you people do n't really have a government at all, in the usual sense of the word.'' Many officials, Americans and non-Americans, fail to grasp the difference between the American system and the parliamentary system. Non-Americans often complain that the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has gone back on a pledge when a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> negotiator promises his best effort to get something done and then <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> _ not operating on the fast track _ refuses to do it. Some blamed President <PERSON> Woodrow </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> for World War II because he negotiated for a League of Nations after World War I and <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> refused to join it. <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> failed to bring key senators close to the negotiations. <PERSON> Vernon </PERSON> identified the inventor of the fast track as <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Rivers </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> lawyer who worked for the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Finance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> in 1973. President <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> was trying to negotiate what was first called the `` <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> round'' of trade agreements. The White House asked <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> for a law that would give him almost unlimited power to negotiate, but allow either house to disapprove the result. <PERSON> Rivers </PERSON> said in an interview that he will always remember former Sen. <PERSON> Herman </PERSON> <PERSON> Talmadge </PERSON>, D-Ga., a key member of the <ORGANIZATION> Finance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, fiery reaction to that proposal: `` That's not the way we make our laws in this country. The <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> since has ruled that such `` legislative vetoes'' are unconstitutional. <PERSON> Rivers </PERSON> wrote a memorandum that devised the fast track for <PERSON> Talmadge </PERSON> and it became law as part of the president's authority to negotiate. It was used under <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> and President Ford to complete what became known as the `` <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION> round'' after <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> resigned. Later versions of the fast track have been used under <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> to negotiate free trade agreements with <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>. In a recent book, `` Beyond Globalism,'' <PERSON> Vernon </PERSON> has proposed widening it. `` There is a strong temptation to look for a mechanism in which the main lines of trade policy, monetary policy, fiscal policy and establishment policy will have been jointly explored between the branches in an effort to identify the key assumptions, establish the principal goals and iron out the gross inconsistencies,'' he wrote. But he added that it is difficult to envision an effective dialogue between the president and <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> on so wide a range of issues. <PERSON> Vernon </PERSON>, 75 years old, has retired as a professor of international relations at <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. His book was written with <PERSON> Debora </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Spar </PERSON>, who was studying for a doctorate there.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Carl </PERSON> <PERSON> Hartman </PERSON> covers international economics for The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881229-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-29-88 0125EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FarmScene     12-29 0902</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Farm Scene,880</SECOND>
<HEAD>Ag Officials Worry That Low Soil Moisture Will Hurt 1989 Harvest</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DON KENDALL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Farm Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 It will be months before the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> begins to estimate the size of 1989 farm crops, but analysts are watching carefully how weather and conditions shape up. Effects of the savage 1988 drought and moisture-sapping heat are still being felt in Corn Belt areas badly deficient in subsoil moisture. Corn and soybeans wo n't be planted until spring, so there's some leeway. But for winter wheat farmers who planted their 1989 crop this fall, the crunch is on right now. And in parts of the <LOCATION> Great </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Plains </LOCATION> the news is far from encouraging. `` Winter wheat fields in <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> continued to show signs of moisture stress,'' the government's Joint Agricultural Weather Facility said Wednesday. `` Greenbug infestation was a continuing problem.'' <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> farmers have been spraying to control the greenbugs, and much of the winter wheat crop in the state also is hurting from lack of moisture. In <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION>, the wheat crop was in `` mostly good'' condition during the week of Dec. 19-25, but more snow cover was needed, the report said. <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION>'s winter wheat was reported in `` mostly fair to good'' shape, and the <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION> crop was said to be in `` mostly good'' condition, although <LOCATION> Russian </LOCATION> wheat aphids continued to be a problem in the eastern part of the state. The farm weather facility is operated by the Agriculture and Commerce departments. On Jan. 13 the <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> will issue a report showing how many acres of winter wheat farmers planted for the 1989 harvest, and there will be `` projections'' of potential harvest output based on past trends, weather indications and other factors. However, the department's first official 1989 winter wheat production estimate will not be ready until May Meanwhile, reports such as the one issued by <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> are sifted carefully by trading interests and others for signs of what the future may bring. Some other observations in Wednesday's report included: _ The <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> cotton harvest was 97 percent complete by Christmas, 14 percentage points ahead of the five-year average for this time of the season _ Peanut harvesting in <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> was virtually complete _ <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>'s soybean harvest was about 96 percent complete _ Tobacco bed preparation continued in the South In <LOCATION> Kentucky </LOCATION>, recent rains brought burley tobacco into `` case,'' and stripping resumed. _ <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>'s citrus groves were in `` mostly good'' condition, although lack of rain forced producers to irrigate in most areas The vegetable harvests were under way, mainly tomatoes, peppers, celery and cucumbers. _ In <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION>, harvesting included lettuce, cauliflower, cabbage and carrots In <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, rain and cool weather slowed vegetable planting and harvesting. _ Pastures in the South were in `` mostly good to fair'' condition, and livestock was reported mostly in good shape Snow and cold temperatures increased livestock stress in <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> says the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> has continued its corn-buying splurge and has added some soybean meal, making up for some orders it had canceled recently. Officials said Wednesday the new sales included 600,000 metric tons of corn and 600,000 tons of soybean meal. The cancellations earlier in the month had totaled more than 300,000 tons. In a separate announcement, <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> said <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> has bought an additional 200,000 tons of wheat at subsidized prices, part of 1 million tons authorized for <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> on Dec. 7. Only 10,000 tons remain in that authorization. The latest sales of corn to the <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION> brought the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>'s total to 9.63 million tons in the agreement's sixth year, which began Oct. 1. Last year, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> corn sales to the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> totaled slightly less than 5.2 million tons. A metric ton is about 2,205 pounds and is equal to 39.4 bushels of corn or 36.7 bushels of wheat or soybeans. The 600,000 tons of corn would be about 23.6 million bushels. Corn prices have been averaging about $ 2.63 per bushel at the farm level, according to <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> estimates, meaning the latest sale could have a farm value of around $ 62 million. The soybean meal, based on recent <LOCATION> Decatur </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ill. </LOCATION>, prices, could have a processor value of around $ 144 million. Although no wheat has yet been sold for 1988-89 delivery under the pact, the Soviets have ordered 500,000 tons of soybeans and 1,132,500 tons of soybean meal, plus 500,000 tons of grain sorghum.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> has proposed to reduce import restrictions on shipments of British swine, pork and pork products. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Glosser </PERSON>, administrator of the department's <ORGANIZATION> Animal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Plant </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inspection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>, said Wednesday the proposal is a result of <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s eradication of hog cholera, a contagious and sometimes fatal disease of swine. He said no cases of the disease have been reported since August 1987. The restriction currently requires that pork and pork products be cooked, heated or cured and dried before being shipped from <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> to ensure that disease organisms were destroyed. Under the proposed rule change, small quantities of untreated pork and pork products for personal consumption will be allowed to enter the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> from <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>. However, commercial shipments must orginate only from plants which meet <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> requirements. <PERSON> Glosser </PERSON> said the proposal would affect some <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> swine producers who have expressed a desire to import swine breeding stock or semen from <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>. However, he said, these expected shipments `` would not have an impact on <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> swine production.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881229-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-29-88 0127EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-BaseClosings-Background     12-29 0538</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Base Closings-Background,510</SECOND>
<HEAD>Base-Closing Panel Grew Out of Grace Commission Report</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Base Closings Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TIM AHERN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The presidential panel charged with the task of recommending which military bases to close was conceived in a 1983 report by a group of private businessmen on how the government could save money. That 1983 group, headed by industrialist <ORGANIZATION> W.R. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Grace </ORGANIZATION>, proposed a non-partisan commission to review the nation's base structure and suggest which should be shut down. The idea was to take <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> out of the picture as much as possible because of the reluctance on <LOCATION> Capitol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION> to permit bases to be closed. Shuttered installations mean lost jobs among voters, and <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> has blocked any base closings since 1977. The Grace panel's proposal was received unenthusiastically in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, but in 1987, Rep. <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Armey </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Texas </LOCATION>, tried to win approval for the commission. His amendment to a <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> budget bill failed by seven votes. <PERSON> Armey </PERSON> was undaunted and spent much of the following winter rounding up support. With <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> under pressure to cut federal spending because of rising budget deficits, there were predictions that closing unneeded bases could save as much as $ 5 billion a year. <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Carlucci </PERSON> signed on to the <PERSON> Armey </PERSON> plan and appointed a commission last summer to begin work. But <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> delayed final approval until early October, shortly before adjourning for the year. The measure passed by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and signed into law by President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> created a 12-member commission and a complicated procedure designed by <PERSON> Armey </PERSON> and other supporters of closing bases as a way to circumvent congressional pressure. Once <PERSON> Carlucci </PERSON> has received the panel's recommendations, he will have until Jan. 15 _ five days before he leaves office _ to either accept or reject the entire list. <PERSON> Carlucci </PERSON> can not pick from among the list, which is expected to recommend closing two dozen or more of the nation's largest facilities. If <PERSON> Carlucci </PERSON> approves the list, <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> will have 45 legislative days, starting March 1, to try to block it. For that to happen, both the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> would have to pass a disapproval resolution, but that could be vetoed by <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. That means the resolution would need the two-thirds support in each chamber required to override a veto. The base-closing commission has grouped all installations by military mission, such as <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> fighter bases and <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> ports for surface ships. Then, five factors will be used to define a facility's military value, including: _ How well a base can fulfill its purpose for deployment of troops _ Availability of physical facilities, including runways, storage areas and warehouses _ The physical condition and technical sophistication of those facilities _ Quality of life for personnel and their families at the base _ Community support, including transportation, utilities, related industrial activities and technical help Bases within a certain group, such as <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> fighter bases, were ranked using those five criteria. Lower-ranking bases were considered for closure if higher-ranking facilities could take over their duties. Other factors also were considered, including cost evaluations of the money to be saved by closing a particular base, environmental factors such as disposal of hazardous waste, and the impact on the community of lost jobs.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881229-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-29-88 0132EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Bush-Pintlala     12-29 0578</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bush-Pintlala,590</SECOND>
<HEAD>President-Elect Drops Line Near Historic Rural Site</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KENDAL WEAVER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PINTLALA, Ala. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President-elect <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s bass fishing excursion today takes him to a crossroads community that once played host to another vice president _ <PERSON> Aaron </PERSON> <PERSON> Burr </PERSON>. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s itinerary calls for about four hours of fishing with prominent <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION> sportsman <PERSON> Ray </PERSON> <PERSON> Scott </PERSON>, whose 55-acre private lake is set in rolling countryside about 15 miles south of <LOCATION> Montgomery </LOCATION>. `` We just want to get in some fishing,'' said <PERSON> Scott </PERSON>, who became a friend, political ally and infrequent fishing partner of <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> in 1978. `` His fishing is so token, he does n't have a chance to get at it much.'' <PERSON> Scott </PERSON>, who founded the <ORGANIZATION> Bass </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Anglers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sportsman </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION> two decades ago and sold the publishing enterprise for $ 15 million in 1986, is an outspoken conservationist who predicts <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> will rival <PERSON> Teddy </PERSON> <PERSON> Roosevelt </PERSON> in supporting <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s outdoors. `` He feels we've spent enough money on research ... and it's time for action,'' said <PERSON> Scott </PERSON> in an interview. `` He'll be reasonable but firm'' in protecting the environment. <PERSON> Scott </PERSON>, who got a Thanksgiving Day call from <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> to arrange the bass fishing outing, has brought attention to a farm community that is composed mainly of a small elementary school, a library, a fire station and <PERSON> Mosley </PERSON>'s store and service station at the junction of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> 31 and Federal Road. <PERSON> Scott </PERSON>, who also has a whitetail deer research program on his land, enjoys talking about the legends of <LOCATION> Pintlala </LOCATION>, including visits made by White House figures prior to <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. He said the old Federal Road that crossed through <LOCATION> Pintlala </LOCATION> _ a paved portion of which now runs in front of <PERSON> Scott </PERSON>'s gate _ was the route taken by Gen. <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> on his way to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION> for the battle of 1812. <PERSON> Scott </PERSON> and historians also say <PERSON> Burr </PERSON>, the vice president who killed <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON> <PERSON> Hamilton </PERSON> in a duel, paid an unplanned visit to <LOCATION> Pintlala </LOCATION> in 1807. <PERSON> Burr </PERSON> was was captured in southwest <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION> on treason charges in Februrary 1807 and was brought up the Federal Road. <PERSON> Scott </PERSON> said <PERSON> Burr </PERSON> spent one night at <ORGANIZATION> Manac </ORGANIZATION>'s Tavern, which was located at a site about a quarter-mile from <PERSON> Scott </PERSON>'s property at <LOCATION> Pintlala </LOCATION>. `` Pintlala is a Creek Indian word that means ` fish swamp.' It once was a heavy <LOCATION> Creek </LOCATION> settlement,'' said <PERSON> Scott </PERSON>. `` Manac's Tavern was owned by <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> <PERSON> Manac </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Creek </LOCATION> with large landholdings ... Manac's son, <PERSON> David </PERSON>, was the first Indian ever to graduate from <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Point </LOCATION>. The news media descended on <PERSON> Mosley </PERSON>'s store and service station in anticipation of <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s visit. `` It's been a three-ring circus around here,'' said <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Meadows </PERSON> as she prepared hot dogs for the lunch crowd Wednesday. <PERSON> Scott </PERSON> said <ORGANIZATION> Secret </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> agents had checked out `` every squirrel nest and deer stand'' on his property. The only overt indication that the president-elect was on his way was a sign outside the <ORGANIZATION> Pintlala </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Baptist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION>. It read: `` Welcome President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. Godspeed and Good Fishing.'' <PERSON> Scott </PERSON>, who remains as a figurehead of the B.A.S.S. operation, plays host at its fishing tournaments, some of which are carried on cable television. <PERSON> Scott </PERSON> said he met <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Montgomery </LOCATION> about 10 years ago and was asked to manage <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s 1980 campaign in <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION>. `` I'm not sure his pickin' was too good, otherwise he would n't have picked me,'' said <PERSON> Scott </PERSON>, recalling their loss to <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> in the state's primary. `` But I'm a good salesman. That's about all politics is anyway,'' he said. `` We just always clicked.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881229-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-29-88 0131EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-OutlawedCarp     12-29 0241</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Outlawed Carp,0247</SECOND>
<HEAD>Trout Farmer Vows To Continue Fight For Grass-Eating Carp</HEAD>
<DATELINE>EGREMONT, Mass. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A trout farmer who lost his fish-breeding license for importing grass-eating carp has vowed to continue his fight to bring the white amur into the state because of its unique way of weeding ponds. State wildlife officials said they dropped criminal charges against <PERSON> Warren </PERSON> <PERSON> Candee </PERSON> because they failed to advise the breeder of his constitutional rights. But the 75-year-old <PERSON> Candee </PERSON> is unrepentant. `` God made these fish and if he made them to eat weeds, why should we use chemicals to pollute our water systems?'' he said. The chairman of the state Division of <ORGANIZATION> Fisheries </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wildlife </ORGANIZATION> said the agency has banned the fish and all other non-native wildlife because their long-term effects on the environment are unknown. `` Mr. <PERSON> Candee </PERSON> certainly is n't a marine biologist, nor is his lawyer,'' <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Darey </PERSON> said Tuesday. `` Until we're 100 percent sure that they wo n't have any negative effects on the environment, we will not turn these fish loose.'' <PERSON> Candee </PERSON> said he imported the fish from <LOCATION> Arkansas </LOCATION> and kept them in a cement pond behind his house. The fish are native to the <LOCATION> Amur </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION>, which flows along the boarder of the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Darey </PERSON> said he is awaiting the findings of a four-year study conducted by the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conservation </ORGANIZATION> to determine whether <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> should continue its ban against the fish.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881229-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-29-88 0133EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Reagan     12-29 0522</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Reagan,510</SECOND>
<HEAD>U.S. Official Says New 12-Mile Offshore Limit Will Help Deter Spies</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDs: Reagan departure scheduled for 6:35 p.m. EST. No tops planned</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By W. DALE NELSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s decision to extend <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> territorial waters an additional nine miles offshore will make it more difficult for foreign countries to spy on <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> shores, administration officials say. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> took the action Wednesday at the Bel Air home where he will live after Jan. 20. He and first lady <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> are spending the holidays there, but were leaving today for three days in <LOCATION> Palm </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Springs </LOCATION>. By a proclamation, the president extended <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> `` sovereignty and jurisdiction'' from the present three miles to 12 miles. <PERSON> Maureen </PERSON> <PERSON> Walker </PERSON>, a foreign affairs officer in the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ocean </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Law </ORGANIZATION> and Policy, said the extension makes the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> the 105th country to claim a 12-mile limit. The 12-mile limit was called for in 1982 by the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Convention </ORGANIZATION> on the Law of the Sea, and the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> action leaves only six countries claiming narrower bands of offshore water. <LOCATION> Finland </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Norway </LOCATION> claim four miles each, and the <LOCATION> Dominican </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Republic </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Greece </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Turkey </LOCATION> each claim six miles, Ms. <PERSON> Walker </PERSON> said. `` It will make foreign intelligence-gathering more difficult and less effective because foreign ships will no longer be able to station themselves off our shores within the 12-mile limit,'' the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> officer said. The proclamation assures foreign ships the right of `` innocent passage'' through <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> territorial waters and the right to pass through straits. Ms. <PERSON> Walker </PERSON> said it would not affect <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and state laws that govern offshore mineral and fishing rights. It applies to the waters off the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Puerto </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rico </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Guam </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Samoa </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virgin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Islands </LOCATION>, the Northern Mariana islands and any other territory over which the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> exercises sovereignty. It applies to airspace over the ocean, as well as the waters and the bed and subsoil of the ocean. In another action, the president extended for six months the state of emergency that he proclaimed in 1986 between the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Libya </LOCATION>. The step was needed to continue in effect the president's 1986 order blocking Libyan assets in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> in retaliation for alleged terrorist action. The president also signed a seven-page executive order implementing the 1,100-page trade act passed by the last <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. White House deputy press secretary <PERSON> Leslye </PERSON> <PERSON> Arsht </PERSON> said the order will enable the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> `` to continue effectively to work for more open world markets and strengthened international institutions.'' Ms. <PERSON> Arsht </PERSON> said the president's national security adviser, Lt. Gen. <PERSON> Colin </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Powell </PERSON>, telephoned him at the Bel Air home to inform him of the announcement by the <ORGANIZATION> British </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transport </ORGANIZATION> that last week's crash of Pan American Flight 103 in <LOCATION> Scotland </LOCATION> was caused by a bomb. `` The investigation will continue to determine how the explosives were introduced into the plane,'' she said. `` The <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> are working closely with the British and Scottish authorities on the investigation. We are determined to find out who did it, using all available resources.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881229-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-29-88 0139EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-PlaneBombings     12-29 0750</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Plane Bombings,750</SECOND>
<HEAD>Pan Am Investigators May Need Lucky Break To Catch Bombers</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-US-Crash Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BARTON REPPERT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Judging by previous crashes in which bombing was suspected, authorities investigating the Pan American Flight 103 disaster may need a lucky break in the case to apprehend those who carried out the sabotage. British authorities said Wednesday that from examining wreckage they had gathered `` conclusive evidence'' that a bomb blew up the <ORGANIZATION> Pan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Am </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> 747 jumbo jet over southern <LOCATION> Scotland </LOCATION> last week. Spokesman <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Boyd </PERSON> said <LOCATION> Scotland </LOCATION> Yard and the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> had joined forces in `` a criminal inquiry of international dimensions.'' The challenge of finding those responsible is illustrated by looking at two crashes widely blamed on bombing: the Nov. 29, 1987, crash of a <ORGANIZATION> Korean </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> 707 off the coast of <LOCATION> Burma </LOCATION> and the plunge of an <ORGANIZATION> Air-India </ORGANIZATION> 747 into the <LOCATION> Irish </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sea </LOCATION> on June 22, 1985. The Korean Air crash killed 115 people, while the <ORGANIZATION> Air-India </ORGANIZATION> tragedy claimed 329 lives. In the incident involving Korean Air Flight 858, suspicion quickly focused on two passengers, a man and a woman, who were detained for questioning about forged Japanese passports in <LOCATION> Bahrain </LOCATION> as they were about to board a plane for <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION>. They had left the doomed Korean aircraft, bound from <LOCATION> Baghdad </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Bangkok </LOCATION>, at an intermediary stop in <LOCATION> Abu </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dhabi </LOCATION>. The pair, who turned out to be <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korean </LOCATION> agents, both bit into cyanide capsules hidden in cigarette filters. The man, identified as <PERSON> Kim </PERSON> <PERSON> Sung </PERSON> <PERSON> Il </PERSON>, 70, succeeded in his suicide attempt, but the woman, <PERSON> Kim </PERSON> <PERSON> Hyon </PERSON> <PERSON> Hui </PERSON>, 25, survived and was extradited to <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>. After questioning by South Korean authorities, Ms. <PERSON> Kim </PERSON> told a nationally televised news conference on Jan. 15, 1988, that she had been involved in bombing the Korean Air jet. She said the episode was intended to disrupt preparations for the 1988 <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION> Olympics and create unrest in the South. `` I came out here hoping such violent, meaningless incidents would never happen again in the future and I would like to apologize to family members of the dead and the people here by disclosing the truth,'' she said in admitting her role in the incident. South Korean intelligence officers said Ms. <PERSON> Kim </PERSON> was acting on the personal orders of <PERSON> Kim </PERSON> <PERSON> Jong </PERSON> <PERSON> Il </PERSON>, son and political heir of top <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korean </LOCATION> leader <PERSON> Kim </PERSON> <PERSON> Il </PERSON> <PERSON> Sung </PERSON>. <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> officially denied involvement with the crash. By contrast, in the crash of <ORGANIZATION> Air-India </ORGANIZATION> Flight 182, lengthy investigations by Indian, Canadian, <LOCATION> British </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Irish </LOCATION> authorities have failed to conclusively pinpoint blame for the tragedy. Soon after the crash, unidentified callers to news media said the crash was the work of extremists associated with Sikh separatist organizations. Spokesmen for <ORGANIZATION> Sikh </ORGANIZATION> groups, however, denied any role and accused <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> of trying to foment anti-Sikh sentiment. According to Indian officials, tapes from the plane's cockpit voice and flight data recorders, recovered from 6,700 feet below the surface of the <LOCATION> Irish </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sea </LOCATION>, neither proved nor disproved the possibility that sabotage was involved. One official, S.N. <PERSON> Sharma </PERSON>, told reporters the cockpit conversation was normal until it came to a `` sudden and abrupt end.'' A report by <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Aviation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION>, disclosed in January 1986, said there was `` considerable circumstantial and other evidence that an explosive device'' detonated in the front cargo compartment of the plane, which was headed from <LOCATION> Toronto </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Bombay </LOCATION> via <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>. The report linked the explosion to a suitcase checked onto the flight by a man using the name <PERSON> Singh </PERSON> who did not board the plane. <PERSON> Singh </PERSON>, meaning lion, is a name used by all male Sikhs. A book published in <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> in May 1987 pointed to the lack of arrests in the Air-India case. `` Among the bereaved families, the call for justice is louder, the bitterness and cynicism sharper than at any time since the crash,'' said the book, `` The Sorrow and the Terror.'' The book by award-winning Canadian writers <PERSON> Clark </PERSON> <PERSON> Blaise </PERSON> and his India-born wife, <PERSON> Bharati </PERSON> <PERSON> Mukherjee </PERSON>, claimed that four members of a Sikh terrorist cell in <LOCATION> Vancouver </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> British </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION>, were suspected by police. It also claimed that the principals in the case celebrated with pizza at a Sikh temple in the <LOCATION> Toronto </LOCATION> suburb of <LOCATION> Malton </LOCATION> at about the time the <ORGANIZATION> Air-India </ORGANIZATION> jet plunged into the sea. The problem is to have a case solid enough to prove in court, the authors said. `` To lose the case on any kind of technicality would be a political nightmare,'' according to the book.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881229-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-29-88 0143EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Homeless     12-29 0622</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Homeless,620</SECOND>
<HEAD>Administration Identifies Public Buildings That Could Shelter
Homeless</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MATT YANCEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Although they may not be available this winter, 44 `` underutilized'' government buildings and 50 land sites have been designated by the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration as suitable for sheltering the nation's homeless. Meeting a court-appointed deadline, the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Housing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Urban </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION> on Thursday ruled that 94 of the 220 pieces of property it reviewed in the past two weeks are suitable for assisting homeless people. However, only 33 of the buildings were determined to be suitable for overnight occupancy or for daytime activities. Another 11 were called suitable only for non-occupancy programs such as warehousing food and clothing. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Schoenberger </PERSON>, deputy assistant <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> secretary for housing, said the unused or underutilized land parcels could be used as sites for erecting mobile homes or modular units as temporary shelters. It is problematic whether any of the facilities might be made available for the homeless before this winter is over. `` This is a multi-stage process and <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> is sort of in the middle of it,'' <PERSON> Schoenberger </PERSON> said. `` But this could be a relatively quick process from this point on.'' Some of the properties could be made available in less than 45 days, <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> officials said, assuming they meet local health and building codes. City and state officials or private, non-profit organizations wanting to use the buildings or land have 30 days to submit applications. The <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Human </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION>, which own the properties, then have a maximum of 15 days to review the applications. <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> was under a Dec. 28 deadline imposed two weeks ago by <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> Judge <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> <PERSON> Gasch </PERSON> here to review at least half of 350 properties listed by <ORGANIZATION> GSA </ORGANIZATION> and HHS as being excess or surplus. He gave <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> until Jan. 12 to survey the rest of the listed properties, which includes some 1,000 buildings. The government defines excess property as buildings or land under the authority of a particular agency that does n't have any use for it. Surplus property is that for which no government agency has any use. Because <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> had only two weeks under <PERSON> Gasch </PERSON>'s order to come up with a list, <PERSON> Schoenberger </PERSON> said the determinations of suitability were made solely on the basis of questionnaires filled out by <ORGANIZATION> GSA </ORGANIZATION> and HHS. `` We originally intended to have <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> field office staff inspect all properties which appeared to be suitable,'' he said. `` However, the short amount of time allowed ... required that we omit the on-site property inspection.'' <PERSON> Gasch </PERSON> imposed the deadlines in response to a suit filed last September by the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coalition </ORGANIZATION> for the Homeless accusing the administration of failing to implement a law passed in July 1987 to make `` underutilized'' federal property available for use as emergency shelters. <PERSON> Maris </PERSON> <PERSON> Foscarinis </PERSON>, an attorney for the coalition, called President-elect <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s support of the program encouraging but said it is `` shameful that the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration forced a protracted court battle before obeying a congressional mandate.'' Of the 126 facilities found unsuitable because they lack sound floors, foundations, roofs, walls, electric power or sanitary or water facilities, 53 are buildings and 73 are land sites. The locations of unused or underutilized federally owned buildings listed as suitable for overnight shelters were listed as: <ORGANIZATION> Bell </ORGANIZATION>, Point Arena, <PERSON> Tracy </PERSON> and <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Waycross </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ga. </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Oxford </LOCATION> and Shoshone, <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION>; <PERSON> Dana </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Ind </LOCATION>.; <LOCATION> Boothville </LOCATION>, La.; <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION>, Md.; <LOCATION> Pontiac </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mich. </LOCATION>; <PERSON> Remer </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Minn. </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Vicksburg </LOCATION>, Miss.; <LOCATION> Tonopah </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Nev. </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Binghamton </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION>; <ORGANIZATION> Smithfield </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> N.C. </LOCATION>; <PERSON> Hauser </PERSON> and <LOCATION> Klamath </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Falls </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ore. </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Phoenixville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Aquadilla </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Juan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Puerto </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rico </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Maryville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Tenn. </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Carrizo </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Springs </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Rockwall </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Antonio </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Arlington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>; <PERSON> Elma </PERSON> and Warden, <LOCATION> Wash. </LOCATION>, and <PERSON> Lander </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Wyo </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881229-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-29-88 0144EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Bush-Gates     12-29 0636</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bush-Gates,630</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush Taps No. 2 CIA Official For Deputy National Security Job</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BRYAN BRUMLEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 President-elect <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has picked No. 2 <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> official <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gates </PERSON> as his deputy national security adviser and is nominating career intelligence analyst <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kerr </PERSON> to replace <PERSON> Gates </PERSON> at the spy agency. Gates `` knows the system, the critical importance of the interagency process for presidential decision-making and the details of the management of that process,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said Wednesday in a statement issued in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> while he was hunting in <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>. Gates gained national attention in the spring of 1987, when President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> nominated him to succeed the late <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Casey </PERSON> as director of central intelligence. Furor over the Iran-Contra affair delayed <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> confirmation of the nomination, and <PERSON> Gates </PERSON> asked that his name be withdrawn in March 1987. <PERSON> Gates </PERSON> has denied consistently that he tried to cover up the <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> role in the <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> arms deal, and he has kept a high reputation among intelligence experts on <LOCATION> Capitol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION>. The vice-chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Intelligence </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, Sen. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Cohen </PERSON>, R-Me., said Wednesday that <PERSON> Gates </PERSON> `` brings a tremendous reservoir of talent'' to the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> staff <PERSON> Cohen </PERSON>, in a statement issued through a spokeswoman, called <PERSON> Gates </PERSON> `` an outstanding choice. <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Gates </PERSON> is a loss for the intelligence agency and a gain for the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>.'' <PERSON> Gates </PERSON> would serve as deputy to <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s designated national security adviser, retired <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> Gen. <PERSON> Brent </PERSON> <PERSON> Scowcroft </PERSON>. Now, Lt. Col. <PERSON> Colin </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Powell </PERSON> is national security adviser and <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Negroponte </PERSON> is his deputy. Gates' appointment is not subject to <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> confirmation; that of <PERSON> Kerr </PERSON> as deputy to <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> Director <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Webster </PERSON> is subject to hearings by the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> intelligence panel and a two-thirds vote of the full <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>. Had Gates been confirmed as director of central intelligence, he would have been the first <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> analyst to have attained that post. Previous <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> directors either have served in the spy agency's clandestine service or have come from outside, like <PERSON> Webster </PERSON> or <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, who was <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> chief in 1976 <PERSON> Kerr </PERSON> has spent his career as a <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> analyst and administrator. <PERSON> Webster </PERSON> said the appointment of <PERSON> Gates </PERSON> `` is tribute to him and a vote of confidence for the agency. While we will miss him here, his appointment is a real plus for the national security of this country.'' <PERSON> Kerr </PERSON> is `` a highly qualified <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> career officer ...,'' said <PERSON> Webster </PERSON>. `` As deputy director for intelligence, heading up the analytical side of the agency, <PERSON> Kerr </PERSON> is my principal adviser on the production of finished intelligence, and is widely respected throughout the intelligence community.'' The Kerr selection also won praise on <LOCATION> Capitol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION>. `` <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Kerr </PERSON>'s appointment sends a message that the new administration is recognizing professional excellence in selecting top officials in the intelligence area,'' said Sen. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Boren </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Okla </LOCATION>., chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Intelligence </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> <PERSON> Gates </PERSON>, 45, has served with the <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> for 22 years, including a five-year loan from 1974-79 to the <ORGANIZATION> NSC </ORGANIZATION> staff. He was raised in <LOCATION> Wichita </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Kan. </LOCATION>, where he earned straight A's in high school and was an Eagle Scout. He received a bachelor's degree from <PERSON> William </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> Mary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> in 1965, a master's degree from <ORGANIZATION> Indiana </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> in 1966 and a doctorate in Russian history from <ORGANIZATION> Georgetown </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> in 1974. <PERSON> Gates </PERSON> was deputy director for intelligence for more than four years, and according to one intelligence source greatly improved the quality of <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> reports. <PERSON> Kerr </PERSON>, 53, joined the <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> as a military analyst in 1960, concentrating on biographical and reference material relating to the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. According to a biography released by the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> transition office, <PERSON> Kerr </PERSON> also has worked as an imagery analyst, apparently scrutinizing satellite photographs. <PERSON> Kerr </PERSON> received a bachelor's degree in history and did some graduate work at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Oregon </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881229-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-29-88 0146EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-PentagonProbe     12-29 0693</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Pentagon Probe,690</SECOND>
<HEAD>Document Points To Alleged Fraud, Bribery By Air Force Official</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DEBORAH MESCE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Wiretaps on the telephones of a defense consultant and bugging devices in his office have helped investigators paint a picture of alleged contract fraud and bribery involving a top <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> procurement official, according to a government affidavit. The eavesdropping on conversations between <PERSON> Victor </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Cohen </PERSON>, a deputy to the assistant <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> secretary for acquisitions, and consultant <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Galvin </PERSON> showed that <PERSON> Cohen </PERSON> `` has used his official position'' to help <PERSON> Galvin </PERSON> or his clients in exchange for `` payments and other gratuities,'' the document says. One example outlined in the affidavit involves <ORGANIZATION> Cubic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Diego </LOCATION>, a client of <PERSON> Galvin </PERSON> and maker of shells that house electronic gear, called pods. Sometime before April 1, 1987, when <PERSON> Galvin </PERSON>'s phones were tapped, <PERSON> Galvin </PERSON> asked <PERSON> Cohen </PERSON> to award an unidentified pod contract to Cubic on a sole-source basis so that Cubic would be the only supplier, the document says In a tapped phone conversation May 15, 1987, <PERSON> Cohen </PERSON> told <PERSON> Galvin </PERSON> he would n't award the contract to Cubic as a sole source. But he said he planned to have the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> issue the request for proposal with a required delivery schedule that Cubic's competitor could not meet, the affidavit says. `` <PERSON> Cohen </PERSON> assured <PERSON> Galvin </PERSON> that by doing it this way, the procurement would appear to have been completed when, in actuality, Cubic would be guaranteed the award of the contract,'' the document said. <PERSON> Cohen </PERSON> also said he would have the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> exercise an option on a joint Air Force-Navy project being built by Cubic's competitor. This way, <PERSON> Cohen </PERSON> assured <PERSON> Galvin </PERSON>, the competitor would not protest the delivery schedule and he would not have to justify a sole source procurement, the document says. However, <PERSON> Colvin </PERSON> <PERSON> Wellborn </PERSON>, president of Cubic, did n't like the plan. <PERSON> Wellborn </PERSON> told <PERSON> Galvin </PERSON> in a phone conversation May 21, 1987, there was adequate justification for giving Cubic the contract as a sole source and `` he saw no reason to do a ` crooked' competition,'' the affidavit said. The document says that later that day <PERSON> Galvin </PERSON> told <PERSON> Wellborn </PERSON> that <PERSON> Cohen </PERSON> had changed his mind and the contract would be given to Cubic as a sole source. The $ 9.8 million contract was awarded to Cubic in December 1987. The affidavit, which was used to justify a search last June of <PERSON> Cohen </PERSON>'s home in <LOCATION> Potomac </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Md. </LOCATION>, does not tie a specific payment from Cubic or <PERSON> Galvin </PERSON> to <PERSON> Cohen </PERSON> for that contract or for other contracts mentioned. However, the document alleged that `` <PERSON> Cohen </PERSON>'s willingness to assist Cubic in obtaining government contracts can be traced to what is believed to be the receipt of a payment from Cubic.'' The section in the affidavit that follows that statement was deleted, as were other parts of the document at the request of the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> attorney's office The affidavit also says that <PERSON> Cohen </PERSON> appears to have been paid by <PERSON> Galvin </PERSON> and two of his other clients _ <ORGANIZATION> Unisys </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Loral </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Electronic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Systems </ORGANIZATION> Division. A receptionist in <PERSON> Cohen </PERSON>'s office said he was `` on leave'' and could not be reached for comment. His home telephone number is unpublished. Cubic and <ORGANIZATION> Loral </ORGANIZATION> are closed for the holidays and officials could not be reached for comment. <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> F.C </PERSON>. <PERSON> Ruff </PERSON>, an attorney for <ORGANIZATION> Unisys </ORGANIZATION>, said he had no comment. The Cohen affidavit and portions of two others were released on Tuesday in response to a lawsuit by The <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION>. A hearing is scheduled for Friday to determine whether portions of the affidavits that were deleted should also be unsealed. The other two affidavits supported searches of the <LOCATION> Berwyn </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Heights </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Md. </LOCATION>, house of <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Seelmeyer </PERSON>, a self-employed consultant, and the <LOCATION> Rockville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Md. </LOCATION>, home and office of consultant <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Sanda </PERSON>. These locations along with <PERSON> Cohen </PERSON>'s home were among 40 locations raided by <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> agents last June, when the case was first revealed. No indictments have been handed down. Prosecutors have said they have evidence that consultants, including some former top <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> officials who worked for the nation's largest defense contractors, bribed <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> officials for information that helped them win billions of dollars in government contracts.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881229-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-29-88 0146EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-PlasticExplosives     12-29 0625</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Plastic Explosives,600</SECOND>
<HEAD>Odorless Explosive Semtex Called Terrorists' Dream</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-US-Crash Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RUTH SINAI</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 When <PERSON> Nezar </PERSON> <PERSON> Hindawi </PERSON> wanted to blow up an Israeli plane in 1986, he packed his girlfriend's suitcase with three pounds of an odorless explosive called Semtex and sent her to <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Heathrow </LOCATION> airport to board an <ORGANIZATION> El </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Al </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> 747 The bomb, which was pre-set to detonate, passed through an airport X-ray machine, and it was discovered only after an <ORGANIZATION> El </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Al </ORGANIZATION> security guard questioned the young woman, <PERSON> Anne-Marie </PERSON> <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON>, who was unaware she was carrying the explosive device. Terrorism experts say Semtex, which is one of the substances suspected in the bombing last week of <ORGANIZATION> Pan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Am </ORGANIZATION> Flight 103 over <LOCATION> Scotland </LOCATION>, is a terrorist's dream. So far, it has defied all detection attempts by X-ray machines, dogs trained to sniff bombs and other devices. `` It's a favorite with these groups because it's significantly harder to detect than anything else _ it's more powerful than other plastics,'' said <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Carver </PERSON>, a senior <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> analyst in the 1960s and 1970s who now is a researcher at the <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Strategic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Studies </ORGANIZATION>, a <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> think tank. Like its American cousin, C-4, Semtex is malleable like putty and shows up on an X-ray operator's screen as an indistinct, dense mass. But unlike C-4 and other known plastic bombs, Semtex is odorless. Semtex also has the advantage of being stable, meaning it can not go off unless it is meant to. Terrorism experts, including <PERSON> Neil </PERSON> <PERSON> Livingstone </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> Georgetown </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, say Semtex is so reliable it has been used by <PERSON> Arab </PERSON> terrorists sending letter bombs to <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> officials. Technology is being developed to overcome the Semtex threat, and two experimental devices are in use at the <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> airports. The devices shoot neutrons which can interact chemically with plastic explosives in luggage and indicate the existence of a bomb. <LOCATION> Czechoslovakia </LOCATION>, which has a well-developed, state-run arms and munitions industry, makes Semtex at a plant called the Eastern Bohemian Works, <PERSON> Livingstone </PERSON> said. <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> officials say they have asked Czech authorities in the past to stop making Semtex or at least to prevent its export. Recently, <LOCATION> Czechoslovakia </LOCATION> indicated it might be willing to stop selling Semtex, said <PERSON> Livingstone </PERSON>, who has served as a consultant to government security and intelligence agencies and has written seven books on international security and terrorism. <LOCATION> Czechoslovakia </LOCATION> is believed to have supplied Semtex to <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Libya </LOCATION>, said one <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> official who spoke on condition of anonymity. In testimony at <PERSON> Hindawi </PERSON>'s 1986 trial, British authorities said <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION> had supplied the bomb for the <ORGANIZATION> El </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Al </ORGANIZATION> plane. The British government subsequently broke off diplomatic relations with <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION> over the affair, although ties later were restored. The <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> official said <LOCATION> Libya </LOCATION> has supplied Semtex in several shiploads of weapons to the <ORGANIZATION> Irish </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> in 1986 and 1987 and may have given it to other terrorist groups. Semtex also is believed to have been used by a tiny <LOCATION> Syrian </LOCATION> - and Libyan-supported Palestinian group once known as the May 15 organization and which is now known as the <PERSON> Hawari </PERSON> group The group is believed to have been responsible for the April 1986 explosion aboard a <ORGANIZATION> TWA </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> 727 flying from <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Athens </LOCATION>. Four Americans were killed in the blast, which Greek investigators said probably was caused by a Semtex bomb the size of two or three cigarette packs. The bomb was placed under a seat in row 10. The <PERSON> Hawari </PERSON> group specializes in plastic bombs, according to <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> counterterrorism experts. One of its operatives, <PERSON> Mohammed </PERSON> <PERSON> Rashid </PERSON>, is being sought by the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> for questioning in the 1982 bombing of a <ORGANIZATION> Pan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Am </ORGANIZATION> jetliner over <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION> which resulted in one death.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881229-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-29-88 0150EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-BombDetector Bjt   12-29 0784</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bomb Detector, Bjt,770</SECOND>
