<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881112-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-12-88 0006EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Reagan-TaxBill     11-12 0364</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Reagan-Tax Bill,360</SECOND>
<HEAD>President Signs Taxpayers' `Bill of Rights'</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> has signed a `` bill of rights'' to protect taxpayers against overzealous tax collectors, but he still must act on bills to put more money into fighting drugs and to authorize the death penalty for some drug kingpins. The tax bill provides $ 4.1 billion in benefits to farmers and other groups. `` After two years of fighting for a bill of rights, the <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> taxpayer can at long last declare victory,'' said Sen. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Pryor </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Ark </LOCATION>. `` For the first time since the <ORGANIZATION> Internal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Revenue </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> was established 124 years ago, <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> has done something for the taxpayer rather than to him.'' <PERSON> Pryor </PERSON>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> IRS </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Oversight </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, was one of the principal architects of the measure, along with Sens. <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> Reid </PERSON>, D-Nev. and <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Grassley </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Iowa </LOCATION>, and Rep. <PERSON> Robin </PERSON> <PERSON> Tallon </PERSON>, D-S The Tax Corrections Act was aimed initially at refining the massive tax overhauls of 1986. The `` bill of rights'' was inserted by lawmakers who wanted to rein in what some said was an overly aggressive IRS. The law requires 30 days' notice before the <ORGANIZATION> IRS </ORGANIZATION> can seize bank accounts and other property. It also prohibits the <ORGANIZATION> IRS </ORGANIZATION> from promoting employees on the basis of how much they collect from taxpayers. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> signed the measure Thursday, and the White House announced the signing Friday without comment. The law will have no effect on the federal deficit. Although it would cut taxes by $ 4.1 billion over three years, it would raise others by the same amount. It orders the government to buy 540 acres bordering the Civil War battlefield at <LOCATION> Manassas </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, where developers wanted to build a shopping mall. Other major provisions: _ Extend expiring tax benefits to help lower-income families buy their first home; reward businesses for increased spending for research and experimentation, and boost incentives for investment in low-income rental housing _ Renew an expired provision that allows workers to exclude as taxable income tuition payments made by their employers; most graduate study would not qualify _ Extend an exclusion for the value of employer-financed legal-service benefits _ Prohibit a business deduction for the basic monthly cost of a home telephone
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881112-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-12-88 0010EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-TaxBill-Glance     11-12 0758</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Tax Bill-Glance,740</SECOND>
<HEAD>With PM-Reagan-Tax Bill</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here, at a glance, are major provisions of a bill signed Friday by President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> designed to clear up confusing language and correct errors in the landmark tax overhaul enacted in 1986. _ BILL OF RIGHTS: A `` taxpayer's bill of rights'' to rein in what some lawmakers view as an overly aggressive <ORGANIZATION> Internal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Revenue </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> For example, the agency would have to give 30 days' notice before seizing bank accounts and other property, and would be prohibited from promoting employees on the basis of how much they collect. _ DIESEL: Wipes out a 1987 requirement that farmers, construction companies and other tax-exempt, off-road users of diesel fuel pay the federal tax of 15.1 cents a gallon and later apply for a refund _ MUTUAL FUNDS: For 1988 and 1989, permit owners of mutual fund shares to deduct certain operating expenses of the fund without regard to a general provision allowing deduction of only miscellaneous expenses that exceed 2 percent of income _ HIGHER EDUCATION: Exempts from taxation interest earned on <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> savings bonds that are redeemed to finance a college or vocational education, starting in 1990 _ TUITION AID: Renews for 1988 an expired law allowing a worker to avoid tax on up to $ 5,250 a year of employer-provided education assistance Graduate education would not qualify. _ HOUSING: Extends through 1989 a tax credit for owners of newly constructed low-income rental housing Also, extends through 1989 and modifies a tax exemption for bonds issued by state and local governments to help low-income families buy their first home. _ TOBACCO: Imposes a tax of 45 cents per pound on pipe tobacco _ WRITERS: Allows free-lance writers, artists and photographers to deduct work-related expenses even before a project produces income _ ` HEIFER TAX': Permits livestock farmers to deduct expenses of producing livestock before the animals begin generating income, thus repealing what has become known as the `` heifer tax.'' _ ATHLETICS: Allows an 80 percent deduction for contributions to college athletic scholarship funds even when such `` gifts'' guarantee a fan the privilege of buying a game ticket _ RESEARCH: Extends through 1989 a credit for increased spending for research and experimentation _ JOB TRAINING: Extends through 1989 a credit under which the government pays the first year of wages for certain newly hired economically disadvantaged workers _ CONTRACTORS: Further restricts the `` completed-contract'' method of accounting that allows defense contractors and most big construction companies to delay taxes on part of their profits until a project is completed This change will raise $ 1.3 billion. _ CORPORATIONS: Accelerate estimated tax payments from corporations that switch from an annualized method of computation, raising $ 869 million _ LIFE INSURANCE: Removes some of the tax advantages of using single-premium life insurance as an investment Loans from such policies would be taxed as cash withdrawals; the new rules would apply to policies whose cash value builds more quickly than one paid through seven equal annual premiums. The change would cost policyholders $ 345 million. _ BUSINESS MEALS: Permit operators of offshore or <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> oil rigs and of some commercial vessels -LRB- but not luxury liners -RRB- to deduct the full cost of meals provided to employees; most business may deduct only 80 percent _ HOME SALE: Allows a surviving spouse to defer taxation on profits from the sale of a principal home, just as though the spouse had not died Present law denies such a break if a spouse dies after a home is sold and before a new one is built. Also, the provision allowing a person over 55 to avoid tax on up to $ 125,000 of profits from the sale of a principal home in which he or she had lived at least three of the last five years would be available to a person who spends up to four of those five years in a nursing home. _ HOME PHONE: Prohibits any person with a home-based business from deducting any part of the base monthly telephone charge as a business expense _ FARM MACHINERY: Tightens depreciation provisions for single-purpose farm structures, such as poultry houses, and farm machinery _ FARM INCOME: Expands a law allowing farmers to defer for one year income from the drought-forced sale of livestock Farmers also could defer taxes on payments received as a result of drought-caused crop losses. _ BANKS: Renews a tax break for healthy savings and loan associations that take over failing associations, and extends the benefit to banks _ BLOOD DONORS: Permits states and blood-collection facilities to require blood donors to list their Social Security numbers so they can be traced if tests determine their blood is carrying the AIDS virus
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881112-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-12-88 0015EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Parents'Choice     11-12 0490</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Parents' Choice,0506</SECOND>
<HEAD>Parents' Choice Names Best In Children's Games, Videos, Toys</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DANA KENNEDY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BOSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An ally for parents in the battle to sift through the annual barrage of products aimed at children has released a recommended list of books, toys, videos, records, games and television shows. Parents' Choice, a quarterly newspaper that calls itself `` a review of children's media,'' announced Friday an eclectic list of winners in its annual awards competition. The winners range from <PERSON> Tracy </PERSON> <PERSON> Chapman </PERSON>'s debut album to a Boston-based children's television show to a publication called Owl Magazine. `` What we do is give information to parents so they can make their own choices about what is right, good and appropriate for out-of-school learning,'' said <PERSON> Diana </PERSON> <PERSON> Huss </PERSON> <PERSON> Green </PERSON>, editor-in-chief of the newspaper, published by the non-profit Parents' Choice Foundation. `` The aim of these awards is to lead mothers and fathers to holiday purchases that are practical and exciting,'' <PERSON> Green </PERSON> said. `` They must work for children of all backgrounds and skills, be of lasting standards and they must be fun.'' Most award categories contain four age groups; each age group has three to four winners. A partial list includes: _ Toys: the Circus Seal by <PERSON> Dakin </PERSON>, for newborns to age 3; the Puppet Factory by Quincrafts, ages 3-5; the Skywatcher's Weather Set by <PERSON> Bushnell </PERSON>, ages 8-12; and the Omagles Super Set by Century Products, for the family _ Home videos: `` Pecos Bill'' from <ORGANIZATION> Sony </ORGANIZATION>, ages 4-8; `` <PERSON> Bach </PERSON> and Broccoli'' from <ORGANIZATION> Family </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Home </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Entertainment </ORGANIZATION>, ages 8-11; and `` The Grizzlies'' from <ORGANIZATION> Vestron </ORGANIZATION>, ages 12-up _ Rock music: `` <PERSON> Tracy </PERSON> <PERSON> Chapman </PERSON>'' by <PERSON> Tracy </PERSON> <PERSON> Chapman </PERSON>, `` Wide Awake in Dreamland'' by <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Benatar </PERSON>, `` One Moment in Time,'' the 1988 Summer Olympics album _ Picture books: `` <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Patrick </PERSON> <PERSON> Norman </PERSON> <PERSON> McHennessy </PERSON> _ The Boy Who Was Always Late,'' by <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Burningham </PERSON>, Crown Publishers; `` Sleepers,'' by <PERSON> Dyal </PERSON> <PERSON> Kaur </PERSON> <PERSON> Khalsa </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Clarkson </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Potter </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>; `` Goldilocks and the Three Bears,'' by <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Marshall </PERSON>, Dial _ Computer programs: `` Amandastories: <PERSON> Inigo </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> Voyager </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, ages 3-up; `` Superprint!,'' <ORGANIZATION> Scholastic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, ages 6-up; and `` Where in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> is <PERSON> Carmen </PERSON> <PERSON> Sandiego </PERSON>? <ORGANIZATION> Broderbund </ORGANIZATION>, ages 9-14. _ Television shows: `` The New Explorers,'' <ORGANIZATION> WBBM </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>; `` Home Turf,'' <PERSON> KRON </PERSON>, <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION>, `` Ready to Go,'' WNEV, <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> _ Magazines: Let's Find Out, <ORGANIZATION> Scholastic </ORGANIZATION>, ages preschool-5; <ORGANIZATION> Penny </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Power </ORGANIZATION>, Consumer Reports, ages 8-14; <ORGANIZATION> Owl </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Magazine </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Young </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Naturalist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION>, ages 8-12 The selections, judged by parents and children, were based on nominations and judgments of critics such as <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Bianculli </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Ed </PERSON> <PERSON> Bark </PERSON> of The Dallas Morning News, <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Medved </PERSON> of TV's `` Sneak Previews,'' <ORGANIZATION> Mopsy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Strange </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Kennedy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Boston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Globe </ORGANIZATION>, and <PERSON> Matt </PERSON> <PERSON> Roush </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> USA </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Today </ORGANIZATION>. Parents' Choice Foundation, based in suburban <LOCATION> Newton </LOCATION>, was formed 10 years ago in response to what the group's literature calls an `` onslaught'' of products aimed at youngsters. `` We have now a large group of parents who are the most educated in history, and many are much older as well,'' <PERSON> Green </PERSON> said. `` Products for children are being aimed at them. They're barraged with stuff.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881112-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-12-88 0016EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-BRF--WhiteHouseIntruder     11-12 0095</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--White House Intruder,90</SECOND>
<HEAD>Man Jumps White House Fence, Is Arrested</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Secret </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> said an unarmed man climbed the White House fence and was immediately apprehended without incident. <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Corbett </PERSON>, spokesman for the service, said the man climbed the 8-foot fence on the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>'s north side at about 6:15 p.m. Friday, but did not verbally or physically threaten anyone. <PERSON> Corbett </PERSON> said the man's identity was being withheld pending a decision by a federal magistrate on whether the intruder should be charged or if he should be held for observation.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881112-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-12-88 0035EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Bush-OnVacation Bjt   11-12 0488</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bush-On Vacation, Bjt,470</SECOND>
<HEAD>RETRANSMITTING to restore Bjt designator</HEAD>
<HEAD>President-Elect and Mrs. Bush Enjoy Atlantic Swim</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RITA BEAMISH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 GULF STREAM, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION> _ A long weekend of ocean swimming, jogging and telephoning political associates from this exclusive <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> seaside community is President-elect <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s formula for unwinding from the election. While aides in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> work today on the transition that will bring <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s appointees to the White House next Jan. 20, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and his wife, <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON>, are spending their second full day vacationing at the seaside home of their multimillionaire friends <PERSON> William </PERSON> and <PERSON> Sarah </PERSON> <PERSON> Farish </PERSON> in this exclusive beachfront community. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> intends to return to <LOCATION> Washinton </LOCATION> late Monday or Tuesday, when he has a meeting scheduled with West German Chancellor <PERSON> Helmut </PERSON> <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON>. On Friday, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> told The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> he had spent the morning poolside talking on the telephone to various political associates, including former President <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON>, whom <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> called to thank for sending a congratulatory telegram. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, appearing in high spirits and in a happy mood as he kidded with his hosts and wife, said he still had not settled down after the election. `` I have n't really gotten down to the bottom of the unwinding yet,'' he said. He went for a jog, accompanied by his <ORGANIZATION> Secret </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> agents, for about two miles around the <ORGANIZATION> Gulf </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Stream </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Country </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Club </ORGANIZATION> golf course across the palm tree-lined street from the <PERSON> Farish </PERSON> home. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and <PERSON> Farish </PERSON> joined their wives, who had been walking on the beach, and then went out to a <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> cutter stationed about 400 yards offshore. The president-elect invited along an <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> reporter who had greeted him at his driveway. The group was ferried to the cutter Point <PERSON> Barnes </PERSON> by a motorized rubber raft, and the Bushes jumped in for a swim _ Mrs. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> first, followed by her husband. This reporter accepted an unexpected invitation and followed them in. Mrs. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, an avid swimmer, swam the full distance back to shore. The president-elect grabbed a line on the back of the raft. He told his agents and aides to `` rev it up'' for the tow back to shore in the choppy, warm <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION>. Back on shore, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> playfully took a camera from his official photographer and snapped pictures of his wife and friends. He commented several times about how pleasant the balmy setting was and joked that he was `` roughing it'' by working at poolside. Later he played some golf. Among those with whom he spoke on the telephone, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said, were <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> leaders <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Carroll </PERSON> <PERSON> Campbell </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON> and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Kean </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Majority Leader <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON> of <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>. Asked if he was doing much work on the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> transition, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said that was being handled by his team in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. Was he making lists of potential appointees? `` No, no,'' he said, then headed off for an afternoon nap.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881112-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-12-88 0039EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Saudi-ChinaTrade     11-12 0368</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Saudi-China Trade,350</SECOND>
<HEAD>China, Saudi Arabia Announce Trade Link</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GENE KRAMER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Saudi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arabia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, participants in a secret arms deal two years ago, have agreed to open trade offices in each other's capitals. A <ORGANIZATION> Chinese </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> statement issued Friday said the two countries' ambassadors to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, Saudi Arabian Prince <PERSON> Bandar </PERSON> <PERSON> bin </PERSON> <PERSON> Sultan </PERSON>, and <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> envoy <PERSON> Han </PERSON> <PERSON> Xu </PERSON>, signed a memorandum of understanding in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> to set up `` commercial representative offices. The decision was reached `` with a view to further developing the friendly relations and cooperation between <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Saudi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arabia </LOCATION> in the economic and commercial field,'' embassy spokesman <PERSON> Wu </PERSON> <PERSON> Zurong </PERSON> said. It was disclosed earlier this year that <LOCATION> Saudi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arabia </LOCATION> secretly purchased medium-range missiles from <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> in 1986. The <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> told <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> last May that while <LOCATION> Saudi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arabia </LOCATION> refused to allow <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> inspection of the <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> missiles it assured the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> that the launchers would not be equipped with nuclear or chemical warheads and it backed this by signing the nuclear non-proliferation treaty. The opening of trade offices is often regarded in diplomacy as a symbol of thawing relations and a prelude to formal diplomatic relations between countries that do not recognize each other, such as <LOCATION> Saudi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arabia </LOCATION> and the People's Republic of <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Saudi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arabia </LOCATION> is one of the larges countries in the world that has continued to recognize the rival <ORGANIZATION> Chinese </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nationalist </ORGANIZATION> government in <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION>. The policy was explained in the past as one of support for offshore <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION>'s staunch anti-communism and opposition to the official atheism of mainland <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>. But in recent months <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION> newspapers have noted that the Saudis and some other countries were drawing closer to <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> and they have speculated that those countries might switch their diplomatic recognition. For its part, <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION> has been relaxing restrictions against its citizens' private contacts with the Chinese mainland and expanding trade and other contacts with communist countries of the Soviet bloc. As of last January, mainland <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> had formal relations with 135 countries and <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION>, only 23. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> switched official recognition from <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> in 1978 and maintains a broad range of relations with <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION> at a non-official level.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881112-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-12-88 0044EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Chile     11-12 0265</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Chile,0273</SECOND>
<HEAD>Military Government Says It Will Not Take Sides In Election</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SANTIAGO, Chile (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The military government says it will not take sides in next year's presidential election, but has warned Chileans about `` the danger'' of returning Marxist parties to power. In a speech Friday on radio and television, Interior Minister <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Caceres </PERSON> also rejected opposition demands for the early resignation of President <PERSON> Augusto </PERSON> <PERSON> Pinochet </PERSON>, who was defeated in an Oct. 5 referendum. <PERSON> Caceres </PERSON> was appointed interior minister after the referendum in which voters rejected a military proposal that <PERSON> Pinochet </PERSON>, 72, remain in power until 1997. Gen. <PERSON> Pinochet </PERSON>, the army commander, has ruled <LOCATION> Chile </LOCATION> since leading the coup in September 1973 that ousted the elected government of Marxist President <PERSON> Salvador </PERSON> <PERSON> Allende </PERSON>. According to provisions of the 1980 constitution, <PERSON> Pinochet </PERSON>'s defeat in the referendum makes an open presidential election mandatory in December 1989, with the president surrendering power to the winner in March 1990 Opposition leaders have demandad constitutional changes to allow a speedier transition to democracy. <PERSON> Pinochet </PERSON> has refused to step down before 1990. <PERSON> Caceres </PERSON> said of next year's election: `` The government will not take any side, as it understands it has a subsidiary political role and must guarantee the develoment of the tasks that correspond to political parties and independent sectors. `` Although the government has the firm purpose of not involving itself in the upcoming electoral contest, it must warn about the danger of bringing to power certain groups that are close to totalitarism,'' <PERSON> Caceres </PERSON> added. `` The government calls on the nation's majorities to reject once and for all the extremists.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881112-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-12-88 0057EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Japan-Defectors     11-12 0199</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Japan-Defectors,0204</SECOND>
<HEAD>Four East Germans Defect During Concert Tour</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Three East German youth choir members and an engineer of an accompanying orchestra defected while on a concert tour of <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, a Foreign Ministry official said today. Three 17-year-old members of the <ORGANIZATION> Dresden </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Kreuzchor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chorus </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Johannes </PERSON> <PERSON> Kluegling </PERSON>, <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Diedrich </PERSON> and <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Nitschke </PERSON>, left their <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION> hotel in late October or earlier this month and asked for asylum at the <ORGANIZATION> West </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> German </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION>, the official said. The official, speaking on condition of anonymity, said the three went on to <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> on Nov. 7, while a fourth defector, <PERSON> Frank-Christian </PERSON> <PERSON> Budde </PERSON>, 42, an engineer of the <ORGANIZATION> Dresden </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Philharmonic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Orchestra </ORGANIZATION>, left <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> on Nov. 9. The ministry official would not provide further details due to humanitarian concerns except to say the defections were not political. West German embassy officials were not available for comment due to a holiday. The Dresden Kreuzchor Chorus is one of the world's oldest choirs. About 150 chior members and the orchestra arrived in <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION> Oct. 26 for a tour of five Japanese cities, including <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Yokohama </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Osaka </LOCATION>, according to the concert organizer. The chorus and the orchestra are to leave <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION> on Sunday.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881112-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-12-88 0100EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     11-12 0910</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0945</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names In The News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SOMERVILLE, N.J. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Reclusive multimillionaire <PERSON> Doris </PERSON> <PERSON> Duke </PERSON> has adopted a 35-year-old woman who has been living with her for three years, her lawyer said. Miss <PERSON> Duke </PERSON>, 75, adopted <PERSON> Chandi </PERSON> <PERSON> Hefner </PERSON>, an `` environmentalist, preservationist and conservationist'' who spends her time `` doing things as a good citizen as Miss <PERSON> Duke </PERSON> does,'' attorney <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> said Friday. The adoption took place Thursday. Miss <PERSON> Duke </PERSON>, who owns a walled, 2,700-acre estate in north-central <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION>, attracted publicity when she allowed <PERSON> Imelda </PERSON> <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> to take her private jet from <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> to face federal racketeering charges and posted bail for the former <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION> first lady last week. <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> said Miss <PERSON> Duke </PERSON> and Miss <PERSON> Hefner </PERSON> met socially in <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, where Miss <PERSON> Duke </PERSON> also maintains homes. Miss <PERSON> Hefner </PERSON>, who also owns property in <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION>, had been `` estranged from her family for a number of years,'' has never been married and has no children, he said. <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> would not comment on whether Miss <PERSON> Hefner </PERSON> would become the heir of <PERSON> Miss </PERSON> <PERSON> Duke </PERSON>, who has been married twice and has no other children. Miss <PERSON> Duke </PERSON>, the daughter of <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Duke </PERSON>, the tobacco and electric power magnate and benefactor of <ORGANIZATION> Duke </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, has a fortune estimated by <ORGANIZATION> Forbes </ORGANIZATION> magazine at $ 800 million and by her former business manager at $ 2.5 billion.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Dancer, actor and director <PERSON> Gene </PERSON> <PERSON> Kelly </PERSON> will be the 25th recipient of the Screen Actors Guild annual achievement award. <PERSON> Kelly </PERSON>, the 76-year-old veteran of more than 40 films and musicals, is best known as the star of `` Singin' in the Rain,'' `` An <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION>'' and `` Anchors Aweigh.'' He also choreographed 10 movies and directed or co-directed a dozen movies, including `` Singin' in the Rain'' with <PERSON> Stanley </PERSON> <PERSON> Donen </PERSON>. The SAG award is given for `` fostering the finest ideals of the acting profession.'' <PERSON> Kelly </PERSON> will accept the award at the guild's annual membership meeting Dec. 11 in nearby <LOCATION> Universal </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, it was announced Friday. Previous recipients include <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Hope </PERSON>, <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Stanwyck </PERSON>, <PERSON> Gregory </PERSON> <PERSON> Peck </PERSON> and <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Stewart </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>MEXICO CITY (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actor <PERSON> Timothy </PERSON> <PERSON> Dalton </PERSON> suffered a slight wrist injury while filming a scene for the next <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Bond </PERSON> film, `` License Revoked.'' In the scene, <PERSON> Bond </PERSON>, played by <PERSON> Dalton </PERSON>, had just been exposed as a mole in a drug lord's cocaine laboratory and was supposed to dangle from the end of a conveyor, his feet inches from a grinding machine. But during Thursday's shooting, <PERSON> Dalton </PERSON>'s watch caught on a metal hook as he flipped off the end of the conveyor, causing a slight cut. <PERSON> Dalton </PERSON> completed the scene after a doctor patched the injury on the set. In the movie, <PERSON> Bond </PERSON>'s 007 license to kill is lifted by the British secret service. Despite that, he goes after the drug lord, played by actor <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Davi </PERSON>, to avenge an assassination attempt on an American <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> agent.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Violinist <PERSON> Dmitri </PERSON> <PERSON> Sitkovetsky </PERSON>, who emigrated from the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> 11 years ago, will give four concerts in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> next month, his press agent said. The 34-year-old violinist will make his first return appearance Dec. 19 with the <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> Philharmonic at <ORGANIZATION> Tchaikovsky </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hall </ORGANIZATION>. His father, <PERSON> Julian </PERSON>, a noted violinist, gave his last performance at the hall before his death in 1958. `` He has been invited back by the <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> Philharmonic for a memorial concert to mark the 30th anniversary of his father's death,'' publicist <PERSON> Stephany </PERSON> <PERSON> Todd </PERSON> said Friday <PERSON> Sitkovetsky </PERSON> has performed widely as a soloist with Western symphony and chamber orchestras and since 1984 has been music director of <LOCATION> Finland </LOCATION>'s Korsholm Festival. He made his debut with the <ORGANIZATION> Cleveland </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Orchestra </ORGANIZATION> in 1986.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>TRENTON, N.J. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Gov. <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kean </PERSON> plans to buy a weekend house in the exclusive <LOCATION> Pottersville </LOCATION> section of <LOCATION> Bedminster </LOCATION>, the heart of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> fox hunting country, his spokesman said. The two-floor, nine-room masonry house with a barn and pond is located in north-central <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION>. `` The governor is very much an outdoors ... type,'' spokesman <PERSON> Carl </PERSON> <PERSON> Golden </PERSON> said Friday. `` When he saw the opportunity to purchase a property in an area that's still rather unspoiled, he took it.'' <LOCATION> Pottersville </LOCATION> is part of the <LOCATION> Somerset </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hills </LOCATION> area, whose rambling mansions house such well known figures as former automaker <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Z </PERSON>. <PERSON> De </PERSON> <PERSON> Lorean </PERSON> and magazine publisher <PERSON> Malcolm </PERSON> <PERSON> Forbes </PERSON>. <PERSON> Golden </PERSON> said the price and seller would not be disclosed. <PERSON> Kean </PERSON>'s choice of quarters has drawn intense interest since his election in 1981. He was roundly criticized several years ago for buying an island beach property in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Long </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> Sound at the same time he was appearing in television commercials extolling the attractiveness of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Coast </LOCATION> resorts.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>PORT ELIZABETH, South Africa (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Mother </PERSON> <PERSON> Teresa </PERSON> called for more love and peace in the world during a visit to an impoverished black shantytown on the outskirts of this city. The 78-year-old nun and Nobel Peace Prize winner was warmly received and her car was immediately surrounded by children when she arrived Friday at <LOCATION> Missionvale </LOCATION>. `` Love is always a work of peace,'' she said. `` Many people suffer from the poverty of love, even the rich.'' <PERSON> Mother </PERSON> <PERSON> Teresa </PERSON> arrived in <LOCATION> Port </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Elizabeth </LOCATION> after spending three days in <LOCATION> Cape </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Town </LOCATION> and selecting a site for a charity mission in <LOCATION> Khayelitsha </LOCATION>, a black township outside that city. She has said she does not plan to establish any other missions on her weeklong visit to <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881112-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-12-88 0112EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Nicaragua     11-12 0340</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nicaragua,0353</SECOND>
<HEAD>Ortega Asks To Extend State of Emergency; Paper Questions Hurricane
Aid</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BRYNA BRENNAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MANAGUA, Nicaragua (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON> asked the national assembly to extend a 30-day state of emergency imposed just before Hurricane <PERSON> Joan </PERSON> ravaged <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>, state radio reported. Meanwhile, <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>'s only opposition newspaper on Friday claimed the government botched the chance to get substantive hurricane assistance by demanding _ rather than asking _ aid in a crude manner. The newspaper <ORGANIZATION> La </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Prensa </ORGANIZATION> charged the <ORGANIZATION> Sandinistas </ORGANIZATION> committed `` a great diplomatic error that cut off the aid'' by asking for `` too much -LRB- assistance -RRB- and in a bad way'' from <LOCATION> Managua </LOCATION>'s diplomatic corps. The newspaper also said some of the Sandinistas' requests appeared targeted for the Nicaraguan army, rather than victims of Hurricane <PERSON> Joan </PERSON>. <PERSON> Joan </PERSON> killed 116 people, left more than 200,000 homeless and caused severe damage to much of the country in its rampage across <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>. Citing a document it said was provided by a diplomatic source, the newspaper said government requests for field tents and certain types of medical supplies generated suspicions the request `` was a maneuver to supply the Sandinista army with medical resources.'' It said the government requested 440,000 analgesic tablets, more than 1 million serum flasks, bandages, plaster for casts, small surgical tools and other supplies more appropriate for field hospitals. La Prensa further charged that tents donated by <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> were not given to the homeless. White House spokesman <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> told reporters last month that the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> feared any emergency aid it offered would help the <ORGANIZATION> Sandinistas </ORGANIZATION> fight U.S.-supported rebels known as Contras. The leftist government had no immediate comment on <ORGANIZATION> La </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Prensa </ORGANIZATION>'s report Radio <PERSON> Sandino </PERSON> on Friday reported <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON> asked the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION> to extend the 30-day state of emergency imposed Oct. 20, two days before Hurricane Joan struck. <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON>'s request was expected to be approved in the assembly, where the ruling <ORGANIZATION> Sandinista </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION> holds 61 of 96 seats. The emergency law suspended several articles of the constitution dealing with freedom of expression.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881112-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-12-88 0119EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-PeaceCorps     11-12 0615</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Peace Corps,0628</SECOND>
<HEAD>Couple Says Peace Corps Easier the Second Time Around</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: First available for Saturday AMs</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By TRUDY TYNAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CHICOPEE, Mass. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The second time around in the <ORGANIZATION> Peace </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corps </ORGANIZATION> is easier, say <PERSON> Catherine </PERSON> and <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Derrenger </PERSON>, who met and married during a stint in <LOCATION> Sierra </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Leone </LOCATION> in the 1960s and have just returned from two years in the <LOCATION> Fiji </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Islands </LOCATION>. `` We had always planned on doing it again, and when our children went off to university, we just decided to do it,'' said Mrs. <PERSON> Derrenger </PERSON>, 47. The couple has a son who graduated from the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chicago </ORGANIZATION> and a daughter who is a senior at <ORGANIZATION> Western </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> England </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Springfield </LOCATION>. No figures were available on Peace Corps volunteer re-enlistments, but corps spokesman <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Flanigan </PERSON> said from <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> that it's happening more and more. Many of those who volunteer a second time first joined right out of college and then decided to return after retiring from their careers. `` It's a trend that's just begining to manifest itself as the <ORGANIZATION> Peace </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corps </ORGANIZATION> enters its third decade, but we have a number of people in both categories,'' he said. `` The first time we were a lot younger,'' <PERSON> Derrenger </PERSON> said. `` This time we were no less enthusiastic, but we were a lot better equipped to really provide useful skills to the people.'' It was more difficult the second time for the Derrengers to break away from their everyday lives. He owned an eight-store shopping center in Billings, <LOCATION> Mont. </LOCATION>, and she ran a pre-school there. At the time of their first Peace Corps tour they were newly graduated from college. But for the second go-round neither found it hard to cast off their possessions. `` It was like taking the ultimate shower. You felt so clean afterwards,'' <PERSON> Derrenger </PERSON> said. `` I had been walking around with two pockets full of keys and when we were through getting rid of the stores, the house, the vehicles, and everything, we had two keys left to the footlockers that held everything we owned.'' Said Mrs. <PERSON> Derrenger </PERSON>: `` It's kind of fun to be starting over again, just like our kids. `` When we decided to go, we got rid of everything down to the things that we were going to pass on to the children after we died. It took us two years to do it, but it's a marvelous, wonderful feeling to sell everything.'' In 1963, Mrs. <PERSON> Derrenger </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Chicopee </LOCATION> native, headed to <LOCATION> Sierra </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Leone </LOCATION> to teach in a girl's school in <LOCATION> Segwema </LOCATION>. Her future husband, who grew up in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION> and graduated from <ORGANIZATION> Baylor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, arrived in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> a few months later to work on a program to build roads and a water supply in the isolated region. The Derrengers currently are staying with relatives in <LOCATION> Chicopee </LOCATION>, near <LOCATION> Springfield </LOCATION>, and have n't made any definite plans. `` It was n't love at first sight,'' he said, recalling how she, with more experience, got the front seat in the truck carrying them from the airfield, leaving him `` to breath dust and grumble for 200 miles.'' `` It was easier this time, because we were a team and had some life experience behind us,'' said Mrs. <PERSON> Derrenger </PERSON>. `` The first time I taught school. The second time I trained teachers.'' Her work in <LOCATION> Fiji </LOCATION> included developing a program to train 150 preschool teachers and establish 90 schools. His involved adapting a program teaching management skills to chiefs and other tribal leaders. `` It was something I thought about during the 25 years we were back in the states,'' he said. `` The chief system is one that works and makes sense. It just needed the application of modern management techniques.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881112-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-12-88 0119EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--SwearingBirds     11-12 0144</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Swearing Birds,0146</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bird-Speaking Contest Bans Foul Language</HEAD>
<DATELINE>KUALA LUMPUR, Malaysia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The organizers of a mynah-speaking contest say birds that swear or screech obscenities will be banned from participation. All mynahs entered in the Sea Carnival contest in <LOCATION> Lumut </LOCATION>, 120 miles northwest of <LOCATION> Kuala </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lumpur </LOCATION>, will have to be judged by `` a censorship board'' before being allowed to take part, contest directors said. <PERSON> Tajuddin </PERSON> <PERSON> Mohamed </PERSON> <PERSON> Talha </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Perak </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wildlife </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Parks </ORGANIZATION> was quoted by the <ORGANIZATION> Star </ORGANIZATION> newspaper today as saying owners of the birds will be asked if their pets speak any obscene words because <LOCATION> Malaysian </LOCATION> royalty, women and children will be watching the contest. <PERSON> Tajuddin </PERSON> said birds speaking Malay, the main language of <LOCATION> Malaysia </LOCATION>, would be given bonus points. The top three mynahs will win cash prizes ranging of 100 ringgit to 300 ringgit -LRB- $ 37 to $ 112 -RRB-.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881112-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-12-88 0143EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-PLO Bjt   11-12 0577</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-PLO, Bjt,0594</SECOND>
<HEAD>Palestinian Leaders Gather For Meeting Of Parliament-In-Exile</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Lead prospects uncertain.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By JEFFREY ULBRICH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ALGIERS, Algeria (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 More than 400 Palestinian leaders gathered today for a meeting of the Palestine parliament-in-exile in a session expected to result in the declaration of an independent <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strip </LOCATION>. A leading <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> official said the declaration would be an important step toward establishing a <LOCATION> Palestinian </LOCATION> homeland in the Israeli-occupied territories. The Israeli government, claiming the move will only cause more violence, tightened security in the territories. `` From the international, legal point of view, this -LRB- independence declaration -RRB- will consecrate officially the identity of the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION>,'' said <PERSON> Bassam </PERSON> <PERSON> Abu </PERSON> <PERSON> Sharif </PERSON>, chief spokesman for <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> leader <PERSON> Yasser </PERSON> <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON>. <PERSON> Abu </PERSON> <PERSON> Sharif </PERSON> said the next step after declaration is recognition of the Palestinian state from other nations. <PERSON> Abu </PERSON> <PERSON> Sharif </PERSON> met with reporters at the heavily guarded seaside center where the <ORGANIZATION> Palestine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>, the parliament-in-exile, begins a four-day meeting today. <PERSON> Abu </PERSON> <PERSON> Sharif </PERSON> claimed the Israelis plan to assassinate top <ORGANIZATION> Palestine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> leaders. He said a list of intended victims included <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON>, and that one assassination had been recently attempted. He did not elaborate. In <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Avi </PERSON> <PERSON> Pazner </PERSON>, spokesman for Prime Minister <PERSON> Yitzhak </PERSON> <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON>, responded: `` The ... imagination of <PERSON> Bassam </PERSON> <PERSON> Abu </PERSON> <PERSON> Sharif </PERSON> has apparently been working overtime in anticipation of the <ORGANIZATION> PNC </ORGANIZATION> -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> Palestine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> -RRB- and he will say anything to get a headline.'' Israeli officials claim an independence declaration will hurt the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> peace process and incite more anti-Israeli violence in the territories. `` The declaration is irrelevant,'' said a <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON> aide, <PERSON> Yossi </PERSON> <PERSON> Ben </PERSON> <PERSON> Aharon </PERSON>. `` But to our sorrow, it will incite the population.'' Underground Palestinian leaders called on supporters to step up protests during the meeting. <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> on Friday closed access to the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> and imposed a curfew on the <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strip </LOCATION>. The meeting of the 450-member council is seen as a historic moment in Palestinian history and comes during an 11-month uprising against <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s 21-year occupation of the territories. At least 310 Palestinians and 11 Israelis have died since the uprising began Dec. 8 in the territories <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> seized from <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION> in the 1967 Middle East War. <PERSON> Abu </PERSON> <PERSON> Sharif </PERSON> told reporters: `` Palestinians have a right to a state. All other details can be negotiated.'' `` This <ORGANIZATION> PNC </ORGANIZATION> will legislate beyond doubt the line that has been presented by Chairman <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON> for a long time _ calling for a just peace in the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> and confirming our readiness to sit down and negotiate at an international conference,'' <PERSON> Abu </PERSON> <PERSON> Sharif </PERSON> said. The Palestinian meeting comes after <PERSON> Jordan </PERSON> severed its links with the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> last summer and after <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> national elections Nov. 1 that produced gains by the right, which rejects giving up any of the occupied territories. In <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION>, where 1.5 million of the world's 5 million Palestinians live, several refugees doubted their parliament-in-exile will achieve a decisive breakthrough for a homeland in the meetings. `` The <ORGANIZATION> PNC </ORGANIZATION> will talk endlessly as usual,'' said <PERSON> Ibrahim </PERSON> <PERSON> Abu </PERSON> <PERSON> Kheit </PERSON>, 87, who owns a coffee shop in the Baqaa camp north of <LOCATION> Amman </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION>'s capital. Support for the <ORGANIZATION> PNC </ORGANIZATION> meeting came from 17-year-old <PERSON> Ziad </PERSON> <PERSON> Naimeh </PERSON>. `` It is for our benefit, if they have positive results,'' he said. But, `` I would not go back to live with an <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> neighbor even if my dad insists on returning,'' said <PERSON> Naimeh </PERSON>, whose family fled <LOCATION> Haifa </LOCATION>, in what is now <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>, in the 1947-48 war.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881112-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-12-88 0202EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-AtlantaEditor     11-12 0434</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Atlanta Editor,0449</SECOND>
<HEAD>Publisher: Atlanta Editor Resigned Over Control Of Washington
Bureau</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ATLANTA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Jay </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, the publisher of <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Atlanta </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Constitution </ORGANIZATION> and The <ORGANIZATION> Atlanta </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Journal </ORGANIZATION>, said in an opinion page article today that Editor <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Kovach </PERSON>'s resignation last week came during a discussion over control of the <ORGANIZATION> Cox </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Enterprises </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>. <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> bureau The publisher, in today's combined editions of the newspapers, said <PERSON> Kovach </PERSON> had wanted `` greater influence'' over the Cox <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> bureau `` for as long as he worked at the Journal-Constitution.'' `` Fair enough,'' <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> said. `` Then I learned about backbiting and rumor-mongering over the bureau that did n't stop even after I said I wanted it stopped about a year ago.'' <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> did not go into any specifics. <PERSON> Kovach </PERSON> could not be reached for comment. His home telephone went unanswered Friday night. A public rally was planned today to show support for <PERSON> Kovach </PERSON>. Last Friday, <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> said in the article, he brought up the problems with <PERSON> Kovach </PERSON>. `` No sooner had I spoken than <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> replied, ` I'm gone,''' <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> said. `` I replied, ` I accept.''' <PERSON> Kovach </PERSON>, who was <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> bureau chief for <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> before he joined the <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> newspapers in 1986, said in announcing his resignation that it came because of a failed effort to build `` a set of shared values and mutual trust with the senior managers of the company. ... `` <PERSON> Kovach </PERSON> was credited with injecting new energy into the papers, and oversaw an expansion of their staffs. <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> said in his article today that <PERSON> Kovach </PERSON> had threatened to resign many times in the past. `` It was as if there were only one permissible way to do newspapering _ <PERSON> Bill </PERSON>'s way,'' <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> said. `` And while he's good _ maybe even great in some ways _ he's not perfect. More important, neither he or anyone else is bigger than the newspapers themselves.'' <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> also apologized for what he called `` our family's discord'' and promised readers `` a continued quest for daily excellence,'' noting that expenditures for editorial payroll and space alloted for news both increased in the past two years. The rally today was organized by author <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Conroy </PERSON>, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Rep. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON>, D-Ga., and other prominent <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> citizens, who took out a full-page ad in Thursday's Journal and Constitution to announce their `` regret'' at <PERSON> Kovach </PERSON>'s departure <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Mashek </PERSON>, a member of the newspapers' <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> staff, resigned Wednesday because of <PERSON> Kovach </PERSON>'s departure. <ORGANIZATION> Cox </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Enterprises </ORGANIZATION> publishes 20 daily newspapers, including the <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> newspapers, as well as weekly newspapers and a monthly publication. The company also owns eight television stations and 11 radio stations and is the nation's fourth-largest multiple cable system operator.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881112-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-12-88 0209EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Israel Bjt   11-12 0573</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Israel, Bjt,0590</SECOND>
<HEAD>Call For Increased Protests As Palestinian Session Opens</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RONI RABIN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>JERUSALEM (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Arab </PERSON> activists called for further protests against the Israelis today as <LOCATION> Palestinian </LOCATION> leaders opened a summit meeting, but <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> closed the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> and confined 650,000 <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strip </LOCATION> residents to their homes. In the <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strip </LOCATION>, Israeli troops shot and wounded three Palestinians during protests Friday, hospital officials said. Two boys aged 12 and 15 were wounded in an Arab neighborhood of <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION> in shootings that were under investigation, <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> television said. The <ORGANIZATION> Palestine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION>'s parliament-in-exile, is expected to declare an independent <LOCATION> Palestinian </LOCATION> state in the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strip </LOCATION> during its four-day meeting beginning today in <LOCATION> Algiers </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Algeria </LOCATION>. All <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> residents were placed under curfew as of 9 p.m. Friday, including at least 250,000 who were confined to small concrete-block homes in refugee camps. Troops standing guard at entry points to <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION> turned away Arab cars from the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION>, the military spokesman said. Earlier Friday, troops rounded up and detained hundreds of Palestinians in an effort to prevent rioting during the council meeting. Israeli television said authorities cut phone links with many <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> areas to further isolate them and prevent organized activities. Soldiers streamed into <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION>'s <PERSON> Arab </PERSON> neighborhoods, doubling the standing police and <ORGANIZATION> Border </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Patrol </ORGANIZATION> forces to 1,100 men. Police Minister <PERSON> Chaim </PERSON> <PERSON> Bar-Lev </PERSON> said further steps would be taken as needed. `` If necessary, we will seal or clamp curfews on neighborhoods on the periphery of <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION>,'' he said on Israeli television, using the Arabic news program to reach Arab viewers. `` Saturday, Sunday and Monday will be days of escalation,'' said leaflet No. 28 of the Palestinian leadership. `` All the strike forces ... should escalate protest and resistance against the forces of occupation, wherever they are in the territories.'' The leaders called for a complete strike Tuesday, at the end of the <ORGANIZATION> Palestine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> session. The Palestinian uprising in the territories has lasted nearly a year and cost the lives of at least 310 Palestinians and 11 Israelis. About 1.5 million Palestinians live in the territories <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> seized from <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION> during the 1967 <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> war. The commander of Israeli forces in the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION>, Maj. Gen. <PERSON> Amram </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitzna </PERSON>, also used Israeli television's Arabic news to appeal to Palestinians to ignore calls for protests. `` No decision from the outside ... will bring change _ it will only make things worse,'' <PERSON> Mitzna </PERSON> said, referring to the anticipated declaration of independence. `` I am appealing to residents ... to avoid clashes with the security forces.'' In the <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strip </LOCATION> Friday, troops shot and wounded three <PERSON> Arab </PERSON> men during clashes in refugee camps, hospital officials said. The camps were under curfew most of the day but clashes broke out in <LOCATION> Jabalia </LOCATION> camp during a temporary lifting of the restrictions, designed to let residents shop for food, an Arab reporter said. Youths took to the streets to protest and hurl stones at soldiers, the reporter said. A 20-year-old was shot in the left foot and a 25-year-old was shot in the back, hospital officials said. In the Nusseirat camp, also in <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION>, a 27-year-old man was shot in the leg when he violated the curfew and left his home, a hospital official said. <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> television said police were investigating whether the two <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION> boys were shot by a civilian who fired live ammunition at stone-throwers who attacked his car.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881112-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-12-88 0228EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-PresidentialStocks Bjt   11-12 0697</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Presidential Stocks, Bjt,0717</SECOND>
<HEAD>Voters `Put Money Where Their Mouth Is' In Presidential Stock
Market</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PAUL RAEBURN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A presidential `` stock market'' that required participants to `` put their money where their mouth is'' accurately predicted the outcome of the presidential election, the market's originators say The computerized market was established by four researchers at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Iowa </ORGANIZATION> who wanted to see if it could outperform opinion polls. In it, professors and students gambled cash to buy shares of the candidates. After the election, share owners were paid a dividend that depended on the fraction of the popular vote received by each candidate. A trader could make money by accurately predicting the outcome and then bidding to buy shares at prices below his forecast or to sell at prices above it. `` In theory it's more accurate -LRB- than polls -RRB- because of the financial incentive people have to put their money where their mouth is,'' said one of the researchers, <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Forsythe </PERSON>, an economist. Prices of the candidates' shares could be converted easily into numbers showing what percentage of the public favored each candidate, <PERSON> Forsythe </PERSON> said. Since shortly after the second presidential debate Oct. 13, the stock market showed Republican <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> with between 51.2 percent and 53.6 percent of the vote, leading Democrat <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> by a margin ranging from 5.2 percent to 8 percent. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> won Tuesday's election with 54 percent of the vote and by an 8-point margin. `` Starting Oct. 17, the market has been predicting about this outcome all along,'' said <PERSON> Forsythe </PERSON>. `` If you look at the polls over that period, they've been a heck of a lot more volatile.'' Gallup polls, for example, gave <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> a 6 percent advantage early in October, a 10 percent advantage near the end of October and a 9 percent advantage just before the election, said <PERSON> Coleen </PERSON> <PERSON> McMurray </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Gallup </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Princeton </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.J. </LOCATION> <PERSON> Forsythe </PERSON>'s collaborators in the project were economists <PERSON> Forrest </PERSON> <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON> and <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Neumann </PERSON> and political scientist <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>. The researchers closed the market Wednesday and are beginning to analyze it. <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON> said they would like to continue their research with a similar market next fall that will allow students at several Big 10 universities to buy and sell stock in the Big 10 football teams. <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON> said the stock traders' profits and losses had not been tallied by Friday, but one trader claimed to have earned a 30 percent profit and another said he had lost $ 40 of $ 150 wagered. Most of the 168 traders' profits and losses were probably less than a few dollars, <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON> said. The market differs from polls in that it does not reflect the traders' preferences, but rather their impressions of how well each candidate is doing. Each stock trader is, in effect, a private pollster, surveying friends and following news reports. The market prices respond to the information traders pick up. Economic theory predicts that because the traders are n't being asked their preferences, they do n't have to be a representative sample of the population to accurately reflect public opinion. The researchers are far from proving that the market is an effective means of surveying public opinion, but they were encouraged when the market did not show the wild swings in public opinion that were registered in polls. <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Ludwig </PERSON>, chief methodologist of the <ORGANIZATION> Gallup </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION>, said an educated group like the <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> stock traders `` would be less likely to show the kind of swings in popularity that the candidates do on a general population basis.'' <PERSON> Ludwig </PERSON> also said he did n't believe that the small sample of white, educated Midwesterners could be used to estimate public opinion nationwide. A potential advantage of the market over opinion polls is that it provides a continuous record of public opinion, <PERSON> Forsythe </PERSON> said. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Eighmey </PERSON>, a senior vice president and market survey expert at the <ORGANIZATION> Young </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rubicam </ORGANIZATION> advertising agency in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, said he had seen the market demonstrated and found it `` really quite intriguing and impressive.'' `` It's one thing to ask a person, ` What do you think about this subject?' It's quite another when they have a personal stake in the answer,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881112-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-12-88 0229EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Poland Bjt   11-12 0678</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Poland, Bjt,0698</SECOND>
<HEAD>Police, Protesters Battle On Anniversary Of Poland's Rebirth</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DEBORAH G. SEWARD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WARSAW, Poland (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Police fought young demonstrators with batons, tear gas and water cannon as tens of thousands of people rallied across <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> on the 70th anniversary of the rebirth of the Polish state. Earlier Friday, communist authorities held their most elaborate ceremonies to celebrate the re-establishment of <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> in 1918, when anti-Soviet leader <PERSON> Jozef </PERSON> <PERSON> Pilsudski </PERSON> took power at the end of World War I. Opposition groups organized independent marches and rallies in the cities of <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Gdansk </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Krakow </LOCATION>, Wroclaw, <PERSON> Lublin </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Lodz </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Poznan </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Tarnow </PERSON> and <LOCATION> Katowice </LOCATION>. But the official news agency <ORGANIZATION> PAP </ORGANIZATION> complained that protests in several cities caused a `` dissonance in the patriotic atmosphere. ... In some cities, there were demonstrations and attempts to disturb public order undertaken by irresponsible groups of youth,'' it said. Reporters watched police fire tear gas and then charge about 500 young people near the Tomb of the Unknown Soldier in <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION> after demonstrators threw sticks at officers. The protesters quickly scattered into a nearby park, but at least 10 were detained. The skirmish followed a torchlight march by more than 20,000 Poles chanting `` Solidarity'' and `` Independence'' in the streets of the capital following a Mass marking the anniversary. An opposition spokeswoman in <LOCATION> Gdansk </LOCATION> said 25,000 people attended a Mass in <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mary </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Basilica </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> church, the country's largest church. Afterward many tried to march but were attacked by police in full riot gear who fired water cannon and beat demonstrators with batons. Referring to plans to shut down the <ORGANIZATION> Lenin </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Shipyard </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Gdansk </LOCATION>, birthplace of the banned Solidarity union, spokeswoman <PERSON> Joanna </PERSON> <PERSON> Wojciechowska </PERSON> said the crowd chanted defiantly: `` Lenin is yours, the shipyard is ours.'' The turmoil ended after Bishop <PERSON> Tadeusz </PERSON> <PERSON> Goclowski </PERSON> appealed to the police commander to call off his troops and let the mainly youthful protesters disperse unattacked, she said. In western <LOCATION> Poznan </LOCATION> city, a two-hour battle erupted between riot police and 4,000 shouting, leaflet-throwing demonstrators, said <PERSON> Alexandra </PERSON> <PERSON> Bessert </PERSON>, a Solidarity activist. She said scores of people were detained. Three people were hospitalized after being beaten by police in the southern industrial city of <LOCATION> Katowice </LOCATION>, said <PERSON> Maria </PERSON> <PERSON> Moczulska </PERSON>, a spokeswoman for the Confederation for an Independent <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>. Police also intervened after a Mass in <LOCATION> Tarnow </LOCATION>, opposition spokesmen said. People gathered peacefuly in <LOCATION> Lodz </LOCATION>, Wroclaw, <PERSON> Lublin </PERSON> and other smaller cities, opposition spokesmen said. But after the main rally attended by 10,000 people in <LOCATION> Krakow </LOCATION>, small groups of youth reportedly clashed with police after they decided to march on the Soviet consulate. The <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION> crowd packed St. <PERSON> John </PERSON>'s Cathedral in the <LOCATION> Old </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Town </LOCATION>, where <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION> Bishop <PERSON> Wladyslaw </PERSON> <PERSON> Miziolek </PERSON> told worshipers: `` The independence of <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> is the concern of every generation.'' After a Mass led by boy scouts, the crowd marched down a historic street past the restored <ORGANIZATION> Royal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Castle </ORGANIZATION> to lay flowers at the Tomb of the Unknown Soldier. The popular demonstrations followed a day of gala celebrations sponsored by Polish officials, including a rare televised Mass and legions of goose-stepping soldiers in a military parade. It was the first time so much attention was paid to <PERSON> Pilsudski </PERSON>, who in 1918 had just been released from a German prison at the end of World War I. On Nov. 11, 1918, a civil council in <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION> turned over military power to <PERSON> Pilsudski </PERSON>, who proclaimed an independent Polish state and disarmed German troops in the capital. The dream of generations of patriots was realized with the re-establishment of <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> after 123 years of being partitioned between <LOCATION> Prussia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Austria </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Russia </LOCATION>. Nov. 11 was celebrated as independence day before World War II but was spurned by communist authorities after the war. Official attitudes toward the date have softened in the aftermath of the 1981 declaration of martial law, with the military government embracing popular patriotic symbols and urging unity in the name of the `` Ojczyzna,'' the fatherland. On Victory Square, Polish <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> leader Gen. <PERSON> Wojciech </PERSON> <PERSON> Jaruzelski </PERSON>, wearing his army uniform and flanked by Prime Minister <PERSON> Mieczyslaw </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Rakowski </PERSON>, presided at the hourlong official ceremonies.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881112-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-12-88 0253EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-People-Guccione     11-12 0226</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-People-Guccione,0233</SECOND>
<HEAD>Court Backs Guccione's Property Purchase</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ATLANTIC CITY, N.J. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Penthouse magazine publisher <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Guccione </PERSON> may buy a $ 12 million Boardwalk tract where a casino hotel was once proposed, a state appeals court has ruled. The decision Thursday was the latest ruling in nine years of protracted litigation over the site where the Mayflower Hotel once stood. <PERSON> Guccione </PERSON> became embroiled in a lawsuit with <PERSON> Greta </PERSON> and <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Shamy </PERSON>, who were under contract to buy the hotel in 1977, according to court papers. The Shamys, of <LOCATION> Galloway </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Township </LOCATION>, and <PERSON> Guccione </PERSON> had agreed to form a corporation to buy the property and develop a new casino hotel. But the Shamys sued for breach of contract in 1979 following a business dispute. Seven years later, after numerous court hearings, a <ORGANIZATION> Superior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> judge ordered the property placed in receivership and sold to a competitive bidder. <PERSON> Guccione </PERSON>'s attorney, <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> N. </PERSON> <PERSON> Luter </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Morristown </LOCATION>, said <PERSON> Guccione </PERSON> and an investment group put together by the <PERSON> Shamys </PERSON> made separate offers. The court-appointed receiver, <PERSON> Arthur </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Greenbaum </PERSON>, recommended that the property be sold to <PERSON> Guccione </PERSON> for $ 12 million, the amount he had already invested in the property, according to court papers. The Shamys appealed that recommendation. But in a decision released Thursday, Judges <PERSON> Herman </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Michels </PERSON> and <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Keefe </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Appellate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Division </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Superior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> affirmed the receiver's recommendation.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881112-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-12-88 0309EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-WallStreet Bjt   11-12 0602</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Wall Street, Bjt,0619</SECOND>
<HEAD>Stocks Fall Sharply Over Dollar Worries</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JULIA MARTINEZ</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Business Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The dollar spiralled downward, depressing stock prices for the biggest daily loss on Wall Street since April and reflecting concerns about how President-elect <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> will manage the economy. On Wall Street, the Dow Jones average of 30 industrial stocks lost 47.66 points Friday to finish at 2,067.03. That gave the blue-chip indicator a net loss of 78.77 points for the week, the steepest election-week decline since the 1948 victory of President <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Truman </PERSON>. The dollar stood at a 10-month low against the Japanese yen and at five-month lows against the West German mark and British pound. Dealers noted that efforts Friday by the central banks of several nations to halt the dollar's slide failed. `` It was not enough,'' said <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Taratunio </PERSON>, a trader at <ORGANIZATION> Manufacturers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hanover </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Trust </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>. Central banks typically try to halt a drop in the dollar's value by buying large amounts of dollars on their domestic exhanges `` The whole market is waiting to test the resolve of the central banks, and given that, unless there is strong intervention or policy statements by the new <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> cabinet, the dollar will continue to slide,'' <PERSON> Taratunio </PERSON> added. The dollar's decline heightened the concerns of investors who spent the week worrying about interest rates, and the nation's budget and trade deficits `` The biggest concern is whether <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> will be able to work with <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to resolve the serious problems,'' said <PERSON> Alfred </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Goldman </PERSON>, vice president of <ORGANIZATION> A.G. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Edwards </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ; </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sons </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, a brokerage firm. Most analysts predicted the stock market's bearish sentiment would persist in the near term as investors try to sort out the prospects for the future. The market started the week on a down note as nervous investors anticipated the outcome of the presidential election. The market gained slightly on Election Day, then slid the remainder of the week in mostly light trading. Analysts said that in the post-election environment, investors felt little conviction to commit their funds in the face of mounting questions about how <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> will deal with the nation's twin deficits and whether the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reserve </ORGANIZATION> will raise interest rates to prop up the sagging dollar. With the government bond market closed for the Veterans Day holiday and little other activity to give Wall Street impetus, stock prices tracked the eroding dollar. Statements made in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> by <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Gould </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> official, and <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Commerce Secretary <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Verity </PERSON> indicated there is support for the dollar at its current, depressed levels. A lower dollar means <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> products are cheaper abroad. <PERSON> Gould </PERSON> said in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> that while the stock market has to seek its own level, `` we, as a matter of policy, have no interest in seeing the dollar lower.'' <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Lipsky </PERSON>, director of international bond research at <ORGANIZATION> Salomon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Brothers </ORGANIZATION>, said: `` We are near the point where unless there is some policy action, the market will decide that a new, lower level of the dollar will not be resisted. There is little doubt that we are going to have a clear test of <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> policy intentions regarding the dollar.'' On Friday, declining stocks outnumbered advancers by about 4-1 in nationwide trading of <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Stock </ORGANIZATION> Exchange-listed stocks, with 1,235 issues down, 292 up, and 414 unchanged. Volume on the floor of the <ORGANIZATION> NYSE </ORGANIZATION> came to 135.50 million shares, up from 128.92 million in the previous session, with many market participants away for the holiday. Nationwide, consolidated volume in NYSE-listed issues, including trading at regional exchanges and on the over-the-counter market, totaled 159.74 million shares.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881112-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-12-88 0328EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Kristallnacht-Past Bjt   11-12 0762</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Kristallnacht-Past, Bjt,0793</SECOND>
<HEAD>Speech Furor Reminder Of Germans' Sensitivity To Nazi Past</HEAD>
<HEAD>AP News Analysis</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TERRENCE PETTY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BONN, West Germany (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The furor over a Kristallnacht speech made by the parliament president, who resigned under intense criticism, reveals West Germans' lingering sensitivity to the <ORGANIZATION> Nazi </ORGANIZATION> past. The address by Bundestag President <PERSON> Philipp </PERSON> <PERSON> Jenninger </PERSON> prompted charges that some Germans have not honestly faced up to what occurred under <PERSON> Adolf </PERSON> <PERSON> Hitler </PERSON>'s Nazi regime, including the extermination of 6 million Jews. `` The background of what happened is the inability of many Germans to stand up to their own past,'' the leftist Greens party said before <PERSON> Jenniger </PERSON>, a conservative <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democrat </ORGANIZATION>, resigned Friday. In his speech Thursday marking the 50th anniversary of Kristallnacht when Nazi thugs attacked Jews, <PERSON> Jenninger </PERSON> attempted to set the scene of <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> in the 1930s when <PERSON> Hitler </PERSON> came to power, saying Germans initially found the <ORGANIZATION> Nazi </ORGANIZATION> era `` glorious.'' <PERSON> Jenninger </PERSON> says the speech was misunderstood and that he is an `` uncompromising foe of every type of totalitarian rule.'' Both <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> and communist <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> devoted themselves this week to decrying Kristallnacht, or Crystal Night, of Nov. 9-10, 1938, the prelude to the Holocaust. The night was named for the shards of glass that littered streets after <ORGANIZATION> Nazis </ORGANIZATION> smashed and burned Jewish business, homes and synagogues. West German President <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> von </PERSON> <PERSON> Weizsaecker </PERSON> has insisted Germans bore full responsiblity for the Nazi era and warned against any attempts to play down its horrors. `` Nothing that historical science brings to light today can diminish the crimes of the Nazi era,'' <PERSON> Weizsaecker </PERSON> said last month. The East German government has also denounced the Nazi years but rejects responsibility for <ORGANIZATION> Nazi </ORGANIZATION> crimes, they say, because the crimes occurred before the 1949 founding of the communist country. <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> was founded the same year. For all their well-intentioned effort, the remembrances of Kristallnacht this week went awry with <PERSON> Jenninger </PERSON>'s speech. <PERSON> Jenninger </PERSON> recalled that many Germans in the 1930s at first felt <PERSON> Hitler </PERSON> brought them `` glorious times.'' His address ignited a storm of protest _ at home and abroad. Politicians across the political spectrum called for Jenninger to resign. Angry responses came from <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> and from Jewish leaders in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>'s official news agency <ORGANIZATION> ADN </ORGANIZATION> called the Jenninger speech `` a scandal.'' Newspapers reported Chancellor <PERSON> Helmut </PERSON> <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON>, a close friend of <PERSON> Jenninger </PERSON>, called him to the office to criticize him for the emotionless tone of the speech. The leftist <ORGANIZATION> Greens </ORGANIZATION> said <PERSON> Jenninger </PERSON>'s speech showed that despite the passage of 43 years, many West Germans still have not sufficiently come to grips with what happened under <PERSON> Hitler </PERSON>'s rule. <PERSON> Hans-Jochen </PERSON> <PERSON> Vogel </PERSON>, head of the opposition <ORGANIZATION> Social </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democrats </ORGANIZATION>, said, `` This event shows us how the darkest chapter of German history is still a present-day thing.'' In <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Morris </PERSON> <PERSON> Abram </PERSON>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Conference </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Presidents </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Major </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Jewish </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organizations </ORGANIZATION>, said: `` Speaker <PERSON> Jenninger </PERSON>, regardless of his intentions, was guilty of insensitivity to that which can never be forgotten or forgiven.'' But many observers rushed to his side, pointing to <PERSON> Jenninger </PERSON>'s record as a steadfast supporter of <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> Also, no one questioned his assertions that he is anti-Nazi. The conservative daily newspaper <ORGANIZATION> Die </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Welt </ORGANIZATION> in today's editions said <PERSON> Jenninger </PERSON>'s main error was the tone of his speech could have given the impression he had `` found a way to understand the developments of 50 years ago'' without balancing that against harsher criticism of the Nazi era. The controversy is likely to keep West Germans thinking about how best to deal with recollections of the <ORGANIZATION> Nazi </ORGANIZATION> years, the newspaper said. `` The reasons for the fast plummet of the second-ranking official in our country will be occupying us for a long time,'' Die <ORGANIZATION> Welt </ORGANIZATION> said. A leader of <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>'s Jewish community Thursday defended <PERSON> Jenninger </PERSON>'s speech. `` I welcome that the Parliament president described in full clarity what was happening in <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> between 1933 and 1938,'' said <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Fuerst </PERSON>, a deputy chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> of Jews in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>. `` Especially the fact that everything that <PERSON> Hitler </PERSON> did was strongly supported by the masses of all Germans,'' <PERSON> Fuerst </PERSON> said. But Friday, Jewish council chairman <PERSON> Heinz </PERSON> <PERSON> Galinski </PERSON> was quoted as disavowing his deputy's comments. `` No one is supporting him. That's shown by the numerous protests that have reached me from all Jewish communities,'' the Neue Presse of <LOCATION> Hanover </LOCATION> quoted <PERSON> Galinski </PERSON> as saying. The newspaper also quoted <PERSON> Galinski </PERSON> as saying <PERSON> Fuerst </PERSON> might lose his job.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 EDITOR ` S NOTE _ <PERSON> Terrence </PERSON> <PERSON> Petty </PERSON>, a newsman in the <LOCATION> Frankfurt </LOCATION> bureau of <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>, has been reporting on German issues since 1987.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881112-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-12-88 0402EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Gulf-Helicopter     11-12 0342</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Gulf-Helicopter,0351</SECOND>
<HEAD>Gulf Crash Kills 3, U.S. Toll In Region Reaches 49</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MANAMA, Bahrain (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials said today that investigators are trying to determine why a <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> helicopter crashed, killing all three crewmen, while preparing to land aboard a warship in the north <LOCATION> Arabian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sea </LOCATION>. The pre-dawn crash Friday was the seventh involving American military aircraft in the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> region, with a total of 12 dead, durin 19 months of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> naval operations to protect commercial shipping caught in the Iraq-Iran war. The overall <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> casualty toll during that time is 49, including 37 aboard the missile frigate USS Stark, mistakenly hit by <LOCATION> Iraqi </LOCATION> missiles in May 1987. The officials, who asked not to be identified, said the SH-2F anti-submarine helicopter crashed while making a routine landing approach to the frigate USS Barbey. `` They were coming in toward the ship, they called in and said they had some kind of a problem, and then the helo -LRB- helicopter -RRB- just went down and hit the water,'' said one official. The aircraft apparently sank immediately because boats and other helicopters from the <PERSON> Barbey </PERSON>, the aircraft carrier USS Nimitz and the missile cruiser USS California were unable to find any survivors or wreckage, the official said. He said names of the crew were being withheld pending notificationof next of kin. The three ships are part of the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> carrier battle group now operating in the <LOCATION> Arabian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sea </LOCATION>, in support of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> forces inside the gulf. The investigation will be conducted by the headquarters of <ORGANIZATION> Naval </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pacific </ORGANIZATION> at <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Diego </LOCATION>, where the <PERSON> Barbey </PERSON> and the helicopter squadron are based. In addition to the three presumed dead in Friday's crash, the overall crash toll includes two <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> pilots killed when their AH-1 Cobra helicopter gunship was lost, apparently due to hostile action by <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>, last April 18 and five killed in two helicopter mishaps last year in the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION>. The other two killed were pilots of a <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> carrier jet that crashed in the Arabian Sea during a training flight.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881112-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-12-88 0418EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-MurderVideo Bjt   11-12 0652</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Murder Video, Bjt,0675</SECOND>
<HEAD>Psychiatrist Says Murder Defendant Has 10 Personalities</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Note use of `bastard' in 18th graf, `The gun...', and
penultimate graf, `Ms. Bonney...'.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>ELIZABETH CITY, N.C. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Videotapes of a man accused of killing his daughter show him assuming the voices of `` Satan,'' his dead grandmother and some other of the 10 personalities that a psychiatrist says he diagnosed. A jury that began watching the videotapes Friday saw a hypnotized <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Bonney </PERSON> tremble with grief and pound his fist on a table as he insisted that his daughter, <PERSON> Kathy </PERSON> <PERSON> Carol </PERSON> <PERSON> Bonney </PERSON>, 19, was not dead. <PERSON> Bonney </PERSON> is charged with shooting his daughter 27 times. In one videotape, <PERSON> Bonney </PERSON> said his daughter visits him in jail. `` Most nights, she'll come in here to see me, after everybody else goes to sleep, and we'll talk,'' a weeping <PERSON> Bonney </PERSON> said. Watching the videotape Friday, <PERSON> Bonney </PERSON> frowned and looked puzzled at what he saw. Outside the courthouse, he said the man in the videotapes was not him. `` Everybody's got a twin in the world,'' the <LOCATION> Chesapeake </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, man said. `` I guess I've got one, too.'' <PERSON> Bonney </PERSON>, 45, who is being held in a jail, is charged with first-degree murder in his daughter's death. Her nude body was found last November next to the <LOCATION> Dismal </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Swamp </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Canal </LOCATION>, just inside <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>'s border with <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>. `` Satan'' and three other of <PERSON> Bonney </PERSON>'s 10 purported personalities revealed themselves in 23 hours of videotaped interviews with Dr. <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Dell </PERSON>, a psychiatry professor at <LOCATION> Norfolk </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Virginia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Dell </ORGANIZATION>'s testimony is key to <PERSON> Bonney </PERSON>'s defense that he is innocent by reason of insanity. If convicted, he could be sentenced to death. Superior Court Judge <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> viewed portions of the tapes Thursday and ruled they could be shown to the jury. <ORGANIZATION> Dell </ORGANIZATION>, in his testimony, said <PERSON> Bonney </PERSON>'s memory problems and inconsistent stories are the result of multiple personalities. In the video the jury saw Friday, <PERSON> Bonney </PERSON> could not remember his height, his age, or the name or phone number of his old businesses. `` It is the switching and struggles among his alternate personalities that is producing his strange and inconsistent behavior,'' <ORGANIZATION> Dell </ORGANIZATION> said. On one tape, <PERSON> Bonney </PERSON>'s voice took on a demonic snarl as he was interviewed. `` You're just a mortal,'' <PERSON> Bonney </PERSON> growled, eyebrows arched, long fingernails clicking on a tabletop. `` You do n't know nothing.'' During other interviews, <PERSON> Bonney </PERSON> assumed the feeble voice of <PERSON> Mammy </PERSON>, his long-dead maternal grandmother, and called out for <PERSON> Kathy </PERSON> <PERSON> Bonney </PERSON>. `` Can you hear me, <PERSON> Kathy </PERSON>?'' <PERSON> Bonney </PERSON> said in his grandmother's voice `` I'm so old, so old. But I got ta fix supper. Maybe you'll change your mind Eat some supper now.'' `` She ai n't supposed to be living in here,'' the Satan voice interrupted, referring to <PERSON> Bonney </PERSON>'s dead daughter. `` She wo n't be in here long. She called me a bastard. `` The gun went off. ... She was sitting there screaming, and I was hollerin'. And I said, ` What are you gon na do?' And she said, ` I'm gon na shoot you, you bastard.' `` I know everything,'' the Satan voice continued. `` I am strong. I can do what I want to, when I want to. I control <PERSON> Tom </PERSON>. He's dumb ... a wimp ... a goody-goody, talking that <PERSON> Jesus </PERSON> garbage all the time.'' Suddenly `` Viking'' spoke up, a noble, friendly personality and the first to reveal itself during <PERSON> Bonney </PERSON>'s evaluation by <ORGANIZATION> Dell </ORGANIZATION>. `` He's gon na shoot her!'' <PERSON> Viking </PERSON> screamed excitedly, apparently reliving the night Ms. <PERSON> Bonney </PERSON> died. `` He's gon na shoot her! No! No! I've got to protect her! Do n't shoot her! I love her.'' Ms. <PERSON> Bonney </PERSON> had argued with her father on a darkened roadside about a love letter to a married boyfriend, whom `` Satan'' called `` that stupid newt.'' Then, according to the Satan personality, Ms. <PERSON> Bonney </PERSON> `` called -LRB- Satan -RRB- a bastard. She sorta goofed when she called him that.'' `` She thought she was talking to <PERSON> Tom </PERSON>,'' Satan said. `` But she was talking to me.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881112-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-12-88 0419EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Soviet-NuclearTest     11-12 0120</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Soviet-Nuclear Test,0121</SECOND>
<HEAD>Underground Nuclear Test Device Set Off By Soviets</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MOSCOW (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> today detonated a 20-kiloton nuclear test device beneath the <LOCATION> Semipalatinsk </LOCATION> proving grounds on the steppes of <LOCATION> Kazakhstan </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION>, the official news agency <ORGANIZATION> Tass </ORGANIZATION> reported. Twenty kilotons, the force of 20,000 tons of <ORGANIZATION> TNT </ORGANIZATION>, was the yield of the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> atom bomb dropped in 1945 on <LOCATION> Hiroshima </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>. `` The goal of the testing was upgrading military technology,'' <ORGANIZATION> Tass </ORGANIZATION> said of the 6:30 a.m. test explosion. <ORGANIZATION> Tass </ORGANIZATION> provided no further details. On Oct. 18, the Soviets detonated another 20-kiloton nuclear device at <LOCATION> Semipalatinsk </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Tass </ORGANIZATION> at the time said that blast was conducted to research the physics involved in a nuclear explosion.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881112-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-12-88 0424EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-PrincipalArrested     11-12 0455</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Principal Arrested,0468</SECOND>
<HEAD>Principal Arraigned On Drug Charges As Officials Question System</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LARRY McSHANE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
