<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880223-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-23-88 0138EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-APArts:Grammys-FemaleRockers     02-23 0855</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AP Arts: Grammys-Female Rockers,0871</SECOND>
<HEAD>THE GRAMMY AWARDS: Let's Hear It for the Girls</HEAD>
<HEAD>Female Rockers Eliminated from Grammys This Year</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By MARY CAMPBELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Three years ago, it was hard to turn on the radio without hearing <PERSON> Joan </PERSON> <PERSON> Jett </PERSON> pound it out, or <PERSON> Madonna </PERSON> whine or <PERSON> Cyndi </PERSON> <PERSON> Lauper </PERSON> tell us that girls just like to have fun. Women had a dominant role in the rock scene. However, at this year's Grammy Awards, to be presented on March 2 at Radio City Music Hall, female rockers are an extinct breed: There's no category, as there has been in the past, for `` best rock vocal performance, female.'' The Grammys have separate categories for men and women singers in pop and rhythm' n' blues. The rock category combines them this year. <PERSON> Tina </PERSON> <PERSON> Turner </PERSON>, the grandmother of rock who was named best female rock vocalist last year, is nominated along with <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Marx </PERSON>, <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Seger </PERSON>, <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Springsteen </PERSON> and <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Cocker </PERSON>. <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> Schlesinger </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Recording </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Arts </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sciences </ORGANIZATION>, said <ORGANIZATION> NARAS </ORGANIZATION> has a rule that the 6,000 industry professionals who are members must nominate 10 different people in a category for that category to exist. The screening committee listens to each nomination and decides whether it has been nominated in the right place. If it is n't, it's moved to where the committee decides it belongs `` Record company executives will always try and enter things in smaller categories where there's less competition,'' <PERSON> Schlesinger </PERSON> said. `` We do n't accept that. `` If we do n't end up with 10 nominations in a category, rather than having insufficient competition, we fold that category into another one. It does n't happen often.'' Another rule, which <ORGANIZATION> RCA </ORGANIZATION> executive <PERSON> Dennis </PERSON> <PERSON> Fine </PERSON> unsuccessfully fought this year, is that the rock vocal performance nominations must be from solo albums; lead singers of groups are n't eligible. `` Grace Slick's ` Babylon' is a rock' n' roll track and a great solo on a Starship album. Unless she does her own solo album, it's not considered a solo,'' Fine said `` It all depends on how a record is billed. It's not fair. <PERSON> Sade </PERSON> is considered to be a group. The screening committee eliminated <PERSON> Patty </PERSON> <PERSON> Smythe </PERSON> and <PERSON> Cyndi </PERSON> <PERSON> Lauper </PERSON> from rock in the past. They determined they were pop.'' During the decade, performers such as <PERSON> Tina </PERSON> <PERSON> Turner </PERSON>, <PERSON> Madonna </PERSON>, <PERSON> Cyndi </PERSON> <PERSON> Lauper </PERSON>, <PERSON> Sheena </PERSON> <PERSON> Easton </PERSON>, <PERSON> Laura </PERSON> <PERSON> Branigan </PERSON>, <PERSON> Joan </PERSON> <PERSON> Jett </PERSON>, <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Benatar </PERSON>, <PERSON> Annie </PERSON> <PERSON> Lennox </PERSON>, <PERSON> Chaka </PERSON> <PERSON> Khan </PERSON>, <PERSON> Donna </PERSON> <PERSON> Summer </PERSON>, <PERSON> Debbie </PERSON> <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> and <PERSON> Grace </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> took rock in new directions with their strong images and hot music. Are these same female rockers _ and others _ suddenly in short supply? The answer to that depends on who you ask. <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Guccione </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> thinks there are lots; <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Graham </PERSON> thinks there are few. <PERSON> Guccione </PERSON>, publisher of Spin magazine, is incensed that the female rock vocalist category was eliminated. `` This is literally a disservice to both males and females,'' he said. `` I think, if anything, the last year to two years has represented the emergence of the female rock superstar. It started with <PERSON> Madonna </PERSON> and it's really just blossoming. `` My favorite is <PERSON> Maria </PERSON> <PERSON> McKee </PERSON> on ` Wheels.' There were a lot of great performances last year _ <PERSON> Grace </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>' ` I May Not Be Perfect But I'm Perfect for You,' <PERSON> Debbie </PERSON> <PERSON> Harry </PERSON>'s ` French Kissing in the <LOCATION> U.S.A. </LOCATION>' <PERSON> Madonna </PERSON> is always to be considered. My perspective is that this past year of all years, females performed better on the whole than the males.'' <PERSON> Graham </PERSON>, rock's best-known impresario, disagrees. `` It is an irony and phenomenon of rock' n' roll that there have been so few women accepted commercially,'' he said. `` I really do n't understand why, other than the fact that the terminology of rock' n' roll sounds more masculine than feminine. The music has got a harder edge sometimes. `` We have to generalize but a young rock' n' roll male listener may have a problem admitting that he's a fan of a female rock' n' roller, if his friends are into all-male groups A woman rocker is going to have to have that extra edge, so that he ca n't get that song out of his head. Otherwise she'll lose.'' However, in the'60s and early'70s, rock fans _ male and female _ had no trouble following <PERSON> Janis </PERSON> <PERSON> Joplin </PERSON> and Grace Slick. Later, male fans were just as enthusiastic as female fans at <PERSON> Joan </PERSON> <PERSON> Jett </PERSON> and <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Benatar </PERSON> concerts. But singer-songwriter <PERSON> Suzanne </PERSON> <PERSON> Vega </PERSON>, nominated for three Grammys this year, including `` best pop vocal, female,'' agrees with <PERSON> Graham </PERSON>. `` When <ORGANIZATION> Rolling </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Stone </ORGANIZATION> ran its list of the Top 100 rock albums, I noticed there were only about six women on this list,'' she said. `` <PERSON> Laura </PERSON> <PERSON> Nyro </PERSON> and <PERSON> Kate </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> have made brilliant albums but they ca n't be considered rock' n' roll. `` Rock' n' roll is an aggressive, very male style of singing. Some women fit into it naturally _ like <PERSON> Chrissie </PERSON> <PERSON> Hynde </PERSON> and <PERSON> Patty </PERSON> <PERSON> Smythe </PERSON>. There are not many women, I think, who naturally take to rock' n' roll, but they do great music. I may have closet tendencies in that direction, but I do n't think of myself as a rock' n' roller.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880223-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-23-88 0141EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Jews-Israel     02-23 1135</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Jews-Israel,1166</SECOND>
<HEAD>U.S. Jews Uneasy With Israeli Policy, But Commitment Remains</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By JERRY SCHWARTZ</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 On Jan. 24, when the Allied Jewish Appeal of <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION> mobilized for the year's biggest fund-raising event, there was little reason to believe that `` Super Sunday'' would live up to its name. The telephone solicitation campaign came at a disturbing moment for many Jews in this country. They have watched with increasing distress and horror as Palestinians rioted in <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s occupied territories, and <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> soldiers retaliated with beatings and bullets. Half of the money collected on `` Super Sunday'' would go to <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>. Are American Jews so pained by <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s actions that they have become disaffected with the Jewish state, and unwilling to make their customary donations? The answer is no. After the last pledge was counted, fund raisers found they had collected $ 2.5 million, up $ 400,000 over the 1986 total. `` <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> is the Jewish homeland, the Jewish heart. No one can live without a heart. They are rallying around the flag,'' said <PERSON> Leonard </PERSON> <PERSON> Barrack </PERSON>, general chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Philadelphia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> AJA </ORGANIZATION>. In city after city, fund raisers have reached the same conclusion. In <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION>, the total collected Jan. 24 was $ 2.6 million, up $ 1 million from last year's figures; in <LOCATION> Cincinnati </LOCATION> it was $ 360,000, up about $ 50,000; in <LOCATION> Rhode </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> it was $ 187,167, up about $ 25,000. `` Wanting to see your kids work on a kibbutz, wanting to plant trees in <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>, wanting a Jewish state _ these things are not affected by political events,'' said <PERSON> Steven </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Cohen </PERSON>, a professor of sociology at <ORGANIZATION> Queens </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> and leading Jewish demographer. But there is no question that many American Jews are anguished by reports of <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> soldiers beating Palestinians, burying them alive, shooting them in street warfare reminiscent of <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>. And some have spoken out. `` As a supporter of <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> ... I am appalled beyond measure by the treatment of the rioting Palestinians by the Jews,'' wrote filmmaker <PERSON> Woody </PERSON> <PERSON> Allen </PERSON>, in a recent op-ed piece in <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION>. `` I mean, fellas, are you kidding? Beatings of people by soldiers to make examples of them? Breaking the hands of men and women so they ca n't throw stones? Dragging civilians out of their houses at random to smash them with sticks in an effort to terrorize a population into quiet?'' Since early December, stone-throwing <LOCATION> Palestinian </LOCATION> protesters have challenged <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s army, demanding an end to its occupation of the <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strip </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> of the <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION>, territories seized by <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> in its wars with the Arabs. More than 50 Arabs have been killed by Israelis in the rioting. Time magazine polled American Jews last month and found that 57 percent opposed the use of force and beatings on Arabs. A Palestinian homeland was opposed only by a small margin _ 39 percent in favor, 42 percent opposed. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Lerner </PERSON>, editor of <LOCATION> Tikkun </LOCATION> magazine, a self-styled leftist alternative to Commentary that is based in <LOCATION> Oakland </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, describes the <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> occupation as `` immoral and stupid.'' `` We did not survive the gas chambers of <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> in order to become the oppressors of <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Lerner </PERSON> writes in an upcoming editorial. <PERSON> Tikkun </PERSON> has been overwhelmed in recent weeks by calls and letters from American Jews who are outraged by what is happening in the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Lerner </PERSON> said. `` There has been unbelievable change,'' he says. `` It used to be that the rule was, ` There is no room for criticism.' Now, the only issue is where do you say it. Do you say it to the press, or do you say it to your friends?'' the editor says. That has been a major issue. Jewish leadership has been divided; some leaders denounce others who have gone public with their criticism _ those like Rabbi <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON> <PERSON> Schindler </PERSON>, the leader of the Reform movement who described the beatings as an `` offense to the Jewish spirit.'' `` The criticism by American Jews of <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> _ I've termed it despicable,'' said Rabbi <PERSON> Avi </PERSON> <PERSON> Weiss </PERSON>, a leader of Americans for a Safe <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>. He deplores those who criticize from `` plush living rooms in <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION>.'' `` These are not protesters. These are rioters who are out there with the intent to maim, to wound and to murder,'' <PERSON> Weiss </PERSON> says. A Newsday poll of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> Jews found that 47 percent thought American Jews should speak out to influence <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> _ and 47 percent felt they should keep their views to themselves. Congregants say Rabbi <PERSON> Jehiel </PERSON> <PERSON> Orenstein </PERSON> of Congregation Beth El of <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orange </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Maplewood </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.J. </LOCATION>, recently took the pulpit to discuss the creation of a <LOCATION> Palestinian </LOCATION> state. But when a reporter asked <PERSON> Orenstein </PERSON> to confirm his remarks, the rabbi was evasive. `` American Jews should not be the critics of <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> because they're standing on the front lines and we're at a distance,'' <PERSON> Orenstein </PERSON> said. But <PERSON> Orenstein </PERSON> indicated that he was uneasy with the growing influence of Rabbi <PERSON> Meir </PERSON> <PERSON> Kahane </PERSON>, the American-born member of the <ORGANIZATION> Knesset </ORGANIZATION> who proposes expelling the Arabs from <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> and its occupied territories. And he recounted that when news of the beatings spread, he told his congregation, `` It can not be the policy of <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> to break arms and legs and pull people from their beds and terrorize them.'' Some say <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> does not deserve the infamy that is coming its way. `` We can not give the impression that we're satisfied to have hands broken,'' says <PERSON> Arnold </PERSON> <PERSON> Lasker </PERSON>, a retired rabbi living in <LOCATION> Margate </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION> `` But the breaking of bone, which is a horrible thing, has to be seen in context'' _ as a tiny aspect of a decent, democratic <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>. Many agree that the context is missing _ that the news media have distorted events in <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>, either by exaggerating the force applied by the Israelis or by neglecting to focus on <PERSON> Arab </PERSON> provocations. And there is the question of whether <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> should be held to a higher standard than other nations. Even <PERSON> Orenstein </PERSON> asks, `` Is anybody asking the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> to give back <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>?'' <PERSON> Elaine </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Charny </PERSON>, a 52-year-old former teacher who lives in the <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION> suburb of <LOCATION> Jenkintown </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION>, feels that a higher standard is justified. `` <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> represents a certain bright hope and ideal,'' she says. She says it is the `` moral responsibility'' of Jews around the world to speak out on Israeli issues; she cringes when she reads the headlines these days. `` We're all hoping and praying that they can find a better way of solving this problem,'' she says. Mrs. <PERSON> Charny </PERSON> and her husband buy Israeli Bonds; they have visited <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> three times. However saddened by recent events, Mrs. <PERSON> Charny </PERSON> does not envision a day when <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> will lose its appeal. `` It's an idea,'' she says. `` The idea that it's there for all of us, kind of like a little utopia. It's just a vision.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880223-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-23-88 0147EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-SouthKorea-Press     02-23 0774</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-South Korea-Press,0798</SECOND>
<HEAD>South Korean Press Enjoying Increased Freedom</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report. Note Feb. 25 date 3rd graf.</NOTE>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>BY PAUL SHIN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SEOUL, South Korea (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The South Korean press is enjoying a broad degree of freedom after years of tough official control, but opposition quarters maintain it still is manipulated by the government's `` hidden hands.'' Nevertheless, the nation's newspapers are reporting and commenting more vigorously on politics and other subjects that for years had been limited or banned by the government. President-elect <PERSON> Roh </PERSON> <PERSON> Tae-woo </PERSON>, who takes office Feb. 25, promises to ensure full press freedom and made it a key point in his election campaign. The government began easing press restrictions last summer under pressure from <PERSON> Roh </PERSON>. `` We have done much and there should be nothing to complain about,'' said <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Jung-bai </PERSON>, the assistant culture-information minister. Journalists agree the government has abandoned most controls on the domestic press, such as regular visits to newspapers by security agents and the issuance of `` press guidelines'' that dictated what could be reported and in what way. Government reguirements on registration of journalists have been dropped and new legislation will end limits on newspapers having news bureaus outside their headquarters locations. There also will be no limits on the number of pages a newspaper can publish. `` The ball is in the court of the news media. It's up to them,'' said Rep. <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Min-sup </PERSON>, a ranking member of <PERSON> Roh </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>. Opposition politicians and dissidents contend, however, that much of the press still remains under government control through `` hidden hands.'' Rep. <PERSON> Kim </PERSON> <PERSON> Tae-ryong </PERSON>, spokesman for the main opposition <ORGANIZATION> Reunification </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, said, `` No basic changes have been made and the press still is no more than a public relations tool of the government.'' The opposition claims the government exerts behind-the-scenes influence and control, ranging from intimidation to patronage and bribery. They also contend the media is packed with government supporters. Rep. <PERSON> Ahn </PERSON> <PERSON> Dong-sun </PERSON>, spokesman for the opposition <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Peace </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democracy </ORGANIZATION>, claimed journalists are practicing self-censorship. <PERSON> Kim </PERSON> <PERSON> Tae-hong </PERSON>, secretary-general of the dissident <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Movement </ORGANIZATION>, said, `` Essentially, <PERSON> Roh </PERSON> is the same as his dictatorial predecessor. He would not give in easily. We must continue to fight for press freedom.'' Several editors and reporters rejected the opposition charges of self-censorship, but said they want to help ensure `` sound political development'' without endangering social stability. One senior editor, speaking only on condition of anonymity, said many journalists are cautious because `` they suspect the true intention of the government.'' The opposition claims the country's two networks, which are state-owned, project only a government viewpoint and that opposing points of view receive little attention or are distorted. A Korea Broadcasting System -LRB- KBS -RRB- spokesman, <PERSON> Lim </PERSON> <PERSON> Ung-shik </PERSON>, rejected the opposition's charges. `` Our news and other programs are fair by any standard,'' he said. <PERSON> Lim </PERSON> said <ORGANIZATION> KBS </ORGANIZATION> has recently started some new programs, including talk shows to which opposition figures are regularly invited. Government officials say the criticism the networks may end after a neutral broadcasting committee is set up in June, as required by a new law, to nominate the heads of the two networks. Some opposition lawmakers will be appointed to serve on the committee to ensure fairness. The government is also preparing to inaugurate in March a new press law that would drop a requirement for government approval to start new newspapers or periodicals. Seven newspapers have so far applied to start publishing under the new law. <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> now has 20 national daily newspapers with an estimated combined circulation of 12 million. The first beneficiary of the new law would be a newspaper that some 200 dissident journalists plan to publish this spring with support from 3,300 sponsors, including 1,000 college professors, 100 lawyers, 200 religious leaders and 200 literary figures. Song Kun-ho, president of the newspaper, The <ORGANIZATION> Hankyoreh </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Shinmun </ORGANIZATION>, said the project will be started with 5 billion won -LRB- $ 6.8 million -RRB- to be raised through public shares. Song said 15,000 people have so far responded, contributing about half of the needed money. Song and the other journalists, dismissed from their previous jobs on grounds of anti-government activity, said their newspaper would emphasize human rights and spearhead press freedom. The influential <ORGANIZATION> Roman </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> also has announced it will start a newspaper in April and set up a nationwide radio network in September. Critics of the government contend the new press law is restrictive because it stipulates that new newspapers must use certain kinds of presses that cost millions of dollars. They contend this would keep control of the press in the hands of establishment groups.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880223-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-23-88 0148EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Israel-ArabHarassment     02-23 0865</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Israel-Arab Harassment,0891</SECOND>
<HEAD>Israeli Distrust Of Arabs Grows In Coastal City</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</NOTE>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MASHA HAMILTON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>TEL AVIV, Israel (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Cafe owner <PERSON> Yosef </PERSON> <PERSON> Weizman </PERSON> said when <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> police beat up his Arab workers three days ago, he understood the depth of distrust between Jews and Arabs after months of clashes in the occupied territories. <PERSON> Eli </PERSON> <PERSON> Ben-Simon </PERSON>, 38, had learned the lesson a few days earlier. <PERSON> Ben-Simon </PERSON>, a Jew, was beaten up in an industrial area near <LOCATION> Tel </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Aviv </LOCATION> because, he said, his Israeli attackers thought he was an Arab. Growing numbers of Palestinians who work in and around this coastal city of 1.5 million people are subject to harassment, primarily by Israelis made suspicious by the unprecedented fury and violence of Arabs opposing <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s 20-year occupation in the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strip </LOCATION>. Arab harassment is leading to a climate of fear among Palestinians and concern among many Israelis. City officials estimate about 40,000 Arabs work in the <LOCATION> Tel </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Aviv </LOCATION> metropolitan area. There are also about 10,000 Arabs with <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> citizenship who live in the area. `` This incident ... is, of course, linked to the unrest in the territories,'' Police Minister <PERSON> Chaim </PERSON> <PERSON> Bar-Lev </PERSON> said in a statement of the beating of <PERSON> Weizman </PERSON>'s workers. `` I am afraid the situation in the territories is having a bad influence on the morals and values of the rest of Israeli society,'' he added. One of the four beaten Arabs, 20-year-old <PERSON> Maysara </PERSON> <PERSON> Al-Ijela </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION>, told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Jerusalem </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> that police entered an apartment shared by nine <PERSON> Arab </PERSON> workers Friday and `` did not say anything at first. They just started to hit us with their hands and walkie-talkies, and also kick us.'' `` One policeman said ` You are smelly Arabs. You go home, throw stones at Jews and afterward return here to work,''' <PERSON> Al-Ijela </PERSON> told the daily <ORGANIZATION> Hadashot </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Weizman </PERSON>, owner of the <ORGANIZATION> Shelly </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cafe </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> in </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dizengoff </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>, said after his workers were beaten, he moved them out of their apartment into a hotel and promised to find them a new, safe place to live. `` Three of them ... said no thanks and quit,'' he told The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>. `` The police said they went into the apartment because they thought the Arabs were organizing something, but that is ridiculous. It's just Israeli suspicion of Arabs.'' `` I guess the police had a right to go into that apartment. But the way they handled it was very bad. I need those workers.'' One Israeli, <PERSON> Dalit </PERSON> <PERSON> Laub </PERSON>, witnessed the beatings when she walked past the Arabs' first-floor apartment and glanced in the window. `` It was really violent. But I was afraid to get involved ... I thought of calling the police _ but they were the police,'' she told Hadashot. City Hall was reluctant to get involved. `` The problem of beating Arabs has to be taken care of by the police because it is a criminal issue,'' city spokesman <PERSON> Shabtai </PERSON> <PERSON> Sheval </PERSON> told the <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION>. He refused to say how many incidents involving Arabs were reported in <LOCATION> Tel </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Aviv </LOCATION> over the last month. Police said they were investigating and legal action would be taken if the allegations were found to be correct, police spokeswoman <PERSON> Shlomit </PERSON> <PERSON> Herzberg </PERSON> told the <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION>. Police also were investigating the incident involving <PERSON> Ben-Simon </PERSON>, who was beaten senseless and left on a street. He was driving to work on Feb. 12 when two Israelis flagged him down. `` I thought they needed help, but when I stopped, one of them shouted, ` Here's an Arab maniac!,''' <PERSON> Ben-Simon </PERSON> told the <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION>. `` I said, ` Hey guys, what's going on? I'm not an Arab.''' His protestations did no good. <PERSON> Ben-Simon </PERSON> saw the license plate number of the car as the two sped away, but he could n't pick himself up. An Arab worker helped <PERSON> Ben-Simon </PERSON> off the street and he was taken to a hospital, where his head was stitched. Israeli newspapers reported the first case of harassment about a month ago. An Arab youth said he was picked up on a <LOCATION> Tel </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Aviv </LOCATION> street by two men who identified themselves as police, taken to a garbage dump and beaten. Some harassment has come from Arab militants. City Hall spokesman <PERSON> Benny </PERSON> <PERSON> Cohen </PERSON> said more than 100 Arab workers left their jobs in <LOCATION> Tel </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Aviv </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Yermiyahu </LOCATION> restaurant district last week after their lives and families were threatened if they disobeyed calls from <LOCATION> Palestinian </LOCATION> activists to stay home. There have been cases of alleged discrimination, as well. One Palestinian said he was turned away from a popular <LOCATION> Tel </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Aviv </LOCATION> discotheque. Another complained in an <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> TV interview he was barred `` for security reasons'' from taking a small craft flight with his two children. One Gazan working in a <LOCATION> Tel </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Aviv </LOCATION> restaurant gave a statement to <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Jerusalem </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> last week on condition that his name not be used. He said he was saving money to get married. `` But now, I get this message saying ` Stop working for the Jews, stop working for the oppressors,' and I have to make up my mind,'' he told the <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION>. `` Most of the others have gone. They do n't want anything to happen to them or their families. For me, it is also dangerous.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880223-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-23-88 0159EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-India-Punjab     02-23 0861</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-India-Punjab,0889</SECOND>
<HEAD>Sikhs Slay Sikhs As Punjab Violence Takes New Turn</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</NOTE>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DILIP GANGULY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>KATHUNANGAL, India (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The turban of <PERSON> Darshan </PERSON> <PERSON> Singh </PERSON>, a 12-year-old Sikh, was half burned from the heat of the mud oven where he hid to escape death. But the killers _ Sikhs themselves _ yanked him out, and he died in a burst of gunfire. The boy, his elder brother and their father all died in the courtyard of the village of <LOCATION> Fattu </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bheela </LOCATION>, home of 2,000 Sikhs. It was one more case of Sikhs killing Sikhs. Never before in the radicals' six-year campaign for an independent homeland have the killers turned their guns so relentlessly on people of their own minority faith. Of the 283 deaths blamed on <ORGANIZATION> Sikh </ORGANIZATION> militants this year in the Sikh-dominated northern state of <LOCATION> Punjab </LOCATION>, at least 169 victims were Sikhs. On Friday and Saturday, 31 people died in attacks, at least 20 of them Sikhs. `` The militants want the message to go deep _ that they will not only kill those who oppose them, but even those who refuse to support them,'' said the <LOCATION> Amritsar </LOCATION> district police superintendent, <PERSON> Mohammed </PERSON> <PERSON> Izhar </PERSON> <PERSON> Alam </PERSON>. <PERSON> Harbhajan </PERSON> <PERSON> Kaur </PERSON>, <PERSON> Darshan </PERSON>'s mother, told of the attack last week in the village 18 miles north of <LOCATION> Amritsar </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Sikh </ORGANIZATION> holy city and heart of the radical campaign. She said she was wounded but because of fear, no neighbor came to help. `` I was laying in my courtyard the whole night, bleeding,'' she said from her hospital bed. The Sikh campaign began with attacks on Hindus, <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>'s religious majority but a minority in <LOCATION> Punjab </LOCATION> Last year, most of the 1,000 victims of Sikh radicals were Hindus. The radicals allege economic and cultural domination by <PERSON> Hindus </PERSON> and want an independent homeland for their 16 million people. But theories vary considerably on <ORGANIZATION> Sikh </ORGANIZATION> guns are now aiming at Sikhs. `` Most of the men killed are either former terrorists or harborers and their families who now refuse to give shelter to the militants,'' said <PERSON> S.S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Virk </PERSON>, deputy director general of the paramilitary <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reserve </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION>. The killers themselves claim all Sikh victims are police informers or enemies of the 500-year-old faith, founded as an alternative to the beliefs of warring Moslems and Hindus. `` We shed the blood of only enemies, not of innocents or passive people,'' said <PERSON> Giani </PERSON> <PERSON> Jagir </PERSON> <PERSON> Singh </PERSON>, spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> Panthic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, an umbrella group that controls the Sikh movement. `` Write it down,'' he commanded during an interview in a bare, windowless room in the Sikhs' Golden Temple. `` I have led half a dozen attacks myself and in every case, we killed only police informers.'' Why are Sikh women and children also killed? `` Have you heard of an old <LOCATION> Punjabi </LOCATION> saying _ when you grind wheat to get flour, some millets also get crushed?'' said <PERSON> Singh </PERSON>, 45, a large man with flowing beard. <PERSON> Dewan </PERSON> <PERSON> Singh </PERSON>, a police detective in <LOCATION> Amritsar </LOCATION>, said in most cases the killers wipe out all witnesses because they are recognized by the victims' families. In 19 of the 25 cases he analyzed, the victims knew the killers. In each of the 19 cases, police found half-emptied glasses of milk or sarbat, sweetened water with lemon, which were believed served to the assailants. Rarely did the killers have to force their entry, <PERSON> Dewan </PERSON> <PERSON> Singh </PERSON> said. Such was the case with the family of <PERSON> Darbar </PERSON> <PERSON> Kaur </PERSON>, 50, in the village of <LOCATION> Khera </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bala-Chak </LOCATION> near <LOCATION> Kathunangal </LOCATION>. `` Five Sikh boys came and asked for my younger son, <PERSON> Surjeet </PERSON>. He opened the door and asked his wife to heat up some milk for the visitors,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Kaur </PERSON> said. `` After a few minutes they fired at Surjeet,'' She said. <PERSON> Surjeet </PERSON>, her husband, another son, and a 4-year-old granddaughter were killed, while Mrs. <PERSON> Kaur </PERSON> and her daughter-in-law hid behind a bolted kitchen door. <PERSON> Surjeet </PERSON> had been arrested in July for illegally possessing a firearm and was believed to be a member of the radical group <PERSON> Babbar </PERSON> <PERSON> Khalsa </PERSON>. He was freed on bail Jan. 1. `` He was not a police informer, but he was required under bail provision to report to the police station once a week,'' said <PERSON> Kathunangal </PERSON> police officer <PERSON> Subba </PERSON> <PERSON> Singh </PERSON>. `` So his former associates drew the conclusion that <PERSON> Surjeet </PERSON> had turned informer.'' <PERSON> Singh </PERSON>, responsible for maintaining order in 70 villages with a population of 200,000, said <PERSON> Surjeet </PERSON> was afraid he might be killed. But he said the police do n't have the resources to protect everyone. The killers often leave behind a note written on the stationery of <LOCATION> Khalistan </LOCATION>, the name of their unborn Sikh nation. The letters sometimes even carry reference numbers, such as the A-159 on one left where 12-year-old <PERSON> Darshan </PERSON> <PERSON> Singh </PERSON> died. `` They are our death warrants. ` A' Stands for <PERSON> Akal </PERSON> -LRB- the immortal throne of the Sikh faith -RRB- and the police informer to be killed was 159 on our list,'' explained <PERSON> Giani </PERSON> <PERSON> Jagir </PERSON> <PERSON> Singh </PERSON>, the militant spokesman. He left no doubt that more death warrants could be expected. `` If any of the men on the hit list die a natural death, we will consider it as a great insult to our faith,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880223-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-23-88 0653EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Obit-Shay     02-23 0254</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Obit-Shay,0266</SECOND>
<HEAD>Composer And Coach Of Greats Al Jolson, Jimmy Durante Dies</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEWPORT BEACH, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Composer <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Shay </PERSON>, onetime musical coach of such greats as <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> Jolson </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jimmy </PERSON> <PERSON> Durante </PERSON>, and best known for the song `` When You're Smiling,'' died Monday of lung cancer. He was 90. <PERSON> Shay </PERSON>'s work was recorded by a number of performers including <PERSON> Judy </PERSON> <PERSON> Garland </PERSON>, <PERSON> Bing </PERSON> <PERSON> Crosby </PERSON>, <PERSON> Perry </PERSON> <PERSON> Como </PERSON>, <PERSON> Andy </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>, <PERSON> Louis </PERSON> <PERSON> Armstrong </PERSON>, <PERSON> Nat </PERSON> <PERSON> King </PERSON> <PERSON> Cole </PERSON>, <PERSON> Dean </PERSON> <PERSON> Martin </PERSON>, <PERSON> Doris </PERSON> <PERSON> Day </PERSON> and <PERSON> Guy </PERSON> <PERSON> Lombardo </PERSON>. He was Metro <PERSON> Goldwyn </PERSON> <PERSON> Mayer </PERSON>'s movie musical director in the early 1930s. The composer died at <LOCATION> Hoag </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Memorial </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION> at 1:20 a.m., said a hospital records secretary who did not want her name used. She did not know how long he had been hospitalized. <PERSON> Shay </PERSON> also suffered from emphysema. Despite his illness, <PERSON> Shay </PERSON> continued to perform in a local band for the past decade, family members said. His career started during World War I, when <PERSON> Shay </PERSON> put together a band and show group for soldiers. In the'20s, he lived in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, coaching stars such as Durante, <PERSON> Jolson </PERSON> and <PERSON> Sophie </PERSON> <PERSON> Tucker </PERSON>. In addition to his stint in the movie industry in the early'30s, he served as program director for <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> radio in the late'30s. Among his hits were `` That's <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION>,'' `` <LOCATION> Kentucky </LOCATION>, Sure As You're Born,'' `` When You're Smiling,'' `` Knee Deep In Daisies,'' and `` Tie Me To Your Apron Strings Again.'' He is survived by his wife, <PERSON> Doris </PERSON>; a daughter; a son; seven granchildren; and three great-grandchildren. Private funeral services were planned.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880223-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-23-88 0707EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     02-23 0740</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0770</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in the News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NASHVILLE, Tenn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Singer <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Mandrell </PERSON> will be the host of a celebrity softball game June 3 to benefit the organ donor program at <ORGANIZATION> Vanderbilt </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>. Miss <PERSON> Mandrell </PERSON> said at a news conference Monday that celebrities at the event will include <PERSON> Roy </PERSON> <PERSON> Acuff </PERSON>, <PERSON> Lucille </PERSON> <PERSON> Ball </PERSON>, <PERSON> Patrick </PERSON> <PERSON> Duffy </PERSON>, <PERSON> Ralph </PERSON> <PERSON> Emery </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Morgan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fairchild </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Gifford </PERSON>, <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Hope </PERSON>, <PERSON> Gladys </PERSON> <PERSON> Knight </PERSON>, <PERSON> Emmanuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON>, <PERSON> Willie </PERSON> <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON>, <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> Payton </PERSON>, <PERSON> Minnie </PERSON> <PERSON> Pearl </PERSON>, <PERSON> Ahmad </PERSON> and <PERSON> Phylicia </PERSON> <PERSON> Rashad </PERSON>, <PERSON> Herschel </PERSON> <PERSON> Walker </PERSON>, <PERSON> Danny </PERSON> <PERSON> White </PERSON>, <PERSON> Betty </PERSON> <PERSON> White </PERSON> and <PERSON> Oprah </PERSON> <PERSON> Winfrey </PERSON>. The game will be played at <ORGANIZATION> Vanderbilt </ORGANIZATION>'s football stadium. Tickets will cost $ 10 each, the university said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Princess <PERSON> Anne </PERSON> left <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> for <LOCATION> Uganda </LOCATION> to begin a 12-day visit to three African nations in her capacity as president of the Save the Children Fund. Buckingham Palace said the trip would be the first official visit to <LOCATION> Uganda </LOCATION> by a member of the royal family since 1965. The 37-year-old daughter of Queen <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> II </PERSON> planned to visit several hospitals and clinics set up by the international charity in <LOCATION> Uganda </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mozambique </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Somalia </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NASHVILLE, Tenn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Pulitzer Prize-winning author <PERSON> Alex </PERSON> <PERSON> Haley </PERSON> will be the first recipient of the Bootstraps Foundation Award for overcoming adversity. He will be honored for `` pulling himself up by his bootstraps'' at an April 14 banquet in <LOCATION> Nashville </LOCATION> at which 45 high school seniors will be honored and seven will be awarded college scholarships. The program was announced Monday by its sponsors, the afternoon daily <ORGANIZATION> Nashville </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Banner </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Shoney </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, which owns a restaurant chain. <PERSON> Haley </PERSON>, who was reared in the small western <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> town of <LOCATION> Henning </LOCATION>, won a Pulitzer Prize for his book, `` Roots,'' which traced his ancestry about 200 years. He determined that his fourth great-grandfather was Kunta Kinte of <LOCATION> Gambia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>, who was kidnapped in 1767 and brought to <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> as a slave. <PERSON> Haley </PERSON> enlisted in the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> in 1939 as a mess boy and served for 20 years in the military before starting a free-lance magazine writing career.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actress <PERSON> Susan </PERSON> <PERSON> Dey </PERSON>, the sulky legal eagle on <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` L.A. Law,'' married movie industry executive <PERSON> Bernie </PERSON> <PERSON> Sofronski </PERSON> during a private ceremony, her publicist says. With a few show business pals as witnesses, Miss <PERSON> Dey </PERSON> recited wedding vows with <PERSON> Sofronski </PERSON> on Saturday at the <LOCATION> Bel-Air </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hotel </LOCATION>, publicist <PERSON> Nann </PERSON> <PERSON> Sumski </PERSON> said Monday. The entire `` L.A. Law'' cast attended, including <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> Hamlin </PERSON>, <PERSON> Corbin </PERSON> <PERSON> Bernsen </PERSON>, <PERSON> Michele </PERSON> <PERSON> Greene </PERSON>, <PERSON> Jill </PERSON> <PERSON> Eikenberry </PERSON>, <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Tucker </PERSON>, <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Dysart </PERSON> and the show's creators <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> <PERSON> Louise </PERSON> <PERSON> Fisher </PERSON> and <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> Bochco </PERSON>, said Ms. <PERSON> Sumski </PERSON>. It was the second marriage for Miss <PERSON> Dey </PERSON>, 35, who has a 9-year-old daughter. <PERSON> Sofronski </PERSON>, 47, formerly with <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Television </ORGANIZATION>, is an executive at <ORGANIZATION> Warner </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bros </ORGANIZATION>. They met through a friend at a party and dated for two years before announcing their engagement 18 months ago, the spokeswoman said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>DENVER (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Outspoken former Gov. <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Lamm </PERSON> is back in the public eye, this time as a twice-weekly commentator for a <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION> television station. `` You can make fun of television. I sometimes do,'' <PERSON> Lamm </PERSON> said in a recent interview. But he quickly added that polls show more than 70 percent of the public's political information comes from TV. `` It's sad but true, we've gone from town hall <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> to airwaves <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>,'' he said. `` How many senators are more powerful than <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Chancellor </PERSON>?'' <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION>'s KMGH-TV, which is running <PERSON> Lamm </PERSON>'s commentaries during its news programs on Tuesdays and Thursdays, says that if <PERSON> Lamm </PERSON> gets too controversial, it will add a `` counterpoint'' speaker for balance. `` All they told me is there are seven words you ca n't use on television. I did n't even ask what they are,'' <PERSON> Lamm </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Lamm </PERSON>, a Democrat, has made a cause of pointing out the pessimistic aspects of the high cost of medical care, earning himself the nickname `` Governor Gloom.'' <PERSON> Lamm </PERSON> also is a professor at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Denver </ORGANIZATION>, and says he may run for the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> in two years.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>BEVERLY HILLS, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actor <PERSON> Patrick </PERSON> <PERSON> Swayze </PERSON>, basking in the $ 60 million box office gross of `` Dirty Dancing,'' will next be cast as the reluctant hero of a <LOCATION> Midwest </LOCATION> town fraught with corruption, a spokeswoman said. <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Artists </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pictures </ORGANIZATION> will soon begin shooting `` Roadhouse'' starring <PERSON> Swayze </PERSON> as a man who rallies townspeople to stand up against corruption, said studio spokeswoman <PERSON> Amy </PERSON> <PERSON> Kimmelman </PERSON>. <PERSON> Swayze </PERSON>'s most recent role was as a charismatic dance instructor in `` Dirty Dancing.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880223-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-23-88 0706EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Deaths 1stLd-Writethru a0797 02-23 0844</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Deaths, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0797,0876</SECOND>
<NOTE>Eds: ADDS Shay a0418, Blackman a0827, Price a0636 and Bishop; AMs
separates moved as a0746 on Williams, a0663 on Allegro, a0666 on
Debo, a0750 on Fuller.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Roger Williams</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>AUSTIN (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>, recognized as one of the world's foremost authorities on nutrition, died Saturday at age 94. <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> was a professor emeritus at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION>. His work in nutrition at the <ORGANIZATION> UT </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Clayton </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Biochemical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION>, which he founded, led to the discovery of more vitamins and their variants than at any other research facility in the world. One of <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>' most significant accomplishments was the discovery and isolation of pantothenic acid, one of the `` universal vitamins'' required by all living cells and essential to life. Later he discovered and named folic acid, a substance used by every cell in the body. <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> wrote a book on `` biochemical individuality,'' a concept that no two people are exactly alike physiologically and therefore everyone has different nutritional requirements. He retired in 1985.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>John Allegro</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Allegro </PERSON>, renowned for his work in deciphering the Dead Sea Scrolls but ridiculed for his theories that Western religions were based on the worship of mushrooms, died Feb. 17. He was 65. Allegro was a brilliant student of Semitic languages at <ORGANIZATION> Manchester </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> and went on to study Hebrew dialects at <ORGANIZATION> Oxford </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. In 1953, <PERSON> Allegro </PERSON> was named to an international team formed to decipher the Dead Sea Scrolls, which were discovered in caves at <LOCATION> Qumran </LOCATION>. The scrolls included the oldest known manuscripts of books from the Old Testament. Allegro's gift for deciphering minute texts was crucial. His book, `` The Dead Sea Scrolls,'' was published in 1956 and became a bestseller. In his 1970 book `` The Sacred Mushroom and the Cross,'' he contended that <ORGANIZATION> Judaism </ORGANIZATION> and Christianity were in fact products of an ancient sex-and-mushroom cult. Allegro also published a 1966 book, `` Search in the Desert,'' about an unsuccessful search for lost scrolls in the <LOCATION> Judean </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Desert </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>Angie Debo</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MARSHALL, Okla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Angie </PERSON> <PERSON> Debo </PERSON>, 98, who came to <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION> by covered wagon and became known as `` The First Lady of <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION> <LOCATION> History </LOCATION>,'' died Sunday. Miss <PERSON> Debo </PERSON> wrote 13 books and hundreds of articles about Indian and <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION> history. Her books include `` The Rise and Fall of the <LOCATION> Choctaw </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Republic </LOCATION>,'' `` And Still The Waters Run,'' `` Geronimo: The Man, His Time, His Place'' and `` Prairie City.'' A one-hour documentary on <PERSON> Miss </PERSON> <PERSON> Debo </PERSON>'s life and work is scheduled to be broadcast next fall as part of <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Broadcasting </ORGANIZATION>'s `` The American Experience'' series.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>David Fuller</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>GRAND RAPIDS, Mich. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Otis </PERSON> <PERSON> Fuller </PERSON>, a fundamentalist preacher who helped found a children's radio ministry and the <ORGANIZATION> Grand </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rapids </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Baptist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> and Seminary, died Sunday at the age of 84. <PERSON> Fuller </PERSON> founded the Children's Bible Hour, a Grand Rapids-based Christian radio program now broadcast by 660 radio stations worldwide. He was pastor until his 1974 retirement.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>Larry Shay</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEWPORT BEACH, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Shay </PERSON>, a composer, the musical coach of such greats as <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> Jolson </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jimmy </PERSON> <PERSON> Durante </PERSON>, and best known for the song `` When You're Smiling,'' died Monday of lung cancer at age 90. <PERSON> Shay </PERSON>'s musical career spanned the 1920s through the 1960s and his work was recorded by <PERSON> Judy </PERSON> <PERSON> Garland </PERSON>, <PERSON> Bing </PERSON> <PERSON> Crosby </PERSON>, <PERSON> Perry </PERSON> <PERSON> Como </PERSON>, <PERSON> Andy </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>, <PERSON> Louis </PERSON> <PERSON> Armstrong </PERSON>, <PERSON> Nat </PERSON> <PERSON> King </PERSON> <PERSON> Cole </PERSON>, <PERSON> Dean </PERSON> <PERSON> Martin </PERSON>, <PERSON> Doris </PERSON> <PERSON> Day </PERSON> and <PERSON> Guy </PERSON> <PERSON> Lombardo </PERSON>. He was Metro <PERSON> Goldwyn </PERSON> <PERSON> Mayer </PERSON>'s movie musical director in the early 1930s. <PERSON> Shay </PERSON> composed such hits as `` That's <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION>,'' `` <LOCATION> Kentucky </LOCATION>, Sure As You're Born,'' `` When You're Smiling,'' `` Knee Deep In Daisies,'' and `` Tie Me To Your Apron Strings Again.'' In the late 1930s, <PERSON> Shay </PERSON> went to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> and served as program director for <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> radio.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>Carl Blackman</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>GEORGETOWN, Guyana (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Carl </PERSON> <PERSON> Blackman </PERSON>, who contributed to Guyanese journalism for more than 40 years, died Thursday of a heart ailment. He was 67. <PERSON> Blackman </PERSON> wrote for the old <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chronicle </ORGANIZATION>, the <LOCATION> Guyana </LOCATION> Graphic, the state-owned <ORGANIZATION> Guyana </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chronicle </ORGANIZATION>, the <LOCATION> Trinidad </LOCATION> Evening News, the <LOCATION> Trinidad </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Guardian </LOCATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Guyana </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Newspapers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Limited </ORGANIZATION>. He also was an <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> stringer in <LOCATION> Guyana </LOCATION>. Seven years ago <PERSON> Blackman </PERSON> retired as first general manager and editor-in-chief of the <ORGANIZATION> Guyana </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Newspapers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Limited </ORGANIZATION>. He continued to write his popular columns regularly for the Sunday Chronicle until shortly before his death.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>Francis Price</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BARTLESVILLE, Okla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Frances </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Price </PERSON>, the sister of <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> radio personality <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Harvey </PERSON>, died Saturday at age 79.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>Isabel Bishop</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Isabel </PERSON> <PERSON> Bishop </PERSON>, 85, a artist known for her work depicting the everyday activities of <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> women, died Friday of Parkinson's disease. Miss <PERSON> Bishop </PERSON> studied at the Arts Students League with <PERSON> Kenneth </PERSON> <PERSON> Hayes </PERSON> <PERSON> Miller </PERSON> and <PERSON> Guy </PERSON> <PERSON> Pene </PERSON> <PERSON> du </PERSON> <PERSON> Bois </PERSON>. She began a series of Union Square paintings after leaving the League in 1924. Miss <PERSON> Bishop </PERSON> joined <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION>'s Midtown Gallery and the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Design </ORGANIZATION> and remained affiliated until her death. <PERSON> Bishop </PERSON> was known for her work depicting the everyday activities of <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> women and for showing life as it existed around Union Square in 1930.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880223-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-23-88 0213EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-SovietEconomist     02-23 0723</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Soviet Economist,0745</SECOND>
<HEAD>Soviet Economist Says Soviet Union at `Critical Stage'</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BRIAN FRIEDMAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s economic reforms have been formulated and explained sufficiently to the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> people, and now it's time to `` start taking action,'' <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>'s top economist says. <PERSON> Abel </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Aganbegyan </PERSON> also said there are `` painful and difficult'' days ahead for the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> under `` perestroika,'' <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s wholesale restructuring of the stagnant economy, and that bureaucratic opposition to the reforms remains <PERSON> Aganbegyan </PERSON>, the chief economic adviser to the Soviet leader and an architect of perestroika, also said the average Soviet family has yet to reap its benefits. `` A little bit more than two years have elapsed since we started the process, the initial stage, where we are developing our concepts, making our programs, trying to understand what's going on, what has to be done, and a period during which we have to try to convince people of the necessity undertaking these new changes,'' he said. `` This period is now coming to an end. We are getting to a much more critical stage, which is a stage where we have to start taking action.'' He and several of his colleagues on Monday outlined the history and pitfalls of perestroika to a conference of economics students and faculty at the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Social </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> as part of an U.S.-Soviet academic exchange program. <PERSON> Aganbegyan </PERSON> said the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> has `` only made the first steps'' toward loosening the top-heavy central controls that have driven the economy since the <PERSON> Stalin </PERSON> era and emphasized heavy industry over consumer goods. `` In fact, most families have not really benefited from what's been done so far,'' he said through a translator `` We have to accelerate the whole process so as to achieve a breakthrough in the next two or three years so that everyone in the country will feel he has a stake in the process.'' In addition to consumer goods, the biggest Soviet economic failures during the past 15 years were in housing, health care, education and agriculture, he said. To remedy the problems, he cited modest increases in construction of new apartments and budget increases for education and medicine, including 30 percent salary increases for teachers, doctors and some other health care workers. He did not say how the military budget would be affected. He also singled out the planned overhaul the machine tool industry, which will be `` the basis for the reconstruction of the whole manufacturing sector.'' `` In 1985, we were able to replace 3.1 percent of all our machine tools. In 1987, 9 percent were replaced, and by 1990 we hope to replace 13 percent of the machine tools yearly,'' <PERSON> Aganbegyan </PERSON> said. `` This is a painful and difficult process, but we have to go through it. We have n't any other alternative.'' <PERSON> Aganbegyan </PERSON> also cited the policies of `` khozrachyot,'' or self-accounting, that went into effect Jan. 1. The law gives state-run factories and firms more autonomy, with more emphasis on profits and job performance. He said factories must go `` on a completely cost-accounting basis, self-financing basis and self-administrating basis.'' <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s policies of perestroika have come under `` a good deal of opposition, however, from the people in the economic administrative bureaucracies,'' in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> and in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>'s 15 republics, he said `` We have reduced the staff and fired or eliminated 110,000 jobs in the central and republican administrative apparatus,'' <PERSON> Aganbegyan </PERSON> said. The opposition has not been confined to the bureaucracy, said another conference participant, <PERSON> Timur </PERSON> <PERSON> T. </PERSON> <PERSON> Timofeev </PERSON>. `` We can not say that the whole working class 100 percent is for <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>,'' said <PERSON> Timofeev </PERSON>, director of the <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> the </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Movement </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> the </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Soviet </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sciences </ORGANIZATION>. `` The new working class _ the younger generation, the much-more-educated generation _ is really the leading force, the dynamic force of perestroika,'' he said. Some Soviets `` are accustomed to the old ways of work,'' preferring less pay and less work. <PERSON> Aganbegyan </PERSON> acknowledged that the restructuring at many factories and companies in the next 15 to 20 years will throw 16 million of people out of work _ in a nation where the constitution provides that everyone shall have a job. These people `` will therefore have to be retrained and given additional jobs,'' he said. Special employment offices will be set up to retrain them and find them work, he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880223-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-23-88 0023EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-BoxOffice 1stLd-Writethru a0818 02-23 0592</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Box Office, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0818,0606</SECOND>
<HEAD>Three Disney Movies in Top 5, `Moonstruck' Gets Oscar Nominations
Boost</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: SUBS 10th graf, `Broadcast News...', to CORRECT that `Last
Emperor' in 9th place, `Broadcast News' in 10th, sted the other way
around. Picks up 11th graf, `Here are..'.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By JEFF WILSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>HOLLYWOOD (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 `` Good Morning, Vietnam'' and two other <ORGANIZATION> Disney </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Studios </ORGANIZATION> pictures remained in the box office Top 5 while the offbeat romantic film `` Moonstruck'' capitalized on its Oscar nominations to secure the No. 3 spot. `` Moonstruck'' seemed to lure moviegoers with its nominations, but weekend receipts do n't reflect an interest surge in other Oscar contenders, including No. 9 `` The Last Emperor'' and No. 10 `` Broadcast News.'' `` The Last Emperor'' got the most Academy Award nominations last week with nine, `` Broadcast News'' got seven and `` Moonstruck'' got six. <PERSON> Disney-Touchstone </PERSON> awoke to a sixth week atop the box office heap with `` Good Morning, <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>,'' featuring best actor Academy Award nominee <PERSON> Robin </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> as a raucous <LOCATION> Saigon </LOCATION> disc jockey, ringing in nearly $ 7 million. Second in the studio's one-two turnstile punch was `` Shoot to Kill,'' featuring <PERSON> Sidney </PERSON> <PERSON> Poitier </PERSON> in his first movie in nine years, taking in $ 4.8 million in its second week of release. `` Moonstruck'' was a close third with $ 4.7 million last weekend and `` Action Jackson'' took in $ 3.6 million in its second week to place fourth. Meanwhile, the No. 5 spot was occupied by <PERSON> Disney-Touchstone </PERSON>'s `` Three Men And A Baby'' which kept turnstiles spinning in its 12th week of release with a $ 3.5 million take The movie has made $ 136 million so far. The three Disney-Touchstone films have raked in $ 220 million for the studio and its <ORGANIZATION> Buena </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Vista </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pictures </ORGANIZATION> distribution arm, whose senior vice president <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Cook </PERSON> said simply: `` We are delighted with these latest box office figures.'' Universal's creepy `` The Serpent and the Rainbow'' brought in $ 2.3 million for a drop to sixth in its second week of release. The <PERSON> Kevin </PERSON> <PERSON> Bacon </PERSON> film `` She's Having a Baby'' was seventh with $ 2.1 million and <PERSON> Justine </PERSON> <PERSON> Bateman </PERSON>'s `` Satisfaction'' was eighth with $ 1.7 million. `` The Last Emperor'' was ninth with $ 1.71 million in receipts and `` Broadcast News,'' which got <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Hurt </PERSON>, <PERSON> Holly </PERSON> <PERSON> Hunter </PERSON> and <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Brooks </PERSON> acting Oscar nominations, was 10th with $ 1.63 million. Here are the top films for the weekend as tallied by <ORGANIZATION> Exhibitor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Relations </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, with distributor, weekend gross, number of theater screens, average per screen, total gross, number of weeks in release and estimated production costs. 1. `` Good Morning, <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>,'' Disney-Touchstone, $ 6.88 million, 1,598 screens, $ 4,308 per screen, $ 71.4 million, eight weeks, $ 21 million. 2. `` Shoot to Kill,'' Disney-Touchstone, $ 4.84 million, 1,519 screens, $ 3,191 per screen, $ 11.93 million, two weeks. 3. `` Moonstruck,'' <ORGANIZATION> MGM-UA </ORGANIZATION>, $ 4.73 million, 1,163 screens, $ 4,057 per screen, $ 36.5 million, nine weeks, $ 17 million. 4. `` Action <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>,'' <PERSON> Lorimar </PERSON>, $ 3.61 million, 1,250 screens, $ 2,888 per screen, $ 10 million, two weeks. 5. `` Three Men And A Baby,'' Disney-Touchstone, $ 3.53 million, 1,689 screens, $ 2,095 per screen, $ 136.58 million, 12 weeks, $ 18 million. 6. `` The Serpent and the Rainbow,'' Universal, $ 2.3 million, 1,211 screens, $ 1,905 per screen, $ 14.5 million, two weeks, $ 8 million. 7. `` She's Having a Baby,'' Paramount, $ 2.1 million, 1,133 screens, $ 1,858 per screen, $ 10.55 million, two weeks, n-a. 8. `` Satisfaction,'' <ORGANIZATION> Twentieth </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Century </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fox </ORGANIZATION>, $ 1.79 million, 1,018 screens, $ 1,763 per screen, $ 5.11 million, two weeks, n-a. 9. `` The Last Emperor,'' <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION>, $ 1.71 million, 375 screens, $ 4,560 per screen, $ 16 million, 13 weeks, $ 25 million. 10. `` Broadcast News,'' <ORGANIZATION> Twentieth </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Century </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fox </ORGANIZATION>, $ 1.63 million, 798 screens, $ 2,065 per screen, $ 40.67 million, nine weeks, $ 15 million.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880223-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-23-88 0246EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Toner-Monopoly     02-23 0415</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Toner-Monopoly,410</SECOND>
<HEAD>ITC Reverses Judge, Says Canon Innocent Of Monopoly Violations</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CHRISTOPHER CALLAHAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An administrative law judge was wrong when he ruled last year that <ORGANIZATION> Canon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> USA </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> illegally monopolized the domestic market for dry ink used in some office copying machines, the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Trade </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> says. The commission, in a 6-0 ruling Monday, overturned Judge <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Mathias </PERSON> and terminated the investigation. <PERSON> Mathias </PERSON> had ruled in November that <ORGANIZATION> Canon </ORGANIZATION>, a copy machine giant, had violated <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> trade laws by unfairly disparaging independent toner distributors. <ORGANIZATION> Aunyx </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, a small toner producer based in <LOCATION> Hingham </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mass. </LOCATION>, had charged that <ORGANIZATION> Canon </ORGANIZATION> representatives were telling customers that toner from competitors was `` pirate'' merchandise. <ORGANIZATION> ITC </ORGANIZATION> attorney <PERSON> Edwin </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Madaj </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> said an opinion detailing why the commission overturned the judge's decision will not be available for at least several days. He declined to outline the commission's reasoning. `` Naturally we're very disappointed,'' said <PERSON> Lorraine </PERSON> <PERSON> Hanley </PERSON>, vice president for dealer sales at <LOCATION> Aunyx </LOCATION>. `` We do n't know why the commission voted this way.'' <ORGANIZATION> Canon </ORGANIZATION> lawyers argued that corporate representatives did not make disparaging remarks about independent competitors, and if they did, `` it was very minor stuff, the kind of competitive talk that is normal in any industry where there are competitors,'' said <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> attorney <PERSON> Harvey </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Applebaum </PERSON>. `` We have always said that we would be completely vindicated as this case evolved,'' <ORGANIZATION> Canon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> USA </ORGANIZATION> President <PERSON> Fujio </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitarai </PERSON> said in a statement from corporate headquarters in <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Success </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION> `` This decision makes clear that we were right on the law, on the facts and in the way we market our products.'' <PERSON> Aunyx </PERSON> has estimated that the toner market for copiers in question is worth about $ 250 million annually, but <PERSON> Applebaum </PERSON> said `` that sounds to me very exaggerated.'' The companies competed for sale of toner for certain types of <ORGANIZATION> Canon </ORGANIZATION> copiers, mostly low - and medium-volume office machines Aunyx President <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Langone </PERSON> said last year that <ORGANIZATION> Canon </ORGANIZATION> had about 99 percent of that market while <PERSON> Aunyx </PERSON> and other independent toner dealers take between 20 percent and 50 percent of the toner markets of other copying giants like <ORGANIZATION> Xerox </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> IBM </ORGANIZATION>. The <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> company, which once had 85 employees, is down to fewer than 30, Ms. <PERSON> Hanley </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Bart </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Fisher </PERSON>, an attorney representing <PERSON> Aunyx </PERSON>, said he would appeal the <ORGANIZATION> ITC </ORGANIZATION> ruling to the <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Circuit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appeals </ORGANIZATION>. A separate $ 300 million antitrust suit filed by Aunyx against <ORGANIZATION> Canon </ORGANIZATION> is pending in <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880223-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-23-88 0248EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FarmScene     02-23 0815</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Farm Scene,810</SECOND>
<HEAD>France Saying Bienvenue To American Farm Goods</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DON KENDALL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Farm Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Farmers hear a lot about the <ORGANIZATION> European </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Community </ORGANIZATION>'s barriers to <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> agricultural exports, but there is a brighter side too. The Europeans, particularly French consumers, are developing as an even larger market for <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> food products. Overall, the 12-nation bloc took $ 6.8 billion of the $ 27.9 billion in <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> farm exports in the 1987 fiscal year that ended last Sept. 30, up 5 percent from 1986. A further gain to around $ 7 billion is expected this year. Despite the increase and prospects for further growth, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> farm exports are still far below the record levels of the early 1980s. Thus, every possibility is examined eagerly by <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> trade experts. The <ORGANIZATION> EEC </ORGANIZATION> ranks second only to <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION> as a regional market for American farmers. <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, with <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> farm imports of $ 5.55 billion last year, is the largest single-country foreign market. A recent <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> report says, `` The time is right for <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> exporters to consider the French food market.'' Last year <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> imported $ 495 million worth of agricultural products from the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, up from $ 435 million in 1986 and $ 403 million in 1985. In the heyday of the early'80s, <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> bought a peak of $ 625 million worth of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> food and raw commodities. <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> is the largest country in <LOCATION> Western </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, with a population of 55 million and an area of 213,000 square miles _ about four-fifths the size of <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, says the report by the department's <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>. `` Changing lifestyles _ more working women, urban rather than rural life, eating lunch at work, and a greater standard of living _ have led to changes in the food habits of the French people,'' the report said. `` They are consuming more processed products, like canned food and precooked dishes.'' For example, the report said, <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>'s per capita consumption of fresh vegetables held steady from 1967 to 1982 but the average use of frozen vegetables rose from 0.5 pounds per capita to 6.6 pounds. The consumption of canned vegetables jumped to 44 pounds per person in 1982 from 24.9 pounds in 1967. `` According to the <ORGANIZATION> French </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Food </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Industry </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> ANIA </ORGANIZATION>, there have been dramatic changes in consumer spending patterns since 1960,'' the report said. `` The association's data show that the French buy more pastries, cooked and preserved meats, cheese, ice cream, cooked dishes, confectionery products and non-alcoholic beverages as a percentage of their total budget.'' Meanwhile, the report added, the share of family spending on wine, bread, fruits and vegetables, and butter, has decreased. The analysis, prepared by <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Newman </PERSON> and <PERSON> Victor </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Miesel </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, was included in the current <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Food </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Review </ORGANIZATION>, a quarterly magazine issued by the <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> agency. American goods compete with agricultural products from other <ORGANIZATION> EEC </ORGANIZATION> member countries, which are generally admitted freely into <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>. `` However, specific products of high quality with unique characteristics can find a place on the French market regardless of barriers, exchange rates and competitive pressures,'' the report said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> has bought an addition 405,000 metric tons of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> wheat at subsidized prices for delivery in the 1987-88 marketing year, according to the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>. The sales, equal to almost 14.9 million bushels, were handled by five companies: <ORGANIZATION> Cargill </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, 135,000 tons; <ORGANIZATION> Nichimen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, 35,000; <ORGANIZATION> Bunge </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, 35,000; <ORGANIZATION> Continental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Grain </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, 100,000; and <ORGANIZATION> Artfer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, 100,000. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Davis </PERSON>, acting general sales manager for the department's <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agricultural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>, said Monday the sales were part of an authorized 1.2 million tons of wheat announced Feb. 5 under the Export Enhancement Program, or EEP. Although no selling prices or other details were announced, recent prices of wheat at farm points have averaged around $ 2.76 per bushel, indicating a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> farm value of about $ 41 million. A metric ton is about 2,205 pounds and is equal to 36.7 bushels of wheat. <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> bought more than 4 million tons of wheat under previous EEP arrangements, which allow exporters to sell commodities at reduced prices in order to meet foreign competition and then collect free government surpluses of grain or other commodities as bonuses, or subsidies. <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> said the bonuses due the five companies averaged $ 40.38 per ton, or about $ 1.10 per bushel of wheat. The bonuses will be paid in the form of surplus commodities owned by the department's <ORGANIZATION> Commodity </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Credit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>. <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> has 495,000 tons remaining for use under the <ORGANIZATION> EEP </ORGANIZATION> initiative announced on Feb. 5, he
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Inventories of frozen beef are down 2 percent from a year ago, but the supply of frozen pork is up 31 percent, an <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> report shows. As of Jan. 31, the beef stockpile was about 313 million pounds, down from 320.6 million a year earlier, the report showed Monday. Frozen pork, at 285.6 million pounds, was up from 217.7 million.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880223-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-23-88 0251EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-BudgetReport     02-23 0477</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Budget Report,460</SECOND>
<HEAD>Social Security Mailouts Affected January Surplus, December
Deficit</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARTIN CRUTSINGER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The government enjoyed a rare budget surplus last month because Social Security checks for January were mailed before the new year began. The <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> said Monday that the surplus between government spending and revenues jumped to $ 16.09 billion in January, a sharp turnaround following a December deficit of $ 24.22 billion. Both months were influenced by Social Security, the government's biggest benefits program The government ended up making two payments in December, the regular one and the January payment, which was mailed on Dec. 31 because of the New Year's holiday. In January, government revenue totaled $ 81.79 billion, down 4.3 percent from December. Government spending was almost half the December total, dropping to $ 65.71 billion in January, compared with $ 109.74 billion the month before. The surplus was the first since September and only the second in the past 16 months. For the first four months of the fiscal year, which began Oct. 1, the deficit totals $ 65.81 billion, down 0.7 percent from the same period in the 1987 fiscal year. For the first four months of this fiscal year, government revenues have totaled $ 286.66 billion, 5.5 percent higher than a year ago. Government spending totaled $ 352.46 billion, an increase of 4.2 percent over the same period a year ago. For all of 1988, the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration is projecting the budget deficit will fall to $ 146.74 billion, down 2.5 percent from last year's deficit of $ 150.4 billion. The <ORGANIZATION> Congressional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Budget </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION>, using less optimistic assumptions about economic growth this year, projects a 1988 budget deficit of $ 157 billion, substantially above the target of $ 144 billion set in the Gramm-Rudman deficit reduction law. President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> sent <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> his budget recommendations for 1989 last Thursday, predicting a 1989 deficit of $ 129.5 billion. The largest spending categories in January were, as usual, the military, followed by Social Security, other programs in the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Human </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> and interest on the national debt. Military spending totaled $ 19.23 billion last month and $ 93.52 billion for the fiscal year so far, up 6.5 percent from the same period a year ago. Spending for Social Security totaled just $ 652 million last month and $ 70.14 billion for the past four months, up 4.6 percent from a year ago. The other Health and Human Services programs, including <ORGANIZATION> Medicare </ORGANIZATION> and Medicaid, spent $ 50.51 billion in January and $ 49.93 billion so far this budget year, a 1.1 percent increase over 1987. Interest on the $ 2.2 trillion national debt totaled $ 14.67 billion last month and $ 75.77 billion so far this fiscal year, an increase of 9.8 percent over the same period last year. For the 1988 fiscal year, interest payments on the debt are expected to total $ 210.06 billion, accounting for 20 percent of total federal spending.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880223-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-23-88 0254EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-WebbResigns Bjt   02-23 0856</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Webb Resigns, Bjt,860</SECOND>
<HEAD>Pentagon Disputes, Dirty Linen Aired in Navy Resignation</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By NORMAN BLACK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Military Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Webb </PERSON>'s abrupt resignation blew the lid off his split with <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Carlucci </PERSON> and revealed bitter infighting at the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> as it grapples with budget cuts after years of Reagan-era increases. <PERSON> Webb </PERSON> resigned Monday and decided to air some dirty linen on the way out, accusing <PERSON> Carlucci </PERSON> of needlessly sinking the administration's dream of building a 600-ship fleet. He further accused <PERSON> Carlucci </PERSON> of ordering him to lie about internal budget fighting, saying the defense chief had written him a note saying he should deny news stories reporting it was the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> _ and not the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> _ proposing to mothball ships. `` Now, I'm not going to deny the truth,'' <PERSON> Webb </PERSON> said. `` This building needs to be led. ... It needs some vision,'' he continued. `` If I had a piece of advice to give to Secretary <PERSON> Carlucci </PERSON>, it would be to spend a lot more time with the top leaders in this building. `` He's been spending a lot of time with the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> and a lot of time on the -LRB- Capitol -RRB- <PERSON> Hill </PERSON>. I think they -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> leaders -RRB- need to feel his vision and to understand what he believes in.'' <PERSON> Carlucci </PERSON> declined to respond Monday, issuing a written statement saying only that he learned of <PERSON> Webb </PERSON>'s resignation `` with regret.'' The <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> added in a separate statement, though, that if <PERSON> Webb </PERSON> decided he could not `` defend the department's decisions'' on the budget, then `` under the circumstances, he has done the honorable thing.'' An administration official who asked not to be identified said <PERSON> Carlucci </PERSON> was recommending that <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Ball </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>, the assistant to the president for legislative affairs, be nominated to replace <PERSON> Webb </PERSON>. The White House might announce <PERSON> Ball </PERSON>'s nomination today at the same time it formally accepts <PERSON> Webb </PERSON>'s resignation, the source said. The 42-year-old <PERSON> Webb </PERSON>, a highly decorated <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> combat veteran who earlier worked as an assistant defense secretary, said he had been contemplating resignation for some time but did n't make up his mind until Sunday. The final impetus, he said, was the submission to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> last week of the fiscal 1989 <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> budget. <PERSON> Carlucci </PERSON> shaped it without regard to the advice of the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>'s top civilian and military leadership, <PERSON> Webb </PERSON> said. `` I can not support the reductions that are in this budget,'' he said. The massive military buildup under President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, which has seen the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION>'s budget more than double, is coming to a halt because of concerns about the huge federal deficits run up during the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> years. <PERSON> Carlucci </PERSON>, following up on a deficit-reduction agreement reached by the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> in December, submitted a fiscal 1989 budget proposal totaling $ 299.5 billion, slightly more than for fiscal 1988 but unlikely to cover inflation. It cuts the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>'s original 1989 spending plan by $ 12.3 billion and calls for, among other things, mothballing 16 older frigates Those ships are at the heart of the dispute that erupted Monday. <PERSON> Webb </PERSON> said they did n't have to be retired and that if they were, the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> could never reach its goal of deploying a 600-ship fleet. The <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> maintains the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> will end fiscal 1989 with 580 ships and can still reach 600 by fiscal 1992. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, former <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Caspar </PERSON> <PERSON> Weinberger </PERSON>, and <PERSON> Webb </PERSON>'s predecessor, <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Lehman </PERSON>, all have insisted that the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> needs a minimum of 600 warships to satisfy <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> commitments around the world without requiring overly long deployments <PERSON> Webb </PERSON>, in his letter of resignation and in a meeting with reporters, said he had provided <PERSON> Carlucci </PERSON> with three different plans for cutting the necessary dollars without mothballing the ships. At the very least, he said, the 16 frigates could be transferred to the <ORGANIZATION> Naval </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reserve </ORGANIZATION> at a cost of less than $ 100 million and stay on standby. `` In each case, the advice of this senior -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> -RRB- leadership, concurred in by the <ORGANIZATION> Joint </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chiefs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Staff </ORGANIZATION>, was ignored,'' <PERSON> Webb </PERSON> wrote. `` I can only conclude that the decision to reduce the level of our fleet ... was motivated by other than military and strategic reasoning.'' <PERSON> Webb </PERSON> declined to say why he thought <PERSON> Carlucci </PERSON> had ignored his advice. A ranking <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> official who asked not to be named, however, said <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> executives for a time eyed the 16 frigates as ships that could be offered for sale to <LOCATION> Portugal </LOCATION> at a cut rate. <LOCATION> Portugal </LOCATION> was n't interested, the source added. The administration is trying to find ways of increasing military assistance to <LOCATION> Portugal </LOCATION> to preserve access to an air base on the <LOCATION> Azores </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Islands </LOCATION>. White House spokesman <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said: `` Secretary <PERSON> Carlucci </PERSON> is having to make some very difficult adjustments in the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> to accommodate budgetary reductions. Secretary <PERSON> Webb </PERSON> indicates he is unable to operate under these constraints, but I know the president feels he has given very valuable service to the country.'' <PERSON> Webb </PERSON>, who became <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> secretary 10 months ago after serving as an assistant defense secretary under <PERSON> Weinberger </PERSON>, is an attorney and the author of the best-selling Vietnam War novel `` Fields of Fire.'' He said he probably would return to writing.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880223-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-23-88 0257EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-TarmacTuesday Bjt   02-23 0844</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Tarmac Tuesday, Bjt,820</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHINGTON WIRE: Covering the South, Airport to Satellite</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By WILLIAM M. WELCH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>DALLAS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 They call it Super Tuesday. A better name might be Tarmac Tuesday. Or maybe Satellite Tuesday. The Tuesday comes in two weeks, on March 8. What's super about it is that the day will be the closest <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> has ever come to holding a national primary election to select presidential nominees. Democratic and Republican nominees may not be decided then, but the presidential landscape will be altered. Twenty of the 50 states hold primaries or caucuses, and they are scattered from <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION>. Yet Tuesday has a distinctly Southern flavor. Fourteen of those 20 states are in the <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> or border regions. Every state of the <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> save <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> holds delegate contests that day _ and the Republicans in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> hold theirs three days earlier. To campaign across that vast expanse of country, the presidential candidates have found agreement. The only way really is for the candidate to wing his way to as many cities as possible each day in an effort to get his face, and maybe even a few of his words, on the local television news. No candidate, they reason, can buy enough television commercials to carry 20 states in a two - to three-week campaign, although some will try So they aim for the `` free'' TV time. Hence Tarmac Tuesday. Many of the candidates are seeing no more of the states or cities where they campaign than can be viewed from the airports where they hold news conferences, or more often the case, from the single event they hold not far from the airport. Then it's quickly off to the next event in the next `` media market.'' They are `` press hits'' in the jargon of this campaign. `` Look for a lot of hits that are close to the airports,'' said <PERSON> Ed </PERSON> <PERSON> Reilly </PERSON>, a polltaker and strategist for one of the Democrats, <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON>. `` You look for your opportunities within 20 minutes from the airports, so you can get back and on to the next one.'' Quick campaign stops are nothing new to presidential campaigns. But it's hardly what the architects of the Southern regional primary had in mind. They wanted to take some of the thunder away from <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION>. For all the criticism of those two early states, candidates do spend a lot of time there and really do meet with real voters. The way it worked out, those states may have gotten even more attention this time, while the South is still waiting to hear about its concerns of, say, rural poverty and development. But still a better name for this mega-primary, <PERSON> Reilly </PERSON> says, may be Satellite Tuesday. Developments in television technology have played directly to the candidates' slavish need to get television airtime. Local TV stations now have _ and use _ the technology to get live reports from from virtually anywhere. The candidates are trying to exploit that by accommodating television stations in the Super Tuesday states, not just by tailoring local events but by making far-flung campaign appearances available via satellite to stations elsewhere. Campaigns may pay to have video pictures of their candidate at an apperance beamed up to a satellite where it is available for stations that want it, even if they did n't have crews on the scene. `` We have found in these small markets, particularly with agriculture stories, we've had enormous success'' getting the candidate on the air, <PERSON> Reilly </PERSON> said. Hence <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> makes three stops as he flies across three time zones one day last week. And he walks through a nearly idle electronics factory, to underscore his attack on unfair trade practices, with only a half-dozen people to hear him talk. It was the handful of television cameras there that he had in mind. Never mind that the factory was in <LOCATION> Rapid </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, S.D. It's one of the five states with primaries or caucuses in the three weeks before Super Tuesday, but it is a state where the primary is meaningless in the allocation of delegates. That will come later at the state caucus. What counted was that the <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> story that day appeared not only on <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION> television, but on some Southern stations too. It is the old story of television creating a `` global village.'' And it means that the campaigns pick events and locations that meld with the point a candidate is trying to make. His message for the day will be summed up in a 30 second bite on television that evening, if he's lucky. So look for <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> to go to a <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> automobile factory and a <LOCATION> Birmingham </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ala. </LOCATION>, steel mill to make his point about foreign competition and lost jobs. `` It's Super-Satellite Tuesday,'' <PERSON> Reilly </PERSON> said. `` Pretty soon the <ORGANIZATION> Secret </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> will have to start attaching those -LRB- satellite -RRB- dishes to the limos so these guys can do link-ups from the road.''
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 EDITOR'S NOTE: <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Welch </PERSON> is covering the 1988 presidential race for The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880223-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-23-88 0201EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-NukePlant     02-23 0403</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Nuke Plant,0411</SECOND>
<HEAD>SRP, DOE Officials Deny Acrimony Before Power Reduction Decision</HEAD>
<DATELINE>COLUMBIA, S.C. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 There were technical disagreements but no acrimony during meetings of scientists that led to the decision to reduce power levels at the <LOCATION> Savannah </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Plant </LOCATION>'s nuclear reactors, plant officials said Monday. The <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> reported Monday that the power levels were reduced by federal officials following a stormy meeting during which scientists warned that the reactor was operating beyond the demonstrated capacity of its emergency cooling system. The Department of Energy officials initially were reluctant to order the reduction because they did n't want to admit they had made a mistake and risk triggering public pressure to close the <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> facility, the newspaper reported, citing unidentified sources. The decision was made during a meeting Feb. 12 to reduce power levels at two of the three government reactors at the <LOCATION> Savannah </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Plant </LOCATION> _ the last <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> facility that produces plutonium, said <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> Rollins </PERSON>, the department's chief of reactors at <ORGANIZATION> SRP </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Rollins </PERSON> described the 10 percent reduction in power _ the third reduction in 14 months _ as a routine action reflecting a change in the way reactor temperatures are measured. The reduction dropped the operating level from 1,100 megawatts thermal to 960 megawatts. Power had been reduced previously from 2,200 megawatts. But the <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> said its sources said the reduction was ordered only at the insistence of scientists working for <ORGANIZATION> Du </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pont </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> DOE </ORGANIZATION>'s contractor at <LOCATION> Savannah </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> The scientists had discovered a fundamental error in the calculations that have been used for decades to justify reactor operating levels, the newspaper said. <LOCATION> Savannah </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> manager <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Morgan </PERSON> decided to reduce the levels following a confrontation with the scientists at a Feb. 8 meeting during which a top <PERSON> Du </PERSON> <PERSON> Pont </PERSON> scientist threw his security badge on the table in front of <LOCATION> Morgan </LOCATION> and threatened to `` go public'' unless the power levels were lowered, the sources said. An unidentified DOE official told the <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> that the department did not want to `` raise the specter of continuing problems at <LOCATION> Savannah </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION>.'' <PERSON> Rollins </PERSON> denied Monday there was a fundamental error in the DOE calculations and denied there were any heated disagreements during either of the meetings Feb. 8 and Feb. 12. `` There were lots of technical discussion, which helped the decision-making process,'' <PERSON> Rollins </PERSON> said. `` There was no dissention. Utilmately, everyone agreed with the decision to make the minor adjustment.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880223-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-23-88 0259EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-ScotusRdp     02-23 0790</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Scotus Rdp,790</SECOND>
<HEAD>Independent Prosecutor Law To Be Ruled On This Summer</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JAMES H. RUBIN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
