<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880307-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-07-88 2340EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Salvador-Duarte 1stLd-Writethru a0798 03-07 0607</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Salvador-Duarte, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0798,0622</SECOND>
<HEAD>President's Son Denies Ties to Party Member Accused of Corruption</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: New material and editing throughout, UPDATING with quotes
from politician involved and party leader. No pickup</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By ANNIE CABRERA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SAN SALVADOR, El Salvador (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION> candidate <PERSON> Luis </PERSON> <PERSON> Mejia </PERSON> <PERSON> Miranda </PERSON> on Monday ridiculed reports he was involved in misusing <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> aid money. `` Can you imagine that if I had ... -LRB- $ 2 million -RRB- I would still be in this country?,'' he asked. President <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Napoleon </PERSON> <PERSON> Duarte </PERSON>'s son denied he was trying to protect <PERSON> Mejia </PERSON>, a fellow <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democrat </ORGANIZATION> who was reported under investigation in the case. `` I deny any tie because I am not protecting him and because I am against corruption,'' said <PERSON> Alejandro </PERSON> <PERSON> Duarte </PERSON>, candidate for mayor of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION> in the March 20 elections. The <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> said Sunday that <PERSON> Mejia </PERSON> is being investigated for allegedly misusing up to $ 2 million of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> aid. It said the money was part of a $ 10 million program to assist war-ravaged areas and help win the support of Salvadorans in the war against leftist rebels. The newspaper quoted unidentified Salvadoran and <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials as saying it could be the largest case of theft of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> aid money during the administration of President <PERSON> Duarte </PERSON>, elected in May 1984 for a five-year term. In an interview with local newspapers, <PERSON> Mejia </PERSON> said `` that news -LRB- about alleged misuse of funds -RRB- surprises me because it is totally false.'' <PERSON> Rodolfo </PERSON> <PERSON> Castillo </PERSON> <PERSON> Claramount </PERSON>, <PERSON> Duarte </PERSON>'s vice president and secretary-general of the governing <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, said the article was `` full of vagueness and imprecisions with the political intention of damaging the party.'' He said it was written `` within a strategic conception of the ultra-right of the country.'' He also read a communique saying the party backed <PERSON> Alejandro </PERSON> <PERSON> Duarte </PERSON> as `` an absolutely honorable, capable and honest man.'' Referring to allegations against <PERSON> Mejia </PERSON>, the communique said `` we abstain from making a value judgment because we do not know if there is evidence.'' <PERSON> Alejandro </PERSON> <PERSON> Duarte </PERSON> denied being an associate of <PERSON> Mejia </PERSON> and said he had urged <PERSON> Mejia </PERSON> to cooperate with any investigation. `` It is vital that the truth be arrived at,'' he told reporters. `` If he -LRB- <PERSON> Mejia </PERSON> -RRB- is clean, he does not have to be afraid. If he feels he is outside of the accusations, then he should submit himself to any investigation.'' `` All this is a dirty political game and I feel indignant for having been involved,'' <PERSON> Alejandro </PERSON> <PERSON> Duarte </PERSON> said. Asked about his relationship with <PERSON> Mejia </PERSON>, he replied, `` I have no personal friendship with him. I know him like the majority of the members of the party.'' The <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> said <PERSON> Mejia </PERSON> resigned three months ago as director of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> the </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Restoration </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Areas </ORGANIZATION>, but President <PERSON> Duarte </PERSON> agreed to allow him to become a party candidate for the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION> on the recommendation of <PERSON> Alejandro </PERSON> <PERSON> Duarte </PERSON>. A <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> source, speaking on condition of anonymity, said `` these allegations are being studied.'' `` At this time the inspector general of AID -LRB- the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION> -RRB- has made no determination of bad use of funds in this program,'' the source said. `` However, other recent studies have identified certain aspects of financial control and management of CONARA -LRB- the restoration commission -RRB- and since January of this year there have been some changes in the method of management.'' <PERSON> Castillo </PERSON> <PERSON> Claramount </PERSON> said the party asked for an investigation of the alleged theft of funds. If there is evidence it occurred, the party will ask the assembly to remove the immunity <ORGANIZATION> Merida </ORGANIZATION> enjoys as a substitute deputy and will ask the electoral council to revoke his candidacy, he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880307-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-07-88 2343EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-FrenchCooking     03-07 0778</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-French Cooking,0803</SECOND>
<HEAD>Paris' Ritz Opens Cooking School And Cordon Bleu Goes Hi-Tech</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</NOTE>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By SUZY PATTERSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PARIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Two French-cooking schools _ one the oldest, the other the newest _ are giving the world's gastronomic capital yet another culinary lift. Cordon Bleu, the oldest and most prestigious, has taken on a high-tech image at a new location in a five-story building that once was an infirmary. The luxurious Ritz Hotel, the newest, is opening its kitchens April 5 to students of haute cuisine. The cachet of the elegant <ORGANIZATION> Right </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> hotel is maintained in the decor of its new basement cooking school, where gleaming white-tiled spaces and hand-painted murals set the tone. The Cordon Bleu, long situated in cramped quarters in the classy Champ de Mars district under the Eiffel Tower, moved in January to the building on an anonymous corner of the 15th arrondissement in southern <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION>. The school where servants from affluent families long ago watched cooking demonstrations in an amphitheater now offers every high-tech amenity, including video screens. Both schools offer all levels of instruction up to professional. Despite the new home, tradition at the venerable Cordon Bleu remains intact. The top diploma at the Cordon Bleu is awarded to students who pass a nine-month session. The Ritz school's top diploma follows a 12-week course. Hardly a newcomer to fine food, the Ritz has been known for its cuisine since <PERSON> Auguste </PERSON> <PERSON> Escoffier </PERSON> attracted international gastronomes early in the century. It decided to spread its know-how as part of an overall renovation plan started by <PERSON> Mohammed </PERSON> <PERSON> Al-Fayed </PERSON>, the Egyptian entrepreneur who bought the hotel nine years ago. `` We feel we're offering unique and superior instruction for a private cooking school,'' said <PERSON> Gregory </PERSON> <PERSON> Usher </PERSON>, an American who left the <ORGANIZATION> Cordon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bleu </ORGANIZATION> to take over the Ritz school's administration. `` Our chefs are tops.'' The courses are to be supervised by three of the <ORGANIZATION> Ritz </ORGANIZATION>'s own chefs, all winners of the top professional award, <PERSON> Meilleur </PERSON> <PERSON> Ouvrier </PERSON> de <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>. Most daily courses will be handled by two chefs with credentials from prestigious <LOCATION> French </LOCATION> restaurants. One, <PERSON> Andre </PERSON> <PERSON> Guillut </PERSON>, perfected his English while working at restaurants like l'Orangerie and <ORGANIZATION> Ma </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cuisine </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>. The up-to-date equipment includes permanently cooled pastry marbles, the latest in ovens, freezers and mixers. The hotel's meat smoker will be used for `` charcuterie'' courses, and video outlets are available for taping recipes. Pupils can browse in a reference library, taste wine with the <ORGANIZATION> Ritz </ORGANIZATION>'s sommelier, and the change and shower after the course in a special area. Across the Seine at Cordon Bleu, in the business since 1896, it's a whole new world. Spanking clean in light greys and blues, today's big-scale school includes two demonstration rooms, four huge cooking and pastry rooms, and a beautiful winter garden. Equipment includes convection ovens, pastry-rising ovens and huge dough-kneaders, plus special machines for a new course on vacuum-packing and cooking _ to be taught by <PERSON> Patrick </PERSON> <PERSON> Martin </PERSON>, the 1987 winner of the French National Cuisine and Pastry trophy. `` We're still emphasizing traditional <LOCATION> French </LOCATION> cuisine,'' said <PERSON> Robin </PERSON> <PERSON> Cahill </PERSON>, a Cordon Bleu graduate and its spokeswoman. `` But in our expanded facilities just about everything is new.'' `` The basics are still the main point,'' said <PERSON> Chef </PERSON> <PERSON> Martin </PERSON>, one of seven chefs. `` The students will still learn how to chop, knead, whip and do everything else by hand as well.'' The overwhelming majority of Cordon Bleu students are from abroad _ about 30 percent <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> and 20 percent Japanese, said Ms. <PERSON> Cahill </PERSON>. While the Ritz plans English translations in all courses, the Cordon Bleu still teaches its advanced courses in French. Financing for the modernization comes from the Pages group, headed by <PERSON> Andre </PERSON> <PERSON> Cointreau </PERSON>, which bought the school in 1981. Intermediate students at the <ORGANIZATION> Ritz </ORGANIZATION> may choose a one-to-six week course of practical sessions and demonstrations at cost in French francs of about $ 800 a week. The Ritz's highest-level <PERSON> Auguste </PERSON> <PERSON> Escoffier </PERSON> course, a 12-week session, costs about $ 10,000. Cordon Bleu's main three 12-week courses comprise a cycle of `` basic'' through `` superior'' at a cost of about $ 4,200 each. To get the coveted Cordon Bleu Grand Diplome, pupils now spend nine months, reduced from 12, in intensive cooking and pastry courses preparing for the big exam, at a cost of $ 19,000. `` We're also offering new intensive four-day practical and demonstration sessions,'' ranging from charcuterie to regional cuisine and costing about $ 500, said Ms. <PERSON> Cahill </PERSON>. Both schools conduct wine tasting courses. A visitor to <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> who wants to compare the big-school ambience of the Cordon Bleu with the tonier <PERSON> Ritz </PERSON> can attend demonstrations at either one for less than $ 35 each.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880307-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-07-88 2343EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-RockwellIndictment     03-07 0175</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Rockwell Indictment,0180</SECOND>
<HEAD>Rockwell Pleads Innocent in Overbilling Indictment</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Rockwell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> and two former managers pleaded innocent Monday to charges that they overbilled the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> by $ 450,000 on a sophisticated satellite navigational system. In a brief hearing, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> Consuelo </PERSON> <PERSON> Marshall </PERSON> ordered the company and its former managers to file pretrial motions by April 4 and set a May 3 trial date, <ORGANIZATION> Rockwell </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Jeff </PERSON> <PERSON> Charney </PERSON> said. He indicated the company plans to make pretrial motions but declined to elaborate. The company and the former managers _ <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Carter </PERSON>, materials division director at the its Seal Beach plant, and <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Zavodnick </PERSON>, manager of major subcontracts within the division _ were named in a 25-count federal indictment in January. The indictment alleged that the company and two men double-billed the government for work on the NAVSTAR global navigational system that uses radio signals from satellites to pinpoint locations on earth. As a result, the indictment claimed, <ORGANIZATION> Rockwell </ORGANIZATION> received $ 450,000 in unlawful profits. The company has denied the allegations.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880307-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-07-88 2343EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-China-Soviet-Minorities     03-07 0546</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-China-Soviet-Minorities,0561</SECOND>
<HEAD>Two Communist Powers Face Similar Minority Problems
^An AP Extra</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By JIM ABRAMS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Militant monks in <LOCATION> Tibet </LOCATION> and restive Armenians in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> are among the minority nationalities in those countries now testing, sometimes with violence, the limits of their governments' professed policies of openness. <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> calls them `` hooligans.'' To <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> they are `` splittists.'' But to both countries they represent a threat to the reputation and unity of the state. Thirty-one people died last week in rioting in the Soviet city of <LOCATION> Sumgait </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Azerbaijan </LOCATION>, where Christian Armenians are unhappy about being part of mostly Moslem <LOCATION> Azerbaijan </LOCATION>. In <LOCATION> Tibet </LOCATION>, up to 23 have died in clashes between <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> police and Tibetans in October and over the weekend. In both countries, the Communist governments in the past have suppressed their minorities to unite vast tracts of land under the ruling ethnic group, the <PERSON> Hans </PERSON> in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> and the Russians in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Josef </PERSON> <PERSON> V. </PERSON> <PERSON> Stalin </PERSON> purged the <LOCATION> Ukraine </LOCATION> in the 1930s, and <PERSON> Mao </PERSON> <PERSON> Tse-tung </PERSON> swiftly cracked down on unrest in <LOCATION> Tibet </LOCATION> and Moslem west <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> in the 1950s and 1960s. Both countries, with <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> in the lead, have now declared greater tolerance for different views, exposing both to flashpoints of nationalist sentiment. <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> blames outside forces for its troubles, saying pro-independence supporters of <LOCATION> Tibet </LOCATION>'s exiled religious leader, the <PERSON> Dalai </PERSON> <PERSON> Lama </PERSON>, were responsible for the first outbreak of violence in the Tibetan capital of <LOCATION> Lhasa </LOCATION> last October. <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> is faced with a wider problem of ethnic disputes in <LOCATION> Armenia </LOCATION>, religious identity in <LOCATION> Kazakhstan </LOCATION> and political activism in the Baltic republics of <LOCATION> Estonia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Lithuania </LOCATION>. Foreign journalists in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> have had slightly better access to the troubled areas than their Moscow-based counterparts. <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> expelled 14 foreign journalists from <LOCATION> Lhasa </LOCATION> last October, and has since given permission for only a few to return. But <LOCATION> Lhasa </LOCATION> authorities, hungry for tourist spending to help <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s poorest province, have not stopped group tours, and some reporters have joined excursion groups to <LOCATION> Tibet </LOCATION>. The <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> let a few correspondents go to <LOCATION> Vilnius </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Lithuania </LOCATION>, on a Foreign Ministry-sponsored trip for a planned demonstration to mark the Feb. 16 declaration of independence. But reporters there were followed constantly. No foreign journalist has been allowed lately into <LOCATION> Armenia </LOCATION> or <LOCATION> Azerbaijan </LOCATION>. Telephone calls to <LOCATION> Yerevan </LOCATION> sometimes went through, but <LOCATION> Nagorno-Karabakh </LOCATION>, the center of the Armenian-Azeri dispute, can not be reached at all and <LOCATION> Sumgait </LOCATION> only rarely. Reflecting <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>'s `` glasnost'' and <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>'s similar policy of `` kaifang,'' the official media in both countries have carried limited reports of the disturbances. <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s press has stressed that only a small number of Tibetans have joined the disturbances, and has sent out a barrage of stories about Tibetans criticizing the separatists and saying how much better life is under socialism. The government has stressed that it will continue to respect the local customs and help alleviate poverty in the regions where the nation's 67 million non-Han minorities live. <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>, too, has linked the rioting to a small number of `` hooligans.'' Soviet leader <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>, however, in a Feb. 18 speech stressed the importance of working out a new policy on nationalities and said the <ORGANIZATION> Cental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> would hold a special plenary session to discuss the matter.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880307-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-07-88 2345EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Reagan-NearCollision     03-07 0297</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Reagan-Near Collision,0304</SECOND>
<HEAD>Private Pilot Sentenced For False Statements</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JEFF WILSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An Army private who flew his small airplane into prohibited airspace over President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Barbara </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> ranch must spend 30 weekends in jail. <PERSON> Ralph </PERSON> <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Myers </PERSON>, 33, of <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lewis </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wash. </LOCATION>, convicted of lying to authorities about the reason he strayed into prohibited airspace on Aug. 13, was sentenced Monday by <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Real </PERSON>. Despite a Probation Department recommendation of probation, Real sentenced <PERSON> Myers </PERSON> to three years in jail for each of two counts of making false statements and then suspended all but 60 days of the incarceration. The judge also ordered <PERSON> Myers </PERSON> to donate 1,000 hours to charitable service. <PERSON> Myers </PERSON>' jail time will begin April 9 and is not to interfere with his military service. <PERSON> Myers </PERSON> could have been sentenced to 10 years' imprisonment and a $ 500,000 fine Outside court, <PERSON> Myers </PERSON> said he was made a scapegoat by the federal government because reports that there had been a near-miss caused `` hysteria.'' <PERSON> Myers </PERSON> maintains his plane was no closer than 800 feet from the president's helicopter, Marine One. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> pilot, Lt. Col. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Glynn </PERSON>, says <PERSON> Myers </PERSON>' plane passed about 200 feet in front of his helicopter and 150 feet below it. <PERSON> Myers </PERSON>' attorney, <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Araujo </PERSON>, said they will appeal the sentence. <PERSON> Myers </PERSON>, who has been stripped of his pilot's license, originally told federal agents he strayed into the prohibited airspace while looking for a lost contact lens in the cabin. He later said he had lied about the lens because, `` I was trying to stay out of more trouble.'' <PERSON> Myers </PERSON> was demoted from private first class to private for being absent without leave. He still has 18 months left in the <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880307-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-07-88 2352EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Panama-Attack 2ndLd-Writethru a0828 03-07 0646</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Panama-Attack, 2nd Ld - Writethru, a0828,0660</SECOND>
<HEAD>Men Backing New Panama Government Smash Into Consulate</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: CORRECTS Delvalle ousted Feb. 26, sted last week, in grafs 3,
10.</NOTE>
<HEAD>With AM-Panama, Bjt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A group of men backing <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s new government seized control of the country's disputed consulate in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> Monday night by smashing through the glass door with a Land Rover, police reported. The <ORGANIZATION> British </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Broadcasting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> said the seizure took place because the consul in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Eduardo </PERSON> <PERSON> Arango </PERSON>, refused to give up his post despite being fired by the new government. Control of <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> is also in dispute following the ouster on Feb. 26 of President <PERSON> Eric </PERSON> <PERSON> Arturo </PERSON> <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON>. He was removed from office after he tried to dismiss Gen. <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>, the military leader and de facto ruler. The <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> consulate is about a mile east of the embassy. The <ORGANIZATION> BBC </ORGANIZATION> said <PERSON> Arango </PERSON> was not in the consulate when the raid occurred. Police said in a statement that six men _ two representatives of Panamanian Ambassador <PERSON> Guillermo </PERSON> <PERSON> Vega </PERSON> and four members of a <LOCATION> British </LOCATION> security firm _ smashed their way into the consulate. `` Shortly after this, several people left the building, including three women believed to be secretaries, and a number of security staff. One glass-paneled front door was damaged and no one was injured as a result of the incident,'' the statement added. One of the staff members forced out of the consulate, Tourism Commissioner <PERSON> Rolando </PERSON> <PERSON> Domingo </PERSON>, 24, said: `` We were just working in there and then suddenly we heard a crash.'' He said the Land Rover broke through the glass doors and then a group of men burst into the building carrying large hammers. `` They threatened us with hammers and one tried to hit my face. They took my passport and documents. Then they pushed me down the stairs and out of the building,'' <PERSON> Domingo </PERSON> said. <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> police sealed off the area around the consulate in <LOCATION> Tudor </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Street </LOCATION> in the City, <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>'s financial district. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and many other countries still consider <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON> the president of <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>. He was removed from office by the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION>, which is dominated by <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> supporters. The <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration has called for <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>'s ouster since he was indicted in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> last month on drug trafficking charges. The <ORGANIZATION> BBC </ORGANIZATION> reported that <PERSON> Arango </PERSON> was in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> at the time of <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON>'s ouster and has said he helped smuggle <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON> from his residence to a hiding place in the Central American country. The British domestic news agency <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> said <PERSON> Arango </PERSON> received a phone call at home from the consulate staff about the Monday night raid. The agency quoted <PERSON> Arango </PERSON> as saying he was prevented from entering the consulate after the attack and that one of the men occupying it had told him they were working for <PERSON> Vega </PERSON> and carrying out orders from <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>. British government officials said they were told last Friday that <PERSON> Arango </PERSON> was being fired as consul. <PERSON> Arango </PERSON> said he had received letters from <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> saying he was dismissed but had ignored them, <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> said. As workmen repaired the doors, one of the British security guards who took part in the raid said: `` It is an exaggeration to say we smashed in. We nudged the doors with the Land Rover. The police say they may prosecute us for mounting the pavement -LRB- sidewalk -RRB- but I do n't think they can do anything else. We were authorized to enter the building but I can not divulge any more.'' The four guards involved work for GB Security, a private security company based in south <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>. They said they would be guarding the building overnight. A spokesman at the British <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION>, who in accordance with British practice declined to be named, said it was too early to say what action, if any, Foreign Secretary Sir <PERSON> Geoffrey </PERSON> <PERSON> Howe </PERSON> might take over the incident.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880307-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-07-88 0543EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Obit-Bradley     03-07 0298</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Obit-Bradley,0307</SECOND>
<HEAD>Chairman of St. Joseph News-Press &amp; Gazette Co. Dies</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ST. JOSEPH, Mo. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON> <PERSON> Sr. </PERSON>, chairman and chief executive officer of the <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Joseph </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News-Press </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <ORGANIZATION> Gazette </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, has died at age 70. <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON>, who died Sunday at a <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> hospital, was the second generation of a communications family that has published The <ORGANIZATION> News-Press </ORGANIZATION> and Gazette for nearly 50 years. He was publisher of the <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Joseph </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> newspapers </ORGANIZATION> from 1956 to 1981, succeeding his father, <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON>, as president of the company in 1972. The elder <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON> died in 1973. <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON> was known for keeping the newspapers on the leading edge of technology, switching to all-electronic production more than a decade ago. He also led the company into the TV market. The company's holdings include stations in <LOCATION> Savannah </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ga. </LOCATION>; <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, Miss.; <LOCATION> Hattiesburg </LOCATION>, Miss.; <LOCATION> Sioux </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Falls </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> S.D. </LOCATION>, and <LOCATION> Wilmington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.C. </LOCATION>, and cable TV systems in <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Joseph </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Savannah </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Macon </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mo </LOCATION>. He was active in The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> and served as a director of the news cooperative from 1970 to 1979. He also was first vice chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION>, serving in that position from 1977-79. `` <PERSON> Dave </PERSON> had a unique combination of common sense, a sharp business mind and a zest for life,'' said <PERSON> Louis </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Boccardi </PERSON>, president and general manager of the <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION>. `` You could count on him to help you get to the heart of any problem, but also to remind you that your problem was probably a little less earth-shaking than you thought it was. He was a treasured friend and a wise counsel.'' <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON> was born in <LOCATION> Toledo </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, and graduated from the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wisconsin </ORGANIZATION> in 1939. Survivors include his wife, <PERSON> Shirley </PERSON> <PERSON> Wyeth </PERSON> <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON>; two daughters; two sons and 11 grandchildren. Funeral arrangements were incomplete Sunday.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880307-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-07-88 0549EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-WeatherpageWeather     03-07 0578</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Weatherpage Weather,0598</SECOND>
<HEAD>Cold And Snow Spread Into Central Rockies</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Wind, cold and snow moved thorugh the central Rockies today, producing brisk wind gusts, thunderstorms, hail and snow squalls. The cold front moved into <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION> and parts of <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION> on Sunday evening. At <LOCATION> Pocatello </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION>, wind gusted to 41 mph as visibility dropped to a quarter mile in snow squalls. Thunderstorms broke out when the cold front passed through northern <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION>, producing small hail, frequent lightning and scattered power outages. Wind gusted to 45 mph in the <LOCATION> Trenton </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Logan </LOCATION> areas. The storm dumped up to a foot of snow in <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION>'s mountains, and lesser amounts elsewhere in the state Snow and blowing snow was reported late Sunday across central and southern <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION>. Wind gusted to near 40 mph at <LOCATION> Rock </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Springs </LOCATION> and visibility at <LOCATION> Laramie </LOCATION> dropped to a half mile. Up to a foot of snow was expected in the southwest mountains of <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION>. Eight to 16 inches of snow was expected in the mountains of <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION>. High winds should cause blowing and drifting snow and poor visibility in the state's mountain passes. Elsewhere, thunderstorms moved through parts of <LOCATION> southeast </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> and eastern <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> on Sunday evening. Nickel-size hail was reported at <LOCATION> Gatesville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.C. </LOCATION>, near the <LOCATION> Virginia-North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> line. <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ana </LOCATION> winds were expected to develop across <LOCATION> Southern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> today. A wind advisory was in effect for the northern mountains of <LOCATION> Southern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>. By tonight, winds may gust faster than 50 mph in some canyon areas of the <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bernardino </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION>. Clear skies covered most of the nation this morning, but dense fog advisories were posted for parts of northern and central <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> and southwest <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION>. Temperatures ahead of the cold front were mild Sunday, with a 72-degree reading at <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> George </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION>. The high for the nation Sunday was 88 at <LOCATION> Yuma </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ariz </LOCATION>. Temperatures around the nation at 2 a.m. EST ranged from 14 at <LOCATION> Yellowstone </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wyo. </LOCATION>, to 71 at <ORGANIZATION> Homestead </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Base </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>. For today, rain or snow showers were forecast from northern <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION> and the central Rockies across the northern Plains; and scattered rainshowers from northwest <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> to the upper <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION> Skies should be mostly sunny over the eastern third of the nation, except for a few snowshowers over northern <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>. Much of the nation should have highs in the 50s or 60s. Highs should be in the 30s and 40s from the northern and central Rockies across the northern half of the Plains and the <LOCATION> Great </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lakes </LOCATION> region into <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>. Temperatures should reach the 70s and low 80s from <LOCATION> Southern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> across the desert <ORGANIZATION> Southwest </ORGANIZATION>, and from the southern <LOCATION> Plains </LOCATION> to the southern <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Coast </LOCATION>. Other reports: _ East: <ORGANIZATION> Atlanta </ORGANIZATION> 45 fair; <ORGANIZATION> Boston </ORGANIZATION> 33 fair; <ORGANIZATION> Buffalo </ORGANIZATION> 36 windy; <LOCATION> Charleston </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> S.C. </LOCATION> 46 foggy; <LOCATION> Cincinnati </LOCATION> 32 foggy; <ORGANIZATION> Cleveland </ORGANIZATION> 36 fair; <ORGANIZATION> Detroit </ORGANIZATION> 33 fair; <ORGANIZATION> Miami </ORGANIZATION> 69 cloudy; <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> 34 partly cloudy; <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION> 34 partly cloudy; <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION> 36 foggy; <LOCATION> Portland </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION> 32 cloudy; <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> 37 fair _ Central: <LOCATION> Bismarck </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.D. </LOCATION> 35 cloudy; <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> 38 fair; <ORGANIZATION> Dallas-Fort </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Worth </ORGANIZATION> 51 partly cloudy; <ORGANIZATION> Denver </ORGANIZATION> 41 cloudy; <PERSON> Des </PERSON> <PERSON> Moines </PERSON> 37 fair; <LOCATION> Indianapolis </LOCATION> 34 fair; Minneapolis-St. <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> 36 cloudy; <ORGANIZATION> Nashville </ORGANIZATION> 36 foggy; <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION> 54 _ West: <ORGANIZATION> Albuquerque </ORGANIZATION> 44 cloudy; <ORGANIZATION> Anchorage </ORGANIZATION> 31 cloudy; <ORGANIZATION> Las </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Vegas </ORGANIZATION> 54 fair; <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> 56 hazy; <LOCATION> Phoenix </LOCATION> 62 fair; <LOCATION> Salt </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> 33 partly cloudy; <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Diego </LOCATION> 57 cloudy; <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> 51 partly cloudy; <ORGANIZATION> Seattle </ORGANIZATION> 41 cloudy _ <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>: <ORGANIZATION> Montreal </ORGANIZATION> 34 partly cloudy; <ORGANIZATION> Toronto </ORGANIZATION> 36 partly cloudy
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880307-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-07-88 0617EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-China-Tibet 1stLd-Writethru a0478 03-07 0671</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-China-Tibet, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0478,0687</SECOND>
<HEAD>Police Chief Calls For Order, Lhasa Said Back to Normal</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Leads with 9 grafs to UPDATE with protest in India. Pickup
6th graf pvs, ``Lang said...''
^By JIM ABRAMS</NOTE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 At least one policeman was killed and 28 injured in <LOCATION> Tibet </LOCATION> over the weekend in clashes between police and protesters demanding <LOCATION> Tibet </LOCATION>'s independence from <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> reported today. The newspaper, the voice of the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, quoted <LOCATION> Tibet </LOCATION>'s top police official in its report on rioting Saturday in the Tibetan capital of <LOCATION> Lhasa </LOCATION> The newspaper did not say how many Tibetans were injured. Unconfirmed reports from Western sources in <LOCATION> Lhasa </LOCATION> said three to nine people were killed, including one <ORGANIZATION> Buddhist </ORGANIZATION> monk and two Chinese police officers. Western sources contacted in <LOCATION> Lhasa </LOCATION> said the city was quiet today and Sunday but that the <ORGANIZATION> Jokhang </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Temple </ORGANIZATION>, around which Tibetans battled police, was closed. The sources, speaking on condition of anonymity, said stores were open and marketplace stalls were doing business today. In <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>, meanwhile, 500 Tibetan refugees, chanting `` We shall overcome,'' demonstrated in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Delhi </LOCATION> today against the Chinese crackdown in <LOCATION> Lhasa </LOCATION>. Police prevented the demonstrators from going to the <ORGANIZATION> Chinese </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION>. No injuries were reported in sporadic clashes between protesters and police. The demonstration was organized by <ORGANIZATION> Tibetan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Freedom </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Movement </ORGANIZATION>, an organization of self-exiled Tibetans, and the Tibetan <ORGANIZATION> Youth </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> has allowed 120,000 Tibetans and their temporal leader, the <PERSON> Dalai </PERSON> <PERSON> Lama </PERSON>, to stay in <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>. The <PERSON> Dalai </PERSON> <PERSON> Lama </PERSON> fled to <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> in 1959 after an abortive Tibetan uprising against the Chinese. The People's Daily today quoted the Tibetan police official, <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> Chief <PERSON> Lang </PERSON> <PERSON> Jie </PERSON>, as saying on Tibetan television Sunday that the disturbances in <LOCATION> Lhasa </LOCATION> began when `` separatists'' infiltrated a crowd on the final day of a 10-day prayer festival. He said they started shouting `` independence for <LOCATION> Tibet </LOCATION>'' and other `` counter-revolutionary'' slogans. <PERSON> Lang </PERSON> said 20 to 30 <ORGANIZATION> Buddhist </ORGANIZATION> monks circled the <ORGANIZATION> Jokhang </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Temple </ORGANIZATION>, shouting slogans and throwing stones and damaging Chinese television vans. The official <ORGANIZATION> China </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> earlier gave the number as 60. They also attacked the Tibetan branch of the <ORGANIZATION> Buddhist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> and set fire to a car belonging to the group, controlled by the Chinese government. `` Their purpose was to destroy the peace and unity of our country and our region and the peaceful and prosperous life of all nationalities -LRB- in <LOCATION> Tibet </LOCATION> -RRB-,'' he was quoted as saying. The report did not say how many Tibetans took part in the riots or if there were any arrests. Saturday was the first outbreak of violence since last Oct. 1, when 2,000 Tibetans, led by <ORGANIZATION> Buddhist </ORGANIZATION> monks, set fire to a police station facing the <ORGANIZATION> Jokhang </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Temple </ORGANIZATION>. Police opened fire, and at least 14 people were killed. <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, which claims <LOCATION> Tibet </LOCATION> has been an integral part of the nation for centuries, moved troops into the remote mountain region in 1950. Many Tibetans deeply resent the <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> government because of oppression of Tibetan religion and customs and the destruction of temples during the 1966-76 ultra-leftist Cultural Revolution. Although <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> has tried to redress past wrongs, friction remains between the Tibetans and the Hans, <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s ethnic majority, which continues to hold many senior posts in <LOCATION> Lhasa </LOCATION>. The official <ORGANIZATION> Xinhua </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> said today that rioters `` stormed, looted and set fire to shops and restaurants and beat up policemen sent to maintain order.'' It said rioters with steel bars and wooden sticks knocked down policemen Yuan Shisheng and <PERSON> Yang </PERSON> <PERSON> Yuchen </PERSON>, stabbed them and threw them from a second-floor window. Yuan, a 22-year-old Tibetan, died later in a hospital and <PERSON> Yang </PERSON> was reported in serious condition. The Western sources said Tibetans set fire to vehicles and lit bonfires over a 12-hour period, and that police fired tear gas during the day to control the violence. Gunshots were heard after dark, they said. The <LOCATION> Lhasa </LOCATION> government has turned down almost all requests by foreign journalists to visit <LOCATION> Lhasa </LOCATION> and has restricted tourism to the area since the disturbances last October.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880307-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-07-88 0623EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Dollar-Gold     03-07 0317</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Dollar-Gold,0337</SECOND>
<HEAD>Dollar Lower, Gold Prices Mixed</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The dollar was lower in thin early European trading today and foreign currency dealers said they do n't expect it to break out of a narrow trading range before new American trade figures are released next week. Gold prices were mixed. The January trade report is due to be released March 17 and one dealer at a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> bank in <LOCATION> Frankfurt </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, said the market will be paralyzed until then. `` We just move along from trade figure to trade figure,'' he said. In <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION>, where trading ends as <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>'s business day begins, the dollar fell 0.35 yen to a closing 128.87. Later, in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>, it was quoted at 128.60 yen. Other dollar rates at midmorning, compared with late Friday: _ 1.6865 West German marks, down from 1.6940 _ 1.3960 Swiss francs, down from 1.4030 _ 5.7090 French francs, down from 5.7300 _ 1.8952 Dutch guilders, down from 1.9010 _ 1,243.75 Italian lire, down from 1,248.00 _ 1.2535 Canadian dollars, down from 1.2547 In <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>, one British pound cost $ 1.7972, more expensive than Traders said the pound was strong throughout <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> because of relatively high British interest rates. Gold prices were lower in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> and higher in <LOCATION> Zurich </LOCATION>. The metal opened in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> at a bid price of $ 437 a troy ounce, compared with late Friday's $ 437.50. At midmorning today, the city's five major bullion dealers fixed a recommended price of $ 436. One bullion dealer said market participants in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> were taking profits following Friday's technical rally in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>. `` It is going to keep falling,'' he said. `` There is a lot of selling around.'' In <LOCATION> Zurich </LOCATION>, the bid price was $ 434.25, up from $ 432 late Friday. Earlier, in <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION>, gold rose 54 cents to close at a bid $ 438.75. Silver was quoted in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> today at a bid price of $ 6.38 a troy ounce, down from Friday's $ 6.41.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880307-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-07-88 0638EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-PrinceCharles     03-07 0522</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Prince Charles,0538</SECOND>
<HEAD>Prince Wins At Polo, Surprises Fans With Handshakes</HEAD>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WEST PALM BEACH, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Prince <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> thrilled spectators by shaking hands on both sidelines after beating an American polo squad assembled for the royal occasion. `` I ca n't believe it. I was so shocked,'' said <PERSON> Anabelle </PERSON> <PERSON> Mariaca </PERSON>, who shook hands with the Prince of <LOCATION> Wales </LOCATION> after the 90-minute match Sunday at the <ORGANIZATION> Palm </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Beach </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Polo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Country </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Club </ORGANIZATION>. `` I told him I was from <LOCATION> Bolivia </LOCATION>, and he said, ` I bet the weather is better there than here.''' The prince's <LOCATION> Windsor </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Park </LOCATION> team beat <LOCATION> Palm </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION> 6-4 on a soggy field doused by occasional rain. The prince, scheduled to fly home today via <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, scored a goal on a penalty shot, and teammate <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Brant </PERSON> said <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> saved five or six goals on defense. `` He played very well,'' <PERSON> Brant </PERSON> said. `` He had n't played in competition since the end of August, but he made some beautiful back shots.'' Spectators included King Constantine of <LOCATION> Greece </LOCATION> and Maj. <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Ferguson </PERSON>, father-in-law of Prince <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON>, <PERSON> Charles </PERSON>' younger brother. <PERSON> Charles </PERSON>' wife, Princess <PERSON> Diana </PERSON>, had other commitments, a Buckingham Palace spokesman said. <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> and his wife, <PERSON> Sarah </PERSON>, finished a 10-day tour of Southern California Sunday and headed back to <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>. Officials said the prince's visit with spectators afterward was unplanned but not unusual. To the fans, however, it was clearly a surprise. <PERSON> Chris </PERSON> <PERSON> Zeiser </PERSON> of <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Palm </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION>, who shook hands with <PERSON> Charles </PERSON>, apologized to him for the weather. `` Well, I'll have to come back again,'' replied the prince, who has visited the club twice before. About 8,500 people attended the match at the 6,200-seat stadium. Both the sporting event and a luncheon for about 500 people beforehand benefitted Friends of the <PERSON> Masai </PERSON> <PERSON> Mara </PERSON>, a conservation group for a wildlife habitat in <LOCATION> Kenya </LOCATION>. The founders of the organization, <PERSON> Geoffrey </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jorie </PERSON> <PERSON> Kent </PERSON>, were the prince's hosts and the first to greet the prince and king when they flew in Saturday from <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION>, where they had attended a fund-raising dinner Friday. <PERSON> Charles </PERSON>, who has been outspoken recently about architecture, went from the airport to visit developer <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Trump </PERSON>'s 118-room mansion <ORGANIZATION> Mar-a-Lago </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Palm </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> spent two nights at the Kents' ranch west of <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Worth </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> was the honored guest at a wildlife demonstration conducted on the polo field by <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Fowler </PERSON> of TV's `` Wild Kingdom,'' who presented a lion cub, aardvark, several birds and a 7-year-old cheetah. When <PERSON> Fowler </PERSON> coaxed an eagle to fly to him by holding up scraps of food, the prince asked, `` Is that off the luncheon menu?'' The eagle landed on the back of <PERSON> Fowler </PERSON>'s hand with a message in its claw. <PERSON> Charles </PERSON>, who read it to the audience, said, `` All wildlife thanks those gathered here for your interest in wildlife.'' The prince joked, `` I did n't know this eagle could write, though clearly it does.'' Cheetah handler <PERSON> Cathryn </PERSON> <PERSON> Hilker </PERSON> took <PERSON> Charles </PERSON>' right hand, and together they petted the cat's face. The prince seemed reluctant, but the animal licked his hand. `` She loves men's hands because they have hair on them,'' Ms. <PERSON> Hilker </PERSON> explained.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880307-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-07-88 0647EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Czechoslovakia-Church     03-07 0406</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Czechoslovakia-Church,0417</SECOND>
<HEAD>Demands For Religious Freedom After Packed Mass</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ALISON SMALE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PRAGUE, Czechoslovakia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Hundreds of Roman Catholics chanted `` We want religious freedom!'' after thousands crowded into a cathedral for a Mass honoring a 13th-century Czech princess who renounced royal wealth to serve God. The Mass on Sunday at <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Vitus </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cathedral </ORGANIZATION>, in the Castle complex where Communist President <PERSON> Gustav </PERSON> <PERSON> Husak </PERSON> lives, drew about 8,000 people. It was one of the biggest religious services in the capital since the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> takeover in 1948 and an indication of the reviving strength of the nation's Roman Catholic church. Dozens of plainclothes security officers were seen inside and outside the cathedral while Mass was held to honor the princess who is to be canonized by the <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION> later this year. Police arrested 16 dissidents and religious activists under 48-hour detention orders on Friday and Saturday, apparently to prevent them from attending the Mass. A dissident source said five people remained in detention Sunday night, but four of them were expected to be freed today. <PERSON> Augustin </PERSON> <PERSON> Navratil </PERSON>, a Roman Catholic activist from <LOCATION> Moravia </LOCATION>, was detained Friday morning but there was no word he was free late Sunday, the source said. <PERSON> Navratil </PERSON> was the author of a 31-point church petition for more religious freedom that has gained more than 300,000 signatures, making it the largest such action in the Soviet bloc since 1945. Five other dissidents were briefly detained when they tried to visit a <LOCATION> British </LOCATION> diplomat Friday, and two others also were briefly held that night. After the Mass, about 1,000 people went from the cathedral to the nearby residence of Cardinal <PERSON> Frantisek </PERSON> <PERSON> Tomasek </PERSON>. A few hundred chanted `` We want bishops,'' `` We want religious freedom'' and `` We want the Pope.'' The chanting crowd appeared to reflect growing discontent among Catholics at the lack of bishops in 10 of the country's 13 sees. The <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION> has refused to accept government proposals to appoint as bishops members of the state-sponsored Pacem in <LOCATION> Terris </LOCATION> organization, a group of priests not recognized by the Holy See. `` Long live the Holy Father'' was another chant from the crowd outside <PERSON> Tomasek </PERSON>'s residence, which adjoins the castle where <PERSON> Husak </PERSON> lives. The presidential flag was flying, indicating the 75-year-old president was home during the unusual demonstration. There is no official estimate of the number of believers in <LOCATION> Czechoslovakia </LOCATION>, but <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION> officials estimate about 60 percent of the 15.5 million citizens are <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880307-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-07-88 0711EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Israel-Bus 3rdAdd a0509 03-07 0110</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Israel-Bus, 3rd Add, a0509,0108</SECOND>
<HEAD>BEERSHEVA: its verdict.</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Soldiers turned back reporters and other motorists at a roadblock at the southern end of <LOCATION> Beersheva </LOCATION>, about 10 miles north of the scene. A group of onlookers shouted insults at journalists gathered there and one man threw a rock at a TV crew. `` Why do n't you go photograph in the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION>. You are the cause of all of this,'' shouted one man. Reporters at the checkpoint saw six or seven ambulances rushing to <LOCATION> Beersheva </LOCATION> starting about 10:45 a.m.. One army ambulance stopped and reporters could see the bodies of three Arabs which a policeman at the scene identified as terrorists
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880307-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-07-88 0719EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a BC-Quotes     03-07 0162</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Quotes,0168</SECOND>
<HEAD>Current Quotations</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 `` The Panamanian people's vocation for peace is less than its vocation for liberty and democracy. Many people think <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> does not have much capacity for violence, but it does.'' _ <PERSON> Roderick </PERSON> <PERSON> Esquivel </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s ousted vice president, who called on Panamanians to take up arms against Gen. <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> if <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> does not relinquish power.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 `` A deaf president is a role model of all deaf people. He is a leader of the whole deaf community.'' _ <ORGANIZATION> Gallaudet </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> student <PERSON> Sherri </PERSON> <PERSON> Lambert </PERSON>, commenting on the uproar caused by the appointment of a new president of the college for the deaf who is not deaf herself and does not understand sign language.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 `` Many times we're not talking rehabilitation, we're talking ` habilitation,' These are new ideas, novel ideas to many, many young people.'' _ <PERSON> Melvin </PERSON> <PERSON> Hollins </PERSON>, superintendent of the <LOCATION> Monterey </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION> -RRB- Shock Incarceration Facility, commenting on the rules and discipline enforced at the boot-camp-style prison
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880307-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-07-88 0807EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-TuitionPlan     03-07 0301</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Tuition Plan,0311</SECOND>
<HEAD>University's Pre-Payment Plan Suspended</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PITTSBURGH (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Falling bond interest rates and unexpectedly high tuition increases have forced <ORGANIZATION> Duquesne </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> to suspend a trendsetting tuition prepayment plan, according to school officials. The small Roman Catholic university announced three years ago that alumni could enroll their newborn children for $ 4,450 as full tuition payment for four years of education. The plan was expanded in 1986 to include non-alumni. The college takes the money and invests it, with the proceeds covering tuition for four years of college when the child is grown. The plan prompted about a dozen other private colleges to follow suit. Six states also adopted plans that would enable parents to prepay a fixed amount of the child's college tuition, starting at birth. <ORGANIZATION> Duquesne </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman <PERSON> Ann </PERSON> <PERSON> Rago </PERSON> confirmed Sunday that the university's board of trustees had voted Wednesday to suspend the plan. `` When we began the program, it was a much different economic climate, but things have changed so we decided to suspend it,'' she said. The college will keep its commitment to 622 families already enrolled in the program, Ms. <PERSON> Rago </PERSON> said. When the plan was created, according to Ms. <PERSON> Rago </PERSON>, the university's rate of return on the bonds was 10.8 percent. It has since dropped to 8.52 percent, she said. Tuition for 1988-89 recently was raised 8 percent, rather than the originally projected 6 percent. The university found it would be necessary to raise the 1987 tuition prepayment for a newborn to $ 8,630. That was calculated to cover tuition costs of $ 102,604 over four years, ending in the year 2005. For a 15-year-old, the one-time investment rose from $ 12,864 to $ 24,310. `` At this time, those numbers do n't make the plan feasible,'' Ms. <PERSON> Rago </PERSON> said. `` The administration will re-examine it if the economic conditions change.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880307-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-07-88 0817EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Hungary-DemocraticForum     03-07 0491</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Hungary-Democratic Forum,0507</SECOND>
<HEAD>Unofficial Democratic Forum Discusses Romanian Minority</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TEDDIE WEYR</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>VIENNA, Austria (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Hungarian intellectuals and a member of <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION> have called on <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> to allow more ethnic Hungarian refugees to emigrate from <LOCATION> Romania </LOCATION> and appealed for international support in monitoring their rights. About 20 people spoke at the all-day forum Sunday in a theater in <LOCATION> Budapest </LOCATION>. More than 700 people attended the meeting, participants informed The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> by telephone from the Hungarian capital. The meeting Sunday was the second one of the `` Democratic Forum'' since the group was formed on Sept. 27 in southern <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>. The document issued at the September meeting called for `` genuinely effective reform'' to resolve <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>'s economic and social problems. The meetings are unusual in communist <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> because authorities, although they have not officially recognized the forum, have not prevented them from taking place, and the results have been discussed in the official press. Most of the speakers Sunday focused on the ethnic Hungarian minority in <LOCATION> Romania </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Romania </LOCATION> are <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION> Pact allies but have engaged in increasingly sharp rhetoric over the question of the ethnic Hungarian minority in <LOCATION> Transylvania </LOCATION> in recent months. <LOCATION> Transylvania </LOCATION> was ruled by <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> before World War I, and both nations claim the area is the cradle of their national cultures and history. Hungarian officials say increasing numbers of <LOCATION> Romania </LOCATION>'s nearly 2 million ethnic Hungarians have sought refuge in <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Geza </PERSON> <PERSON> Szoecs </PERSON>, an ethnic Hungarian poet from <LOCATION> Transylvania </LOCATION> who now lives in <LOCATION> Switzerland </LOCATION>, suggested that the Hungarian government consider allowing a certain quota of ethnic Hungarians from <LOCATION> Romania </LOCATION> emigrate to <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>. He suggested the quota correlate to the number of Hungarians who apply for asylum in the West each year, as well as the general decline of the population through the sinking birthrate. However, <PERSON> Zoltan </PERSON> <PERSON> Kiraly </PERSON>, a member of <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION>, warned against establishing a refugee program that would help Romanian Communist leader <PERSON> Nicolae </PERSON> <PERSON> Ceausescu </PERSON> get rid of the Hungarian minority. Ethnic Hungarians have said they are increasingly restricted in the use of their language and expression of their culture in <LOCATION> Romania </LOCATION>, which denies the charges and accuses <LOCATION> Budapest </LOCATION> of meddling in its affairs. <PERSON> Kiraly </PERSON> told the gathering he and five other parliamentarians drafted a resolution calling on the government to set up a settlement fund for Transylvanian Hungarians who wish to stay in <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>. He said the draft resolution, which is to be put before <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION> when it meets in spring session later this month, also calls on the government to seek the cooperation of the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION> and to mobilize international public opinion. <PERSON> Kiraly </PERSON>, one of the most outspoken members of <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION>, said many Hungarians who enter <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> from <LOCATION> Romania </LOCATION> go on to third countries because the Hungarian authorities are not prepared to receive them. He said many of these ethnic Hungarians, if given the chance, would opt to stay in <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> because of the cultural affinity.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880307-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-07-88 0817EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-People-AIDS     03-07 0224</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-People-AIDS,0230</SECOND>
<HEAD>Telephone Poll Finds Women Are Changing Sexual Attitudes Because
of AIDS</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Single women are changing their attitudes about sexual relationships because of the threat of getting AIDS, according to a poll conducted for People magazine. The national telephone survey, conducted by Market Facts of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, asked 500 women ages 18 to 49 about the impact of AIDS, the magazine reported in this week's issue. The survey found that the threat was on their minds even though the medical community has said very few AIDS cases have occurred outside of the known risk groups, which include homosexuals and intravenous drugs users, People said. The poll found that 75 percent said they were extremely or very concerned and 40 percent said their sex lives had been directly affected. Of those who said their sex lives have changed, 78 percent said they've become more choosy about sex partners and three-fourths said they want to know a new partner's sexual history and insist that he use a condom, the poll said. Acquired immune deficiency syndrome is caused by a virus that damages the body's immune system, leaving victims susceptible to infections and cancer. It is spread most often through sexual contact, needles or syringes shared by drug abusers, infected blood or blood products, and from pregnant women to their offspring.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880307-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-07-88 0858EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-FerryMemorial     03-07 0557</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Ferry Memorial,0570</SECOND>
<HEAD>Tears, Pleas For A New Beginning On Ferry Anniversary</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By EDITH M. LEDERER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ZEEBRUGGE, Belgium (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Survivors and those who lost loved ones in a ferry disaster retraced the voyage of the <ORGANIZATION> Herald </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Free </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Enterprise </ORGANIZATION>, casting wreaths and notes over the spot where it capsized a year before. `` Daddy, Miss You,'' said one of the more than 100 cards dropped into the water Sunday, a cold, bleak day with a fine drizzle _ remarkably similar to the day the <ORGANIZATION> Herald </ORGANIZATION> turned over and 193 of its passengers died. Others joined in prayer Sunday in this Belgian port and across the <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sea </LOCATION> in the English port of <LOCATION> Dover </LOCATION> to mark the worst peacetime disaster involving a British ship since the sinking of the Titanic in 1912. About 270 set out from <LOCATION> Zeebrugge </LOCATION> and stopped just outside the harbor wall where the ferry capsized March 6, 1987, when water rushed in through its open bow doors five minutes after it left port. For 20 minutes they cast flowers onto the choppy seas from the Baltic Ferry, which the <ORGANIZATION> Herald </ORGANIZATION>'s owners P and O pressed into service for the sad pilgrimage. Some were led away to be comforted by <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION> and social workers. Others clung to their families. A few went off by themselves and stood looking into the murky waters. On the upper car deck, which was transformed into a makeshift chapel bedecked with flowers, prayers were said by three clergymen _ an Anglican, a <ORGANIZATION> Roman </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> and a major from the <ORGANIZATION> Salvation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> _ during a half-hour service. `` This service can mark a new beginning,'' said The Rev. <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Bowers </PERSON>, vicar of <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Peter </LOCATION>'s and <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Paul </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Dover </LOCATION>. `` It does not mean we forget those who we have loved. ... In fact, it is from that memory that we build a new future.'' His words were echoed by The Bishop of <LOCATION> Dover </LOCATION>, The Rt. Rev. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Third </PERSON>, who told more than 600 bereaved at the Anglican church of <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Virgin </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Dover </LOCATION> that it was time to leave their grief behind. `` It is right to grieve. It is health-giving to express your sorrow _ but you ca n't go on doing it for a lifetime. There must come a moment when you surrender your grief, when you stop crying.'' At St. Donaas Roman Catholic church across the road from <LOCATION> Zeebrugge </LOCATION> port, the Sunday service was turned into a memorial for the ferry victims. The Rev. <PERSON> Wim </PERSON> <PERSON> Catry </PERSON> also offered prayers that the survivors and bereaved would be able to reconstruct their lives. He said in his sermon that a rose garden and plaque would be unveiled in May in front of the church to commemorate the dead. <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> <PERSON> Parker </PERSON>, who turned his body into a human bridge so 20 passengers including his wife and daughter could walk across his back to safety, paid his own private tribute. He went out on a Belgian tug to the spot where the <ORGANIZATION> Herald </ORGANIZATION> capsized and with his 13-year-old daughter <PERSON> Janice </PERSON> dropped 193 flowers into the water, one by one. His wife, <PERSON> Eleanor </PERSON>, like several other Britons who came here, remained onshore, unable at the last minute to relive their nightmares. Said Mrs. <PERSON> Parker </PERSON>: `` I hate this day _ I just wish I could take it off the calendar.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880307-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-07-88 0900EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-ChickenPuck     03-07 0218</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Chicken Puck,0225</SECOND>
<HEAD>Man Arrested For Throwing Live Chicken Onto Ice During Hockey Game</HEAD>
<DATELINE>INGLEWOOD, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An overwrought hockey fan was arrested after he tossed a live chicken in a purple uniform onto the ice during a game, police said. `` The chicken was the victim of fowl play,'' police Lt. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Westlake </PERSON> quipped Sunday. <PERSON> Craig </PERSON> <PERSON> Rodenfels </PERSON>, 30, of <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Segundo </LOCATION>, was booked for investigation of malicious mischief and cruelty to animals Saturday night and released on his own recognizance Sunday, <PERSON> Westlake </PERSON> said. The chicken hit the ice just before the end of the first period of the <ORGANIZATION> Los </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Angeles </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Kings </ORGANIZATION>' game with the <ORGANIZATION> Montreal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Canadiens </ORGANIZATION>. `` Apparently he was n't happy with how the Kings were playing, which is understandable,'' <PERSON> Westlake </PERSON> said. Lt. <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Frazier </PERSON> said <PERSON> Rodenfels </PERSON> smuggled the bird into the Forum inside a sack. He said the man was n't arrested before the chicken hit the ice because `` there's no violation for carrying a chicken around.'' The purple-uniformed Kings fell to the <ORGANIZATION> Canadiens </ORGANIZATION> 7-6 in overtime, their 39th loss of the season. The bird, which suffered minor bruises, was being held by county animal control officers, <PERSON> Westlake </PERSON> said. `` The guy actually called us this morning and asked us to release his chicken to him,'' <PERSON> Westlake </PERSON> said Sunday. `` Of course, we declined because the bird is evidence.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880307-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-07-88 0919EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--ChickenSign     03-07 0182</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Chicken Sign,0187</SECOND>
<HEAD>Chicken Violates Sign Code</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SANTA ANA, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Sanford </PERSON> and <PERSON> Linda </PERSON> <PERSON> Simmons </PERSON> have run afoul of <LOCATION> Orange </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>'s sign code, but they want their six-foot mechanical chicken to keep on clucking. `` We've got a lot of money tied up in this chicken, so we're fighting back,'' <PERSON> Simmons </PERSON> said The couple started a `` Save Our Chicken'' petition drive at their <ORGANIZATION> Stuf </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 'd </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chicken </ORGANIZATION> restaurant and say they have about 500 signatures. The issue involves an ordinance prohibiting free-standing or temporary signs in unincorporated parts of the county, said <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Boettcher </PERSON>, the <LOCATION> Southern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> <LOCATION> county </LOCATION>'s enforcement manager. `` We're trying to improve the visual aspects of <LOCATION> Sunset </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION>, and if everybody did this it would promote a garish image,'' <PERSON> Boettcher </PERSON> said. The restaurant faces fines or citations if they do n't take the chicken down. <PERSON> Simmons </PERSON> said the $ 800 mechanical chicken, which went up two weeks ago, has proved an ideal replacement for reluctant teen-agers he had been paying to stand by the side of the road dressed in chicken outfits. `` It's hard to find people to be a chicken,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880307-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-07-88 0921EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-People-HoseaWilliams     03-07 0151</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-People-Hosea Williams,0153</SECOND>
<HEAD>Atlanta Councilman Charged After Carrying Weapon Into Airport</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ATLANTA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 City Councilman <PERSON> Hosea </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> was charged with carrying a weapon without a license when security officers at <LOCATION> Hartsfield </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> <LOCATION> International </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION> found a gun in his briefcase at an airport checkpoint. The .38 - caliber revolver was confiscated when <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> was charged about 11:30 a.m. Sunday, but the councilman and civil rights activist was allowed to continue to his plane, said <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Hyndman </PERSON> of the airport police. <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> `` said he had been cleaning his car out and took it out of his car and put it in his briefcase but forgot to leave it in his house,'' <PERSON> Hyndman </PERSON> said. Police reports did not say whether the gun was loaded. The charge is a misdemeanor, and <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> could face up to $ 1,000 in fines. <PERSON> Hyndman </PERSON> declined to give <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>' destination, and calls to the councilman's home went unanswered.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880307-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-07-88 0937EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-UN-Afghanistan 2ndLd-Writethru a0512 03-07 0598</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-UN-Afghanistan, 2nd Ld - Writethru, a0512,0612</SECOND>
<HEAD>Talks Resume With Pakistan Insisting On Interim Afghan Government</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: CLARIFIES lead. INSERTS 3 grafs after 4th graf pvs, `Soviet
leader ...,' to UPDATE with Zia interview. PICKS up 5th graf, `Upon
his ...'</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By HANNS NEUERBOURG</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>GENEVA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 U.N.-sponsored <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> peace talks resumed today with uncertainty persisting over whether <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> is ready to sign an agreement with the Soviet-backed <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION> government which it does not recognize. Resumption of talks came after unprecedented consultations between the Pakistani government and opposition leaders attended by <LOCATION> Islamabad </LOCATION>'s chief negotiator, acting Foreign Minister <PERSON> Zain </PERSON> <PERSON> Noorani </PERSON>. Sources close to the meetings held during the weekend in <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> said most of 19 opposition parties urged the government not to stand in the way of the proposed pullout of the estimated 115,000 Soviet troops helping <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION> to fight Moslem insurgents. Soviet leader <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> has said a withdrawal could start in mid-May if a settlement is signed by next week. In an interview published today, Pakistani President <PERSON> Mohammad </PERSON> <PERSON> Zia </PERSON> <PERSON> ul-Haq </PERSON> said his country will not budge from its demand for an interim government in <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION> as part of a settlement. The Gulf News daily reported that <PERSON> Zia </PERSON> was optimistic that the proposed peace accord on <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> will be signed on schedule. `` There is no question of the accord not going through. Allowing it to be dropped is no option,'' he was quoted as saying. Upon his return to <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> Sunday night, <PERSON> Noorani </PERSON> said the formation of a broad-based transitional government was as important as the troop withdrawl in bringing peace to the region. `` Why should we not insist on an interim government,'' he said in response to a question from a reporter at the airport. Last week <PERSON> Noorani </PERSON> said <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> would make up its mind after the <LOCATION> Islamabad </LOCATION> consultations on whether to sign a settlement with the present <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION> government of President <PERSON> Najib </PERSON>, which <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> does not recognize. He put up only a cryptic smile when asked again before today's session if <LOCATION> Islamabad </LOCATION> was now prepared to sign <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> has insisted that any agreement on the withdrawal Soviet troops should be linked to formation of an interim government that is acceptable to all sides in the 9-year-old war. The <LOCATION> Islamabad </LOCATION> government says this is the only way to ensure the safe repatriation of 5 million Afghan refugees from <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> has been representing Afghan rebels at the U.N.-sponsored talks, which began in 1982. The resistance movements, which say they represent 200,000 guerrillas, have rejected any power-sharing with <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>'s President <PERSON> Najib </PERSON> and have presented a plan of their own for an Islamic government The Afghan government says its own policy of national reconciliation envisages a `` coalition government'' open to all political forces including the Pakistan-based resistance movements. The <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, which sent its troops in December 1979 to help a faltering Marxist government suppress a Moslem insurrection, no longer demands a transitional government be formed before withdrawal. <PERSON> Diego </PERSON> <PERSON> Cordovez </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> undersecretary general who has been mediating the Afghan talks, said last week all major differences had been resolved in the first three days of the new negotiating round, which began last Wednesday. The two sides agreed on a nine-month timetable for the withdrawal of Soviet troops from <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Cordovez </PERSON> said this agreement, following years of stalling on the timetable issue, represented a `` significant step'' toward a final political settlement. The sides also agreed that half of the Soviet troops would leave in the first three-month phase, the so-called `` front-end loading'' which had been a major concern of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880307-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-07-88 0948EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Iran-Iraq 2ndLd-Writethru   03-07 0477</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Iran-Iraq, 2nd Ld - Writethru,a0492,0489</SECOND>
<HEAD>Iran And Iraq Lob More Missiles Into Each Other's Capitals</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: LEADS with 13 grafs to UPDATE attack numbers, edits to
conform; picks up 14th graf pvs; Iran's Foreign...</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By ED BLANCHE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NICOSIA, Cyprus (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> shot missiles into each other's capitals today and both reported dozens of deaths as the `` war of the cities'' persisted between the two <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> war foes. <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'s official <ORGANIZATION> Islamic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> said 12 civilians, including women and children, were killed and 30 wounded when an Iraqi missile exploded in <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION> today. It said a hospital clinic, several houses and 30 vehicles were destroyed in the blast. The missile was one of three <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> said its army shot into <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION> early today in the latest round of the bruising offensive that has claimed hundreds of lives in both countries. <ORGANIZATION> IRNA </ORGANIZATION> said another 61 civilians were killed and 427 wounded Sunday in Iraqi air raids on 16 Iranian cities and towns. The agency said schools and hospitals were hit in the wave of Iraqi raids on the southern city of <LOCATION> Shiraz </LOCATION> and Dezful, <LOCATION> Arak </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Khorramabad </LOCATION> and other population centers in the west. Eight other people were wounded in missile strikes on <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION> on Sunday, it said. It said Iraqi artillery was shelling the northwestern border town of <LOCATION> Marivan </LOCATION>, but made no mention of casualties or damage. <LOCATION> Baghdad </LOCATION> communiques said <LOCATION> Iraqi </LOCATION> fighter-bombers flew 118 combat missions against `` military and economic targets'' in 12 Iranian cities Sunday in retaliation for `` criminal attacks on Iraqi civilian areas.'' <ORGANIZATION> IRNA </ORGANIZATION> reported that Revolutionary Guards fired four missiles into <LOCATION> Baghdad </LOCATION> today. It said they were aimed at `` military centers.'' <LOCATION> Baghdad </LOCATION> said the first two missiles crashed into residential sections of the capital, killing or wounding `` many civilians, including women and children.'' The agency said <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> retaliated by firing three long-range `` <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> Hussein </PERSON>'' missiles, named after a 7th Century Shiite Moslem saint, into <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION> today. <ORGANIZATION> INA </ORGANIZATION> quoted a military communique as saying: `` <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'s rulers must realize their weakness and stop fighting.'' The eight-day missile exchange has been the fiercest since the gulf war began in September 1980 and the first time that <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION> has been hit by missiles. <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> says it has fired 41 projectiles into the Iranian capital since the eye-for-an-eye missile duel began Feb. 29, when <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> sent two missiles crashing into <LOCATION> Baghdad </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'s Foreign Minister, <PERSON> Ali </PERSON> <PERSON> Akbar </PERSON> <PERSON> Velayati </PERSON>, admitted Saturday that `` more than 30'' missiles had hit <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION>. The Iranians have reported firing 22 missiles in that period, but the Iraqis have only acknowledged 18 hits. <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> has reported at least 106 civilians killed and more than 200 wounded in the <LOCATION> Iraqi </LOCATION> missile blitz, with more than 100 killed and more than 500 wounded in air raids over the last week. <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> has reported heavy civilian casualties, but has given no numbers.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880307-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-07-88 0959EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-SchoolRape     03-07 0445</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-School Rape,0460</SECOND>
<HEAD>Student Says Youths Laughed As They Watched Her Being Raped</HEAD>
<DATELINE>JACKSON, Miss. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A special education student says no other youths moved to help her when two boys raped her in a classroom, and when the bell rang at the end of the period they left laughing. The Magee resident also said two boys charged with the rape at <ORGANIZATION> Magee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> High </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> had harassed her for about two years. `` Me and -LRB- he -RRB- fight every day,'' the 16-year-old girl said in a weekend interview with The Clarion Ledger at her parents' rural <LOCATION> Simpson </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> home. `` He just picks on me and call my mom and daddy names.'' The girl said she was raped by two male students on Feb. 26 while she and other students were in study hall under the supervision of teacher <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Grantham </PERSON>, who said he had gone to check on a school bus he drives when the attack occurred. The girl, who has a learning disability, and her family agreed to discuss the attack if their identities were n't disclosed, the newspaper said Sunday. The girl said the youths, ages 15 and 17, grabbed her around the neck when she and another girl went to sharpen their pencils. They grabbed the other girl, too, but let her go, she said. `` They carried me in the back of the room. I told them to leave me alone.'' The girl said the youths pulled off her underwear, and each raped her twice, she said. `` One was holding me,'' she said. `` Every time I tried to get up, they hold me down.'' The attack occurred within sight of several other students, she said. All the students in the study hall, except for one of the attackers, were regular students, said <PERSON> Betty </PERSON> <PERSON> Dickson </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Simpson </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> chairwoman. One of the boys is educably mentally retarded, according to special education director <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Hardy </PERSON>. No one stopped the attack, the girl said, even though she told the other girl at the pencil sharpener to alert a principal or teacher. `` When the bell rang, they walked out the door, laughing,'' she said. The girl's father said he is as upset with school officials as he is the two boys. `` I send them to learn, not to be going down there to get raped,'' he said. The father said he called police and took his daughter to <ORGANIZATION> Magee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION> that night to be examined. The two youths were arrested Thursday, charged with rape and jailed in lieu of $ 50,000 bond each. Although they will be tried as adults, officials refused to release their names. <PERSON> Dickson </PERSON> said school officials are planning counseling for the girl.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880307-0025 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-07-88 1002EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Israel-Bus 4thLd-Writethru   03-07 0894</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Israel-Bus, 4th Ld - Writethru,a0532,0921</SECOND>
<HEAD>Arab Guerillas Seize Bus; Six Killed</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: LEADS with four grafs to UPDATE with report of PLO claiming
responsibility, PLO denial; picks up 3rd graf, `A special ...'
EDITS to tigten.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By DAN IZENBERG</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BEERSHEVA, Israel (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Arab guerrillas in southern <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> hijacked a passenger bus today and held it for three hours before <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> troops stormed it, killing three gunmen. Three Israeli civilians also were killed and eight were wounded, an army communique said. <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s state-run radio said the terrorists infiltrated from <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION> and were armed with fragmentation grenades, assault rifles and a submachine gun. A man claiming to represent the <ORGANIZATION> Palestine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> 17 phoned a Western news agency in <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION> and claimed responsibility for the hijacking. <ORGANIZATION> Israel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> radio </ORGANIZATION> said a <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> spokesman in <LOCATION> Tunis </LOCATION> told <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> news the group was not responsible for the attack. But a survivor from the bus said she heard the Arab gunmen say they were from <ORGANIZATION> Fatah </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> faction headed by <PERSON> Yasser </PERSON> <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON>. A special anti-terrorist unit and border police stormed the bus, which was loaded with nuclear plant workers and hijacked near the Aroer junction eight miles from the Dimona nuclear facility. Prime Minister <PERSON> Yitzhak </PERSON> <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON> linked the attack to the rioting in the occupied <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strip </LOCATION>. `` These are the same people who incite violence in the -LRB- occupied -RRB- territories. We shall not tire from fighting them,'' said <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON>. He noted today's attack was the second infiltration in two days. Three Palestinian guerrillas were killed by army soldiers on Sunday after they tried to cross the <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> border. <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> radio and officials said the terrorists came across the lightly guarded border from <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION> at night near <LOCATION> Ramat </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Nafha </LOCATION> and commandeered an Israeli military automobile at about 7 a.m. The Arab guerrillas drove the Renault-4 towards the <LOCATION> Beersheva-Dimona </LOCATION> highway, throwing a hand grenade at an Israeli semi-trailer but causing no injuries. The army and witnesses said a <ORGANIZATION> Volvo </ORGANIZATION> bus with the nuclear workers was coming from the opposite direction, and the gunmen fired at the bus and threw grenades until it stopped. Most of the passengers and the driver escaped but a man and nine women remained, the radio said. The last bus hijacking inside <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> occurred on April 12, 1984, when four bomb-weilding Palestinians hijacked an <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> bus near the <LOCATION> Mediterranean </LOCATION> coastal city of <LOCATION> Ashdod </LOCATION>. A soldier was killed on the bus when Israeli troops stormed the vehicle and captured the hijackers. Officials at <ORGANIZATION> Soroka </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Beersheva </LOCATION> said eight women were admitted for treatment of gunshot wounds. Police forced the bus to stop after the terrorists fired from the bus at passing people and cars. Police closed the area, and army officers entered into negotiations with terrorists. The Arab gunmen demanded to speak with representatives of the <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION> and also asked for a loudspeaker. Maj. Gen. <PERSON> Yitzhak </PERSON> <PERSON> Mordechai </PERSON>, commander of <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s southern region, decided to storm the bus rather than negotiate further after the gunmen opened fire. `` We made every effort to both relax them and to promise them that negotiations may bring results,'' <PERSON> Mordechai </PERSON> told reporters at the scene. `` -LRB- But -RRB- they fired at us twice and afterwards they fired and killed one of the hostages and fired at women who were inside the bus,'' he said. In all, he said, the storming operation lasted about a minute. <PERSON> Mordechai </PERSON> said the man was killed by <PERSON> Arab </PERSON> gunmen during negotiations. He said shots fired by the terrorists when the bus was stormed appeared to have killed the women. The victims were not identified, apparently because of the sensitivity of their jobs. At the hospital, <PERSON> David </PERSON>, a curly-haired man in his late 20s, said he saw armed terrorists block the blue <ORGANIZATION> Volvo </ORGANIZATION> bus, a special commuter vehicle carrying women workers from a plant in <LOCATION> Dimona </LOCATION>. `` The terrorists blocked the bus and did n't give the driver a chance to turn around and get away,'' he said. `` The driver opened the door and many of the passengers scrambled out. About a half-dozen remained on the bus.'' <PERSON> David </PERSON> said the bus hijacking began about 7:30 a.m. and he watched the hijacking from another bus. He declined to give his last name. <PERSON> Rafi </PERSON> <PERSON> Hayon </PERSON>, a motorist traveling the <LOCATION> Beersheva-Dimona </LOCATION> highway, said the Arab gunmen armed with Soviet-made automatic rifles shot at his car when he refused to stop for them. `` I saw only two Kalashnikovs in front of my eyes,'' he said in an interview broadcast by <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> radio. It was the bloodiest attack by Palestinian guerrillas since a hang-glider attack in late November in which a guerrilla landed in northern <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> and shot to death six <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> soldiers and wounded eight. The Dimona plant is at the center of a secret trial now going on in <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Mordechai </PERSON> <PERSON> Vanunu </PERSON>, a former nuclear technician at Dimona, revealed <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s atomic secrets to <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sunday </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> London </ORGANIZATION> in an expose published Oct. 5, 1986. Based on <PERSON> Vanunu </PERSON>'s information, the newspaper concluded <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> possessed the world's sixth largest nuclear arsenal. In the Sunday Times story, <PERSON> Vanunu </PERSON> detailed the route taken by 40 blue and white <ORGANIZATION> Volvo </ORGANIZATION> buses he said transported workers to the nuclear plant each day. <PERSON> Vanunu </PERSON>, 33, was tried on charges of treason and espionage for revealing <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s nuclear capability and the three-judge panel in the closed-door trial is currently deliberating its verdict.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880307-0026 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-07-88 1009EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-HouseShot     03-07 0322</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-House Shot,0330</SECOND>
<HEAD>Teen-ager Upset About School, Basketball Shoots Up Own House</HEAD>
<DATELINE>RIGA, N.Y. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A 15-year-old boy described as despondent over school problems and upset about the outcome of a college basketball game blasted away with an assortment of rifles and handguns for five hours inside his home, officials said today. No one was injured in the incident, which ended when deputies talked the boy into surrendering early today, said <LOCATION> Monroe </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> sheriff's spokesman <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Ryan </PERSON>. `` The house is a shambles,'' <PERSON> Ryan </PERSON> said this morning. `` He shot out the television, the stove, the walls and ceilings, windows, sliding glass doors, a water pipe which ruptured and squirted water everywhere, and even the electrical box in the basement.'' <PERSON> Ryan </PERSON> said the boy, whose name was withheld because of his age, had picked up a gun and started shooting Sunday night. His mother ran next door to call police. When deputies arrived at the house in the rural area southwest of <LOCATION> Rochester </LOCATION>, they heard bullets whizzing by their heads and evacuated the house next door. Deputies then set up a command post in a house down the road, from which negotiators talked to the youth by telephone, <PERSON> Ryan </PERSON> said. Before the boy surrendered early Sunday morning he had fired at least 300 rounds of ammunition had been fired from a variety of weapons, <PERSON> Ryan </PERSON> said. The boy's father had four or five rifles and shotguns and four handguns, <PERSON> Ryan </PERSON> said. `` The boy had been suspended from high school last week for disciplinary problems,'' <PERSON> Ryan </PERSON> said. `` Whether this triggered him, we do n't know. The only other thing he mentioned to hostage negotiators was that he was upset that <ORGANIZATION> Syracuse </ORGANIZATION> lost to <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION>.'' <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION> edged <ORGANIZATION> Syracuse </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> 85-84 to take the <ORGANIZATION> Big </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> East </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conference </ORGANIZATION> college basketball title Sunday afternoon. The youth was taken to Strong Memorial Hospital in <LOCATION> Rochester </LOCATION> for a mental examination before being turned over to family court officials, said <PERSON> Ryan </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880307-0027 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-07-88 1012EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Scotus-Canton     03-07 0705</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Scotus-Canton,700</SECOND>
<HEAD>Court Will Try Again to Decide on Suing Cities in Ohio Case</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JAMES H. RUBIN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
