<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880908-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-08-88 0107EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Israel-SlainTeen     09-08 0443</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Israel-Slain Teen,0460</SECOND>
<HEAD>Police: Palestinian Killed Jewish Teen Who Dreamed Of Co-Existence</HEAD>
<DATELINE>JERUSALEM (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> teen-ager who dreamed of Jewish-Arab co-existence and befriended many Arabs in the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> was slain by a <LOCATION> Palestinian </LOCATION> acquaintance after she refused to get him a gun, police said Wednesday. The Palestinian, whose name was not released, confessed to the slaying of 18-year-old <PERSON> Ziva </PERSON> <PERSON> Goldovsky </PERSON> and reconstructed the crime for police, said investigator <PERSON> Uri </PERSON> <PERSON> Weisskoop </PERSON>. Ms. <PERSON> Goldovsky </PERSON>'s charred remains were found Aug. 15 in a field near the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> town <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bireh </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Weisskoop </PERSON> said her assailant choked her from behind and struck her repeatedly with a large stone before he and an accomplice set the corpse on fire. Ms. <PERSON> Goldovsky </PERSON> became the fifth Israeli to die in the 9-month-old Palestinian uprising. The Palestinian death toll has reached 259. <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> radio described Ms. <PERSON> Goldovsky </PERSON>, an immigrant from the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, as an activist in the left-wing <ORGANIZATION> Mapam </ORGANIZATION> party `` who could be found at most pro-Palestinian demonstrations.'' Ms. <PERSON> Goldovsky </PERSON>, a resident of the <LOCATION> Tel </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Aviv </LOCATION> suburb of Holon, was engaged to a Palestinian from the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> city of <LOCATION> Hebron </LOCATION>, friends of the victim told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> last month. Ms. <PERSON> Goldovsky </PERSON>'s fiance, who has a police record, is in custody on robbery charges but is not a suspect in the slaying, police said. On Aug. 13, Ms. <PERSON> Goldovsky </PERSON> and a Palestinian acquaintance went for a walk near <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bireh </LOCATION> and began to argue, <ORGANIZATION> Israel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> radio </ORGANIZATION> said. The man started hitting her and shouted: `` Why do you dress so immodestly?'' the report said. `` Do n't hit me,'' she said. `` Even my parents do n't beat me.'' The man then accused her of being an informer for <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s <PERSON> Shin </PERSON> <PERSON> Bet </PERSON> security service. When she denied this, he said: `` Prove it, get me a pistol.'' She refused, saying: `` I should get you a gun so you can kill young Jewish boys and girls?'' The man again slapped Ms. <PERSON> Goldovsky </PERSON> and then choked her. `` He took us to the place where he killed her,'' <PERSON> Weisskoop </PERSON> was quoted as telling the radio. `` He approached her from behind, choked her and laid her on the ground. `` Then he hit her with a large stone. About 50 yards from the site of the killing he and a friend burned the body and this is how she was found.'' One of Ms. <PERSON> Goldovsky </PERSON>'s Jewish friends, speaking on condition of anonymity, said last month she often hitchhiked to the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> and formed friendships with many Palestinians. The friend said Ms. <PERSON> Goldovsky </PERSON> dreamed of Jewish-Arab co-existence. `` <PERSON> Ziva </PERSON> would have continued her road of co-existence even if she knew what her end would be,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880908-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-08-88 0109EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Amnesty-Kurds 1stLd-Writethru a0816 09-08 0436</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Amnesty-Kurds, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0816,0443</SECOND>
<HEAD>Security Council Asked To Act For Iraqi Kurds</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: LEADS throughout to UPDATE with Kurdish leader saying
fighting continues in Iraq. No pickup.</NOTE>
<HEAD>With AM-Gulf Talks</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Amnesty </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> said on Thursday that it has appealed to the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> to `` act immediately to stop the massacre of Kurdish civilians by Iraqi forces.'' Meanwhile, the leader of the Kurdish rebels said that <LOCATION> Iraqi </LOCATION> government troops are still attacking guerrillas and civilians in northern <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> despite the government's amnesty offer. <ORGANIZATION> Amnesty </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION>, the London-based human rights organization, said in a statement that it made its first direct appeal on Wednesday night to the 15-member <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> body in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> because the `` systematic and deliberate'' killings `` call out for immediate action by the <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>.'' The statement charged <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> wants to punish the Kurds for their political sympathies and in retaliation for opposition Kurdish activities. More than 100,000 Iraqi Kurds fled across the border to <LOCATION> Turkey </LOCATION> and many of them gave consistent accounts of the use of chemical weapons, the statement said. Amnesty last week accused <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> of killing hundreds of Kurdish villagers with chemical weapons in mountainous northern <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> and of employing helicopter gunships, tanks and artillery in <LOCATION> Duhok </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mosul </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Arbil </LOCATION> provinces. <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>'s ambassador to <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Mohammed </PERSON> <PERSON> Sadiq </PERSON> <PERSON> al-Mashat </PERSON>, denied chemical weapons were used. He was summoned to the <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> on Tuesday and was told of British concern over the large numbers of Kurdish refugees and the reports of chemical weapons use. The latest <ORGANIZATION> Amnesty </ORGANIZATION> statement gave a qualified welcome to the <LOCATION> Iraqi </LOCATION> amnesty for Kurds, saying it received reports in the past of Kurds being imprisoned and executed after responding to previous amnesties. <PERSON> Massoud </PERSON> <PERSON> Barzani </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> Kurdistan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, said in a telex sent to The Associated Press office in <LOCATION> Cyprus </LOCATION> on Wednesday that the Kurds will not accept the general amnesty offered by <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> the day before. `` The Kurds have not struggled to be pardoned but to acheive their national and democratic rights within autonomy,'' <PERSON> Barzani </PERSON> said. `` Our struggle will continue until these goals are fulfilled.'' <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> launched the offensive against the Kurdish rebels after a cease-fire in its eight-year war with <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> went into effect Aug. 20. <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>'s 3.5 million Kurds have been struggling on and off for 50 years for an autonomous homeland. The <ORGANIZATION> Kurdistan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> has said that nearly 2,000 civilians have been killed and another 5,000 injured, many by chemical weapons. In his statement Wednesday, <PERSON> Barzani </PERSON> said the amnesty offer was an attempt by <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> to deflect attention from its use of chemical weapons.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880908-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-08-88 0010EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p AM-Bush 2ndLd-Writethru   09-08 1013</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Bush, 2nd Ld-Writethru,a0795,960</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush Stumbles On Pearl Harbor, But Crowd Applauds Him</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: INSERTS five new grafs after 3rd pvs, Bush said...military
occupation, to UPDATE with Bush statement on wanting to raise
minimum wage and showing in polls, picking up 4th pvs, On the
question...Bush said.
^By TERENCE HUNT</NOTE>
<BYLINE>AP White House Correspondent</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LOUISVILLE, Ky. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Republican <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> stunned an American Legion convention Wednesday by mistakenly saying Sept. 7 marked the anniversary of the attack on <LOCATION> Pearl </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Harbor </LOCATION> that led <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> into World War II. The gaffe _ which he corrected after prompting from the audience _ overshadowed a campaign day in which the vice president also stumped for Jewish votes at a B'nai B'rith convention in <LOCATION> Baltimore </LOCATION>, Md. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said he opposes creation of an independent Palestinian state in the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION>, but also cautioned <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> against annexation of the occupied territories or exercising permanent control by military occupation. In another matter signaling a departure from the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> told <ORGANIZATION> Knight-Ridder </ORGANIZATION> newspapers Wednesday he will soon outline a proposal calling for `` some adjustment'' in the minimum wage. The administration opposes raising the minimum wage, which is now $ 3.35 an hour. But campaign sources told <ORGANIZATION> Knight-Ridder </ORGANIZATION> that <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was expected to link a raise in the minimum wage to a sub-minimum wage `` training differential'' for teen-agers and other new hires. <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> has opposed such a differential in the past. `` We ought to maintain a minimum wage differential for training people,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has been criticized by his opponents as insensitive to the needs of working people. The vice president received encouraging news from the latest <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News-Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> poll which found <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> leading <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> by an eight-point margin. The survey of 1,104 likely voters found that 51 percent favored <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> while 43 percent prefer <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>. The poll, conducted Aug. 31 to Sept. 6, had a margin of error of 3.5 percent. On the question of a <LOCATION> Palestinian </LOCATION> state, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> sharply criticized Democratic rival <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, although he did n't mention him by name. `` Anyone who has trouble making up his mind on this issue, or who proposes to leave it open, just does n't understand the dangers to <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> and to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>; just does n't understand the very real threats that continue to exist,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> opened the day in <LOCATION> Louisville </LOCATION> with a speech before about 6,000 veterans at their 70th annual meeting. Departing from his prepared remarks, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said, `` I wonder how many Americans remember today is Pearl Harbor Day. Forty-seven years ago to this very day we were hit and hit hard at <LOCATION> Pearl </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Harbor </LOCATION> and we were not ready. `` In a <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration that lesson would not be forgotten,'' said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, who was a <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> flyer decorated for combat missions during the war. `` It would guide my defense and foreign policy.'' The words were barely out of his mouth before the crowd turned uneasy. A buzz of mumurs rose among the audience as legionnaires began whispering about it. `` I thought nobody would forget that date,'' one veteran commented to another. A minute after his mistake, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> stopped dead in his speech, alerted by the stir in the audience and people waving at him over his error. `` Did I say Sept. 7th? Sorry about that,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said, adding quickly that the correct date of the attack was Dec. 7, 1941. The audience applauded his correction and generally gave him a warm, polite reception. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> told reporters later, `` I just got messed up. I wanted to work <LOCATION> Pearl </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Harbor </LOCATION> in and just got carried away.'' It was the second rocky day in a row for <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s campaign, following a booing, jeering reception from shipyard workers in <LOCATION> Portland </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ore. </LOCATION> on Tuesday. <PERSON> Sheila </PERSON> <PERSON> Tate </PERSON>, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s press secretary, said the vice president had ad libbed his <LOCATION> Pearl </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Harbor </LOCATION> remark, perhaps because it was 44 years ago this week that <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, a decorated <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> flyer in the war, was shot down on over the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION>. The gaffe marred <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s attempt to highlight differences with <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>. He accused <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> of trying to `` cancel and delay our strategic modernization with what amounts to an undeclared unilateral freeze.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> noted that <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> opposes the MX and Midgetman missiles, the <ORGANIZATION> Strategic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> System </ORGANIZATION> and has called for cancellation of two aircraft carrier task forces. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> has opposed the Stealth bomber in the past `` although this may be changing.'' `` Let me be clear,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said. `` I do not question his patriotism. But patriotism is not the issue. The issue is how best to deter war, to keep the peace, to fulfill our country's special responsibility as leader of the free world.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said, `` I think <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> wants tough, tested, experienced leadership ... I am proud of having served my country in combat. I believe I have the fiber and the experience to lead this country.'' Later, in <LOCATION> Baltimore </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> underscored the closeness of U.S.-Israeli relations. `` No threat, no stone thrown, is strong enough to divide us. No wedge will be driven between us,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> pledged. In warning against <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> annexation of the occupied territories, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said, `` There has got to be another way, and that's what the peace process is all about.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said he opposes creation of a <LOCATION> Palestinian </LOCATION> state on grounds it would be a threat to <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> as well as to <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION>, which he said is crucial to any lasting peace settlement. Moreover, he said, `` it would be contrary to American interests.'' On the flight from <LOCATION> Louisville </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Baltimore </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said that anti-abortion protestors who disrupted <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' speech Tuesday in a <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> suburb `` in my view went too far.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, who opposes abortion in most instances, said, `` I would ask any supporter of mine to resist carrying their right to demonstrate to an extreme.'' Explaining his gaffe, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> explained: `` I just got messed up. I wanted to work <LOCATION> Pearl </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Harbor </LOCATION> in and just got carried away, and then I looked up and saw incredulity on the face of one particular guy down to my left and I thought, ` Whoops ... My Heavens! I've done it!' So I was glad to correct it.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880908-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-08-88 0127EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-FairyShrimp     09-08 0245</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Fairy Shrimp,0250</SECOND>
<HEAD>Calif. County Moves To Save Fairy Shrimp's Skunk Hollow Swimming
Hole</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MURRIETA HOT SPRINGS, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Tiny Riverside fairy shrimps can keep splashing around in their swimming hole thanks to county supervisors who ordered developers to help save the recently discovered fresh-water crustacean. Developers planned to bulldoze a low-lying pond and build more than 2,500 homes, unaware that the species, whose ancestors date back millions of years, occupied the seasonal pool. <LOCATION> Riverside </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> supervisors on Tuesday ordered <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tolman </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Irvine </LOCATION> to preserve the threatened habitat after they were alerted by biologists who discovered the fairy shrimp species two years ago. The 22-legged fairy shrimp is about as wide as a pencil and 1 -LCB- inches long. It has been described by biologists as the most primitive crustacean living in fresh water. A group of biologists named the species the Riverside fairy shrimp after finding them in 15-acre Skunk Hollow pond and five smaller ponds in southern <LOCATION> Riverside </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, about 80 miles southeast of downtown <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>. The fairy shrimp population survives dry summer months by burying eggs in the clay soil of the seasonal pools. The eggs of some desert species have been known to survive for as long as 25 years between adequate rains. The Board of Supervisors gave the developer and the biologists until Sept. 27 to come up with a proposal that would permit the survival of the fairy shrimp and <PERSON> Tolman </PERSON>'s proposed 2,571-unit housing project.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880908-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-08-88 0139EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-FamilyFeud     09-08 1104</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Family Feud,1137</SECOND>
<HEAD>Riches Didn't Bring Happiness; Law Revision Might Have Helped,
Some Say</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report; note time element, Sept. 12, in
29th graf, ``Meanwhile, he...''</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By GEORGE ESPER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Special Correspondent</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PITTSBURGH (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilke </PERSON> parlayed $ 500 and frugality into a quarter-million-dollar estate, but after eight decades of tending his finances' growth, his harvest is heartache. At age 103, his yield is unhappiness. A family feud has grown up over who should handle his money and how his estate should be divided. As a result, the courts have declared him incompetent and placed him and his personal wealth under guardianships. Advocates for the elderly say proposed reforms in <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION>'s guardianship law might have spared him anguish and indignities in old age, including three medical examinations and the loss of many of his rights On the one side are <PERSON> Wilke </PERSON> and his two sons, <PERSON> Robert </PERSON>, 60, and <PERSON> William </PERSON>, 54. On the other side are his two daughters, <PERSON> Frances </PERSON> <PERSON> McAleer </PERSON>, 62, and <PERSON> Sylvia </PERSON> <PERSON> Eaborn </PERSON>, 50, who successfully petitioned a judge to declare him incompetent and to appoint guardians to make his personal and financial decisions. It was in the midst of the incompetency hearings in April that <PERSON> Wilke </PERSON>'s wife of 63 years, <PERSON> Amelia </PERSON>, died at age 89, and his mourning for her mixes with bitterness toward his daughters, with whom he no longer speaks. `` Both daughters wanted to take everything over that I worked all my life for,'' <PERSON> Wilke </PERSON> contends, even though an audit found no impropriety when Mrs. <PERSON> McAleer </PERSON> was handling his day-to-day finances. `` I ca n't even spend my money after saving it,'' complains <PERSON> Wilke </PERSON>, who started work at age 15 for a dollar-and-a-half a week. `` When you think you got money, you ai n't got nothin'.'' He never earned more than $ 4,200 a year in 57 years of work as a machinist and maintenance engineer. He retired at age 72. He started saving when he was 29 by putting $ 500 from his share of the family house, sold upon his father's death, into five banks. Shopping for bargains and rarely traveling, <PERSON> Wilke </PERSON> saved and saved. His will provided that each of his children would receive one-fourth of the accumulated wealth. After he and his wife entered a nursing home, he asked his elder daughter in late 1986 to help with his bill-paying and other accounts and gave her legal authority under a power of attorney. Still, he continued to monitor his finances, and at one point their figures conflicted. Father accused daughter of being unable to explain how $ 20,000 was spent. Last October, <PERSON> Wilke </PERSON> transferred his power of attorney to his sons. He also changed his will to make the sons executors instead of the daughters. `` I cried the whole day,'' Mrs. <PERSON> McAleer </PERSON> testified. `` My heart was broken that my father would do this to me without telling me.'' Mrs. <PERSON> McAleer </PERSON> and her sister filed the incompetency petition 2 -LCB- weeks later, and an Orphans Court judge declared <PERSON> Wilke </PERSON> incompetent on June 1, naming the <ORGANIZATION> Pittsburgh </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> as his financial guardian and a lawyer as his personal guardian. The incompetency petition upset <PERSON> Wilke </PERSON> so much that he rewrote his will in March. Now, the daughters are to receive 10 percent each, the sons 40 percent each. The daughters declined to be interviewed, but their lawyer, <PERSON> Geoffrey </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Wozman </PERSON>, said they apparently `` wanted protection'' after Mrs. <PERSON> McAleer </PERSON> was accused. `` I do n't think they particularly thought the sons were going to take his money. They did n't think the sons were the proper people to take care of it. They did n't think they were either. No matter who controls the money, someone is going to complain they're not doing something right,'' <PERSON> Wozman </PERSON> said. Explaining why the guardianship was sought, the lawyer said the old man was not `` rational in terms of financial affairs.'' A psychiatrist testifying for the daughters said <PERSON> Wilke </PERSON> was incompetent `` due to the infirmities of old age.'' Another psychiatrist testified for the sons that while <PERSON> Wilke </PERSON> needed help managing his finances, he found no evidence of incompetency. A third psychiatrist, appointed by the court, examined <PERSON> Wilke </PERSON> seven weeks after he was declared incompetent and concluded that he is `` suffering from some mild cognitive impairment.'' When the guardianship was declared, <PERSON> Wilke </PERSON> lost the right to vote, to make decisions about his own health care and to travel without approval from his guardian. Against his wishes, he was initially ordered back into a nursing home. Later, the judge allowed him to continue to live with son <PERSON> William </PERSON> in suburban <PERSON> Green </PERSON> <PERSON> Tree </PERSON>, where he had moved after his wife's death The elder <PERSON> Wilke </PERSON> is permitted to keep his monthly $ 537 Social Security check and his $ 210 pension check for expenses and for spending money. `` I think the <PERSON> Wilke </PERSON> case provides an example of flaws in our current state law,'' said Dr. <PERSON> Linda </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Rhodes </PERSON>, secretary of the <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> Department of Aging. Among proposed legal changes now before the <ORGANIZATION> Legislature </ORGANIZATION> is a provision to authorize limited guardianships for people who are only `` partially incapacitated,'' as two doctors found <PERSON> Wilke </PERSON> to be. A number of states already allow such guardianships, which tailor assistance to specific areas, such as managing a person's income and assets, while leaving most rights intact Current <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> law does not recognize partial incompetence and allows only for a blanket guardianship, under which virtually all decision-making is turned over to someone else. `` Here's an individual who could use some assistance in financial planning but certainly he can make choices we all make every day,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Rhodes </PERSON> said of <PERSON> Wilke </PERSON>. At a Department of Aging hearing last month, <PERSON> Wilke </PERSON> himself testified in favor of the reform bill, which would also eliminate `` infirmities of old age'' as a reason for a finding of incompetency. An individual's faculties, not birth date, should be the deciding factor, department officials have argued. Meanwhile, <PERSON> Wilke </PERSON> is challenging the incompetency finding. A hearing is set before an Orphans Court panel Sept. 12. As he sits in a rocking chair, watching the news or the <ORGANIZATION> Pirates </ORGANIZATION> ballgames, the white-haired man ponders what he'll do if he's declared competent and gets control of his money again He'll pay off some bills, he says, and visit his son <PERSON> Robert </PERSON>, who lives in <LOCATION> Tallahassee </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>. <PERSON> William </PERSON> says his father also feels he should pay him and his wife, <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON>, for his care and shelter, no more than $ 1,000 But reconciliation with his daughters is not in the cards. `` They're looking out for themselves, not me,'' he said. `` It hurt me a lot. I just ca n't forget.''
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Esper </PERSON> is the <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Northeast </ORGANIZATION> regional reporter, based in <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880908-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-08-88 0142EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BlackDoctors     09-08 0800</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Black Doctors,0824</SECOND>
<HEAD>Black Medical School In South Africa Debunks Skeptics</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By GREG MYRE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> GA-RANKUWA </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> -RRB- _ A creation of apartheid politics, <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>'s black medical school is producing 70 badly needed doctors a year, and even those who oppose it concede it is advancing black medicine in the country. <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> has 26 million blacks but only about 800 black doctors, as opposed to more than 21,000 white doctors among its 5 million whites. When the <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Africa </ORGANIZATION> was established 11 years ago in the homeland of <LOCATION> Bophuthatswana </LOCATION>, however, many activists rejected the school as an inferior institution built to keep medical training segregated. However, modern facilities and a qualified staff have helped the university graduate 273 doctors who work in some of the country's best hospitals as well as remote rural areas where health workers are in severely short supply `` The students reject the idea of segregated education, but we accept that we are getting good training,'' said a 26-year-old student asking to be identified only as <PERSON> Gwen </PERSON>. The school's new buildings and landscaped grounds sit behind a barbed-wire fence 20 miles outside <LOCATION> Pretoria </LOCATION>, the capital. The pristine campus appears out of place in dusty, run-down Ga-Rankuwa, a sprawling collection of dirt roads and squatter shacks. Many of the prospective doctors come from similarly impoverished communities. Some students arriving for the six-year program live with electricity for the first time, and most have little or no experience in laboratories. `` When students come here, they face tremendous adjustments,'' said the vice principal, <PERSON> Len </PERSON> <PERSON> Karlsson </PERSON>, who is white, as are all the top administrators. `` The pace and the intensity of the program is unlike anything they've experienced previously.'' He said black public high schools do not adequately prepare students for the rigors of medical school, and therefore the university often selects older students with some practical medical experience. About half the students are at least 25 years old and most have worked in the health care field before enrolling, said <PERSON> Karlsson </PERSON>. The university offers remedial courses in most basic subjects, but the failure rate remains high. About 40 percent of the 120 first-year students fail, although they are given the chance to repeat. The university is expanding its entering class annually and is one of the largest medical schools in <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> with about 1,500 students including its denistry, veterinary, nursing and post-graduate programs. The school, referred to by the acronym <LOCATION> MEDUNSA </LOCATION>, produces half of <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>'s 140 new black physicians each year. The rest come from schools that are predominantly white, such as the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> the </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Witwatersrand </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Johannesburg </LOCATION>. `` MEDUNSA is producing some outstanding doctors,'' said Dr. <PERSON> Nthato </PERSON> <PERSON> Motlana </PERSON>, a prominent anti-apartheid activist who runs a clinic in <LOCATION> Soweto </LOCATION>, the black township outside <LOCATION> Johannesburg </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Motlana </PERSON> and other activists initially opposed MEDUNSA, calling it a `` racist plan to build black medical school out in the <PERSON> bush </PERSON>.'' <PERSON> Motlana </PERSON> still opposes segregated schools, but says <ORGANIZATION> MEDUNSA </ORGANIZATION> has served to increase the meager supply of black doctors. Health services remain segregated, and the shortage of doctors and facilities is acute in most black areas. <LOCATION> Johannesburg </LOCATION>'s main white hospitals are about 50 percent empty, while an average of more than 200 patients sleep on the floor each night at <LOCATION> Soweto </LOCATION>'s 2,700-bed <ORGANIZATION> Baragwanath </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION>, the only full-service health facility for the township's 2.5 million residents. Despite the overcrowding at black hospitals in urban areas, the quality of care is much higher than in rural areas where the doctors are far too few and the facilities often inadequate or non-existent, <PERSON> Motlana </PERSON> said. <ORGANIZATION> MEDUNSA </ORGANIZATION> encourages graduates who want to work in rural areas, but most students are from the cities and see no incentive to relocate, school officials and students said. To combat the dearth of rural doctors, black homeland governments provide scholarships for MEDUNSA students, who then are required to return to work in the territories for several years after graduation. `` Until its becomes attrative for doctors to practice in rural areas most blacks will have trouble getting adequate health care,'' said <PERSON> Motlana </PERSON>. `` MEDUNSA has helped the situation, but it is not enough by itself.'' The university is financially supported by the South African government, but students are required to pay a tuition the equivalent of about $ 2,500 a year. Virturally every student receives some form of financial aid, however. School officials say <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> companies were generous with scholarship money, but many of them have pulled out of <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> because of its apartheid policies and no longer donate funds. School officials did n't have exact figures on the reduction in American assistance, but said its amounts to thousands of dollars annually. Some U.S.-based firms still operating in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>, including 3M, <ORGANIZATION> Colgate </ORGANIZATION>, and <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> and <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>, continue to provide scholarship money.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880908-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-08-88 0212EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Buddhists     09-08 0773</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Buddhists,0796</SECOND>
<HEAD>Buddhist Societies Becoming Prone To Violence</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By DENIS D. GRAY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BANGKOK, Thailand (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Buddhists in <LOCATION> Burma </LOCATION> kill each other while saffron-robed monks shake fists against the government, violating a 2,500-year-old rule against taking life and a tradition of <ORGANIZATION> Buddhist </ORGANIZATION> clergy shunning politics. <ORGANIZATION> Buddhist </ORGANIZATION> societies from <LOCATION> Sri </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lanka </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Burma </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Tibet </LOCATION> have proved as prone to violence as others in recent times despite the precepts of Lord <PERSON> Buddha </PERSON>, the great religious teacher of the 5th century B.C. <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION>, once a land of 90,000 monks in scores of quiet temples, was turned into a killing field by the savage <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION>. The current government says 3 million died in the 1975-78 reign of terror. In wartime <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>, protesting monks set themselves afire. More recently, conflict between the majority <ORGANIZATION> Sinhalese </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Buddhists </ORGANIZATION> and Hindu Tamils have left more than 8,000 dead in <LOCATION> Sri </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lanka </LOCATION>. A monk in <LOCATION> Burma </LOCATION> told an <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> visitor: `` If the government does n't change, the only way to prevent shedding the people's blood is to fight them to the death.'' The image of Buddhist gentleness persists, however. Proponents like to say Buddhists have not waged crusades or burned heretics at the stake, as Christians did, or established anything akin to today's strident Islamic states. <LOCATION> Southeast </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION>'s Theravada Buddhism, one of the religion's two major branches, places special emphasis on tolerance, equanimity and non-confrontation. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Klausner </PERSON>, an American expert on Thai culture, says Buddhists try to avoid the confrontational behavior _ a sharp word, a push, a slap _ others might employ in a situation of conflict. `` Violence is the last resort,'' he said, `` but when the eruption comes it's going to be more dramatic. The Thais say there is little maneuvering room between the smile and the knife.'' <PERSON> Chatsumarn </PERSON> <PERSON> Kabilsingh </PERSON>, a religion professor at <LOCATION> Bangkok </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Thammasat </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, believes Buddhism to a large extent explains why the <LOCATION> Burmese </LOCATION> put up with 26 years of authoritarian misrule before rising up last month Demonstrating along with students and workers were monks who, at least in Theravada tradition, are enjoined to restrict their activities to the sprititual. But monks marched, gave fiery speeches and were said to have largely replaced the government in <LOCATION> Mandalay </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Burma </LOCATION>'s second-largest city and a great religious cener. <PERSON> Klausner </PERSON> said in an interview that monks in <LOCATION> Sri </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lanka </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Burma </LOCATION> and to some degree <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> had `` legitimized a politial role for themselves.'' When <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> was the colonial power in <LOCATION> Burma </LOCATION>, it reduced the power of the monkhood, or `` sangha,'' and the <ORGANIZATION> Buddhist </ORGANIZATION> clergy assumed a political role, helping expel the alien, <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> conquerors. <LOCATION> Burma </LOCATION> became independent in 1948. Some analysts say many monks similarly regarded the socialism of military strongman Ne Win as an alien ideology and resented his efforts to co-opt and control clergy after he seized power in 1962. A strain of aggressiveness is a long-standing characteristic of <ORGANIZATION> Mahayana </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Buddhism </ORGANIZATION>, practiced in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Tibet </LOCATION>. Buddhist-backed groups in 16th century <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> would band together to overthrow feudal lords, and the monks of the Shaolin Temple in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> were noted for truculence and their skill as warriors. The Shaolin Temple remains a center for the study of martial arts. About 70 people have been injured in recent fueding between the main <LOCATION> Chokey </LOCATION> sect in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> and its rivals. The antagonists, including monks, have attacked one another with clubs, iron pipes and knives. Although <LOCATION> Tibet </LOCATION>'s exiled religious leader, the <PERSON> Dalai </PERSON> <PERSON> Lama </PERSON>, urges non-violent resistance to Chinese rule, young <ORGANIZATION> Buddhist </ORGANIZATION> monks led riots last year and in March. They were involved in throwing rocks, burning vehicles and the death of a policeman who was beaten and flung from a monastery window. In a little-publicized conflict, <ORGANIZATION> Buddhist </ORGANIZATION> rebels called Chakmas raid villages and battle authorities in eastern <LOCATION> Bangladesh </LOCATION> to halt government efforts to settle Moslems on land traditionally held by Buddhists. At least 4,000 people have been killed, by official count. <LOCATION> Thailand </LOCATION>, which calls itself the `` Land of Smiles,'' has one of <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION>'s highest homicide rates periodic outbursts of brutality. Faced with mounting evidence in the early 1980s that <LOCATION> Thai </LOCATION> pirates were killing and raping Vietnamese `` boat people,'' several officials said the equivalent of: `` They ca n't be Thais. Thais are Buddhists and Buddhists would n't act like that.'' <ORGANIZATION> Buddhist </ORGANIZATION> scholars say much of this violence, and political activism by the clergy, results from rapid modernization, economic inequalities and political repression. Chatsumarn, the <LOCATION> Bangkok </LOCATION> professor, said in an interview: `` Buddhism molds the mentality to be tolerant, to bear all, but even good Buddhists ca n't live solely on religion. Basic needs must be met and stomachs filled.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880908-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-08-88 0148EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Irish     09-08 0785</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Irish,0811</SECOND>
<HEAD>Neighbors Remember Slain IRA Man As `Friendly Lad'</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By BEN DOBBIN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SIXMILECROSS, Northern Ireland (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The elderly manager of a hardware store in this farming village remembered <PERSON> Brian </PERSON> <PERSON> Mullin </PERSON> as `` a friendly lad,'' a bricklayer who often dropped by for supplies. `` He just got caught up in the troubles because he knew nothing else,'' the manager said. `` He's only one of hundreds of young men in the area who have been harassed every day by the security forces.'' <PERSON> Mullin </PERSON>, 25, and two other local <ORGANIZATION> Irish </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> men died in a British army ambush Aug. 30 as they drove along a country road near <LOCATION> Drumnakilly </LOCATION>, 5 miles north of here. Their funerals over the weekend drew mourners from all around the area and hundreds of riot police. The mourners, mostly Catholic, and the police, mostly Protestant, faced each other in stony silence. Physically, they were inches apart. Mentally, a gulf separated them. Police said the three dead men were armed and dressed in ski masks when they died. The <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> newspapers called them terrorists, murderers and `` IRA rats.'' But in the countryside of <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Tyrone </LOCATION>, many residents knew these part-time guerrillas or their families and spoke of them in sympathetic terms. Their deaths helped exacerbate the divisions between local Catholics and the <ORGANIZATION> IRA </ORGANIZATION>'s most frequent targets in rural districts _ the police and the <ORGANIZATION> Ulster </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Regiment </ORGANIZATION>. `` There's a majority of Protestants with nothing wrong with them,'' said a 28-year-old decorator sitting on a grassy bank outside <ORGANIZATION> Dunmoyle </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> on Saturday waiting for <PERSON> Mullin </PERSON>'s hearse to pass `` It's those that join the security forces we ca n't live with,'' he said, glancing at policemen searching mourners at a crossroads at the start of a two-mile trek to <PERSON> Mullin </PERSON>'s family farm outside <PERSON> Sixmilecross </PERSON>. Like the store manager, he spoke on condition of anonymity, fearing retaliation for criticizing the police. `` If you come up this road at 2 or 3 in the morning, and you're stopped by them, you're sure to get a kicking because of who you are,'' he said `` The police force would be welcome, surely, if they were 50-50 -LRB- Catholic-Protestant -RRB- and they were fair.'' The police and army say they ca n't get <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> recruits because the <ORGANIZATION> IRA </ORGANIZATION> would kill them as collaborators. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Gallagher </PERSON>, 53, of <LOCATION> Strabane </LOCATION> in neighboring <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Fermanagh </LOCATION>, said he was a `` political activist'' with two sons serving lengthy prison sentences for <ORGANIZATION> IRA </ORGANIZATION> bombings. `` The British never listen to anything except a gun,'' he said. `` You could n't name three countries the British have not been at war with.'' The mainly <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> IRA </ORGANIZATION> is fighting to end British rule in predominantly <ORGANIZATION> Protestant </ORGANIZATION> <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION> and unite it with the 95 percent <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> <LOCATION> Irish </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Republic </LOCATION>. Like many <ORGANIZATION> IRA </ORGANIZATION> recruits in rural districts alongside the <LOCATION> Irish </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Republic </LOCATION>'s border, the slain men led double lives, their <ORGANIZATION> IRA </ORGANIZATION> activities camouflaged by ordinary civilian pursuits. <PERSON> Brothers </PERSON> <PERSON> Gerard </PERSON> and <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Harte </PERSON>, who were buried Friday in their nearby home village of <LOCATION> Loughmacrory </LOCATION>, were leading players in the local Gaelic football team. <PERSON> Gerard </PERSON> <PERSON> Harte </PERSON>, a 29-year-old architect, designed his own grandiose house overlooking the village. His 21-year-old brother was a carpenter. Both were married, <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Harte </PERSON> to <PERSON> Mullin </PERSON>'s sister, and each had an infant son Police said <PERSON> Gerard </PERSON> <PERSON> Harte </PERSON> was the commander of the <ORGANIZATION> IRA </ORGANIZATION>'s mid-Tyrone unit and that his brother was responsible for selecting <ORGANIZATION> IRA </ORGANIZATION> targets from police and <ORGANIZATION> Ulster </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Regiment </ORGANIZATION> ranks <PERSON> Mullin </PERSON>, whose elder brother <PERSON> Patrick </PERSON> is serving a life sentence for the 1977 <ORGANIZATION> IRA </ORGANIZATION> murder of a bus driver, was questioned after a bomb killed eight British soldiers Aug. 20 in a bus in nearby <LOCATION> Ballygawley </LOCATION>. He was released without charge after five days. News reports said the trio were on their way to kill an off-duty member of the <ORGANIZATION> Ulster </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Regiment </ORGANIZATION> when soldiers ambushed their stolen car. The government says the <ORGANIZATION> IRA </ORGANIZATION> men fired first. At <PERSON> Mullin </PERSON>'s funeral, riot squads massed to block any repetition of the <ORGANIZATION> IRA </ORGANIZATION> gun salutes that have sparked clashes with police at previous burials. The 2,000 mourners inched along narrow country lanes, flanked by long lines of police in helmets, guns and riot shields. They trudged through rain-sodden fields, climbing over ditches and hedges and scattering cows and sheep. When one policeman fell over a barbed-wire fence, the crowd roared approval. Police ringed the church walls during the Mass, sometimes banging batons against shields in what sounded like a tribal beat. Three officers videotaped the crowd, and a helicopter clattered overhead, almost drowning out the graveside prayers. When the service ended, the crowd quickly dispersed. The weather switched from driving rain to warm sunshine, and the tensions from the 3 -LCB- - hour service lifted
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880908-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-08-88 0220EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Nielsens     09-08 0259</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nielsens,0266</SECOND>
<HEAD>NBC Makes It 11 In a Row, But Few Are Watching</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> made it 11 in a row in the weekly <ORGANIZATION> A.C. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nielsen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> ratings, but as summer reruns dragged into September, not that many people were watching. Reruns of <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Full House'' and <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>' `` Designing Women'' turned up in the top 10, but they were behind five <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> comedies. `` Full House'' is being broadcast two nights a week. A Tuesday episode came in sixth, but the episode on Friday, the regular time period, was 40th. The top 10 shows last week were: <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` A Different World,'' `` Cheers,'' `` The Cosby Show,'' `` Night Court'' and `` Golden Girls,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Full House,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` <LOCATION> L.A. </LOCATION> Law,'' and `` Amen''; and a tie between <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>' `` Blood and Orchids, Part Two'' and `` Designing Women'' and <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Who's the Boss?'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> finished the week with an average, prime-time rating of 11.6; CBS 10.8; and <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> 9.3. The network averages for the season that began 50 weeks ago are: <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> 14.5, <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> 12.3 and <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> 12.1. The three-network share of the total viewing audience was 60, up somewhat from the the previous week's 56. The all-time low, set this summer, was 47. The rating is a percentage of the nation's 88.6 million homes with televisions. The share is a percentage of sets in use. The `` CBS Evening News'' regained the lead in the news race with an average rating of 9.8 and a 21 share. `` ABC World News Tonight'' had a 9.4 and 20; `` NBC Nightly News'' an 8.8 and 19.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880908-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-08-88 0225EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-NielsensList     09-08 0687</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nielsens List,0764</SECOND>
<HEAD>List of Week's Top-Rated TV Shows</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Nielsens</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the prime-time television ratings as compiled by the <ORGANIZATION> A.C. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nielsen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> for the week of Aug. 29-Sept. 4 Top 20 listings include the week's ranking, with full season-to-date ranking in parentheses, rating for the week, and total homes. An `` X'' in parentheses denotes one-time-only presentation. A rating measures the percentage of the nation's 88.6 million TV homes. 1. -LRB- 2 -RRB- `` A Different World,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 19.2 rating, 17.0 million homes. 2. -LRB- 3 -RRB- `` Cheers,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 19.0, 16.8 million homes. 3. -LRB- 1 -RRB- `` The Cosby Show,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 18.5, 16.3 million homes. 4. -LRB- 5 -RRB- `` Night Court,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 18.2, 16.1 million homes. 5. -LRB- 4 -RRB- `` Golden Girls,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 17.0, 15.0 million homes. 6. -LRB- 37 -RRB- `` Full House-Tuesday,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 15.6, 13.8 million homes. 7. -LRB- 13 -RRB- `` <LOCATION> L.A. </LOCATION> Law,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 15.3, 13.5 million homes. 8. -LRB- 18 -RRB- `` Amen,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 15.2, 13.4 million homes. 9. -LRB- 60 -RRB- `` Blood & amp; Orchids, Part 2,'' - `` CBS Tuesday Movie,'' 14.8, 13.1 million homes. 9. -LRB- 36 -RRB- `` Designing Women,'' CBS, 14.8, 13.1 million homes. 9. -LRB- 8 -RRB- `` Who's the Boss,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 14.8, 13.1 million homes. 12. -LRB- 15 -RRB- `` ALF,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 14.7, 13.0 million homes. 13. -LRB- 22 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Matlock </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 14.4, 12.7 million homes. 14. -LRB- 24 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Hunter </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 14.1, 12.4 million homes. 14. -LRB- 9 -RRB- `` Murder, She Wrote,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 14.1, 12.4 million homes. 16. -LRB- 45 -RRB- `` Kate & amp; <PERSON> Allie </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 13.8, 12.2 million homes. 17. -LRB- 7 -RRB- `` 60 Minutes,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 13.6, 12.0 million homes. 18. -LRB- 19 -RRB- `` Higher Ground,'' - `` CBS Sunday Movie,'' 13.3, 11.7 million homes. 19. -LRB- 49 -RRB- `` Desperado,'' - `` NBC Movie of the Week-Wed.,'' 13.1, 11.6 million homes 20. -LRB- X -RRB- `` NFL Game 2,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.0, 11.5 million homes. 20. -LRB- 24 -RRB- `` Head of the Class,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.0, 11.5 million homes. 22. -LRB- 10 -RRB- `` Growing Pains,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.8. 23. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Tank,'' - `` CBS Special Movie Presentation-Thur.,'' 12.7 24. -LRB- 28 -RRB- `` Heat of the Night,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.4. 25. -LRB- 27 -RRB- `` 227,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.3. 26. -LRB- 53 -RRB- `` 20-20,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.2. 27. -LRB- 44 -RRB- `` Magnum, P.I.,'' CBS, 12.0. 28. -LRB- 38 -RRB- `` Hooperman,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.3. 29. -LRB- 21 -RRB- `` Fandango,'' - `` NBC Monday Night Movies,'' 10.9. 29. -LRB- 72 -RRB- `` Mr. <PERSON> Belvedere </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 10.9. 31. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Life on the Flipside,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 10.8. 31. -LRB- 65 -RRB- `` Wiseguy,'' CBS, 10.8. 33. -LRB- 31 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Newhart </PERSON>,'' CBS, 10.7. 34. -LRB- 107 -RRB- `` Cavanaughs,'' CBS, 10.6. 34. -LRB- X -RRB- `` A Report on Foster Care,'' - `` ABC News Closeup,'' 10.6. 36. -LRB- 64 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Jake </PERSON> and The Fatman,'' CBS, 10.5. 37. -LRB- 55 -RRB- `` The Equalizer,'' CBS, 10.4. 38. -LRB- x -RRB- `` Badlands: 2005,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 10.3. 39. -LRB- 26 -RRB- `` Moonlighting,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 10.2. 40. -LRB- 60 -RRB- `` Full House,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 10.1. 41. -LRB- 45 -RRB- `` Facts of Life,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 9.9. 42. -LRB- 56 -RRB- `` <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION>,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 9.4. 43. -LRB- X -RRB- `` The Journey of <PERSON> Natty </PERSON> <PERSON> Gann </PERSON>,'' - `` ABC Movie Special-Sat.,'' 9.2 44. -LRB- 92 -RRB- `` Kung Fu: The Movie,'' - `` CBS Friday Movie,'' 9.1. 45. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Second Start,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 9.0. 46. -LRB- 43 -RRB- `` Poltergeist,'' - `` ABC Sunday Night Movie,'' 8.8. 46. -LRB- 67 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Slap </PERSON> <PERSON> Maxwell </PERSON>,'' CBS, 8.8. 48. -LRB- 101 -RRB- `` 48 Hours on <LOCATION> Runway </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Street </LOCATION>,'' CBS, 8.7. 49. -LRB- 29 -RRB- `` The Right Stuff, Part 2,'' - `` <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> Monday Night Movie,'' 8.5. 50. -LRB- 95 -RRB- `` Summer Showcase,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 8.4. 50. -LRB- 40 -RRB- `` Perfect Strangers,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 8.4. 52. -LRB- 49 -RRB- `` <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> Vice,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 8.3. 52. -LRB- 69 -RRB- `` Beauty and the <LOCATION> Beast </LOCATION>,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 8.3. 54. -LRB- 23 -RRB- `` The Man Who Was n't There,'' - `` NBC Sunday Night Movie,'' 8.0. 55. -LRB- 106 -RRB- `` TV Bloopers and Practical Jokes,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 7.9. 55. -LRB- 120 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Blacke </PERSON>'s Magic,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 7.9. 57. -LRB- 98 -RRB- `` Funny People,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 7.8. 58. -LRB- 71 -RRB- `` Macgyver,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 7.7. 59. -LRB- 14 -RRB- `` My Two Dads,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 7.6. 60. -LRB- 116 -RRB- `` <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Football </ORGANIZATION>,'' - `` <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> State vs. <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION>,'' 7.4. 61. -LRB- X -RRB- `` A Whole Lotta Fun,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 7.3. 62. -LRB- 78 -RRB- `` Spenser: For Hire,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 7.2. 63. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s Most Wanted,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 7.0. 64. -LRB- 95 -RRB- `` Disney Sunday Movie, `` - `` Not Quite Human, Part 1,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 6.9. 64. -LRB- 34 -RRB- `` Family Ties,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 6.7. 66. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Half and Half,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 6.6. 67. -LRB- 95 -RRB- `` Deadline,'' - `` ABC Thursday Night Movie,'' 6.4. 68. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` Married ... With Children,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 5.9. 69. -LRB- 123 -RRB- `` CBS Summer Playhouse: Further Adventures,'' 5.6. 70. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` 21 Jump Street,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 4.4. 71. -LRB- 127 -RRB- `` First Impressions,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 4.3. 72. -LRB- 78 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Frank </PERSON>'s Place,'' CBS, 4.1. 73. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` <PERSON> Garry </PERSON> <PERSON> Shandling </PERSON> Show,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 3.7. 74. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` Reporters,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 3.6. 75. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` <PERSON> Tracey </PERSON> <PERSON> Ullman </PERSON> Show,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 3.5. 76. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` Duet,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 3.0. 77. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` <PERSON> Suzi </PERSON>'s Story,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 1.9.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880908-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-08-88 0020EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-NorthKorea-40Years Bjt   09-08 0883</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-North Korea-40 Years, Bjt,0907</SECOND>
<HEAD>North Korea Marks 40th Anniversary In Troubled Year</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TERRIL JONES</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Four decades after its founding, <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> remains an isolated, secretive state with an enigmatic leader who shows no signs of handing over power to his designated heir _ his son. The Democratic People's Republic of <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> celebrates its 40th anniversary Friday with praise for President <PERSON> Kim </PERSON> <PERSON> Il </PERSON> <PERSON> Sung </PERSON>, 76, the communist strongman. The country plans a huge celebration, with senior foreign emissaries including President <PERSON> Yang </PERSON> <PERSON> Shangkun </PERSON> of <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> and Soviet <ORGANIZATION> KGB </ORGANIZATION> chief <PERSON> Viktor </PERSON> <PERSON> Chebrikov </PERSON> representing <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>'s two major allies. No political figures or journalists from the West have been invited, and requests from Western news agencies to cover the anniversary have gone unanswered. <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> rarely allows <LOCATION> Western </LOCATION> journalists into the country. The ceremonies Friday will include a mass rally, a sports competition and cultural performances in praise of <PERSON> Kim </PERSON>. `` Koreans respect <PERSON> Kim </PERSON> <PERSON> Il </PERSON> <PERSON> Sung </PERSON> as a prominent leader in anti-Japanese warfare and hero of the Korean revolution,'' said <PERSON> Choe </PERSON> <PERSON> Kwan </PERSON> <PERSON> Ick </PERSON>, an official of the pro-North <ORGANIZATION> Korean </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Korean </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Residents </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Japan </ORGANIZATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Chongryon </LOCATION> -RRB-. `` He goes to every corner of the country, among farmers and workers, to solve problems they face. The people respect this, and that is why he has remained in power so long.'' A 1986 <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> report called <PERSON> Kim </PERSON> `` the object of an intensive and far-reaching personality cult, probably unequalled in the rest of today's world.'' Huge statues of the Great Leader, as <PERSON> Kim </PERSON> is known, stand throughout the country and almost all <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Koreans </LOCATION> wear badges with his picture. Similar public loyalty to <PERSON> Kim </PERSON>'s son <PERSON> Kim </PERSON> <PERSON> Jong </PERSON> <PERSON> Il </PERSON>, 46, is encouraged. The elder <PERSON> Kim </PERSON> plans to hand power over to his son in what may be the world's first communist dynasty. It has been a troubling year for <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>. World attention has focused on rival <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> and on the upcoming Olympic Games, which begin in <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION> Sept. 17. <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> has stressed security preparations against a possible terrorist attack from the north. <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> finally stated this week that it would not use military or other means to interrupt the Olympics. `` As for ` terrorism,' it is utterly alien to us and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> itself is the chieftain of state terrorism as already exposed to the world,'' the <ORGANIZATION> North </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Korean </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> said. Tension remains high along the Demilitarized Zone with <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>'s deployment of Soviet-made missiles and jet fighters, including MiG-23s and MiG-29s. The North has an estimated 850,000 troops _ the world's fifth largest army _ against 650,000 <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korean </LOCATION> and 42,000 American soldiers. <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> failed in its attempt to share in the glory of the Olympics, and is now watching allies <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Yugoslavia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> and probably <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> establish trade relations with <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION>. Eclipsed by <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> in industry and foreign trade, the country faces two formidable tasks: ensuring a smooth transfer of power and modernizing its economy. The country has a foreign debt of about $ 4.2 billion against foreign trade of only $ 3.5 billion annually, according to Western estimates. Last year, <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> was declared in default on its foreign loans. Trade is modest, amounting to only $ 1.7 billion annually with the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>'s largest trading partner and main economic benefactor. `` They -LRB- <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> -RRB- import machinery and vehicles, but lack parts and skill and ca n't get them repaired,'' a Japanese intelligence official said. To earn badly needed foreign currency, <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> is on a building spree of luxury hotels and sports and cultural facilities, but `` they're building everything literally by hand, with shovels and wheelbarrows,'' the official said. `` It reminds me of <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> in the 1950s,'' said <PERSON> Masaru </PERSON> <PERSON> Nishida </PERSON>, a literature professor at <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Hosei </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> who has visited the country three times. Strapped for cash, <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> has been shifting some of the 20 percent of its GNP currently spent on the military to joint ventures with the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, according to the Japanese official. The products include household goods, clothing, shoes and are sold in <LOCATION> Siberia </LOCATION>. `` <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> wants to cut down military expenditures because they're a waste of money,'' said <PERSON> Choe </PERSON>. Authorities have demobilized 200,000 soldiers in the last two years and shifted them to economic reconstruction, he said. How to solidify the political position of <PERSON> Kim </PERSON>'s son is a more delicate issue. Little is known about <PERSON> Kim </PERSON> <PERSON> Jong </PERSON> <PERSON> Il </PERSON>, but he clearly lacks the charisma of his father, the Japanese official said. <PERSON> Kim </PERSON> <PERSON> Pyong </PERSON> <PERSON> Il </PERSON>, 34, <PERSON> Kim </PERSON> <PERSON> Jong </PERSON> <PERSON> Il </PERSON>'s half-brother, has been posted as ambassador to <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> in an apparent move to avoid a challenge to <PERSON> Kim </PERSON> <PERSON> Jong </PERSON> <PERSON> Il </PERSON>, the official said. A major question is when <PERSON> Kim </PERSON> <PERSON> Il </PERSON> <PERSON> Sung </PERSON> will abdicate in favor of his son _ or be forced to for health reasons. During a visit to <LOCATION> Mongolia </LOCATION> in July, he had difficulty climbing slopes and once abandoned an attempt to enter a pavillion because he could not negotiate the stairs, the Japanese official said. `` <PERSON> Kim </PERSON> <PERSON> Il </PERSON> <PERSON> Sung </PERSON> wants quickly to give reins to his son,'' the official said. `` But the domestic situation does n't allow that right now.'' He said <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> had been pressuring <PERSON> Kim </PERSON> not to put his son in power yet because they do not have complete confidence in him.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880908-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-08-88 0157EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-JonesClub     09-08 0596</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Jones Club,0617</SECOND>
<HEAD>`Barnaby Jones' Club Thrives, To Delight Of Buddy Ebsen</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By LARRY NEUMEISTER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Do n't try to tell <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Camerada </PERSON> about <PERSON> Madonna </PERSON>, <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Selleck </PERSON> or <PERSON> Elvis </PERSON>. He's got his own idol: <PERSON> Barnaby </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>. `` I just like his easygoing style,'' <PERSON> Camerada </PERSON> says. Camerada is not alone. He is one of more than 800 members of the <PERSON> Barnaby </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> <PERSON> Fan </PERSON> <PERSON> Club </PERSON>, dedicated to the memory of the venerable detective who ambled across the nation's television screens from 1973 to 1980, and in countless reruns. Unlike most fan clubs, the members of this one actually get to meet their idol regularly. <PERSON> Buddy </PERSON> <PERSON> Ebsen </PERSON>, who played <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>, is a frequent guest at the club's weekly meetings at a restaurant off Times Square. `` It's a cult now,'' says <PERSON> Ebsen </PERSON>, 80. `` I love them. They're great guys. The great guys are mostly retired executives, men of <PERSON> Ebsen </PERSON>'s own generation. They include former President <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON>, a fan of the show who joined the club at <LOCATION> Ebsen </LOCATION>'s suggestion. This fan club collects no dues, sells nothing, follows no rules and only loosely organizes an occasional golf outing. `` It is instantaneous. You walk in and you're a member,'' said member <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Desimone </PERSON>, 57. `` It really was a sincere, grass-roots germination,'' <PERSON> Ebsen </PERSON> said. President <PERSON> Alfred </PERSON> <PERSON> Lamberti </PERSON> said the club started some years ago when a retired <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> colonel was hospitalized for an operation. Each day, the patient watched <PERSON> Barnaby </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> reruns, and soon he and his visitors were hooked. Thereafter, they met for lunch or drinks each week. They would send <PERSON> Ebsen </PERSON> birthday cards each year. His curiosity was piqued, and one day he dropped in to La Vert-Galant, official meeting place of the <ORGANIZATION> BJFC </ORGANIZATION>. Now, whenever he's in town, <LOCATION> Ebsen </LOCATION> is a regular. And when he shows up, the bartender whips up an alcoholic drink that looks like the favored drink of the club's favorite detective _ a glass of milk. The meetings are not like Trekkie conventions _ there are no trivia contests, with questions of what color tie <PERSON> Barnaby </PERSON> wore in episode 33; there is no swap meet of <PERSON> Barnaby </PERSON> memorabilia. Mostly, the guys talk about sex, fights, baseball and dirty jokes. `` It's like a family,'' said <PERSON> Gordon </PERSON> <PERSON> McKay </PERSON>, 60. The club has attracted Ebsen lookalikes and a Scottish man who, like <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>, drank only milk. There are members in <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>. Then there was the visit from <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON>. <PERSON> Ebsen </PERSON>, who is on the board of directors of <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON>'s library, said he recruited <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> into the club when <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> asked him why the <PERSON> Barnaby </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> private detective show was taken off the air in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> and how he could help get it back on. Now, said <PERSON> Ebsen </PERSON>, `` He's a card-carrying member.'' When <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> stopped by, more than 40 members gathered at the restaurant and listened to plenty of behind-the-scenes stuff, as <PERSON> Lamberti </PERSON> recalls. `` He was going to stay a half hour but he stayed two hours,'' he said. `` He told us things about <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> that I ca n't tell you. He said of all the clubs he ever went to this was the greatest because there was no ulterior motive.'' <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> also figured in another big moment in club history _ the time members rented a yacht and followed <PERSON> Ebsen </PERSON> in a race around <LOCATION> Staten </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION>. `` I had a <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> mask on,'' <PERSON> Lamberti </PERSON> said, with a chuckle. <PERSON> Ebsen </PERSON> said he recalls racing in the Liberty Regatta. There, tagging along behind him, was a yacht bearing a large banner. `` Go Barnaby,'' the sign said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880908-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-08-88 0158EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-NobelCandidates     09-08 0286</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nobel Candidates,0294</SECOND>
<HEAD>Ninety-Seven Candidates For Nobel Peace Prize</HEAD>
<DATELINE>OSLO, Norway (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Norwegian <ORGANIZATION> Nobel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> says it will choose this year's Nobel Peace Prize laureate from 97 candidates, including 74 people and 23 organizations. President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and Soviet leader <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> reportedly are in the running for their agreement to dismantle intermediate range nuclear missiles. <PERSON> Jakob </PERSON> <PERSON> Sverdrup </PERSON>, secretary of the five-member committee, said Wednesday that the winner will be announced Sept. 29 by chairman <PERSON> Egil </PERSON> <PERSON> Aarvik </PERSON>. The number of approved candidates is close to the all-time record of 100. Last year, President <PERSON> Oscar </PERSON> <PERSON> Arias </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Costa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rica </LOCATION> was chosen from among 93 candidates for his Central American peace plan. The committee refuses to confirm the names of candidates. Nominations for the 1988 prize closed on Feb. 1 Speculation has focused on <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION>' General Secretary <PERSON> Javier </PERSON> <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Cuellar </PERSON>, who reportedly was nominated for the 1989 prize by Foreign Minister <PERSON> Hans-Dietrich </PERSON> <PERSON> Genscher </PERSON> of <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> for his efforts to end the Iran-Iraq and <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> wars. A Norwegian member of parliament has said he has proposed President <PERSON> Cory </PERSON> <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON> for her efforts for a peaceful tranisition in the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION>. Prime Minister <PERSON> Gro </PERSON> <PERSON> Harlem </PERSON> <PERSON> Brundtland </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Norway </LOCATION> reportedly was nominated for her U.N.-appointed work on drafting a program for environment and development. Other unconfirmed nominations were jailed black anti-apartheid leader <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON> <PERSON> Mandela </PERSON> of <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>, and Indian Prime Minister <PERSON> Rajiv </PERSON> <PERSON> Gandhi </PERSON>. Members of <LOCATION> Finland </LOCATION>'s parliament reportedly have nominated the <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> -LRB- WHO -RRB- celebrating its 40th anniversary this year, and Swedish parliamentarians proposed the Rev. <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Ingle </PERSON> of the Nashville-based <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coalition </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> on </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Jails </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Prisons </ORGANIZATION>, who campaigns against the death penalty. This prize is worth about $ 385,000, up 15 percent from last year.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880908-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-08-88 0235EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-MurderousRelic     09-08 0231</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Murderous Relic,0237</SECOND>
<HEAD>Case Made of Murderer's Skin Sold At Auction</HEAD>
<DATELINE>KNOWLE, England (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A visiting-card case made from the skin of executed 19th century mass murderer <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Burke </PERSON> was bought at auction for $ 1,785 by a man whose business takes tourists to the scenes of notorious crimes. `` The price was much more than <PERSON> Burke </PERSON> and <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Hare </PERSON>, his accomplice, received for all the bodies of their victims, which they sold to anatomists,'' said <PERSON> Robin </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON>, who bought the relic in a sale at <LOCATION> Knowle </LOCATION> in central <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Burke </PERSON> and <PERSON> Hare </PERSON>, who began as grave-robbers, went on to murder at least 15 people in <LOCATION> Edinburgh </LOCATION> in 1827 and 1828, a time when medical professors could not get enough bodies for demonstrations to their students. <PERSON> Burke </PERSON> was hanged in 1829 on the evidence of <LOCATION> Hare </LOCATION>, who fled the city and disappeared. <PERSON> Burke </PERSON>'s body was flayed after dissection by <LOCATION> Edinburgh </LOCATION>'s medical authorities and part of his skin was used by one of those surgeons to make the ornate case with gold tooling which passed to his descendant _ who sold it Wednesday. A notebook covered in <PERSON> Burke </PERSON>'s skin is still in the possession of <LOCATION> Edinburgh </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Royal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Surgeons </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON> is a partner in an <LOCATION> Edinburgh </LOCATION> guide business, which takes tourists to the scenes of notorious crimes. `` We will be showing the case to our clients on the tours,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880908-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-08-88 0235EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--France-ChinaRadio     09-08 0151</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--France-China Radio,0152</SECOND>
<HEAD>Radio Accord Reached Between Paris and Beijing</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PARIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> have signed an accord for the joint production of some radio programs and the cooperation between radio correspondents in the two countries, French radio reported. The accord was signed Wednesday by <PERSON> Roland </PERSON> <PERSON> Faure </PERSON>, president of <ORGANIZATION> Radio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> France </ORGANIZATION>, and <PERSON> Yang </PERSON> <PERSON> Zhengquan </PERSON>, director general of <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Popular </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Radio </ORGANIZATION> Under the agreement, the two radio networks will co-produce an anthology of traditional Chinese music and other programs. Radio reporters will receive technical assistance in the country they are covering and radio trainees will be exchanged, the radio reported. The report said the exchange was timed to allow <LOCATION> French </LOCATION> radio to carry reports on the 40th anniversary of the founding of Communist <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> and for <ORGANIZATION> Chinese </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> radio </ORGANIZATION> to broadcast reports on the celebration of the bicentennial of the French Revolution, events that will take place next year.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880908-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-08-88 0146EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lites     09-08 0393</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lites,0409</SECOND>
<HEAD>On The Light Side</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LARKSPUR, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Quiba, <PERSON> Jamal </PERSON>, <PERSON> Zubag </PERSON>, <PERSON> Kubla </PERSON> <PERSON> Khan </PERSON> and six pals give new meaning to the expression `` dog's life.'' Every canine should be as lucky as the 10 silky <PERSON> Salukis </PERSON> who share a posh <LOCATION> Marin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> doghouse with color television, art gallery and raised beds with white fur blankets. `` I just thoroughly love them,'' <PERSON> Sandra </PERSON> <PERSON> Wornum </PERSON> said Wednesday of her pampered purebreds. <PERSON> Wornum </PERSON> built the $ 15,000 enclosed kennels partly to appease neighbors, who complain about noise and worry about property values, but also out of devotion to her thin, elegant hounds, believed to be the world's oldest breed. The carpeted dog home designed by <PERSON> Wornum </PERSON>'s architect husband, <PERSON> Michael </PERSON>, also features four redwood-and-glass bedrooms and a bathroom with a Moroccan tile shower and claw-footed bathtub. Salukis, which resemble greyhounds, were developed in the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> as early as 4000 B.C. for hunting gazelles. <PERSON> Wornum </PERSON>, like other lovers of the breed, say their animals are delightfully different from other dogs. `` Their demeanor is much more like a cat,'' she said. `` They are reserved, quiet, intense. They like to sit up high and observe. They are not ground sleepers.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>PITTSBURGH (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A baggage handler may keep the $ 10,000 he found at <LOCATION> Greater </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION> <LOCATION> International </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION>, authorities say. But his wife says she still feels bad for whoever lost the cash. `` We had kind of hoped the guy who lost it would have gotten it,'' said <PERSON> Gloria </PERSON> <PERSON> Shergi </PERSON>. <LOCATION> Allegheny </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> Deputy Solicitor <PERSON> Ira </PERSON> <PERSON> Weiss </PERSON> said Wednesday that <PERSON> Patrick </PERSON> <PERSON> Shergi </PERSON> may keep the cash because the owner has n't turned up. `` To date, no one has satisfactorily established that he or she is the owner of the property,'' <PERSON> Weiss </PERSON> wrote. The law states that `` reasonable time'' must elapse before a finder may claim the goods. <PERSON> Weiss </PERSON> said a month is sufficient. Shergi found the hundred $ 100 bills Aug 3 in a bag beside a curb. Publicity about the discovery brought claims of ownership from more than a dozen people who telephoned police, but none was able to provide convincing evidence. Mrs. <PERSON> Shergi </PERSON> said her husband never thought twice about turning the money over to authorities. `` He is probably one of the most honest people I've ever met,'' she said. `` He never would have been able to sleep, worrying about whether someone had lost the money and really needed it.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880908-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-08-88 0200EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-People-Taylor     09-08 0126</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-People-Taylor,0130</SECOND>
<HEAD>Liz Cancels Tour On Doctor's Order</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 On her doctor's orders, <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON> is canceling an international tour promoting a new line of bath products, a spokesman said. A publicist for Miss <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON> on Wednesday quoted Dr. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Skinner </PERSON> as saying the actress needs six to eight more weeks of therapy to recuperate from a fractured vertebra in her lower back. Miss <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON> was hospitalized for treatment of the fracture from July 25 to Aug. 17. Miss <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON> had been scheduled to appear at stores in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION> to promote her line of bath products, `` <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON>'s Passion Body Riches.'' She also was to have gone to stores in <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880908-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-08-88 0154EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-TVA-Nuclear     09-08 0403</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-TVA-Nuclear,0415</SECOND>
<HEAD>TVA Names Successor To Nuclear Chief White</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAN GEORGE</BYLINE>
<HEAD>Associated Press Writer</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CHATTANOOGA, Tenn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> <PERSON> Kingsley </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, a retired <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> man with more than 20 years experience in nuclear energy, was hired Wednesday to succeed <PERSON> Steven </PERSON> <PERSON> A </PERSON>. White as head of the <ORGANIZATION> Tennessee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Valley </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Authority </ORGANIZATION>'s nuclear program. White, 59, has run <ORGANIZATION> TVA </ORGANIZATION>'s nuclear program since January 1986, five months after the federal utility shut down its five-reactor system because of safety and management concerns. Since then, Unit 2 at <ORGANIZATION> Sequoyah </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nuclear </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Plant </ORGANIZATION> outside <LOCATION> Chattanooga </LOCATION> has returned to operation and Unit 1 is scheduled for restart later this month. <ORGANIZATION> Browns </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ferry </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Unit </ORGANIZATION> 2 is expected to be back on line by next spring. <PERSON> Kingsley </PERSON>, vice president of nuclear operations for <ORGANIZATION> Systems </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Resources </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, in <LOCATION> Jackson </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Miss. </LOCATION>, will join <ORGANIZATION> TVA </ORGANIZATION> on Oct. 1 and assume command of the nuclear program a month later. <ORGANIZATION> TVA </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Marvin </PERSON> <PERSON> Runyon </PERSON> revealed <PERSON> Kingsley </PERSON>'s appointment and <PERSON> White </PERSON>'s resignation during a TVA board meeting in <LOCATION> Tupelo </LOCATION>, Miss. `` <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> White </PERSON> has done an excellent job of starting the <ORGANIZATION> TVA </ORGANIZATION> nuclear program on its way to complete recovery,'' <PERSON> Runyon </PERSON> said in a statement released in <LOCATION> Chattanooga </LOCATION>. `` His assignment is essentially complete and he has stated several times that he wants to return home to his farm in <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> TVA </ORGANIZATION> appreciates the work he has done in making our nuclear program safer,'' <PERSON> Runyon </PERSON> said. White indicated in recent weeks that he would probably leave the $ 355,200-a-year job in January 1989 when his contract expires to be with his family in <LOCATION> Charlottsville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va </LOCATION>. The retired admiral who once headed the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>'s nuclear submarine program has also been under fire from congressional staffers critical of <ORGANIZATION> TVA </ORGANIZATION>'s nuclear program. The <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> is still investigating claims by the <ORGANIZATION> Nuclear </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Regulatory </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> that White lied in March 1986 when he told the <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION> that <ORGANIZATION> TVA </ORGANIZATION>'s unlicensed Watts Bar Nuclear Plant near <LOCATION> Spring </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Tenn. </LOCATION>, met certain safety standards. White has denied the charges, and <PERSON> Gerald </PERSON> <PERSON> Charnoff </PERSON>, an attorney for <ORGANIZATION> TVA </ORGANIZATION>, said he expects the investigation to be dismissed soon. Like White, <PERSON> Kingsley </PERSON> is an ex-Navy officer, retiring in 1971 to join <ORGANIZATION> Alabama </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Power </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> as senior engineer in nuclear production. Unlike him, he will be paid as a <ORGANIZATION> TVA </ORGANIZATION> employee, not a contractor, and his $ 77,200 salary will be governed by a federal pay cap. He also will receive a $ 100,000 cash relocation incentive and $ 40,000 in retirement benefits.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880908-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-08-88 0146EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Abrahamson-StarWars     09-08 0201</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Abrahamson-Star Wars,0206</SECOND>
<HEAD>General Proposes Changes In `Star Wars' System, Lower Cost</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> officer who heads the nation's anti-missile program says tens of billions of dollars could be cut from the program to develop a `` Star Wars'' system Lt. Gen. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Abrahamson </PERSON> says in an interview in today's <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> that the design of the weapons to be used in the system can be simplified and that the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration's deployment date of the late 1990s still could be met. He said the savings can be made by changing the design of a few major components, including the space-based anti-missile rockets that would be the most expensive element of the program. `` We're not trying to restructure the program,'' <PERSON> Abrahamson </PERSON> stressed. He said his proposal was developed over the last several months at the request of <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Carlucci </PERSON> and will be presented to top <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> officials in about two weeks. The <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> told <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> last year that development of the first phase of the Strategic Defense Initiative would cost between $ 75 billion and $ 150 billion. Estimates of the long-term cost of the program have ranged as high as $ 1 trillion.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880908-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-08-88 0201EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-BillieBoggs     09-08 0205</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Billie Boggs,0210</SECOND>
<HEAD>Joyce Brown Charged with Possession of Small Amount of Heroin</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A woman who successfully fought the city's attempt to confine her for mental illness has been arrested and charged with possessing $ 40 worth of heroin and two hypodermic needles, police said <PERSON> Joyce </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>, who also has used the name <PERSON> Billie </PERSON> <PERSON> Boggs </PERSON>, was arrested on the street Wednesday evening, shortly after she was discharged from a hospital, authorities said. She was charged with criminal possession of a controlled substance, a misdemeanor because of the amount of heroin recovered, and issued a desk appearance ticket to return to court Sept. 28, said Officer <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Donnell </PERSON>, a police spokesman. Ms. <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>, 40, was admitted to <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Clare </LOCATION><LOCATION> 's </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION> on Aug. 29, but neither the hospital nor her lawyers would say what was wrong with her. She was discharged Wednesday, said <PERSON> Rose </PERSON> <PERSON> Viera </PERSON>, a nursing supervisor. Ms. <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> was the first person picked up last fall under Mayor <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> I. </PERSON> <PERSON> Koch </PERSON>'s plan to hospitalize some of the mentally ill homeless. She was released when a judge ruled that city doctors, who contended she was psychotic, could not force her to take medication for the condition. She later moved into a hotel.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880908-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-08-88 0040EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-ForestFiresRdp 3rdLd-Writethru a0804 09-08 1085</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Forest Fires Rdp, 3rd Ld-Writethru, a0804,1113</SECOND>
<HEAD>Old Faithful Complex Evacuated for First Time in Yellowstone's
History</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Leads with 12 grafs to UPDATE with 17 buildings destroyed,
details; officials hopeful that threat is ended; background on inn;
quote from visitor; windy weather forecast; picks up 13th graf:
`The National ...</NOTE>
<HEAD>LaserPhotos XYS1, CKCX5-6</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LEN IWANSKI</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>YELLOWSTONE NATIONAL PARK, Wyo. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Windblown embers from a 165,000-acre forest fire ignited rooftops Wednesday inside the Old Faithful Geyser complex of Yellowstone National Park, after hundreds of tourists evacuated the area. At least 17 buildings were destroyed as the big North Fork fire moved into the outskirts of the complex Wednesday afternoon when 40-mph winds shifted, creating a wall of flame that forced 40 firefighters to retreat from the lines. `` When that firestorm went through there, we had to move our people out of there,'' said <PERSON> Denny </PERSON> <PERSON> Bungarz </PERSON>, fire incident commander. `` When you can feel the heat inside your car, it's time to move.'' Embers rained down on firefighters who wetted roofs inside the complex and activated a sprinkler atop the historic Old Faithful Inn to protect the 84-year-old log building, a national historic landmark since 1987. Two cabins in the employee housing area were destroyed by the wall of flame and winds gusting to 50 mph showered sparks into the complex, igniting the roofs of 14 other guest cabins and a utility shed, <PERSON> Bungarz </PERSON> said. As winds died down late Wednesday night, authorities began to hope that the fire threat near the park's most popular attraction again was over. `` I would consider it over,'' <PERSON> Bungarz </PERSON> said. `` The main fire front passed through here. It really fireproofed this area.'' Wednesday's evacuation of the geyser complex was the first in the 116-year history of the oldest <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> national park, ordered as the fire burned to within a half-mile of the park's most popular attraction. About 800 visitors calmly left the 320-room inn, which park officials decided to close for the season more than a month early. Later, however, park officials decided to allow day visitors in the area. Inside the complex, firefighters hosed down buildings to protect them from flames as a handful of tourists sightseeing when the flames erupted, were held in the area until fire activity slowed. `` It's the safest place to be in spite of what it feels like,'' <PERSON> Bungarz </PERSON> said. `` I've been coming up here a long time,'' said <PERSON> Ken </PERSON> <PERSON> Miller </PERSON>, a visitor from <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION>. `` Thank God I've got a lot of pictures of the way the park was, because I'll never see it like that again.'' <PERSON> Bungarz </PERSON> said he expected winds to subside by midnight and weather to remain calm Thursday and Friday, but he added forecasts called for a return of high winds by the weekend. The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Weather </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> said a storm front could bring significant precipitation to <LOCATION> Yellowstone </LOCATION> by Sunday or Monday. Forecaster <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Oard </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Great </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Falls </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mont. </LOCATION>, said the storm was `` looking more likely all the time.'' In <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Sens. <PERSON> Malcolm </PERSON> <PERSON> Wallop </PERSON> and <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Simpson </PERSON> asked <ORGANIZATION> Interior </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Hodel </PERSON> to declare their state a disaster area, eligible for relief because of the forest blazes in and around <LOCATION> Yellowstone </LOCATION>. The two Republicans also called for the resignation of <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Park </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> Director <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Penn </PERSON> <PERSON> Mott </PERSON> for his service's policy of letting naturally-sparked fires burn unless they threaten manmade structures or people. However, in the last month <LOCATION> Yellowstone </LOCATION> officials have tried to suppress all new fires, whether caused by man or nature, but unusually dry conditions and gusting winds thwarted efforts by thousands of firefighters. Fires in the <LOCATION> Greater </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Yellowstone </LOCATION> area, which includes nearby national parks in <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION>, have charred close to 1 million acres, park spokeswoman <PERSON> Marsha </PERSON> <PERSON> Karle </PERSON> said. On Yellowstone's northern border, a river of fire flowed within feet of two small tourist towns, and firefighters hoped winds would continue to shepherd the Storm Creek fire past <LOCATION> Cooke </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> and Silver Gate, <PERSON> Mont </PERSON>. Nearly 550 firefighters and a fleet of bulldozers were moved to the <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Park </LOCATION> area, across the state line in <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION>, to keep the North Fork fire from spreading there. Forest fires also burned in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION>. Officials expected winds of 30 to 40 mph from midday to midnight, he said. <PERSON> Bungarz </PERSON> said the 13 fires in the <LOCATION> Greater </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Yellowstone </LOCATION> area had advanced a total of about 80,000 acres on Tuesday. The fires burning in the park, which has a total of 2.2 million acres, are the worst by far in the park's history. In no year has the acreage consumed by fire exceeded 30,000 acres, park naturalists say. Elsewhere in the Greater Yellowstone complex: _ The 260,000-acre Clover Mist fire made a 10-mile run toward the east entrance of <LOCATION> Yellowstone </LOCATION>. Fire information officer <PERSON> Dave </PERSON> <PERSON> Damron </PERSON> said the fire grew 20,000 acres Tuesday night and endangered the Pahashka Tepee, which was <PERSON> Buffalo </PERSON> <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Cody </PERSON>'s original hunting lodge. The east and northeast gates to the park were both closed Wednesday. Two fires in <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION> have cut off access to the roads leading to the northeast entrance. _ The 224,600 Mink fire, 15 miles northeast of Moran Junction in the <LOCATION> Teton </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Wilderness </LOCATION>, continued to burn to the northeast near the boundary of the Bridger-Teton and Shoshone national forests. _ The 53,275-acre <PERSON> Huck </PERSON> fire spread to the southeast into the <LOCATION> Teton </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Wilderness </LOCATION> in the Bridger-Teton. _ The 22,195-acre <LOCATION> Fayette </LOCATION> fire, five miles east of <LOCATION> Pinedale </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wyo. </LOCATION>, continued to burn. In <LOCATION> Southern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, firefighters extinguished the last in a series of wildfires that blackened more than 25,000 acres. A shift in winds and weather and the use of irrigation systems spared central <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>'s orchard belt from a 30,000-acre fire. The fire, 50 percent contained on Wednesday, was not expected to be completely contained before Friday, officials said. In <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION>, residents of more than 60 canyon homes were allowed to return home as firefighters neared containment of a 5,600-acre fire east of <LOCATION> Salt </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, officials said. Fire bosses hoped to contain the fire by late Thursday. A fire in <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Nez </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Perce </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION> spread from 25,900 acres Monday to 36,780 by Tuesday night. The <ORGANIZATION> Boise </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Interagency </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fire </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>, the coordinating office for firefighting in the West, said fires this year have charred 3.65 million acres, an area larger than <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION>. Slightly more than 2 million of the acres are in <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>. During the last big fire season, 1985, 2.8 million acres burned. The fire center has called this the worst fire season in 30 years.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880908-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-08-88 0222EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     09-08 0926</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0968</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in the News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>DEAUVILLE, France (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 `` Ironweed'' author <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> won the prize for literature at the <ORGANIZATION> Deauville </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Festival </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cinema </ORGANIZATION> being held in this resort on <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>'s north coast. <PERSON> Lucine </PERSON> <PERSON> Barriere </PERSON>, president of the society of <ORGANIZATION> Deauville </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hotels </ORGANIZATION> and Casinos, presented the honor on Wednesday to <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, who already has won the Pulitzer Prize and a National Book Critics Circle award for his novel about a drifter in his native <LOCATION> Albany </LOCATION>, N.Y. The movie version of `` Ironweed,'' starring <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Nicholson </PERSON> and <PERSON> Meryl </PERSON> <PERSON> Streep </PERSON>, is set to open in <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>BUDAPEST, Hungary (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
