<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880623-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-23-88 0036EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Soviet-Census     06-23 0272</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Soviet-Census,0279</SECOND>
<HEAD>Researchers Find Census Thought Destroyed by Stalin</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MOSCOW (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A Soviet demographer was quoted as saying Wednesday that researchers have found the results of a 1937 census thought to have been destroyed by <PERSON> Josef </PERSON> <PERSON> V. </PERSON> <PERSON> Stalin </PERSON> to hide millions of deaths caused by his policies. Demographer <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Tolts </PERSON> said the census showed a population of 162 million, the official <ORGANIZATION> Tass </ORGANIZATION> news agency said. The weekly magazine <ORGANIZATION> Ogonyok </ORGANIZATION>, in a story about the census published in December, said <PERSON> Stalin </PERSON> claimed a population in 1937 of 170 million even though statistics could not confirm it. <PERSON> Tolts </PERSON> did not say where the census results were found, and said it was too early to use its figures to estimate how many people died in the purges, collectivization of agriculture and forced industrialization <PERSON> Stalin </PERSON> imposed in the 1930s. Current Soviet reference books put the population at 163 million for 1917, the year of the revolution that brought the <ORGANIZATION> Bolsheviks </ORGANIZATION> to power. The current population is 284 million. <PERSON> Ogonyok </PERSON> blamed many of the deaths on a famine forced upon rural residents by government grain requisitions, but <PERSON> Tolts </PERSON> said <PERSON> Stalin </PERSON>'s repressive policies also apparently were to blame He said the population of the <LOCATION> Saratov </LOCATION> region on the <LOCATION> Volga </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> southeast of <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> declined by 20 percent between 1927 and 1937, and the population of the Kursk region south of <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> declined by 14 percent in the same period. <PERSON> Stalin </PERSON> told a <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> congress </ORGANIZATION> in 1934 that the Soviet population the previous year was 168 million, although census officials put the figure at 165.7 million and one scientist put it as low as 158 million.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880623-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-23-88 0044EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-RacialAssault 1stLd-Writethru a0787 06-23 0631</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Racial Assault, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0787,0645</SECOND>
<HEAD>Three Men Arrested In Racial Beating Incident</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: SUBS 5th graf, ``It's the ..., to UPDATE with Buckner's
injuries; ADDS 3 grafs with arrests, arraignment, bail set; note
language in 11th and 14th grafs</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By VIRGINIA BYRNE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A black man walking home from his job at a fast-food restaurant was attacked early Wednesday by six white men who shouted racial slurs as they pummelled him with sticks and a baseball bat, police said. The victim, <PERSON> Raymond </PERSON> <PERSON> Buckner </PERSON>, took refuge in a pizza parlor, where the owners defended him against the gang and were themselves later harassed and assaulted, according to police. Three whites were arrested, and police were seeking three others. <PERSON> Buckner </PERSON>, 24, was treated for bruises at a hospital and released. He said the assault, which occurred on <LOCATION> Staten </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION>, reminded him of the attack by a dozen white youths on three blacks in the <LOCATION> Howard </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION> section of <LOCATION> Queens </LOCATION> in December 1986. In that highly publicized case, one of the black men died when he was hit by a car while trying to escape. Three white teens were convicted of manslaughter last December. `` It's the same incident, racial,'' said <PERSON> Buckner </PERSON>, who was treated for contusions at <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Vincent </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION>. `` I was minding my own business. I just get jumped for no reason.'' A short time after the attack, officers arrested <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Dessoye </PERSON>, 19; <PERSON> Steven </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Russell </PERSON>, 18; and <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Kish </PERSON>, 20, all of <LOCATION> Staten </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION>. They were charged with second-degree assault, aggravated harassment, criminal possession of a deadly instrument and possession of a controlled substance, marijuana. <PERSON> Dessoye </PERSON> was also charged with driving while intoxicated. `` <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> <PERSON> Beach </PERSON> was the first thing I thought of,'' said <PERSON> Jeff </PERSON> <PERSON> Lamartina </PERSON>, one of the owners of the Cafe DiSicilia pizzeria, who aided <PERSON> Buckner </PERSON>. `` It was n't right. This guy was doing nothing wrong.'' <PERSON> Buckner </PERSON>, a cook at a Burger King restaurant, said he was walking home through a mostly white section of <LOCATION> Staten </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> at about 12:20 a.m. when a car slowed down and the occupants began harassing him. `` They were calling me racial names _ nigger, <PERSON> blackie </PERSON>,'' <PERSON> Buckner </PERSON> said. The men left their car and began beating him on the arm with sticks and a baseball bat, chasing him down the street. When <PERSON> Buckner </PERSON> fled into the pizzeria, `` he was nervous; his arm was messed up,'' <PERSON> Lamartina </PERSON> said. `` He said he just got jumped by a carload of white guys.'' <PERSON> Lamartina </PERSON> gave <PERSON> Buckner </PERSON> some ice and offered to have a worker drive him home. The group of white men appeared in front of the store, but they left after <PERSON> Lamartina </PERSON> and an employee went outside to disperse them. At about 1:20 a.m., after <PERSON> Buckner </PERSON> had been taken home, the group reappeared in front of the pizza parlor and taunted <PERSON> LaMartina </PERSON> and the store's other owner, <PERSON> Sal </PERSON> <PERSON> Taormina </PERSON>, calling them `` nigger lovers,'' <PERSON> LaMartina </PERSON> said. Both owners are white. `` One of them had a bat, and went to swing it at me, but <PERSON> Sal </PERSON> caught it,'' <PERSON> Lamartina </PERSON> recounted. `` We smacked them around a little bit, and they ran away.'' Neighbors who had witnessed the altercation called police, as did <PERSON> Buckner </PERSON> when he got home. A short time later, officers pulled over a red car and arrested <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Dessoye </PERSON>, 19, <PERSON> Steven </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Russell </PERSON>, 18, and <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Kish </PERSON>, 20, all of <LOCATION> Staten </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION>. They were identified by <PERSON> Buckner </PERSON>, <PERSON> LaMartina </PERSON> and <PERSON> Taormina </PERSON> as the assailants. The three men were charged with second-degree assault, aggravated harassment, criminal possession of a deadly instrument and criminal possession of a controlled substance, marijuana. <PERSON> Dessoye </PERSON> was also charged with driving while intoxicated. All three pleaded innocent to the charges before Criminal Court Judge <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Brennan </PERSON>. Bail was set for Dessoye at $ 5,275 and $ 2,500 for both <PERSON> Russell </PERSON> and <LOCATION> Kish </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880623-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-23-88 0136EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-APArps:ScottThomas     06-23 0717</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AP Arps: Scott Thomas,0733</SECOND>
<HEAD>A Star Rises from `Dust'</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By MATT WOLF</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A new film talent has emerged from the satirical movie `` A Handful of Dust.'' Her name is <PERSON> Kristin </PERSON> <PERSON> Scott </PERSON> <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON>. The movie features <PERSON> Alec </PERSON> <PERSON> Guinness </PERSON> and <PERSON> Anjelica </PERSON> <PERSON> Huston </PERSON> in small but telling cameos, but it is dominated by <PERSON> Scott </PERSON> <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> as the elegant English rose, <PERSON> Lady </PERSON> <PERSON> Brenda </PERSON> <PERSON> Last </PERSON>, who drifts into a destructive affair with the young roue <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Beaver </PERSON> -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> Rupert </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Graves </ORGANIZATION> -RRB-. Based on <PERSON> Evelyn </PERSON> <PERSON> Waugh </PERSON>'s savage 1934 novel, the $ 6 million film co-stars <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilby </PERSON> -LRB- Graves' co-star last year in `` Maurice'' -RRB- as <PERSON> Lady </PERSON> <PERSON> Brenda </PERSON>'s hapless husband, <PERSON> Tony </PERSON>. It opens in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> on June 24. `` I'm very pleased, I'm afraid, about the reaction that I'm getting It's so nice to have one's work appreciated,'' <PERSON> Scott </PERSON> <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> said in an interview about her repeated raves from the British press. While reviews were mixed for the movie as a whole, critics hailed its female lead with the kind of accolades that banish anonymity forever. <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON> <PERSON> Walker </PERSON> in The Standard called the actress `` the film's great find,'' adding, `` It will be criminal if British cinema does n't ... make a great star of her. <PERSON> Hugh </PERSON> <PERSON> Montgomery-Massingberd </PERSON> in The <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Telegraph </ORGANIZATION> and <PERSON> Derek </PERSON> <PERSON> Malcolm </PERSON> in The Guardian both called her `` a revelation.'' <PERSON> Iain </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnstone </PERSON> in The Sunday Times found the Paris-based actress `` a singular sensation'' in a movie that has returned her in triumph to the country she left eight years ago. `` I never really thought I'd be able to work in <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>, so ` A Handful of Dust' was an enormous pleasure and a great privilege,'' said the 28-year-old actress, who dropped out of <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Speech </ORGANIZATION> and Drama after a year to move to <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION>. `` I was doing a teacher training course and hated it, wanted to change and could n't,'' said <PERSON> Scott </PERSON> <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON>, occasionally interrupting the interview to tend to the cries of her month-old daughter, <PERSON> Hannah </PERSON>. `` I was told I'd never be an actress anyway, and would never be able to play for real,'' she said. `` I thought it would be better to be totally miserable somewhere else and learn French at the same time.'' In <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION>, her life took a happier turn, beginning with her marriage to a French obstetrician. After drama training in French, she began getting parts in theater and in movies, and landed a role opposite the rock superstar Prince in his second movie, a bomb called `` Under the Cherry Moon.'' The film was not a financial success and was lampooned by critics. However, it enjoyed an international release. <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Sturridge </PERSON>, the director of `` Handful of Dust'' and of the hit <PERSON> Waugh </PERSON> TV adaptation, `` Brideshead Revisited,'' saw it and cast <PERSON> Scott </PERSON> <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> as <PERSON> Lady </PERSON> <PERSON> Brenda </PERSON>. She had studied the book at school and said she seized the chance to become part of the film. `` I was sure it was going to be great,'' she recalled, before going back to the novel to immerse herself in Lady <PERSON> Brenda </PERSON>'s emotionally fatal attraction to the callow and cunning <PERSON> Beaver </PERSON> `` She likes taking someone who is absolutely dreadful and turning him into this fascinating young man whom no one can understand what she sees in him,'' <PERSON> Scott </PERSON> <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> said, explaining the fascination on which the film's denouement depends: `` It makes her different, too.'' `` In the end, <PERSON> Beaver </PERSON> is much worse than <PERSON> Lady </PERSON> <PERSON> Brenda </PERSON> ever thought he was, really; by then she's in too deep,'' she said. The daughter of an affluent naval officer who died when she was five, <PERSON> Scott </PERSON> <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> said she was bemused by the critique of the English class system that pervades the book and the film. `` It's quite sort of endearing, really, but it is ridiculous,'' said <PERSON> Scott </PERSON> <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON>, a graduate of the posh <ORGANIZATION> Cheltenham </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ladies </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ' </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> `` It's like some dear old piece of furniture that you like but you think is quite the most hideous thing in the world.'' She hopes not to be typecast as aristocratic English swells, and would like to do a French film next. `` I live there and I want to work there. You have to work hard, and I really mean to work hard,'' she said. `` I've got to make sure that the revelation does n't turn out to be a disaster.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880623-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-23-88 0138EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Brazil-TrainSurfers     06-23 0740</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Brazil-Train Surfers,0763</SECOND>
<HEAD>Brazilian Youths Go `Surfing' on Train Roofs</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>BY JORGE MEDEROS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>RIO DE JANEIRO, Brazil (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The commuter train zips along at 50 miles an hour. On top of a car a young man stands up and waves his arms like a bird in flight. The slightest slip could mean a fatal fall; the slightest jolt could mean contact with a 3,000-volt electrical wire overhead. Nevertheless, <PERSON> Paulo </PERSON> <PERSON> Evaristo </PERSON>, 15, and hundreds of other youths from <LOCATION> Rio </LOCATION> <LOCATION> de </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Janeiro </LOCATION>'s poor outlying suburbs risk their lives every day showing off their skills in what is known as train surfing. Some 150 train surfers were killed last year, 40 in the first five months of this year. The government company that runs the commuter trains has had to pay the equivalent of $ 700,000 in claims filed by the survivors of youths killed or by youths who have been injured. More than 400 young men were injured in 1987, some permanently paralyzed. `` These people are seeking new thrills, but in my opinion they're suicidal,'' said <PERSON> Helio </PERSON> <PERSON> Barros </PERSON>, spokesman for the railroad. He added that efforts to discourage the train surfers have failed. `` With the money we spent on claims, we could have repaired 10 trains,'' he said. He added that the railroad is trying to persuade judges not to validate claims in cases of train-surfing accidents. `` I've been doing this since I was 13,'' said <PERSON> Paulo </PERSON> <PERSON> Evaristo </PERSON>. `` You get a feeling of freedom that is greater than any fear.'' <PERSON> Paulo </PERSON> <PERSON> Evaristo </PERSON> is a grade-school dropout and works as a messenger. He declined to give his last name in an interview. Train surfers come from poor neighborhoods, and some Brazilian newspapers have speculated the young people are trying to emulate the sea surfers at wealthy beachfront districts, such as <LOCATION> Copacabana </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Ipanema </LOCATION>. The newspaper accounts also have suggested the surfers ride train roofs because they ca n't afford the 15-cruzado -LRB- 8-cent -RRB- fare, or that there's no room in the crowded trains, which transport 1.2 million passengers daily. But <PERSON> Barros </PERSON>, the railroad spokesman, dismissed all these arguments. `` It's strictly for the fun,'' he said. `` In the first place, you have to pay the fare to get inside the train stations. And even when it's not rush hour and there are plenty of seats, you still see these kids on top of the cars.'' The train company has assigned 200 guards a day to try to stop train surfers. But the guards are not enough to cover the commuter system's 450 miles of track and 110 stations. When they do arrest a train surfer, the penalty is a fine equivalent to $ 1 and a lecture from a government psychologist. `` The purpose is not to jail these people,'' <PERSON> Barros </PERSON> said. `` It is to save their lives.'' Chief <PERSON> Fernando </PERSON> <PERSON> Rodrigues </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Almeida </PERSON> of the police precinct of the Engenho Novo neighborhood ordered 11 train surfers jailed without bail on charges of obstructing railroad traffic. But a judge ruled that train surfing was not a crime, but rather an act of `` self-injury,'' similar to attempted suicide, and not dealt with in the Brazilian legal code. The judge reprimanded the chief for abuse of authority. `` We're not crazy, and we're not bums either,'' said train surfer <PERSON> Luiz </PERSON> <PERSON> Claudio </PERSON>, 18, an apprentice lathe operator who makes $ 70 a month, slightly more than the minimum wage. `` We're just looking for a little fun, to pass the time during the train ride.'' <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON>, 19, a maid, who like <PERSON> Luiz </PERSON> <PERSON> Claudio </PERSON> would not tell her last name, said she sometimes rides on top of the commuter trains because the atmosphere inside the cars is `` violent,'' with frequent muggings. But she added, `` It's a lot of fun, too.'' <PERSON> Barros </PERSON>, the railroad spokesman, said train surfers have always been a problem, but the practice reached an all-time high last year. He added that the suburb of <LOCATION> Nilopolis </LOCATION> has a `` Train Surfers Association'' with three tests for membership: 1 -RRB- Ride hanging from the outside of a window or door. 2 -RRB- Climb up a car in motion and lie on the roof. 3 -RRB- Stand on the roof of a moving car. The founder of the association, known as Rambo, was killed when he fell from a train. Another member of the group who was killed had a membership card in his pocket. It said, `` Evanil dos <PERSON> Santos </PERSON> passed his test and is authorized to hang from trains.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880623-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-23-88 0139EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Haiti-Coup     06-23 0857</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Haiti-Coup,0884</SECOND>
<HEAD>Manigat Apparently Misread Haitian Army's Inner Workings</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP News Analysis</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By ED McCULLOUGH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> PORT-AU-PRINCE </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Haiti </LOCATION> -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> -RRB- _ <PERSON> Leslie </PERSON> <PERSON> Manigat </PERSON>, a political science professor with pride in his grasp of strategy, apparently misunderstood the army and may have been duped into trying to exploit what he read as dissension within it. His attempt did n't work, and the general who handed <PERSON> Manigat </PERSON> the presidency in February took it back and sent him into exile. Several versions are circulating of the overthrow of <PERSON> Manigat </PERSON> this week by Lt. Gen. <PERSON> Henri </PERSON> <PERSON> Namphy </PERSON>, who ran the ruling junta for two years after the <PERSON> Duvalier </PERSON> dictatorship ended and proclaimed himself president Monday. All focus on miscalculations by <PERSON> Manigat </PERSON>, a civilian who was eager to assert control over the army after four months in power. Some say <PERSON> Manigat </PERSON> overreached by trying to use what seemed to be a split between <PERSON> Namphy </PERSON> and Col. <PERSON> Jean-Claude </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON>, a powerful commander, to carry out a general purge of the army. Others say the dispute between <PERSON> Namphy </PERSON> and <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> may itself have been a sham, and <PERSON> Manigat </PERSON> walked into the trap. The army has not explained. A friend and sometime adviser to <PERSON> Namphy </PERSON> said privately `` the high command tricked <PERSON> Manigat </PERSON>,'' using his desire to control the army as a tool to overthrow him. <PERSON> Namphy </PERSON>'s escape from house arrest Sunday evening and his noisy takeover of the National Palace `` seems to have been a well-set-up sham,'' a Western diplomat said, also on condition of anonymity. No one was killed and nothing destroyed at the palace, the scene of most of the shooting Sunday night, and soldiers who allegedly were fighting one another at midnight stood together amicably on television early in the morning. About 1:30 a.m., only 55 minutes after the heaviest gunfire, <PERSON> Namphy </PERSON> appeared on television at the palace carrying an Uzi submachine gun. A military band played the national anthem. When he announced a military government later in the morning, also on television, he was surrounded by <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> and representatives of other units. The 7,000-man army appears united behind him. Later Monday, he announced promotions of officers <PERSON> Manigat </PERSON> had retired or transferred, including Col. Prosper Avril to brigadier general and adjutant general of the military. Many observers believe <PERSON> Avril </PERSON>, who had been a military adviser to the <ORGANIZATION> Duvaliers </ORGANIZATION>, was a key figure in the coup. Political observers still are trying to piece together how <PERSON> Namphy </PERSON> ended up in the National Palace and <PERSON> Manigat </PERSON> in a small hotel in <LOCATION> Santo </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Domingo </LOCATION>, capital of the <LOCATION> Dominican </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Republic </LOCATION> on the other side of Hispaniola island. This is what is known: <PERSON> Namphy </PERSON> tried 10 days ago to transfer <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> to an administrative post from command of the 700-man Dessalines Battalion stationed just behind the National Palace. <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> refused. <PERSON> Manigat </PERSON> sided with <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> and dismissed <PERSON> Namphy </PERSON> as army chief on Friday. When <PERSON> Namphy </PERSON> appeared to accept, `` <PERSON> Manigat </PERSON> thought he had an opportunity'' to exert control over officers who had hampered his initiatives since he took office, a diplomat said. The portly 57-year-old professor and linguist, who has studied and lectured at some of the world's major universities, tried his own series of transfers and promotions Sunday afternoon. Within hours he was arrested and sent with his family across the border to the <LOCATION> Dominican </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Republic </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Manigat </PERSON> admitted Tuesday he was surprised by the coup, had believed most of the military supported him and did n't understand why <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> rejoined <PERSON> Namphy </PERSON>. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Sen. <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Graham </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Fla </LOCATION>., who follows events in <LOCATION> Haiti </LOCATION> closely, said it appears <PERSON> Manigat </PERSON> hoped to consolidate power by dominating the army as <PERSON> Francois </PERSON> `` Papa Doc'' <PERSON> Duvalier </PERSON> did `` The <ORGANIZATION> Duvaliers </ORGANIZATION> were able to control the military for years by a divide, confuse and conquer approach,'' <PERSON> Graham </PERSON> said from <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> Duvaliers </ORGANIZATION> frequently dismissed officers they distrusted, and they diluted the army's power with a private security force, the feared <ORGANIZATION> Tontons </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Macoute </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Jean-Claude </PERSON> <PERSON> Duvalier </PERSON>, son of <PERSON> Papa </PERSON> <PERSON> Doc </PERSON>, fled the country Feb. 7, 1986, ending the 29-year family dictatorship, and the junta led by <PERSON> Namphy </PERSON> took over. <PERSON> Graham </PERSON> said one interpretation of the Namphy-Paul rift was that <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> realized `` the <PERSON> Namphy </PERSON> components of the army were stronger, so he recognized he did n't have an alternative other than to cut a deal.'' Another theory is that <PERSON> Manigat </PERSON> simply gambled and lost, that a showdown with the army was inevitable and he moved when he thought his chances were best. <PERSON> Namphy </PERSON>'s brother <PERSON> Joe </PERSON>, a businessman, has said the general did not know soldiers would free him Sunday night. A close friend of Gen. <PERSON> Namphy </PERSON> said <PERSON> Manigat </PERSON> put him up to transferring <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> and turned on the general when <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> refused to go. <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> has been indicted on drug trafficking charges by a federal court in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>. He a dominant figure in <LOCATION> Haiti </LOCATION>'s army, which is top-heavy with officers and so factionalized that a colonel can be more powerful than a general. <PERSON> Namphy </PERSON>'s justification for returning to the palace was that <PERSON> Manigat </PERSON>'s attempted reorganization of the army was unconstitutional, dangerously partisan and endangered democracy.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Ed </PERSON> <PERSON> McCullough </PERSON> is <LOCATION> Caribbean </LOCATION> news editor of The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>, based in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Juan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Puerto </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rico </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880623-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-23-88 0612EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--ChristmasInJune     06-23 0151</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Christmas In June,0156</SECOND>
<HEAD>Honolulu Get Christmas Serenade On Radio</HEAD>
<DATELINE>HONOLULU (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Beachgoers soaking up the Hawaiian summer sun were serenaded by the strains of `` White Christmas'' and `` Jingle Bell Rock'' on a radio station here. <ORGANIZATION> KSSK </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Radio </ORGANIZATION> billed Wednesday as a day of yuletide music to remind listeners that drinking and driving kills. `` We've had 41 traffic fatalities so far this year and if we continue at this rate we'll have 46 more before Christmas,'' said <PERSON> Suzi </PERSON> <PERSON> Mechler </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> KSSK </ORGANIZATION> director of operations. `` So we're playing them their Christmas music now.'' There were 32 traffic fatalities on <LOCATION> Honolulu </LOCATION> roads at the same time last year, police said. <PERSON> Mechler </PERSON> said the music also was played to give would-be drinken drivers a desire to live until Christmas and to think before getting behind the wheel. <PERSON> Mechler </PERSON> said the station has celebrated Christmas in June for the past three or four years.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880623-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-23-88 0613EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--VintageRace     06-23 0155</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Vintage Race,0159</SECOND>
<HEAD>120 Vintage Vehicles Roll Off in 4,500-Mile Race to Boston</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ANAHEIM, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Mickey </PERSON> <PERSON> Mouse </PERSON> dispatched 120 vintage vehicles from <ORGANIZATION> Disneyland </ORGANIZATION> for a 12-day, 4,500-mile race to <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>. Balloons went up and confetti came down as the sixth annual Great American Race for pre-1937 vehicles began Wednesday with a parade from Small World, down Main Street U.S.A. and out of the park, said spokeswoman <PERSON> Louanne </PERSON> <PERSON> Cappiello </PERSON>. First prize in the transcontinental road rally is $ 50,000, out of a total of $ 250,000 in prizes. The race route ran through <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Luis </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Obispo </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Sacramento </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Elko </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Nev. </LOCATION>; Rock Springs, <LOCATION> Wyo </LOCATION>.; <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Salina </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Kan. </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Louis </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Cincinnati </LOCATION>; <PERSON> Erie </PERSON> and <LOCATION> Wilkes-Barre </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION>; ending at <ORGANIZATION> Boston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hall </ORGANIZATION> on July 3. Participants included a steam-powered 1909 <ORGANIZATION> Stanley </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Steamer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mountain </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wagon </ORGANIZATION>, a 1912 American La <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> fire engine, a 1905 French <PERSON> De </PERSON> <PERSON> Dietrich </PERSON> automobile and a 1912 Metz Roadster. Each vehicle carried a driver and a navigator.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880623-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-23-88 0154EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Million-DollarCello     06-23 0307</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Million-Dollar Cello,0316</SECOND>
<HEAD>World Record $1.2 Million Paid For Stradivari Cello</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An anonymous bidder paid $ 1.2 million for a cello made by <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Stradivari </PERSON> about 1698 _ a world record auction price for a musical instrument, the <PERSON> Sotheby </PERSON>'s auction house said. The cello, known as the <PERSON> Cholmondeley </PERSON> after a previous owner, was auctioned Wednesday and the seller also asked to remain anonymous. The previous record for a musical instrument was $ 890,000 paid by an anonymous <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> on March 31 for a violin known as the Marie Hall that was also made by <PERSON> Stradivari </PERSON>, an Italian. The previous record for a cello was $ 393,000 paid in 1984 by <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Cohen </PERSON>, an eminent <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> cellist, for a <LOCATION> Stradivari </LOCATION> instrument known as the Bonjour. Sotheby's said several people were bidding for the <PERSON> Cholmondeley </PERSON> `` in a relaxed way.'' They said they were not surprised by the price as they had expected the cello to sell for at least $ 1 million. They said the buyer might decide at some time to disclose his or her identity. British cellist <PERSON> Julian </PERSON> <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Webber </PERSON>, younger brother of composer <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Webber </PERSON>, spent $ 280,000 in 1986 on a <PERSON> Stradivari </PERSON> cello and was not immediately identified as the purchaser. `` The Cholmondeley -LRB- pronounced <PERSON> Chumley </PERSON> -RRB- is so well made that it almost plays itself _ as if it had cruise control,'' said <PERSON> Adam </PERSON> <PERSON> Watson </PERSON>, the cataloguer of Wednesday's auction. The cello has a head by a different maker, <PERSON> Joannnes </PERSON> <PERSON> Florenus </PERSON> <PERSON> Guidantus </PERSON>. The instrument is just over 29 inches long and rich golden-brown in color. It belonged in the mid-19th century to the Marquess of <LOCATION> Cholmondeley </LOCATION>. It later went to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and was played at the <LOCATION> Stradivari </LOCATION> memorial concert in 1937 by <PERSON> Ralph </PERSON> <PERSON> Oxman </PERSON>. `` It is a well-known instrument and has been in the hands of several collectors recently,'' said <PERSON> Watson </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880623-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-23-88 0125EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lites     06-23 0483</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lites,0502</SECOND>
<HEAD>On The Light Side</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WATERTOWN, Conn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 They came to curry <PERSON> Caesar </PERSON>, not craze him. <PERSON> Caesar </PERSON>, an African gray parrot that's been the <PERSON> Briere </PERSON> family pet for 11 years, took his first-ever flight Sunday afternoon while his cage was being moved outside and spent two days as a free bird. The parrot, who eschews the traditional cracker in favor of provolone cheese and bolgona, perched atop a tall tree across the street from his home after he flew the coop. <PERSON> Caesar </PERSON> remained free until Tuesday. The fire department on Sunday responded by sending Chief <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> `` Buddy'' <PERSON> Judd </PERSON> up in a ladder truck bucket. <PERSON> Judd </PERSON> said as soon as he got close, <PERSON> Caesar </PERSON> just squealed and flew away. The bird's quest for freedom kept family members, friends and neighbors busy as they took shifts throughout the day and night keeping track of the parrot, according a family member. <PERSON> Jeannine </PERSON> <PERSON> Briere </PERSON> said she spent the days sitting in the back yard, whistling and calling the bird until her voice started tiring. She then made a tape recording of her calls and played it over and over. Her husband, <PERSON> Fern </PERSON>, said he told her at one point that the parrot was trying to come home, but did n't know how to land. On Tuesday, the Brieres bought a large fishing net and attached it to a 10-foot pole. After tracking <PERSON> Caesar </PERSON> to a neighbor's tree, they reached up and after a couple of tries, bagged the bird. <PERSON> Briere </PERSON>, with gloves on, grabbed the bird from the net. <PERSON> Caesar </PERSON>'s first word was `` Hello.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>MIAMI (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A falafel vendor is claiming victory in a food fight against hot dogs. The ruckus started when <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Bonan </PERSON>, who has sold falafel at <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> street festivals for nine years, moved his sidewalk cart to a busy downtown street where hot-dog carts have long had a monopoly. The hot dog vendors complained, and <LOCATION> Dade </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> health inspectors ordered <PERSON> Bonan </PERSON> to close the business March 9. <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>'s health code limits mobile food units to `` frankfurters only,'' they said That's because hot dogs are covered with `` a membrane that prevents pathogenic organisms from entering the food.'' <PERSON> Bonan </PERSON> claimed the code was unconstitutional, sued the state in federal court and refused to budge. Earlier this month, a health inspector and three police officers confiscated $ 100 of falafel, doused it with liquid bleach and threatened to arrest <PERSON> Bonan </PERSON> if he did n't stop. An emergency hearing was held Friday and <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION> Magistrate <PERSON> Samuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Smargon </PERSON> ruled in <PERSON> Bonan </PERSON>'s favor. `` Just standing up for my rights through the legal system,'' said <PERSON> Bonan </PERSON>, who vows to add two carts selling the mashed chick-pea mixture on city streets by next week. The state has 10 days to appeal. <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> Ros </PERSON>, assistant county director of environmental health, said he is worried that the falafel case will open the streets to everything from tacos to chicken wings.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880623-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-23-88 0613EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--MissingDoorknobs     06-23 0144</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Missing Doorknobs,0148</SECOND>
<HEAD>Doorknob Caper Baffles Police</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BOSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Doorknobs are back at police headquarters, but there are no so suspects in the theft of six ornate knobs stolen last month. Police say they are more vigilant about watching the hardware _ and each other. So was the doorknob caper an inside job? `` We're not sure who did it,'' police spokesman <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Jordan </PERSON> said. `` Police or no police, it's a work place.'' Half a dozen metal knobs the color of pewter and embossed with the city seal were discovered missing about five weeks ago. They disappeared one night from middle-level floors, where administrative offices are located in the seven-floor building that was built in 1924. The knobs have since been replaced, some with the same fancy design, others without. <PERSON> Jordan </PERSON> said he did n't know the knobs' value, but said it was modest
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880623-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-23-88 0109EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-ScotchWhisky     06-23 0171</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Scotch Whisky,0173</SECOND>
<HEAD>``Scotch'' to Become Protected Trademark like ``Champagne''</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Parliament has passed a law that will ensure the integrity of spirits labeled `` Scotch'' by making the appellation a protected trademark. Under the law, no whisky can be called Scotch unless it conforms to standards set by the <ORGANIZATION> Scotch </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Whisky </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>: matured for at least three years, in oak casks with charred insides, and using only Scottish ingredients like Highland water. The law passed the House of Lords Tuesday and now awaits the formality of the queen's signature, said <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Walker </PERSON>, a Scottish lawmaker for the ruling <ORGANIZATION> Conservative </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> and sponsor of the bill. <PERSON> Walker </PERSON> said Wednesday that the new law would empower whisky distillers to prosecute anyone violating Scotch standards. He said it was modeled on a law that prevents drinks being called champagne unless they come from the province of Champagne in <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> and conform to its standards. <PERSON> Walker </PERSON> said more than 90 percent of Scotch is exported, and earns <LOCATION> Scotland </LOCATION> $ 1.8 billion a year.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880623-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-23-88 0158EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lottery     06-23 0049</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lottery,0051</SECOND>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the winning weekly state lottery numbers picked Wednesday:
</TEXT>
<HEAD>MASSACHUSETTS</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Wednesday Megabucks: 05; 09; 23; 28; 32; 35.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>NEW YORK</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Wednesday Lotto 54 Game: 06; 23; 26; 34; 43; 44. Supplementary 05.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>RHODE ISLAND</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Grand Lot Game: 7-7-6; 8-3-4-9; 7-8-5-9-3; 6-6-4-1-0-2.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880623-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-23-88 0030EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-PrisonEscape 1stLd-Writethru a0833 06-23 0402</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Prison Escape, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0833,0413</SECOND>
<HEAD>Police Capture Two Escapees in Taylor County</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Leads with 6 grafs to UPDATE with details of capture; ADDS 2
grafs on further investigation.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>CAMPBELLSVILLE, Ky. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Two escaped murderers from the <ORGANIZATION> Kentucky </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Penitentiary </ORGANIZATION> were captured in a rural field Wednesday night after a brief exchange of gunfire with state police. State police Sgt. <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Sapp </PERSON> said nobody was injured during the exchange. He said <PERSON> Ronnie </PERSON> <PERSON> Hudson </PERSON>, 29, and <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Montgomery </PERSON>, 27, were taken into custody about 8:21 p.m. in a cornfield about 300 feet from a temporary command post that state police had set up in a church parking lot. The two were seen crawling through the field by several children playing kickball behind the church before Wednesday night prayer meeting. The two surrendered after their escape from the field was halted by a barbed wire fence. Both men were armed, <PERSON> Sapp </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Sapp </PERSON> said <PERSON> Hudson </PERSON> had died his hair red, and <PERSON> Montgomery </PERSON> had cut his hair. State police said neighborhood children had found two tote bags Tuesday night that were believed to have been dropped by the escapees. The bags contained bullets, clothing and hair dye. The escapees, both from <LOCATION> Louisville </LOCATION>, were among eight who fled the <ORGANIZATION> Kentucky </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Penitentiary </ORGANIZATION> at <LOCATION> Eddyville </LOCATION> in western <LOCATION> Kentucky </LOCATION> last Thursday. Three others have been captured. State police said they believed the two men had been staying with friends or relatives of <PERSON> Hudson </PERSON>'s since arriving in the area Sunday. `` I anticipate some charges against local people for aiding these fugitives,'' said state police Sgt. <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Sapp </PERSON>. Those still at large include another murderer, <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Blanton </PERSON>, 29, of <LOCATION> Farler </LOCATION>; <PERSON> Billy </PERSON> <PERSON> Hall </PERSON>, 25, of <LOCATION> Paducah </LOCATION>, serving 23 years for burglary and assault, and <PERSON> Derek </PERSON> <PERSON> Quintero </PERSON>, 26, of <LOCATION> Clarksville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Tenn. </LOCATION>, serving 37 years for kidnapping and robbery. The eight sawed their way to freedom from an upper level of Cellhouse 3. The breakout was apparently well-planned, with inmates on the cellhouse's lower level setting small, diversionary fires to distract guards. Officials in <LOCATION> Dover </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Tenn. </LOCATION>, were investigating Wednesday whether the murder of an elderly couple in rural <LOCATION> Leatherwood </LOCATION>, a resort community on <LOCATION> Kentucky </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> about 50 miles south of the prison, was linked to the escapes. <LOCATION> Stewart </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> Sheriff's dispatcher <PERSON> Tina </PERSON> <PERSON> Hicks </PERSON> said investigators from the <ORGANIZATION> Tennessee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Investigation </ORGANIZATION> and a laboratory team from the <ORGANIZATION> Tennessee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Highway </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Patrol </ORGANIZATION> linked the slayings to the fugitives, but had no details.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880623-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-23-88 0200EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-RainbowFamily     06-23 0178</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Rainbow Family,0182</SECOND>
<HEAD>Forest Service To Bring In More Officers For Rainbow Gathering</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ZAVALLA, Texas (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A plan by a back-to-nature group to hold a gathering of thousands of people in a national forest has prompted the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> to place 24 additional officers on patrol. Between 12,000 and 20,000 people are expected to attend the annual `` gathering of the tribes'' held by the Rainbow Family during the Fourth of July weekend, officials said. The <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> blocked roads to the site where many are camped after the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> 5th </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Circuit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appeals </ORGANIZATION> last week reinstated a temporary restraining order forbidding more than 25 Rainbow Family members from meeting in one place without a <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> permit. An appeals panel has not announced if it will continue the restraining order while considering an appeal of a ruling by <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Judge </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> William </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wayne </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> that the group does n't need a permit. About 400 `` family'' members are now camped in the forest, officials said Tuesday. One forest service agent is usually assigned to the area.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880623-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-23-88 0132EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w AM-US-Australia 1stLd-Writethru a0706 06-23 0552</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-US-Australia, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0706,450</SECOND>
<HEAD>Hawke Arrives With Messages for Reagan, Congress, Candidates</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: INSERTS 4 grafs after pvs 2nd graf bgng ``The prime ...'' to
include information and quotes from dinner hosted by Shultz; picks
up pvs 3rd graf bgng ``Hawke told ...''</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By GENE KRAMER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Australian Prime Minister <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Hawke </PERSON> arrived in the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> capital Wednesday for meetings with President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and the leading presidential candidates and to speak to both houses of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. The prime minister and his wife, <PERSON> Hazel </PERSON> <PERSON> Masterson </PERSON> <PERSON> Hawke </PERSON>, were in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> this week. Secretary of State <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> and Mrs. <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> met their helicopter near the <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> monument and escorted them to their hotel. <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> hosted a dinner for the <PERSON> Hawkes </PERSON> at the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> Wednesday night and praised <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION>'s strong ties with the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. He said the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> was posing new challenges in <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION> and the two allies must face the question `` how do we meet the challenge.'' On <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION>, where the Soviet-backed <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> is withdrawing some of its forces, <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> said `` we must keep up the pressure now that we see things are going our way.'' <PERSON> Hawke </PERSON> paid tribute to <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> as a good friend of <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION> and joined him in calling for an end to agricultural subsidies. `` It's insane to spend $ 200 billion on them,'' <PERSON> Hawke </PERSON> said <PERSON> Hawke </PERSON> told a television interviewer his message to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and other <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> leaders will be <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION>'s familiar appeal against <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> farm subsidies that <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION> says are unfair competition and cause economic harm to `` a first class ally of <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, the best ally you've got.'' In trade, `` that first class relationship is n't reflected. We do n't like our farmers and our economy being hurt by action here which is against your own interests. ... That's my message,'' <PERSON> Hawke </PERSON> said on <ORGANIZATION> ABC-TV </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Good Morning America.'' `` It's against the self-interest of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> to be spending the billions of dollars it is on farm supports and subsidies,'' <PERSON> Hawke </PERSON> said. `` It does n't get into the right hands. It increases the cost and price structure of this country.'' But Australians, with unsubsidized wheat and meat to export, are `` the innocent people in the middle who get caught by the subsidies cross fire between the Europeans and the Americans,'' <PERSON> Hawke </PERSON> added. The prime minister also branded as `` nonsense'' the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Zealand </LOCATION> anti-nuclear restrictions that barred American warships from visiting <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Zealand </LOCATION> and led to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Zealand </LOCATION>'s ouster from the three-cornered <ORGANIZATION> ANZUS </ORGANIZATION> alliance between the two <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> countries and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. Seventy-four <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> warships visited <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION> last year with `` no restrictions,'' <PERSON> Hawke </PERSON> said. `` We've got an alliance relationship with the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, and we do n't buy the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Zealand </LOCATION> proposition that you can have an alliance relationship and say to your ally, ` We're allies, but I'm sorry, boys, your ships ca n't come. <PERSON> Hawke </PERSON> will address a meeting of the two houses of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> on Thursday and then lunch with <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>. An afternoon meeting was planned with Vice President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, probable <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> candidate in the November presidential election, and the <PERSON> Hawkes </PERSON>' host at dinner later Thursday The <ORGANIZATION> Australian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> said <PERSON> Hawke </PERSON> also would meet <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, the probable <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> candidate for president. <PERSON> Hawke </PERSON> planned to fly Friday to a speaking engagement at <LOCATION> Austin </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880623-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-23-88 0054EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Summit-Japan Bjt   06-23 0645</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Summit-Japan, Bjt,0664</SECOND>
<HEAD>Smooth Ride At Summit Reflects Japan's Emerging Role in World
Affairs</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JEFF BRADLEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>TORONTO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A familiar ingredient was missing from this week's economic summit in <LOCATION> Toronto </LOCATION>: No one did any Japan-bashing. Unlike past summits when the Japanese sat quietly on the sidelines and other countries complained of surging trade deficits, <LOCATION> Toronto </LOCATION> was more like a corporate board meeting with <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> an equal partner. `` Statistics talked on our behalf,'' explained <PERSON> Michihiko </PERSON> <PERSON> Kunihiro </PERSON>, chief cabinet counselor on foreign affairs. He was referring to three inter-related developments in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s economy Over the last three years, the value of the yen has doubled against the dollar, making Japanese exports more expensive and American imports cheaper. Second, <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> has agreed it needs to develop its domestic market and thus increase its import. Most important, the island nation has promised to work for a gradual narrowing of its record trade surpluses. The performance of the Japanese economy led several summit partners to compliment Japanese Prime Minister <PERSON> Noboru </PERSON> <PERSON> Takeshita </PERSON>, making his debut at the annual gatherings. `` He was very pleased,'' said Kunihiro. By fully cooperating with international efforts to coordinate economic policies, <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> now feels treated like an `` insider'' in the cliquish Group of Seven major industrialized democracies, he said. `` Perhaps Japanese leaders finally thought they can contribute more substantively than before. I will leave the judgment to you,'' Kunihiro said of the <LOCATION> Toronto </LOCATION> meeting. <PERSON> Jacques </PERSON> <PERSON> Delors </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> European </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Community </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION>, referred to the gathering as a `` trilateral'' summit that balanced the interests of <LOCATION> Western </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> and `` <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> with <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION> behind it.'' <PERSON> Takeshita </PERSON> expressed satisfaction that action was taken on all three of his priorities. There was a joint commitment to growth-without-inflation, a determination to fight protectionism and agreement on relieving Third World debt. <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> used the summit platform to announce its waiving of $ 1 billion in debt repayments from 17 of the world's poorest countries over the next five years. Even on farm subsidies, the result was to <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s liking. President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> had proposed ending the $ 200 billion subsidy war by the year 2000, but the final communique merely targeted reductions provided such factors as `` social concerns,'' `` food security'' and agricultural `` diversity'' are taken into account. Farmers in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> are a powerful political force and farm subsidies, including tariffs that restrict competition from cheaper <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> goods, are their life blood. Even as the summiteers gathered, <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> reached agreement with the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> in a longstanding dispute over raising quotas for <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> beef and citrus products. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and <PERSON> Takeshita </PERSON> also signed a pact to open up Japanese laboratories to <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> researchers for closer collaboration in science and technology. While not presuming to speak directly for <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Takeshita </PERSON> said he was happy summit partners pledged a new dialogue with the newly industrialized nations of <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Singapore </LOCATION>. There was even speculation that the so-called `` four tigers'' might be invited as observers at future summits, and the suggestion <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> might stage an Asian economic summit. `` The Japanese have a growing sense that <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> should play a greater role in affairs outside <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> ... except for military activities. That is something constitutionally we have to refrain from,'' Kunihiro said. One future goal, the official said, is to help <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s 122 million people mix better with the rest of the world. `` We should be better understood despite the difficult language of Japanese, and try to educate our people -LRB- in other cultures -RRB-,'' he said. This new, outgoing <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> was reflected in the summit briefings. Foreign journalists, including Japanese speakers, were barred from briefings for reporters from <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> _ a tradition. But there were separate, informative and good-natured sessions in English. Kunihiro drew laughs when he sidestepped a question about vague free-trade language in the final communique. `` This is the text my boss agreed to,'' he said with a smile.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880623-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-23-88 0110EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-FishermenAdrift Bjt   06-23 0496</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Fishermen Adrift, Bjt,0507</SECOND>
<HEAD>After Nearly Five Months Adrift, Fishermen Say Sea Still Beckons</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JUAN MALTES</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SAN JOSE, Costa Rica (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The song of the sea is still music to the ears of five fishermen now home to family and friends after 144 days adrift in the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ocean </LOCATION> on a disabled boat. `` We're sea dogs. The sea calls to us,'' said one, 27-year-old <PERSON> Joel </PERSON> <PERSON> Omar </PERSON> <PERSON> Gonzalez </PERSON>. `` The sea is the source of life for us and our families.'' The five, headed by skipper <PERSON> Gerardo </PERSON> <PERSON> Obregon </PERSON>, 33, received a hero's welcome Wednesday from dozens of people including first lady <PERSON> Margarita </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Arias </PERSON> when they flew in from <LOCATION> Honolulu </LOCATION> by way of <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>. Relatives, friends, neighbors and fellow `` pescadores'' flocked in from <LOCATION> Puntarenas </LOCATION>, their home port 95 miles away, to welcome them at <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jose </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Santamaria </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION>. The engine of their 33-foot fishing vessel, the <PERSON> Cairo </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>, was knocked out beyond repair during a storm Jan. 24, five days after they sailed out of <LOCATION> Puntarenas </LOCATION>, leaving them adrift in the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION>. What was to have been an eight-day fishing trip turned into a nearly five-month quest for survival. <PERSON> Gonzalez </PERSON>, his eyes moist as he hugged his wife, <PERSON> Edith </PERSON>, told reporters ships passed them twice but did not see them. A Japanese tuna boat finally ran into them about 700 miles southeast of <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION> on June 15 and took them to <LOCATION> Honolulu </LOCATION>, where doctors found them all in good health. All in all, it was a 3,600-mile journey. The five said they survived by catching turtles and sharks, collecting rainwater and cooking them on wood fires they made by tearing pieces of wood from the boat. They said the pain was in the loneliness and not knowing when help would come. `` We spent months and months without seeing anyone, but we never lost our faith in God. We knew he was with us and he finally sent us this Japanese vessel,'' said crewman <PERSON> Jorge </PERSON> <PERSON> Hernandez </PERSON> <PERSON> Castillo </PERSON>, 22. <PERSON> Obregon </PERSON>, <PERSON> Gonzalez </PERSON>, <PERSON> Hernandez </PERSON> and their two mates _ <PERSON> Juan </PERSON> <PERSON> Cernas </PERSON> <PERSON> Bolivar </PERSON>, 47, and Pastor <PERSON> Lopez </PERSON> <PERSON> Rojas </PERSON>, 30 _ attended Mass at a Roman Catholic church and gave thanks for their deliverance. `` Imagine! Our little boat in the middle of the ocean, directionless. The hot sun of the daytime, the darkness of the night, the stars and the cold. They were truly terrible days,'' <PERSON> Obregon </PERSON> said. Once they had to go without water for four days because it did n't rain and, <PERSON> Gonzalez </PERSON> said, `` There was a moment when were drinking the blood of a turtle and I looked at Pastor and he was foaming at the mouth.'' The <LOCATION> Cairo </LOCATION> III and its crew may have broken the record for survival at sea. The Guinness Book of World Records lists the record for survival on a raft as 133 days, set by a <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> man who was adrift in the <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ocean </LOCATION> from Nov. 23, 1942, to April 5, 1943 after his ship was torpedoed.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880623-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-23-88 0235EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-AIDSTesting Bjt   06-23 0640</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AIDS Testing, Bjt,640</SECOND>
<HEAD>AIDS Confidentiality Bill Clears Committee</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JILL LAWRENCE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Expanded AIDS testing, mandatory counseling and tough punishment for violations of patient confidentiality are prescribed in a bill that won <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> committee approval after a year of negotiation and compromise. `` We're going to move it as quickly as possible. The chances of it passing are very, very bright. I expect it to become law this year,'' Rep. <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> Waxman </PERSON>, D-Calif., said Wednesday after the Energy and <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> sent the measure to the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> floor by voice vote The bill authorizes $ 400 million to expand testing and counseling activities for each of the next three years. Half the money would go to states and the other half would go directly to clinics, health centers and hospitals. Counseling would be required for anyone taking a test, whether the results were positive or negative. Anyone who intentionally or negligently breached the confidentiality of test results could be charged a fine of up to $ 10,000. An intentional violation could also bring up to a year in jail. The bill bans use of federal funds for counseling `` that promotes or encourages homosexual sexual activity or unsafe heterosexual sexual activity or intravenous drug abuse.'' But it also says counselors must provide the best information available on how to avoid getting or transmitting AIDS, `` provided that any informational materials used are not obscene.'' The major casualty of the many controversies stirred by the bill was a section banning private-sector discrimination against people with AIDS or the AIDS virus. The federal government already has a ban. <PERSON> Waxman </PERSON>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> health subcommittee, called the omission unfortunate but said it would have been impossible to pass such a policy in the current political climate. Getting rid of the discrimination provision also makes it much less likely the bill will be blocked in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Waxman </PERSON> said, because it `` removes the biggest objection that some of the right-wingers have.'' The counseling and testing bill is pending in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Human </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Resources </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>. Rep. <PERSON> Ron </PERSON> <PERSON> Wyden </PERSON>, D-Ore., said he may attempt to restore the anti-discrimination provision on the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> floor He called its deletion `` a terrible public health mistake'' because the most likely AIDS victims, without protection against losing their jobs, insurance or housing, would not volunteer for tests. <PERSON> Wyden </PERSON> said he would try to build bipartisan support for the discrimination ban on the grounds that the president's commission on AIDS recently recommended precisely such a federal policy. But <PERSON> Waxman </PERSON> said the commission view is useless without President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s backing. `` Without it I ca n't see that members are going to be willing to vote for it, have the courage to vote for it, in an election year,'' he said. `` If the president will stand behind his commission's recommendations, we will join him in sponsoring an amendment.'' Before approving the AIDS testing bill, the committee rejected a series of amendments sponsored by Rep. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Dannemeyer </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Calif </LOCATION>. Among them were attempts to require testing of all prisoners, marriage license applicants and hospital admittees. <PERSON> Dannemeyer </PERSON> also failed to win approval of a requirement that people with AIDS or the AIDS virus be reported to authorities by name; the bill requires instead that cases be reported with statistical and demographic information. Another unsuccessful <PERSON> Dannemeyer </PERSON> amendment would have required doctors to notify spouses, sex partners or IV needle partners if the patient did n't notify them within a reasonable period. Members of both parties said the bill permits doctors to make such notifications but should n't require them to do so. AIDS renders the body's immune system incapable of resisting other diseases and infections. The virus most often is spread through close contact with blood, blood products or semen from infected persons. Its chief victims have been homosexual men and intravenous drug users.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880623-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-23-88 0237EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Drought-Exports     06-23 0653</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Drought-Exports,630</SECOND>
<HEAD>Drought Could Affect U.S. Export Prospects</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDS: Stands for PM-Farm Scene</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By DON KENDALL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Farm Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The drought that threatens <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> crop production also is sending shock waves through world markets and prospects for exports, according to <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> analysts. But it could be one of those `` good news, bad news'' situations, says <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Kay </PERSON>, administrator of the department's <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agricultural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>. `` There's no question that the higher commodity prices we see today will likely raise the value of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> exports,'' <PERSON> Kay </PERSON> said. `` On the other hand, you have to recognize that higher prices might reduce the total quantity traded.'' In other words, one bushel of wheat selling for $ 3 is worth as much as three bushels selling for $ 1 each. <PERSON> Kay </PERSON> and other <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> and farm officials contacted Wednesday agreed that it is too early for a realistic appraisal of the export situation. No one can be sure what this year's harvests of corn, wheat and soybeans will be, and until that is known, the global supply and price situation is mostly guesswork. The department's first overall crop production estimates of the season, including total wheat, corn and soybeans, will be released on Aug. 11. <PERSON> Kay </PERSON> said there `` could be a tendency for foreign buyers to want to increase nearby purchases to cover their future needs.'' And that could cause even further upward pressure on commodity prices. Are there indications now that foreign buyers might be getting leery of higher prices for <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> grain? `` No, there has n't been much activity of late in the international market,'' <PERSON> Kay </PERSON> said. `` Not much is being sold anywhere. There seems to be a general lull all over.'' So it's wait-and-see what the drought will do, at least for many foreign buyers. Meanwhile, the <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> has not revised its latest export forecast, which showed the value of shipments in the fiscal year that began last Oct. 1 could rise to $ 33.5 billion from $ 27.9 billion last season. The actual volume of products in the month-old forecast is expected to rise to 145.5 million metric tons from 129.2 million tons in 1986-87. Except for soybeans, which are in relatively scant supply, the inventories of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> wheat and corn are more than ample to take care of foreseeable export needs. The big question, which officials say ca n't be answered now, is how much 1988 crop production will be reduced and how far prices will increase. <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Drazek </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Farm </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federation </ORGANIZATION>'s <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> office agreed that export prospects are undecipherable at this point. `` Any time you have a drought of the apparent magnitude that this is, you have to start to be concerned about what it will do to our export volume,'' he said. `` My guess is that nobody quite knows what the effect will be on production, so it's going to be difficult to attach some kind of an estimate to the effect on exports.'' `` But with the price going up the way it is,'' <PERSON> Drazek </PERSON> continued, `` that alone will have a depressing effect on our ability to move products.'' Although there is a `` one-world market'' for some commodities, he said, `` our prices are going to be less competitive ... and that could have an effect on where people buy.'' <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Denman </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Farmers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION> said, `` The next couple of weeks are going to really make the determination as to what starts to happen in that export market.'' <PERSON> Denman </PERSON> said that he `` would n't be surprised'' to see some foreign buyers come back into the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> market for corn and other feed grains to protect themselves against further crop deterioration and even higher prices. Regarding wheat, <PERSON> Denman </PERSON> said that a lot will depend on the quality of this year's European harvest and also on <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>'s production `` It's not just in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>,'' he said. `` That Canadian crop, as I understand it, is really being hurt pretty bad, too.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880623-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-23-88 0239EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Democrats-Platform     06-23 0683</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Democrats-Platform,670</SECOND>
<HEAD>Democratic Party Panel To Review Platform Draft</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CHRISTOPHER CONNELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Democratic platform writers, borrowing a page from congressional procedures, are putting a preliminary draft into a format that a party panel can mark up when it resumes deliberations Friday in <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION>. The Democratic platform drafting committee, headed by Rep. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gray </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION>, has already distributed a draft document to the campaigns of <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Barnes </PERSON>, a former <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION> congressman serving as <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>'s chief link to the platform committee, said Wednesday, `` There will be a draft put before the members Friday morning.'' <PERSON> Barnes </PERSON> said the draft incorporates the dozen separate issue `` working papers'' produced at an earlier meeting of the platform writers on <LOCATION> Mackinac </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mich. </LOCATION> `` It pulls them all together,'' he said. But <PERSON> Barnes </PERSON> said there has been no closing of the gap between the <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> camps on whether the platform should embrace <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s call for higher taxes on the wealthy and a freeze on Pentagon spending. <PERSON> Rosemary </PERSON> <PERSON> Freeman </PERSON>, executive director of the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Platform </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, said the preliminary draft was still being finalized. She called it `` a collective effort'' by the same people who hammered out the earlier issue papers. The party released two final working papers on national security and political empowerment. The former reflects the <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> campaign's insistence that the platform call for `` stable'' defense budgets; the latter, in a nod to <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, commits the party to removing `` impediments to the one-person, one-vote principle.'' Whatever emerges Friday from <PERSON> Gray </PERSON>'s 16-member drafting committee will be subject to further discussion and revision when the full 186-member <ORGANIZATION> Platform </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> meets over the weekend in <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION> for the first time. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> has enough delegates to force a floor fight at next month's <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Convention </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> over any platform issue he chooses. Some <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> backers have hinted they would welcome a chance to shoot down a plank promising a tax hike. <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> Mondale </PERSON>, the 1984 nominee, got nothing but grief from his promise to raise taxes. <PERSON> Gray </PERSON>, the chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Budget </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, has had his staff put the draft in mark-up format, with numbered lines, to make it easier for the drafting committee to make additions and deletions. Although a <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> supporter, <PERSON> Gray </PERSON> has been handling his drafting role in an impartial fashion. The 16 members include six each from the <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> camps and four appointed by <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kirk </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, the party chairman, who has asked the platform writers to produce a short, visionary statement, free of special interest boilerplates. The new working paper on national security says the nation's strength has been `` sapped by a defense establishment that has wasted money on duplicative and dubious new weapons instead of investing more in readiness and mobility. `` We further believe that our strength is enhanced by stable defense budgets and by a commitment by our allies to assure their fair share of the costs and responsibilities required to maintain peace and liberty,'' the paper says. It says the Democrats `` will promote peace and prevent war _ not by trading weapons for hostages, not by sending brave Americans to undefined missions in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION> ... not by toasting a tyrant like <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> as a disciple of democracy, but by maintaining a stable nuclear deterrent sufficient to counter any <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> threat, in standing up to any <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> adversary whenever necessary and sitting down with him whenever possible.'' The document calls for `` maintaining the special relationship with <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>,'' while promoting a <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> agreement that hews to the Camp David Accords. It says a Democratic administration would `` end all vestiges of the failed policy of constructive engagement and will declare <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> a terrorist state -LRB- and -RRB- impose comprehensive sanctions.'' The paper would commit the party to same-day voter registration and registration by mail and calls for a removal of `` impedidents to the one-person, one-vote principle,'' it said. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, who won 29 percent of the primary votes but just 24 percent of the delegates, has complained about the way some states allocated delegates.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880623-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-23-88 0242EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Iran-Contra     06-23 0795</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Iran-Contra,780</SECOND>
<HEAD>Classified Documents Ruling Indicates Fall Trial for North</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JAMES ROWLEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The judge in the Iran-Contra conspiracy case is setting up procedures for dealing with classified documents in an apparent effort to bring fired <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> aide <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> North </PERSON> to trial by fall. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> Gerhard </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gesell </PERSON> ordered North to identify by July 11 which secret government documents the retired <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> lieutenant colonel wants to disclose in court to rebut charges that he illegally diverted Iranian arms-sale profits to the Nicaraguan rebels. In a ruling on Wednesday, <PERSON> Gesell </PERSON> said that both the public and prosecutors would be barred from a July 14 hearing to determine if any of the documents are relevant to the case against <PERSON> North </PERSON>. The judge also rejected a defense motion to declare the Classified Information Procedures Act unconstitutional as it applied to the case of North, former national security adviser <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Poindexter </PERSON> and arms dealers <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Hakim </PERSON> and <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> V. </PERSON> <PERSON> Secord </PERSON>. The four defendants, whom <PERSON> Gesell </PERSON> has said must be tried separately, contended that the law unfairly required them to tell the prosecution what documents they intended to make public before the trials. Such disclosures would give independent counsel <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Walsh </PERSON> an unfair tactical advantage, the defense said. Acknowledging the problem, <PERSON> Gesell </PERSON> said `` strict application of the statute to this proceeding would not only be difficult, but impossible to accomplish consistent with a fair and expeditious resolution of this case.'' <PERSON> Gesell </PERSON> noted that the large volume of classified documents collected by <PERSON> Walsh </PERSON>'s investigation about 200,000 pages by the latest count _ posed unique problems for a trial judge that were probably not envisioned when <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> passed the classified information statute in 1980. `` Some of the witnesses and defendants, particularly <PERSON> North </PERSON>, operated from secure locations in the White House with full access to the most sensitive information and most critical national security intelligence methods and sources available to the government,'' <PERSON> Gesell </PERSON> said. `` This information, and even some methods and sources, are inextricably enmeshed in the events challenged by the indictment,'' he added. But in enacting the law, <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> gave trial judges authority `` to fashion creative and fair solutions'' to difficult problems posed by such sensitive information, <PERSON> Gesell </PERSON> said. Lawmakers `` emphasized that the court should not undertake to balance the national security interests of the government against the rights of the defendant but rather that in the end remedies and sanctions against the government must be designed to make the defendant whole again.'' `` While afforded this leeway, the court is unable to determine definitively at this stage whether or not the classified document problems presented by this case can be resolved,'' <PERSON> Gesell </PERSON> said in the 16-page opinion. `` It proposes to make the effort, but the complexity of the situation defies obvious answers. Final ruling on the -LRB- defense -RRB- motion must await further developments.'' <PERSON> Gesell </PERSON> said that he would exclude <PERSON> Walsh </PERSON> from discussions of whether classified documents that <PERSON> North </PERSON> proposes to disclose are relevant to the case. <PERSON> Gesell </PERSON> will decide which documents are relevant and admissible as evidence. Only after an interdepartmental task force has identified relevant documents that pose national security problems will <PERSON> Walsh </PERSON> be included in the process of how to present them in court, <PERSON> Gesell </PERSON> said. Indicating a desire to move the case to trial, <PERSON> Gesell </PERSON> gave the government secrecy experts until Aug. 1 to complete their review of the documents identified by North. The task force, composed of representatives of various government intelligence agencies, is reviewing the documents that <PERSON> Walsh </PERSON> collected during his investigation from the <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>. After the panel's task is completed, <PERSON> Gesell </PERSON> said he would convene closed hearings to determine how to edit out portions of documents that can not be declassified. Under the law, the court has the power to order deletions of sensitive material or to substitute a statement of facts that the document would prove if it were shown to the jury. If a sufficient number of documents can not be disclosed in any fashion, the court can dismiss charges against a defendant on the ground he could not get a fair trial. <PERSON> Gesell </PERSON>'s ruling follows his determination last week that <PERSON> Walsh </PERSON>'s investigation was not tainted by impermissible use of the testimony that <PERSON> North </PERSON>, <PERSON> Poindexter </PERSON> and <PERSON> Hakim </PERSON> gave to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> last year under limited grants of immunity from prosecution Both decisions indicate that <PERSON> Gesell </PERSON> has determined that, barring unforeseen problems created by classified documents, the case can move ahead to trial by September. In a statement, <PERSON> Walsh </PERSON> said: `` We appreciate the court's prompt ruling on the constitutionality of the Classified Information Procedures Act as it applies to this case and we are prepared to move forward as directed by the court.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880623-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-23-88 0249EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     06-23 0623</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0650</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in The News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Ballet superstar <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> Baryshnikov </PERSON> has canceled a nationwide tour to undergo surgery for an aggravated knee condition, his spokesman said. <PERSON> Baryshnikov </PERSON>, artistic director of the American Ballet Theater, had scheduled 28 dance performances of his own, from <LOCATION> Arlington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, on July 1 to <LOCATION> Columbus </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, on Aug. 7, said spokesman <PERSON> Bernie </PERSON> <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> on Wednesday. The surgery, to correct an aggravated condition of his knee, will be performed in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, possibly Tuesday, said <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON>, who would not give identify the hospital. `` The subsequent recovery period will be determined by the findings at surgery,'' said a statement by <PERSON> Baryshnikov </PERSON>'s publicist, <PERSON> Edgar </PERSON> <PERSON> Vincent </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Flamboyant pop singer will <PERSON> Cyndi </PERSON> <PERSON> Lauper </PERSON> will sing the praise of education next week when she receives a belated high school diploma. <PERSON> Lauper </PERSON> will get her sheepskin along with the 400 graduates of <ORGANIZATION> Richmond </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hill </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> High </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Queens </LOCATION> at Monday's ceremonies, school officials said Wednesday. <PERSON> Lauper </PERSON>, whose hits include `` Girls Just Wan na Have Fun'' and `` True Colors,'' dropped out of the high school several years ago, said her publicist, <PERSON> Robin </PERSON> <PERSON> Riggs </PERSON>. After getting her diploma, <PERSON> Lauper </PERSON> will address the class on the importance of education, <PERSON> Riggs </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Lauper </PERSON> already has a high-school equivalency diploma.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LENOX, Mass. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Friends of conductor <PERSON> Leonard </PERSON> <PERSON> Bernstein </PERSON> have orchestrated a birthday bash to include appearances by <PERSON> Beverly </PERSON> <PERSON> Sills </PERSON>, <PERSON> Lauren </PERSON> <PERSON> Bacall </PERSON>, <PERSON> Betty </PERSON> <PERSON> Comden </PERSON> and <PERSON> Phyllis </PERSON> <PERSON> Newman </PERSON>. The <PERSON> Leonard </PERSON> <PERSON> Bernstein </PERSON> Gala Birthday Performance is a benefit concert set for the composer's 70th birthday, Aug. 25, to raise money for the <ORGANIZATION> Berkshire </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Music </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> at <LOCATION> Tanglewood </LOCATION>, where <PERSON> Bernstein </PERSON> got his conducting start. Miss <PERSON> Sills </PERSON> will be host of the event that will include performances by the <ORGANIZATION> Boston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Symphony </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Orchestra </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Boston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pops </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Orchestra </ORGANIZATION> and the Tanglewood Festival Chorus. The concert plans to celebrate <PERSON> Bernstein </PERSON>'s accomplishments in popular music with excerpts from his `` West Side Story,'' `` On the Town'' and others.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Sylvester </PERSON> <PERSON> Stallone </PERSON> has filed a $ 3 million lawsuit against <ORGANIZATION> Colt </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Industries </ORGANIZATION>, alleging a photograph and caption in Guns Magazine falsely implied he endorsed a Colt handgun. In the <ORGANIZATION> Superior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> lawsuit filed here, <PERSON> Stallone </PERSON> claims a <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION> advertising agency hired by <PERSON> Colt </PERSON> contacted his agent asking to use his name and photograph to promote a 45.-caliber, $ 1,500 pistol called the Heirloom gun. The lawsuit, filed Friday, said <PERSON> Stallone </PERSON> refused, and after that, Colt requested a bogus article to be placed in the magazine with an accompanying photograph of Colt's fake Heirloom gun firearm with <PERSON> Stallone </PERSON>'s name inscribed on the barrel. The picture printed in the July 1987 issue shows the actor, the gun and a caption saying `` <PERSON> Sylvester </PERSON> <PERSON> Stallone </PERSON>'s personal Colt Heirloom gun.'' `` We have no comment on the lawsuit or firearm in question,'' <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Williamson </PERSON>, spokesman for New York-based <ORGANIZATION> Colt </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Industries </ORGANIZATION>, said Wednesday. Guns Magazine is not a defendant. The star of such action-packed films as `` Rocky'' and `` Rambo'' said his reputation and the market value of his name were damaged and he should receive profits Colt unfairly gained from them.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>MILWAUKEE (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Berenger </PERSON> and <PERSON> Charlie </PERSON> <PERSON> Sheen </PERSON> will hit the diamond at the <LOCATION> Milwaukee </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Stadium </LOCATION> to slug it out in motion picture called `` Major League,'' according to the movie's producer. The movie will chronicle the exploits of the <ORGANIZATION> Cleveland </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Indians </ORGANIZATION>, with <ORGANIZATION> Milwaukee </ORGANIZATION> doubling as <LOCATION> Cleveland </LOCATION>, said producer <PERSON> Irby </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> on Wednesday, after selecting <ORGANIZATION> Milwaukee </ORGANIZATION> as the filming site. The 50-member film crew starts work July 25 and is expected to continue through September. The <ORGANIZATION> Milwaukee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Brewers </ORGANIZATION> are planning to move out of the 35-year-old County Stadium. <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> decided on the spot after scouting <LOCATION> Midwest </LOCATION> locations, saying the city and the stadium were well suited to the independent production.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880623-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-23-88 0251EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Taxes     06-23 0599</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Taxes,590</SECOND>
<HEAD>Panel Wants Two Special Tax Breaks Back in Law</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JIM LUTHER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Tax Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 House tax-writers want to renew two targeted benefits of the type that were supposed to be wiped out when the tax law was overhauled in 1986. The <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ways </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Means </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> agreed Wednesday to renew for three years a tax benefit for employees who receive educational assistance from their bosses, and to extend for one year a special credit for owners of low-income rental housing. The panel, working on a package of miscellaneous tax items proposed by Chairman <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Rostenkowski </PERSON>, D-Ill., is considering extension of a third special benefit: tax-exempt mortgage bonds used to help low-income people buying their first home That exemption is a favorite of state and local government officials, who administer the mortgage assistance. The <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Accounting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION>, the auditing arm of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, says the program `` does little to increase home ownership opportunities.'' About $ 50 billion of such bonds were issued between 1982 and 1986, at a cost to the federal government of about $ 7.5 billion, <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION> estimated. About two-thirds of the homebuyers who benefited could have bought their homes without assistance, the agency said. <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> wiped out several such special-interest benefits when it revised the tax law two years ago, contending that the tax system should not be used to provide subsidies when federal appropriations could do the job better. But several still remain. The committee hopes to complete work next week on this year's tax bill, which is designed mainly to correct hundreds of errors that found their way into the 1986 law The `` technical corrections'' bill is being used as the vehicle for a few substantive tax amendments, including those proposed by <PERSON> Rostenkowski </PERSON>. The committee, meeting behind closed doors, voted Wednesday to: _ Tighten and renew through 1990 an expired law under which employees could avoid tax on up to $ 5,250 a year worth of educational assistance provided by their employers The benefit was designed to help lower-income workers prepare for better jobs. Under the new version, the exclusion would be reduced as income rises above a level that is yet to be determined, and upper-income workers would receive no benefit. No benefit would be available for post-graduate work. The <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration opposes renewal of the exclusion, which would cost the government about $ 540 million. _ Extend for one year the credit for owners of low-income rental housing, which is due to expire at the end of 1989 This would cost $ 543 million. _ Write into law an <ORGANIZATION> Internal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Revenue </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> decision that sick pay, accumulated vacation leave and similar compensation received by employees of state and local governments and non-profit organizations should not be taxed when earned _ Exempt from Social Security taxes the wages of members of Amish and other religious sects that have religious objections to such programs Committee aides estimated this would affect about 10,000 workers; about 750 self-employed people _ most of them <LOCATION> Amish </LOCATION> _ already are exempt. _ Deny Social Security benefits to any person who in the future is ordered deported as a Nazi war criminal _ Exempt from taxation a $ 10-million trust fund created in 1985 to finance rehabilitation of <LOCATION> Enjebi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> in the <ORGANIZATION> Enewetak </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Atoll </ORGANIZATION>, which the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> used as a target for testing nuclear weapons in the 1940s and 1950s A similar exemption was voted in 1982 for the benefit of <LOCATION> Bikini </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION>. The biggest portion of the tax increase required to pay for the benefits in the bill would come from corporations that own shares of other corporations and from owners of single-premium life insurance.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880623-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-23-88 0253EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-ScotusRdp     06-23 0574</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Scotus Rdp,560</SECOND>
<HEAD>Supreme Court Blocks Billions in Pension Payments</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JAMES H. RUBIN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 State and local governments and other private employers have received some welcome news from the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> in a decision that could save them billions of dollars in pension benefits. The court on Wednesday used a case from <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> to limit the application of two previous rulings, which bar sex discrimination, in determining retirement benefits. `` We're very happy and very pleased,'' said <PERSON> Andy </PERSON> <PERSON> McMullian </PERSON>, director of <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>'s division of retirement. `` We really thought they would rule in our favor all along and that's why we took it to the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>.'' By a 5-4 vote, the justices said <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> taxpayers do not have to pay $ 43.6 million to male state workers who retired between March 24, 1972, and Aug. 1, 1983. The court said that it would be unfair to retroactively apply the anti-discrimination principles the court first established in a 1978 ruling and greatly expanded in 1983. Imposing such extra costs on pension plans would threaten their existence and, therefore, the rights of other workers to collect benefits, the court said. A <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> study estimates that the ruling will save public and private employers nationwide from $ 817 million to $ 1.26 billion a year well into the next century. The court in 1978 barred employers from requiring women to make higher contributions to pension plans based on their generally longer lifespans, even though as a group they receive more retirement benefits as a result. In 1983, the court made it illegal for women to receive smaller monthly retirement pay than men based on life expectancy when employees of both sexes contributed equal amounts. That ruling took effect Aug. 1, 1983. Both pension benefit rulings were based on the Civil Rights Act of 1964 banning sex discrimination in the work place. Until Wednesday, the court had not said whether the sex-neutral principles it established in the pension cases apply to a vast number of workers who retired sometime between 1964 and 1983. The justices said Wednesday that employers, such as the <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> government, should not be penalized for failing to eliminate all sex-based pension options after the court's 1978 ruling. That decision failed to place employers on notice that all pension options taking gender into account were illegal, the court said. Some options in the <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> state retirement plan continued to use sex-based mortality rates until 1983. The state was sued by male workers on behalf of themselves and their wives, who also were beneficiaries of the pension plan. They said their benefits were reduced illegally because of the use of the sex-based life expectancy figures. Lower courts ruled in their favor and ordered the state to pay an additional $ 43.6 million in benefits to them. In other decisions, the court: _ Upheld by a 6-3 vote the way <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> courts administer that state's death penalty law, dashing the hopes of about 260 death row inmates _ Split 5-4 in upholding an <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION> man's murder conviction and death sentence even though the presiding judge wrongly refused to exclude one potential juror The juror was disqualified when the defendant's lawyer used one of the defense's limited number of automatic challenges. _ Ruled, 8-1, in a case from <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION> that federal judges may not throw out an indictment because of a prosecutor's misconduct unless the defendant can show there would have been no indictment without such misconduct
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880623-0025 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-23-88 0254EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Congress-DrugTesting     06-23 0469</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Congress-Drug Testing,460</SECOND>
<HEAD>House Panel Approves Drug and Alcohol Testing For Rail Workers</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ALAN FRAM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
