<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880514-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-14-88 0042EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-AngolaSouthAfrica     05-14 0397</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Angola South Africa,0410</SECOND>
<HEAD>Both Sides Say Second Round of Talks Made Progress</HEAD>
<BYLINE>BY ROBERT WELLER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BRAZZAVILLE, Congo (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Both sides reported progress at the second round of South Africa-Angola talks which ended Friday and said the talks would lead to further meetings soon involving the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION>. The governments are seeking an end to conflicts in southern <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> that include a civil war in Marxist <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION> and a war for independence in <LOCATION> South-West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>, also known as <LOCATION> Namibia </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>'s foreign minister, <PERSON> Roelof </PERSON> <PERSON> Botha </PERSON>, said, `` I hope that what we have started would one day be rewarded with peace, stability and prosperity for the whole of southern <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>. `` We are both agreed that there can be no military solution for our continent and in particular for southern <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>.'' The South African delegation was exuberant and clearly considered its reception in this socialist nation a triumph. <PERSON> Botha </PERSON> exchanged gifts with Foreign Minister <PERSON> Antoine </PERSON> <PERSON> Ndinga-Oba </PERSON> of the <LOCATION> Congo </LOCATION> before leaving for home. Congolese sources said <PERSON> Botha </PERSON> met privately with President <PERSON> Denis </PERSON> <PERSON> Sassou </PERSON> <PERSON> Nguesso </PERSON>, one of the continent's most vocal opponents of apartheid, <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>'s policy of racial separation. The sources spoke on condition of anonymity. Justice Minister <PERSON> Fernando </PERSON> <PERSON> Van-Dunem </PERSON> led <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION>'s delegation. `` We do know what each other wants and we cleared our stance,'' he said. Angolan and South African officials said <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Cuban </LOCATION> diplomats would attend the next session of talks. Both nations attended talks last week in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> aimed at a regional peace settlement. The <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> administration seeks withdrawal of an estimated 40,000 Cuban soldiers from <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> says its forces are there to help <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION> fend off South African incursions. Rebels who have been fighting a guerrilla war for 13 years, seeking to overthrow the Angolan government, are supported by the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> South-West </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Africa </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION>, or <ORGANIZATION> SWAPO </ORGANIZATION>, also is fighting a bush war trying to force <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> to leave <LOCATION> South-West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>, commonly known as <LOCATION> Namibia </LOCATION>, and for <LOCATION> Namibia </LOCATION> to become independent. Friday's four-hour talks were held in a small, government-owned villa and ended on a cordial note with each side thanking the other for its frankness. By law and custom, apartheid establishes a racially segregated society in which the 26 million blacks have no vote in national affairs. The 5 million whites control the economy and maintain separate districts, schools and health services.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880514-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-14-88 0042EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w AM-MalpracticeAward     05-14 0341</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Malpractice Award,340</SECOND>
<HEAD>Jury Awards $10 Million to Brain-Damaged Boy</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A federal jury awarded $ 10 million Friday to a <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> child who suffered irreversible brain damage during birth. The four-man, two-woman <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> jury decided on the award after hearing testimony that three doctors named in the case did not act quickly when tests indicated the baby's heart rate was slowing. <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Olender </PERSON>, attorney for 3-year-old <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Leahy </PERSON>, <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, said he believed it was the largest medical malpractice award ever in the <LOCATION> District </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Olender </PERSON> said obstetricians <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Newman </PERSON>, <PERSON> Julian </PERSON> <PERSON> Safran </PERSON>, and <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> Horwitz </PERSON> performed an emergency caesarian section delivery about four hours after problems were first noticed. The operation was not conducted in time to prevent the child from suffering irreversible brain damage, <PERSON> Olender </PERSON> said. `` He's unable to walk, talk, or feed himself,'' said <PERSON> Olender </PERSON>. `` Everything has to be done for him.'' The judgment is about $ 6 million dollars greater than the malpractice insurance policy held by the doctors, who are in partnership. The child's parents, <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> and <PERSON> Patricia </PERSON> <PERSON> Leahy </PERSON> of <LOCATION> McLean </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, will receive no compensation in the award, <PERSON> Olender </PERSON> said. Instead, the money will be placed in a trust fund under court approval and used for the child's care. Attorneys for the doctors did not say whether an appeal of the verdict or award is planned. Problems in the birth arose around 4 a.m. on Dec. 11, 1984, when an electronic fetal monitor indicated that the child's heart rate was slowing, <PERSON> Olender </PERSON> told the court. In such cases, a declining heart rate often indicates a shortage of oxygen, usually resulting from a pinching of the umbilical cord, and emergency caesarian section deliveries are usually performed as soon as the problem is discovered, <PERSON> Olender </PERSON> asserted. The emergency operation did not take place until 9:15 a.m. <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Women </ORGANIZATION> _ the <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION> hospital where the birth took place _ originally was named in the suit, but was dropped from the case when it agreed to pay $ 800,000 in a settlement.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880514-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-14-88 0134EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Publisher-Holocaust     05-14 0371</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Publisher-Holocaust,0383</SECOND>
<HEAD>Publisher Gets Nine-Month Sentence For Printing Statements Denying
Holocaust</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TORONTO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A publisher convicted in a retrial of maliciously publishing statements denying the Holocaust was sentenced Friday to nine months in jail. <PERSON> Ernst </PERSON> <PERSON> Zundel </PERSON>, 49, arrived at the district courthouse bearing a small coffin inscribed with the words `` Free Speech is Dead.'' After his 1985 conviction he went to his sentencing carring a heavy wooden cross, also signifying the demise of freedom of speech in <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>. As in his earlier conviction, <PERSON> Zundel </PERSON> is seeking to appeal his sentence and jury conviction and has applied for bail to keep him out of jail at least until his appeal can be considered. But he had to start the weekend behind bars awaiting a bail decision. The West German immigrant won his first appeal and was granted a new trial in district court that ended in the second conviction. <PERSON> Zundel </PERSON>, who operates <ORGANIZATION> Samisdat </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Publishers </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Toronto </LOCATION>, was charged under a law forbidding publication of statements known to be false or likely to cause injury or mischief to the public interest. <PERSON> Zundel </PERSON> was charged with publishing a booklet _ which he did not write _ that denies official accounts of Nazis exterminating Jews in wartime prison camps. The booklet says the horror stories about the Holocaust were all a hoax and a fraudulent scheme by Zionists to extract financial reparation from postwar <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>. However, Judge <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> took judicial notice of the Holocaust at the beginning of the trial, recognizing it as a historical fact. From then on, <PERSON> Zundel </PERSON>'s essential defense was that he honestly believed the contents of the pamphlet and was not knowingly spreading false news, as the charge alleged. Jewish leaders were happy with the verdict, saying it would serve to protect ethnic minorities from social intolerance. The Canadian Jewish <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> said it `` demonstrates that Canadians will not tolerate the vilification of ethnological communities. `` It reaffirms the effectiveness of the Criminal Code in upholding social and racial harmony,'' group officials said. B'nai B'rith <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> expressed confidence the outcome `` will serve to deter hatemongers, no matter who their targets may be, from pursuing their aim of dividing Canadian society and turning some of us against our fellow citizens.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880514-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-14-88 0151EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-WrongRaid     05-14 0275</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Wrong Raid,0284</SECOND>
<HEAD>Police `Sorry' For Raiding Wrong House</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEWARK, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Police blamed a bad tip from an informant for the mistaken drug raid that left a family frightened and sent the father to a hospital with multiple cuts and bruises. `` These people are the victims of a tragic set of circumstances,'' <ORGANIZATION> Newark </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION> Chief <PERSON> Ken </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> said Thursday. A police informant pointed out the <PERSON> Kim </PERSON> apartment as a place where narcotics had been dealt, <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Bok </PERSON> <PERSON> Hwan </PERSON> <PERSON> Kim </PERSON>, 49, said he was alone Tuesday in the living room of the apartment he shares with his wife, three daughters and 78-year-old mother-in-law when police arrived outside his door. Seven or eight members of the three-department <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Alameda </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Narcotics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Enforcement </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Team </ORGANIZATION> swarmed into the house, put a gun to <PERSON> Kim </PERSON>'s head and wrestled him to the floor, <PERSON> Kim </PERSON> said. Attorney <PERSON> Shawn </PERSON> <PERSON> Steel </PERSON> said he plans to file a $ 1 million claim against the city, the first step in filing a lawsuit. <PERSON> Kim </PERSON>, who was treated at a hospital for cuts and bruises about the face, said the officers grabbed his wife, <PERSON> Jung </PERSON> <PERSON> Ja </PERSON> <PERSON> Kim </PERSON>, handcuffed her and forced her to lie on the floor. Police have apologized to the family for the raid. The officers ransacked the house for more than a half-hour before realizing they were not in the home of drug dealers, <PERSON> Kim </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> disagreed, and said he believed that the officers did not search the apartment beyond `` determining who was in the apartment.'' `` It is my understanding,'' <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> said, `` that shortly after entering the building they realized they must have gotten bad information and immediately backed off.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880514-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-14-88 0000EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-Prom-DivorcedMen     05-13 0347</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Prom-Divorced Men,0361</SECOND>
<HEAD>Divorced Prom Escort Arrested On Charges Of Trespassing</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SMITHVILLE, Tenn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A divorced man who defied a principal's prohibition against escorting a high school student to her prom was promptly arrested on trespassing charges after arriving with his date Friday <PERSON> Troy </PERSON> <PERSON> Cripps </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>, dressed in a black tuxedo, was taken into custody at the <ORGANIZATION> Dekalb </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> High </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> prom after arriving with 18-year-old <PERSON> Tammy </PERSON> <PERSON> Sliger </PERSON>, said <LOCATION> Dekalb </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> sheriff's Deputy <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>. <PERSON> Cripps </PERSON>, 23, was freed on $ 250 bond, <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> said. He was scheduled to appear in court May 25. Circuit Court Judge <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Maddux </PERSON> had ruled earlier Friday that the school board and <PERSON> Principal </PERSON> <PERSON> Ernest </PERSON> <PERSON> Ray </PERSON> could bar <PERSON> Cripps </PERSON> from escorting Sliger to the dance. <PERSON> Ray </PERSON> had barred four divorced men from the prom after receiving an anonymous letter threatening `` trouble'' if they were allowed to attend, said school Superintendent <PERSON> Aubrey </PERSON> <PERSON> Turner </PERSON>. `` We felt that it was probably from one of the divorced wives, saying they did n't feel the school should let this type of thing occur,'' he said. `` There was a threat as far as just causing a disturbance.'' <PERSON> Sliger </PERSON> and <PERSON> Laura </PERSON> <PERSON> Lea </PERSON> <PERSON> Cooper </PERSON>, 17, asked the court for a restraining order, arguing that that school officials were discriminating against their dates because of age and marital status, said <PERSON> Carolyn </PERSON> <PERSON> Todd </PERSON>, <PERSON> Sliger </PERSON>'s mother. `` She's just crushed and her feelings were hurt so bad,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Todd </PERSON> said after the court ruling. <PERSON> Turner </PERSON> conceded that the fact that the four men were divorced may have disturbed some school officials. `` I ca n't say that that was n't a factor, that might be a secondary factor because that gets into morals,'' he said. `` The primary factor was that there might be some problems, we have to ensure a safe environment for their prom.'' Mrs. <PERSON> Todd </PERSON> said that divorced people had been allowed to attend the prom in the past and that school officials overreacted to the anonymous letter. `` If they can keep people from going to the prom, then they can keep people who write a threatening letter from coming into the prom,'' she said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880514-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-14-88 0128EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-AIDS-Education 1stLd-Writethru a0798 05-14 0486</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-AIDS-Education, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0798,0496</SECOND>
<HEAD>CDC and Teachers Open Conference on AIDS Education</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: LEADS with four grafs to ADD NEA membership; PICKS UP 4th
graf pvs, `The role ...'</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT BYRD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ATLANTA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Centers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Disease </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Control </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> the </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Education </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> launched their first joint conference on AIDS and education Friday with a focus on showing teachers how to teach about the deadly disease. The three-day conference, expected to draw 100 educators from around the country, is the latest event in what <ORGANIZATION> NEA </ORGANIZATION> President <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Hatwood </PERSON> <PERSON> Futrell </PERSON> described as her association's `` all-out war against AIDS.'' `` We are going to work with our members to determine what we can do as an organization to raise the consciousness level of the members of our profession,'' said Ms. <PERSON> Futtrell </PERSON>. The NEA is the nation's largest teacher union, with 1.9 million members. `` The role of a teacher is a especially critical in dealing with young people,'' she said. `` Children trust their teachers and they will go to their teachers for information. We must have factual information and know how to respond to young people.'' Ms. <PERSON> Futrell </PERSON> added she hopes the conference will spur action on AIDS education. `` We do n't think we can wait five years,'' she said. `` We need to begin to talk to young people now about changing their behavior so they do n't get the disease.'' Friday's keynote speaker was <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Washburn </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, an AIDS patient who is retired superintendent of the <ORGANIZATION> Brighton </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> near <LOCATION> Rochester </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION> `` We've got a mission,'' <PERSON> Washburn </PERSON> said in an interview before his address. `` The kids in our high schools are going to bear the brunt of this disease and they're going to bear the cost.'' <PERSON> Washburn </PERSON>, 48, was diagnosed last spring with AIDS and disclosed his illness in January, when he embarked on a series of appearances and speeches to educate high school and college students and teachers about the disease. `` Exploit me,'' said <PERSON> Washburn </PERSON>. `` My time is limited. I want to be exploited by whoever can use me to put windows on what is now happening with AIDS and what is likely to happen. `` My years in public school work have groomed me. ... I'm not embarrassed by the questions,'' said <PERSON> Washburn </PERSON>, who is homosexual. Other participants in the conference include researchers and officials of the Atlanta-based <ORGANIZATION> CDC </ORGANIZATION>. Discussion will include ways to incorporate AIDS education into the school curriculum. The <ORGANIZATION> NEA </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> CDC </ORGANIZATION>'s parent agency, the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>, are members of the <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Information </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Network </ORGANIZATION>, created in 1987 in an AIDS education effort. Last fall, the network distributed 1.9 million copies of a handbook for teachers on AIDS. AIDS has struck 973 <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> children under age 13; of those, 566 have died, according to the <ORGANIZATION> CDC </ORGANIZATION>. In all, AIDS has struck more than 61,000 people in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, killing more than 34,000 of them.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880514-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-14-88 0158EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-TaxesSimplified Bjt   05-14 0598</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Taxes Simplified, Bjt,600</SECOND>
<HEAD>IRS Says It Welcomes Suggestions From Students</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JIM LUTHER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Tax Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Internal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Revenue </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> is promising that next year's tax returns will be a little easier to understand, thanks in part to a handful of college students. The students, working through the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Akron </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Taxation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Studies </ORGANIZATION>, told a <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> subcommittee earlier this year that tax forms and the instructions for filling them out can be made simpler. They took their recommendations to the <ORGANIZATION> IRS </ORGANIZATION> Friday and the <ORGANIZATION> IRS </ORGANIZATION> was impressed. `` We intend to look at the result of their wrestling with the instructions, of our wrestling, and then use the best of both,'' said <PERSON> Arthur </PERSON> <PERSON> Altman </PERSON>, chairman of the agency's forms committee. `` It's a friendly effort,'' he added. `` There's going to be good come out of it.'' <PERSON> Nicholas </PERSON> <PERSON> Creme </PERSON>, director of the taxation center in northeast <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, agreed. `` The 1040EZ and the 1040A should be a lot easier and understandable come next January,'' he said. Students at the center, who help low-income taxpayers facing <ORGANIZATION> IRS </ORGANIZATION> penalties, were spurred on by a study showing that more than half of Americans can not understand the instructions for the simplest tax form, the 1040EZ. They tackled first the instructions for the 1040EZ and the 1040A, and presented these recommendations Friday. By July 1 they hope to complete their proposed revisions of those two tax forms. Later, they want to rewrite thusands of pages of tax regulations and publications that are used by lawyers and other tax professionals. <PERSON> Altman </PERSON> and leaders of the student effort met for more than an hour Friday. `` It's a terrific experience to work with folks outside our organization and give them an opportunity to stand in our shoes,'' <PERSON> Altman </PERSON> said. He acknowledged, however, that `` We still have a long way to go.'' <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Nye </PERSON>, an <LOCATION> Akron </LOCATION> law student, praised the <ORGANIZATION> IRS </ORGANIZATION> for its interest in the effort. `` Many people do n't realize the problems of taking new tax laws and converting them into readable instructions,'' he said. `` We're interested in getting a real good product for the taxpayers.'' <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Ray </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Carnegie-Mellon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> graduate student who is serving as design consultant for the project, called it `` the type of work we live for _ to take a document and see what it really means, what the people really need to know.'' The bulk of the suggestions for cleaning up the tax instructions dealt with format and layout. One of the key suggestions was that a final checklist be included in the instructions, since the <ORGANIZATION> IRS </ORGANIZATION> acknowledges that most penalties are imposed because of mathematical errors. Another urged that the instructions be written alongside the tax forms; another called for fewer words and more white space on each page. The students also urged that the tone of the instructions be made more friendly, by generous use of the word `` please.'' They called for elimination of most of the multisyllable words and of double and triple negatives. As an example of how the wording can be cleaned up, the students pointed to a sentence in the instructions aimed at taxpayers who do n't get home-delivered mail. The instructions now read: `` If your post office does not deliver mail to your street address and you have a post office box, enter your post office box number on the line for your personal home address instead of your street address.'' The students' suggestion: `` If your mail is not delivered to your home, and you have a post office box number, put that number in the place of your street address.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880514-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-14-88 0149EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     05-14 0753</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0789</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in the News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>FREEHOLD, N.J. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A judge ordered actor <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Toole </PERSON> to return his 5-year-old son to a former girlfriend by Tuesday or face fines and possible arrest. <ORGANIZATION> Monmouth </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Superior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> Judge <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON> <PERSON> Lehrer </PERSON> issued the order Friday after <PERSON> Raoul </PERSON> <PERSON> Felder </PERSON>, an attorney for <PERSON> Karen </PERSON> <PERSON> Sommerville </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Toole </PERSON>, requested an arrest order because <PERSON> O'Toole </PERSON> had not returned his son, <PERSON> Lorcan </PERSON>, by a May 7 deadline. <PERSON> O'Toole </PERSON> and his former girlfriend, a <LOCATION> Navesink </LOCATION> resident who has taken the 55-year-old actor's name but never married him, have joint custody of the boy. Last December, they agreed to switch custody of <PERSON> Lorcan </PERSON> every three months until September 1989, when they hope to reach a long-term agreement. <PERSON> O'Toole </PERSON> took <PERSON> Lorcan </PERSON> to <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> in February. His attorney, <PERSON> Jeffrey </PERSON> <PERSON> Weinstein </PERSON>, said <PERSON> O'Toole </PERSON> held on to the boy because Ms. <PERSON> Somerville </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Toole </PERSON> violated the custody agreement by firing <PERSON> Lorcan </PERSON>'s nanny. `` <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> was acting ... in the interests of <PERSON> Lorcan </PERSON>,'' <PERSON> Weinstein </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Lehrer </PERSON> scheduled a hearing on the custody case for June 14. <PERSON> O'Toole </PERSON> faces $ 1,000 a day in fines if he does not comply with the order, <PERSON> Felder </PERSON> and <PERSON> Weinstein </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>ORLANDO, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Comedian <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Hope </PERSON> says he's planning to build a museum and entertainment complex near here featuring mementoes from 50 years in show business. The complex will be built on 80 acres that <PERSON> Hope </PERSON> owns near <LOCATION> Walt </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Disney </LOCATION> <LOCATION> World </LOCATION>, the 85-year-old entertainer said Friday. `` It's going to have all my memorabilia and movies from the past 50 years,'' <PERSON> Hope </PERSON> told WESH-TV in an interview from <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>. Details on a design and an opening date have not been worked out, <PERSON> Hope </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>MOSCOW (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actor-director <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Redford </PERSON> has been keeping busy during his journey to the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. On Friday, he announced that Soviet scientists would attend a conference on ecology this fall at the <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Resource </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Management </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> in </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sundance </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION>, which he founded. He also said two Soviet movie makers would visit his <ORGANIZATION> Sundance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Independent </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Filmmakers </ORGANIZATION> next year to meet with <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> counterparts. <PERSON> Redford </PERSON> said the agreements resulted from meetings in the past four days with prominent members of both professions. <PERSON> Redford </PERSON>, long active as an environmentalist, also moderated a two-day conference on depletion of the ozone layer in the upper atmosphere. Not everything, however, was conducted over a conference table. <PERSON> Redford </PERSON> presided over the showing of eight of his movies in <LOCATION> Leningrad </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>. He was scheduled to put on more showings in <LOCATION> Tiblisi </LOCATION>, the capital of <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION>, today and Sunday.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NASHVILLE, Tenn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Gov. <PERSON> Ned </PERSON> <PERSON> McWherter </PERSON> has appointed former <ORGANIZATION> Miss </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Kellye </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cash </ORGANIZATION> the spokeswoman for state anti-drug `` Just Say No'' clubs. `` I hope ... I can emphasize the value of organizing and working together in our communities to help put an end to the abuse of alcohol and other drugs,'' Miss Cash told a news conference Friday shortly before a rally by about 500 `` Just Say No'' club members. The <ORGANIZATION> Memphis </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> communications student and 1987 Miss <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> will help local groups with fund-raising projects to raise $ 1 per school-age child for drug education and prevention projects.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>DUBUQUE, Iowa (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The baseball movie `` Shoeless Joe'' has two new members of its team _ <PERSON> Burt </PERSON> <PERSON> Lancaster </PERSON> and <PERSON> Ray </PERSON> <PERSON> Liotta </PERSON>. <PERSON> Lancaster </PERSON> will play Dr. <PERSON> Archibald </PERSON> <PERSON> Graham </PERSON>, who under the moniker `` Moonlight <PERSON> Graham </PERSON>'' played one inning of one game for the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Giants </ORGANIZATION> in 1905, said publicist <PERSON> Dave </PERSON> <PERSON> Fulton </PERSON>. <PERSON> Liotta </PERSON>, who appears in the current movie `` <PERSON> Dominick </PERSON> and <PERSON> Eugene </PERSON>,'' will play the title character of <PERSON> Shoeless </PERSON> <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, the baseball star who was disgraced in the 1919 <ORGANIZATION> Chicago </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Black </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sox </ORGANIZATION> scandal. Filming in the <LOCATION> Dubuque </LOCATION> area is scheduled to begin May 31, <PERSON> Fulton </PERSON> said recently. The story centers on an <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> farmer who hears a voice telling him that if he builds a baseball diamond in his cornfield, <PERSON> Shoeless </PERSON> <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> will return to the game. <PERSON> Kevin </PERSON> <PERSON> Costner </PERSON> has already been cast as the farmer. The female lead for the movie has not been chosen, <PERSON> Fulton </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Publisher <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> Annenberg </PERSON> donated $ 2 million to <ORGANIZATION> Howard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Communications </ORGANIZATION> to provide scholarships and establish an endowed chair on the institution's faculty, officials said The donation Friday was the largest received from a living person in the university's 120-year history, school officials said. <PERSON> Annenberg </PERSON> is president of <ORGANIZATION> Triangle </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Publications </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, which publishes Seventeen and TV Guide magazines and the Daily Racing Form. He was <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> ambassador to <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> from 1974 to 1978.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880514-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-14-88 0205EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--China-Execution     05-14 0140</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--China-Execution,0143</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bicycle Thief Executed</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A 29-year-old man in the southern <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> province of <LOCATION> Guangdong </LOCATION> was executed for stealing 113 bicycles over more than two years, an official newspaper reported today. The Legal Daily said the intermediate people's court of <LOCATION> Shantou </LOCATION> had sentenced to death <PERSON> Xiao </PERSON> <PERSON> Guoqi </PERSON>, who was executed Friday, for infringing on the legitimate property of citizens and jeopardizing social order. It said <PERSON> Xiao </PERSON> stole $ 7,000 worth of bikes between March 1984 and May 1986. An accomplice, <PERSON> Zheng </PERSON> <PERSON> Kundi </PERSON>, was sentenced to 13 -LCB- years in prison. <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> releases no figures on capital punishment, but is believed to have executed more than 10,000 convicted criminals since initiating an anti-crime drive in 1983. Murder, rape and multiple thefts are among the most common crimes leading to execution, normally a bullet to the back of the head.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880514-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-14-88 0205EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-CyanideTrial     05-14 0443</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Cyanide Trial,0455</SECOND>
<HEAD>Defense Attorney to Seek Mistrial In Cyanide Tampering Case</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GEORGE TIBBITS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SEATTLE (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The lawyer for a woman convicted of poisoning two people with cyanide said he wants a mistrial after a juror admitted settling an unrelated product contamination lawsuit shortly before the trial began. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Dwyer </PERSON> questioned jurors Friday about whether they were improperly influenced during deliberations in the nation's first death-by-product-tampering trial. Most of the questioning was directed at juror <PERSON> Laurel </PERSON> <PERSON> Holliday </PERSON>, who has acknowledged being the lone holdout for <PERSON> Stella </PERSON> <PERSON> Nickell </PERSON>'s acquittal before switching her vote to guilty on Monday, the fifth day of deliberation Mrs. <PERSON> Nickell </PERSON>, 44, of <LOCATION> Auburn </LOCATION>, was convicted of five counts of contaminating over-the-counter medicine capsules with cyanide. They included two counts of spiking the Excedrin capsules that killed her husband, <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Nickell </PERSON>, 52, and <PERSON> Susan </PERSON> <PERSON> Katherine </PERSON> <PERSON> Snow </PERSON>, 40, of <LOCATION> Auburn </LOCATION>, in June 1986. She faces possible life imprisonment at a June 17 sentencing. Prosecutors said she killed her husband to collect $ 176,000 in life insurance. Before a verdict was reached, Ms. <PERSON> Holliday </PERSON> told <PERSON> Dwyer </PERSON> she had received an anonymous phone call the previous Friday telling her Mrs. <PERSON> Nickell </PERSON> had failed an <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> lie detector test. That information was inadmissible at trial. After the verdict, it was revealed Ms. <PERSON> Holliday </PERSON> had filed a lawsuit of her own last year in a contaminated product incident, but had not mentioned that fact during jury selection. Ms. <PERSON> Holliday </PERSON> sued <ORGANIZATION> Pepperidge </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Farm </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> after she bit into a Goldfish cracker in July 1986 that she said contained an aspirin-substitute pill. The matter was settled out of court for $ 500, less than two months prior to Ms. <PERSON> Holliday </PERSON>'s selection for Mrs. <PERSON> Nickell </PERSON>'s jury. Ms. <PERSON> Holliday </PERSON> told <PERSON> Dwyer </PERSON> she dismissed the anonymous call from her mind and judged the case on the facts. She also said she did not mention her own lawsuit during jury selection because she did not think it was relevant. Ms. <PERSON> Holliday </PERSON> also said Friday that during the trial, she had talked with friends about writing an article about her jury experiences, but did not discuss facts of the case. After the unusual session Friday, defense lawyer <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Hillier </PERSON> said he would file a mistrial motion within a week. `` The testimony of juror <PERSON> Holliday </PERSON> raised very serious and troubling questions on her ability to sit on this jury,'' <PERSON> Hillier </PERSON> said. Ms. <PERSON> Holliday </PERSON>'s failure to reveal her own suit kept lawyers from questioning her about that fact, <PERSON> Hillier </PERSON> said. Further, he said there was no way to verify her statements that the phone call had no effect on her decision. Federal prosecutor <PERSON> Joanne </PERSON> <PERSON> Maida </PERSON> declined to comment.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880514-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-14-88 0014EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-BuildingCollapse 2ndLd-Writethru a0795 05-14 0517</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Building Collapse, 2nd Ld-Writethru, a0795,0532</SECOND>
<HEAD>Rescuers Dig for Missing in Building Collapse; 13 Dead</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: SUBS grafs 5-6 ```Hundreds of...Mexico City.'' to UPDATE with
two or three still trapped. Pickup 7th graf pvs ```Relatives
of...'''</NOTE>
<DATELINE>AGUASCALIENTES, Mexico (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Soldiers were called out Friday to help dig for people missing in the rubble of a building collapse that killed at least 13 the day before. Red Cross and state government officials confirmed the number known dead and said 53 people were injured. <PERSON> Gilberto </PERSON> <PERSON> Sanchez </PERSON>, radio officer at police headquarters, said about 60 soldiers from the army garrison joined firefighters, police and volunteers in the rescue effort. Bulldozers and cranes were brought from as far away as <LOCATION> Salamanca </LOCATION>, 78 miles to the southwest. <LOCATION> Aguascalientes </LOCATION>, a city of about 500,000 people 320 miles northwest of <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, is the capital of <LOCATION> Aguascalientes </LOCATION> state. By late Friday, two or three people were believed still trapped in the rubble, <PERSON> Celia </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> la </PERSON> <PERSON> Torre </PERSON>, a state government spokeswoman said. <PERSON> Juan </PERSON> <PERSON> Diaz </PERSON>, head of special services for the local <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION>, said hundreds of people came to help in the rescue. At least 116 workers were in the building when the four upper stories collapsed, said <PERSON> Diaz </PERSON>, reached by telephone from <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. `` Relatives of the victims practically attacked the ambulances, trying to identify'' the victims, he said. The building, still under construction, consisted of three basements, a main floor and three upper stories. As workers were about to pour the last concrete late Thursday afternoon, it collapsed onto a furniture factory that occupied the ground floor and part of the basement area. Lower floors of buildings in <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> often are occupied while the upper stories are constructed. <PERSON> Roberto </PERSON> <PERSON> Padilla </PERSON>, an <LOCATION> Aguascalientes </LOCATION> state government spokesman, said the state attorney general's office was investigating the collapse of the building, which was three blocks from the main plaza and the state capitol. <PERSON> Jorge </PERSON> <PERSON> Castaneda </PERSON>, head of the <ORGANIZATION> Aguascalientes </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Civil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Engineers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, said a committee of engineers and architects also would investigate. <PERSON> Juan </PERSON> <PERSON> Navarro </PERSON>, a police duty officer, said by telephone: `` They were apparently pouring fresh concrete when it caved in. Apparently the building did not resist the weight.'' <PERSON> Juan </PERSON> <PERSON> Flores </PERSON>, a survivor who was buried for five hours, was quoted by the Excelsior news agency as saying: `` I had finished working and was about to leave when ... all of a sudden everyone started yelling hysterically that there was an earthquake. I dashed under a table and all of a sudden everything went dark, and there was this terrific noise and there was dust everywhere.'' He said a slab of concrete fell on the table and `` that is what protected me from the rest of the debris.'' <PERSON> Flores </PERSON> said he was quiet at first, but `` the fear and the anguish of being buried ... impelled me to yell very loud, and the rescue squads dug me out.'' Earlier Friday, the <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION> had reported 18 killed and 96 injured. <PERSON> Juan </PERSON> <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Diaz </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION> duty officer at <LOCATION> Aguascalientes </LOCATION>, said there had been confusion about reports from the scene. He did not elaborate.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880514-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-14-88 0156EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-DefenseSpending Bjt   05-14 0643</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Defense Spending, Bjt,640</SECOND>
<HEAD>Senate Votes To Use Military Against Drugs</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TIM AHERN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> has joined the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> in ordering the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> to jump into the war on drugs even though lawmakers say the plan wo n't solve <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s illicit drug problems. `` I think we all know the drug epidemic in this country is far past the stage where interdiction can stop it,'' said Sen. <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> <PERSON> Nunn </PERSON>, D-Ga., chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Armed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> Senate Republican leader <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Kan </LOCATION>., agreed, noting that ordering the military to help `` shows that we're serious about drugs ... -LRB- but -RRB- I do n't think anybody's certain how much impact this will have. <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> and <PERSON> Nunn </PERSON> were among the supporters Friday night as the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> voted 83-6 to order the military to join the anti-drug war, including having <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> officers arrest suspected drug traffickers who are stopped by <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> warships in international waters. The plan was tacked on as an amendment to a <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> budget bill, which the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> is likely to approve early next week. <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> passage will send the measure to a <ORGANIZATION> House-Senate </ORGANIZATION> conference committee to be reconciled with the different <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> budget bill passed Wednesday by the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>. That measure includes an even stronger anti-drug package, ordering President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> to have the military seal <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> borders against drug traffickers. Senators trying to fashion an anti-drug plan for the military had spent three days working out the details, with the arrest provisions being the chief stumbling block. The military is prohibited from enforcing civilian laws by tradition and by the 1878 Posse Comitatus Act. But that law is in force only within the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and its territorial waters and the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> arrest powers would be outside that jurisdiction. Sen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Ohio </LOCATION>, voted against the plan and criticized his colleagues for voting `` in a great hysteria.'' `` We're posturing on this,'' <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON> said. `` We all get up, posture, make our little statements and it is n't going to make any difference. ... This is not the mission for the military.'' Military officials have generally opposed the plan, arguing that military personnel are trained differently than civilian law enforcement officials, and noting that traditionally there has been a firm line drawn between civilian and military law enforcement. But <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Carlucci </PERSON> worked on the plan with the senators, and <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> approved it before the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> voted, <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> and other senators noted. Sen. <PERSON> Pete </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON>, R-Calif., said he had originally opposed using the military to fight drugs, but changed his mind because `` the drug flow has reached flood tide ... we can not ignore. In other action on the bill Friday, the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>:
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 _ Killed, 56-37, a proposal to permit the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> to have just 14 deployable aircraft carriers, rather than the 15 the service says it wants and needs The proposal would have required the retirement of the aging carriers Midway and <LOCATION> Coral </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sea </LOCATION> faster than the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> wanted. _ Defeated, 56-37, a plan to spend $ 100 million to begin development of a system of protection against the accidental launch by an enemy of nuclear weapons The plan would have used technology now being studied for early phase deployments of <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s Star Wars anti-missile system. _ Rejected, 51-43, a proposal to cut the budget for the Strategic Defense Initiative, as Star Wars is formally known, from $ 4.6 billion to $ 4 billion and use the extra $ 600 million for a variety of non-nuclear weapons The House bill proposes $ 3.5 billion for SDI. Voting against the drug amendment were Sens. <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.J. </LOCATION>; <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Cranston </PERSON>, D-Calif.; <PERSON> Christopher </PERSON> <PERSON> Dodd </PERSON>, D-Conn.; <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Evans </PERSON>, R-Wash.; <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON>; and <PERSON> Lowell </PERSON> <PERSON> Weicker </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Conn </LOCATION>. Not <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Biden </PERSON>, D-Del.; <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Gore </PERSON>, D-Tenn.; <PERSON> Orrin </PERSON> <PERSON> Hatch </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Utah </LOCATION>; <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Hatfield </PERSON>, R-Ore.; Chic Hecht, R-Nev.; <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Karnes </PERSON>; <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> <PERSON> Kassebaum </PERSON>, R-Kan.; <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Kerry </PERSON>, D-Mass; <PERSON> Warren </PERSON> <PERSON> Rudman </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-N.H. </LOCATION>; <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Simon </PERSON>, D-Ill.; and <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Simpson </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Wyo </LOCATION>
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880514-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-14-88 0211EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Business-Trade Bjt   05-14 0614</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Business-Trade, Bjt,610</SECOND>
<HEAD>Trade Bill Likely To Survive Veto, Business Leaders Say</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVE SKIDMORE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>HOT SPRINGS, Va. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Business leaders and <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration officials are betting that <ORGANIZATION> Democrats </ORGANIZATION> have worked too hard to fashion trade legislation to scuttle it after President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s expected veto. `` Members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> have put a great deal of work in this legislation and my judgment is that these persons will not wish to see the bill disappear,'' <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Trade Representative <PERSON> Clayton </PERSON> <PERSON> K. </PERSON> <PERSON> Yeutter </PERSON> said Friday. `` They have a great deal of time, effort, energy and creativity invested in this piece of legislation.'' <PERSON> Yeutter </PERSON> said he expected the president to deliver his veto message to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> next week, but he said he was optimistic about it not meaning the end of the three-year effort to write the trade bill. Although not specifically mentioning <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Speaker <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Texas </LOCATION>, by name, <PERSON> Yeutter </PERSON> noted that a provision repealing the windfall oil profits tax is dear to the hearts of <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> legislators. `` I suspect it will be particularly difficult for them to explain to <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> constituents that they were willing to drop a piece of legislation so important to the state of <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>,'' he said. <PERSON> Yeutter </PERSON> spoke with reporters after addressing a private session of the Business Council. Composed of 61 chief executives of the nation's largest corporations, the council meets twice a year at the Homestead, a posh resort in the mountains of southwestern <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> is vetoing the massive trade bill because of a provision that would require companies to give 60 days' notice of plant closings and major layoffs. The administration supports much of the 1,000-page bill, but objects to the plant-closing provision, which <PERSON> Yeutter </PERSON> called `` onerous.'' <PERSON> Yeutter </PERSON> said the technical language of the provision would provide `` a field day for lawyers and a nightmare for American businessmen'' by providing a legal basis for challenging virtually every plant closing or layoff. <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Express </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>. Chairman <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>, one of the executives attending the retreat ending today, acknowledged that a veto of the trade bill risked losing `` very constructive'' legislation, but he said, `` The business community is prepared to take that risk. `` It's been called simple plant-closing legislation, well it's 10 sections and 56 subsections and inconsistent language,'' he said The business executives, in an economic report issued at the start of their conference, predicted that last year's record trade deficit of $ 171.2 billion would drop below $ 150 billion this year. But, the forecast, which reflects a consensus of the member companies' chief economists, said the reduction would not be enough to stem the fall of the dollar. It said the dollar, which has lost about half of its value against the Japanese yen in two years, would fall from its present level of 125 yen to about 115 yen by the end of 1989. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Reed </PERSON>, chairman of <ORGANIZATION> Citicorp </ORGANIZATION>, the nation's largest bank holding company, said a substantial improvement in the trade deficit was iminent because of the devalued dollar. A weaker dollar improves <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> export prospects by lower the cost of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> goods overseas. `` There is a price at which the trade balance will turn around, and most of us think we're pretty close to it,'' <PERSON> Reed </PERSON> said. Generally, the executives' forecast painted a rosy picture of moderate economic growth, manageable inflation and low unemployment. It said growth, as measured by the gross national product, would be 2.4 percent this year, down from 3.8 percent last year. Inflation of consumer prices was expected to be 3.9 percent this year, down from 4.4 percent in 1987. Unemployment, now at 5.4 percent, should remain under 6 percent through 1989, the executives said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880514-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-14-88 0213EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FarmScene     05-14 0900</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Farm Scene,950</SECOND>
<HEAD>Farmers A Little More Immune From Outside Economic Forces</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DON KENDALL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Farm Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A big question for farmers is whether the general recovery in <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> agriculture will continue long enough for them to pull out of the financial mire that has gripped many since the early 1980s. The <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> is n't making flat predictions about that, but one of its economists says general economic conditions `` are not expected to make or break the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> agricultural sector'' during the next 18 months. <PERSON> Ralph </PERSON> <PERSON> Monaco </PERSON> of the department's <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> says the next year and a half will be one of those periods when `` macroeconomic factors'' are n't likely to set the course for the nation's farmers. By contrast, the financial crunch on farmers in the early'80s sprang largely from events over which they had no control: a worldwide recession, a rise in the value of the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> dollar against foreign currencies, and high interest rates. For the last couple of years, however, the farm outlook has improved dramatically, overall, and in 1987 <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> says the net cash income of farmers was at a record level of $ 57 billion. This year's forecast is down, perhaps in the range of $ 50 billion to $ 55 billion, because of higher production costs and a reduction in federal payments But <ORGANIZATION> Monaco </ORGANIZATION>, whose assessment was reported in this month's Farmline magazine, says he is optimistic about the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> economy in general and that he expects a replay of 1987 conditions For the next year and a half, <ORGANIZATION> Monaco </ORGANIZATION> thinks, the real growth of the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> economy will be about 3 percent a year, inflation will not accelerate significantly -LRB- remaining at 3.5 percent to 4 percent annually -RRB-, interest rates will be relatively stable, and unemployment will continue its slow decline. Some other <ORGANIZATION> Monaco </ORGANIZATION>'s observations: _ Both the federal budget deficit and the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> trade deficit should continue to improve The budget deficit dropped to $ 150 billion in the fiscal year that ended last Sept. 30 from $ 221 billion in 1986. The trade deficit improved in real terms by $ 10 billion last year, the first substantial gain since 1980. _ Exports of both agricultural and non-agricultural products are likely to continue gaining in 1988 A key factor has been the decline in the value of the dollar against foreign currencies, which makes it cheaper to buy <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> products. _ The improved exports and business investment should continue to drive the current <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> economic expansion, now in its sixth straight year In the 1983-86 period, however, the economy was led by consumer and government spending. _ Real growth, as measured by the nation's gross national product, or GNP, has done well since 1982, the last recession year, averaging a gain of 3.1 percent a year `` In general, positive signs seem to prevail over recent concerns about deficits and stock market volatility,'' <ORGANIZATION> Monaco </ORGANIZATION> said. But he added: `` Prospects for the rest of the world are less favorable than for this country. Low export earnings and high debts are still a serious problem for many developing countries. And economic growth remains uneven around the world.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Farmers are hiring more workers this spring, and they are paying more for them, according to an <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> survey. The department said Friday that its survey last month indicated 958,000 hired workers were employed by farmers, compared with 885,000 in the comparable period of April 1987. Those did not include 224,000 `` agricultural service'' workers provided by crew chiefs and labor contractors. Those were up from 188,000 a year earlier, the report said. Field work was hampered in some parts of the country by rain and wet ground when the survey was taken during the week of April 10-16, the report said. But corn planting was getting under way in most major production states and was about 6 percent completed by the end of the week. Planting of cotton, spring wheat and other crops also took place during the week surveyed. `` Lettuce harvest was just beginning in <LOCATION> Salinas </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, and was very active in the <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Joaquin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION>,'' the report said. `` Harvest of cantaloups, watermelons and honeydew melons progressed well in <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>'s valencia orange harvest continued, and grapefruit movement was strong.'' The report said the national figures for hired workers had a sampling error of 4.5 percent. Average pay for all workers hired directly by farmers was $ 5 per hour, up from $ 4.90 a year earlier, the report said. For those workers provided by contractors, there was no national wage rate available. However, workers in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> averaged $ 5.68 per hour, down from $ 6.15 a year ago, while those in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> received an average of $ 6.15 per hour in April, up from $ 5.85 a year ago, the report said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> says wool and mohair price supports will be down slightly this year. Shorn wool marketed in 1988 will be supported at $ 1.78 per pound, down from $ 1.81 in 1987, the department said Friday. <PERSON> Milton </PERSON> <PERSON> Hertz </PERSON>, executive vice president of the department's <ORGANIZATION> Commodity </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Credit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, said the support for 1988 mohair will be $ 4.69 per pound, down from $ 4.95 last year When market prices are depressed, wool and mohair producers get federal payments to raise their earnings nationally to the announced support level. This spring about $ 130 million in subsidies are being paid to producers for wool and mohair sold in 1987.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880514-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-14-88 0030EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-ChildSlaying     05-14 0200</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Child Slaying,0206</SECOND>
<HEAD>Man Charged in Slaying of Daughter Whose Organs Donated</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PENNINGTON GAP, Va. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A father has been charged with murder in the Oct. 30 death of his 7-week-old daughter whose five donated organs kept 3-year-old <PERSON> Tabatha </PERSON> <PERSON> Foster </PERSON> alive for six months. <PERSON> Earl </PERSON> <PERSON> Franklin </PERSON> <PERSON> Shirks </PERSON>, 44, of <PERSON> Pennington </PERSON> <PERSON> Gap </PERSON>, was arrested late Thursday and jailed without bond in the death of <PERSON> Heather </PERSON> <PERSON> Renee </PERSON> <PERSON> Orick </PERSON>, said <LOCATION> Lee </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> Sheriff <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Chadwell </PERSON>. Shirks had told authorities at the time that she was injured in an auto accident. <PERSON> Chadwell </PERSON> declined to reveal the cause of the girl's death. <PERSON> Heather </PERSON>'s liver, pancreas and parts of her stomach, small intestine and colon were donated to <PERSON> Tabatha </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Madisonville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ky. </LOCATION>, toddler whose five-organ transplant in <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION> received national attention. She died Wednesday. <PERSON> Shirks </PERSON> took his daughter to <ORGANIZATION> Lee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Community </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION> on Oct. 8. The child died 22 days later at <LOCATION> Children </LOCATION><LOCATION> 's </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION> at <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sanders </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Knoxville </LOCATION>. In an interview after his daughter's organs were donated, <PERSON> Shirks </PERSON> said <PERSON> Heather </PERSON> was in a little seat on the console of his car when he slammed on the brakes to avoid another vehicle. He said she struck her head on the gear shift.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880514-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-14-88 0215EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-China-Taiwan     05-14 0270</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-China-Taiwan,0276</SECOND>
<HEAD>Chinese, Taiwanese Musicians To Meet In U.S.</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Composers from <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION> will meet in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> in August in the first large-scale conference supported by professional arts organizations from the two rival governments, organizers say. In a release received in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> today, the Center for <ORGANIZATION> U.S.-China </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Arts </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Exchange </ORGANIZATION> at <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> said 10 composers each from <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION> will take part in the Aug. 6-14 conference on `` Tradition and the Future of Chinese Music.'' Center Director <PERSON> Chou </PERSON> <PERSON> Wen-chung </PERSON> said the 1987 relaxation of restrictions on <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION> residents visiting mainland <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> contributed to a growing interest in cultural and educational exchanges. `` Because the center is in touch with artists in both places, we were aware that this moment offered an extraordinary opportunity,'' he said. <PERSON> Chou </PERSON> said he hoped the conference would lead to greater cultural cooperation and contact in the arts between <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION>. The Nationalist government on <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION> has rejected all proposals by <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> for direct trade and cultural contacts. However, <LOCATION> Taipei </LOCATION>'s decision last year to let residents visit the mainland led to a sharp increase in contacts between people on both sides of the <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strait </LOCATION>. The release said consultants who will help choose the conference participants include <PERSON> Hsu </PERSON> <PERSON> Tsang-houei </PERSON>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Chinese </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Composers </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ' </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> League </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION>, and <PERSON> Wu </PERSON> <PERSON> Zuqiang </PERSON>, secretary-general of the <ORGANIZATION> China </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Literary </ORGANIZATION> and Arts Circles. The center is the only <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> agency dedicated solely to cultural exchange with <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>. It brought <PERSON> Arthur </PERSON> <PERSON> Miller </PERSON>'s `` Death of a Salesman'' to <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> and was behind the Academy Award-winning film `` From <PERSON> Mao </PERSON> to <LOCATION> Mozart </LOCATION>: <PERSON> Isaac </PERSON> <PERSON> Stern </PERSON> in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880514-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-14-88 0218EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-ImportedAutos     05-14 0279</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Imported Autos,300</SECOND>
<HEAD>Trade Bill Would Hold Import Dealer Hostage, Trade Group Says</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TIM BOVEE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Trade legislation passed by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> could cost the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> thousands of jobs in the nation's nearly 10,000 imported-auto dealerships, their trade association says. `` The massive <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> imported automobile market is going to be held hostage,'' said <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> McElwaine </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Automobile </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dealers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, at a news conference Friday. The $ 40 billion-a-year imported automobile industry is a likely target if the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> move to restrict imports in a trade dispute, <PERSON> McElwaine </PERSON> said. `` We are the first target for retaliation,'' he said. `` We are such a huge target. Not only is there a large volume of product, it is such an expensive product, and there is a large amount of money involved.'' President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> has vowed to veto the trade bill because of a provision requiring advance notice of plant closings. Should <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> veto the bill, <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> would be in a better position next year to write less damaging trade legislation, <PERSON> McElwaine </PERSON> said. `` By next year, according to our calculations, the trade deficit will have been drastically reduced, the export wave will be at full flood, -LRB- and -RRB- <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s prosperous economy will be so export-dependent that few would be willing to risk derailing the economy with an ill-advised trade bill,'' <PERSON> McElwaine </PERSON> said. <PERSON> McElwaine </PERSON> said the danger to his industry comes from provisions designed to encourage the executive branch to retaliate against nations restricting <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> access to their markets. `` I think it would cause us damage,'' <PERSON> McElwaine </PERSON> said. Restrictions on imports of <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Hyundai </ORGANIZATION> cars alone could potentially cost 15,000 jobs at dealerships, <PERSON> McElwaine </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880514-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-14-88 0218EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-China-ArtTroupes     05-14 0265</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-China-Art Troupes,0270</SECOND>
<HEAD>State to Drop Controls Over Art Troupes</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The government is lifting controls on most art troupes and will let individuals organize their own performing groups, the official <ORGANIZATION> China </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> reported today. The daily quoted Culture Minister <PERSON> Wang </PERSON> <PERSON> Meng </PERSON> as saying state-run art troupes will be replaced with a system that will permit free and open competition among troupes. Performers will be allowed to set their own box office prices and decide their own programs as long as they are licensed and do not violate state laws and regulations. <PERSON> Wang </PERSON> said the reforms are designed to stimulate the professional enthusiam of the 200,000 people working in the nation's 3,094 art troupes. He said many state-run troupes, where lifetime employment prevails, are overstaffed, especially with those who are old and in poor health. <PERSON> Wang </PERSON> said the state will continue to run a small number of the country's best troupes or those needing special state support. Among those are new experimental groups and groups in ethnic minority areas. <PERSON> Wang </PERSON> said state-run troupes will also adopt a new salary system with outstanding performers receiving better pay than those with mediocre skills or past their prime. The state's decision to give up its monopoly over the arts has drawn some criticism in the official press, with artists being quoted as saying many traditional Chinese and minority musical, dance and opera troupes are doomed by the `` survival of the fittest'' policy. Concern has also been raised that troupes forced to pay their own way will turn to sex, violence and superstition to draw audiences.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880514-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-14-88 0218EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-ArmsTreaty     05-14 0438</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Arms Treaty,430</SECOND>
<HEAD>Verification Accord Could Speed Up Agreement On INF Treaty</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LAWRENCE L. KNUTSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> leaders appear satisfied enough with verification measures worked out in <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> to open debate next week on the U.S.-Soviet medium-range missile treaty. But Majority Leader <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON>, D-W. <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, said he will not formally schedule that debate until three <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> committees hold hearings and approve the `` I want to hear what the chairmen and ranking Republican members of these committees have to say following these hearings,'' <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON> said. `` They are the experts in this field.'' Some senators said there is now at least a chance the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> will consent to the ratification of the treaty by the time President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and Soviet leader <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> convene their <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> summit on May 29. Secretary of State <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> is set to testify before the Foreign Relations Committee on Monday afternoon on the agreement he reached this week in <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> with Soviet Foreign Minister <PERSON> Eduard </PERSON> <PERSON> Shevardnadze </PERSON>. The Armed Services and Intelligence committees announced they will hold a joint private meeting late Monday afternoon. Following a 90-minute luncheon briefing Friday by <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> national security adviser <PERSON> Colin </PERSON> <PERSON> Powell </PERSON>, <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON> said he and other <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> leaders were told the agreement removes a roadblock and is a forward step. Senate Republican leader <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> quoted <PERSON> Powell </PERSON> as saying <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON>'s decision last week to postpone <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> action on the treaty `` did make a difference'' in <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION>. Negotiators addressed concerns in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> that the Soviets were backing away from effective implementation of the on-site inspection provisions of the treaty. Other senators who attended the briefing also said the results of the <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> talks seem constructive. `` I'm optimistic we can move ahead,'' said Sen. <PERSON> Claiborne </PERSON> <PERSON> Pell </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-R.I. </LOCATION>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Relations </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>. `` I think at this moment there is more optimism for the passage of this treaty than at at any other time during this long process,'' said Sen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Warner </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Va </LOCATION>., the ranking <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> member of the <ORGANIZATION> Armed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Warner </ORGANIZATION> said the Soviets changed their position to meet <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> objections on every issue that was raised. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> signed the Intermediate-range Nuclear Forces treaty, providing for the total elimination of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and Soviet mid-range missiles, at their <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> summit last December. Sen. <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> <PERSON> Nunn </PERSON>, D-Ga., the <ORGANIZATION> Armed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> chairman, said he now hopes that the treaty can be ratified in the 15 days that remain before the summit Opponents of the treaty were not satisfied, and Sen. <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Helms </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-N.C. </LOCATION>, said he would offer `` something like a dozen'' amendments to the pact.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880514-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-14-88 0219EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-BaldEagles     05-14 0344</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bald Eagles,0349</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bald Eagle Deaths Worrisome to Environmental Officials</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CAMBRIDGE, Md. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The deaths of 10 bald eagles that apparently ate illegally poisoned animal carcasses threaten the comeback of the endangered birds in the <LOCATION> Chesapeake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION> area, federal officials said. `` While our national symbol is making a recovery, it can not sustain this rate of loss month after month nor will we tolerate it,'' said <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Dunkle </PERSON>, director of the <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. Fish and <ORGANIZATION> Wildlife </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>. Five dead eagles, one adult and four immature bald eagles, were found May 3 in a field near the carcasses of three raccoons, a deer and a vulture. Five others were found elsewhere in <LOCATION> Dorchester </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> between March 12 and May 1, including the <ORGANIZATION> Blackwater </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wildlife </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Refuge </ORGANIZATION> near <LOCATION> Cambridge </LOCATION>. `` The birds are not in danger of becoming extinct'' because of illegal poisoning of animals, but `` the deaths resulting will have some impact on their recovery because the deaths are occurring in an area where we have a large amount of bald eagles,'' <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Therres </PERSON>, the non-game and endangered species program manager for the <ORGANIZATION> Maryland </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION>, Park and <ORGANIZATION> Wildlife </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>. State and federal officials said they are particularly concerned because the county has the greatest concentration of bald eagles in the <LOCATION> Chesapeake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION> area. The eagle population, devastated by the use of the pesticide DDT in the 1950s and 1960s, had been restored to its highest levels on the East Coast. Officials are testing tissue from the dead eagles and the carcasses for chemicals. Results are expected in several weeks, but because the eagles had been dead at least a month before they were found, such analyses can be difficult, said <PERSON> Inez </PERSON> <PERSON> Connor </PERSON>, a spokeswoman for the Fish and <ORGANIZATION> Wildlife </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Newton </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Corner </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mass </LOCATION>. `` The fact there has been a carcass near all of the eagles we have found leads us to think that they died as a result of eating poisoned animals,'' Ms. <PERSON> Connor </PERSON> said. Criminal charges could be brought against anyone found to be poisoning animals. Bald eagles are protected under federal law.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880514-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-14-88 0227EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Iran-Contra     05-14 0532</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Iran-Contra,520</SECOND>
<HEAD>Walsh Says Justice Department Has Final Word On Document
Declassification</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Independent counsel <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Walsh </PERSON> says the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> has the final word on whether certain classified material can be used in the Iran-Contra trial of <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> <PERSON> North </PERSON> and three co-defendants. That concession could enable the department to scuttle the prosecution of the fired <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> aide, former national security adviser <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Poindexter </PERSON> and arms dealers <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> V. </PERSON> <PERSON> Secord </PERSON> and <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Hakim </PERSON>. In a legal memorandum filed in the case, <PERSON> Walsh </PERSON> said he `` must be deferential to the executive's determination as to whether national security concerns prevent public disclosure of validly classified information.'' <PERSON> Walsh </PERSON> has amassed 50,000 classified government documents that may be relevant to the prosecution of charges that <PERSON> Hakim </PERSON>, <PERSON> North </PERSON>, <PERSON> Poindexter </PERSON> and <PERSON> Secord </PERSON> conspired to illegally divert to the Nicaraguan Contra rebels the profits from sales of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> arms to <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>. Another 250,000 secret documents may contain information relevant to the defense of the case. By <PERSON> Walsh </PERSON>'s description, the most sensitive 5 percent to 10 percent of the documents contain secrets about <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> intelligence and military operations and sensitive foreign policy initiatives. Under the Classified Information Procedures Act -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> CIPA </ORGANIZATION> -RRB-, the attorney general must certify to the court that disclosure of certain documents as evidence in court would endanger national security. The law provides for substitution of summaries of the documents or statements of what the evidence would prove if revealed in open court. The court has the power to dismiss criminal cases if too much evidence is withheld. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> Gerhard </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gesell </PERSON> has warned that he would dismiss charges if relevant secret documents are not declassified for use at the trial as evidence. <PERSON> Gesell </PERSON> also has expressed an unwillingness to spend a lot of time rewriting classified documents so that they could be presented as evidence in a public trial. He has given <PERSON> Walsh </PERSON> until June 10 to submit a list of documents the independent counsel wants to use as prosecution evidence that wo n't be declassified. The legal memorandum from <PERSON> Walsh </PERSON> to <PERSON> Gesell </PERSON> was filed in response to a question about the issue that the judge posed during a May 6 hearing. <PERSON> Walsh </PERSON> said: `` It is an inherent function of the executive branch to maintain the confidentiality of sensitive national security information to the extent necessary to permit the government to conduct its foreign affairs and national defense activities effectively. `` Neither the independent counsel statute nor the regulation purports to confer upon independent counsel any general power of declassification.'' Attorney General <PERSON> Edwin </PERSON> <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>, who has been questioned repeatedly by the Iran-Contra grand jury about his November 1986 investigation of the arms-for-hostages deals, has recused himself from the case, or any others involving independent counsels. Any decision about classified information in the Iran-Contra case would have to be made by an acting attorney general. <PERSON> Walsh </PERSON> said that under a 1982 executive order on classified documents, he has no authority to declassify government secrets and must therefore defer to the authority of the attorney general. <PERSON> Walsh </PERSON> said he agreed to comply with the 1982 executive order when he obtained the 300,000 pages of classified documents in the course of his investigation.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880514-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-14-88 0130EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-AlohaPilots     05-14 0344</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Aloha Pilots,0355</SECOND>
<HEAD>Aloha Pilots Say They Are Ready To Return To Air</HEAD>
<DATELINE>HONOLULU (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The pilots who safely landed an <ORGANIZATION> Aloha </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> jetliner April 28 after the cabin blew open at 24,000 feet said Friday they look forward to returning to the air in a few days. `` I've ridden in a couple airplanes since the incident,'' the pilot, <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Schornstheimer </PERSON>, said at a news conference. `` I'm really more comfortable at the controls of an airplane than I am in this setting here. Schornstheimer and co-pilot <PERSON> Mimi </PERSON> <PERSON> Tompkins </PERSON> landed the <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> 737 on the island of <LOCATION> Maui </LOCATION> after a third of the cabin peeled away on a Hilo-to-Honolulu flight. A flight attendant was swept to her death and 61 passengers were injured. A check of <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aviation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> records Friday showed 14 cracks or instances of corrosion were found in several routine maintenance checks on the plane before the accident, but none of the defects was found in the area of the damage. According to <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> records, each of the cracks or corroded areas was repaired by replacing sections of the plane's metal skin. A federal investigation has focused on metal fatigue as a possible cause of the accident. Neither pilot would discuss the cause. However, they related the 15 harrowing minutes while they guided the crippled plane to an emergency landing. `` It was a split-second thing. There was a loud noise and the cockpit door was gone and there was blue sky,'' Schornstheimer said. He added: `` Normally, you do n't expect to lose that much of an airplane and still be able to fly it.'' According to <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> records, the defects uncovered during routine maintenance by <PERSON> Aloha </PERSON> were on the rear-bottom portions or wings of the plane during routine <LOCATION> Aloha </LOCATION> inspections. The top of the cabin peeled away in the accident. <PERSON> Nick </PERSON> <PERSON> Wantiez </PERSON>, <PERSON> Aloha </PERSON> director of engineering, said the number of defects was `` not untypical of some airplanes, but probably better than most.'' `` Generally, it was in quite good shape from a corrosion standpoint,'' <PERSON> Wantiez </PERSON> said. `` The basic airplane looked quite clean.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880514-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-14-88 0244EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Candidates-Schedules     05-14 0203</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Candidates-Schedules,200</SECOND>
<HEAD>Presidential Candidates' Schedules</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are tentative schedules for the presidential candidates for the week beginning May 15. The information was provided by the candidates. Sunday, May 15: Democrats: <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jackson </LOCATION> _ <ORGANIZATION> Hampton </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>; <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Jersey </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION>: <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> Medford </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ore. </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION> Monday, May 16: Democrats: <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jackson </LOCATION> _ <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION> Republican: <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wash. </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Fresno </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>; Tuesday, May 17: Democrats: <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jackson </LOCATION> _ <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> Republican: <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> Fresno </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>. Wednesday, May 18: Democrats: <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jackson </LOCATION> _ <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> Republican: <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION> Thursday, May 19: Democrats: <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jackson </LOCATION> _ <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> Republican: <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION> Friday, May 20: Democrats: <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jackson </LOCATION> _ <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> Republican: <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION> Saturday, May 21: Democrats: <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Louis </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jackson </LOCATION> _ <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> Republican: <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION> Sunday, May 22: Democrats: <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> -LRB- down day -RRB- <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> Republican: <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C </LOCATION>
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880514-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-14-88 0111EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Soviet-Opposition     05-14 0455</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Soviet-Opposition,0472</SECOND>
<HEAD>Week-Old Soviet Opposition Party Outlines Bold Platform</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CAROL J. WILLIAMS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MOSCOW (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A new opposition group challenging the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>'s political monopoly has outlined a platform that calls for free trade unions and end to Soviet domination of the Baltic states and of <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>. The week-old <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION>, whose members have been harassed by authorities as `` anti-social,'' said in unveiling the progam Friday that it plans to try to register with the state but expects to be rebuffed. At least a dozen uniformed policemen milled around outside as party organizers gathered in a crowded eighth-floor apartment in northwest <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> to discuss plans for political action. Police made no attempt to stop those entering or leaving. The group's declaration of goals and principles followed a week of meetings in which organizers said more than 150 Soviets from 27 cities took part. <PERSON> Yuri </PERSON> <PERSON> Denisov </PERSON>, one of the party's 15 Central Coordinating Council members, told journalists it would try to comply with laws requiring groups to register their activity, `` but of course we expect problems with that and we do not expect to succeed.'' Another coordinating council member, <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON> <PERSON> Lukashev </PERSON>, outlined broad party policies. He said the group aims to present an `` opposition'' to the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>'s monopoly on power and political thought. The group opposes the `` Soviet occupation'' of the Baltic states of <LOCATION> Lithuania </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Latvia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Estonia </LOCATION>, and Soviet actions in <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> that have helped keep Communist government in power there, he said. The party has called for independent trade unions, and on Friday issued a statement denouncing Polish officials' actions to halt industrial strikes over the past month in the Soviet-allied country. `` The <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION> comes out in opposition to totalitarianism of political parties,'' the group's statement of principles declares as its first objective. The party program sets out methods for calling elections and filling leadership positions, and says funds raised by the group will be used for `` informational activity, agitation, printing costs and organizational needs.'' Party activists complained that their first week was marred by `` repressive'' and `` unconstitutional'' actions of the <ORGANIZATION> KGB </ORGANIZATION>, local police forces and the state-run press. The official <ORGANIZATION> Tass </ORGANIZATION> news agency denounced the party on Wednesday, accusing the activists of `` slanderous, anti-social activity.'' Dozens of participants were detained by police after meetings last weekend, with sentences of five to seven days in jail handed down summarily to four of them, including dissident magazine editor <PERSON> Sergei </PERSON> <PERSON> Grigoryants </PERSON>. <PERSON> Grigoryants </PERSON>, who edits the unofficial magazine `` Glasnost,'' remained jailed Friday night and no one had been permitted to see him, the activists said. <PERSON> Denisov </PERSON> said the party planned a political conference in the fall, but that details of that gathering had not been worked out yet.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880514-0025 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-14-88 0240EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-DecoDemolition Bjt   05-14 0556</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Deco Demolition, Bjt,0572</SECOND>
<HEAD>Preservationists Vow To Keep Vigil At Historic Hotel Slated For
Destruction</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto MH1</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By A.J. DICKERSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MIAMI BEACH, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The battle to keep a landmark art deco hotel from being turned into a parking lot heated up as preservationists and the city struggled to save it and the owner began pulling plumbing from the building. `` People are distressed and distraught that we would be losing a building,'' <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> <PERSON> Liebman </PERSON>, legislative liaison for the <ORGANIZATION> Miami </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Design </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Preservation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> League </ORGANIZATION>, said Friday as a work crew carted plumbing and scrap metal from the beachfront Senator Hotel. `` While it's still here, it's worth a continuous battle,'' she said. The three-story, green-and-white hotel was built in 1939, and is on the National Register of Historic Places, Ms. <PERSON> Liebman </PERSON> said. It is one of 800 art deco buildings in the mile-square area that comprises the only official art deco district in the world, she said. The closed hotel's owner, the <ORGANIZATION> Royale </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Group </ORGANIZATION>, must raze the Senator for parking spaces as a condition for obtaining bank loans to renovate other art deco buildings it owns, <ORGANIZATION> Royale </ORGANIZATION> attorney <PERSON> Harold </PERSON> <PERSON> Rosen </PERSON> said. `` It's not we're anti-preservation, but we have to be practical, too,'' <PERSON> Rosen </PERSON> said. A date for demolishing the building has not been set. Mayor <PERSON> Alex </PERSON> <PERSON> Daoud </PERSON> said he hopes last-ditch negotiations scheduled next week with the <ORGANIZATION> Royale </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Group </ORGANIZATION>'s owners will keep the wrecking ball away. `` We're doing everything within our power to preserve it,'' said <PERSON> Daoud </PERSON>, whose staff is checking legal avenues, possible land swaps and the feasibility of buying the hotel. Preservationists will keep an eye on the building, Ms. <PERSON> Liebman </PERSON> said. `` It's hard to see where this urgent crush for parking is,'' she said. `` The Senator has every single deco feature. It's a perfect example, an important masterpiece.'' The art deco district's buildings are painted pastel colors and sport geometric designs, its sidewalks are painted pink and it's often featured on <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Miami Vice'' television show The city is pushing for the renovation of the district's buildings in its effort to bring back the glory days of tourism The 70-room Senator is a crucial part of the district, said <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Capitman </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> Art </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Deco </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Miami </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Beach </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Art </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Deco </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Societies </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION>. `` The Senator ... has probably the most famous etched glass in the district,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Capitman </PERSON> said. `` It is a particularly seductive building.'' Ms. <PERSON> Liebman </PERSON> and Mrs. <PERSON> Capitman </PERSON> accuse the <ORGANIZATION> Royale </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Group </ORGANIZATION> of ignoring pleas from them and city officials to save the hotel, which was closed after the group bought it in 1984. <PERSON> Rosen </PERSON> countered that in the nine months it took his clients to obtain a demolition permit, no one offered a viable alternative. He said none is expected now. `` Our people are more active in preserving than any others on the beach,'' <PERSON> Rosen </PERSON> said. Preservationists `` have blinders on, they're not in the real world.'' <PERSON> Daoud </PERSON> said he remained optimistic, but understood the <ORGANIZATION> Royale </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Group </ORGANIZATION>'s problems. `` They first started to restore it, purchased new doors and fixtures, but what happened was they had to provide this parking,'' <PERSON> Daoud </PERSON> said. `` It's almost a Catch-22: you've got a developer renovating the area, doing a great job, and he's the same individual who's knocking down one of our architectural treasures to make room for parking.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880514-0026 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-14-88 0256EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-KatyMerger     05-14 0331</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Katy Merger,320</SECOND>
<HEAD>ICC Tentatively Votes To Approve Union Pacific Merger</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BARRY MASSEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A proposed purchase of the regional <ORGANIZATION> Missouri-Kansas-Texas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Railroad </ORGANIZATION> by the <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pacific </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> has been tentatively approved by the <ORGANIZATION> Interstate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION>, sources say. The regulatory agency has scheduled an official announcement on Monday of its decision. Agency and congressional sources, speaking on condition they not be identified, said the commission had voted 4-0 on Friday to permit the <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pacific </ORGANIZATION> and MKT merger. The Union Pacific, a 21,500-mile network, proposed in November 1986 to acquire the 3,100-mile MKT system, known as the Katy line, for $ 110 million and to assume its outstanding debts. As proposed, the merger would eliminate about 1,100 <PERSON> Katy </PERSON> jobs because of closing of rail yards and repair shops. <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pacific </ORGANIZATION> also proposed the abandonment of 405 miles of track, mostly operated by <PERSON> Katy </PERSON>. The Union Pacific, the nation's third largest railroad system in terms of track mileage, serves about 20 states with routes from <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION> in the West to <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION>. The company was formed in 1982 with the merger of the <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pacific </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Missouri </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pacific </ORGANIZATION> and <LOCATION> Western </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> railroads. The Katy serves six states, with mostly north-south routes running from <LOCATION> Omaha </LOCATION> to the <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Coast </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Dennis </PERSON> <PERSON> Watson </PERSON>, an <ORGANIZATION> ICC </ORGANIZATION> spokesman, said he had no information on how commissioners had voted in the case, and could not confirm or deny that the merger had been approved. The sources said retiring commissioner <PERSON> Malcolm </PERSON> <PERSON> Sterrett </PERSON>, who did not seek reappointment to a new term on the agency, did not vote. The agency made its decision by a voting system that does not require a public meeting. The railroads say consolidating their operations would provide shippers with better service at lower costs, and offer direct single-line routes in some areas. Without the merger, the <ORGANIZATION> ICC </ORGANIZATION> has been told, the financially troubled <PERSON> Katy </PERSON> will have difficulty surviving against bigger competitors.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880514-0027 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-14-88 0253EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-FatalFire     05-14 0296</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Fatal Fire,0303</SECOND>
<HEAD>Girl Dies in House Fire Started by Candles Used For Light</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LENNOX, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
