<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881223-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-23-88 2339EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-Robinson-Memorial 2ndLd-Writethru a0715 12-23 0620</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Robinson-Memorial, 2nd Ld-Writethru, a0715,620</SECOND>
<HEAD>Friends Pay Last Respects to Max Robinson</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDs: SUBS graf 6 to correct Jackson's characterization of
conversation with Robinson about contracting AIDS, adding quote from
Jackson eulogy</NOTE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Rev. <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> eulogized former <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> anchorman <PERSON> Max </PERSON> <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> on Friday as a man who `` would n't adjust, would n't knuckle under the face of racism.'' <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, a close friend of <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON>'s, delivered the eulogy at a <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> church where friends and co-workers of the nation's first black network television anchor paid their last respects to <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON>. The former anchor, said <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, `` would n't adjust, would n't knuckle under the face of obvious and not so obvious racism. <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> had been ill for more than a year when he died Tuesday at <ORGANIZATION> Howard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION> of complications resulting from AIDS. He was 49. `` <PERSON> Max </PERSON> <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> never adjusted,'' <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> said. `` He sought to transform. He was not a TV thermometer who measured things and spilled them back out. He tried to be a thermostat _ to change the temperature.'' <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> told reporters that he talked to <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> about how <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> contracted AIDS and that <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> told him: `` It is not homosexuality but it was promiscuity. ... Let my predicament be a source of education to our people.'' Among those attending the ceremony were ABC News President <PERSON> Roone </PERSON> <PERSON> Arledge </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> anchorman <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Jennings </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> anchorman <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Rather </PERSON>, 60 Minutes reporter <PERSON> Ed </PERSON> <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> CNN </ORGANIZATION> anchorman <PERSON> Bernard </PERSON> <PERSON> Shaw </PERSON>. `` I think ABC News is a better place today than it was before <PERSON> Max </PERSON> was there,'' said <PERSON> Arledge </PERSON>. `` A lot of that is due to his efforts.'' <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> began his broadcasting career as a radio station disc jockey in his hometown of <LOCATION> Richmond </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va </LOCATION>. He moved to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> in 1965 and three years later became the first black to anchor newscasts at a major TV station, appearing on the 6 p.m. and 11 p.m. news on Channel 9 <ORGANIZATION> WTOP </ORGANIZATION>, now <ORGANIZATION> WUSA </ORGANIZATION>, with co-anchor <PERSON> Gordon </PERSON> <PERSON> Peterson </PERSON>. <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> then left <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> after 10 years at the top of the ratings to join <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> as the first black to anchor a network news show. He was one of three anchors at <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, along with <PERSON> Jennings </PERSON> and <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Reynolds </PERSON>. `` He did an enormous amount for us,'' said <PERSON> Jennings </PERSON>. `` He did an enormous amount, I think, for his community. ... When <PERSON> Max </PERSON> died, we all hoped he'd find some peace.'' The frustrated <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> made headlines publicly denouncing racism at the news organization during a speech at <ORGANIZATION> Smith </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> in February 1981. <PERSON> Arledge </PERSON> was supervising news coverage when <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> was an anchor, and he changed <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION>' three-anchor format after <PERSON> Reynolds </PERSON> died in 1983. At that point, <PERSON> Jennings </PERSON> inherited the job as sole anchor of the newscasts, and <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> was assigned to do news briefs and weekend anchor. In 1984, he left <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> and joined <ORGANIZATION> WMAQ-TV </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>. The following June, he entered a hospital specializing in alcohol rehabilitation suffering from emotional and physical exhaustion, according to <PERSON> Nick </PERSON> <PERSON> Aronson </PERSON>, director of communications at <ORGANIZATION> WMAQ-TV </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Aronson </PERSON> said <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> never returned to the station, and did sporadic freelance work after that. `` I think one of my basic flaws has been the lack of esteem, not really feeling great about myself, always feeling like I had to do more,'' <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> said in a <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> profile. He is survived by his mother, <PERSON> Doris </PERSON> <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> <PERSON> Griffin </PERSON>, and stepfather, the Rev. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Griffin </PERSON>, both from <LOCATION> Norfolk </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, and four children, <PERSON> Mark </PERSON>, <PERSON> Maureen </PERSON>, <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> and <PERSON> Malik </PERSON> <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON>. <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> also leaves three surviving siblings, <PERSON> Jewel </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shepperd </PERSON>, <PERSON> Jean </PERSON> <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> <PERSON> Yancey </PERSON> and civil rights activist <PERSON> Randall </PERSON> <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON>, the head of <ORGANIZATION> TransAfrica </ORGANIZATION>. All live in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. There will be no private funeral, as <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON>'s family has decided to have his remains cremated.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881223-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-23-88 2344EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a BC-Crash-List-1stAdd 1stLd-Writethru a0466 12-23 0640</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Crash-List - 1st Add, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0466,0762</SECOND>
<NOTE>Eds: As noted in editor's note on first take, this writethru
CORRECTS reference to Roller family as being part of Syracuse
University group; adds first names for some passengers.</NOTE>
<HEAD>NEW YORK: ... Johnson, New Jersey.</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Christopher </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Claverack </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Syracuse </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> group. <PERSON> Julianne </PERSON> <PERSON> Kelly </PERSON>, 20, <LOCATION> Dedham </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mass. </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Syracuse </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> group. <PERSON> Jay </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kingham </PERSON>, 44, <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION> <PERSON> Patricia </PERSON> <PERSON> Klein </PERSON>, 35, <LOCATION> Trenton </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.J. </LOCATION> <PERSON> Gregory </PERSON> <PERSON> Kosmowski </PERSON>, 40, <LOCATION> Milford </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mich. </LOCATION>. <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kulukundis </PERSON>, <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Larivier </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>. <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Leckburg </PERSON>. <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Leyrer </PERSON>. <PERSON> Joanna </PERSON> <PERSON> Lichtstein </PERSON>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Wendy </PERSON> <PERSON> Lincoln </PERSON>, 23, <PERSON> North </PERSON> <PERSON> Adams </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Mass. </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Syracuse </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> group. <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON> <PERSON> Lowenstein </PERSON>, 21, <LOCATION> Morristown </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.J. </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Syracuse </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> group. Army Sgt. <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Ludlow </PERSON>, 41, Sinthen Airfield, <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>. <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Luerbke </PERSON>. <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Macallister </PERSON>. <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Mack </PERSON>. <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Maijala </PERSON>. Spec. 4 <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON> <PERSON> Malicote </PERSON>, 22, <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Wendy </PERSON> <PERSON> Forsythe </PERSON> <PERSON> Malicote </PERSON>, 21, <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>. <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Mareck </PERSON>. <PERSON> Lou </PERSON> <PERSON> Marengo </PERSON>, 33, <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Diane </PERSON> <PERSON> Maslowski </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Haddonfield </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.J. </LOCATION> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> McCarthy </PERSON>. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> McCollum </PERSON>, 61, <PERSON> Wayne </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> McKee </PERSON> <PERSON> Bernard </PERSON> <PERSON> McLaughlin </PERSON>, 30, <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>. <PERSON> X. </PERSON> <PERSON> Melber </PERSON>. <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Merrill </PERSON>. <PERSON> Suzanne </PERSON> <PERSON> Miazga </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Utica </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Syracuse </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> group. <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> K. </PERSON> <PERSON> Miller </PERSON>, 56, <LOCATION> Woodmere </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON>. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Monetti </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Cherry </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.J. </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Syracuse </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> group. <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Morgan </PERSON>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>. <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Morson </PERSON>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Helga </PERSON> <PERSON> Mosey </PERSON>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION>. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Mulroy </PERSON>, 59, <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Northport </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION> <PERSON> Sean </PERSON> <PERSON> Mulroy </PERSON>, 25, <LOCATION> Sweden </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Ingrid </PERSON> <PERSON> Mulroy </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Sweden </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Karen </PERSON> <PERSON> Noonan </PERSON>, 20, <LOCATION> Potomac </LOCATION>, Md. <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Connor </PERSON>. <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Neil </PERSON>, <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Anne </PERSON> <PERSON> Lindsay </PERSON> <PERSON> Otenasak </PERSON>, 21, <LOCATION> Baltimore </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Syracuse </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> group. <PERSON> Gwyneth </PERSON> <PERSON> Owen </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Bristol </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>. <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Owen </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Bristol </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> P </PERSON> <PERSON> Owens </PERSON>, 45, <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Martha </PERSON> <PERSON> Owens </PERSON>, 44, <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Laura </PERSON> <PERSON> Owens </PERSON>, 8, <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Sarah </PERSON> <PERSON> Owens </PERSON>, 14, <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>. <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Pagnucco </PERSON>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Papadopoulos </PERSON>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Peirce </PERSON>, 40, <LOCATION> Perrysburg </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Syracuse </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> group. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Pescatore </PERSON>, 33, <ORGANIZATION> Solon </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Sarah </PERSON> <PERSON> Phillips </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Newtonville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mass. </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Syracuse </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> group. <PERSON> Frederick </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Phillips </PERSON>, 25, <LOCATION> Little </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rock </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ark. </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Syracuse </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> group. <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Pitt </PERSON>, 23, <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hadley </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mass </LOCATION>. <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Platt </PERSON>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Porter </PERSON>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Posen </PERSON>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Pugh </PERSON>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Quiguyan </PERSON>. <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Ramses </PERSON>. <PERSON> Anmol </PERSON> <PERSON> Rattan </PERSON>, 2, <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Garima </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Rattan </PERSON>, 29, <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Suruchi </PERSON> <PERSON> Rattan </PERSON>, 3, <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION>. <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Reeves </PERSON>, <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>. Mark A. Rein, 44, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Diane </PERSON> <PERSON> Rencevicz </PERSON>, 21, <LOCATION> Burlington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.J. </LOCATION> <PERSON> Louise </PERSON> <PERSON> Rogers </PERSON>, 20, <PERSON> Olney </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Md. </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Syracuse </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> group. Roller, Mr., <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>. Roller, Mrs., <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>. Roller -LRB- child -RRB-, <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Saul </PERSON> <PERSON> Rosen </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Morris </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Township </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.J. </LOCATION> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Rosenthal </PERSON>. <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Rosenthal </PERSON>. <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Rubin </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Belgium </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Elyse </PERSON> <PERSON> Saraceni </PERSON>, 20, <PERSON> Crabtree </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION>. <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Saunders </PERSON>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> <PERSON> T. </PERSON> <PERSON> Saunders </PERSON>. <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Schaeuble </PERSON>. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> T. </PERSON> <PERSON> Schlageter </PERSON>, 20, <LOCATION> Warwick </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> R.I. </LOCATION> <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Schultz </PERSON>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Syracuse </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> group. <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Scott </PERSON>. <PERSON> I. </PERSON> <PERSON> Seigal </PERSON>. <PERSON> Amy </PERSON> <PERSON> Shapiro </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Stamford </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Conn. </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Syracuse </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> group. <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shastri </PERSON>. <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Simpson </PERSON>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Cynthia </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, 21, <LOCATION> Milton </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mass. </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Syracuse </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> group. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, 55, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. <PERSON> I. </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, 34, <LOCATION> Kalamazoo </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mich. </LOCATION>. <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Stevenson </PERSON>, <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Stevenson </PERSON>, <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>. <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Stevenson </PERSON>, <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>. <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Stevenson </PERSON>, <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Charlotte </PERSON> <PERSON> Stinnett </PERSON>, 36, <LOCATION> Wiesbaden </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Stinnett </PERSON>, 26, <LOCATION> Wiesbaden </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Stacy </PERSON> <PERSON> Stinnett </PERSON>, 9, <LOCATION> Wiesbaden </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>. J. Stow, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Stratis </PERSON>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION>. A. Swan, <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kingdom </LOCATION>. F. Swire. <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Tager </PERSON>, <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kingdom </LOCATION>. <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Tanaka </PERSON>. <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Teran </PERSON>. <PERSON> Arva </PERSON> <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON>, 17, <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Jonathan </PERSON> <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON>, 2 months old, <ORGANIZATION> Detroit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> Sgt. <PERSON> LaWanna </PERSON> <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON>, 21, <PERSON> Detroit </PERSON> <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Tobin </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Hempstead </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Syracuse </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> group. <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Trimmersmith </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Oxford </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Alexia </PERSON> <PERSON> Tsairis </PERSON>, 20, <LOCATION> Franklin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lakes </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.J. </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Syracuse </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> group. <PERSON> Barry </PERSON> <PERSON> Valentino </PERSON>, 28, <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>. <PERSON> T. </PERSON> <PERSON> Vantienhoven </PERSON>. <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Vejdany </PERSON>. <PERSON> Nicholas </PERSON> <PERSON> Vrenios </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Syracuse </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> group. <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Vulcu </PERSON>, a native of Alliance, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>. <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Waido </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Krakow </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>. <PERSON> T. </PERSON> <PERSON> Walker </PERSON>. <PERSON> Kesha </PERSON> <PERSON> Weedon </PERSON>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Syracuse </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> group. <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Weston </PERSON>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. J. White, <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Bonnie </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>, Crown Point, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION> Sgt. <PERSON> Eric </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>, Crown Point, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION> First Lt. <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>, 24, <PERSON> Joppatowne </PERSON>, Md. <PERSON> I. </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>. <PERSON> Miriam </PERSON> <PERSON> Luby </PERSON> <PERSON> Wolfe </PERSON>, 20, <LOCATION> Severna </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Park </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Md. </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Syracuse </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> group. <PERSON> Chelsea </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Woods </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Willingboro </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> N.J. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> Sgt. <PERSON> Dedera </PERSON> <PERSON> Lynn </PERSON> <PERSON> Woods </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Willingboro </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.J. </LOCATION> <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> N. </PERSON> <PERSON> Woods </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Willingboro </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.J. </LOCATION> <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Woods </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Willingboro </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.J. </LOCATION> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Wynenburg </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881223-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-23-88 0101EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-China-Dissident     12-23 0457</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-China-Dissident,0472</SECOND>
<HEAD>China Arrests Man Linked To U.S.-Based Dissident Group</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A man linked to a U.S.-based Chinese dissident group has been arrested, and an organization he led has been suppressed, according to two official newspapers. The reports said <PERSON> Lei </PERSON> <PERSON> Yuanhai </PERSON> and five members of his group received funds from the New York-based <ORGANIZATION> Chinese </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Alliance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democracy </ORGANIZATION>. The group, established in 1983 by a former <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> citizen, advocates democracy in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> News and the <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> reported Thursday that <PERSON> Lei </PERSON> and his colleagues had been accused of passing out copies of `` <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Spring </LOCATION>,'' the alliance's magazine that is banned in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>. In addition, they allegedly `` attacked the dictatorship of the people and the socialist system, and actively plotted riotous, illegal activities.'' The reports, which cited no specific instances of illegal activities, said Lei founded the <LOCATION> Chongqing </LOCATION> branch of the <ORGANIZATION> Chinese </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Alliance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democracy </ORGANIZATION> two years ago. Following its founding, the branch received regular payments from <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> and agents came to <LOCATION> Chongqing </LOCATION> to help with organizing, the reports said. <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> News and the People's Daily said Lei and the five others have admitted their involvement in the group and expressed repentance. A letter of apology, written by <PERSON> Lei </PERSON>, has been published in the Chongqing Daily. The reports said the <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> had taken note of Lei's apology and would deal leniently with <PERSON> Lei </PERSON> and the five others. <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> tolerates little political dissent. Political reform here is viewed by the state as a necessary evil that will help spwr economic growth. Any moves that would challenge the supremacy of the <ORGANIZATION> Chinese </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> are checked. The press remains tightly controlled. And tough censorship laws limit access to new political ideas. The <ORGANIZATION> Chinese </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Alliance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democracy </ORGANIZATION>, based in <LOCATION> Queens </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, is run by <PERSON> Wang </PERSON> <PERSON> Bingzhang </PERSON>, now a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> citizen. <PERSON> Wang </PERSON> came to <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> in the late 1970s from <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> to study at <ORGANIZATION> McGill </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Montreal </LOCATION>. In 1983, he became an American citizen and the alliance was founded. <PERSON> Wang </PERSON> has said the alliance receives money from <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION> and from other Chinese groups interested in democracy in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>. His organization, he says, is committed to bringing about a democratic revolution in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Wang </PERSON>'s group and magazine, `` <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> Spring,'' are relatively popular among the 27,000 Chinese students now studying in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. The magazine regularly runs articles written by people it says are `` sources in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>.'' The magazine takes its name from `` <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> Spring,'' a period of time from 1979-80 when <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> experienced relative cultural and political freedoms. The magazine lists as honorary co-editors, <PERSON> Wei </PERSON> <PERSON> Jingsheng </PERSON>, <PERSON> Liu </PERSON> Qing and <PERSON> Xu </PERSON> <PERSON> Wenli </PERSON>, three imprisoned dissidents who were active during the `` Beijing Spring'' period. However, there is no known connection between the dissidents and <PERSON> Wang </PERSON>'s group.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881223-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-23-88 0111EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Crash-Bombs     12-23 0761</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Crash-Bombs,0794</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bombings Of Commercial Airliners</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Suspicion has focused on terrorist sabotage as the cause of Wednesday's <ORGANIZATION> Pan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Am </ORGANIZATION> jetliner crash in <LOCATION> Scotland </LOCATION>. Here is a look at five air disasters involving bombs over the past 12 years:
</TEXT>
<HEAD>NOV. 29, 1987</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Korean Air Flight 858 disappears over the jungle near the Thailand-Burma border. All 115 people aboard the <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> 707 are killed. Suspicion about a planted bomb focused on two passengers, a man and woman, detained after they were questioned about forged Japanese passports and bit into cyanide capsules hidden in cigarette filters. The couple had left the <ORGANIZATION> KAL </ORGANIZATION> flight, which was bound from <LOCATION> Baghdad </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Bangkok </LOCATION>, in <LOCATION> Abu </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dhabi </LOCATION>, one stop before it disappeared. The man succeeded in his suicide attempt, but the woman survived. South Korean officials believe the couple left bags on the plane that contained a bomb, and suggested they were North Korean agents who blew up the plane as part of a long-range scheme to disrupt the 1988 <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION> Summer Olympics. <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> called the accusation `` silly and far-fetched.''
</TEXT>
<HEAD>APRIL 2, 1986</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Four Americans are killed when a bomb under a seat explodes on <ORGANIZATION> Trans </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> Flight 840 from <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Athens </LOCATION>. Nine other passengers are injured. The <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> 727 was beginning its descent into <LOCATION> Athens </LOCATION> when the bomb blew a gaping hole in the fuselage. Two women, a mother and daughter, and the daughter's baby were killed when they were sucked from the plane and plummeted to the ground. The fourth victim, also found on the ground, was killed instantly when the bomb exploded under his seat. Authorities speculated that the terrorist who set the charge may have been confused by <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>'s recent shift to daylight-saving time. Had the bomb gone off an hour earlier _ before the jet began its descent _ the massive decompression of the fuselage would have caused a crash killing all 122 people aboard. Police said the explosive device was left under the seat by a woman carrying a Lebanese passport under the name <PERSON> Mei </PERSON> <PERSON> Mansour </PERSON> who sat in the seat earlier, when the plane was westbound. <PERSON> Mansour </PERSON> later appeared in <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> and denied responsibility.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>JUNE 22, 1985</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Air-India </ORGANIZATION> Flight 182 blows apart off the coast of <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION>, killing all 329 people aboard. The <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> 747 was on its way from <LOCATION> Toronto </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Bombay </LOCATION>, via <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>. An inquiry by the Indian government concluded that a bomb caused the crash. Canadian authorities said a man checked a suitcase onto the plane but did not board. In another incident the same day, Canadian officials say, <ORGANIZATION> Sikh </ORGANIZATION> militants planted a suitcase bomb on a Canadian jetliner in <LOCATION> Vancouver </LOCATION>. The bag exploded while being transferred to an <ORGANIZATION> Air-India </ORGANIZATION> flight at the <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION> airport, killing two baggage handlers. Despite circumstantial evidence, police have been unable to prove their contention that extremist Sikhs based in <LOCATION> British </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION> planted the bombs to retaliate for the storming of a Sikh shrine in <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> by government troops. Anonymous callers claimed responsibility for the crash on behalf of <ORGANIZATION> Sikh </ORGANIZATION> groups.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>AUG. 11, 1982</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 A 16-year-old Japanese boy is killed by a bomb that explodes aboard a <ORGANIZATION> Pan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Am </ORGANIZATION> jetliner bound from <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION>. Fifteen other passengers, including the boy's parents, are injured. The plane, carrying 285 people, landed safely despite the explosion, which occurred about 140 miles out from <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION>. No individual or group claimed responsibility for the explosion. In May 1988, a Palestinian, <PERSON> Mohammed </PERSON> <PERSON> Rashid </PERSON>, was arrested at <LOCATION> Athens </LOCATION> airport, on a tip from the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Embassy in the Greek capital, and charged with planting the bomb aboard the trans-Pacific airliner. American officials have said <PERSON> Rashid </PERSON> also was involved in the 1986 <ORGANIZATION> TWA </ORGANIZATION> bombing. His extradition to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> remains under consideration.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>OCT. 6, 1976</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 A <ORGANIZATION> Cubana </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> DC8 crashes into the sea minutes after taking off from <LOCATION> Seawell </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Barbados </LOCATION>, killing 73 people, including 24 members of the Cuban national fencing team. Nine minutes after takeoff, the pilot contacted the control tower: `` <PERSON> Seawell </PERSON>, <PERSON> Seawell </PERSON>, C0455. We have an explosion on board. We're descending fast. ... We have fire on board. ... Request immediate landing permission.'' Another explosion went off and the pilot was heard shouting, `` Shut the door!'' The plane hit the ocean several miles offshore. Four Cuban exiles living in <LOCATION> Venezuela </LOCATION> were charged with the bombing. Two were convicted, one escaped, and a fourth, anti-Castro radical <PERSON> Orlando </PERSON> <PERSON> Bosch </PERSON>, spent 11 years in Venezuelan prisons while fighting the charges, was never convicted, and finally was released and returned to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> last February.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881223-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-23-88 0112EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Armenians-Christmas     12-23 0594</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Armenians-Christmas,0611</SECOND>
<HEAD>America's Armenians Plan Somber Christmas To Commemorate Quake
Victims</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By GEORGE P. BAYLISS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The catastrophic earthquake in <LOCATION> Armenia </LOCATION> has dampened the Christmas spirit in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s Armenian community, with many festivities canceled and money normally spent on gifts being sent for relief efforts. Armenians in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, as well as in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, have canceled or postponed Christmas and New Year's parties, weddings, dances, tree decorating and other activities to mourn the thousands killed in the Dec. 7 quake. `` The earthquake has pretty much ruined Christmas for most of the Armenians I know,'' said <PERSON> Jean-Marie </PERSON> <PERSON> Atamian </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> lawyer who had volunteered to answer phones for the Armenian <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Benevolent </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Saddle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Brook </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.J. </LOCATION> `` We have canceled all of the gatherings and dances and social functions. We felt it would be totally inappropriate.'' The earthquake devastated the cities of <LOCATION> Leninakan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Spitak </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Kirovakan </LOCATION> and up to 100 rural settlements in northwest <LOCATION> Armenia </LOCATION>. Official Soviet sources have put the death toll as high as 55,000 and estimated the number of homeless at over 500,000. Christmas is celebrated Jan. 6 by the Armenian church and Dec. 25 by Armenian Catholics and Protestants. Leaders of the two branches of the Armenian church in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> declared a 40-day period of mourning when the earthquake hit. But many Armenians say the decision to mute celebrations was spontaneous. In <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, Archbishop <PERSON> Torkom </PERSON> <PERSON> Manoogian </PERSON>, head of the <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Diocese </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> the </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Armenian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION>, will hold a requiem Mass for children Jan. 7 instead of the Christmas party he usually holds for youngsters, according to <PERSON> Adrienne </PERSON> <PERSON> Alexanian </PERSON>, a volunteer at <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Vartan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Armenian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cathedral </ORGANIZATION>. About 70,000 Armenians live in the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York-New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> area. In <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, with the largest Armenian population outside the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> _ some 250,000 live in the <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> area _ Armenians have canceled weddings and holiday parties. Churches are holding special requiem services after Sunday Masses. Armenian Protestants are preparing for a somber holiday. `` Of course we will still observe <PERSON> Christ </PERSON>'s birth,'' said <PERSON> Rosey </PERSON> <PERSON> Maranjian </PERSON>, who answered the telephone for the <ORGANIZATION> Armenian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mission </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> at its headquarters in <LOCATION> Paramus </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.J. </LOCATION> `` But there is nothing to celebrate even though <PERSON> Christ </PERSON> is born.'' `` We keep asking, ` Why us?''' she said. One of her cousins died in <LOCATION> Leninakan </LOCATION>, she added. `` It's a sad way to celebrate such a joyous event,'' said the Rev. <PERSON> Moses </PERSON> <PERSON> Janbazian </PERSON>, the association's executive director. `` Instead of sending out Christmas cards to friends and exchanging gifts, we are sending the money to <LOCATION> Armenia </LOCATION>. And most families are doing that,'' said <PERSON> Shakeh </PERSON> <PERSON> Kadehjian </PERSON>, a secretary in the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> office of the Armenian <ORGANIZATION> Evangelical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION>, which celebrates Christmas Dec. 25. `` Most of the people, without asking us, are canceling their wedding ceremonies'' until after the mourning period ends Jan. 17, said Rev. <PERSON> Nareg </PERSON> <PERSON> Shrikian </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mary </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Armenian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Apostolic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Glendale </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION> `` The first reaction among Armenians was to cancel everything, not even to decorate Christmas trees,'' said <PERSON> Ara </PERSON> <PERSON> Kalaydjian </PERSON>, editor of the Armenian Mirror-Spectator, an English-language newspaper published in <LOCATION> Watertown </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mass </LOCATION>. The area is home to 30,000-40 ,000 Armenians <PERSON> Kalaydjian </PERSON> said he planned a quiet dinner with his family. `` We wo n't exchange gifts. We wo n't have a tree,'' he siad. <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Bogosian </PERSON>, editor of the Armenian Reporter, said his English-language weekly, published in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, ordinarily carries announcements of holiday events. But over the past two weeks, he said, `` all the listings carried a notation: canceled, canceled, canceled, one after another.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881223-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-23-88 0114EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-China-Nudes     12-23 0702</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-China-Nudes,0726</SECOND>
<HEAD>First All-Nude Exhibition Opens In Beijing</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By JOHN POMFRET</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Thousands packed into <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s top art gallery for the opening of <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>'s first painting exhibition devoted entirely to the study of nudes. Some leered and shook their heads in disbelief at what they saw, but many others gazed with obvious appreciation at the works. Poets, top government officials, schoolchildren, young couples and workers gathered Thursday around the paintings by some of <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s best artists. `` I feel this exhibition shows we have achieved a little more freedom. In the past you would never see this,'' said <PERSON> Wang </PERSON> <PERSON> Xing </PERSON>, 22, a student from <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> Teacher's College as he viewed a study of a man and a woman touching a bird. `` It also shows our level is rising. The paintings here move me, they are beautiful.'' `` Underneath, everyone is naked and everyone knows their nakedness,'' said Ai Qing, who at 79 is <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s best known living poet. `` Why then, when we want to paint our bodies, do so many <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> think it's strange? I think it is good.'' The Exhibition of Figure Oil Painting at the <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> Art Gallery features 128 paintings by 21 artists. Gallery official estimated that about 20,000 people came on the first day, paying about 27 cents each, five times the normal admission price. `` We have traditional nudes, realistic nudes, expressionist nudes, abstract nudes, even cubist and deformist nudes,'' said <ORGANIZATION> Ge </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pengren </ORGANIZATION>, a painting instructor at the <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Arts </ORGANIZATION> who organized the show. `` Our purpose is to educate the people about nudes and to show them, through these paintings, how we value life.'' Ge said the exhibition, which was approved by the <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Culture </ORGANIZATION> before it was opened, had n't met with any `` major interference'' since it was sanctioned a year ago. `` When we chose the paintings, there was no censorship at all,'' he said. Artistic freedom in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> is very limited. Books and movies have to pass through a censor and artists are often restricted in what they can create. During the ultra-leftist Cultural Revolution from 1966-76, painters were banned from displaying nude paintings and only in 1978 were they again allowed to use nude models. Society and the state have been slow in accepting the change. Newspapers carried a report earlier this year about a 19-year-old girl who suffered a nervous breakdown because of the abuse she received for posing nude at the <ORGANIZATION> Nanjing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Arts </ORGANIZATION>. In recent years, only two exhibitions devoted to nudes have opened in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>. In addition, a nude mural by <PERSON> Yuan </PERSON> <PERSON> Yunsheng </PERSON>, painted in 1979 during a period of relative cultural freedom, remains covered at the <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION>. `` In the past, society's ideas about morality were a little backward,'' said Ge. `` It was like we were afraid of our bodies. With this exhibition, we want to open a new road.'' Inded, the educational nature of the exhibition is very strong. A lengthy explanation of the nude's place in art history lines the middle of one hall. A discussion of the artists' work lines another. `` We still have to introduce things to the masses,'' said artist <PERSON> Cao </PERSON> <PERSON> Li </PERSON>. `` Without this introduction, many people would n't understand at all.'' But even with the introduction, <PERSON> Fu </PERSON> <PERSON> Kegan </PERSON> was having a hard time. `` I'm going to stand here until I understand this painting,'' the former teacher said as he stood, head shaking, in front of a gray canvas. `` The artist told me this is an abstract nude,'' said <PERSON> Fu </PERSON>, 68. `` But it looks like a pile of rocks.'' Despite his confusion, <PERSON> Fu </PERSON> said he welcomed such exhibitions. `` We hear that nude exhibitions in the West are normal,'' he said. `` So why in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> should they be so mysterious? This show could teach people that nude painting is n't dangerous.'' `` It may not be dangerous,'' said <PERSON> Wang </PERSON> <PERSON> Bing </PERSON>, 48, a housewife. `` But I think it's dirty. Look at those boys staring at that painting.'' Across the room, a pack of 20 men appeared perilously close to diving into a painting of two <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> women. `` Oh, there will always be uneducated people,'' <PERSON> Fu </PERSON> said. `` But maybe this show will teach them to change.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881223-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-23-88 0116EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Israel-Profiles     12-23 0593</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Israel-Profiles,0612</SECOND>
<HEAD>Familiar Faces In New Israeli Cabinet</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Israel-Politics</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>JERUSALEM (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Sketches of four key figures in the new Israeli Cabinet:
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 Prime Minister <PERSON> Yitzhak </PERSON> <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON>, leader of the right-wing <ORGANIZATION> Likud </ORGANIZATION> bloc, retains his post in the new government. A former underground fighter and <ORGANIZATION> Mossad </ORGANIZATION> secret agent, <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON> has been characterized as a politician with the tenacity of a bulldog. He has rejected any negotiations with the <ORGANIZATION> Palestine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Oganization </ORGANIZATION> and is opposed to calls for an international peace conference on the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION>. But he has pledged to introduce new peace proposals after his new government is in place. <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON>, 73, was born in <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> and emigrated to what was then <LOCATION> Palestine </LOCATION> in 1938, a decade before the founding of <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>. He has a law degree and did not enter politics until 1956. He served as prime minister in 1983-84 and again starting Oct. 14, 1986.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Shimon </PERSON> <PERSON> Peres </PERSON> moves to the <ORGANIZATION> Finance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> from the <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION>. The son of a Polish timber merchant, he arrived in <LOCATION> Palestine </LOCATION> in 1934 and as a teen-ager delivered messages on his motorcycle for <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s founding father, <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Ben-Gurion </PERSON>. <PERSON> Peres </PERSON>, 65, has written at least four books and has said that in his youth he wanted to be a poet. He is seen as an intellectual, but many Israelis also view him as arrogant and distant. <PERSON> Peres </PERSON>' once-dominant <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> has won national elections only once in the past 11 years, and the 1983 victory was not by a sufficient margin to allow Labor to rule without <ORGANIZATION> Likud </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Peres </PERSON> favors an international peace conference and has promoted the idea of a dialogue with Palestinians in confederation with <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION>. As finance minister, <PERSON> Peres </PERSON> will have to confront growing budget deficits and major financial problems in <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s industries, including companies owned by the Labor-allied <ORGANIZATION> Histadrut </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federation </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Yitzhak </PERSON> <PERSON> Rabin </PERSON> remains defense minister, a post he held when the Israeli Cabinet voted to withdraw its invading force from <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> after a three-year occupation. A native of <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION>, he was ambassador to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> from 1968-73. His term as prime minister was cut short in 1977 when he was forced to resign in a scandal over his wife's illegal overseas bank accounts. He and <PERSON> Peres </PERSON> have had a long rivalry for leadership of the <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Rabin </PERSON>, 66, fought in World War II, taking part in allied operations in <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION> and fighting behind enemy lines. He was army chief of staff during the 1967 Six-Day War, in which <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> took control of the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strip </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Golan </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Heights </LOCATION> from neighboring Arab countries. He has ordered a firm response to the year-old <LOCATION> Palestinian </LOCATION> uprising in the occupied territories.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Moshe </PERSON> <PERSON> Arens </PERSON> replaces <PERSON> Peres </PERSON> as foreign minister. A native of <LOCATION> Lithuania </LOCATION>, he immigrated with his family to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> at the age of 14 and studied aeronautical engineering at the <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Technology </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Massachusetts </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Technology </ORGANIZATION>. He moved to <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> in 1950 and is said to be proudest of the planes and missiles he designed here, both for the <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> military and for export. Colleagues describe <PERSON> Arens </PERSON> as cool and thoughtful. He was ambassador to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> in 1982-83, and he is likely to be heavily engaged in dialogue with <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> following the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> decision to open talks with the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION>, which <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> considers a terrorist organization. <PERSON> Arens </PERSON>, 62, is an extreme conservative and reportedly turned down the job of defense minister in 1980 because he opposed the just-concluded Israel-Egypt peace treaty.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881223-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-23-88 0121EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Crash-Warning     12-23 0633</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Crash-Warning,630</SECOND>
<HEAD>Legal Experts Say Crash Could Raise Liability Problems For Pan Am</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Crash Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PETE YOST</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The decision by <ORGANIZATION> Pan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airways </ORGANIZATION> and the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government not to alert the public to a fairly specific bomb threat received long before <ORGANIZATION> Pan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Am </ORGANIZATION> Flight 103 crashed in <LOCATION> Scotland </LOCATION> could raise liability problems for the airline but probably not for the government, attorneys say. `` I do n't know of any legal requirement that the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> go public on a thing like that other than notifying the airline involved and possibly the embassies,'' said <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Kreindler </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> lawyer who specializes in aviation accident cases. `` It's a difficult area, but if the government notifies the airline in question, I think the government position is justified,'' <PERSON> Kreindler </PERSON> said Thursday. <PERSON> Kreindler </PERSON> said there are `` some policy reasons from the government's standpoint for not'' notifying the traveling public. One of the purposes of the Federal Aviation Act is to enhance aviation and an announcement of a specific threat which might not be bona fide could conceivably result in travelers not flying. Flight 103, originating in <LOCATION> Frankfurt </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, with a change of planes at <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Heathrow </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION>, crashed in <LOCATION> Scotland </LOCATION> on Wednesday, killing all 258 people aboard and more than 20 on the ground. It was bound for <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Phyllis </PERSON> <PERSON> Oakley </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman, said that an unidentified individual telephoned the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Helsinki </LOCATION> on Dec. 5 and said there would be a bombing attempt within two weeks against a <ORGANIZATION> Pan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Am </ORGANIZATION> aircraft flying from <LOCATION> Frankfurt </LOCATION> to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. The conduit would be an `` unwitting'' passenger who would take the device from <LOCATION> Helsinki </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Frankfurt </LOCATION> and then board a U.S.-bound flight, she said. It has not been established, however, that the telephoned tip was related to the Pan Am crash. Mrs. <PERSON> Oakley </PERSON> said dozens of threats are received each day and all are taken seriously. <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Bremer </PERSON>, who heads the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>'s counter-terrorism office, said there have been 87 calls similar to the <LOCATION> Helsinki </LOCATION> call over the past three months. But the Dec. 5 call, apparently from a tipster, appeared to be taken more seriously than most others. Many <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> embassies were apprised of the threat, including the <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> mission in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>, where a notice of the threat was posted on a bulletin board. No word went out to the general public. The prior notification `` is going to raise an interesting question'' in connection with the other passengers `` who were not members of the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> staff whether they should have received similar notice from <ORGANIZATION> Pan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Am </ORGANIZATION>,'' said <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> N. </PERSON> <PERSON> Tompkins </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, a lawyer specializing in defending airlines in accident cases. <PERSON> Bremer </PERSON> said in an interview Thursday night that not enough is known to conclude that sabotage caused the jumbo jet to crash. `` We do n't know if this is a terrorist attack,'' he said. Asked what an airline's obligation is once it has been notified of a specific threat, <PERSON> Kreindler </PERSON> said, `` It's a tough situation. ... They do n't have to stop operating or stop flying, but certainly they have a duty to meticulously inspect.'' <PERSON> Kreindler </PERSON> said that in some other instances of terrorism involving air travel, evidence-gathering in lawsuits has focused on airline security precautions. Officials said <ORGANIZATION> Pan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Am </ORGANIZATION> stepped up security at key airports in the wake of the threat. Anyone filing lawsuits seeking settlements in excess of a $ 75,000 limit in international airlines cases would have to show willful misconduct on the part of the airline in order to be successful. <PERSON> Tompkins </PERSON> said willful misconduct is extremely difficult to prove, carrying with it a heavier burden of proof than gross negligence. Willful misconduct is a wrongful act done intentionally or an improper act done wantonly with knowledge of the probable consequences.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881223-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-23-88 0123EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-ArmyEspionage Bjt   12-23 0637</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Army Espionage, Bjt,635</SECOND>
<HEAD>Pentagon Says Espionage Damage May Be Limited</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By NORMAN BLACK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Military Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The damage to national security caused by a soldier accused of spying for the <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION> Pact might not be as severe as originally feared, <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> officials say. The officials, who insisted on anonymity, said Thursday that continuing interrogation of Warrant Officer <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Hall </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON> `` suggests he might have been selective in the documents he passed.'' `` When all is said and done, it does n't look too bad,'' said one official. `` It's not great, but it's not a crisis, either,'' said another. `` The counter-intelligence people are wringing him out now,'' said one source. `` He's still cooperating, singing.'' Hall, 30, of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, was arrested Wednesday at his home near <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Stewart </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ga. </LOCATION>, by <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> intelligence agents after a successful Army-FBI sting operation. Lt. Col. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Chapla </PERSON>, an <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> spokesman, said <PERSON> Hall </PERSON> was moved Thursday from <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Stewart </LOCATION> to a prison cell at <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Meade </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Md. </LOCATION>, outside <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> D.C </ORGANIZATION>. According to affidavits filed in federal court in <LOCATION> Savannah </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ga. </LOCATION>, where <PERSON> Fort </PERSON> <PERSON> Stewart </PERSON> is located, <PERSON> Hall </PERSON> bragged to an unidentified <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> agent `` that he had been passing highly sensitive signal intelligence documents to both the Soviets and the East German intelligence services since late 1982.'' `` Hall boasted of the important signal intelligence information he had passed, and admitted his motivation to be greed,'' the document said. It did not give details on the information. Hall allegedly passed the information through a Turkish-born, naturalized citizen named <PERSON> Huseyin </PERSON> <PERSON> Yildirim </PERSON>. <PERSON> Yildirim </PERSON> also was arrested Wednesday at his home in <LOCATION> Belleair </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>, near <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Petersburg </LOCATION>. He had been scheduled to appear at a bond hearing Thursday but the proceeding was postponed until Tuesday because <PERSON> Yildirim </PERSON>'s attorney had a scheduling conflict <PERSON> Chapla </PERSON> said <PERSON> Hall </PERSON> was moved to `` facilitate security,'' noting the base at <ORGANIZATION> Fort </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Meade </ORGANIZATION> has `` secure facilities'' that can be used for courts-martial that involve the presentation of classified material as evidence. Fort <PERSON> Meade </PERSON> also is the site of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION>, the supersecret spy agency that conducts electronic surveillance around the world. Hall worked in the field of electronic surveillance for the <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> and, indirectly, the <ORGANIZATION> NSA </ORGANIZATION>. The spokesman declined to say whether <ORGANIZATION> NSA </ORGANIZATION> specialists were sitting in on the interrogation of Hall. <PERSON> Chapla </PERSON> said <PERSON> Hall </PERSON> not been formally charged with any crimes as of Thursday evening but was being detained under the Uniform Code of Military Justice for suspicion of espionage. He can be held for up to three days on that basis, <PERSON> Chapla </PERSON> said. According to <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> records, <PERSON> Hall </PERSON> held a `` Top Secret'' security clearance and spent most of his 12 years in the service at posts in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, where the <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> maintains electronic listening posts and intelligence units that would play critical roles in time of war. During his service career, Hall rose in rank to a point where he could have provided `` a detailed and damaging look at our techniques and capabilities when it comes to intercepting radio and voice traffic and breaking codes,'' explained one official. `` But we've got to find out how far he went. He could have kept his handlers happy with less sensitive stuff, too.'' Added an <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> source: `` He was a worker bee. He had familiarity with the techniques and technology of the business of signals intelligence. It's logical to say he could have really hurt us.'' <PERSON> Chapla </PERSON> said <PERSON> Hall </PERSON> had been flown on an Army airplane from <PERSON> Fort </PERSON> <PERSON> Stewart </PERSON> to <PERSON> Fort </PERSON> <PERSON> Meade </PERSON> on Thursday afternoon and that in the process, legal jurisdiction over the warrant officer was shifted to the commander of the Military District of <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. That commander is Maj. Gen. <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Hilbert </PERSON>. Should investigators recommend a grand jury-type proceeding and court martial, it will be up to <PERSON> Hilbert </PERSON> to decide how to proceed, <PERSON> Chapla </PERSON> added.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881223-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-23-88 0127EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-AIDS-Mice Bjt   12-23 0584</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AIDS-Mice, Bjt,580</SECOND>
<HEAD>Lowly Rodent Thrust To Forefront Of War On AIDS</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JERRY ESTILL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Researchers have infected mice with the AIDS virus for the first time, moving the lowly rodent to the front lines of the battle against the fatal disease. Mice have long been a staple of biomedical research, but until scientists in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> were able to develop mice with human immune systems _ and then get the AIDS virus to spread in them _ the animals had been largely useless in AIDS research. The main breakthrough _ getting a human immune system to function in mice _ has had scientists excited since the work was reported in Science magazine in September. The current issue of the magazine, out today, contains an updated report from the same <ORGANIZATION> Stanford </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> researchers confirming their assumption that they would be able to get the AIDS virus _ HIV _ to `` take'' in their special mice. Mice with standard immune systems are impervious to the AIDS virus. In another report in Science, scientists at the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institutes </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> provided additional information on their previously reported success in producing mice that carry the genetic code for the AIDS virus in every cell of their bodies. A third paper is on the work of scientists at the Hospital for Sick Children in <LOCATION> Toronto </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>, who have transplanted human bone marrow into mice with human-like immune systems. That research is geared toward studying such blood diseases as leukemia and sickle cell anemia. As previously reported, the human immune system was developed in mice by transplanting liver, thymus, spleen and lymph node cells from aborted human fetuses into them. The significance of all three reports is not in what has been learned thus far about AIDS or any other specific disease, but rather the demonstrated ability to use mice in new ways. For example, the <ORGANIZATION> Stanford </ORGANIZATION> scientists purposely limited the scope of their initial efforts to infect mice with AIDS to observing them for no more than eight weeks, too short to lead to full-blown AIDS, but enough to show researchers the virus would flourish in their new breed of mice. `` By limiting the study to eight weeks, we can not yet predict whether the mice would get the full AIDS syndrome,'' said Dr. <PERSON> Irving </PERSON> <PERSON> Weissman </PERSON>, one of the Stanford researchers. `` It's too early to tell. This experiment was n't designed to mimic AIDS in human patients exactly.'' In a twist of irony, 127 of the 130 the special `` AIDS-coded'' mice developed at NIHealth died in a freak accident earlier this month, when the ventalition system in the building housing them was cut off too long during repairs. Although it will take four to five months to replenish the <ORGANIZATION> NIH </ORGANIZATION> herd, <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Fauci </PERSON>, director of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Allergy </ORGANIZATION> and Infectious Disease said they `` are expected to be valuable not only for better understanding of HIV effects on tissue, but also for testing of therapeutics to prevent HIV-induced disease.'' In the <ORGANIZATION> NIH </ORGANIZATION> work, complete copies of the AIDS virus DNA were injected into fertilized mouse eggs that subsequently were implanted into adult female mice. Of the 64 mice born, researchers identified seven `` founder mice'' that contained complete copies of the AIDS virus DNA in their chromosomes and subsequently transmitted the copies to their offspring. Dr. <PERSON> Malcolm </PERSON> <PERSON> Martin </PERSON>, head of the <ORGANIZATION> NIH </ORGANIZATION> team, said the accident was made worse by the fact that none of the `` founder mice'' was among the three survivors.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881223-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-23-88 0037EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-SRPManager     12-23 0241</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-SRP Manager,0247</SECOND>
<HEAD>SRP Manager Says Plant Could Be Started Immediately If Needed</HEAD>
<DATELINE>AUGUSTA, Ga. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The manager of the <LOCATION> Savannah </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> nuclear material production plant said Thursday the facility's reactors, which have been shut down because of safety concerns, could be restarted immediately if necessary. `` I certainly think they can be restarted safely,'' said <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> T. </PERSON> <PERSON> Lowe </PERSON>. `` I think if the nation judged there was a need for the materials ... they could be restarted today.'' The plant near <LOCATION> Aiken </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> S.C. </LOCATION>, is the nation's sole producer of tritium, a crucial ingredient in nuclear weapons. <PERSON> Lowe </PERSON>, who works for <ORGANIZATION> Du </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pont </ORGANIZATION>, the operator of the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> plant, said in an interview Thursday with The <ORGANIZATION> Augusta </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chronicle </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Augusta </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Herald </ORGANIZATION> that political pressures have contributed to recent, highly publicized problems at the plant. <PERSON> Lowe </PERSON> was interviewed on the same day that <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Herrington </PERSON> announced that ultrasonic testing will be used to check for possible cracks in reactor vessels. That could delay <ORGANIZATION> SRP </ORGANIZATION>'s restart until next summer All three <LOCATION> Savannah </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> reactors have been shut down since summer for safety upgrades and maintenance. <PERSON> Lowe </PERSON> declined to say when he thought the plant would resume operations. `` I think that remains to be defined. There has been speculation that it would be six months or 12 months. I really think until the ... criteria are well defined ... it's sheer speculation to pick a date,'' <PERSON> Lowe </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881223-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-23-88 0128EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-TradingSecrets     12-23 0205</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Trading Secrets,190</SECOND>
<HEAD>Pentagon Says Official Mistaken In Listing Contractors Under
Investigation</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> official who told <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> eight major defense contractors were under investigation for possible illegal trading of classified documents was mistaken, a <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> spokesman said. The spokesman, <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Howard </PERSON>, said Thursday that only four of the companies are being investigated. <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> said <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Donnelly </PERSON>, director of the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Investigative </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>, `` made a mistake'' when he told the <ORGANIZATION> Joint </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> on Wednesday that <ORGANIZATION> Litton </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Systems </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> McDonnell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Douglas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Northrop </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, and <ORGANIZATION> TRW </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> remain part of the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION>'s investigation of alleged trafficking of department secrets among defense contractors Investigations of these companies were closed in 1986, <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> said <PERSON> Donnelly </PERSON> was correct in listing four other companies as remaining under investigation. Those are <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dynamics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Matin </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Marietta </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Saunders </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associates </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Donnelly </PERSON> had insisted the eight companies remained under investigation, even after being told by subcommittee members that his testimony was at odds with a government report on the investigation The <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> also criticized the congressional panel for making the information public. `` We do not approve of the committee making public this type of information,'' the department said in a statement.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881223-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-23-88 0130EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     12-23 1056</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,1099</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names In The News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SANTA BARBARA, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A predawn <PERSON> Kenny </PERSON> <PERSON> Loggins </PERSON> concert for Japanese television drew a `` lynch mob'' of pajama-clad residents to the stage after they were awakened by the big beat of the unauthorized show, police said. `` Our switchboard lit up like the Rockefeller Center Christmas tree,'' said Police Lt. <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>. Complaints began coming in shortly before 5 a.m. Wednesday. The show was set for prime time in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, just before 10 p.m. <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> said the show from the steps of the historic Old Mission did not have the city's permission, and when officers arrived they found a wooden stage full of rock musicians, speakers, electrical generators, lights and cameras plus a production crew of 75. The singer-songwriter later left without being reached for comment. Police shut the show down despite protests from the producer, <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Okumura </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>, who said he would lose millions of dollars, according to <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>. Officials said permits he had requested via facsimile machine a few hours before the show claimed it would be `` low volume.'' Some officers had to hold back angry neighborhood residents, many of whom came to the scene in their nightclothes. `` Understandably, it resembled a lynch mob,'' <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> said. The Rev. <PERSON> Virgil </PERSON> <PERSON> Cordano </PERSON> of the Mission said he had been told the production would be quiet, and he granted permission for use of the building as a backdrop because `` it was good for <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Barbara </LOCATION> and good for the Mission.'' `` I thought I was doing the city of <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Barbara </LOCATION> a favor and spreading the good news to <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION>,'' he said. The matter will be forwarded to the City Attorney's office for further review, police said. <PERSON> Okumura </PERSON> did not immediately return a telephone message left by The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> on his answering machine Thursday night.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> will join the office of <ORGANIZATION> Manhattan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> Attorney <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Morgenthau </PERSON> in August, working for a man who once worked as a prosecutor for his father. <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, a 29-year-old third-year student at <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Law </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION>, will start as a prosecutor at just under $ 30,000 a year if he graduates next summer and passes the state bar examination, according to prosecution sources who spoke on condition of anonymity. <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, interviewed earlier this month by <PERSON> Morgenthau </PERSON>, will be one of 20 just-graduated new hires next summer. Until he passes the bar exam he will not litigate cases. Instead he will help in research and trial preparation. The fledgling prosecutor was spotted a few weeks ago in the <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION> Criminal Courts Building in the 11th-floor courtroom where accused child killer <PERSON> Joel </PERSON> <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON> is on trial for allegedly beating his 6-year-old illegally adopted daughter to death. <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> declined to talk to reporters. <PERSON> Morgenthau </PERSON> was appointed a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> attorney during President <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>'s administration. He resigned to run for governor of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> against <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON> <PERSON> Rockefeller </PERSON> in 1962. He lost and resumed his job as a prosecutor.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Max </PERSON> <PERSON> von </PERSON> <PERSON> Sydow </PERSON>, whose roles have ranged from <PERSON> Jesus </PERSON> <PERSON> Christ </PERSON> to intergalactic space villain <PERSON> Ming </PERSON> the Merciless, dredged memories from his childhood in <LOCATION> Sweden </LOCATION> to play a downtrodden field hand in his latest movie. In `` Pelle the Conqueror,'' which won top honors at this year's <ORGANIZATION> Cannes </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Film </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Festival </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Sydow </PERSON> portrays <PERSON> Lasse </PERSON> <PERSON> Karlsson </PERSON>, father of the title character The 59-year-old, 6-foot-4 actor tells the audience about the itinerant farm worker's life of labor and oppression with a jerky, shuffling walk _ hands flapping, elbows and knees protruding _ marked by habitual head bobbing of a servile peasant. The son of a university professor, <PERSON> von </PERSON> <PERSON> Sydow </PERSON> left the city after the spring thaw to visit maternal relatives in Swedish farm country. `` I felt I knew this man,'' <PERSON> von </PERSON> <PERSON> Sydow </PERSON> said. `` I met people like this, spent every summer with them.'' The story of <PERSON> Pelle </PERSON>'s struggle to overcome social restrictions and farm labor poverty accurately depicts real life during <PERSON> von </PERSON> <PERSON> Sydow </PERSON>'s childhood, the actor said `` The social structure in <LOCATION> Scandinavia </LOCATION> was pretty primitive in rural areas until, oh, the early'40s,'' he said. `` The people who worked the big farms were essentially migrant workers.'' <PERSON> Von </PERSON> <PERSON> Sydow </PERSON> has appeared on stage, and in numerous films including, `` The Greatest Story Ever Told,'' in which he played <PERSON> Jesus </PERSON>; `` The Exorcist,'' and `` Flash <PERSON> Gordon </PERSON>,'' in which he portrayed the science-fiction villain <PERSON> Ming </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Thirteen-year-old actress <PERSON> Drew </PERSON> <PERSON> Barrymore </PERSON> has been released from a rehabilitation center after treatment for alcohol abuse, her publicist said. She was released `` a couple of days ago,'' publicist <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Freeman </PERSON> said Thursday. `` She is in good health and great spirits.'' No other details would be provided, <PERSON> Freeman </PERSON> said. Miss <PERSON> Barrymore </PERSON> already was an actress with television commercial and movie experience at age 6 when she played the impetuous <PERSON> Gertie </PERSON> in `` E.T. the Extra-Terrestrial.'' The daughter the reclusive <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Barrymor </PERSON> -RCB- ~ d Hungarian-born actress <PERSON> Ildiko </PERSON> <PERSON> Jaid </PERSON>, Miss <PERSON> Barrymore </PERSON> is the granddaughter of <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Barrymore </PERSON>, who starred in such film classics as `` Grand Hotel'' and `` Dr. <PERSON> Jekyll </PERSON> and Mr <PERSON> Hyde </PERSON>.'' Miss <PERSON> Barrymore </PERSON> also has starred in movies such as `` Firestarter'' and `` Cat's Eye.'' She appeared in the made-for-television movies `` Conspiracy of Love'' and `` <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Sawyer </PERSON> and <PERSON> Huckleberry </PERSON> <PERSON> Finn </PERSON>.''
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> PEAPACK-GLADSTONE </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.J. </LOCATION> -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> -RRB- _ It's no king's ransom, but even the monarch from <LOCATION> Morocco </LOCATION> has to enjoy unexpected tax rebates. The borough council determined this week that <PERSON> King </PERSON> <PERSON> Hassan </PERSON> <PERSON> II </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Morocco </LOCATION> had paid too much in 1988. A check of $ 4,894 was sent to <PERSON> Hassan </PERSON>, who owns 500 acres of property in Peapack-Gladstone and two adjacent towns. Councilman <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON> <PERSON> McDowell </PERSON> said the refund comes from tax appeals heard by the <ORGANIZATION> Somerset </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Taxation </ORGANIZATION> that were not contested by the borough. Last month, <PERSON> Hassan </PERSON> was awarded a $ 146,000 rebate on his county taxes because his estate was overappraised. The county revised his land's appraised value from $ 25.98 million to $ 7.3 million. As a result, the monarch's 1988 county tax bill was cut from $ 204,591 to $ 57,764. The king's attorney, <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Goodwin </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Saddle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION>, argued before county tax officials in October that 225 acres of the king's estate should be assessed at cheaper farmland rates for 1988 In addition, <PERSON> Goodwin </PERSON> maintained the remaining 97 acres the monarch owns in the borough also were assessed too high. The king's land is spread over <LOCATION> Bedminster </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Far </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hills </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Peapack-Gladstone </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881223-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-23-88 0131EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Ray-Parole     12-23 0329</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Ray-Parole,0339</SECOND>
<HEAD>Governor Halts James Earl Ray Parole Hearing</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By D.A. ELLIOTT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NASHVILLE, Tenn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Gov. <PERSON> Ned </PERSON> <PERSON> McWherter </PERSON> on Thursday blocked a Jan. 26 parole hearing for the man convicted in the 1968 sniper slaying of civil rights leader <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Luther </PERSON> <PERSON> King </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>. <PERSON> McWherter </PERSON> exercised a law giving the governor authority to halt early parole hearings for prisoners convicted of certain crimes <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Earl </PERSON> <PERSON> Ray </PERSON>, 60, is serving 99 years in prison for first-degree murder of King in <LOCATION> Memphis </LOCATION> on April 4, 1968. A 1985 law designed to reduce prison overcrowding made <PERSON> Ray </PERSON> eligible for a parole hearing in November. `` We've been advised that he -LRB- Ray -RRB- is among that class of inmates who will be affected by that order,'' said <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, <PERSON> McWherter </PERSON>'s chief of staff <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> said the order was effective immediately for <PERSON> Ray </PERSON>, who has been turned down for early parole at least twice before. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Welles </PERSON>, legal counsel for the governor, said <PERSON> McWherter </PERSON>'s decision would not affect <PERSON> Ray </PERSON>'s original parole eligibility date in 1998 but removes him from consideration for an early release because of his escape record <PERSON> Ray </PERSON> was a fugitive from a <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION> prison at the time of King's murder He is held at <ORGANIZATION> Brushy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mountain </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Prison </ORGANIZATION>, from which he escaped in June 1977 and was tracked down and placed briefly on Death Row in <LOCATION> Nashville </LOCATION>. King was in <LOCATION> Memphis </LOCATION> to assist in a strike by city sanitation workers seeking higher pay on the day he was felled by a sniper's bullet <PERSON> Ray </PERSON> was identified from fingerprints found on a rifle near the <PERSON> Lorraine </PERSON> <PERSON> Motel </PERSON>, where King was standing on a balcony at the time of his death. <PERSON> Ray </PERSON> pleaded guilty on the day of his trial on March 9, 1969, but retracted his story three days later and has since maintained his innocence. <PERSON> McWherter </PERSON> had said he opposed <PERSON> Ray </PERSON>'s parole but would not try to influence the state <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Paroles </ORGANIZATION>, which is independent from the administration.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881223-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-23-88 0132EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lites     12-23 0675</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lites,0703</SECOND>
<HEAD>On The Light Side</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BERLIN, Vt. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Lucky the lobster has gone back to sea, thanks to an outpouring of support for the 17-pound crustacean who proved too big for the tank at the Fisherman's Galley seafood restaurant. Waitresses took up a collection from staff and customers to pay the giant critter's expenses for a trip to <LOCATION> Portsmouth </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.H. </LOCATION>, where it recently boarded a lobster boat for the trip out to sea. `` The chef and I packed him up and off he went,'' said restaurant manager <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Renaud </PERSON>. Lucky, wrapped in salt-water-soaked paper, traveled in an insulated box with ice packs. Lobsters can breathe out of water. Lucky's driver was <PERSON> Shelley </PERSON> <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON>, a waitress and one of his most ardent supporters. <PERSON> Renaud </PERSON> said one of the restaurant's reasons for giving up Lucky was that it needed room in its tank for other, more normal-size lobsters.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>HOLYOKE, Mass. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Debra and <PERSON> Gregory </PERSON> <PERSON> Linderme </PERSON> did n't get a surprise party on their joint birthday but they did receive an unexpected gift against long odds: 7-pound, 20-inch <PERSON> Brian </PERSON> <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> Linderme </PERSON>. The Lindermes, both born on Dec. 21, did n't expect the baby until Dec. 27. Nevertheless, he emerged at 5:30 p.m. Wednesday in <LOCATION> Providence </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Holyoke </LOCATION>. Linderme, a 25-year-old <LOCATION> Holyoke </LOCATION> landscaper, said he thought he might get an unexpected birthday gift when his 22-year-old wife woke him at 2 a.m. with contractions. `` I was pretty amazed that she was going to have it that day,'' he said. `` You ca n't ask for a better birthday present.'' The odds of three people in the same family being born on the same day are 7.5 in 1 million, according to <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Buonaccorsi </PERSON>, a mathematics professor at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Massachusetts </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Amherst </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>PITTSBURGH (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A suburban fire company that published a 1989 calendar displaying photographs of scantily clad women will bow to complaints from feminists by publishing a beefcake version for 1990. `` We know what these ladies want, and we'll give it to them,'' said <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Haeck </PERSON>, chief of the <ORGANIZATION> Pleasant </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hills </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Volunteer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fire </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> `` They say we've exploited women with our calendar. Well, next year we'll even up the score.'' A calendar featuring scantily clad men will accompany the next version of the cheesecake calendar, he said recently. `` We're not real good-looking guys, so we might only use a couple of our guys and hire professionals,'' <PERSON> Haeck </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Haeck </PERSON> said the company received letters from women demanding the second version featuring men. Meanwhile, he said, the 1989 `` Blazes of Glory'' calendar is `` selling ... like crazy.'' The company produced the calendar, priced at $ 12.95 by mail, after more traditional fund-raising methods failed to raise the $ 800,000 needed to for fire equipment.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>TRENTON, N.J. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Yes, <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>, even <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Claus </LOCATION> gets parking tickets. <PERSON> Wes </PERSON> <PERSON> Rupell </PERSON> looked authentic when he pulled up at the <ORGANIZATION> Hughes </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Complex </ORGANIZATION> on Thursday to distribute candy canes and yuletide cheer. He sported a real beard, jingle bells, spectacles, rosy cheeks and the requisite red suit. But that did n't prevent the long arm of the law from slapping him with a parking ticket at the state-operated child care center. `` I say, ` Bah, humbug! Three days before Christmas a <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> gets a ticket,'' said <PERSON> Cindy </PERSON> <PERSON> Carella </PERSON>, who runs the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Juniors </ORGANIZATION> center, which cares for children of state employees. It seems the officer who spotted his car illegally parked in a popular spot outside the state's headquarters for law and order did n't buy the sign he posted in his window. The sign said <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> was making a brief stop inside at a children's party. Ms. <PERSON> Carella </PERSON> said <PERSON> Rupell </PERSON> spent about 30 minutes with the 25 youngsters, distributing candy canes and letting them sit on his lap. Because parking is tight at the state building, she had told him to park in front if he could n't find a spot. `` Everyone should have a <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> like this,'' she said. `` He even ties jingle bells to his pants so he jingles when he walks.'' Ms. <PERSON> Carella </PERSON> said she will foot the bill.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881223-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-23-88 0133EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-DukakisInterview Bjt   12-23 0689</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Dukakis Interview, Bjt,0709</SECOND>
<HEAD>Dukakis Won't Judge Bush Yet, But He Applauds Some Moves</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto BX1</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CHRISTOPHER B. DALY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BOSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Gov. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> gave President-elect <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> some early praise in his first interview since losing the election, and said he was still `` decompressing'' from the campaign and would n't want to replay it. `` There's not much sense in rerunning the campaign,'' the defeated <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> candidate told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> on Thursday. `` I mean, we did some things well, we did other things not so well. It was n't successful. Obviously, I'm disappointed. Lots of people are disappointed. We worked very hard. But I do n't think it's something to dwell on. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> declined an opportunity to criticize <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, whom he had lambasted during a bitter campaign, saying he would give the president-elect `` a good six months to a year'' before speaking out. However, the governor, who attacked President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s policy in <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> during the campaign, said he was pleased by reports that <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has decided not to ask <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> immediately for renewed <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> support for the rightist Contra rebels in <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> and that <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> hopes to forge a bipartisan consensus and involve Latin leaders. `` I think it's the right policy,'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> said. `` When I met with him I strongly urged him to do that. I said I think the present policy is a failure, it's getting worse not better.'' `` If that's the way the new administration begins, then I think that's hopeful,'' the governor said. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, who held one press conference immediately after his loss to assess the campaign, refused to review the campaign in detail, saying he preferred to focus on the future. But he also declined to tip his hand about any plans he may have for his own career after his current term as governor ends in 1990. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> has refused previously to say whether he would run for president again. `` It's much too early. At this point, I'm decompressing, working hard on what's happening here, enjoying a certain amount of normalcy in my life,'' he said. Seated in his <ORGANIZATION> Statehouse </ORGANIZATION> office after a week's vacation in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> appeared relaxed and reflective, more interested in his state's budget problems than in the national agenda he was pushing before losing to <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> 54 percent to 46 percent just six weeks ago. `` It's been quite a year. And I must say it's nice to reflect a little bit on the blessings of life, welcome my crew home and to play the role of father and husband, and enjoy and relax a little bit,'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> said. Asked if he ever has days when he wishes he could have another shot at the campaign, or even another week to battle <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> said no. `` At some point, there has to be a conclusion. You work hard to that day, then people go and vote. Certainly, nobody ever suggested <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> presidential campaigns are too short. Twenty months is a long time.'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, who had never waged a national political campaign before, said his biggest surprise was the change that overtook him immediately after the Democratic National Convention in July. `` I think the one thing that you never quite experience until you experience it is the post-convention period _ when, unfortunately, you are kind of walled off from citizens, communities. ... `` Everything you do is a kind of massive public event. I found that difficult, frustrating. I do n't think it's good. But it is the presidency and the most important political office there is, and that's the reality,'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> said. The governor said the process could be improved. `` But at this point,'' he said, `` I do n't have any brilliant ideas for changing it.'' Asked to evaluate <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s initial appointments and policy statements, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> said it's too soon to draw conclusions. `` A new president deserves a chance to put a team together and get under way. Everything is n't going to be perfect; there will be bumps along the way,'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> said. `` These are all things that had been deferred, swept under the rug _ this kind of thing. He's got to deal with them,'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881223-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-23-88 0140EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Terrorism     12-23 0749</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Terrorism,730</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHINGTON TODAY: Looking For Clues On Terrorism</HEAD>
<BYLINE>An AP News Analysis</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>By BARRY SCHWEID</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Diplomatic Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
