<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880905-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-05-88 2332EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Israel-Spy     09-05 0277</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Israel-Spy,0283</SECOND>
<HEAD>Soviet Emigree Accused Of Being Moscow Spy Goes On Trial</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TEL AVIV, Israel (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A Soviet emigrant with links to <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> politicians and military officers went on trial Monday insisting his confession of spying for the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> was obtained under duress, his lawyer said. <PERSON> Shabtai </PERSON> <PERSON> Kalmanovich </PERSON>, 43, was taken into the closed courtroom under heavy guard. He stopped briefly to embrace his father and wife who handed him newspapers, cigarettes and a sack of cheese and lettuce sandwichs. Attorney <PERSON> Amnon </PERSON> <PERSON> Zichroni </PERSON> said his client took extensive notes during the five-hour hearing. He said only one witness testified Monday, an agent of <PERSON> Shin </PERSON> <PERSON> Bet </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s secret service, who helped obtain <PERSON> Kalmanovich </PERSON>'s confession during his eight months in custody. `` We are arguing that this confession was not made voluntarily,'' <PERSON> Zichroni </PERSON> told The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>. `` I am not permitted ... to give details, but I can say we oppose its submission.'' The exact charges <PERSON> Kalmanovich </PERSON> faces have not been revealed. He is expected to plead innocent after the hearing resumes Thursday. <PERSON> Kalmanovich </PERSON>, who emigrated from the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> in 1971, was arrested in December. He had established himself in <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> as an international businessman, an activist in the <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> and a socialite who mixed with leading politicians and senior army officers. <PERSON> Zichroni </PERSON> declined to comment on foreign reports that the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> may be working on a deal to trade <PERSON> Kalmanovich </PERSON> in a spy swap involving <PERSON> Jonathan </PERSON> <PERSON> Jay </PERSON> <PERSON> Pollard </PERSON>, an American convicted of spying for <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>, and another unidentified American. <PERSON> Kalmanovich </PERSON> wore sneakers and was dressed neatly Monday but had long hair. `` The security men do n't take me to the barber,'' he told reporters.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880905-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-05-88 2340EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-RagingWatersFire     09-05 0205</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Raging Waters Fire,0209</SECOND>
<HEAD>Fire Near Aquatic Park Destroys Eight Cars</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SAN DIMAS, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A fire Monday near an aquatic park that boasts `` five million gallons'' burned about 10 acres of brush before it was extinguished, and destroyed eight cars, authorities said. Firefighters had some difficulty in controlling the fire at first because `` there's no fire hydrant in the parking lot. We ca n't get any water to the cars,'' <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> fire Inspector <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Lenihan </PERSON> said. County fire Capt. <PERSON> Garry </PERSON> <PERSON> Oversby </PERSON> said later that water was rerouted from hydrants nearby. It was not immediately known whether the blaze began in a vehicle or on the vegetation in <LOCATION> Bonnelli </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Park </LOCATION>, but the flames leaped from car to car, <PERSON> Oversby </PERSON> said. The fire was reported shortly after 2 p.m. in an overflow parking area for Raging Waters amusement park less than one mile away. The park was not evacuated and no one was injured. `` Raging Waters is 44 acres, five million gallons and tons of fun for everyone,'' said a tape-recorded message at the park, about 25 miles northeast of <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>. The park features 12 water slides, a fresh-water surf pool, and a river-rafting ride. Damage was estimated at $ 50,000, Oversby said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880905-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-05-88 2351EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-China-Carlucci     09-05 0327</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-China-Carlucci,0337</SECOND>
<HEAD>Official says China is not a major arms dealer</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JIM ABRAMS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s top military official, speaking to reporters Tuesday before meeting with <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Defense Secretary <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Carlucci </PERSON>, said <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> is not a major arms dealer. `` <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> is a developing country. <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> can only sell a little. It is only a small fraction of what the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has sold,'' Defense Minister <PERSON> Qin </PERSON> <PERSON> Jiwei </PERSON> said. <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s sales of missiles to <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> nations, including Silkworm missiles to <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>, have been criticized by the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. According to <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> figures, <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> sold about $ 2 billion worth of arms last year, mainly to developing countries. <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> does not provide information on its arms sales. <PERSON> Qin </PERSON> said <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> and other Third World countries sell only conventional arms `` but the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> is selling advanced arms such as the F-16'' jet fighter. `` We ca n't compare the two kinds of arms,'' he said. Deputy Chief of Staff <PERSON> Xu </PERSON> <PERSON> Xin </PERSON>, also talking to reporters in the Great Hall of the People, insisted <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> strictly regulates its arms sales. `` First, they are for defense. Second, they are for maintaining stability and peace, not war,'' he said. Earlier Tuesday the American national anthem echoed off the gray walls of the <ORGANIZATION> Chinese </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Military </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Museum </ORGANIZATION> as <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s top military leaders welcomed <PERSON> Carlucci </PERSON> on his first official visit. <PERSON> Carlucci </PERSON>, accompanied by <PERSON> Qin </PERSON>, reviewed a 120-member honor guard from the <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Carlucci </PERSON> arrived Monday for a five-day visit to discuss international and bilateral issues. <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> is expected to call on the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> to remove restrictions on technology transfers and approve export licenses for <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> companies wanting to use Chinese Long March missiles to launch satellites. Use of the Chinese missiles has been opposed by <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> defense officials concerned about giving <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> access to <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> satellite technology. Regional conflicts in <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION> and the Soviet military stance in the <LOCATION> Far </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> are also likely to be discussed.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880905-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-05-88 2349EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-AlaskaCrash 2ndLd-Writethru a0685 09-05 0225</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Alaska Crash, 2nd Ld - Writethru, a0685,0224</SECOND>
<HEAD>One Dead, Nine Injured In Mountain Plane Crash</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Subs 3rd graf to CORRECT spelling of Britten and name of
aviation company.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>SITKA, Alaska (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 One person was killed and nine others aboard a commercial aircraft were injured when the plane crashed near a mountain lake Monday shortly after takeoff from <LOCATION> Sitka </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> said. The crash was reported at about 3:35 p.m. near <LOCATION> Indigo </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION>, about five to 10 miles east of the <LOCATION> Sitka </LOCATION> airport, <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> Cmdr. <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Merchant </PERSON> said. Merchant said the twin-engine Britten-Norman BN-2 operated by <ORGANIZATION> Wrangell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> crashed in a mountainous area at about the 2,000-foot level. Nine passengers and a pilot were on board the flight from <LOCATION> Sitka </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Petersburg </LOCATION>, he said. One person, whose identify was not immediately released, died at the scene. The other nine were evacuated by helicopters from the <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> and from <ORGANIZATION> Mountain </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aviation </ORGANIZATION>, a private air service, Merchant said. He said all were taken to hospitals, where two people were in serious condition. They were to be flown to <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION> for treatment, <ORGANIZATION> Sitka </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fire </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> Assistant Chief <PERSON> Doug </PERSON> <PERSON> Karpstein </PERSON> said. Merchant said the cause of the crash was not immediately known. The weather at the time was rainy, with clouds at the tops of the mountains that surround <LOCATION> Sitka </LOCATION>, he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880905-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-05-88 2356EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-Food-Arrests 2ndLd-Writethru a0652 09-05 0654</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Food-Arrests, 2nd Ld - Writethru, a0652,0667</SECOND>
<HEAD>Dozens Arrested Trying To Distribute Free Food</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Inserts one graf after fourth `It was...' with advocacy group
giving city an ``award.''</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By JACK SCHREIBMAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SAN FRANCISCO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Fifty people were arrested Monday when a group trying to distribute free food and leaflets scuffled with police, who had previously warned the group to get a permit or move elsewhere. A television cameraman was injured when a police officer knocked him to the ground at the fracas on the edge of Golden Gate Park. Food and fists went flying when a squad of police officers wearing riot gear closed in on about 200 people gathered for the `` Food Not Bombs'' give-away. It was the second time in a week the group had clashed with police. On Aug. 29, 29 people were arrested in a similar confrontation. Group leaders said they will return each Monday. Later Monday in <LOCATION> Warwick </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mass. </LOCATION>, a group active on behalf of the homeless, the <ORGANIZATION> Gandhi </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Peace </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>, gave its annual <PERSON> Marie </PERSON> <PERSON> Antoinette </PERSON> Award for Community Consciousness to the city of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> to recognize the arrests. The tongue-in-cheek award refers to the French queen's famous remark of, `` Let them eat cake,'' when told the peasants were without bread. The latest confrontation took place about 45 minutes after the group marched into the southeast corner of the park, adjacent to the <LOCATION> Haight-Ashbury </LOCATION> district, popular in the 1960s among hippies and in the'80s among people who buy and restore Victorian homes. Police moved in as the group's members began giving food to one another. Police spokesman Sgt. <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Senkir </PERSON> said it was considered an illegal give-away after food was given to 25 people. As the officers approached, food began to fly through the air. One officer was hit in the face with a plate of rice and another was struck in the neck with a tomato. A police officer grabbed <ORGANIZATION> KPIX </ORGANIZATION> cameraman <PERSON> Hank </PERSON> <PERSON> Schoepp </PERSON>, knocking him to the ground. The cameraman lay stunned for a few moments with blood trickling from his cheek and his camera tossed aside. He then got up and resumed filming the clash. Some of those arrested were dragged away with their wrists bound by plastic ties. They were loaded into police vans and taken away. <PERSON> Senkir </PERSON> said they faced a possible misdemeanor count of creating a nuisance and two park infractions: illegal distribution of food and illegal leafleting. The park infractions carry a maximum penalty of a $ 50 fine. <PERSON> Senkir </PERSON> said one woman also faced a charge of assaulting an officer. <PERSON> Senkir </PERSON> said the giveaway would not be illegal if the group had obtained permits. He said the group had been offered other sites for the give-away, but rejected that idea. The group had 15 to 20 cartons of food, including bread, carrots, lettuce, rice, melons and corn. The leaflets said the group had been harassed in recent months by police and had been unfairly characterized by Mayor <PERSON> Art </PERSON> <PERSON> Agnos </PERSON> as being interested in exploiting the homeless and hungry. <PERSON> Patrisha </PERSON> <PERSON> Vestey </PERSON>, who was handing out deviled eggs, said she was a legal assistant in a law office and lived in the neighborhood. `` I disapproved of what the police are doing. I think the poor should be taken care of,'' she said. It was not clear if she was a member of the group. <PERSON> Lorraine </PERSON> <PERSON> Rorke </PERSON>, vice president of <ORGANIZATION> Stanyan-Fulton </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, said, `` I'm against this particular give-away in this particular location. `` I also feel that they are not so interested in giving away food as they are in promoting their particular message,'' said Ms. <PERSON> Rorke </PERSON>, whose organization is one of several neighborhood associations opposed to the `` Food Not Bombs'' give-aways. `` It's a free country, and if they want to have their political views, they can have them. I just do n't like their means of using the hungry and blocking the entrance to the park,'' she said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880905-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-05-88 0010EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-FloridaPrimary     09-05 0703</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Florida Primary,0721</SECOND>
<HEAD>Mack, Merkle Battle; Six Democrats In Race For Chiles' Seat</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By DAN SEWELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MIAMI (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> Republicans, with a good shot at gaining a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> seat two years after losing one, will be choosing between the arch-conservative grandson of a baseball legend and the brash prosecutor who put a Colombian drug lord behind bars. Meantime, six Democrats are battling in their primary, prompted by the decision of the popular incumbent, <PERSON> Lawton </PERSON> <PERSON> Chiles </PERSON>, not to seek re-election. An October runoff will be necessary if, as expected, no one gets more than half the votes on Tuesday. Seven of <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>' 19 congressional districts are also holding primaries. Raising funds has been the dominant topic of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> races, two years after then-Gov. <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Graham </PERSON> unseated Republican Sen. <PERSON> Paula </PERSON> <PERSON> Hawkins </PERSON> in a race that cost them a combined $ 13 million. <PERSON> Chiles </PERSON>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Budget </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, stunned state politicians with his decision in December not to seek a fourth term. <PERSON> Chiles </PERSON> said he was burned out by his <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> workload and the high cost of campaigns. Rep. <PERSON> Connie </PERSON> <PERSON> Mack </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>, a three-term Republican, had already begun piling up funds when <PERSON> Chiles </PERSON> dropped out. <PERSON> Mack </PERSON>, whose late grandfather managed the <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION> A's and is in Baseball's Hall of Fame, has spent at least $ 2.2 million so far. Democrats were pleased when former Gov. <PERSON> Reubin </PERSON> <PERSON> Askew </PERSON> announced his candidacy. But <PERSON> Askew </PERSON>, though running well ahead of <PERSON> Mack </PERSON> in the polls, abruptly quit May 7, saying he did n't like all the time spent raising funds. <PERSON> Askew </PERSON>'s withdrawal left Rep. <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Mica </PERSON> the only Democrat to oppose <PERSON> Mack </PERSON>. But quickly, five others entered the race: three-term state Insurance Commissioner <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Gunter </PERSON>, Rep. <PERSON> Kenneth </PERSON> `` Buddy'' <PERSON> MacKay </PERSON>, state Sen. <PERSON> Patricia </PERSON> <PERSON> Frank </PERSON>, former Republican Gov. <PERSON> Claude </PERSON> <PERSON> Kirk </PERSON> and former <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> postal clerk <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> Rader </PERSON>. <PERSON> Mack </PERSON> got a surprise of his own when <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Merkle </PERSON>, fresh from gaining the conviction of Colombian cocaine kingpin <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Lehder </PERSON> <PERSON> Rivas </PERSON>, quit as <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> attorney and entered the Republican race in June. President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and former Marine Lt. Col. <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> <PERSON> North </PERSON> made campaign appearances for <PERSON> Mack </PERSON>, a 47-year-old with one of the most conservative records in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. The outspoken <PERSON> Merkle </PERSON>, also a conservative, has likened <PERSON> Mack </PERSON> to a `` shiny new car'' with `` no engine under the hood.'' When <PERSON> Mack </PERSON> refused to debate him, <PERSON> Merkle </PERSON> started carrying around a life-sized replica of <PERSON> Mack </PERSON> he called `` Cardboard Connie.'' However, he did not make an issue of <PERSON> Mack </PERSON>'s admission last year that he had used marijuana in his younger days. <PERSON> Merkle </PERSON>, 43, has spent only about $ 100,000 but has garnered more newspaper endorsements that credit him with more specific stands on issues than <PERSON> Mack </PERSON>. Still, published polls make <PERSON> Mack </PERSON> the heavy favorite to win the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> nomination, and his well-financed campaign and the divided campaign on the Democratic side give him a good chance of prevailing in November. `` I do n't think it'll be an easy race, but I think it's winnable,'' said <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Whitehead </PERSON> In the Democratic primary, polls give <PERSON> Gunter </PERSON> the lead with about 40 percent of the vote. A candidate needs to top 50 percent to avert a runoff Oct. 4. <PERSON> Gunter </PERSON>, who lost to Mrs. <PERSON> Hawkins </PERSON> in 1980, raised $ 1 million within six weeks of entering the race, and opponents noted he took at least $ 160,000 from the insurance industry he regulates as state insurance commissioner. <PERSON> MacKay </PERSON> campaign manager <PERSON> Greg </PERSON> <PERSON> Farmer </PERSON> called <PERSON> Gunter </PERSON>'s department `` a saga of sleaze.'' Polls indicated the race for second was too close to call between MacKay, a three-term congressman, and <PERSON> Mica </PERSON>, a five-term congressman. In the congressional races, 10th-term Rep. <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Chappell </PERSON>, touched by the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> procurement scandal, faced a little-known engineer in the Democratic primary, while three Republicans are vying for the chance to challenge him. <PERSON> Chappell </PERSON> has denied wrongdoing, although his name has been mentioned repeatedly during the probe. Six Republicans are battling to succeed <PERSON> Mack </PERSON>. Former Rep. <LOCATION> L.A. </LOCATION> `` Skip'' <PERSON> Bafalis </PERSON>, who gave up the seat in an unsuccessful run for governor in 1982, was expected to be in a runoff with former <LOCATION> Lee </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> Commissioner <PERSON> Porter </PERSON> <PERSON> Goss </PERSON> or retired Army Gen. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Dozier </PERSON>, who was held hostage by terrorists in <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880905-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-05-88 0015EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Korea-USForces     09-05 0752</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Korea-US Forces,0779</SECOND>
<HEAD>U.S. Forces In South Korea Help To Safeguard Olympics</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</NOTE>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military forces in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> are helping to protect the Olympic Games. The writer, the <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>' bureau chief in <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION>, went on a <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> flight to get a view of the preparations
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>By BARRY RENFREW</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ABOVE NIGHTMARE RANGE, South Kore (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Capt. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Vandervalk </PERSON> scanned the target and flung the plane in a stomach-wrenching attack dive into the rocky valley below. The small <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> OV-10 Bronco nose-dived, the force of the acceleration forcing its two occupants back against their armor-plated seats. <PERSON> Hills </PERSON> flashed past as <PERSON> Vandervalk </PERSON> streaked toward the target, calmly checking the attack coordinates. White phosphorous rockets flashed from the plane's belly and slammed into the practice target as the pilot jerked the plane up over a rock cliff. <PERSON> Vandervalk </PERSON> glanced back to check his handiwork. `` We do everything as if it were Day One of a war, except nobody shoots at us,'' <PERSON> Vandervalk </PERSON> explained after Thursday's flight. `` You really have a sense of urgency and mission in <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>.'' <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> forces stationed in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> are on increased alert in case communist <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> makes any attempt to disrupt the Olympic Games, which begin Sept. 17 in <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION>. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> is helping guarantee the security of the Olympics. <PERSON> Vandervalk </PERSON> and other pilots of the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION>'s 19th <ORGANIZATION> Tactical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Control </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Squadron </ORGANIZATION> serve as forward air controllers whose mission is to spot and mark targets with smoke for other planes to attack. Their small planes also fly attack missions against ground targets. `` We control violence,'' is the motto worn by members of the squadron based at <ORGANIZATION> Osan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Base </ORGANIZATION> south of <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION>. Hundreds of thousands of troops, including 42,000 <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> troops, face each other in a tense confrontation on the Demilitarized Zone that divides the peninsula. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> forces have been based in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> since the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> intervened to help the <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> after <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> invaded in 1950 to begin the Korean War. An armistice was signed in 1953, but the north and south technically are still at war. Col. <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Hammond </PERSON>, commander of the <ORGANIZATION> 5th </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tactical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Control </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Group </ORGANIZATION>, said the <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korean </LOCATION> threat is a daily fact of life. `` I think the threat presented by the <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Koreans </LOCATION> is real. They are not what could be classified as rational actors,'' he said. South Korean and <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> commanders fear <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> will attempt to disrupt the Olympics because its demand to be a co-host of the Games has been rejected. The North has a long history of launching terrorist attacks against the South. `` The <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Koreans </LOCATION> would like to see an embarrassment to the Republic of -LRB- South -RRB- <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Hammond </PERSON> said. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> troops wo n't be guarding Olympic venues, but the Games have increased the sense of tension and spurred greater vigilance, <PERSON> Hammond </PERSON> said. `` Everyone's adrenalin goes up. Everyone leans forward in their foxholes,'' <PERSON> Hammond </PERSON> said. Airspace over <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION> and all Olympic sites has been declared off-limits during the Games. South Korean military air controllers quickly challenge any approaching plane. `` If you get real close to the capital area they threaten to shoot you down,'' <PERSON> Vandervalk </PERSON> said after being challenged by an air controller over the radio. <PERSON> Vandervalk </PERSON>, who has been stationed in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> for three years, said training is intense because hostile forces are poised just a few miles away. Pilots carry war plans on all missions. `` We're ready to go to work at a moment's notice,'' he said. Flying over Nightmare Range about 15 miles from the border, <PERSON> Vandervalk </PERSON> pointed out a <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korean </LOCATION> military air base visible across the border. `` The North Korean MiGs can be on us in two minutes,'' he said. <PERSON> Vandervalk </PERSON> said he has not seen a North Korean jet during his tour of duty in the South, but he and other pilots often hear the north's military radio traffic while they are flying. The airwaves along the border constantly crackle with <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korean </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military air controllers giving instructions. The area routinely is busy with warplanes on patrol or practicing. South Koreans have to live with a constant military presence and frequent exercises that can be disruptive, but they accept the inconveniences as unavoidable, <PERSON> Vandervalk </PERSON> said. `` It shows how lucky people in the West are,'' he said. `` When was the last time an American had a tank roll through his garden?''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880905-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-05-88 0017EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Britain-IRA     09-05 0763</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Britain-IRA,0784</SECOND>
<HEAD>Long-Awaited Inquest Into Gibraltar IRA Deaths To Begin</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By MARCUS ELIASON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 When three <ORGANIZATION> Irish </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> members were gunned down in <LOCATION> Gibraltar </LOCATION> on March 6 while allegedly plotting a car bombing, the British government claimed a victory on the battlefield of terrorism. Instead it got a political controversy that is still simmering six months later. A long-awaited inquest into the killings opens Tuesday in the British colony on the southeast tip of <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Mairead </PERSON> <PERSON> Farrell </PERSON>, <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> MacCann </PERSON> and <PERSON> Sean </PERSON> <PERSON> Savage </PERSON> were unarmed when they died. The car bomb, much to the British government's embarrassment, never materialized, although the <ORGANIZATION> IRA </ORGANIZATION> admitted the three were on a guerrilla mission and a car full of explosives was found 40 miles from the scene two days later Moreover, two British television networks investigating what had happened that sunny Sunday in <LOCATION> Gibraltar </LOCATION> found witnesses whose accounts strongly suggested the three were shot without being given any chance to surrender. It all boiled down to a simple question that confronts every democracy facing a terrorist threat: Did <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> bend the rule of law? Critics like <ORGANIZATION> Amnesty </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION>, the human rights watchdog, which demanded an inquiry into the shootings in hopes of answering that question, were rebuffed by Prime Minister <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON>, who said she was outraged that the question was even being asked. As far as the government was concerned, a disaster was averted. It argued that there was no way of knowing on that day that no car bomb was in <LOCATION> Gibraltar </LOCATION>; that it had to be assumed a bomb was set to blow up a military parade and hordes of onlookers; that there was no certainty the perpetrators were not armed and did not have remote-control detonators to explode the bomb the moment they were told to surrender. The government sought to dissuade <ORGANIZATION> Thames </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Television </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> British </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Broadcasting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> from broadcasting the documentaries, arguing that `` trial by TV'' would prejudice the inquest. The broadcasts went ahead, confronting viewers with some chilling accounts from witnesses. <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> Bullock </PERSON>, a lawyer, told the <ORGANIZATION> BBC </ORGANIZATION> he `` saw a chap with a white shirt reeling backward, with a man standing four feet away from him, firing a gun constantly and following him down as he fell.'' He said: `` It was n't a question of just putting one or two shots into him just to stop him. It seemed to me this was a deliberate shooting to kill, no question.'' The <ORGANIZATION> BBC </ORGANIZATION> also quoted an unidentified witness who saw <PERSON> Sean </PERSON> <PERSON> Savage </PERSON> on his back, with another man standing over him with his foot on his chest. `` I heard no warning before the shots were fired,'' she was quoted as saying. `` He continued to fire shots into the man as he lay on the ground.'' <PERSON> Carmen </PERSON> <PERSON> Proetta </PERSON>, watching from her apartment, said she believed <PERSON> Mairead </PERSON> <PERSON> Farrell </PERSON> and <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> McCann </PERSON> had their hands up in surrender when they were shot dead by a man who `` went into a crouch position and took deliberate aim at them.'' The issues have been debated since 1982, when police in <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION> killed five unarmed suspects and an innocent youth in three separate incidents. The arguments arose anew after three <ORGANIZATION> IRA </ORGANIZATION> men were gunned down in a British army ambush in the west of the province last Tuesday. Defending the government in the right-wing <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Express </ORGANIZATION> after the TV documentaries, Lord <PERSON> Chalfont </PERSON> denounced any `` equivalence between indiscriminate killing in the course of political terrorism, and the killing of terrorists by security forces engaged in counterterrorist operations.'' The liberal Guardian, on the other hand, maintained: `` A state that turns to terror itself in desperate recourse'' in the end endorses values of terrorists. Tuesday's inquest, which was postponed from June, is now the focus of attention. Sixty-five witnesses have been called, and <LOCATION> Gibraltar </LOCATION> is in a state of high alert, wracked by frequent bomb scares. The seven operatives involved in the March 6 incident are thought to belong to the <ORGANIZATION> army </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Special </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION>, a top-secret anti-terrorist team, and they will testify behind a screen to prevent their being marked for reprisals. But the British government has reserved the right to keep them away from the inquest. If the 11-member jury returns a verdict of unlawful killings, Attorney General <PERSON> Eric </PERSON> <PERSON> Thistlethwaite </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Gibraltar </LOCATION> will prosecute the perpetrators, according to high-level sources in the colony who requested anonymity. The mainly <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> IRA </ORGANIZATION> is fighting to end British rule in <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION> and unite the Protestant-dominated province with the <LOCATION> Republic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION> under socialist rule.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880905-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-05-88 0020EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-CocaineFreighter     09-05 0212</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Cocaine Freighter,0217</SECOND>
<HEAD>Coast Guard Intercepts Cocaine-Laden Colombian Freighter</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MIAMI (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> fired warning shots at a cocaine-laden freighter heading into St. <PERSON> John </PERSON> in the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virgin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Islands </LOCATION> and arrested five crewmen who said they were Colombian nationals, a spokesman said Sunday night. The freighter She-Me turned around and fled <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> territorial waters about 7:30 p.m. EDT Saturday after the <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> cutter Nunivak ordered it to stop, said <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> Lt. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Felker </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION>. Narrowly avoiding several collisions in an attempt to intercept the freighter, the cutter received permission from <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> headquarters in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION>, to fire warning shots across the freighter's bow, <PERSON> Felker </PERSON> said. `` Under the doctrine of hot pursuit, he was still in territorial seas,'' <PERSON> Felker </PERSON> said. `` He was approximately nine or 10 miles off St. <PERSON> John </PERSON> when the warning shots were fired, and the vessel was seized.'' <PERSON> Felker </PERSON> said 1,000 pounds of cocaine, hidden in a secret compartment, were seized, and five crewmen were taken into custody at <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Juan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Puerto </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rico </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Felker </PERSON> said authorities were still trying to determine the She-Me's country of origin and registry Sunday night. The seizure was aided by intelligence information from the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Narcotics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Border </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Interdiction </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>, headed by Vice President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, <PERSON> Felker </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880905-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-05-88 0027EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-LostRiver     09-05 0584</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lost River,0602</SECOND>
<HEAD>Town Seeks Recourse To Missing River</HEAD>
<DATELINE>GRAYVILLE, Ill. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 When a town loses a river, the situation can become explosive. It has for <PERSON> Grayville </PERSON>, a town of about 2,300 that, until 1985, sat on the banks of the <LOCATION> Wabash </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION>. The town did n't move; the river did, and now, after three years of waiting for federal agencies or floods to return the river to its `` rightful'' course, some frustrated residents are threatening to use dynamite. `` If Mother Nature does n't do it, man will,'' said <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Farmer </PERSON>, who owns the Hard Times fish market in this southeastern <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> town. If <PERSON> Grayville </PERSON>'s economic situation were better, residents might be more tolerant of the river's shift. Several years ago, <PERSON> Grayville </PERSON> was a thriving oil producer, but about the time the river changed course, cheaper imports glutted the market. And because this year's drought dried up anticipated agricultural income, the stagnant channel has become an unpleasant reminder of hard times. Before the river changed course, hundreds of fishermen used to crowd <PERSON> Grayville </PERSON>'s restaurants, bars and gas stations every weekend. The money they spent once would have buffered losses from oil and agriculture. But now, like the <LOCATION> Wabash </LOCATION>, the anglers do n't come around anymore. When spring floods receded in 1985, residents discovered the river had left them. A new channel had cut off the horseshoe bend upon which <PERSON> Grayville </PERSON> was founded. These days, fishermen are lucky to get a flat-bottomed boat in the shallow waters of the old channel. And they'd better be prepared to row, because a motor will strike bottom, residents say. Water that used to flow at 40 feet per second now does n't move at all. Silt that once was washed downstream is now filling in the old channel, and tall weeds have taken over the sand bars that boaters and swimmers once flocked to. <PERSON> Grayville </PERSON>'s boat ramp is usually empty. For three years, residents pleaded with federal and state officials for money to bring the rambling river home. Federal agencies came up with a package that would cost the town $ 900,000, a quarter of the cost to build a dam to divert the <LOCATION> Wabash </LOCATION> back. `` There's no way the town could come up with $ 900,000,'' said Mayor <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Hagedorn </PERSON>, noting that the town's entire annual budget is barely over $ 1 million. Talk at <PERSON> Bob </PERSON>'s barbershop and other hangouts has focused on residents taking care of the problem themselves. A recent editorial in The Mercury Independent, <PERSON> Grayville </PERSON>'s hometown newspaper, criticized the lack of help from authorities and reported `` growing sentiment among <PERSON> Grayville </PERSON> citizens to take matters into their own hands `` The editorial refers to a rumored plan to dynamite a trench to relocate the river, but adds, `` We have no idea this will actually be carried out `` `` It's talk,'' said <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Ritchey </PERSON>, who runs the <LOCATION> Grayville </LOCATION> sewage plant. `` No one's got the courage to do it. Vandalism like that is unheard of in <LOCATION> Grayville </LOCATION>.'' He hates to see <PERSON> Grayville </PERSON> lose its source of pride. Some of the town's most exciting history is tied to the river. A paddlewheeler once sank there, and a train trestle collapsed into the river when the town was young. Labor Day crowds will pack <PERSON> Grayville </PERSON>, but they're coming for the town's annual holiday celebration, not to fish or swim in the <LOCATION> Wabash </LOCATION>. Most of them will drive by the sign that welcomes visitors to `` <LOCATION> Grayville </LOCATION> _ On the Banks of the Wabash.'' `` I would start looking for another monument to the town,'' <PERSON> Ritchey </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880905-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-05-88 0039EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-TeamstersElection Bjt   09-05 0772</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Teamsters Election, Bjt,0799</SECOND>
<HEAD>After Two Years Of Government Control, Local Braces For Election</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MICHAEL MORAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>KEARNY, N.J. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Evidence of the pugnacious politics of Teamsters Local 560 can be seen in the graffiti spray-painted on the concrete base of the <LOCATION> Pulaski </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Skyway </LOCATION>'s hulking black girders. `` Remember Castellito,'' exhorts a scrawl, referring to <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON> <PERSON> Castellito </PERSON>, a Local 560 official slain in 1961. Reputed Genovese crime family figure <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON> `` Tony Pro'' <PERSON> Provenzano </PERSON> and his brothers <PERSON> Salvatore </PERSON> and <PERSON> Nunzio </PERSON> ran the Union City-based local until 1979, when <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON> <PERSON> Provenzano </PERSON> was convicted of racketeering and ordering Castellito's killing. In 1984, a federal judge removed 560's executive board and placed the local under a trustee to end a quarter-century of organized crime domination. It was the first such action in <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> history. This Labor Day finds Local 560 in its 26th month under the trustee, <PERSON> Edwin </PERSON> <PERSON> Stier </PERSON>. But the trusteeship is scheduled to end Dec. 6, the date <PERSON> Stier </PERSON> set for 560's first contested election since 1965, the last year anyone ran against the <ORGANIZATION> Provenzanos </ORGANIZATION>. `` What's happening here is exactly what we wanted,'' said <PERSON> Stier </PERSON>. `` The candidates are going to each barn and campaigning in an open election.'' But in the barns, as the sprawling truck depots are known, the trusteeship has not pleased many members. Some at first welcomed the efforts to exorcise corruption but grew wary when <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Attorney <PERSON> Rudolph </PERSON> <PERSON> Giuliani </PERSON> of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> recently sued to place a trusteeship over the <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Brotherhood </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Teamsters </ORGANIZATION>. `` We are keeping a sharp eye on events over the river,'' said a federal prosecutor in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> who spoke on condition of anonymity. `` A smooth transition back to union control of the local could mean a lot to our case against the international.'' Three men are running for president of the 8,000-member local, the <ORGANIZATION> Teamsters </ORGANIZATION>' largest: <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Sciarra </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Teamsters </ORGANIZATION> for Liberty, who served on the ousted board; <PERSON> Russ </PERSON> <PERSON> Viggiani </PERSON>, a Local 560 business agent and head of <ORGANIZATION> Teamsters </ORGANIZATION> for Solidarity; and <PERSON> Ray </PERSON> <PERSON> Carney </PERSON>, a trucker who ran against <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON> <PERSON> Provenzano </PERSON> in 1965 and leader of The Committee for the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ticket </ORGANIZATION>. The government had sought to bar <PERSON> Sciarra </PERSON> from running, saying the local would again be dominated by organized crime under his leadership. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> Dickinson </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Debevoise </PERSON> is expected to rule soon on the government motion. After <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> Harold </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Ackerman </PERSON> ordered the ouster of the local's leadership, <PERSON> Sciarra </PERSON> served as interim president for two years until June 1986, when appeals were exhausted. The goverment's case against <PERSON> Sciarra </PERSON> rests partly on secretly recorded tapes of conversations. The tapes, made public during hearings, allegedly depict <ORGANIZATION> Genovese </ORGANIZATION> captain <PERSON> Matthew </PERSON> `` Matty the Horse'' Ianiello telling a former Local 560 official that <PERSON> Sciarra </PERSON> should `` take over'' the union after the trusteeship. <PERSON> Sciarra </PERSON> has denied any link to organized crime or any intention to take orders from anyone once elected. Though he declined to be interviewed, he authorized union member and friend <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> Laurie </PERSON> to speak for him. <PERSON> Laurie </PERSON> said the tape transcripts are unclear about the subject being discussed and who is speaking. `` Apparently from what we read of the transcripts there is the indication that the things being said there were completely contrary to some of the things the government is trying to prove,'' <PERSON> Laurie </PERSON> said. Whether or not the 55-year-old <PERSON> Sciarra </PERSON> is permitted to run, <PERSON> Laurie </PERSON> said, <ORGANIZATION> Teamsters </ORGANIZATION> for Liberty will have a candidate. `` <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> has been president before and he's qualified to step right into that job,'' <PERSON> Laurie </PERSON> said. `` Members may not realize that this is n't a personality contest. This is about bread and butter and about the pension and welfare fund, which is now about $ 230 million.'' <PERSON> Stier </PERSON>, who has taken no official position on <PERSON> Sciarra </PERSON>'s participation, agrees <PERSON> Sciarra </PERSON> is probably the front-runner, but that <PERSON> Carney </PERSON> has made inroads <PERSON> Sciarra </PERSON>'s two opponents, concerned about the possible backlash that barring <PERSON> Sciarra </PERSON> could create, say they would like him to run. <PERSON> Viggiani </PERSON>, 48, said he believes the intimidation of the <PERSON> Provenzano </PERSON> years still remains, though more subtle. `` There are still members concerned with reprisals who are not openly supportive of an opposing ticket,'' he said. <PERSON> Stier </PERSON> said that intimidation has been `` only minor at this point.'' Members `` understand if that starts to develop, it could seriously hurt the chances for an election,'' he said. <PERSON> Carney </PERSON>, 58, admits that <PERSON> Sciarra </PERSON> has more experience because of his 14 years in union office. `` But that's why we're where we are today,'' he said. `` I'm a truck driver and I want to give this union back to the members. They should have a voice and know where their money is going.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880905-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-05-88 0043EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-PresidentialHorserace Bjt   09-05 1124</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Presidential Horserace, Bjt,1100</SECOND>
<HEAD>50-State Survey Shows Dukakis, Bush Neck-and-Neck</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID ESPO</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Political Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> are locked in an extremely tight race for the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> as the fall campaign opens, with the vice president hoping to sustain his late summer surge and his Democratic rival angling to regain the momentum, according to an <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> survey of the 50 states. Advisers to both men as well as politicians around the country say they expect a close race right up to Election Day on November 8. `` It's going to be down and dirty to the very end,'' said Republican state Rep. <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Ryder </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> _ a key battleground where Republicans concede that <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> maintains a slight edge. In <LOCATION> Delaware </LOCATION>, `` as in the rest of the country, there's been a substantial shift in the last three weeks from <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> to <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>,'' said the state's GOP Gov. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> N. </PERSON> <PERSON> Castle </PERSON>. `` I think it started at the -LRB- Republican National -RRB- Convention, as to be expected. But since the convention, it's continued, even with the problems surrounding the <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> candidacy.'' The late-summer surge by <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> eroded <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' earlier advantages in key <ORGANIZATION> Electoral </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> battlegrounds from <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION>, with <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION> in between, say leaders in both political parties. The result is a series of tight, big-states races whose outcome will likely determine <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s successor in the White House. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' selection of <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> Sen. <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> as his vice presidential running mate transformed <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s adopted home state and its 29 electoral votes into an instant toss-up. But <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has countered elsewhere: the vice president seemingly has moved ahead in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>, with 21 electoral votes, as well as making up ground in the industrial <LOCATION> Midwest </LOCATION>. One poll in <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> even rated <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' home state a toss-up, though the <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> survey still found the state to be solid ground for <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>. In small states and large, politicians report a close contest that is unlikely to be decided until the final few days. Campaign debates and unexpected international events could have a dramatic influence on the outcome. `` I'd say right now it's a flip of the coin,'' said former <ORGANIZATION> Iowa </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> chairman <PERSON> Ed </PERSON> <PERSON> Campbell </PERSON>, reflecting the sentiment of party professionals around the country. `` It could go either way.'' Senior officials of the two campaigns pronounce themselves pleased with the shape of the race. Said <PERSON> Susan </PERSON> <PERSON> Estrich </PERSON>, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' campaign manager, `` Nationally, we're competitive. States will go up and down. It's exactly where we thought it would be. ... This is a very evenly matched contest.'' `` We all felt like we'd be lucky if we were in the single digits, meaning seven, eight, or nine points'' behind by Labor Day, said <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Atwater </PERSON>, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s campaign manager. Officials in both camps agree that the race is subject to sharp swings, especially since neither candidate is an incumbent. That heightens the importance of debates, the subject of negotiations between the two campaigns with <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> seeking more and <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> less. It also could heighten the effect of any mistakes by either of the candidates or their running mates, Democratic Sen. <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> and Republican Sen. <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>. <PERSON> Rich </PERSON> <PERSON> Bond </PERSON>, a senior aide in the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> camp, says the race shapes up this way: `` Basically you've got a tight race with the South looking pretty much <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s way. The West with the exception of the Coast -LRB- <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> -RRB- is heading our way, but ca n't be taken for granted.'' Bond estimated that <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> heads into the race armed with a solid 150 to 200 electoral votes, principally from Southern and <LOCATION> Rocky </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mountain </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, and that <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> probably can count on a base of 150 electoral votes, largely from the Northeast. Democrats believe they can win electoral votes from each region of the country, and note that <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>'s addition to the ticket makes <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> and its 29 electoral votes an extremely competitive race. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> adviser <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Kiley </PERSON> puts each candidate's reliable base at closer to 100 <ORGANIZATION> Electoral </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> votes. Even so, recent opinion polls indicate a dwindling advantage for <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> in states he has long counted in his column, including <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> as well as <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Charlie </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON>, who is in charge of <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' field organization, said the Democratic goal is to keep the race competitive in 45 or 46 states so that if the Republicans `` have a bad week they can lose'' in any of them. `` And I think we can keep it that close,'' he said. It takes 270 electoral votes to win the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, and Republicans have won four of the last five elections with solid southern and western support. <PERSON> Jimmy </PERSON> <PERSON> Carter </PERSON>, a southerner, is the only Democrat to break the Republican string of victories in the last 20 years. With nine weeks until Election Day, these are some straws in the wind: _ <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, the biggest state with 47 electoral votes, is viewed by both sides as a toss-up with a slight, initial edge to <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> The state was a tie in one recent poll. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> led in one recent poll in <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION>, and <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> was a tie in another. _ Republicans express confidence they can virtually sweep the Rocky Mountain region Democrats hope to steal a state or two, perhaps <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> or <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION>. _ The deep South looks strong for the Republicans, but <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' selection of <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> already has forced <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> to devote several days to campaigning in <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> hopes to peel away a border state or two, and maybe even challenge in <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>. _ The <LOCATION> Northeast </LOCATION> is <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' home region and his strongest, from <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION> Both sides give the Democrat the early edge in <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION> have recent Republican histories, but are key targets for both candidates. _ The <LOCATION> Midwest </LOCATION> is wide open, although <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>'s spot on the Republican ticket ended any talk of a Democratic surprise in <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION> Aside from <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> is viewed as the strong leader in <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION>, and ahead less convincingly in <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> led by 9 percentage points in a recent <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION> poll, but Republicans rushed to say they doubted either candidate could carry the state by that much. Republicans expect to carry <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION>. Democrats say they have spent the past several weeks methodically building a field organization, preparing television commercials and mapping out their fall campaign, and that the race wo n't be decided until the final days of the campaign. But where the Democrats sounded optimistic 10 weeks ago, now it is the Republicans who have been heartened by their candidate's late-summer offensive Republicans concede <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> probably has the lead in <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> and a narrow advantage in <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> for the moment.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880905-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-05-88 0043EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Horserace-List     09-05 0495</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Horserace-List,470</SECOND>
<HEAD>With PM-Presidential Horserace Bjt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here is a state-by-state look at the <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush-Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> campaign for the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, based on an <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> survey. Electoral College votes are in parenthesis, and it takes 270 to win. <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION> -LRB- 9 -RRB- _ Southern edge to <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> -LRB- 3 -RRB- _ One of <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s strongest states. <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION> -LRB- 7 -RRB- _ Edge to <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. <LOCATION> Arkansas </LOCATION> -LRB- 6 -RRB- _ Close race. <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> -LRB- 47 -RRB- _ Statistical dead heat in recent poll in the biggest state. <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION> -LRB- 8 -RRB- _ Both sides see tough race but GOP sounds confident. <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION> -LRB- 8 -RRB- _ <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> hopes to win next door to home state, but <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> has carried each time since 1968. <LOCATION> Delaware </LOCATION> -LRB- 3 -RRB- _ Toss-up. District of <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION> -LRB- 3 -RRB- _ Safe for <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>. <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> -LRB- 21 -RRB- _ <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> holds advantage. <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION> -LRB- 12 -RRB- _ <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> holds edge. <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION> -LRB- 4 -RRB- _ Should be <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>. <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION> -LRB- 4 -RRB- _ Should be <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> -LRB- 24 -RRB- _ Both sides see initial <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> edge in key swing state. <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION> -LRB- 12 -RRB- _ Safe for <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> in running mate <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>'s home state. <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> -LRB- 8 -RRB- _ Tight race but <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> rates early favorite. <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> -LRB- 7 -RRB- _ Advantage to <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. <LOCATION> Kentucky </LOCATION> -LRB- 9 -RRB- _ <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> has hopes in border state. <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION> -LRB- 10 -RRB- _ Southern advantage to <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION> -LRB- 4 -RRB- _ New <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> toss-up. <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION> -LRB- 10 -RRB- _ Part of <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' natural base. <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> -LRB- 13 -RRB- _ Democrats confident of a win on <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> home court, although recent polls show it close. <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION> -LRB- 20 -RRB- _ Republicans concede early <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> advantage in key swing state. <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION> -LRB- 10 -RRB- _ <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> ahead. <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> -LRB- 7 -RRB- _ <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> led strongly in recent poll. <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION> -LRB- 11 -RRB- _ <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> led by 9 in recent poll but both sides see tough race. <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION> -LRB- 4 -RRB- _ Democrats claim advantage, Republicans see tough race. <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION> -LRB- 5 -RRB- _ Both sides see close race but <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has the edge. <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION> -LRB- 4 -RRB- _ Advantage to <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hampshire </ORGANIZATION> -LRB- 4 -RRB- _ Should be <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s. <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> -LRB- 16 -RRB- _ Both sides see a toss-up in usually Republican state. <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> -LRB- 5 -RRB- _ Edge to <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> but could be a contest. <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> -LRB- 36 -RRB- _ Advantage to <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>. <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> -LRB- 13 -RRB- _ Part of <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> base but <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> making an effort. <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION> -LRB- 3 -RRB- _ Both sides claim early advantage. <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> -LRB- 23 -RRB- _ Narrow <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> edge early in critical Midwestern state. <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION> -LRB- 8 -RRB- _ Edge to <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION> -LRB- 7 -RRB- _ Slight edge to <LOCATION> Dukakis </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> -LRB- 25 -RRB- _ Early advantage to <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>. <LOCATION> Rhode </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> -LRB- 4 -RRB- _ Part of <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> base. <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> -LRB- 8 -RRB- _ Presumed <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> lead <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION> -LRB- 3 -RRB- _ Both sides see close race <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> -LRB- 11 -RRB- _ Advantage to <LOCATION> Bush </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> -LRB- 29 -RRB- _ <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>'s spot on Democratic ticket transforms into toss-up. <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION> -LRB- 5 -RRB- _ Should be strong for <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. <LOCATION> Vermont </LOCATION> -LRB- 3 -RRB- _ Both sides see close race. <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> -LRB- 12 -RRB- Advantage <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> -LRB- 10 -RRB- _ Dead heat in one poll. <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> -LRB- 6 -RRB- _ Edge to <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>. <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION> -LRB- 11 -RRB- _ Early advantage to <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>. <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION> -LRB- 3 -RRB- _ Strong advantage for <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880905-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-05-88 0046EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-ThunderandLightning     09-05 0678</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Thunder and Lightning,670</SECOND>
<HEAD>Lightning Danger Greater Than Thunder Indicates</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RANDOLPH E. SCHMID</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Both people and lightning-sensitive industries may be in more danger than they realize, according to a researcher who says the hazards of electrical storms have been underestimated. Lightning strikes the earth much more often than weather records based on observers' reports indicate, says <PERSON> Stanley </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Changnon </PERSON> in the Journal of Geophysical Research-Atmospheres. `` Those who have to worry about the risk of lightning damage, for example nuclear power plants, have had to use data based on -LRB- thunder records -RRB- to develop their risk analyses,'' Changnon said in a telephone interview. `` It's very clear that thunder rather dramatically underestimates the frequency of lightning near a given point.'' Changnon discovered by using electromagnetic detectors to record actual cloud-to-ground flashes that between 22 percent and 40 percent of lightning flashes occurred at times when no thunder was heard. `` It is not good news,'' he concluded. Changnon, a researcher affiliated with the <ORGANIZATION> Illinois </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Water </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Survey </ORGANIZATION>, also teaches at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rochester </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Rochester </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION> His report was done in conjunction with his son, <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Changnon </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> Colorado </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> and <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Pyle </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> at <LOCATION> Albany </LOCATION>. Detailed thunderstorm records go back to the late 1800s, <PERSON> Changnon </PERSON> explained, but they have always depended on the reports of trained observers, primarily listening to the thunder generated by lightning. In recent years, however, electromagnetic detectors have been installed in many areas to record actual lightning strokes. The researchers compared reports by weather observers with the lightning records from sensors used by the federal <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Land </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Management </ORGANIZATION> in Western states and by electrical utilities along the Eastern seaboard. `` The degree of relationship is relatively weak,'' Changnon reported. `` It gives one a lot of pause, in many respects, about how the atmosphere works, how good our weather records are and how safe we are.'' In the West, Changnon reported, between 31 percent and 40 percent of all lightning strokes were missed by observers listening for thunder. The situation was better in the East, with 22 percent to 26 percent of lightning strokes being missed, the report said. `` The differences are very marked between the East and West,'' Changnon said. This occurs, at least in part, because it is more difficult to hear thunder in mountainous areas, he said. Another batch of the missed lightning strokes occurs before a storm is reported in an area, he said. `` People sometimes say lightning comes out of the blue. It's not necessarily out of the blue, just the front edge of a new or fast-moving storm,'' he said. The study also confirmed that lightning varies considerably from storm to storm. More than half of all electrical storms had only a few cloud-to-ground lightning flashes, while a small number of storms had hundreds of strokes. Indeed, in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION>, records for three years showed that nearly one-quarter of all the lightning strokes were accounted for in just two big storms. The researchers also found a considerable number of thunderstorms with no cloud-to-ground lightning. Cloud-to-cloud lightning is blamed for the thunder in those cases. <PERSON> Changnon </PERSON> said that is more common in the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION>, where storm clouds tend to be higher above the ground than in the East. Lightning killed 86 Americans last year, the highest death toll in this decade, according to records kept by the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Oceanic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Atmospheric </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>. And the 365 lightning-related injuries reported across the nation were nearly 50 percent more than the long-term average, the agency said. As usual, <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> led the nation with 11 lightning deaths last year. <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> ranked second with six, followed by five in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> and four each in <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Arkansas </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> each recorded three fatalities. There were two each in <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Kentucky </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> District </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION> each recorded a single lightning death for the year.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880905-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-05-88 0047EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-WaterPolicy     09-05 0431</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Water Policy,420</SECOND>
<HEAD>Council Recommended to Direct Federal Water Policy</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GUY DARST</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The next president should set up a `` water council'' in his executive office to coordinate federal water policy, which is now fragmented among several agencies, a <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> study recommends. Such a council should include representatives of the states and should be headed by a chairman free of ties to existing departments, said a paper from the <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Water </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Policy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Project </ORGANIZATION>, part of the energy and environment program at the university's <ORGANIZATION> John </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> F. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Kennedy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Government </ORGANIZATION>. The new council `` would derive its principal influence from its direct relationship with the president,'' the paper said. `` The absence of such an entity at present has led to the intolerable situation of no agency within the executive branch currently responsible for taking a comprehensive view of federal water programs.'' The report was written by <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Rogers </PERSON>, professor of environmental engineering and city planning, and <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> H.W </PERSON>. Foster, adjunct research fellow and environment secretary in the administration of <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> Republican Gov. <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Sargent </PERSON> in 1971-1975. The project was supported by grants from Resources for the Future, a <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> think-tank which released the report last week. Several previous attempts to coordinate federal water policy have failed. Most recently, a statutory inter-agency <ORGANIZATION> Water </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Resources </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cabinet </ORGANIZATION> secretaries was formed in 1965 to oversee planning, but was killed by agreement of the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration and <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> in 1981. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> Cabinet </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> on </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Natural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Resources </ORGANIZATION>, which tried to do some of the same work, `` proved ineffectual and became essentially non-functional after its principal enthusiast, <ORGANIZATION> Interior </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Watt </PERSON>, left office.'' In an interview from <LOCATION> Cambridge </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mass. </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Rogers </ORGANIZATION> said the <ORGANIZATION> Water </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Resources </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> `` moved in on agency programs, and the agencies quite properly went to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>.'' The new council, he said, should `` stay out of agency turf,'' and try to `` pull the policy debates out of the agencies, where people are debating themselves, and put them in a forum where they debate other agencies.'' By default, the <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Management </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Budget </ORGANIZATION> is now the chief coordinating agency, and <ORGANIZATION> OMB </ORGANIZATION> _ a <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> agency _ strongly opposes creation of a new council on the grounds that `` everybody wants a connection to the president,'' <PERSON> Rogers </PERSON> said. `` We have a colossal federal establishment, 60,000 or 70,000 employees, working on water subjects,'' he said. `` They ought to be doing things that fit into some plan. `` It's not the most urgent issue facing the incoming president, but if we do n't do something the issues are going to just sit there.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880905-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-05-88 0038EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Chile Bjt   09-05 0537</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Chile, Bjt,0555</SECOND>
<HEAD>Anti-Pinochet Demonstrators Battle Police, More Than 200 Arrested</HEAD>
<HEAD>Laserphoto NY5</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KEVIN NOBLET</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SANTIAGO, Chile (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Thousands of protesters battled police following the largest anti-government rally since the military nominated right-wing President <PERSON> Augusto </PERSON> <PERSON> Pinochet </PERSON> as the only candidate in a fall presidential referendum. More than 100,000 people packed blocks of a broad avenue in central <LOCATION> Santiago </LOCATION> on Sunday chanting `` Pinochet's going to fall!'' Police arrested 262 demonstrators and a police officer and eight civilians were wounded, said Gen. <PERSON> Sergio </PERSON> <PERSON> Badiola </PERSON>, the governor of <LOCATION> Santiago </LOCATION>. He said six of the injured, including the policeman, were seriously hurt. Police fired tear gas, buckshot and water cannons when tens of thousands of people began a march on the government palace after the generally peaceful rally had ended. Organizers said 300,000 people attended the rally and journalists estimated the crowd at more than 100,000. Gen. <PERSON> Pinochet </PERSON>, the 72-year-old army commander who has ruled <LOCATION> Chile </LOCATION> with a military junta since a coup in September 1973, was selected last Tuesday by himself and the commanders of the navy, air force and national police as the sole candidate in the presidential referendum scheduled for Oct. 5. Sunday's rally was the largest show of force by the opposition since <PERSON> Pinochet </PERSON>, seeking popular support, lifted on Aug. 27 the state of emergency that restricted public gatherings. There had been scattered street demonstrations after <PERSON> Pinochet </PERSON>'s nomination was announced Tuesday and three people were shot to death and hundreds were arrested <PERSON> Hector </PERSON> <PERSON> Moya </PERSON>, the main speaker at Sunday's rally, told the cheering crowd: `` We can now clearly see that the <PERSON> Pinochet </PERSON> regime already has been defeated.'' <PERSON> Moya </PERSON> is the head of the truckers' union When the rally ended a column of tens of thousands of people marched to the city's center, blocking traffic. Police broke up the procession and there were skirmishes throughout the area between rock-throwing demonstrators and police firing birdshot and tear gas. <PERSON> Pinochet </PERSON>, in an `` open letter to the men and women of my country'' printed Sunday in most local newspapers, promised full democracy if he is returned to office in the referendum. `` If Chileans call me to govern, each one of them will govern, too,'' the letter said. In an interview printed Sunday in the conservative newspaper <ORGANIZATION> El </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mercurio </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Pinochet </PERSON> also promised to resign as army commander and govern as a civilian. <LOCATION> Chile </LOCATION>'s 7.2 million voters are to vote either for or against <PERSON> Pinochet </PERSON> in the referendum. If approved, <PERSON> Pinochet </PERSON> will begin a new eight-year term in March. If rejected, an open presidential election is to be held in December 1989 with <PERSON> Pinochet </PERSON> remaining in power until an elected president takes office. <PERSON> Pinochet </PERSON> led the 1973 military coup that ousted the elected government of Marxist President <PERSON> Salvador </PERSON> <PERSON> Allende </PERSON>. <PERSON> Ricardo </PERSON> <PERSON> Lagos </PERSON>, a socialist opposition leader, called the rally `` the first step toward the final defeat of <PERSON> Pinochet </PERSON>.'' Rally participants, including Chileans who have returned from exile, sang and danced to political songs. Among the former exiles was <PERSON> Isabel </PERSON> <PERSON> Allende </PERSON>, 44, a daughter of the late president, who died during the coup. She received a huge ovation when her name was announced and joined in the dancing with <LOCATION> Lagos </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Pinochet </PERSON> on Thursday decreed an end to political exile.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880905-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-05-88 0059EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Veep-FringeBenefits 1stLd-Writethru a0426 09-05 0902</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Veep-Fringe Benefits, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0426,860</SECOND>
<HEAD>Quayle, Bentsen Differ in Cashing In on Senate Fringe Benefits</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDS: subs 3rd graf, bgng: Bentsen, a, to restore dropped word;
picks up 4th graf pvs, bgng: This doesn't</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By DAVID GOELLER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Vice presidential candidates <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> and <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> are in sharp contrast when it comes to two of the more valuable congressional fringe benefits _ speaking fees and free trips. In the last six years, <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> senator from <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION>, reported honoraria earnings of $ 250,050 from speechmaking and another $ 4,830 from writing articles. <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>, a Democratic senator from <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, accepted absolutely nothing for outside speaking and writing, according to the required financial disclosure statements covering 1982 through 1987. This does n't mean that <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>, the chairman of the tax-writing <ORGANIZATION> Finance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, is n't popular on the speechmaking circuit. It's because he is one of a handful of senators who decline to take honoraria <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>'s receipts put him in the mainstream of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>, where most members routinely pick up $ 1,000 to $ 2,000 a speech from trade associations, corporations, non-profit groups, think tanks and universities. The only restriction in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> on such outside income is that if a member's speech and writing fees total more than 40 percent of the official salary _ $ 89,500 _ the excess must be given to a bona fide charity. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>'s 1982-1987 disclosure forms also show that he was far ahead of <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> in getting free trips _ air fare, lodging and sometimes meals _ often in connection with a paid speech. The Indianian reported 44 expense-paid excursions, including destinations in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION>. In the same six years, <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> took four free trips, three to his home state, the fourth to <LOCATION> Modesto </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif </LOCATION>. The two rivals showed parity in one fringe-benefit area, gifts. <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> listed two gifts, each a Steuben glass sculpture, with a combined value of $ 2,750. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>'s $ 2,436 in gifts were in the form of golf equipment and clothing, including $ 825 worth in 1987 from pro golfer <PERSON> Fuzzy </PERSON> <PERSON> Zoeller </PERSON>, a fellow Indianian. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> is an avid, low-handicap golfer. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>'s top honoraria year was 1983, when he got $ 54,150 for 50 speeches and $ 1,500 for an article for the Institute for <ORGANIZATION> Socioeconometric </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Studies </ORGANIZATION>. There was no limit then on how much a senator could keep. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> gave $ 1,250 of his 1983 speaking fees to charity, the same amount as in 1982, when his honoraria totaled $ 40,650, including $ 1,000 from his alma mater, <ORGANIZATION> DePauw </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, for one of his 38 paid speeches. A 30 percent-of-salary limit was in effect for 1984, when he made 25 speeches, received $ 26,700 and gave $ 4,930 to charity. In 1985, he got $ 32,600 from 28 speeches, $ 40 from one article and gave $ 10,277 to charity. The following year, with a 40 percent limit, he gave $ 19,991 to charity after earning $ 49,400 from 37 speeches and $ 585 from three articles. Last year, he got $ 46,900 from 35 speeches and $ 2,355 from nine articles and gave $ 14,302 to charity. During the six years, <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> spoke most often to the <ORGANIZATION> Brookings </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institution </ORGANIZATION>, a <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> think tank. His 21 appearances there brought him $ 6,600. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> was popular with the Grocery Manufacturers of <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, making a speech to the trade association in 1982 for $ 1,000 and in 1984, 1986 and 1987 for $ 2,000 each of those years. He also received pay for speaking to defense contractors, drug companies and health care associations. He is a member of the <ORGANIZATION> Armed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Human </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> committees, which handle defense and health care issues. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> received speaking fees on 35 of the 44 free trips he made during the six years. There was no speaking money on a five-day stay in <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION> with his wife in 1982, compliments of the <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Steel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Distributors </ORGANIZATION>. He did get $ 1,500 for a speech on a trip to <LOCATION> Palm </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>, that year paid for by the <ORGANIZATION> Independent </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bankers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>. His peak travel year was 1983 with 15 trips, including three nights in <LOCATION> Orlando </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>, _ and a $ 2,000 honoraria _ from the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>. Other free destinations that year included <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> with <ORGANIZATION> Magnavox </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Electronic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Systems </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, and <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Palm </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>, with <ORGANIZATION> Chase </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Manhattan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION>. Six trips in 1984 included three nights in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Palm </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION> with his wife. <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Technologies </ORGANIZATION> picked up two nights' lodging. The airfares and the third night were paid by the <ORGANIZATION> Indiana </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Constructors </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>. After a quiet one-trip year in 1985, he made three in 1986, including three nights at an <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION> tennis resort for the `` 13th Annual Senators' Cup'' charity event. From there, the <ORGANIZATION> Outdoor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Advertising </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION> flew the Quayles to <LOCATION> Palm </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Springs </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, for three days. Last year, there were eight free trips, including charity sports events in <LOCATION> Park </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION>, and <LOCATION> Sun </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION>. He also received a six-night stay in <LOCATION> Monterey </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, from <ORGANIZATION> AT </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; T; four nights in Ft.. <PERSON> Myers </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>, from the <ORGANIZATION> Electronic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Industries </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>; and a day trip to <LOCATION> White </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sulphur </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Springs </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> W. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, from the <ORGANIZATION> Pharmaceutical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Manufacturers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, which paid $ 2,000 for a Each of <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>'s four trips was reported as a one-day excursion. In 1985, the <ORGANIZATION> West </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Oil </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Gas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> took him to <LOCATION> Abilene </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>. The following year, he went to <LOCATION> Modesto </LOCATION> with the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Venture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Capital </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>; to <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION> with the Forum Club of <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION>; and to <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION> with the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Home </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Builders </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880905-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-05-88 0125EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-LotteryWinners-List     09-05 0637</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lottery Winners-List,0664</SECOND>
<HEAD>With PM-Lotto Winner</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here is a list of top state lottery winnings, including three large jackpot drawings made this weekend: _ The as-yet-unidentified buyer or buyers of a single <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> lottery ticket can claim a $ 54 million jackpot from Sept. 3, 1988 drawing. _ Two winners split $ 51.4 million <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> lottery jackpot on June 4, 1988: <PERSON> Shelby </PERSON> <PERSON> Carroll </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Vacaville </LOCATION>, and <PERSON> Randy </PERSON> <PERSON> Pennington </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Sacramento </LOCATION>. _ <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Woomer </PERSON> Sr. and <PERSON> Linda </PERSON> <PERSON> K. </PERSON> <PERSON> Despot </PERSON>, a couple from <LOCATION> Hollidaysburg </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION>, won $ 46 million, <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> lottery, Oct. 14, 1987. _ Three winners split $ 41 million <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> lottery jackpot on Aug. 21, 1985: <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Moore </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Brooklyn </LOCATION>; <PERSON> Debbie </PERSON> <PERSON> Turcotte </PERSON>; Troy, and 21 <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> factory workers who shared a ticket. _ <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Wittkowski </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>, won $ 40 million, <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> lottery, Sept. 1, 1984. _ Three winners split $ 35 million <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> lottery jackpot on June 11, 1988. <PERSON> Debbie </PERSON> <PERSON> Buchanan </PERSON> and <PERSON> Tony </PERSON> <PERSON> Godinez </PERSON> of Stone Park shared one ticket, <PERSON> Edythe </PERSON> <PERSON> Gardiner </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Park </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION>, and <PERSON> Ollie </PERSON> <PERSON> Carter </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Rockford </LOCATION>, held the other two tickets. _ Two couples shared the $ 32 million <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> lottery jackpot for Jan. 9, 1988. <PERSON> Anna </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> and <PERSON> Orville </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Walker </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Utica </LOCATION> had one ticket, and <PERSON> Zelma </PERSON> <PERSON> Eil </PERSON> and <PERSON> Sharon </PERSON> <PERSON> Barnes </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Columbus </LOCATION> shared the other. _ <PERSON> Pasquale </PERSON> <PERSON> Consalvo </PERSON>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, won $ 30.5 million, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> lottery, Jan. 18, 1986. _ A group of four men shared one winning ticket worth $ 28 million, <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> lottery, January 20, 1988. The four winners _ <PERSON> Todd </PERSON> <PERSON> Perry </PERSON>, of <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION>; his brother <PERSON> Bryan </PERSON>, 27, of <LOCATION> Pine </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Grove </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION>; <PERSON> Gerald </PERSON> <PERSON> Welsh </PERSON>, 46, of <LOCATION> Ebervale </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION>; and <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Rubinic </PERSON>, 39, of <LOCATION> Oberlin </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pa </LOCATION>.. _ <PERSON> Emily </PERSON> <PERSON> Davidheiser </PERSON>, <PERSON> Brandon </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>, won $ 26 million, <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> lottery, Aug. 6, 1988 _ Two groups split $ 26 million <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> jackpot, April 17, 1987. One group of 29 people works at an elementary school in <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION>, the other group of 20 people works for a company in <LOCATION> Scranton </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION> _ <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> Magdeline </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Morgan </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Centerville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ind. </LOCATION>, won $ 25 million, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> lottery, April 9, 1986. _ Two winners split $ 24 million <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lotto </LOCATION> jackpot of Nov. 8, 1986. <PERSON> Osnat </PERSON> <PERSON> Burdman </PERSON> of <PERSON> Albertson </PERSON>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION>, and <PERSON> Melanie </PERSON> <PERSON> Richards </PERSON> of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> each win approximately $ 12 million. Ms. <PERSON> Richards </PERSON>, a 20-year-old college student, waited 3 -LCB- months before she claimed her share of the winnings. _ The as-yet-unidentified buyer or buyers of a single ticket in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> lottery can claim a $ 23 million jackpot from drawing of Sept. 3, 1988. _ <PERSON> Candido </PERSON> <PERSON> Ortiz </PERSON>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION>, won $ 22 million, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> lottery, July 6, 1988. _ Five co-workers split one winning ticket for a $ 21.4 million <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> jackpot on May 14, 1987. <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Yevak </PERSON>, <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Budziak </PERSON>, <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Wargo </PERSON>, <PERSON> Bernard </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Zawatsky </PERSON> worked for coal company in <LOCATION> Harleigh </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION> _ <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Couchet </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Ashland </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Ky. </LOCATION>, won $ 21 million, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> lottery, March 2, 1988. _ The as-yet-unidentified buyers of four <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> lottery tickets can split a $ 21 million jackpot from drawing of Sept. 3, 1988. _ <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON> and <PERSON> Dorothy </PERSON> <PERSON> Banner </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Lancaster </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION>, won $ 20.3 million, <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> lottery, June 10, 1987. _ <PERSON> Venero </PERSON> <PERSON> Pagano </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Bronx </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION>, won $ 20 million, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> lottery, July 25, 1984. _ Twelve workers from <LOCATION> Solon </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, split $ 20 million <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> lottery jackpot of Aug. 17, 1988. _ <PERSON> Gordon </PERSON> <PERSON> Pivar </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Oceanside </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, won $ 17.9 million, <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> lottery, Dec. 6, 1986. _ <PERSON> Helen </PERSON> <PERSON> Gueli </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Methuen </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mass. </LOCATION>, $ 17 million, won <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> lottery, March 4, 1988. _ <PERSON> Roland </PERSON> <PERSON> Roberts </PERSON>, <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Croix </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Virgin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Islands </LOCATION>, won $ 16 million, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Yor </LOCATION> lottery, Jan. 6, 1988. -LRB- claimed Jan. 14 -RRB- _ <PERSON> Marcia </PERSON> <PERSON> Sanford </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>, won $ 15.6 million, <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> lottery, July 13, 1984. _ Eve <LOCATION> Spencer </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Saratoga </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, won $ 15.2 million, <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> lottery, June 21, 1986. _ <PERSON> Josie </PERSON> <PERSON> Moore </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Port </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Charlotte </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>, won $ 14 million, <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> lottery, May 28, 1988. _ Wing <PERSON> Por </PERSON> <PERSON> Ng </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION>, won $ 12.8 million, <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> lottery, Dec. 31, 1986.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880905-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-05-88 0127EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names SUB a0414 09-05 0381</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names, SUB, a0414,0390</SECOND>
<NOTE>Eds: SUBS item on Tyson to lead with 5 grafs to UPDATE with
identity of car; witness reporting Tyson seemed to have been
knocked unconscious; picks up 3rd graf pvs, `Tyson, who ...';
Longer version moved on sports wires.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Heavyweight boxing champion <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Tyson </PERSON> is recuperating today from minor head and chest injuries after apparently being knocked out in a single-car accident near his upstate training camp. <PERSON> Tyson </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> BMW </ORGANIZATION> apparently skidded on a wet road Sunday morning, said a spokesman for the boxer, <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Klores </PERSON>, who gave no other details of the crash. A witness said the accident occurred while <PERSON> Tyson </PERSON> was driving his car out of the yard at his adopted family's home in <LOCATION> Catskill </LOCATION> and it skidded and slammed into a tree. He was found, apparently unconscious. `` <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> was just leaning back in his car seat and I took his pulse,'' said <PERSON> Yvonne </PERSON> <PERSON> Conrad </PERSON>, a niece of <PERSON> Camille </PERSON> <PERSON> Ewald </PERSON>, whom <PERSON> Tyson </PERSON> has been close to since he began training in <LOCATION> Catskill </LOCATION> eight years ago. `` He was normal, his breathing was n't heavy or labored. I did n't hear anything wrong with him We just could n't arouse him. We tried to wake him up by asking ` <PERSON> Mike </PERSON>, <PERSON> Mike </PERSON>,' and we just could n't get anything from him.'' <PERSON> Tyson </PERSON>, who was recovering from a broken bone in his right hand suffered in a street fight two weeks ago with heavyweight <PERSON> Mitch </PERSON> <PERSON> Green </PERSON>, was taken to two upstate hospitals before being transferred Sunday night to <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Presbyterian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> here. <PERSON> Tyson </PERSON> was hospitalized for observation and diagnostic tests, said Dr. <PERSON> Carolyn </PERSON> <PERSON> Britton </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Presbyterian </LOCATION>. `` He suffered minor trauma to the head and the chest wall,'' <PERSON> Britton </PERSON> said, adding that <PERSON> Tyson </PERSON>'s condition was stable. `` He's neurologicallly normal.'' As <PERSON> Tyson </PERSON> arrived in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, his wife, actress <PERSON> Robin </PERSON> <PERSON> Givens </PERSON>, tried to keep waiting photographers away from her husband. As cameramen pressed forward, <PERSON> Givens </PERSON> pushed them back, shouting, `` Give him a break.'' <PERSON> Tyson </PERSON>, whose championship bout against British champ <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Bruno </PERSON> was recently postponed until Oct. 22 because of the hand injury, was scheduled to accompany his wife to the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> on Wednesday. In his last fight in the ring on June 27, <PERSON> Tyson </PERSON> knocked out previously unbeaten <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Spinks </PERSON> in 91 seconds, earning $ 22 million.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880905-0020 </DOCNO>
