<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880220-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-20-88 0240EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Israel-Assess     02-20 0725</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Israel-Assess,0749</SECOND>
<HEAD>Prime Minister Will Be Focus Of Shultz Mission</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Analysis</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Saturday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By NICOLAS B. TATRO</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>JERUSALEM (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Secretary of State <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> will have to overcome <PERSON> Yitzhak </PERSON> <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON>'s growing opposition if he expects the new <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> peace proposals to get anywhere. The 72-year-old prime minister, a former underground fighter and senior spymaster, has a reputation for being tough-minded. Aides say he will not yield to the pressure of negative publicity or diplomatic arm-twisting. <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON> has expressed serious reservations, and some annoyance, about <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> ideas for reviving progress toward peace in the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION>. To clear the air in advance of the <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> visit next week, he sent emissaries to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> to declare what he would and would not accept. One envoy was <PERSON> Ehud </PERSON> <PERSON> Olmert </PERSON>, a senior figure in <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON>'s conservative <ORGANIZATION> Likud </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bloc </ORGANIZATION>, who said he told <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> the prime minister would not agree to territorial compromise in advance of peace talks `` Territory for peace is a non-starter,'' <PERSON> Olmert </PERSON> said in an interview. `` We are ready to negotiate on the territorial issue, but that does n't mean we are ready to accept withdrawing from the territories before negotiations.'' <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> has occupied the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strip </LOCATION> since capturing them from <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION> in the 1967 <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> war. <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> suggested the land-for-peace formula in a speech to the Council on Foreign Relations in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> and it apparently upset <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON>. `` The timing, manner and phrasing was inappropriate, inasmuch as he wants to have the prime minister in the process,'' <PERSON> Olmert </PERSON> said, adding that he believed the secretary of state realized his `` mistake.'' <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON>'s plan calls for: _ An international forum that would convene by April to launch Arab-Israeli negotiations. The Soviets would likely play an equal role with <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. _ An interim solution for the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> in the form of self-rule for the 1.5 million Palestinians who live there. Elections would be held by October to choose a self-governing body. _ Talks on the final status of the occupied lands to start by December even without progress on autonomy. <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON> initially indicated flexibility, to encourage negotiations, but the suggestion that he would agree to yield some of the occupied land caused a storm of protest among <ORGANIZATION> Likud </ORGANIZATION> hard-liners. Perhaps fearing concessions would be seen as giving in to Arab rioters, <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON> has drawn back, with tougher rhetoric and warnings between the lines that he will not accept pressure from the Americans. He has been cool to Soviet involvement, requested a clearer definition of the forum that would launch negotiations, and expressed opposition to linking talks on a temporary solution in the occupied territories with negotiations on a permanent settlement. He argues that several years of experience with limited self-rule is needed to build confidence for a stable solution. `` There is a need for a considerable period of practical experience, of coexistence between us and the <LOCATION> Palestinian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arab </LOCATION> authorities before the question of sovereignty can be approached,'' <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON> said in a speech this week. <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> will begin a <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> shuttle Thursday after a visit to <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>, using <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION> as a base and traveling to <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION> and possibly other Arab countries, Israeli officials said. His most intensive shuttle, however, may be between <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON> and Foreign Minister <PERSON> Shimon </PERSON> <PERSON> Peres </PERSON>. The two partners and rivals in <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s coalition government and who disagree sharply on strategy for peace. `` They are miles apart,'' an official close to <PERSON> Peres </PERSON> said privately. `` <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> will try to bring them to together as he has in the past.'' <PERSON> Peres </PERSON>, leader of the center-left <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, has endorsed <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION>'s proposal for an international conference, which <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON> says would be biased against <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>. Labor accepts the land-for-peace formula but the <ORGANIZATION> Likud </ORGANIZATION> fears giving up land would make <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> vulnerable. Aides to both leaders say <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> will concentrate on winning <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON>'s agreement, since <PERSON> Peres </PERSON> already has accepted the <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> plan. `` <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON>'s major goal is to convince <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON>,'' one official said. A senior aide to <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON>, also speaking on condition of anonymity, said the prime minister views the <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> visit `` with caution'' but is ready to listen and give his position. `` Some of his -LRB- <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON>'s -RRB- ideas are okay and others are not,'' the aide said.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Nicolas </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Tatro </PERSON> is chief of <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> bureau in <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880220-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-20-88 0225EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-SkinheadIndictments 1stLd-Writethru a0757 02-20 0557</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Skinhead Indictments, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0757,0567</SECOND>
<HEAD>Skinhead Boss, Four Others Indicted for Racial Assault</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: SUBS 4th graf, `Arrested with ...' to UPDATE with arraignment
delayed.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By ELIZABETH SHOGREN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CHICAGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The reputed leader of a Chicago-area group called the Skinheads and five other alleged white supremacists were indicted Friday for attacking a woman and drawing a swastika on her wall with her blood. Authorities believe the defendants beat the 20-year-old woman, with whom they were acquainted, because she had black friends, state's attorney's spokeswoman <PERSON> Lisa </PERSON> <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> said. The group's leader, <PERSON> Clark </PERSON> <PERSON> Martell </PERSON>, 28, and the others were charged with home invasion, robbery, theft and two counts of aggravated battery, Ms. <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> said. Arrested with them Jan. 25 was an unidentified 16-year-old whose indictment had been expected Friday but was delayed until later this month because a special hearing must be held to charge him as an adult, Ms. <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> said. The victim was not identified to protect her from members of the white supremacist group, Ms. <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> said. The suspects are accused of pushing their way into the woman's North Side apartment last April, forcing her to the floor and repeatedly punching and kicking her After her attackers sprayed a Mace-type chemical in her face, the woman managed to break free and lock herself in the bathroom, where she passed out, Ms. <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> said. The defendants allegedly ransacked her apartment, stole jewelry and clothing and drew swastikas throughout her home, Ms. <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> said. `` Most of the Nazi symbols were spray-painted or drawn with markers, but one swastika on the woman's living room wall was drawn with the victim's blood,'' Ms. <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> said. `` Prosecutors believe the attack was motivated by the defendants' anger over the victim's friendship'' with blacks, Ms. <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> said. The victim had formerly associated with the Skinheads, she said. `` This type of crime, which is nothing more than vicious race hatred, will not be tolerated in <LOCATION> Cook </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, just as it can not be tolerated anywhere in our society,'' State's Attorney <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Daley </PERSON> said in a statement. `` These defendants will be prosecuted to fullest extent of the law, as will anyone who dares to commit such a cowardly crime,'' he said. The home invasion charge, which is the most serious, has a maximum prison sentence of 30 years and a minimum of six years without probation, Ms. <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> said. The robbery charge can bring as much as seven years in prison and the theft and battery charges can bring as much as five-year terms each, she said. The others indicted were identified as <PERSON> Morgan </PERSON> <PERSON> Kipp </PERSON>, 18, her brother <PERSON> Sean </PERSON> <PERSON> Kipp </PERSON>, 20, <PERSON> Cassandra </PERSON> <PERSON> Clark </PERSON>, 20, <PERSON> Tracy </PERSON> <PERSON> Zajdel </PERSON>, 20, and <PERSON> Kevin </PERSON> <PERSON> Jamison </PERSON>, 26. They are scheduled to be arraigned March 11 before Chief Criminal Court Judge <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzgerald </PERSON>. All except <PERSON> Martell </PERSON> are free on $ 50,000 bond. The state's attorney's office will seek to try the juvenile as an adult. <PERSON> Martell </PERSON> is scheduled to appear in court twice on charges stemming from separate racial attacks before the hearing on the latest indictments. Skinheads is a name some white supremacists across the nation have given themselves, in accordance with their practice of shaving their heads. But some people enjoy the music and fashion of the Skinheads without sharing their racist sentiments, said <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> <PERSON> Levin </PERSON>, a spokesman for the state's attorney's office.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880220-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-20-88 0242EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--Spain-Women     02-20 0150</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Spain-Women,0154</SECOND>
<HEAD>Spanish Women Eligible for Armed Forces</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MADRID, Spain (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Spanish </LOCATION> women will be able to enlist in the armed forces under a decree that takes effect next week, but they wo n't be eligible for combat or military academies. Women will be allowed to serve in 24 noncombatant units in the armed forces and paramilitary <ORGANIZATION> Civil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guards </ORGANIZATION>, government spokesman <PERSON> Javier </PERSON> <PERSON> Solana </PERSON> told reporters Friday after the weekly Cabinet meeting. The Cabinet had just approved a decree providing for volunteer female military service in keeping with an article in the Constitution that prohibits discrimination on the basis of sex. Women can sign up for military service after publication Tuesday of the decree in the Official State Bulletin, but they will not be eligible for admittance to the country's three military academies. All Spanish males over the age of 18 are required to serve one year in the military.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880220-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-20-88 0603EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-US-Panama Bjt   02-20 0484</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-US-Panama, Bjt,470</SECOND>
<HEAD>Panama Indicates Interest in Deal on Noriega</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GEORGE GEDDA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>, apparently seeking a way out of a legal and diplomatic predicament with the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, made discreet inquiries about <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> willingness to drop federal charges against military strong man Gen. <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>, administration officials say. The <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> confirmed Friday that <LOCATION> Panamanian </LOCATION> authorities had asked about that possibility and that Assistant Secretary of State <PERSON> Elliott </PERSON> <PERSON> Abrams </PERSON> raised the matter with the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>. After being told that dropping the charges was `` technically possible,'' <PERSON> Abrams </PERSON> relayed that message Wednesday to Panamanian President <PERSON> Eric </PERSON> <PERSON> Arturo </PERSON> <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON> during an unannounced meeting in <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION>. But during their discussion, <PERSON> Abrams </PERSON> `` made no deal, offered no deal and was not in a position to offer a deal,'' <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Redman </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Redman </PERSON> added that the indictments against <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> are `` obviously based on strong evidence, and we have every intention on carrying through with them.'' The Panamanian Embassy had no comment on the <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> meeting, saying only that <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON> had gone to <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> for medical treatment. <PERSON> Redman </PERSON> denied an account in <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> that said <PERSON> Abrams </PERSON> told <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON> the indictment might be dropped if <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> withdrew from politics and went into exile. <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> cited as its sources <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials and congressional staff members it did not name. The Panamanian inquiry was made as a political crisis grew in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>, brought on in part by <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>'s legal problems. Indictments handed down in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> two weeks ago portrayed <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> as a key member of an international drug trafficking conspiracy. Among other activities, he was accused of providing protection and other government services to international drug smugglers who shipped cocaine and marijuana to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> through <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>. U.S.-Panamanian agreements do not provide for his extradition, making it virtually impossible for <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> to be brought to trial. At the same time, the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration is deeply concerned about <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s political stability and has been encouraging <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> and his military allies to withdraw from politics. The administration believes that the security of the <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Canal </LOCATION> is best assured through elected civilian rule. <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON> is widely viewed as a figurehead president who bows to <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>'s wishes The Times account said that under the formula <PERSON> Abrams </PERSON> discussed, <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> could move to any country he wished without having to concern himself with the possibility of extradition to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. With <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> living in exile, this scenario also could enhance the possibility _ consistent with <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> objectives _ of an evolution to a civilian-led government in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>. But <PERSON> Redman </PERSON> insisted that the administration has no interest in any arrangement for <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> to be exiled in exchange for a drop of the charges. `` We all see the drug problem of tremendous importance in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> as well as throughout the hemisphere,'' <PERSON> Redman </PERSON> said, reaffirming that the indictments will not be withdrawn.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880220-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-20-88 0006EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a PM-BlackSchool-Georgia CORRECTIVE   02-20 0076</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Black School-Georgia, CORRECTIVE,0081</SECOND>
<TEXT>
 EDITORS: Members who used the publishable editor's note on PM-Black School-Georgia, sent Feb. 12 in advance as b0200 and repeated Feb. 18 as a0414, are asked to use the following: <LOCATION> NEW </LOCATION> <LOCATION> YORK </LOCATION> -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> -RRB- _ In an editor's note preceding a story Feb. 18 about black private schools, The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> erroneously said the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Independent </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Schools </ORGANIZATION> represents Roman Catholic schools. It does not.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>The AP</HEAD>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880220-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-20-88 0603EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-North'sNetwork Bjt   02-20 0701</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-North's Network, Bjt,720</SECOND>
<HEAD>Assistant U.S. Attorney Shunned When He Found Iran-Contra
Operation</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LARRY MARGASAK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A federal prosecutor in <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> says he was `` treated like the enemy'' by <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> diplomats and stymied by superiors in the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> attorney's office after he discovered <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> <PERSON> North </PERSON>'s Contra supply network. <PERSON> Jeffrey </PERSON> <PERSON> Feldman </PERSON>, an assistant <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> attorney, says in a sworn statement the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> ambassador to <LOCATION> Costa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rica </LOCATION> `` turned white'' after learning what <PERSON> Feldman </PERSON> knew in the spring of 1986 _ eight months before the Iran-Contra arms and money affair dominated the news. And <PERSON> Feldman </PERSON> described months of unsuccessful efforts to take the investigation to the grand jury, with his boss telling him in August 1986 that `` politics'' was responsible for the delay. <PERSON> Feldman </PERSON>, other prosecutors and an <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> agent unveiled the story of the <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> investigation in sworn statements to the congressional Iran-Contra committees. They were released this week by a <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Foreign Relations subcommittee. <PERSON> Feldman </PERSON> admitted he should have `` been more aggressive'' in pursuing the North network, `` because history has basically spoken.'' <PERSON> Feldman </PERSON> and two <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> agents went to <LOCATION> Costa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rica </LOCATION> on March 31, 1986, to investigate an alleged murder plot against then-U. Ambassador <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON> <PERSON> Tambs </PERSON>. The prosecutor said the plot proved to be bogus, but he did obtain details about a private supply network for the U.S.-backed Contra rebels trying to overthrow the Nicaraguan government. <PERSON> Feldman </PERSON> said he made the information into a chart with <PERSON> North </PERSON>'s name on the top North, a <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> aide, directed the secret operations to sell arms to <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> and aid the Contras despite a law prohibiting such assistance. `` The ambassador turned white,'' <PERSON> Feldman </PERSON> said, describing <PERSON> Tambs </PERSON> after he was shown the chart. <PERSON> Tambs </PERSON> was identified in the Iran-Contra hearings as a key link in <LOCATION> North </LOCATION>'s network. `` The only thing he said when I pulled out the chart was ` Get <PERSON> Fernandez </PERSON> in here.' The words are indelibly imprinted in my mind,'' <PERSON> Feldman </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Fernandez </PERSON>, then <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> station chief in <LOCATION> Costa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rica </LOCATION>, `` knew he was dealing with three people -LRB- <PERSON> Feldman </PERSON> and two <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> agents -RRB- who had only seen the tip of an iceberg and was ... trying to rip the credibility of the various people who were making the allegations that we were exploring,'' <PERSON> Feldman </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Feldman </PERSON> said he and the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> investigators with him in <LOCATION> Costa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rica </LOCATION> `` were being treated like the enemy'' for the rest of their stay. He added, `` I felt perhaps we were being watched.'' Throughout the spring and summer of 1986, <PERSON> Feldman </PERSON> asked his boss, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Attorney <PERSON> Leon </PERSON> <PERSON> Kellner </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION>, to allow the case to go to a grand jury. But <PERSON> Feldman </PERSON> _ who at the time did not realize the full significance of what he had discovered _ said he was stalled for months by <PERSON> Kellner </PERSON> and other top assistants in the office. <PERSON> Kellner </PERSON>'s assistants said the case was n't far enough along to move to the grand jury. And on Aug. 29, <PERSON> Feldman </PERSON> said <PERSON> Kellner </PERSON> told him, `` politics are involved.'' The secret sale of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> weapons to <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> and the diversion of profits to the Contras did n't dominate public attention until Nov. 25, 1986, after a Lebanese news magazine disclosed secret negotiations over American hostages between the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Kellner </PERSON>, in his deposition, acknowledged telling <PERSON> Feldman </PERSON> that politics were causing a delay, but denied that he was referring to the discovery of North's network. Instead, <PERSON> Kellner </PERSON> said he referred to allegations he received from pro-Contra mercenaries that aides to <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> Sen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Kerry </PERSON> were paying informants to lie. <PERSON> Kellner </PERSON> admitted he did not tell <PERSON> Feldman </PERSON> about these allegations when he used the word `` politics'' _ but <PERSON> Kellner </PERSON> decided not to give the case to the grand jury without first discussing these allegations with the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Feldman </PERSON>, who then was 29 years old, acknowledged in his statement that he did not focus on <PERSON> North </PERSON>, who was directing the Iran-Contra effort. <PERSON> Feldman </PERSON> said he thought the case was mainly about paramilitary groups illegally aiding the Contras. `` For the most part, the case is about people in private organizations, basically on their own, going out and recruiting help for the -LRB- Contras -RRB- or putting their own little paramilitary groups together,'' <PERSON> Feldman </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880220-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-20-88 0616EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FarmScene     02-20 0604</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Farm Scene,590</SECOND>
<HEAD>Boost in Pork, Poultry Output Should Temper Retail Price Increases</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MIKE ROBINSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Retail food prices will rise more slowly this year than last year's 4.2 percent increase, mainly because of a sharp increase in meat production, the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> says. The forecast, however, is based on an expected jump in pork and poultry production, which should more than offset a drop in beef output in figuring retail food prices, according to a <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> report issued this week. That does not necessarily mean any boon for consumers unwilling to forgo beef in favor of pork and poultry. The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cattlemen </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> already is hailing a decline of 3 million head in the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> herd as of Jan. 1 to 99 million as a `` bullish'' signal for increased beef prices. <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> says red meat production in 1987 totaled 38,449,000 pounds and poultry 19,765,000 pounds. Consumption of red meat and poultry combined was 216.7 pounds per capita last year. The forecast issued this week said red meat production this year should reach 38,345,000 pounds and poultry 20,935,000. It estimated per capita consumption at 221.9 pounds. Retail food prices last year were 333 percent of their 1967 level, according to the report. The report did not attempt to estimate precisely how much they would climb over the year ahead but merely said the increase would be less than that of 1987. The report also said hog profits fell sharply in the final quarter of 1987 and probably will continue to drop this year. Net returns could average only slightly above the break-even point, it said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Overseas sale of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> wheat climbed sharply last week, primarily because of Soviet, Chinese and Moroccan purchases, the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> says. Soybean and sorghum sales also climbed, but corn, barley and cotton fell compared with the four-week average, the department said. Wheat sales hit 1,178,100 metric tons. The Soviets purchased 308,500 tons, <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> 299,000 tons and <LOCATION> Morocco </LOCATION> 220,800 tons, the department said. <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> said sales of sorghum totaled 347,100 tons, the most in the current marketing year. The increase was attributed mainly to purchases by <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Venezuela </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>. Soybean sales of 589,500 tons were 56 percent over the previous week's mark and 72 percent above the four-week average. <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> was the main purchaser, followed by <LOCATION> Romania </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> Netherlands </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>. Corn sales fell to 777,400 tons, 14 percent below the previous week and 44 percent lower than the four-week average, despite substantial purchases by <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>. Barley sales were down, with <LOCATION> Tunisia </LOCATION> purchasing all of the 25,000 tons sold last week. According to the report, cotton sales totaled 55,700 bales, 13 percent below the previous week's mark and 50 percent off from the four-week average. Rice sales of 23,900 tons were 56 percent above the previous week but 46 percent below the four-week average. <LOCATION> Trinidad </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Saudi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arabia </LOCATION> were the main purchasers. Among other commodities, soybean cake and meal sales were up for the week but still well short of the four-week average, while soybean oil sales were down. Sales of hides and skins were lower for the week but a shade above the four-week average.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The nation's catfish farms processed a total of 26 million pounds of fish in January, the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> says. That represents a 24 percent gain from January 1987, <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> says. The average price was 68 cents a pound, up 8 cents from a year earlier. Sales of catfish in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> totaled 5,680 metric tons in January, the report said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880220-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-20-88 0617EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Candidates-Schedules     02-20 0405</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Candidates-Schedules,400</SECOND>
<HEAD>Presidential Candidates' Schedules</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are tentative schedules for the presidential candidates for the week beginning Feb. 21. The information was provided by the campaigns, most of which are holding open late-week schedules.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 Sunday, Feb. 21:
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 Democrats: <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> _ Down <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> _ <ORGANIZATION> Aberdeen </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Watertown </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Sioux </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Falls </LOCATION>, S.D. <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hart </LOCATION> <LOCATION> _ </LOCATION> <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jackson </LOCATION> _ <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pa </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Newark </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.J. </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Augusta </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ga. </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Mount </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rushmore </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Rapid </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, S.D; <PERSON> Worthington </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Minn </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 Republicans: <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> _ Down <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kemp </LOCATION> _ <LOCATION> Minneapolis </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Eden </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Prairie </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Minn. </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> _
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 Monday, Feb. 22:
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 Democrats: <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gephardt </LOCATION> _ <LOCATION> Sioux </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Falls </LOCATION>, S.D.; <PERSON> Sheridan </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Wyo </LOCATION>.; <LOCATION> Rapid </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, S.D. <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> Baltimore </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> D.C. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hart </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> _ </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Madison </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Watertown </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Sioux </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Falls </LOCATION>, S.D. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> Macon </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Griffin </PERSON> and <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>, Ga; <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Simon </LOCATION> _ <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Peter </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Minneapolis </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Rochester </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Winona </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Minn. </LOCATION>. Republicans: <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dole </LOCATION> _ <LOCATION> Duluth </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Moorhead </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Rochester </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Minneapolis </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Minn. </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Paul </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Minn. </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION> <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 Tuesday, Feb. 23:
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 Democrats: <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> _ open <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> Rapid </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, S.D.; <LOCATION> Rock </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Springs </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Laramie </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Cheyenne </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wyo </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Sioux </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Falls </LOCATION>, S.D. <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> Norfolk </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Greensboro </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.C. </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Little </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rock </LOCATION> and Ft.. <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, Ark <PERSON> Hart </PERSON> _ open <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> _ open <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> D.C </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 Republicans: <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> _ open <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> Mankato </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Minneapolis </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Coon </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rapids </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Paul </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Minn. </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> _
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 Wednesday, Feb. 24:
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 Democrats: <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> _ open <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> _ open <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hart </LOCATION> _ open <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> _ open <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> _ open
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 Republicans: <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> _ open <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> _ open <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Robertson </LOCATION> _ open
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 Thursday, Feb. 25:
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 Democrats: <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> _ open <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> _ open <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> Lafayette </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> La </LOCATION>.; Mobile, <LOCATION> Ala. </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Jacksonville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Hart </PERSON> _ open <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> _ open <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> _
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 Republicans: <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> _ open <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> _ open <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Robertson </LOCATION> _ open
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 Friday, Feb. 26:
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 Democrats: <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> _ open <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> _ open <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> _ open <PERSON> Hart </PERSON> _ open <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> _ open <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> _ open
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 Republicans: <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> _ open <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> _ open <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Robertson </LOCATION> _ open
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 Saturday, Feb. 27:
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 Democrats: <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gephardt </LOCATION> _ <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gore </LOCATION> _ <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hart </LOCATION> _ <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jackson </LOCATION> _ <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Simon </LOCATION> _ <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 Republicans: <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> _ open <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> _ open <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Robertson </LOCATION> _ open
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880220-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-20-88 0620EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-AIDS-Koop     02-20 0504</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AIDS-Koop,490</SECOND>
<HEAD>Koop Emphasizes Risk To Heterosexuals From AIDS</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto WX9</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JILL LAWRENCE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Surgeon General <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Everett </PERSON> <PERSON> Koop </PERSON> says public health officials agree that heterosexuals are at risk for contracting AIDS, despite recent published accounts that give the impression heterosexuals are relatively safe. <PERSON> Koop </PERSON> said Friday that several articles, including one in Cosmopolitan magazine, wrongly led women and heterosexual men to believe they are not at risk. `` The risk is real,'' <PERSON> Koop </PERSON> told the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> subcommittee on health. `` It is just not true that there is no danger from normal vaginal intercourse. What is unknown is the level of danger. There is always a danger whenever people engage in casual sex outside the marriage relationship, even if their promiscuity is heterosexual.'' As of Feb. 15, there were 53,814 cases of acquired immune deficiency syndrome reported to the federal <ORGANIZATION> Centers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Disease </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Control </ORGANIZATION>. About 65 percent were in homosexual or bisexual males, and 17 percent were in intravenous drug abusers. While only 4 percent of current AIDS cases are reported among heterosexuals, <PERSON> Koop </PERSON> said that proportion is expected to rise to 5 percent in the 1990s. <PERSON> Koop </PERSON> told the subcommittee that medical personnel generally have responded well to the AIDS crisis. But he said there is a minority of medical personnel who `` refuse not only to treat persons with AIDS, but also turn away patients alleged to be from population groups identified with those two high-risk behaviors: that is, homosexual and bisexual males and intravenous drug abusers.'' He characterized that behavior as `` unworthy of anyone in the health or social service professions.'' Those who turn away AIDS patients use the excuse that the disease is fatal and contagious, <PERSON> Koop </PERSON> said. `` But the plain fact is that the risk of contracting -LRB- AIDS -RRB- from an infected patient is extremely small and nearly always preventable.'' Of nearly 7 million health professionals in the country, <PERSON> Koop </PERSON> said, fewer than a dozen became infected with the AIDS virus while doing their jobs and, in most cases, that exposure could have been prevented if the person had followed guidelines published five years ago by the <ORGANIZATION> CDC </ORGANIZATION>. <ORGANIZATION> CDC </ORGANIZATION> director <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Mason </PERSON>, another witness, said more than 15 million Americans are being tested anonymously each year for AIDS through blood banks and the military and in 30 communities. He said more anonymous testing should be done to get a better fix on the extent of AIDS infection in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, but he rejected Rep. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Dannemeyer </PERSON>'s idea that anyone coming in contact with the health system be tested. <PERSON> Dannemeyer </PERSON>, R-Calif., has introduced legislation that would require testing of hospital patients, clinic patients, marriage license applicants and others He also wants to require reporting by name of any positive test results. <PERSON> Mason </PERSON> endorsed the general approach sponsored by subcommittee chairman Rep. <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> Waxman </PERSON>, D-Calif., which includes voluntary testing, confidentiality and anti-discrimination protection for those with the disease or virus `` Where there's worry about confidentiality or discrimination, there's a chilling effect,'' <PERSON> Mason </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880220-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-20-88 0244EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Narcotics-Military     02-20 0408</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Narcotics-Military,400</SECOND>
<HEAD>Kerry Suggests U.S. Military Intervention In Colombian Drug Wars</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CHRISTOPHER CALLAHAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 American military intervention may be needed in <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION> to halt the flow of narcotics to <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> cities, Sen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kerry </PERSON> says. `` We've gotten to the point where we have to be prepared to be tough. We can not be patsies about this stuff,'' the <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> Democrat said Friday. `` We ought to make it permanently hot for them down there.'' <PERSON> Kerry </PERSON>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Foreign Relations subcommittee on narcotics and terrorism, said the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> should provide <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION> with helicopters, communications equipment and other military systems to combat the region's drug czars. He said an estimated 80 percent of the narcotics entering the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> come from <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION>. But the senator added that military assistance may not be enough and that the administration should be willing to send troops to the area, if necessary, to help <LOCATION> Colombian </LOCATION> agents. `` I'm willing, and I think we ought to consider, the use of our <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Command </ORGANIZATION> forces to assist in the interdiction effort on a case-by-case basis. They ought to be able to do that because what you have here is literally a paramilitary organization that you're fighting against,'' <PERSON> Kerry </PERSON> told reporters `` This is a very sophisticated effort we're working against, and if it takes the visibility of our military force ... that's worth it to me,'' he added. Last April, 14 <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military advisers were sent to <LOCATION> Bolivia </LOCATION> to help train Bolivian anti-drug police. In July 1986, the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> sent 175 soldiers provide logistical support for Bolivian anti-drug operations. That program ended in November 1986. Meanwhile, <PERSON> Kerry </PERSON> released a letter to Sen. <PERSON> Lawton </PERSON> <PERSON> Chiles </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Fla </LOCATION>., chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Budget </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, urging the immediate transfer of $ 50 million from the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> to the <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION>, which is charged largely with battling drug trafficking at sea <PERSON> Kerry </PERSON> lambasted President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> for a series of <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> budget cuts. `` I'm tired of this phony war on drugs where they talk about it, where they stand <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> -LRB- <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> -RRB- up at the State of the Union message and try to pretend the war on drugs is rampaging across the country, and meanwhile they cut the guts out of the law enforcement effort. That type of hypocrisy has simply got to stop,'' <PERSON> Kerry </PERSON> said. He also called for a tightening of banking regulations for cash transactions and increasing penalties for drug trafficking.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880220-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-20-88 0622EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-US-Germany     02-20 0581</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-US-Germany,570</SECOND>
<HEAD>Kohl, Reagan Reaffirm United Strategy Against Soviets</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto WX8</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By HENRY GOTTLIEB</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and West German Chancellor <PERSON> Helmut </PERSON> <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON> are lauding a Western effort to build a common arms control strategy so <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> can manage the Soviets with `` realism, strength and alliance unity.'' The two leaders ended talks at the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> on Friday with a pledge to intensify the effort at a <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> summit March 2-3. `` What we need now is an overall concept covering the whole field of disarmament, and there I do not see any difference between us and the Americans,'' <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON> told reporters before heading back to <LOCATION> Bonn </LOCATION>. `` We agreed that we must deal with the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> from a position of realism, strength and alliance unity,'' Since reaching agreement with the Soviets to eliminate land-based nuclear missiles with ranges between 300 miles and 3,125 miles, the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and its allies have been trying to set goals for further talks with Soviet leader <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> and his aides. `` We want to get out of a situation where we merely react to proposals which have been submitted by <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>. We want to put down proposals and let him react to them,'' <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON> said. Secretary of State <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON>, who attended the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> meeting, left later in the day for another round of negotiations with the Soviets in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON> said <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> pledged to convey to the Soviets the West German concern about ethnic Germans facing discrimination in <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> bloc countries. <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> already has agreed on a first priority of a U.S.-Soviet reduction in long-range missiles and bombers, while seeking cuts in conventional and chemical weapons. `` We were in agreement that all these disarmament questions and issues as well as the necessary measures to preserve our common security should be combined in form and overall concept for our alliance,'' <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON> said. Each of the 16 allies, depending on its politics and geography, has different interests to advance, and one of the key differences was reflected in comments after <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON>'s meeting with <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>. <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> is particularly eager for negotiations to reduce tactical nuclear weapons _ those with ranges below 300 miles _ and wants those talks included in any conferences that deal with conventional weapons. <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON>, whose country would be threatened by such weapons if a war broke out in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, reiterated the desire for quick and comprehensive talks on the short-range systems. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, which believes tactical nuclear weapons are necessary to deter a conventional attack, wants to defer negotiations to reduce the short-range systems. Indeed, it is working on plans to modernize these weapons, with <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> approval. During <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON>'s visit, the two sides sought to minimize the importance of the disagreement. <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON> said he did not favor the elimination of the tactical nuclear weapons: artillery shells and short-range missiles. He does not seek a `` denuclearized zone, least of all in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON> was asked at the news conference about concerns that modernization of short-range weapons would touch off protests like those that rocked <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> in the early 1980s after <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> decided to deploy intermediate-range weapons. `` I do n't share that fear,'' <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON> said. In its efforts to play down the issue, the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration noted during <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON>'s visit that further study is needed before the most powerful of the short-range systems _ a missile to replace the 75-mile-range Lance _ is deployed and it may not go into operation before 1995.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880220-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-20-88 0246EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Gingrich-Wright     02-20 0550</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Gingrich-Wright,540</SECOND>
<HEAD>Gingrich To Ask House Ethics Committee To Investigate Speaker</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID PACE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Rep. <PERSON> Newt </PERSON> <PERSON> Gingrich </PERSON>, contending that published reports have outlined `` clear violations of <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> rules'' by Speaker <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>, says he intends to ask the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> ethics committee next month to launch a formal investigation. <PERSON> Gingrich </PERSON>, R-Ga., told a news conference Friday that the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> needs to know the truth about the allegations of corruption that have been leveled at <LOCATION> Wright </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D-Texas </LOCATION>, in news accounts over the past decade `` We're going to have to at least at a minimum insist that we find out what the truth is, and on March 3, I intend to create that opportunity,'' <PERSON> Gingrich </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>'s office did not return a telephone call Friday seeking comment on <PERSON> Gingrich </PERSON>'s plan to seek an ethics committee investigation. <PERSON> Gingrich </PERSON> said two specific published reports about <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> provide clear evidence that he violated House rules. One involved <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>'s failure since 1980 to file the required financial disclosure reports for a company in which he is a partner. The other involved 55 percent royalties <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> received for a book published by a friend whose printing company worked for <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>'s campaign committee. House rules prohibit members from receiving royalties in excess of `` the usual and customary value for such services,'' <PERSON> Gingrich </PERSON> said, and most authors receive royalties of 6 percent to 8 percent. <PERSON> Gingrich </PERSON> said the ethics panel also should investigate <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>'s connection to <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> savings and loan association officials who are under investigation by federal authorities The <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Congressional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Campaign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> last month accused <PERSON> Gingrich </PERSON> and a political action committee he heads of mail fraud and asked the <ORGANIZATION> Postal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> to investigate. The <ORGANIZATION> DCCC </ORGANIZATION> said the PAC collected more than $ 200,000 through mail solicitations of contributions for conservative candidates, but provided only $ 3,000 to such candidates. <PERSON> Gingrich </PERSON>, who has denied the accusations, said Friday the <ORGANIZATION> DCCC </ORGANIZATION> complaint was a `` smoke screen'' designed to discredit him politically so he could not pursue the ethics complaints against <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>. Under House rules, any member can ask the ethics panel to investigate another member. The committee, composed of six Democrats and six Republicans, can reject such a request only by a majority vote. <PERSON> Gingrich </PERSON> said it would be `` inconceivable'' that the committee would refuse to investigate the allegations. But if that happens, he said he intends to force the issue on the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> floor with a series of privileged votes that could tie up <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> business. <PERSON> Gingrich </PERSON> tried unsuccessfully last year to persuade the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> to create an outside commission to investigate ethics complaints against <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> and other Democratic leaders. He said he was announcing his intention to seek an investigation of <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> now to give other <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> members time to familiarize themselves with the long list of allegations. <PERSON> Gingrich </PERSON> has criticized the ethics committee in the past for its lenient treatment of Democrats accused of wrongdoing. But he said Friday he has more confidence in the panel after its recent votes to reprimand one Democratic congressman and recommend the expulsion of another. He said he believes the panel can conduct a fair investigation of <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> if it will agree to hire an outside attorney acceptable to both <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> leaders and to complete its investigation before <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> adjourns for the year.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880220-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-20-88 0623EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-GlassMerger     02-20 0366</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Glass Merger,360</SECOND>
<HEAD>Appeals Court Keeps Glass Merger on Hold</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JAMES HANNAH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A proposed merger between two of the nation's largest manufacturers of glass containers remains on hold today in the wake of a ruling by a federal appeals court Late Friday afternoon, the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appeals </ORGANIZATION> issued an administrative stay of a lower court decision that would have cleared the way for the merger between <ORGANIZATION> Owens-Illinois </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Brockway </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc </ORGANIZATION>. Earlier in the day, the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Trade </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> had asked the appeals court to extend until next Tuesday a restraining order blocking the merger until the agency could decide whether to appeal a ruling by <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> Judge <PERSON> Joyce </PERSON> <PERSON> Hens </PERSON> <PERSON> Green </PERSON>. On Thursday, <PERSON> Green </PERSON> refused the <ORGANIZATION> FTC </ORGANIZATION>'s request for a preliminary injunction, ruling that the <ORGANIZATION> FTC </ORGANIZATION> had not proven the deal would harm competition. <ORGANIZATION> FTC </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman <PERSON> Susan </PERSON> <PERSON> Tichnor </PERSON> said the agency will have until next Tuesday to file an appeal and that the court will issue a decision sometime after <ORGANIZATION> Owens-Illinois </ORGANIZATION> files a response Wednesday. Attorneys for <ORGANIZATION> Owens-Illinois </ORGANIZATION> said there is no excuse for the <ORGANIZATION> FTC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` unusual filing'' Friday to keep the merger on hold until the agency can decide whether to appeal. `` The <ORGANIZATION> FTC </ORGANIZATION> has been acutely aware since the beginning of this case of the extreme time sensitivity surrounding the merger and, in that regard, has had ample time to prepare for the possibility of a decision adverse to it,'' said <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Warnke </PERSON>, an attorney for <ORGANIZATION> Owens-Illinois </ORGANIZATION>. Last September, the <LOCATION> Toledo </LOCATION>, Ohio-based <ORGANIZATION> Owens-Illinois </ORGANIZATION> proposed to buy <PERSON> Brockway </PERSON>, of <LOCATION> Jacksonville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>, for $ 750 million, or $ 60 per share. The merger would make the combined company the largest manufacturer of glass containers in the industry. The nation's top manufacturer is <ORGANIZATION> Anchor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Glass </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Container </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, which controls 23.7 percent of the market. The <ORGANIZATION> FTC </ORGANIZATION> has said the merger might violate federal antitrust laws by substantially reducing competition in the glass container industry and creating conditions for price discrimination. It wants to halt the merger until it can conduct an administrative review of the proposal. But <PERSON> Green </PERSON> accepted the argument advanced by the two manufacturers that competition from the plastics and metal-packaging industry will hold down prices.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880220-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-20-88 0013EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-CentralAmerica Bjt   02-20 0721</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Central America, Bjt,0741</SECOND>
<HEAD>Contra-Sandinista Peace Talks End Over Democracy, Truce</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY4</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By REID G. MILLER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>GUATEMALA CITY (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Peace talks between <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>'s leftist Sandinista government and Contra rebels are right back where they began _ mired in a dispute over what comes first, democracy or a truce. Cardinal <PERSON> Miguel </PERSON> <PERSON> Obando </PERSON> y Bravo, the <ORGANIZATION> Nicaraguan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Roman </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> leader who has been mediating the negotiations, abruptly suspended the latest round of talks Friday, indirectly blaming the <ORGANIZATION> Sandinistas </ORGANIZATION> for their failure. <PERSON> Obando </PERSON> y <PERSON> Bravo </PERSON> said he was disappointed that both sides had not accepted, at least in principle, a proposal he put forth Thursday in an attempt to break a deadlock that arose in the first hours of the talks. That impasse stemmed from what the cardinal said was the inability of the two sides to agree on whether they should negotiate a cease-fire to obtain democracy, or negotiate democracy to obtain a cease-fire. More than 40,000 people have been killed since November 1981, when the Contras began fighting the Sandinista government. The cardinal's plan called on the Contras to accept a truce in exchange for four major concessions by the government. They were concessions the Contras have long sought, and they quickly accepted the proposal in principle. But <PERSON> Victor </PERSON> <PERSON> Hugo </PERSON> <PERSON> Tinoco </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>'s deputy foreign minister, said the cardinal suspended the talks in mid-afternoon Friday before he could deliver his government's formal, written response, which also conditionally accepted the plan. The confusion apparently arose because President <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON> initially instructed his negotiators to reject <PERSON> Obando </PERSON> <PERSON> y </PERSON> <PERSON> Bravo </PERSON>'s proposal as unsuitable for discussion at talks the Sandinista leader felt should be aimed solely at the mechanics of achieving a cease-fire The government apparently changed its mind later and authorized <PERSON> Tinoco </PERSON> to accept conditionally the cardinal's plan. By then, <PERSON> Obando </PERSON> <PERSON> y </PERSON> <PERSON> Bravo </PERSON> had suspended the negotiations without setting a time or place for a new round of talks. Contra negotiators announced their tentative acceptance of <PERSON> Obando </PERSON> y <PERSON> Bravo </PERSON>'s proposal at a news conference Thursday night. Shortly afterward, <PERSON> Tinoco </PERSON> told reporters the plan was `` interesting and constructive,'' but needed clarification. <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Reichler </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION>, attorney advising the <ORGANIZATION> Sandinistas </ORGANIZATION>, said <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON> advised the government negotiators during a telephone conference later Thursday evening to reject <PERSON> Obando </PERSON> y <PERSON> Bravo </PERSON>'s proposal. <PERSON> Reichler </PERSON> quoted <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON> as saying that if <PERSON> Obando </PERSON> <PERSON> y </PERSON> <PERSON> Bravo </PERSON> felt the issues he raised in his proposal were of vital importance to the <LOCATION> Nicaraguan </LOCATION> people, the president would discuss them with the cardinal personally. But <PERSON> Reichler </PERSON> said <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON>'s initial reaction was that he would not discuss political issues at the bargaining table with the Contras _ a position the <LOCATION> Nicaraguan </LOCATION> leader has long held. <PERSON> Obando </PERSON> <PERSON> y </PERSON> <PERSON> Bravo </PERSON>'s plan called for the Contras to move into unspecified `` enclaves or zones'' with their arms and equipment during a 30-day truce, during which talks would continue toward a more lasting cease-fire. In exchange, the cardinal called on the Nicaraguan government to: _ Grant a `` full, general'' amnesty to the several thousand political prisoners in Nicaraguan jails, including members of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> of former dictator Gen. <PERSON> Anastasio </PERSON> <PERSON> Somoza </PERSON>, whom the <ORGANIZATION> Sandinistas </ORGANIZATION> overthrew in 1979 _ Permit `` unrestricted'' freedom of the press, a right now granted only to a few mass media, including the opposition newspaper <ORGANIZATION> La </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Prensa </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Radio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Catolica </ORGANIZATION>, the voice of the <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> _ `` Reconsider'' mandatory military draft law, which has provoked violent disturbances by youths and mothers of draft-age people in several Nicaraguan cities. _ Reopen a dialogue with its internal opposition, including 14 dissident political parties and a coalition of business, labor and political groups known as the Democratic Coordinating Council Those talks broke down late last year. <PERSON> Tinoco </PERSON>'s initial response and the government's later written statement said the <PERSON> Obando </PERSON> y <PERSON> Bravo </PERSON> plan needed clarification on the size and location of the cease-fire zones, when the truce would start, how it would be verified and how the Contras would be supplied during the cessation of hostilities. <PERSON> Reichler </PERSON> said <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON> suggested that <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> Fisher </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> professor who heads the <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conflict </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Resolution </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>, draw up a new cease-fire proposal, drawing on plans already submitted by both sides. But in announcing suspension of the talks, <PERSON> Obando </PERSON> y <PERSON> Bravo </PERSON> issued a communique rejecting <PERSON> Fisher </PERSON>'s participation in the negotiations. The communique said such work was the proper task of each side's technical advisers
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880220-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-20-88 0249EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--France-Space     02-20 0163</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--France-Space,0169</SECOND>
<HEAD>Ariane Rocket To Put American, French Satellites Into Space</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PARIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A European Ariane rocket will launch an American and a <LOCATION> French </LOCATION> satellite into orbit next month from the program's <LOCATION> French </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Guiana </LOCATION> space center, the commercial arm of the <ORGANIZATION> European </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Space </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> announced The March 11 launch from the <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> base is to be Ariane's 21st and the first of eight planned for this year. It is to lift the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Spacenet </ORGANIZATION> 3-R satellite and the <ORGANIZATION> French </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Telecom </ORGANIZATION> 1C into orbit, <ORGANIZATION> Arianespace </ORGANIZATION> said in its announcement Friday. The 20th Ariane shot on Nov. 20 placed the West German satellite TV-SAT1 into orbit. The launch was flawless, but one of the satellite's solar panels failed to deploy and it has not been able to carry out its function of direct television broadcasts. The <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> space shuttle program was suspended after the January 1986 Challenger disaster, making the Ariane program the West's only regular vehicle for the lucrative satellite-launching market.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880220-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-20-88 0251EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Stroke-World     02-20 0508</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Stroke-World,0523</SECOND>
<HEAD>Siberia Is World's Stroke Capital</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DANIEL Q. HANEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Science Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SAN DIEGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Siberia </LOCATION> is the stroke capital of the world, and heavy drinking and cold weather could be partly to blame, researchers say. Soviet stroke data, gathered as part of a <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> program, were released for the first time Friday at a stroke conference sponsored by the American <ORGANIZATION> Heart </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>. `` We were surprised,'' said Dr. <PERSON> Kjell </PERSON> <PERSON> Asplund </PERSON>. `` We thought that <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> would be the higest.'' The study showed that <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Denmark </LOCATION> are the safest places to live, at least as far as stroke is concerned, although the stroke rate is low throughout most of <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, southern <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Asplund </PERSON>, a researcher at <ORGANIZATION> Umea </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Umea </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Sweden </LOCATION>, said the data suggest that strokes must have several causes. While racial differences may play a role, they do n't explain all of the variations in the risk of stroke around the world. The study found that in <LOCATION> Siberia </LOCATION>, the stroke rate was 119 for every 100,000 men and 107 for every 100,000 women. These figures were the highest in the world and significantly ahead of <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, the country with the second highest stroke rate. Strokes are also common in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, but data collected there were so sparse they were not included in the analysis. Strokes among men are least common in <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>, where they strike 21 in 100,000. In women they are least frequent in <LOCATION> Denmark </LOCATION>, where they occur in 8 in 100,000. Asked why strokes are so common in <LOCATION> Siberia </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Asplund </PERSON> said, `` At this point, we can only guess. We know that alcohol consumption is very high. High alcohol use among men is associated with a high risk for stroke. I also suspect that there are some climate factors involved.'' Although there are exceptions, such as <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>, he said it appears that strokes are more common in cold climates than in milder places. He noted that people are more likely to suffer strokes in northern <LOCATION> Sweden </LOCATION> than in southern <LOCATION> Sweden </LOCATION> and in <LOCATION> Scotland </LOCATION> than in <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>. Some experts suspect that Asians are more likely to suffer strokes, at least in part, because of racial differences. However, <PERSON> Asplund </PERSON> said that most people in <LOCATION> Siberia </LOCATION> moved there from <LOCATION> European </LOCATION> parts of the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. `` It's not only a racial thing,'' he said. `` It must have other determinants as well. The goal of this study is to find the determinants of the huge variations in stroke around the world.'' He said the researchers will be trying to learn why the stroke rate is falling rapidly in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, while it is stable or increasing in many other countries. The study found that in most places, strokes are more common in men than in women. The only exceptions to this were <LOCATION> Sweden </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>, where strokes are slightly more common among women. The 10-year project, called Monitoring of Trends and Determinants of Cardiovascular Disease, or MONICA, is being conducted in 26 countries and will conclude in 1994.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880220-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-20-88 0254EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Contras-Redeye     02-20 0183</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Contras-Redeye,0188</SECOND>
<HEAD>Contras Claim To Down Soviet-Made Helicopter With Redeye Missile</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SAN JOSE, Costa Rica (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Contra rebels claim they downed a Soviet-made Sandinista air force helicopter in eastern <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> with a U.S.-made Redeye missile this week. The rebels, in a statement released in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jose </LOCATION> Friday, said they used the heat-seeking anti-aircraft weapon last Sunday to shoot down the MI-17 helicopter in Chontales province. In the Nicaraguan capital of <LOCATION> Managua </LOCATION>, a <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> spokesman denied the rebel claim, saying mechanical failure caused the crash. The spokesman demanded anonymity. The <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> had reported on Monday that seven people were killed in the crash, which occurred near the village of <LOCATION> Santo </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Tomas </LOCATION>, about 120 miles east of <LOCATION> Managua </LOCATION>. The Contras claimed 15 people. Sandinista authorities said the helicopter was carrying new currency to the region to be exchanged for old bills. The Contra statement said the rebels recovered 10 million new cordobas in the crash. The Contras say they downed 26 helicopters with Redeye missiles last year. Foreign military observers put the number at a dozen. The Sandinistas admitted to six.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880220-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-20-88 0025EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-DrugReport     02-20 0258</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Drug Report,0265</SECOND>
<HEAD>Times: Drug Report Urges No Penalty for Mexico, Panama</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> should not be penalized by the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> despite their failure to take adequate steps to control drug trafficking, according to a draft <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> report. The <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION>, citing unidentified administration officials, reported Saturday that the report, prepared by the <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Narcotics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Matters </ORGANIZATION>, said `` other national interests'' warrant that the countries not be penalized. Under a 1986 law, the president certifies countries that are `` fully cooperating'' in cracking down on the drug trade. Those that do n't qualify lose military and economic aid, trade preferences, loans and other economic advantages. The report charged that <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> have n't made adequate progress in combating the drug trade but said they should be certified, the Times reported. <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s military leader, Gen. <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>, and some of his aides were indicted this month on drug and racketeering charges. `` It's ridiculous and stupid, absolutely ludicrous, and sends the wrong signals to both countries,'' Sen. <PERSON> Alfonse </PERSON> <PERSON> D'Amato </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-N.Y. </LOCATION>, said of the report's recommendation. Sen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Kerry </PERSON>, D-Mass., said, `` It is totally outrageous, particularly in the case of <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>. The report is provisional and subject to clearance by other governmental agencies and regional assistant secretaries of state. It would then be submitted to the secretary of state and the president, who is to announce his decision March 1. The report also recommended decertification of <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Paraguay </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Laos </LOCATION>. It said <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> Bahamas </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Bolivia </LOCATION> should be certified.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880220-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-20-88 0033EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-Brain-DeadBaby     02-20 0246</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Brain-Dead Baby,0253</SECOND>
<HEAD>Three Hospitals Reject Brain-Dead Baby's Liver</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOMA LINDA, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Three hospitals turned down the liver of a brain-dead baby whose body was being maintained on life-support systems to preserve his organs for transplant, officials said Friday. <PERSON> Baby </PERSON> <PERSON> John </PERSON>, who was born Tuesday with most of his brain missing, a condition known as anencephaly, was pronounced brain dead Thursday at <ORGANIZATION> Loma </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Linda </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>. No other cases in which anencephalics have been kept on life-support for organ transplant have been announced in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, although Dr. <PERSON> Leonard </PERSON> <PERSON> Bailey </PERSON>, chief of <PERSON> Loma </PERSON> <PERSON> Linda </PERSON>'s heart transplant program, last year suggested there have been such infants. Doctors plan to maintain the body on life support for up to seven days in hope of finding recipients for its organs, hospital spokeswoman <PERSON> Anita </PERSON> <PERSON> Rockwell </PERSON> said. One liver transplant candidate in <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION> was not an appropriate match and another in that city became infected, delaying any transplant, Ms. <PERSON> Rockwell </PERSON> said. A medical center in <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION> also was unable to accept the liver for another candidate because it had committed itself to do another transplant and could not perform two in one day, Ms. <PERSON> Rockwell </PERSON> said. <ORGANIZATION> UCLA </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> turned rejected the liver as not an ideal candidate for their recipient, Ms. <PERSON> Rockwell </PERSON> said. Anencephaly usually is fatal within days after birth. An anencephalic infant's organs can be transplanted only if organ damage is prevented by maintaining the infant on life-support from birth.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880220-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-20-88 0629EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Mexico-Debt     02-20 0459</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Mexico-Debt,0471</SECOND>
<HEAD>Mexico Asks U.S. for Favorable Treatment for Banks Involved In
Debt Swap</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By SALLY JACOBSEN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MEXICO CITY (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> has asked the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> to give favorable treatment to banks that take part in the government's new program to exchange part of its foreign debt for long-term bonds, the <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> said. Finance Secretary <PERSON> Gustavo </PERSON> <PERSON> Petricioli </PERSON> said in a statement that he discussed the plan with <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials during President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s recent meeting with President <PERSON> Miguel </PERSON> de la <LOCATION> Madrid </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Mazatlan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> `` The Mexican delegation,'' the statement said, `` emphasized that it is necessary that all parties involved continue working in the search for deeper and more permanent solutions to the problem of the foreign debt and financing.'' It said <LOCATION> Mexican </LOCATION> officials acknowledged the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> help to <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> in restructuring foreign debt and in fashioning <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>'s new debt exchange program. <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> has a foreign debt of $ 105 billion, the second highest in the developing world after <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION>. The new program involves exchanging some of the debt <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> owes foreign commercial bankers for new, 20-year bonds that will be issued by the government. <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> has set Feb. 26 as the date for an auction of the bonds. The bonds will be backed by $ 10 billion worth of special securities to be issued this year by the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government. <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> is expected to pay about $ 2 billion for the 20-year, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> zero-coupon bonds, which pay no interest but are issued at a sharp discount of their face value. The government statement said <PERSON> Petricioli </PERSON> asked <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials at the <LOCATION> Mazatlan </LOCATION> meeting `` that they give the most favorable treatment possible to the banks that decide to participate in this operation.'' Some <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> banks reportedly have expressed concern about taking part in the program because they are unhappy that <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> will continue obtaining loans at 100 percent of their value while paying back, through the bond program, its old loans at about half their value. They also are reportedly reluctant to accept losses of 50 percent or so on the loans entered into years ago, and worry about government regulations concerning accounting for the securities on their books. Most of <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>'s about 600 creditor banks have authorized the government to go ahead with the auction, which would apply to $ 51 billion of the foreign debt. Under the program, banks would exchange their old debt for the new bonds, letting <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> recover 52 cents or so for each dollar in the secondary market. That means that <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> could retire part of its debt for half its face value. By reducing its debt, the government will also pare the amount of interest it pays each year on the loans. <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> has annual interest charges of $ 8 billion to $ 9 billion.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880220-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-20-88 0105EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a PM-Names     02-20 0838</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0874</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in The News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>HOLLYWOOD, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Heavy-metal rock group <PERSON> Motley </PERSON> <PERSON> Crue </PERSON> warned fans not to imitate its show stunts after a 12-year-old boy set his blue jeans on fire while trying to copy the group's `` human torch'' video act. <PERSON> Bryan </PERSON> <PERSON> Tucker </PERSON>, who had burns over 10 percent of his body, was reported in good condition today at Memorial Hospital after he poured rubbing alcohol on his jeans and torched them. He put the flames out in a filled bathtub. `` Various of <PERSON> Motley </PERSON> <PERSON> Crue </PERSON>'s show stunts require special equipment, clothing and other materials ... and should not be attempted at home,'' said the statement released Thursday by management firm <ORGANIZATION> McGhee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Entertainment </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Bryan </PERSON>'s mother, <PERSON> Wendy </PERSON> <PERSON> Tucker </PERSON>, said he was in great pain but that <PERSON> Motley </PERSON> <PERSON> Crue </PERSON> was not to blame for her son's experiment at their home Wednesday. `` In my day, my mom would not let me watch <PERSON> Superman </PERSON>, because he jumped out of buildings,'' she said. `` It's just a different time.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>BERLIN (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actor <PERSON> Kirk </PERSON> <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON>, a veteran of more than 70 movies, was honored for his life's work at the <ORGANIZATION> Berlin </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Film </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Festival </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>'s second-largest annual movie event. The 71-year-old actor received the honorary Golden Camera award Thursday in an invitation-only ceremony attended by about 500 guests. `` This evening, I am really very happy,'' said <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON>, speaking in German. `` I have made three films in <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, and so have had the opportunity to learn a little German.'' <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON>' wife, <PERSON> Anne </PERSON>, also attended the ceremony. The Berlin Film Festival is <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>'s second-biggest annual movie event after the more prestigious festival in <LOCATION> Cannes </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>PENSACOLA, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Singer <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, rehearsing in secret for a new national tour, gave a sneak preview to 420 school children after viewing a rap video made in his honor by a third-grade class. In their video, the third-graders at the Hallmark School rapped that they and other Hallmark students `` do n't have much money _ if they could just see you, it would make their lives bright and sunny.'' The video was sent to <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> at the Civic Center last week. Teachers asked students to get permission slips signed by their parents for a trip to the Civic Center but the youngsters were n't told they were going to see <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> until just before boarding buses Thursday `` It was good,'' said a smiling <PERSON> Kevin </PERSON> <PERSON> Morris </PERSON>, 6, before bein spirited to the back of his bus by a woman who crisply said, `` We ca n't talk to anybody.'' <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> ended nearly two weeks of secretive rehearsals Friday in the <ORGANIZATION> Pensacola </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Civic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> for the tour scheduled to begin Tuesday in <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mo </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Film great <PERSON> Myrna </PERSON> <PERSON> Loy </PERSON> says she seldom gets the opportunity to see `` The Thin Man'' and her other classic movies because there are n't many theaters that show them. `` I'm glad to see people are making an effort'' to bring back old films, the 82-year-old Miss <PERSON> Loy </PERSON> said at a news conference Friday. `` I applaud this effort to restore them.'' Ms. <PERSON> Loy </PERSON> and other celebrities were on hand at an opening ceremony for <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Cineplex </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Odeon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Biograph </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cinema </ORGANIZATION>, formerly the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carnegie </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Cinema </LOCATION>. A letter from President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> wishing Ms. <PERSON> Loy </PERSON> `` warm wishes'' was read, and <PERSON> Ms. </PERSON> <PERSON> Loy </PERSON> and <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Rowley </PERSON>, who will program and operate the theater, cut a symbolic strip of celluloid before a crowd of more than 100 people.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>HONOLULU (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Selleck </PERSON> and two top executives from his `` Magnum P.I.'' television series are considering producing another series in <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION> that could make its debut this fall. <PERSON> Selleck </PERSON>, along with `` Magnum'' co-executive producer <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Floyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> and head writer <PERSON> Chris </PERSON> <PERSON> Abbott </PERSON> formed their own production company recently, and have been asked by <ORGANIZATION> Universal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Studios </ORGANIZATION> to think about producing a show here. Universal produces the 8-year-old `` Magnum P.I.'' series, which is wrapping up its final season. <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> said <PERSON> Selleck </PERSON>'s participation in the new series would be limited to off-camera work, but said `` Magnum'' co-star <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Hillerman </PERSON>, who plays stuffy major-domo <PERSON> Jonathan </PERSON> <PERSON> Higgins </PERSON>, might star in the new show. <PERSON> Hillerman </PERSON> said the series would not be a Higgins spinoff.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Dino </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Laurentiis </PERSON>, whose film company has been battered by a string of box-office flops, has stepped down as chairman and chief executive of <ORGANIZATION> De </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Laurentiis </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Entertainment </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Group </ORGANIZATION>. The 68-year-old <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Laurentiis </PERSON>, who was a successful filmmaker in his native <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>, also gave proxy to the company's board Friday to vote his stock. He owns 60 percent of the <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> company he founded in May 1986. For the nine months ended Nov. 30, the company posted losses of $ 36.2 million on revenues of $ 46 million. The most recent results included $ 27 million in writedowns on four films that flopped at the box office _ `` Near Dark,'' `` Weeds,'' `` Hiding Out'' and `` Date With an Angel'' _ and on a fifth, `` Total Recall,'' on which work was suspended. <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> Greenwald </PERSON>, the company's president, was elected to take <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Laurentiis </PERSON>' posts.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880220-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-20-88 0104EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-North-Moon     02-20 0259</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-North-Moon,250</SECOND>
<HEAD>Group Linked to Unification Church Lobbies for North Pardon</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A nationwide lobbying campaign seeking a pardon for Lt. Col. <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> <PERSON> North </PERSON> for his involvement in the Iran-Contra affair has been launched by a conservative group that is working with activists from the Rev. <PERSON> Sun </PERSON> <PERSON> Myung </PERSON> <PERSON> Moon </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> Unification </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> reported Saturday `` We think <PERSON> North </PERSON> is a hero and he ought to be treated as such,'' said <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Grant </PERSON>, chairman of the lobbying group <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Voice </ORGANIZATION> and president of the new <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Freedom </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coalition </ORGANIZATION>. The coalition has extensive links to <PERSON> Moon </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> Unification </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> movement, according to the newspaper. It said <PERSON> Bo </PERSON> <PERSON> Hi </PERSON> <PERSON> Pak </PERSON>, <PERSON> Moon </PERSON>'s top deputy and president of <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION>, which is owned by <PERSON> Moon </PERSON>, was instrumental in founding the group and <PERSON> Phillip </PERSON> <PERSON> Sanchez </PERSON>, one of <PERSON> Pak </PERSON>'s chief political aides and president of <ORGANIZATION> Causa </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> USA </ORGANIZATION>, is a member of the coalition's national policy board. <PERSON> Grant </PERSON> said <PERSON> Causa </PERSON> has given the coalition a network of activists throughout the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> _ most of whom are <ORGANIZATION> Unification </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> members _ to help build local support. However, the coalition's literature never mentions the <ORGANIZATION> Unification </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> and <PERSON> Pak </PERSON>'s name is not included on the group's five-member board of directors, the <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> said The coalition, chaired by former Reps. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Ichord </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Mo </LOCATION>., and <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON>, R-Calif., recently sent more than a million letters asking recipients to sign a `` Pardon Colonel North'' petition to President North is a target of the Iran-Contra investigation being conducted by independent counsel <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> <PERSON> Walsh </PERSON> but has not been indicted.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880220-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-20-88 0632EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-DemocratsDebate     02-20 0591</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Democrats Debate,580</SECOND>
<HEAD>Democratic Front-Runners Pushed By Rivals In Midwestern Test</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Political Rdp Bjt</HEAD>
<NOTE>With LaserPhotos</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By MIKE GLOVER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ST. PAUL, Minn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, trying to add some Midwestern momentum to his win in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION>, was pushed by Democratic presidential rivals to defend his economic policies and complained during a debate that `` my name was taken in vain.'' Missouri Rep. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON>, another <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> front-runner, also found himself in the cross fire Friday during the latest debate of Democratic presidential candidates, as <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> asked if the <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION> congressman was `` proud of your vote for the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> tax cut in 1981.'' <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> and <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, the governor of <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION>, were the biggest targets in a debate that was freewheeling but less fiesty than a jangling exchange among the candidates in <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> the day before. The St. <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> debate came as the focus of the presidential campaign shifted briefly away from the Super Tuesday battlefield mainly in the South and returned to the <LOCATION> Midwest </LOCATION>, where <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION> hold contests on Tuesday. Though the delegates at stake from those two contests pale next to those to be allocated in the South, the closely bunched candidates are looking for a Midwestern edge to propel them toward the March 8 Super Tuesday primaries and caucuses. In the latest debates, the candidates tried to block <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> and <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> from gaining more momentum. <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> was hit on trade and taxes, while <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> was forced to defend his budget plans. <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> defended his overall tax voting record, saying most of the tax cut derided by <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> `` went to ordinary people.'' `` That was the trigger of this whole deficit crisis,'' <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> countered. And <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> agreed: `` It was n't just a bad vote as a matter of tax policy, it was the worst trade bill ever passed.'' The <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION> debate drew five of the six Democratic contenders. <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> Sen. <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> was absent. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> fired one of the most direct shots of the debate at <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON>'s trade policies, warning that `` we've got to do more than wave a fist at our foreign competitors.'' But <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> queried: `` Why is everyone defending unfair trade practices?'' After the candidates' exchange was interrupted by a moderator, <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> predicted `` we'll never finish on trade.'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> complained that `` my name was taken in vain'' by <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Hart </PERSON>, who demanded to know why <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> had not followed his example and released a budget proposal. `` The reason my colleagues have not put out budgets is because they do n't want to tell the <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> people the facts,'' <PERSON> Hart </PERSON> said. `` I'm the only person on this platform who has balanced a budget,'' retorted <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>. Turning to Sen. <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Simon </PERSON>, <PERSON> Hart </PERSON> asked, `` Why do n't you put your budget out, <PERSON> Paul </PERSON>?'' When a moderator interrupted the exchange with a joke about `` exchange your budgets tomorrow,'' <PERSON> Hart </PERSON> complained: `` I thought that's what we were here to debate.'' The candidates paid homage to former Vice President <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Mondale </PERSON>, one of the ceremonial sponsors of the debate, with <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> saying that <PERSON> Mondale </PERSON>'s call for a tax hike during his failed 1984 Democratic presidential bid was `` to his everlasting credit.'' <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> noted that this campaign is the first in 20 years that Minnesotans do n't have a favorite son candidate to vote for. `` Do n't despair, let me be your favorite son,'' <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> said. `` I want to be your other favorite son'' interjected <PERSON> Simon </PERSON>. Friday's debate was sponsored by a series of groups, including the <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Paul </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pioneer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dispatch </ORGANIZATION> and radio and television station <ORGANIZATION> WCCO </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Minneapolis </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880220-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-20-88 0332EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BombExpert     02-20 0427</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bomb Expert,0440</SECOND>
<HEAD>French Bomb Expert Wraps Up 43-year Career With One Last Blast</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CAEN, France (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Marcel </PERSON> <PERSON> Piattier </PERSON> cleared <LOCATION> Omaha </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION> of German mines the day after the Allies stormed it on D-Day, and went on to make a career out of defusing or detonating unexploded World War II bombs. On Friday, The 66-year-old <PERSON> Piattier </PERSON> retired with a bang, safely exploding a 300-pound English bomb found in January in this town 150 miles north of <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION>. The live bomb could n't be moved and was detonated near the center of town, causing no damage. In his last year as head of the regional bomb and mine clearing service, the man considered the dean of the 25 civil defense explosive experts in <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> was kept busy. `` In the second half of 1987, we received 560 calls to neutralize bombs found by individuals,'' <PERSON> Piattier </PERSON> said. He says his work in his later years was safer than it used to be. `` In 1945, we probed mine fields with bayonettes,'' he recalled. `` In two years, 27 French mine clearers died, and that's not counting the German prisoners of war we used.'' To determine if the bomb detonated Friday was still live, <PERSON> Piattier </PERSON> used sophisticated X-ray equipment, similar to that used at nuclear power plants, to see inside to the strike-pin. <LOCATION> Normandy </LOCATION> was the scene of the Allied invasion in 1944 and saw intense fighting that left behind thousands of bombs and mines that often turn up unexpectedly. In the past year, bombs have been found by workers digging the English Channel tunnel and near a hospital in <LOCATION> Caen </LOCATION>. The most dangerous explosives still scattered throughout the verdant countryside are small anti-personnel bombs dropped in bunches from German planes. `` A woman had her leg torn away in June and a child died in September from these bombs,'' said <PERSON> Piattier </PERSON>, who added that he has found `` several thousand'' bombs and mines in four decades of work. <PERSON> Piattier </PERSON>'s first task was clearing the German mines from <LOCATION> Omaha </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION> the day after <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> forces landed on June 6, 1944. `` I was the first French soldier on the beach and even before the second soldier arrived I had found hundreds and hundreds of mines,'' he said. <PERSON> Piattier </PERSON> was lucky to reach retirement. In the past two years, six of his colleagues have died in the line of duty, he said. `` My wife is happy. She thinks I'll be safe now at home, but I'm not so sure,'' he said `` I'd like to stay in contact with the service and help out when I can.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880220-0025 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-20-88 0635EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Theater-Carrie     02-20 0417</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Theater-Carrie,0430</SECOND>
<HEAD>Broadway-Bound Musical Gets Wan Reviews</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
