<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880605-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-05-88 2331EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-NorthernIreland     06-05 0247</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Northern Ireland,0257</SECOND>
<HEAD>Sentence Review for Convicted Terrorists</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BELFAST, Northern Ireland (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The British government will review the life sentences of dozens of convicted terrorist prisoners in this <LOCATION> British </LOCATION> province, officials said Sunday. The <ORGANIZATION> Life </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sentence </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Review </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> will review the records of the Special Category inmates over the next six months and report back to <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION> Secretary <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> King </PERSON>, his office reported. No reason was given for the review, but it appeared aimed at reducing tensions. The Special Category laws for suspected terrorists in <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION>'s sectarian warfare were introduced in 1972 after inmates staged a hunger strike at <LOCATION> Belfast </LOCATION>'s Maze Prison, demanding to be treated as political prisoners. Their special privileges include political status and allow them to avoid prison work, wear their own clothes, have extra visits and food parcels and to live in isolated groups. In 1976, the Special Category status was ended for crimes committed after that date and in 1980 no more prisoners were admitted to the category. There are now 90 Special Category prisoners compared with 1,500 in 1975. There are 31 members of the outlawed <ORGANIZATION> Irish </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>, 27 of the mainly <ORGANIZATION> Protestant </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ulster </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> and 32 from the outlawed <ORGANIZATION> Ulster </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Volunteer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION>. All but five are serving life sentences or are detained on orders of the secretary of state. The predminantly <ORGANIZATION> Roman </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> IRA </ORGANIZATION> is fighting to unite Protestant-dominated <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION> and unite the province with the <LOCATION> Irish </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Republic </LOCATION>, which is overwhelmingly <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880605-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-05-88 2340EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-AlligatorAttack 3rdLd-Writethru a0836 06-05 0755</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Alligator Attack, 3rd Ld - Writethru, a0836,0774</SECOND>
<HEAD>10-Foot Gator Shot After Killing Little Girl
^Eds: Subs 4th graf ``Since 1948'' to add that number refers to
Florida only.</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhotos FTM1, FTM2</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MICHAEL WARREN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ENGLEWOOD, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A 10 -LCB- - foot alligator lunged from a residential lake, seized a 4-year-old girl who was wading with her brother and a friend and dragged her to her death Game officers spotted the alligator on the bank of Hidden Lake around midnight carrying the limp body of <PERSON> Erin </PERSON> <PERSON> Glover </PERSON> in its jaws. The reptile was immediately shot to death with a .357 - caliber Magnum pistol, said <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> Condit </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION> disaster services The girl's body was recovered, he said. Since 1948, there have been 95 unprovoked alligator attacks in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>, with five previous deaths, said game commission Lt. <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Farrior </PERSON>. `` An autopsy of the alligator was performed on the scene and determined it to be the -LRB- alligator that killed her -RRB-,'' <LOCATION> Charlotte </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> dispatcher <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Kefer </PERSON> said Sunday. He did not know what aspect of the autopsy identified the reptile as the killer. <PERSON> Erin </PERSON> was walking along the lake's south shore with her brother <PERSON> Justin </PERSON>, 8, their dog, and neighbor <PERSON> Jason </PERSON> <PERSON> Kershanick </PERSON>, 9, at 6:30 p.m. Saturday when the gator bolted from the water and snapped up the girl in its teeth. <PERSON> Jason </PERSON> said Sunday that the children were walking in ankle-deep water. `` The little girl was throwing rocks and kicking the water. While she was kicking, she must have kicked the alligator. Right when she stopped kicking, the alligator jumped up out of the water and started biting her two times in the stomach,'' <PERSON> Jason </PERSON> said. `` Then he dropped her and she crawled away, and then he got out of the water more and grabbed her from the back and went in the water.'' `` After it happened, then we ran,'' he added. `` It was pretty quick. It seemed like a nightmare, a dream. But then the way she screamed, when I saw the blood after he went in, then I realized it was real.'' Alligators tend to pull their prey underwater, drowning them and stashing the body for later feeding. <PERSON> Wayne </PERSON> <PERSON> Kershanick </PERSON> went to the lake with a pistol after his son alerted him. `` I saw it taking her off to the other side'' of the lake, <PERSON> Kershanik </PERSON> said. `` I tried to track it through the weeds, but by the time I got there he went under with her, and that was the last I seen of him.'' Neighbor <PERSON> Nolan </PERSON> <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> said he had heard <PERSON> Erin </PERSON>'s mother screaming and took a rifle to the lake. He said he saw a large alligator surface with a light-colored object in its mouth. `` It was within rifle range but I was afraid to shoot because of the object,'' <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> said. The gator was spotted after five divers had searched the lake and weeds surrounded by the Gardens of Gulf Cove development while six <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> Game and <ORGANIZATION> Fresh </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Water </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fish </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> officers and several deputies and emergency workers walked the land. The area is about 25 miles south of <LOCATION> Sarasota </LOCATION> on <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>'s west coast. `` It was a shock. It will be a while getting over it,'' <PERSON> Erin </PERSON>'s stepfather, <PERSON> Ty </PERSON> <PERSON> Bowns </PERSON>, said outside the family's house `` All the kids around here played around all these lakes. I do n't think anybody took the alligators all that seriously. <PERSON> Justin </PERSON> was staying with neighbors after the incident. <PERSON> Kershanick </PERSON>'s wife, <LOCATION> Charlotte </LOCATION>, said nothing had been done about past alligator complaints. `` A lot of them are aggravated because they've complained about the alligators being here, but nobody does anything,'' she said. `` They ought to have the ponds fenced in.'' Alligators once were vigorously hunted and their population dwindled in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>. They were made a protected species in the mid-1960s. But in the past few years, it has become clear that the species is in no danger of extinction, said <PERSON> Farrior </PERSON>. State wildlife experts estimate there are 1 million alligators on 6.7 million acres of land. On Sept. 1, for the first time since 1962, the state will hold a one-month gator hunt in which no more than 3,000 are to be taken. `` They occupy pretty much any body of water that would look like an alligator lives there, and lots that do n't,'' <PERSON> Farrior </PERSON> said. Last year, 3,853 gators were killed because they were declared a nuisance, threatening children and livestock. The attack on <PERSON> Erin </PERSON> was the third gator attack on the Gulf Coast in the past six months. Both previous victims survived the attacks.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880605-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-05-88 2353EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Mine-Survival     06-05 0781</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Mine-Survival,0819</SECOND>
<HEAD>Sixty-Five Hours Underground _ A Reconstruction</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</NOTE>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 For 65 hours, six men were trapped deep underground after a mine explosion in central <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>. Here, based on interviews with the survivors, mine officials, rescue workers and <LOCATION> German </LOCATION> news reports, is the story of their harrowing ordeal.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>By GEORGE BOEHMER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>and KEVIN COSTELLOE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writers</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BORKEN, West Germany (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Huddled in the depths of a coal mine, six trapped miners take turns banging hammers together to signal rescuers. Their colleagues keep as still as possible to save precious air. `` Lie down, move as little as you can, drink the water in sips and breath as regularly as possible,'' veteran miner <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Gepperth </PERSON> barks to his five-man crew. Toward the end of their 65-hour ordeal, their oxygen almost gone, the men hear a rescue worker screaming into his walkie-talkie: `` I see a light! I see two lights, I see three lights! I see people alive!'' The drama begins at 12:30 p.m. Wednesday, when a gas explosion traps 57 men in the mine in this town 70 miles northeast of <LOCATION> Frankfurt </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Gepperth </PERSON> and his five-man crew race toward the exit of the 500-foot-deep shaft. `` Maybe the blasting material storeroom blew up,'' the strapping, 36-year-old <PERSON> Gepperth </PERSON> says to himself. Out of the darkness, illuminated by the lights on the miners' helmets, appears the figure of a colleague staggering toward them <PERSON> Gepperth </PERSON> instantly recognizes the symptoms of the miners' dreaded foe _ carbon monoxide. He yells, `` Turn back, turn back!'' <PERSON> Gepperth </PERSON> and his crew head in the other direction. Other men nearby race toward the exit, into certain death from mounting levels of carbon monoxide that filled the tunnels. <PERSON> Gepperth </PERSON>'s crew, wearing emergency masks containing about 45 minutes' worth of oxygen, rush to a point more than a mile from the blast site in the underground labyrinth of tunnels. Guided by the flames of cigarette lighters, they search for a space free of the deadly gas. Finally, the group finds air _ and a chance for survival. `` Be quiet, so you use up less oxygen,'' Gepperth orders. Huddled in the dark are: _ <ORGANIZATION> Egon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dehn </ORGANIZATION>, a bearded, 36-year-old father of two _ <PERSON> Helmut </PERSON> <PERSON> Gesner </PERSON>, 27, engaged to be married in August _ <PERSON> Heinz </PERSON> <PERSON> Roese </PERSON>, 33, married two years and the father of one _ <PERSON> Wilfried </PERSON> <PERSON> Doench </PERSON>, at 21 the youngest of the group Just four weeks earlier he'd walked away unharmed from a car wreck. _ <PERSON> Ahmet </PERSON> <PERSON> Batkan </PERSON>, 33 The Turkish immigrant has two children and his wife is expecting a third. The sixth man is <PERSON> Gepperth </PERSON>, who is married. He often sports a diamond earring in his left ear. The men start shouting frantically into their walkie-talkies: `` One north 4-5, one north 4-5 six people.'' They hope to give rescue workers their precise location. Radio contact is made. But a radio operator orders the men to stop sending distress calls so he can try to reach other possible survivors. They try using the walkie-talkies again later but ca n't make contact The miners sit in the dark _ having turned off their miners' lamps to save batteries _ with their only nourishment a sandwich and mineral water Taking turns, they pound two hammers together in rhythmic blows to try to catch rescuers' attention. The banging goes on for nearly 65 hours. <PERSON> Gepperth </PERSON> tells his men to remember the `` Miracle of Lengede'' _ in which 11 miners were pulled to the surface two weeks after water flooded an iron mine in <LOCATION> Lower </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Saxony </LOCATION> in 1963. Some of the men start to make last wills and testaments, but <PERSON> Gepperth </PERSON> gruffly tells them `` You do n't have to do that.'' <PERSON> Gepperth </PERSON> senses that the deadly carbon monoxide levels are advancing toward them, and the group retreats into the furthest recesses of the mine. Finally, their backs are against the wall. They can go no further and must stay in a prison-like space 6 -LCB- feet high and 8 feet wide. After waiting in vain Thursday, the men hear drilling on Friday. But it stops at mid-afternoon. <PERSON> Gesner </PERSON> says to himself: `` Have they forgotten us or something? Maybe they figure it's not worth it.'' He starts imagining he sees lights coming toward him, but there's no one there. They keep tapping, louder and louder. On Friday night, rescuers above think they've heard something. Hours pass. Then one of the trapped men screams: `` They've drilled a hole! At 4:21 a.m. Saturday, the rescue worker calls that he's found the men. A little more than an hour after they're discovered, the men are hoisted to the surface. After all 57 miners had been given up for dead, the `` Miracle of Borken'' had occurred.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880605-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-05-88 2355EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-EconomicSummit     06-05 0794</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Economic Summit,0817</SECOND>
<HEAD>Toronto Summit May Be More Informal, Focused On Narrow Issues</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By JEFF BRADLEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>TORONTO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s final meeting with major <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> trading partners, coming just two weeks after the <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> summit, will focus on both macro and micro, from averting another stock market crash to debating whether longer shopping hours might ignite more economic growth in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> will meet with leaders of six other major industrial democracies _ <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> _ plus the <ORGANIZATION> European </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Community </ORGANIZATION> in the downtown convention center of <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>'s biggest city, June 19-21. The economic summit will give <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> an opportunity to brief his partners on his May 29-June 2 talks with Soviet leader <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>. However, two of the participants, <LOCATION> British </LOCATION> Prime Minister <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> and Japanese Prime Minister <PERSON> Noburu </PERSON> <PERSON> Takeshita </PERSON> got an early report from the president during his <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> stop last week. <LOCATION> Toronto </LOCATION>, hoping that a favorable impression will bolster its bid to host the 1996 Olympic Games, is busy sprucing up for an expected invasion of 1,400 summit delegates and 5,000 news media representatives. The city has a graffiti squad scrubbing everything clean. A giant parking lot is being converted into `` Summit Square'' where reporters will be offered free food and drink around the clock. To guard against terrorist attacks, 3,000 police officers will be deployed around the city and sharpshooters will be stationed on rooftops along motorcade routes to prevent anyone from getting within a bomb's throw of visiting foreign leaders. The security operation will cost an estimated $ 6 million, the equivalent of $ 4.8 million in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. `` We are taking the precautions because of the history -LRB- of terrorist attacks -RRB- at previous summit conferences,'' said police Supt. <PERSON> Bernard </PERSON> <PERSON> Nadeau </PERSON>. Rockets were fired in downtown <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION> at the 1986 economic summit and bombs were thrown at embassies in <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION> during last year's <LOCATION> Venice </LOCATION> summit. Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON>, in office since 1979, will be dean of the summiteers. This will be <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s eighth such summit. Newcomers at the <LOCATION> Toronto </LOCATION> summit will be <PERSON> Takeshita </PERSON> and <LOCATION> Italian </LOCATION> Prime Minister <PERSON> Ciriaco </PERSON> <PERSON> De </PERSON> <PERSON> Mita </PERSON>. Also attending will be West German Chancellor <PERSON> Helmut </PERSON> <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON> and French President <PERSON> Francois </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitterrand </PERSON>, who will bring his new premier, <PERSON> Michel </PERSON> <PERSON> Rocard </PERSON>. Host Prime Minister <PERSON> Brian </PERSON> <PERSON> Mulroney </PERSON> wants the 14th economic summit _ the annual parleys began in 1975 at <LOCATION> Rambouillet </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> _ to be less formal and more productive than its predecessors. <PERSON> Mulroney </PERSON> has ruled out the usual opening day festivities in favor of getting right down to business. He plans to start with an afternoon working session on economic issues, followed by a working dinner on political matters. At the dinner, `` clearly the the overarching theme will be East-West relations,'' says <PERSON> Mulroney </PERSON>. The second summit day will see an innovation _ a 90-minute meeting without aides at which the leaders will toss around ideas about prospects for the next decade. They are to discuss economics on the final day before closing with a news conference. `` It's essential that this summit concentrate rather heavily on economic issues,'' said <PERSON> Sylvia </PERSON> <PERSON> Ostry </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>'s multilateral trade ambassador. `` The summit is the terminal day of what is almost a continuing process of international economic cooperation.'' Ms. <PERSON> Ostry </PERSON> said the two major summit issues will be: _ How to manage the transition from huge trade deficits and surpluses to balanced global trade _ How to prevent a repetition of the Oct. 19 stock market crash The crash did not result in a recession, as some experts had predicted, but continued growth has raised fears of a new inflationary spiral. To avert that danger, the <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Canada </ORGANIZATION> this week pushed interest rates to a two-year high, with prime rates rising to 10.75 percent. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Treasury Secretary <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> is urging the seven summit nations to adopt an index of 35 to 40 key commodities, including gold, to help track inflation. <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> proposed last month that they also closely monitor growth rates and trade balances to better coordinate their economies, in addition to watching exchange and interest rates and fiscal policies. <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> are expected to press the 12-nation <ORGANIZATION> European </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Community </ORGANIZATION> and <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> for progress in the farm subsidy war that is crippling treasuries, driving down prices and restricting markets. Summit leaders also are expected to consider options for solving the Third World debt problem, in which 121 developing countries owe a total of $ 1.25 trillion. Commercial banks want governments to increase contributions to the <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Monetary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fund </ORGANIZATION>. With monetary policies already being closely monitored, Canadian officials said the summit emphasis may focus on `` micro-economic'' policies such as taxation, deregulation, land use restrictions in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> or extension of West German shopping hours to boost imports.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880605-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-05-88 2355EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-FantasyHotel     06-05 0539</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Fantasy Hotel,0556</SECOND>
<HEAD>Hotel Chain Tries To Satisfy Guests' Fantasies</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto MP3</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TOM KRATTENMAKER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BURNSVILLE, Minn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The bedposts are artificial trees, and the suite's private whirlpool is nestled in a crop of synthetic rocks complete with a mini-waterfall. The walls are a deep-green painted forest. Welcome to the treehouse suite, part of the new fantasy wing of the <LOCATION> Burnsville </LOCATION> Royale Hotel. For $ 165 to $ 195 a night, guests also can retire to an igloo, a whaling ship, a sheik's tent, a <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> beach, a 1973 Olds or any of a number of settings at this latest addition to <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> Dehring </PERSON>'s growing chain of fantasy hotels `` We're really just another hotel company that has a part of its business that's a little unusual,'' said <PERSON> Dehring </PERSON>, 43, of <LOCATION> Minnetonka </LOCATION>, owner of the refurbished <LOCATION> Burnsville </LOCATION> motel and similar outposts in the <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION> towns of <LOCATION> Antigo </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Dodgeville </LOCATION>, and <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bend </LOCATION>. Before the fantasy wing opened here in May, the hotel had the usual trappings for travelers: convention and meeting rooms, a restaurant, swimming pool and 88 standard rooms for $ 42 to $ 50 per-night. `` In addition, we have this one wing that looks like any other hotel wing _ until you open the -LRB- room -RRB- door,'' <PERSON> Dehring </PERSON> said. In the Moby <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> suite, guests are confronted with the wide-open mouth of a whale. The whirlpool _ mandatory fare in the 12 fantasy suites _ is inside the behemoth, ribs showing through a ceiling of whale stomach. Then there's the car suite. `` Bring back the memories,'' bids the promotion on the hotel fare sheet. `` The stars, the moon and young loves' first kiss in the backseat.'' The beach room, bedless, offers sleep on a beige carpet randomly padded to give the impression of sand. `` Pharoah's Tomb'' puts you inside a pyramid with sand - and cement-sprayed walls cracked to lend a more realistic look and feel `` It's a very definite, authentic feeling. Whatever authentic is. I have n't been there either,'' <PERSON> Dehring </PERSON> said. The story of <ORGANIZATION> Royale </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospitality </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Group </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, the Bloomington-based parent company of <PERSON> Dehring </PERSON>'s four hotels, began at the Don Q. Inn in <LOCATION> Dodgeville </LOCATION>. The Don Q. offers such oddities as a 120-year-old barn for a restaurant and a steeple converted into a suite. <PERSON> Dehring </PERSON> bought it in 1979 and quickly learned that something out of the ordinary is something in demand. `` We've kind of been expounding on it ever since,'' said <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Isabella </PERSON>, hotel group president. The two are full of ideas for more elaborate _ maybe impossible _ suites. They picture guests sleeping on a 27-foot boat floating in real water, `` God and code willing,'' <PERSON> Dehring </PERSON> says. Another idea is a hot-air balloon. Such a suite probably would have to be a three-story affair, they said. Expansion of the chain is more than a brainstorm. Contracts have been signed for the purchase of new properties in <LOCATION> Muscatine </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>, and <PERSON> Greenwood </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Ind </LOCATION>. With the <LOCATION> Burnsville </LOCATION> specialty rooms already booked for the summer, <PERSON> Dehring </PERSON> and <PERSON> Isabella </PERSON> think it will pay to build more of the unexpected at their fifth and sixth hotels. They'll entertain all ideas. In fact, they give guests `` suite suggestion'' cards that solicit names and concepts for future rooms and promise a free night for winners.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880605-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-05-88 2355EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Obit-Gildea     06-05 0137</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Obit-Gildea,120</SECOND>
<HEAD>Former Pennsylvania Congressman Dead At 97</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ARLINGTON, Va. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gildea </PERSON>, a Democrat who represented <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> in the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> from 1935 to 1939, died Sunday of cardiac arrest at age 97. <PERSON> Gildea </PERSON>, who died at the Manor Care nursing home in <LOCATION> Arlington </LOCATION>, was a native of Coaldale, <LOCATION> Pa </LOCATION>. He made his home in <LOCATION> Bethesda </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Md. </LOCATION>, before entering <ORGANIZATION> Manor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Care </ORGANIZATION> four years ago. He was elected to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> in 1934 and re-elected two years later. He was defeated by a <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> opponent in 1938, and also was defeated in <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> races in 1940 and 1950. <PERSON> Gildea </PERSON> had become a printing apprentice in 1905 and a newspaper publisher in 1910. He founded the <ORGANIZATION> Coaldale </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Observer </ORGANIZATION>, a weekly newspaper, and the <ORGANIZATION> Schuylkill </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Legal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Record </ORGANIZATION>, a law publication. Survivors include his wife, <PERSON> Genevieve </PERSON>, of <LOCATION> Bethesda </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880605-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-05-88 2357EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-RadarBalloon Bjt   06-05 0692</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Radar Balloon, Bjt,0711</SECOND>
<HEAD>Balloon Ready to Eye Drug Smugglers</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto PN2</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ARTHUR H. ROTSTEIN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SIERRA VISTA, Ariz. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A huge blimp-like balloon floating serenely in the southern <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION> sky is a new weapon in a widening war, a radar-packed eye-in-the-sky searching for airborne drug smugglers. When it becomes fully operational this month, the nearly $ 18 million balloon will scan the sky to the south, tracking low-flying planes that try to evade regular radar, and helping <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Customs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> aircraft chase smugglers within 80,000 square miles. The helium-filled, white balloon already has tracked planes twice, leading to arrests and seizure of drugs, said <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Wiley </PERSON>, senior engineer and site manager for the contractor, <ORGANIZATION> Westinghouse </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Electronic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Systems </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co </ORGANIZATION>. It is the first of at least five balloons Customs officials hope to position along the <LOCATION> Southwest </LOCATION> border to plug gaps in ground-based radar surveillance that have allowed smugglers to enter the country with impunity via <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>. Some residents near the giant balloon's mooring on the southern edge of the <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Huachuca </LOCATION> military reservation say they're worried that it poses a danger to them. `` I'm sure the government's going to leave it there until it has an accident, and then things will change. And it ultimately will have an accident,'' said <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> Woodward </PERSON>, whose home is within the radius of the balloon's 10,000-foot-long tether. Within the balloon's range are 1,000 homes, five churches and <ORGANIZATION> Huachuca </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mountain </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Elementary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION>, where <PERSON> Carol </PERSON> <PERSON> Southland </PERSON>, a second-grade teacher, is among those who appreciate its deterrent role in the war on drugs. `` I just do n't think the risk is there,'' she said. `` I do n't think the balloon's gon na run away through the neighborhood and carry off the children. Army and Customs officials say the site was the best available and fears of an accident are unfounded. The balloon has a rapid deflation device to allow operators to lower it quickly while controlling where it lands if it were to break from its tether. Sabotage would be the most likely cause of a breakaway from the mooring, but it would be a difficult target for anything but a rocket, <PERSON> Wiley </PERSON> said. Because of the helium's low pressure, `` you could put probably a dozen -LRB- bullet -RRB- holes in this Aerostat out here and it would probably take us days to even find out we had a leak,'' he said. The balloon goes by various names: Aerostat -LRB- for air stationary -RRB- Borne Radar Surveillance System; SOWRBALL -LRB- Southwest Radar Balloon -RRB-; `` Fat <PERSON> Albert </PERSON>,'' and even `` <PERSON> Little </PERSON> <PERSON> Shamu </PERSON>,'' after the whale of Sea World fame. At 245 feet long and 72 feet in diameter, it dwarfs a <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> 747. It weighs 12,750 pounds, including the 3,500-pound down-looking radar payload strapped to its underbelly. But its eight-layered skin is puff-pastry thin _ at 12 mils, or 12-thousandths of an inch, it's about twice the thickness of the tape in an audio cassette. That high-technology skin has high-intensity strength: about 275 pounds per linear inch, <PERSON> Wiley </PERSON> said. The Aerostat is anchored at a maximum height of 10,000 feet by another high-tech wonder: a tether less than an inch in diameter and made of <LOCATION> Kevlar </LOCATION>, a lightweight material used in bulletproof vests. The tether weighs 4,250 pounds but can handle tension of more than 75,000 pounds. Inside the Kevlar are three wires providing power for the radar package and other computerized controls, all run by ground-station crew in an around-the-clock command center. `` What we have here is the latest technology in aerostats,'' <PERSON> Wiley </PERSON> said. Comparing it with another Customs surveillance balloon flying in the <LOCATION> Bahamas </LOCATION> or with two <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> radar devices in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> is `` like comparing an F-16 fighter to a P-51 World War II fighter,'' he said. Its radar range is estimated at 160 miles, which means it can provide detection over 80,000 square miles. That's enough to pinpoint planes within range of <PERSON> Hermosillo </PERSON>, the <LOCATION> Sonora </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, state capital, or twice the distance from here to <LOCATION> Tucson </LOCATION>. The balloon is intended to operate except in snow or icy conditions, thunderstorms or heavy winds, conditions likely to keep smugglers grounded. `` These cats are n't gon na be flying through those thunderstorms either,'' <PERSON> Wiley </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880605-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-05-88 2358EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Nicaragua-Peace     06-05 0653</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nicaragua-Peace,0675</SECOND>
<HEAD>Contras, Sandinistas Closer Than Ever To Agreement</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</NOTE>
<HEAD>AP News Analysis</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ELOY O. AGUILAR</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MANAGUA, Nicaragua (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Sandinista government and U.S.-backed rebels are closer than ever to ending their 6 -LCB- - year war, but the last few steps to halt the fighting will be the most difficult The final measures are particularly crucial for the rebels, known as Contras, who may negotiate themselves out of existence in peace talks scheduled to resume Tuesday. The rebels do not have the political structure to survive as a separate organization on the Nicaraguan political scene. Their role likely will be taken over by the political parties already established in the country. Despite their rhetoric and posturing, the Contras and the government have been getting closer to a permanent agreement and have set a temporary truce that no one wants to break. The two sides signed a preliminary agreement on March 23 in <LOCATION> Sapoa </LOCATION>, a small village on the Costa Rican border. A 60-day cease-fire, which expired last Tuesday, has been extended until the two sides renew their discussions in <LOCATION> Managua </LOCATION>, the Nicaraguan capital. During the last negotiating session, the government agreed to discuss some political reforms the Contra leadership considers essential. These include calls for political pluralism, equality before the law, the right to strike and a pluralistic electoral system. The reforms deal with definitions of `` democratization'' _ concepts that first led to the war, which has killed more than 26,000 people and ruined the country's economy. The Contra leadership feels the Sandinista regime is undemocratic, repressive and based on Marxism-Leninism. `` When it comes to definition of freedom of the press, civil rights, human rights, democracy, we are using the same words with different meanings. We are talking about two interpretations of reality based on different ideologies,'' said <PERSON> Virgilio </PERSON> <PERSON> Godoy </PERSON>, leader of the opposition <ORGANIZATION> Independent </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>. `` I am reasonably optimistic there will be an agreement,'' he said. `` It is not a question here of defeating the government at the negotiating table, but of finding a way to live together.'' <PERSON> Luis </PERSON> <PERSON> Rivas </PERSON> <PERSON> Leiva </PERSON>, a Contra adviser, said, `` The government must learn to live with what they term petite bourgeoisie. We can live with some of their leaders.'' <PERSON> Bayardo </PERSON> <PERSON> Arce </PERSON>, deputy coordinator of the political commission of the ruling <ORGANIZATION> Sandinista </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION>, said, `` There are some in the opposition who have realized that there is political room for them here.'' <PERSON> Arce </PERSON> rejected charges that the government is trying to impose a communist state. `` We came to power talking about building socialism in <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>,'' he said. `` But as we developed our struggle, we understood the national realities and we opted for a system of mixed economy with private and government property.'' <PERSON> Eric </PERSON> <PERSON> Ramirez </PERSON>, president of the opposition <ORGANIZATION> Social </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, called the <ORGANIZATION> Sandinistas </ORGANIZATION> `` pragmatic and opportunistic'' but said there was little chance of a definite agreement on democratic reforms. `` Democratization is utopian in a country like ours where there has been no democracy for more than 60 years,'' he said. `` What we need is a continued process of democratic practices to test the political will of the government.'' `` If we do not agree on this,'' he said, `` the government will act unilaterally enacting electoral laws, and other changes that will make it look good abroad, while still talking to a divided opposition.'' The Sandinista government already has announced plans for municipal elections before the 1990 presidential elections. Opposition party leaders believe the Contras, as an organization, served a purpose in forcing the government to the negotiating table, but are at their weakest while negotiating an end to the war. <PERSON> Ramirez </PERSON> said they will have to return and rejoin one of <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>'s 14 political parties or form another party, `` which is the last thing <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> needs,'' <PERSON> Ramirez </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Eloy </PERSON> <PERSON> O. </PERSON> <PERSON> Aguilar </PERSON> is The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>' bureau chief for <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880605-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-05-88 0009EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-BRF--MysteryCircles     06-05 0181</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Mystery Circles,0185</SECOND>
<HEAD>Scientist Says Crop Circles Caused By Whirlwinds, Not Flying
Saucers</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Mysterious circles of flattened crops in the British countryside over the centuries have been caused by stationary whirlwinds and not ghosts or UFOs, a scientist said Saturday. About 50 of the circles, with diameters of 10 to 100 feet, show up every summer usually in fields of long grass, barley, oats or wheat near hills, said tornado expert <PERSON> Terence </PERSON> <PERSON> Meaden </PERSON>. Speaking at a conference in <LOCATION> Oxford </LOCATION>, he dismissed speculation the circles were caused by flying saucers, helicopters flying upside down, supernatural beings or even herds of rotating hedgehogs, a small porcupine. `` Wind usually blows round both sides of a hill and merges smoothly round the other side,'' <PERSON> Meaden </PERSON> said. `` However, sometimes there is a gust on one side but not the other which creates vortices or sudden whirlwinds. These sink to the ground and flatten crops in a spiral.'' <PERSON> Meaden </PERSON> said the Tornado and <ORGANIZATION> Storm </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> at <LOCATION> Bradford </LOCATION> in northern <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>, where he works, investigated 150 crop circles over the past eight years.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880605-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-05-88 0026EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-AlligatorAttack     06-05 0275</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Alligator Attack,0282</SECOND>
<HEAD>Four-year-old Dragged Into Pond By Alligator, Officials Say</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ENGLEWOOD, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An alligator grabbed a 4-year-old girl walking along the shores of a pond and dragged her underwater Saturday as two horrified playmates watched, police said. The girl, who was not identified, remained missing after an extensive search, <LOCATION> Charlotte </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> deputies said. She was walking at the edge of the pond at the Gardens of Gulf Cove development at about 6:30 p.m. when the alligator lunged from the water, said sheriff's Capt. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Miller </PERSON>. `` The child was forcibly dragged into the water by the alligator,'' <PERSON> Miller </PERSON> said. `` Our rescue units and dive teams have conducted an extensive search and the child has not yet been located.'' A neighbor, <PERSON> Debbie </PERSON> <PERSON> Triplett </PERSON>, said the girl's 6-year-old brother and a friend who is about 7 witnessed the attack. The children were walking a dog, she said. Another neighbor, <PERSON> Nolan </PERSON> <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON>, said when he heard the girl's mother screaming he went to the lake and saw a 10 - to-12-foot alligator surface twice about 20 yards away but saw nothing in its He said that the third time the gator came up, he saw a light-colored object in its mouth. Deputies and neighbors said gator prints and the child's shoe were found at the scene. Divers searched for three hours among the weeds in the freshwater lake but failed to find the alligator, <PERSON> Miller </PERSON> said. Six <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> Game and <ORGANIZATION> Freshwater </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fish </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> agents and several deputies and emergency workers also participated. The search was scheduled to continue Sunday, <PERSON> Miller </PERSON> said, adding that the child is still listed as missing and is not presumed dead.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880605-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-05-88 0055EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-NavyDeath 2ndLd-Writethru a0684 06-05 0788</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Navy Death, 2nd Ld - Writethru, a0684,0804</SECOND>
<HEAD>Witnesses Begin Telling of Recruit's Death</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: INSERTS 3 grafs after 6th graf pvs to update with testimony
from two other recruits; picks up 7th graf pvs ``Prior to ...'';
edits 21st graf to conform.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By BILL KACZOR</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PENSACOLA, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> rescue instructor yelled `` Get him!'' before a panic-stricken recruit was forced back into the swimming pool where he died, a classmate testified Saturday. The classmate, Airman Apprentice <PERSON> Gregory </PERSON> <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Boos </PERSON>, was unable to identify which instructors were among the four or five who pulled Airman Recruit <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Mirecki </PERSON>, 19, of <LOCATION> Appleton </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wis. </LOCATION>, into the pool March 2 at the <ORGANIZATION> Pensacola </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Naval </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Station </ORGANIZATION>. Boos was the lead witness in an investigative hearing to determine whether six sailors should face court-martial in the death of <PERSON> Mirecki </PERSON>. Another one of <PERSON> Mirecki </PERSON>'s classmates, Airman Recruit <PERSON> Gregory </PERSON> <PERSON> Harkrider </PERSON>, testified that the panic-stricken recruit had shouted `` Leave me alone ... I quit,'' and indicated he was quitting the rescue school. A heart specialist testified that heart failure most likely caused by fear-induced stress apparently killed <PERSON> Mirecki </PERSON>. But Cmdr. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Osborne </PERSON>, a cardiologist at the <ORGANIZATION> Naval </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aviation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION>, said his assessment was only conjecture based on a review of the autopsy report. The doctor said the heart problem, known medically as ventricular fibrillation, also could have been caused by drowning, hyperventilation or, less likely, by gastric juices coughed up by a victim during resuscitation attempts. A third student, Airman Apprentice <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Shiver </PERSON>, testified he heard the command as `` Get Mirecki!'' Seaman Apprentice <PERSON> Scott </PERSON> <PERSON> Riemer </PERSON> said he overheard someone say, `` Maybe we used too much force,'' during a meeting between two instructors and Lt. <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Torchia </PERSON>, the school's commander, shortly after <PERSON> Mirecki </PERSON> was taken away in an ambulance. <PERSON> Riemer </PERSON>, Shiver, Boos and <PERSON> Harkrider </PERSON> now are taking technical training at the <LOCATION> Memphis </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Naval </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Air </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Station </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION>. Prior to the testimony, Lt. <PERSON> Steven </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Cohen </PERSON>, the lawyer for one of the accused, Petty Officer 1st Class <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Blevins </PERSON>, complained that information from an investigation by the Judge Advocate General's office was being withheld on orders of the Secretary of the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Cohen </PERSON> and lawyers for other defendants made a motion that the proceedings be suspended until that information is released. Presiding Cmdr. <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> J </PERSON>. <PERSON> D'Alesio </PERSON> rejected the request, saying administrative proceedings are separate from the criminal case and that he lacked authority to release the information. Lt. Cmdr. <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Wynne </PERSON>, the prosecutor, assured defense lawyers the information would be made available before the conclusion of the hearing, which is expected to last several days. Boos testified that <PERSON> Mirecki </PERSON> panicked during a drill known as `` sharks and daisies.'' The exercise pits instructors, playing the role of panicky drowning victims, against trainees, who then are supposed to drag them underwater to break their hold and rescue them. <PERSON> Mirecki </PERSON> was having difficulty and swam to the side of the pool. He was pulled off the poolside, swam back to the side, climbed out and held on to an equipment rack, <PERSON> Boos </PERSON> said. `` He was panicked,'' <PERSON> Boos </PERSON> said. `` He was scared ... He was yelling ... It was obvious he did n't want to be back in the pool.'' <PERSON> Boos </PERSON> said he could n't understand what <PERSON> Mirecki </PERSON> was screaming. The next time he saw <PERSON> Mirecki </PERSON>, <PERSON> Boos </PERSON> said, the recruit was pulled to the side of the pool by one of the defendants, Petty Officer 2nd Class <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Combe </PERSON>. A second class member, Petty Officer 3rd Class <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> T. </PERSON> <PERSON> Breeden </PERSON>, said at one point he saw Combe trying to calm <PERSON> Mirecki </PERSON> down and run through the drill with him. <PERSON> Mirecki </PERSON> then successfully accomplished the escape and towed <PERSON> Combe </PERSON>, he said. But after that exercise, <PERSON> Breeden </PERSON> testified, he saw both <PERSON> Mirecki </PERSON> and <PERSON> Combe </PERSON> go under and then <PERSON> Combe </PERSON> surface towing <PERSON> Mirecki </PERSON>. <PERSON> Breeden </PERSON> said he did n't actually see <PERSON> Mirecki </PERSON> being forced back in, but felt <PERSON> Mirecki </PERSON> was clearly panicked and would not possibly have returned voluntarily. Five enlisted instructors are charged with involuntary manslaughter and conspiracy to commit battery. They are <PERSON> Blevins </PERSON>, <PERSON> Combe </PERSON>, Petty Officer 1st Class <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, Petty Officers 2nd Class <PERSON> Frankie </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Deaton </PERSON> and <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Zelenock </PERSON>. <PERSON> Torchia </PERSON>, the school's commanding officer, is charged with dereliction of duty. When the hearing ends, <PERSON> D'Alesio </PERSON> will make a non-binding recommendation to Rear Adm. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Morris </PERSON>, chief of naval air training in <LOCATION> Corpus </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Christi </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>. The admiral can drop the charges, court-martial the defendants or impose a non-judicial punishment. If convicted at court-martial each of the six could be dismissed from the service. The five instructors also face maximum penalties of three years in prison on the manslaughter counts and six months for conspiracy. <PERSON> Torchia </PERSON> could be sentenced to a maximum of three months in jail.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880605-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-05-88 0114EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-WritersStrike     06-05 0236</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Writers Strike,0241</SECOND>
<HEAD>Writers-Producers Continue Contract Talks</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Negotiators for striking scriptwriters and movie and television producers met for about seven hours Saturday and agreed only to return to the bargaining table Sunday, a spokeswoman said. The two chief negotiators for the <ORGANIZATION> Writers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guild </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Alliance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Motion </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Picture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Television </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Producers </ORGANIZATION> met from 1 p.m. until 8 p.m. Saturday at the producers' headquarters, said <ORGANIZATION> WGA </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman <PERSON> Cheryl </PERSON> <PERSON> Rhoden </PERSON>. The two sides were scheduled to meet again Sunday in an effort to end the 13-week-old walkout, she said. The substance of the talks was withheld, as were details of a negotiating session on Friday. `` I can only say the discussions are ongoing,'' <PERSON> Rhoden </PERSON> said Saturday night. The writers walked out March 7 in a dispute that centers on payments, called residuals, for reruns of one-hour television shows. Demand for one-hour shows in rerun, or syndication, is declining, and the producers had sought to tie payments to a show's success in reruns. Also at issue in the strike are writers' demands for more say over changes made in scripts during filming and more credit on and off screen for their work. The guild has signed other contracts with about 80 independent producers, but the alliance maintains none of its larger members have signed and that the producers who did defect employ only a tiny fraction of the 3,000 active writers.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880605-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-05-88 0147EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-NewZealand-Earthquake     06-05 0164</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-New Zealand-Earthquake,0169</SECOND>
<HEAD>Earthquake Sets Off Landslides, Blackouts and Shatters Windows</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WELLINGTON, New Zealand (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A strong earthquake triggered landslides, shattered windows and caused power blackouts in the lower half of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Zealand </LOCATION>'s south island on Saturday, officials said. The quake measured 6.5 on the <PERSON> Richter </PERSON> scale, but damage was limited because the quake was centered on the sparsely-populated area of <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Te </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Anau </LOCATION>, north of the town of <LOCATION> Invercargill </LOCATION>, officials said. There were no immedate reports of injuries. <PERSON> Murray </PERSON> <PERSON> Lowry </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Wellington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Seismological </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Observatory </ORGANIZATION> said Sunday that aftershocks could be expected to continue for as long as a month. The Richter scale measures ground motion as recorded on seismographs. Every increase of one number means a tenfold increase in magnitude. Thus a reading of 7.5 reflects an earthquake 10 times stronger than one of 6.5. An earthquake of 6.0 on the <PERSON> Richter </PERSON> scale can cause severe damage and a 7.0 reading is a `` major'' earthquake, capable of widespread heavy damage.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880605-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-05-88 0152EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-PhonesAtLast     06-05 0239</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Phones At Last,0243</SECOND>
<HEAD>Illinois Bell Restores Regular Service To Remaining Hinsdale
Residents</HEAD>
<DATELINE>HINSDALE, Ill. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Telephone technicians restored service just after midnight Sunday to the last of 35,000 western suburban customers whose phones were disrupted by a Mother's Day fire, company officials said. `` It went very smoothly, and everything should be back to normal now,'' <ORGANIZATION> Illinois </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bell </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Montgomery </PERSON> said early Sunday, shortly after the final adjustments were made at the <LOCATION> Hinsdale </LOCATION> switching station. By throwing the switch at midnight, <ORGANIZATION> Bell </ORGANIZATION> hooked up the last set of subscribers in <LOCATION> Hinsdale </LOCATION> and five other west <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> suburbs. The customers would be switched to new state-of-the-art digital equipment at the <LOCATION> Hinsdale </LOCATION> station, which was ravaged by fire May 8. `` Technically, this should be the end of it,'' said <PERSON> Hilary </PERSON> <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON>, an <ORGANIZATION> Illinois </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bell </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman. `` We are putting everybody back in service ... but there might be some little glitches that we will have to work out. The switching station equipment connects local and long distance calls. Half the <LOCATION> Hinsdale </LOCATION> customers were connected to the new equipment at midnight May 26, but the other half continued to suffer impaired phone service, including sporadic dial tones and static on the line. The company promised rebates to customers for the disruptions, but several businessmen upset about their losses have filed lawsuits charging the telephone company was negligent in failing to staff the switching station at the time of the fire.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880605-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-05-88 0318EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i BC-Israel-ArabAmerican 2ndLd-Writethru a0724 06-05 0523</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Israel-Arab American, 2nd Ld-Writethru, a0724,0536</SECOND>
<HEAD>Supreme Court Rules Awad Deported</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: ADDS 6 grafs of detail on deportation case and libel suit,
background on uprising.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>JERUSALEM (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> on Sunday upheld a government decision to deport Arab-American <PERSON> Mubarak </PERSON> <PERSON> Awad </PERSON>, an advocate of civil disobedience toward Israeli rule in the occupied territories. The court said it will delay the deportation until next Sunday, apparently to give <PERSON> Awad </PERSON> time to appear in court for a civil libel suit against the Israeli daily <ORGANIZATION> Maariv </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Awad </PERSON>, 44, responded to the ruling by saying, `` I am not disappointed. I will continue to fight for a Palestinian state wherever I am.'' The decison by the three-judge panel was read in a 10-minute session only hours before <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Secretary of State <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON>, who protested the deportation order, was due to arrive in <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> to pursue a peace initiative. Prime Minister <PERSON> Yitzhak </PERSON> <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON> ordered <PERSON> Awad </PERSON> deported May 6, after the Arab-American was arrested the previous day and accused of playing a role in inciting the six-month-old Arab uprising in the occupied territories. The Jerusalem-born <PERSON> Awad </PERSON>, who also has a home in <LOCATION> Wapakoneta </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, has denied the charges. <PERSON> Awad </PERSON> describes himself as an adherent of the late Indian leader <PERSON> Mohandas </PERSON> <PERSON> K. </PERSON> <PERSON> Ghandi </PERSON>'s philosophy of civil disobedience. He has authored a widely-circulated pamphlet called ` Non-Violent Resistance: A Strategy for the Occupied Territories.'' In a statement from jail after he was ordered deported, <PERSON> Awad </PERSON> said: `` For Prime Minister <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON> to say that I, a Christian, will be forever prevented from returning to my city of <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION> to pray in my holy places is totally unacceptable.'' <PERSON> Awad </PERSON> was born in <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION> when the city was ruled by neighboring <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION>. His appeal against the deportation was considered by his lawyers to be a test case for the status of Palestinians under Israeli rule in the city. <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> annexed east <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION> after capturing the sector of the city from <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION> in the 1967 Middle East War. <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s grounds for deportation was that <PERSON> Awad </PERSON> failed to renew a tourist visa that expired last year. <PERSON> Awad </PERSON>'s attorneys, <PERSON> Jonathan </PERSON> <PERSON> Kuttab </PERSON> and <PERSON> Avraham </PERSON> <PERSON> Gal </PERSON> contended he did not need a visa and should be allowed permanent residence because he was born in <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION>. In issuing the deportation order, <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON>'s spokesman <PERSON> Avi </PERSON> <PERSON> Pazner </PERSON> accused <PERSON> Awad </PERSON> on May 7th of helping to compile a series of leaflets urging Palestinians to throw stones and firebombs at Israeli targets. According to <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> figures, 201 Palestinians have been killed in the uprising. Three Israelis have also died. <PERSON> Awad </PERSON>'s American-born wife <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> <PERSON> Nye </PERSON> responded by telling reporters last month that her husband was committed to non-violence but also to the `` intefadeh,'' which is Arabic for uprising. She said <PERSON> Awad </PERSON> supported measures such as merchant strikes and boycotts of <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> goods which matched <PERSON> Awad </PERSON>'s philosophy of civil disobedience. <PERSON> Awad </PERSON>'s Israeli lawyer <PERSON> Avraham </PERSON> <PERSON> Gal </PERSON> won court approval to delay his client's deportation, pending another hearing in a $ 100,000 libel suit. In the suit filed last week, <PERSON> Awad </PERSON> challenged Maariv for claiming in an article on May 13 that he dealt in drugs and channeled the proceeds to the <ORGANIZATION> Palestine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880605-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-05-88 0504EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w BC-JacksonBrother1stLd-Writethru a0727   06-05 0550</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Jackson Brother 1st Ld-Writethru, a0727,530</SECOND>
<HEAD>Candidate's Half-Brother Charged in Attack On Murder Witness</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Adds two new grafs after 10th graf pvs, bgng A duty xxx, with
more detail on charge and arrest of alleged attacker; picks up 11th
graf pvs, Morton said, but subs last graf to conform.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By PAUL PAGE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The half-brother of Democratic presidential candidate <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> was arrested in <LOCATION> Greenville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> S.C. </LOCATION>, and charged with hiring someone to attack a murder witness, police said Sunday. <PERSON> Noah </PERSON> <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON>, 45, was arrested late Saturday night and charged with being an accessory to a felony, obstruction of justice, intimidating a witness and criminal conspiracy, according to <ORGANIZATION> Greenville </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION> Detective <PERSON> Keith </PERSON> <PERSON> Morton </PERSON>. <PERSON> Morton </PERSON> said <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON>, a small businessman in <LOCATION> Greenville </LOCATION> who has also worked in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>, is suspected of hiring someone who slashed and stabbed a woman who was a witness to the execution-style murder of a man who had worked for <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON>. `` We think he was responsible for the solicitation of the act and took part in the arranging,'' said <PERSON> Morton </PERSON>. <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON>, who gave police a home address in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>, and <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> have the same father. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, who has spoken frequently on the campaign trail of his beginnings, was born out of wedlock to a woman who had an affair with the candidate's father, who was married at the time. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> and <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> have had a chaotic relationship over the years, at times working together but also quarreling and staying apart. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> had <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> take control of the federally funded <ORGANIZATION> Breadbasket </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commercial </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, an arm of <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s civil rights group, Operation PUSH, that helped minority firms bid for public contracts. But <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> was quoted as saying in 1987, when <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> was reportedly being investigated for allegedly violating federal bankruptcy laws, `` I have no connection with him.'' <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Borosage </PERSON>, a <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> campaign spokesman, declined to comment early Sunday. A duty officer at the <LOCATION> Greenville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> S.C. </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Detention </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> said <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> was being held Sunday in lieu of $ 100,000 bond, although <PERSON> Morton </PERSON> said prosecutors planned to seek a higher bond. The warrant filed late Saturday charges that <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> `` did advise, counsel, urge encourage or otherwise aid a co-defendant in the commission of a felony, assault and battery with intent to kill ... and later rendered assistance to the co-defendant in absconding the jurisdiction.'' A man turned charged with assault and battery with intent to kill in the attack turned himself in to authorities in January, according to the <ORGANIZATION> Greenville </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Morton </PERSON> said <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> was arrested after statements from `` co-defendants'' and that more arrests are expected. According to <PERSON> Morton </PERSON>, <PERSON> Janice </PERSON> <PERSON> Denice </PERSON> <PERSON> Rosemond </PERSON> was stabbed repeatedly in December 1987, after she had testified before a grand jury in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> about the slaying of <PERSON> Leroy </PERSON> <PERSON> Barber </PERSON>. <PERSON> Barber </PERSON> was shot to death in January 1986 outside a plaza in <LOCATION> Greenville </LOCATION> <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> owns. `` From what we understand, there had been several altercations over the years between <PERSON> Barber </PERSON> and <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON>. He had been working for <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> and come back to <LOCATION> Greenville </LOCATION>,'' said <PERSON> Morton </PERSON>. `` They'd gotten into a fight a couple of weeks before'' <PERSON> Barber </PERSON> was shot. <PERSON> Morton </PERSON> said <PERSON> Barber </PERSON> was shot once in the head by an unidentified assailant and `` <PERSON> Rosemond </PERSON>, unfortunately, was a witness to that.' No one has been charged with the Barber slaying, said <PERSON> Morton </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880605-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-05-88 0611EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i BC-MineDisaster 1stLd-Writethru a0726 06-05 0254</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Mine Disaster, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0726,0257</SECOND>
<HEAD>Rescuers Find More Bodies</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: UPDATES with two more bodies found</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By GEORGE BOEHMER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BORKEN, West Germany (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Rescuers on Sunday found the bodies of eight more miners killed in a powerful coal mine blast, bringing the confirmed death toll to 45 in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>'s worst mining accident in 26 years. Six men who survived three days in an underground air pocket were rescued Saturday after a microphone lowered into a shaft picked up their voices and tapping sounds. <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Carl </PERSON> <PERSON> Ruehland </PERSON>, a spokesman for <ORGANIZATION> Preussen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Elektra </ORGANIZATION>, the company that owns the mine, said rescuers were continuing the search for six miners still missing since the blast Wednesday. Residents of <LOCATION> Borken </LOCATION>, 70 miles northeast of <LOCATION> Frankfurt </LOCATION>, were to hold a service later Sunday to remember the victims of the tragedy. In an interview with the <ORGANIZATION> ZDF </ORGANIZATION> television network, surviving miner <PERSON> Ahmet </PERSON> <PERSON> Batkan </PERSON> said he and the five other miners contacted rescuers by radio just hours after the blast, but that the rescuers apparently thought the six were with the search teams. Officials said the survivors were trapped about 500 feet underground in an air pocket away from carbon monoxide estimated at 50 times the level fatal to humans. Officials said about 200 workers were involved in the search in <LOCATION> Borken </LOCATION>, a town of 15,000 people. The Borken explosion is the worst West German mining accident since 299 men died in 1962 at the <LOCATION> Luisenthal </LOCATION> mine in <LOCATION> Saarland </LOCATION> state along the border with <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880605-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-05-88 0629EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i BC-Soviet-TrainBlast 1stLd-Writethru a0731 06-05 0408</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Soviet-Train Blast, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0731,0421</SECOND>
<HEAD>More Than 50 People Killed When Freight Car Explodes</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: ADDS 9 grafs of detail.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>MOSCOW (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A freight car exploded as a train approached a station east of the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> capital, killing more than 50 people, injuring hundreds more and throwing cars and trucks into the air like feathers, <ORGANIZATION> Izvestia </ORGANIZATION> reported Sunday. The government newspaper said the accident occurred at exactly 9:30 a.m. Saturday and the blast was so powerful it broke windows a quarter-mile away. It said the cause of the explosion was as yet unknown, and gave no hint of what the freight car that exploded might have been carrying. The blast occurred as the train neared the station in <LOCATION> Arzamas </LOCATION>, about 240 miles east of <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Izvestia </ORGANIZATION> said. `` At its very epicenter were trucks and cars, which were waiting for the train to pass,'' <ORGANIZATION> Izvestia </ORGANIZATION> said. `` They were scattered about as though they were down.'' As a result of the explosion, <ORGANIZATION> Izvestia </ORGANIZATION> said, `` more than 50 people were killed, and hundreds were wounded.'' More than 80 doctors were airlifted by helicopter to the accident site from the regional center of Gorky, <ORGANIZATION> Izvestia </ORGANIZATION> said. The explosion destroyed nearby homes and businesses, set off small fires in many places, derailed other freight cars and damaged the rails, <ORGANIZATION> Izvestia </ORGANIZATION> said. Driven forward by the blast, the locomotive was flipped end over end and landed beside the tracks. Firefighters manning a dozen fire trucks managed to douse the main blaze about a half-hour after the explosion, the newspaper said. A mobile hospital able to care for 230 people was quickly set up near the accident scene, it said. A special government commission was created under the deputy chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministers </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Gennady </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Vedernikov </PERSON>, to determine the causes of the explosion and deal with the consequences. <PERSON> Vedernikov </PERSON>'s high position indicated the seriousness of the accident. He told <ORGANIZATION> Izvestia </ORGANIZATION> local residents instantly offered to help victims of the explosion by donating blood and food. People left homeless by the explosion have been placed in apartments, <PERSON> Vedernikov </PERSON> said. A special `` operations group,'' military units and the local civil defense are directing relief work, <PERSON> Vedernikov </PERSON> said. The 14-member government commission includes representatives of the <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION>, police, the <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION>, the prosecutor's office and other agencies. `` A thorough investigation is being conducted into the causes of the explosion,'' <PERSON> Vedernikov </PERSON> said. `` I can not yet say anything about the results.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880605-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-05-88 0649EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i BC-Zimbabwe-Wreck     06-05 0127</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Zimbabwe-Wreck,0132</SECOND>
<HEAD>Sixteen People Died In Bus-Train Wreck</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: RETRANSMITTING to fix cycle designator</NOTE>
<DATELINE>HARARE, Zimbabwe (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A bus collided with a freight train at a railroad crossing near the capital, killing 16 people and injuring 56, police said Sunday. A police spokesman, speaking on condition of anonymity, said nine bus passengers died late Saturday when the bus smashed into the train about 12 miles west of <LOCATION> Harare </LOCATION>. Seven others died at <LOCATION> Parirenyatwa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Harare </LOCATION> and 56 people were hurt in the wreck, nine of them seriously, he said. One railroad worker aboard the train was among the injured. On May 20, six people died and about 50 were injured in a similar smash on the railroad line 60 miles east of <LOCATION> Harare </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880605-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-05-88 0835EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i BC-Shultz     06-05 0509</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Shultz,0526</SECOND>
<HEAD>Shultz Arrives For Talks</HEAD>
<DATELINE>JERUSALEM (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Secretary of State <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> on Sunday urged <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> to end its occupation of the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strip </LOCATION> and restore rights to Palestinians. `` Now is the time for further progress toward peace,'' <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> said at <LOCATION> Ben </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gurion </LOCATION> <LOCATION> International </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION> near <LOCATION> Tel </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Aviv </LOCATION> after he arrived for a seven-hour visit to pursue his <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> peace initiative. `` The continued occupation of the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strip </LOCATION> and the frustration of Palestinian rights is a dead end. To continue it is an illusion,'' <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> said. `` The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has put forward a plan for negotiations. No party has the luxury to turn aside a chance to negotiate.'' <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> seized the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strip </LOCATION> during the 1967 <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> war. Since anti-occupation unrest broke out in the occupied lands on Dec. 8, <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> soldiers have killed more than 200 Palestinians. Two Israelis have been killed. Israeli Foreign Minister <PERSON> Shimon </PERSON> <PERSON> Peres </PERSON> greeted <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON>. `` We look upon you as a man with a message, a man who carries a message of peace to all of us,'' he said. <PERSON> Peres </PERSON> said there was a choice `` between the continued arms race, fanatacism, fundamentalism and other manifestations of extremism and the tough decision required to block this trend and to offer the Middle East Arabs and Jews alike a different future.'' Before <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> arrived, <PERSON> Peres </PERSON>, who heads the leftist <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, told <ORGANIZATION> Israel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> radio </ORGANIZATION>, `` I will do all I can to advance the peace process. ... Let's say the peace process dies, then what's the alternative?'' Prime Minister <PERSON> Yitzhak </PERSON> <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON>, however, who objects to parts of <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON>'s plan, told <ORGANIZATION> Israel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> radio </ORGANIZATION> Saturday he does not expect a breakthrough. <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON>, who heads the right-wing <ORGANIZATION> Likud </ORGANIZATION> bloc, objects to trading land for peace. He also opposes a proposed international peace conference in which Western countries would mediate a settlement of the <LOCATION> Arab-Israeli </LOCATION> conflict. On Sunday, <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON>'s spokesman <PERSON> Yossi </PERSON> <PERSON> Ahimeir </PERSON> said the premier `` greatly welcomes the visit, the efforts Mr. <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> is making to advance the peace process.'' <PERSON> Ahimeir </PERSON> also said <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON> will will raise <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s concern about the use of chemical weapons by <PERSON> Arab </PERSON> states and their newly-purchased medium-range missiles. `` He -LRB- <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON> -RRB- feels that the whole free world should raise its voice against the use of these weapons'' by <PERSON> Arab </PERSON> states, <PERSON> Ahimeir </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> is also expected to report to <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> leaders on <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> summit last week and the talks he held in <LOCATION> Cairo </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> officials said. <PERSON> Peres </PERSON> told <ORGANIZATION> Israel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> radio </ORGANIZATION> he was encouraged by changes he said he has detected in the <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION>'s approach to the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION>. The <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> broke diplomatic ties with <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> during the 1967 war, but gradually has resumed contacts over the last two years. After the <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> summit, Soviet leader <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> also said he would consider `` regularizing'' ties with <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> once an international conference was underway. `` In the past the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> has been mostly a weapons supplier to the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Peres </PERSON> said. Now `` they -LRB- the Soviets -RRB- support compromise. This is a real change.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880605-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-05-88 1121EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Libya-US     06-05 0353</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Libya-US,0366</SECOND>
<HEAD>Libya Denounces U.S. For Terrorist Allegations</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ROME (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Libya </LOCATION> on Sunday denounced the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> for saying that groups supported by <LOCATION> Libya </LOCATION> were suspected in recent attacks against Americans and <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> facilities around the world. The official <ORGANIZATION> JANA </ORGANIZATION> news agency, monitored in <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION>, said the allegations were made to undermine <LOCATION> Libya </LOCATION>, hinder <PERSON> Arab </PERSON> unity and force <LOCATION> Libya </LOCATION> to retreat from its `` support of the massive popular revolution in occupied Palestine.'' <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman <PERSON> Phyllis </PERSON> <PERSON> Oakley </PERSON> said in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> on Friday that groups that have received support from <LOCATION> Libya </LOCATION> were the `` prime suspects'' in recent attacks against <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and western European interests in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Latin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>. She did not accuse <LOCATION> Libya </LOCATION> directly but said suspicion of its continued support of terrorism was accompanied by `` concrete evidence.'' Mrs. <PERSON> Oakley </PERSON> referred to the seizure last November in <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> of a shipment of <LOCATION> Libyan </LOCATION> weapons allegedly intended for the outlawed <ORGANIZATION> Irish </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>. She also cited reports that suspected Libyan agents were arrested carrying bomb-making materials in <LOCATION> Senegal </LOCATION> in February. <ORGANIZATION> JANA </ORGANIZATION> said the statements affirm again the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government's `` reliance on the language of threat in international dealings. `` We interpret this new threat by the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> administration against <LOCATION> Libya </LOCATION> as a start of aggression ... without any justification but hatred and the spirit of domination and racism,'' it said. For years, <LOCATION> Libya </LOCATION> has been one of a few nations identified by the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> as sponsors of terrorist groups. The <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration has accused <LOCATION> Libyan </LOCATION> leader <PERSON> Moammar </PERSON> <PERSON> Gadhafi </PERSON> of fomenting terrorism. In April 1986, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> warplanes attacked his personal living quarters in <LOCATION> Tripoli </LOCATION>. He was not hit. Around the second anniversary of the attack, there were several terrorist attacks on installations and clubs owned or frequented by Americans. Among the targets hit this year were <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Information </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> offices in <LOCATION> Costa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rica </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Peru </LOCATION> and a club frequented by American servicemen in <LOCATION> Naples </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>. Five people were killed in the <LOCATION> Naples </LOCATION> attack. Two Americans were wounded in an attack on a club in <LOCATION> Khartoum </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Sudan </LOCATION>, last month, and the office of a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> bank in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Delhi </LOCATION> was also targeted.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880605-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-05-88 1123EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Philippines     06-05 0470</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Philippines,0484</SECOND>
<HEAD>Sixteen Soldiers Killed In Rebel Ambush</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BACOLOD, Philippines (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Communist rebels ambushed a platoon of soldiers trying to retrieve a hijacked truck Sunday, killing 16 and wounding eight in one of the bloodiest rebel attacks this year, officials said. The officials, who spoke on condition of anonymity, said the troops managed to fight back and killed an undetermined number of rebels during the hour-long battle on an isolated mountain road. Foreign Minister <PERSON> Raul </PERSON> <PERSON> Manglapus </PERSON> charged that unidentified European governments were indirectly financing communist rebels. <PERSON> Manglapus </PERSON> made the accusation on the third day of a conference among representatives of 13 Asian, European and <LOCATION> Latin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> countries that have won their freedom from dictators. A sketchy military report said 24 soldiers and militiamen were traveling on foot when they came under fire from an unknown number of <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> guerrillas outside <LOCATION> Silay </LOCATION> city, 300 miles southeast of <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION> and about 25 miles from <LOCATION> Bacalod </LOCATION>. The rebels fled when more troops backed by helicopter gunships and armored personnel carriers arrived, the report said. Residents of nearby villages evacuated their homes as troops continued to hunt the rebels after the battle, which began at 2 p.m., the officials said. Local radio reports said the ambushed soldiers were on their way to retrieve a truck loaded with fertilizer that rebels abandoned after hijacking it Saturday night. The truck belonged to one of the biggest sugar producing companies on <LOCATION> Negros </LOCATION> island. The <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> is one of 12 Marxist groups that have been waging a 19-year insurgency in the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION> is the umbrella organization for the groups. The Philippine military estimates that the front received $ 15 million in aid last year from groups in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Zealand </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Manglapus </PERSON> said foreign aid to the rebels came from non-governmental organizations but noted that such groups in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> are subsidized by some governments. `` This, of course, is practically an official flow of money, and our armed forces and intelligence agencies tell us that this takes place regularly in a systematic manner,'' <PERSON> Manglapus </PERSON> said. He said he has filed formal protests with the European governments concerned but did not identify any of them. He said he has not raised the matter with the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION>, Japanese, Australian and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Zealand </LOCATION> governments but did not say why. Earlier, <LOCATION> Greece </LOCATION>'s representative in the conference denied claims by the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION> that <LOCATION> Greece </LOCATION>'s governing <ORGANIZATION> Panhellenic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Socialist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> was among its supporters. `` We have nothing in common with insurgents and, therefore, we deplore such cheap and shameless lies,'' said <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Lianis </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Greece </LOCATION>'s ambassador to <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>. Other countries attending the conference were <LOCATION> Portugal </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Uruguay </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ecuador </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Peru </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Argentina </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Dominican </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Republic </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Norway </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Switzerland </LOCATION> and were represented as observers.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880605-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-05-88 1126EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-CocaineCrash     06-05 0674</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Cocaine Crash,0691</SECOND>
<HEAD>Up In Smoke: From Millionaire Go-Getter To Imprisoned Dope Addict</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BIRMINGHAM, Ala. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Raymond </PERSON> <PERSON> Riha </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> was worth between $ 6 million and $ 10 million before he was 45, had a successful company, owned property in <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>, drove expensive cars and was married with two children. That life collapsed in less than two years after he began smoking cocaine. He recently pleaded guilty to two cocaine trafficking charges and one possession charge, and was sentenced to 15 years on each. A hearing is scheduled June 17 to determine how much of the sentence must be served behind bars. He also awaits trial on a fourth charge. During a recent series of interviews at the <ORGANIZATION> Jefferson </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Jail </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Riha </PERSON>, 45, told the <ORGANIZATION> Birmingham </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post-Herald </ORGANIZATION> about his downfall. `` That pipe, that person, that thing in my hand, it was very much alive; it was a living thing to me,'' <PERSON> Riha </PERSON> said. `` I talked to it, and it answered me. It came back with positive-plus reactions and answers and made me work everything out in my mind. It lies all the time.'' His personal net worth is down to $ 100,000 by some estimates. The company he founded in <LOCATION> Pelham </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Resistance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Welding </ORGANIZATION>, which grossed about $ 6 million a year and employed 25 people, is bankrupt. He says he had never used any kind of drug until one day in October 1986 when he walked into the home of a friend and walked out about 12 hours later, hooked on cocaine. `` I said, ` What is this? There is no such thing on earth that could do that to me, that could take control of me,'' <PERSON> Riha </PERSON> said. `` I took the pipe and smoked it so nonchalantly that first time.'' The drug relaxed him. `` All my worries disappeared,'' he said. He had plenty of money and plenty of time, and gave himself over to binge after binge. `` It is not unusual for a person to lose everything they have,'' said Dr. <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Rice </PERSON>, clinical director of the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Alabama </ORGANIZATION> at <ORGANIZATION> Birmingham </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Professionals </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Chelsea </LOCATION>. `` The unusual situation here is that this individual had so much to lose.'' The drug interfered with <PERSON> Riha </PERSON>'s closest interests. A horse-racing fan from his childhood in <LOCATION> Cleveland </LOCATION>, he was one of the first to invest in the new <ORGANIZATION> Birmingham </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Turf </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Club </ORGANIZATION>, purchasing 1,000 shares of stock and 51 limited partnerships. He signed up his company to rent of one of the prestigious boxes at $ 25,000 a year. But when the horse track opened March 3, 1987, `` it took everything I could muster to get there,'' he said. `` I almost did n't make it through the evening And I found myself leaving to go to my car between the races to hit the pipe.'' He fulfilled another lifelong dream by investing about $ 400,000 to put together a dragster and crew, but when the car was ready to race in January 1987, it held no interest and <PERSON> Riha </PERSON> only made it to a few races. `` It's amazing how the drug can take your interest in everything away, from hobbies to your business, sex, love, everything, and replace it with itself,'' said <PERSON> Riha </PERSON>. <PERSON> Riha </PERSON> was arrested on drug charges twice but returned to cocaine use late last year after a month in a rehabilitation program. On Christmas Day last year, <PERSON> Riha </PERSON> said, `` I sat there looking at bankruptcy papers, the suit my father filed against me for the $ 400,000 I had borrowed from him over the years, divorce papers that never went through and the criminal charges. ` Well, merry Christmas, <PERSON> Ray </PERSON>,' I said. But at least I had my pipe there, too.'' Later he was arrested for allegedly giving cocaine to a minor, the 17-year-old daughter of his mistress. He said she took it from him. She testified she was working for the police and that he gave her cocaine when she asked for it. `` I do n't think I was meant to go sit in prison,'' <PERSON> Riha </PERSON> said. `` I did n't go through all this to end this way.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880605-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-05-88 1127EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-People     06-05 0830</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-People,0862</SECOND>
<HEAD>People In The News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY44</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Princess <PERSON> Diana </PERSON>'s mother, <PERSON> Frances </PERSON> <PERSON> Shand-Kydd </PERSON>, said Sunday she has separated from her second husband, wallpaper heir <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Shand-Kydd </PERSON>. `` I would like it to be known that my husband and I have separated, which is a great sadness to us both. No one else is involved,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Shand-Kydd </PERSON>, 52, said in a statement issued by her lawyers. Buckingham Palace had no comment, and Mrs. <PERSON> Shand-Kydd </PERSON> said, `` Neither <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> nor I will be making any further statement.'' The announcement followed a report in the Sunday tabloid News of the World that the marriage was on the rocks and <PERSON> Shand-Kydd </PERSON>, 63, wanted to return to his first wife, <PERSON> Janet </PERSON>. <PERSON> Diana </PERSON>, wife of British heir apparent <PERSON> Prince </PERSON> <PERSON> Charles </PERSON>, was 6 years old when her mother left her father, the eighth <PERSON> Earl </PERSON> <PERSON> Spencer </PERSON>, in 1967. <PERSON> Spencer </PERSON> was granted a divorce two years later because of his wife's adultery with <PERSON> Shand </PERSON> <PERSON> Kydd </PERSON>, and she was named the `` other woman'' in the uncontested divorce of <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> and <PERSON> Janet </PERSON> <PERSON> Shand-Kydd </PERSON>. She married <PERSON> Shand-Kydd </PERSON> soon after both divorces were final.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>KOSCIUSKO, Miss. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Television talk show host <PERSON> Oprah </PERSON> <PERSON> Winfrey </PERSON> came home for the renaming of the winding gravel road that runs in front of the house where she was born. The three-mile lane that is wide enough for two cars is now officially known as the <LOCATION> Oprah </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Winfrey </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Road </LOCATION>. `` This is a real homecoming,'' <PERSON> Winfrey </PERSON> said to the 300 people gathered Saturday for the ribbon-cutting ceremony in the rural community of <LOCATION> Buffalo </LOCATION>, three miles outside <LOCATION> Kosciusko </LOCATION> in central <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION>. `` It is a deeply humbling experience to come back to the place where it all started. No one ever goes very far in life without remembering where they came from.'' `` Hopefully, we can get it blacktopped,'' <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Hayes </PERSON>, chairman of the `` Welcome Home Oprah'' day festivities, said of the road. `` Most of her family lived in that community.'' <PERSON> Winfrey </PERSON>, 34, spoke at the old, white, wood-frame <ORGANIZATION> Buffalo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Methodist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION>, where she said she made her first public appearance at an Easter recital when she was 3 years old. A new brick church stands across the road. <PERSON> Winfrey </PERSON> spent the early part of her childhood living with her grandmother in the poor community before moving to <LOCATION> Milwaukee </LOCATION> with her mother at age 6. `` We love you, we love what you are doing,'' said Northern District Highway Commissioner <PERSON> Zack </PERSON> <PERSON> Stewart </PERSON>, who cut the ribbon with <PERSON> Winfrey </PERSON>. `` We love what you stand for.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>RADNOR, Pa. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Like the yuppies they play on `` thirtysomething,'' <PERSON> Ken </PERSON> <PERSON> Olin </PERSON> and <PERSON> Patricia </PERSON> <PERSON> Wettig </PERSON> worry about juggling careers, ambition, marriage and a home life. <PERSON> Olin </PERSON>, who plays the brooding, analytical <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION> adman <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Steadman </PERSON>, and <PERSON> Wettig </PERSON>, his real-life wife who plays the wife of <PERSON> Steadman </PERSON>'s partner <PERSON> Elliott </PERSON>, both admit in the June 11 issue of TV Guide that active acting careers cause other aspects of their lives to suffer at times. `` You've got kids and a marriage and work, all at the same time,'' said <PERSON> Wettig </PERSON>. `` From my perspective all three things are extremely important and I'm not willing to give up any of them, but I find at different times one is always suffering.'' `` Sometimes I feel like I'm in competition with her work,'' <PERSON> Olin </PERSON> said. `` It's like being in competition with the children. I'm competitive for her attention. He also admits he fears being eclipsed by his wife. `` My fear is that <PERSON> Patti </PERSON> will have all these opportunities and she will meet men and work more interesting than I am ... and she will leave me.'' But <PERSON> Wettig </PERSON> said she expects almost the opposite. `` I assume that <PERSON> Ken </PERSON>, being a guy, being his age, and where he's sitting now, I kind of assume that he will probably make more money than me and be more famous.'' Sound familiar? It should. Producer <PERSON> Marshall </PERSON> <PERSON> Herskovitz </PERSON> uses the couple as a sounding board for scripts and plots on the nature of a yuppie marriage.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LEXINGTON, Ohio (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Rock singer <PERSON> Ted </PERSON> <PERSON> Nugent </PERSON> escaped injury when he crashed on the cool-down lap after winning the Dodge International Star Challenge celebrity auto race. <PERSON> Nugent </PERSON> rolled his <ORGANIZATION> Dodge </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Shelby </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Z </ORGANIZATION> after the race was over at <ORGANIZATION> Mid-Ohio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sports </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Car </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Course </ORGANIZATION>, but walked away from the accident Saturday. `` I did n't have a brake to be found,'' <PERSON> Nugent </PERSON> said. `` I dragged my foot, I started back peddling _ it did n't work!'' <PERSON> Nugent </PERSON> beat <ORGANIZATION> RATT </ORGANIZATION> drummer <PERSON> Bobby </PERSON> <PERSON> Blotzer </PERSON> by 19.612 seconds in the 12-lap race around the 2.4-mile road course. He averaged 76.376 mph. The race was the second in a series of four races to highlight a national public awareness campaign called `` TH! NK, Do n't Drive and Drink.'' `` If people who drink and do drugs could ever get as high as I did just driving that car, they'd realize what chumps they are,'' <PERSON> Nugent </PERSON> said. Fee Waybill, former lead singer of the Tubes, finished third, and <PERSON> Alto </PERSON> <PERSON> Reed </PERSON>, <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Seger </PERSON>'s saxaphonist in the Silver Bullet Band, was fourth.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880605-0025 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-05-88 1141EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Israel-Merchants Bjt   06-05 0736</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Israel-Merchants, Bjt,0761</SECOND>
<HEAD>Arab Merchants Threatened From Both Sides of Uprising</HEAD>
<HEAD>With AM-Israel, Bjt</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By G.G. LaBELLE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>JERUSALEM (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
