<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880411-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-11-88 2343EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-Oscars-Wilder 1stLd-Writethru a0754 04-11 0410</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Oscars-Wilder, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0754,0417</SECOND>
<NOTE>Eds: Inserts 3 grafs acceptance quotes after 3rd pvs bgng
``Wilder, 81''</NOTE>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Film legend <PERSON> Billy </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilder </PERSON>, a six-time Oscar winner for such films as `` The Lost Weekend'' and `` The Apartment,'' on Monday night became the 25th recipient of the <ORGANIZATION> Motion </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Picture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION>'s <PERSON> Irving </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Thalberg </PERSON> Award. The award goes to `` a creative producer whose body of work reflects a consistently high quality of motion picture production.'' It is given only when the <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Motion </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Picture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Arts </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sciences </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Directors </ORGANIZATION> decides there is a deserving recipient. <PERSON> Wilder </PERSON>, 81, has had a movie career of nearly 60 years, during which he has been nominated for an Oscar 21 times. `` As I look back, I've lived a charmed life,'' <PERSON> Wilder </PERSON> said, after being honored by the audience with a standing ovation. <PERSON> Wilder </PERSON> recounted how he had left <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> to escape the <ORGANIZATION> Nazis </ORGANIZATION>, and was granted a chance to stay in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> by a consular official in <LOCATION> Mexicali </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, who asked <PERSON> Wilder </PERSON> what he did for a living. Upon hearing <PERSON> Wilder </PERSON> wrote movies, the official stamped his passport and said, `` Write some good ones. `` That was 54 years ago, I've tried ever since,'' <PERSON> Wilder </PERSON> said. In 1961, he became the first person to win three Oscars at once for producing, directing and co-writing on `` The Apartment,'' best picture for 1960. <PERSON> Wilder </PERSON>'s career began in <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> and continued after he fled the <ORGANIZATION> Nazis </ORGANIZATION> and came to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> in 1933. His mother, grandmother and stepfather died at <LOCATION> Auschwitz </LOCATION>. When he arrived in <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION>, he spoke fewer than 100 words of English and took up residence in the ladies' room of the Chateau Marmont Hotel. <PERSON> Wilder </PERSON> won Academy Awards for both directing and co-writing `` The Lost Weekend'' in 1945. He won a screenwriting award for `` Sunset Boulevard'' along with <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Brackett </PERSON> and D.M. <PERSON> Marshman </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr </PERSON>. The Thalberg award has been presented 28 times, sometimes more than once to the same individual. <PERSON> Steven </PERSON> <PERSON> Spielberg </PERSON> received it last year. <PERSON> Darryl </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Zanuck </PERSON> won the award three times and <PERSON> Hal </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Wallis </PERSON> twice, meaning it has gone to 25 people since it was established in 1937. Rules now prohibit a person from receiving the award more than once. <PERSON> Thalberg </PERSON> was an MGM production chief who died at age 37 but left a legacy of elevating the artistic quality of film with such movies as `` The Good Earth'' and `` Romeo and <PERSON> Juliet </PERSON>.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880411-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-11-88 2353EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Leeches     04-11 0409</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Leeches,0421</SECOND>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</NOTE>
<HEAD>Scientists Discover New Anti-Clotting Enzymes In Leech Saliva</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAN IZENBERG</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>JERUSALEM (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Israeli scientists have reported discovering two enzymes in leech saliva that help keep blood from clotting and may be used to fight blood disorders and facilitate surgery. `` We found two enzymes never reported before: collagenase, which breaks down collagen, and apyrase, which breaks down ADP -LRB- adenosine diphosphate -RRB-,'' said <PERSON> Meir </PERSON> <PERSON> Rigbi </PERSON>, a professor at the <ORGANIZATION> Hebrew </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. He said collagen and ADP induce blood cells called platelets to stick together, the first step in blood clotting. He and research partners <PERSON> Miriam </PERSON> <PERSON> Orevi </PERSON> and <PERSON> Amiram </PERSON> <PERSON> Eldor </PERSON> have been studying leech saliva for three years. Scientists have known of the fluid's anti-clotting qualities for a century. Three decades ago, a German scientist isolated and identified hirudin, a protein contained in leech saliva that now is considered the most powerful anti-coagulent agent available. Progress in research was hampered because of the scarcity of leech saliva until a new technique was developed by by <PERSON> Rachel </PERSON> <PERSON> Galun </PERSON>, a research scientist in the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Parasitology </ORGANIZATION> at <ORGANIZATION> Hebrew </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. She prepared arginine, a solution of amino acid, and placed it over a membrane of dried calf intestine. She found that leeches took to the solution as an alternative to blood. After leeches drank their fill scientists squeezed them to force out the liquid, which also contained saliva, and the thirsty leeches went back for more. `` The technique gave us two advantanges,'' <PERSON> Rigbi </PERSON> said. `` We start with a much purer material and we can repeat the process several times.'' He found several small molecules that also contribute to the anti-hemostatic process, the researcher said. `` It seems that the leech has a battery of components which inhibit platelet aggregation by a variety of agents,'' he said. `` This is the lesson we are getting. It may also be a lesson for physicians that a certain balance of drugs is necessary in the treatment of patients suffering blood disorders.'' <PERSON> Rigbi </PERSON> said his team found another enzyme called eglin, which he described as `` an inhibitor of elastase, produced by white blood cells,'' and is trying to identify its chemical components to isolate them from the saliva and reproduce them as drugs. `` We have grounds to believe we will discover some unknown compounds,'' he said. The research has aroused commercial interest and <PERSON> Eldor </PERSON>, who is associated with <ORGANIZATION> Hadassah </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION>, is working on practical applications, <PERSON> Rigbi </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880411-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-11-88 2356EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Philby     04-11 0713</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Philby,0736</SECOND>
<HEAD>Arch-Traitor, Still Haunts Britain</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By MARCUS ELIASON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Each of the past four Sundays the ghost of treachery joined Britons at the breakfast table. <PERSON> Harold </PERSON> `` Kim'' <PERSON> Philby </PERSON>, the gentleman traitor who spied for the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, granted his first interview to a Western journalist since defecting to <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> in 1963 and it appeared in the Sunday Times. Critics say publication of the four-part interview in the Times, which has a circulation of 1.4 million, was a propaganda gift to the <ORGANIZATION> KGB </ORGANIZATION>. The Soviet secret police agency still employs <PERSON> Philby </PERSON>, now 76. For journalist <PERSON> Phillip </PERSON> <PERSON> Knightley </PERSON> the evening of Jan. 19, when he entered <PERSON> Philby </PERSON>'s apartment in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>, climaxed 20 years in which he secretly corresponded with <PERSON> Philby </PERSON> but the master spy repeatedly refused to see him. When he did agree to talk, <PERSON> Philby </PERSON> dropped no bombshells. But the myriad details reveal an English gentleman who despised his privileged background, espoused Soviet communism as a <ORGANIZATION> Cambridge </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> student in the 1930s and penetrated the highest levels of British intelligence in the <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION>'s service. Because of his high contacts in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Philby </PERSON> was able to betray the whole Western alliance. He sent many Western agents to their deaths and was even able to head off the defection of a <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> diplomat who threatened to expose him. The most controversial point in the interview is <PERSON> Philby </PERSON>'s contention that <LOCATION> British </LOCATION> intelligence let him defect rather than face an embarrassing public trial He told <PERSON> Knightley </PERSON> he suffered severe self-doubt after fleeing to <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> and began drinking heavily. `` Doubt is a terrible thing,'' he said. `` Had I done the right thing? You see, I never swallowed everything -LRB- about Soviet communism -RRB-. I never took it ALL in.'' <PERSON> Philby </PERSON> said he has found peace and a happy fourth marriage, to a <LOCATION> Russian </LOCATION> woman, feels at home in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, and believes today's <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> would be a foreign country to him. `` No faith? Come, come,'' he said. `` Only a fool would deny me my faith.'' He likes to keep in touch with British gossip, listens to the <ORGANIZATION> BBC </ORGANIZATION>, does the <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> London </ORGANIZATION> crossword and misses English mustard. Ever the English gentleman, he greeted <PERSON> Knightley </PERSON> at his door with a cheerful: `` Come on through, dear chap.'' `` I do n't like deceiving people, especially friends, and contrary to what some people believe I feel very badly about it,'' he said in the interview. `` But then, decent soldiers feel badly about the necessity of killing in wartime.'' The unmasking after <PERSON> Philby </PERSON> had been under suspicion for 12 years climaxed a nightmare episode for British intelligence. It began in 1951 with the defection of top spies <PERSON> Guy </PERSON> <PERSON> Burgess </PERSON> and <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> McLean </PERSON> and reverberated into the 1980s with the revelation that <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON> <PERSON> Blunt </PERSON>, another upper-class Englishman, had been unmasked as a traitor secretly and went unpunished. When <PERSON> Philby </PERSON> defected, Blunt was given immunity from prosecution in exchange for information. He later became art adviser to Queen <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> II </PERSON>. Blunt died in 1983 but the scandal continues to shake the intelligence establishment. There are allegations that the late Sir <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> Hollis </PERSON>, director of the MI5 intelligence service from 1956 to 1965, also worked for the KBG. Some commentators feel things have gone too far. `` These treacheries marked the end of a certain idea which the British upper classes once entertained of themselves. But all that is over now. Its legacy, unfortunately, is increased cynicism and incipient paranoia,'' <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON> <PERSON> Hartley </PERSON> wrote in The Sunday Telegraph. Others ridiculed <PERSON> Philby </PERSON>'s notion that he was allowed to defect. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Mates </PERSON>, a member of <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION> from the governing <ORGANIZATION> Conservative </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, told the <ORGANIZATION> Sunday </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> the defection caused much greater scandal than <PERSON> Philby </PERSON>'s arrest would have. <PERSON> Knightley </PERSON> came in for some snide remarks. <PERSON> Hartley </PERSON> urged his colleagues to forget the traitors and not make `` journalistic pilgrimages to <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>.'' The Observer said his story was more appropriate for <ORGANIZATION> Izvestia </ORGANIZATION>, the Soviet government daily, than a British newspaper. <PERSON> Tony </PERSON> <PERSON> Loynes </PERSON> of the media magazine <LOCATION> U.K. </LOCATION> Press Gazette, however, said <PERSON> Knightley </PERSON> had done `` the kind of thing every journalist dreams of.'' <PERSON> Knightley </PERSON> wrote: `` Why give publicity to a self-confessed traitor? Because unless we understand the motives and compulsions of <PERSON> Philby </PERSON> and his ilk, then we will have learned nothing from the affair.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880411-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-11-88 2358EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Hijack-Chronology     04-11 0422</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Hijack-Chronology,0429</SECOND>
<HEAD>Chronology of Events in Hijacking of Kuwait Airways Flight 422</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Hijack Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here is a chronology of events in the hijacking of <ORGANIZATION> Kuwait </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airways </ORGANIZATION> Flight 422: April 5 _ The <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> 747 with 112 people aboard, including three members of the <LOCATION> Kuwaiti </LOCATION> royal family, is hijacked on a flight to <LOCATION> Kuwait </LOCATION> from <LOCATION> Bangkok </LOCATION> and diverted to <LOCATION> Mashhad </LOCATION> in northeastern <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>. The Arab hijackers demand freedom for 17 pro-Iranian extremists jailed in <LOCATION> Kuwait </LOCATION> for their convictions in the bombings of the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and French embassies there in 1983. They threaten to blow up the plane if the demand is not met. <LOCATION> Kuwait </LOCATION> refuses. One passenger with heart condition is released. <LOCATION> Kuwait </LOCATION> asks <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> not to allow the plane to take off. April 6 _ <LOCATION> Kuwait </LOCATION> sends a team to <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> to negotiate with the hijackers but vows not to yield to their demands. The hijackers release 24 women passengers and call a doctor on board to treat passengers they describe as `` unwell.'' April 7 _ The hijackers release 32 more hostages and again threaten to blow up the plane if security forces try any move against it. The plane is refueled after hijackers shoot at airport security and threaten to force the plane to take off with fuel tanks near empty. April 8 _ The plane leaves <LOCATION> Mashhad </LOCATION> but is refused permission to land in <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Damascus </LOCATION>, despite pleas from the pilot who says the fuel tank is nearly empty. After seven hours in the air, the plane lands at <LOCATION> Larnaca </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Cyprus </LOCATION>. April 9 _ The hijackers kill a <LOCATION> Kuwaiti </LOCATION> security guard on the plane and toss his body to the tarmac after their demands for fuel are not met. The pilot says captives are being beaten. The <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION>'s deputy director in <LOCATION> Cyprus </LOCATION> and two <LOCATION> Cypriot </LOCATION> officials go to the plane and talk with the hijackers, who free another captive Sunday _ Negotiations with <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> officials continue. The hijackers threaten a `` slow and quiet massacre'' and say they'll force the pilot to take off and crash into the <LOCATION> Kuwaiti </LOCATION> royal palace if demands are not met. In <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>, the pro-Iranian Islamic Jihad terrorist group threatened to kill kidnapped foreign hostages if any attempt is made to storm the plane. Monday _ The hijackers kill a second captive, identified as a <LOCATION> Kuwaiti </LOCATION> security officer, and dump his body on the tarmac. A passenger tells airport officials via radio that the hijackers have threatented to shoot all of the passengers if the plane is not refueled.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880411-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-11-88 0012EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Canada-Campeau     04-11 0816</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Canada-Campeau,0842</SECOND>
<HEAD>Takeover Of Bloomingdale's Is Latest Canadian Foray Into U.S.</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</NOTE>
<NOTE>Eds: All dollar figures U.S.</NOTE>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Once the junior partner in U.S.-Canadian business relations, Canadian entrepreneurs are becoming more aggressive in investing in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. In fact, in the last 10 years, Canadian investment in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has grown faster than <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> investment in <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>. Here is a report on the situation.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>By JEFF BRADLEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>TORONTO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Retailing magnate <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Campeau </PERSON>'s $ 6.6 billion takeover of the <ORGANIZATION> Federated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Store </ORGANIZATION> empire topped a surge in Canadian investment south of the border. The <ORGANIZATION> Campeau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> deal last month was the largest Canadian takeover in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. For <ORGANIZATION> Campeau </ORGANIZATION>, who left his native <LOCATION> Sudbury </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ontario </LOCATION>, with an eighth grade education and retains a slight French-Canadian accent, it surpassed his $ 3.6 billion acquisition of <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York-based </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Allied </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Stores </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> in 1986. Canadian investment in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has encompassed prime real estate from <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Minneapolis </LOCATION>, railways, pulp and paper mills, oil wells, telecommunications and many other industries. Here are some examples: _ The <PERSON> Reichmann </PERSON> brothers of <LOCATION> Toronto </LOCATION> _ <PERSON> Paul </PERSON>, <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> and <PERSON> Ralph </PERSON> _ control 8 percent of <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION>'s office space, including the <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Financial </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> and <LOCATION> Battery </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Park </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, through their Olympic and <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Developments </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ltd. </ORGANIZATION> _ <ORGANIZATION> Northern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Telecom </ORGANIZATION>, a subsidiary of <ORGANIZATION> BCE </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, which includes <LOCATION> Bell </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>, is the second-largest telecommunications manufacturer in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> with 14 <ORGANIZATION> Nortel </ORGANIZATION> plants and about 23,000 American employees. _ <ORGANIZATION> Imasco </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ltd. </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Montreal </LOCATION> owns the <PERSON> Hardee </PERSON>'s fast-food chain and 830 <ORGANIZATION> Peoples </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Drug </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Stores </ORGANIZATION> in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>; <ORGANIZATION> Seagram </ORGANIZATION> recently bought Tropicana orange juice from <ORGANIZATION> Beatrice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foods </ORGANIZATION>; Canadians <PERSON> Ken </PERSON> <PERSON> Thomson </PERSON> and <PERSON> Conrad </PERSON> <PERSON> Black </PERSON> publish dozens of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> newspapers; and the forestry and paper empires of <ORGANIZATION> Noranda </ORGANIZATION> and <PERSON> MacMillan </PERSON> <PERSON> Bloedel </PERSON> extend across the border, as does the industrial might of <ORGANIZATION> Alcan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aluminium </ORGANIZATION>. <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> form the world's largest trading partnership, and a majority of the Fortune 500 companies long have operated above the 49th parallel. But until recently, <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> had been relegated to junior partner. As recently as 1975, direct Canadian investment in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> stood at just $ 5.4 billion. By the end of 1986, however, this had soared to $ 29 billion, and the Canadian stake is now closer to $ 40 billion, according to Canadian government statistics. The 1986 figure compares with $ 55 billion worth of direct <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> investment in <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>, and the gap is closing. `` Over the past 10 years, Canadian investment in the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> is growing faster than <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> investment in <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>,'' said business management professor <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Rudman </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Toronto </ORGANIZATION>, a specialist in the topic. He cited 20 percent annual growth in Canadian investment in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, compared with 7 percent growth in the other direction. By the early 1990s, the amounts will be equal, he predicted. `` What's happened is that in the past 20 years the <LOCATION> Canadian </LOCATION> economy has matured, and our business sector has become world class.'' <PERSON> Rudman </PERSON> said 70 percent of Canada-U.S. trade is conducted by multinationals _ 22 based in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and 21 in <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> _ and 30 percent of the volume is from <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Motors </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Chrysler </ORGANIZATION>, and their Canadian subsidiaries. Meanwhile, <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>'s overall share of investment in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> actually has declined from 20 percent to 8 percent in the past 12 years, <PERSON> Rudman </PERSON> said, because Europeans and Japanese have been pouring dollar holdings back into <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> businesses. Many of those foreign acquisitions have alarmed Americans, but the <LOCATION> Canadian </LOCATION> invasion has met little opposition. `` Canadian firms blend in so well they cause little hostility,'' said <PERSON> Rudman </PERSON>. Flushed with success at netting <PERSON> Federated </PERSON> _ more than 650 stores in 15 chains, including the tony <ORGANIZATION> Bloomingdale </ORGANIZATION>'s _ <ORGANIZATION> Campeau </ORGANIZATION> told a news conference in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>: `` I consider myself a North American. What I like about the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> is a more wide-open private enterprise system where there is less interference by government than there is in <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>.'' That will remain the case for Canadians under a bilateral Free Trade Agreement to take effect next January if ratified by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION>. Canadian investors will enjoy unfettered access in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, but any <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> investment over $ 150 million will come in for scrutiny by <LOCATION> Ottawa </LOCATION>. Other attractions for Canadian investors include a market 10 times bigger and lower taxes. <ORGANIZATION> Campeau </ORGANIZATION>, 63, the youngest of seven children, runs his real estate and retailing empire from offices in <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Toronto </LOCATION>. Father of six, he lives in <LOCATION> Toronto </LOCATION> with his second wife in a 11,000-square foot mansion with an Olympic-sized swimming pool. A personal friend of former Premier <PERSON> Pierre </PERSON> <PERSON> Trudeau </PERSON>, a fellow French-Canadian, <ORGANIZATION> Campeau </ORGANIZATION> became the federal government's biggest landlord after building 40 percent of the government-occupied office space in <LOCATION> Ottawa </LOCATION>. `` He got too big for <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>,'' said analyst <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Tigert </PERSON> of investment brokers <ORGANIZATION> Burns </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fry </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ltd </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880411-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-11-88 0017EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-OPEC     04-11 0745</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-OPEC,0767</SECOND>
<HEAD>OPEC Hopes Courting Competitors Will Help Keep Prices Up</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</NOTE>
<HEAD>AP News Analysis</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT BURNS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>VIENNA, Austria (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 In deciding to pursue a new courtship with its oil-producing competitors, <ORGANIZATION> OPEC </ORGANIZATION> is betting that such nations as <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Norway </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> are ready for a historic shift in global oil relations. At stake is the future direction of oil prices, which have fallen steadily this year, partly due to increases in supply from non-OPEC nations. Leaders of the <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Petroleum </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Exporting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Countries </ORGANIZATION> this week are inviting government representatives from at least seven independent oil-producing nations to meet with five <ORGANIZATION> OPEC </ORGANIZATION> oil ministers in <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION>, where <ORGANIZATION> OPEC </ORGANIZATION> keeps its headquarters, on April 23. All 13 <ORGANIZATION> OPEC </ORGANIZATION> members are to meet two days later. The invitation, announced by a committee of five <ORGANIZATION> OPEC </ORGANIZATION> oil ministers on Saturday, is a clear acknowledgement by the cartel that it alone no longer can exert enough control over oil supplies to keep prices up. <ORGANIZATION> OPEC </ORGANIZATION>'s president, <PERSON> Rilwanu </PERSON> <PERSON> Lukman </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Nigeria </LOCATION>, said the cartel simply wanted to discuss `` methods of cooperation'' with non-OPEC producers. But the meeting probably will give rise to talks on oil production cuts intended to boost prices. <ORGANIZATION> OPEC </ORGANIZATION> has an official target price for its oil of $ 18 a barrel, but little, if any, of its exports is fetching more than $ 15 a barrel. The loose association of oil-producing states has in past years been unable to prevent many of its own members from underselling. For much of the past six years, <ORGANIZATION> OPEC </ORGANIZATION> has responded to declining prices and a buildup of surplus by cutting its production. Although this sometimes has provided a temporary boost to the market, <ORGANIZATION> OPEC </ORGANIZATION> over time has suffered an erosion both of prices and exports. The lower <ORGANIZATION> OPEC </ORGANIZATION>'s output has fallen, the less influence it has carried in the market and the more its poorer members, such as <LOCATION> Nigeria </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Indonesia </LOCATION>, have suffered. Now the cartel is hoping that the prospect of further decline in prices this year will move non-OPEC oil producers to cooperate by sharing the financial burden of restraining oil supplies. Oil production by non-OPEC nations has risen to 28 million barrels a day from 22 million a day in 1979. In that time, <ORGANIZATION> OPEC </ORGANIZATION>'s output has tumbled from about 31 million barrels daily to 17.5 million <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> has indicated it wants to improve cooperation in restraining oil supplies, but it is unclear how many other independent producers _ particularly the larger ones _ want to cut a deal with <ORGANIZATION> OPEC </ORGANIZATION>. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, the world's second-largest oil producer, is virtually certain to avoid any sort of cooperation with <ORGANIZATION> OPEC </ORGANIZATION>, as is <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>, whose <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sea </LOCATION> oil makes it a major factor in the market. The world's No. 1 producer, the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, has shown little inclination to act in concert with <ORGANIZATION> OPEC </ORGANIZATION>. Those that have expressed interest recently _ including <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Malaysia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Brunei </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Oman </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION> _ are mostly small producers with little room to reduce their production. Two years ago, <ORGANIZATION> OPEC </ORGANIZATION> held meetings with representatives of <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION> and several other smaller producers in a vain attempt to agree on joint production cuts. <ORGANIZATION> OPEC </ORGANIZATION> was told that it must reduce its output first before the independents would consider a response in kind. Other independent producers include <LOCATION> Norway </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>. The problem for <ORGANIZATION> OPEC </ORGANIZATION> then and now is that some of its members _ notably cartel leader <LOCATION> Saudi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arabia </LOCATION> _ simply do not want to continue the tactic of reducing production without firm pledges from producers outside <ORGANIZATION> OPEC </ORGANIZATION>. The Saudis, backed by their allies on the <LOCATION> Arabian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Peninsula </LOCATION>, think it's more important to preserve their current share of world oil exports than to defend a fixed oil price most <ORGANIZATION> OPEC </ORGANIZATION> members ignore anyway. Even so, <ORGANIZATION> OPEC </ORGANIZATION> has signaled that it is ready to make a fresh attempt to change global oil relations by drawing independent producers into an agreement. <ORGANIZATION> OPEC </ORGANIZATION> President <PERSON> Lukman </PERSON> told reporters he saw an important difference between the current situation and that of two years ago. `` The major difference is that non-OPEC have, on their own, realized the need to cooperate ... and they have made approaches voluntarily ... to get together with us,'' he said. In this industry of maverick nations, however, many obstacles remain for an internally divided <ORGANIZATION> OPEC </ORGANIZATION> trying to bridge differences with independents.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Burns </PERSON> has covered <ORGANIZATION> OPEC </ORGANIZATION> for <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> for six years.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880411-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-11-88 2352EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-Oscars-List 3rdLd-Writethru a07767 04-11 0212</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Oscars-List, 3rd Ld - Writethru, a07767,0224</SECOND>
<HEAD>Partial List of 60th Academy Award Winners.</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: UPDATES with next three awards.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here is a partial list of Oscar winners at Monday night's 60th annual Academy Awards ceremony. 1. VISUAL EFFECTS: `` Innerspace,'' <PERSON> Dennis </PERSON> <PERSON> Muren </PERSON>, <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> George </PERSON>, <PERSON> Harley </PERSON> <PERSON> Jessup </PERSON> and <PERSON> Kenneth </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>. 2. SUPPORTING ACTRESS: <PERSON> Olympia </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, `` Moonstruck.'' 3. ART DIRECTION: `` The Last Emperor,'' <PERSON> Ferdinando </PERSON> <PERSON> Scarfiotti </PERSON>; Set Direction, <PERSON> Bruno </PERSON> <PERSON> Cesari </PERSON>. 4. CINEMATOGRAPHY: `` The Last Emperor,'' <PERSON> Vittorio </PERSON> <PERSON> Storaro </PERSON>. 5. ANIMATED SHORT FILM: `` The Man Who Planted Trees,'' <PERSON> Frederic </PERSON> <PERSON> Back </PERSON>. 6. DOCUMENTARY SHORT SUBJECT: `` Young at Heart,'' <PERSON> Sue </PERSON> <PERSON> Marx </PERSON> and <PERSON> Pamela </PERSON> Conn. 7. DOCUMENTARY FEATURE: `` The Ten-Year Lunch: The Wit and Legend of the Algonquin Round Table,'' <PERSON> Aviva </PERSON> <PERSON> Slesin </PERSON>. 8. SOUND: `` The Last Emperor,'' <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Rowe </PERSON> and <PERSON> Ivan </PERSON> <PERSON> Sharrock </PERSON>. 9. SUPPORTING ACTOR: <PERSON> Sean </PERSON> <PERSON> Connery </PERSON>, `` The Untouchables.'' 10. FILM EDITING: `` The Last Emperor,'' <PERSON> Gabriella </PERSON> <PERSON> Cristiani </PERSON>. 11. ORIGINAL SONG: `` -LRB- I've Had -RRB- The Time of My Life,'' `` Dirty Dancing;'' music by <PERSON> Franke </PERSON> <PERSON> Previte </PERSON>, <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> DeNicola </PERSON> and <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Markowitz </PERSON>; lyric by <PERSON> Franke </PERSON> <PERSON> Previte </PERSON>. 12. ORIGINAL SCORE: `` The Last Emperor,'' <PERSON> Ryuichi </PERSON> <PERSON> Sakamoto </PERSON>, <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Byrne </PERSON> and Cong Su. 13. ACTOR: <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON>, `` Wall Street.'' Announced in advance: <PERSON> IRVING </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> THALBERG </PERSON>: Director <PERSON> Billy </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilder </PERSON>. SPECIAL ACHIEVEMENT: Sound effects editing team on `` Robocop.'' <PERSON> GORDON </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> SAWYER </PERSON>: Movie sound specialist <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> Hynes </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880411-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-11-88 2354EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>b a AM-Oscars 9thLd a0786 04-11 0611</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Oscars, 9th Ld, a0786,0623</SECOND>
<HEAD>URGENT</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: ``Emperor'' up to 7 awards including director, costumes; also
gives live action short film winner, rearranges to dash.</NOTE>
<HEAD>LaserPhotos LA10, LAA1,2, Others Upcoming</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BOB THOMAS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON> won the Oscar as best actor Monday night for his role as a ruthless inside trader in `` Wall Street,'' while `` The Last Emperor,'' a tragic epic of modern <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, captured seven awards, including one for Italian director <PERSON> Bernardo </PERSON> <PERSON> Bertolucci </PERSON>. Best supporting performers at the 60th annual Academy Awards were <PERSON> Olympia </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, as the outspoken Italian mother with a wayward husband in `` Moonstruck,'' and <PERSON> Sean </PERSON> <PERSON> Connery </PERSON>, as the hard-fisted, incorruptible <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> beat cop in `` The Untouchables.'' <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON>, who also starred in last year's box-office smash `` Fatal Attraction,'' thanked his father, actor <PERSON> Kirk </PERSON> <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON>, for helping `` a son step out of his father's shadow.'' <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON>' award was presented by <PERSON> Marlee </PERSON> <PERSON> Matlin </PERSON>, a deaf actress who won last year's Oscar. She has been taking speech lessons, and after signing her opening remarks she named all the nominees to prolonged cheers. `` Emperor'' had the most nominations with nine from the <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Motion </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Picture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Arts </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sciences </ORGANIZATION>, and picked up awards for direction, costumes, original score, art direction, cinematography, sound and editing. The sweeping story of <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s last imperial ruler had been widely favored to win the most honors, including best picture. `` OK, <PERSON> Michael </PERSON>, let's go!'' a jubilant Miss <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> whooped after accepting the gold statuette. The reference was to her cousin, <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, who is seeking the Democratic nomination for president. <PERSON> Connery </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION>'s original <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Bond </PERSON>, addressed his acceptance to the audience, his friends `` and a few enemies'' and put in a fervent plea for an end to the strike by movie and TV writers, which has stalled production and disrupted preparations for the Oscar show. The best original movie song of 1987 was `` The Time of My Life'' from `` Dirty Dancing.'' The actress category sparked the most interest this year, with many critics picking <PERSON> Cher </PERSON> for her role as a widow who discovers love in `` Moonstruck.'' <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON> <PERSON> Close </PERSON> was a strong contender, as was <PERSON> Sally </PERSON> <PERSON> Kirkland </PERSON>, as the faded Czech actress in `` <PERSON> Anna </PERSON>.'' Also nominated were <PERSON> Holly </PERSON> <PERSON> Hunter </PERSON> for `` Broadcast News'' and two-time winner <PERSON> Meryl </PERSON> <PERSON> Streep </PERSON> for `` Ironweed.'' The first prize of the night, for best visual effects, went to `` Innerspace,'' a <PERSON> Steven </PERSON> <PERSON> Spielberg-produced </PERSON> fantasy about a test pilot reduced to microscopic size and accidentally injected into the body of a grocery clerk. The award for best animated short film went to `` The Man Who Planted Trees.'' `` Young at Heart'' was best documentary short subject and `` The Ten-Year Lunch: The Wit and Wisdom of the Algonquin Roundtable'' was best documentary feature. Best live action short film was `` Ray's Male Heterosexual Dance Hall.'' More than 1,000 movie fans had packed bleachers hours in advance to cheer celebrities arriving at the Shrine Auditorium for the ceremonies, where much of the excitement focused on whether <PERSON> Cher </PERSON> would triumph as best actress. Many in the crowd wore shorts and T-shirts, ready for temperatures that rose into the 90s. But the most visible of the lot were seven 30ish women with teased blond hair. They carried rubber daggers and wore long white dresses with `` Fatal Attraction'' printed on the chest in red. One had come from <LOCATION> Maui </LOCATION>, another from <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION>. `` We're pulling for <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON> <PERSON> Close </PERSON> to win,'' one of the women said in referring to the actress's nomination for her portrayal of the vengeful spurned lover in that movie. Comedian <PERSON> Chevy </PERSON> <PERSON> Chase </PERSON> was host for the festivities, carried on live national television by <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> and also broadcast widely overseas.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>Pickup at dash</HEAD>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880411-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-11-88 0012EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Panama-Squatters     04-11 0839</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Panama-Squatters,0863</SECOND>
<HEAD>The Poor, Battered By Panama's Crisis, Seize Land</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Panama, Bjt</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DOUGLAS GRANT MINE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PANAMA CITY, Panama (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Nearly 600 poor families made poorer by <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s political and economic crisis have taken over a stretch of seaside landfill and covered it with precarious shacks. The shanty town, a half mile from the ruins of the colonial city sacked and burned by pirate <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> Morgan </PERSON> in 1671, has swollen rapidly since 60 families `` invaded'' the privately-owned land before dawn on March 25. Their takeover is a headache for the regime of Gen. <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> and a dramatic example of the devastation the nation's crisis has wrought on the poor, most of whom lived hand-to-mouth even in the best of times. <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>, as head of the 15,000-member <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forces </ORGANIZATION>, is the power behind the civilian government. After <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> was indicted on drug trafficking charges in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> imposed economic sanctions on <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>, hoping its action and months of civil unrest would oust <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>. Although the sanctions have bankrupted the nation's economy, <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> remains in power. `` We were obliged by necessity to act,'' said <PERSON> Marcelino </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Gracia </PERSON>, one of five organizers of the takeover. Each of the squatter familes has staked out a 10-by-15 yard plot with rope, wire, ribbon or knotted strips of cloth. <PERSON> De </PERSON> <PERSON> Gracia </PERSON>, a 29-year-old unemployed tire salesman, lives with his wife <PERSON> Yadilia </PERSON> and their two infant children in a shanty made of mangrove poles, cardboard, a shower curtain, palm fronds and a sheet of corrugated zinc. It, like hundreds of other shacks spread over the seized 30 acres, is built on reclaimed land that until two years ago was a garbage dump. The indigent community is bordered by a foul-smelling tidewater tributary on which float bloated fish poisoned by raw sewage. Part of the camp was carved out of an auto graveyard. The rusted bodies and tattered interiors provide building materials, furnishings and a tetanus trap for the approximately 3,000 children living there. The dump has fostered a local population of raccoons, which have augmented the squatters' diet. Skins were tacked on the walls of several shacks. <PERSON> De </PERSON> <PERSON> Gracia </PERSON> said camp dwellers dig clams on the edge of their settlement and catch lizards and armadillos as well as the ring-tailed mammals. `` Nothing gets out of here alive,'' he said. `` Whack, and into the pot.'' <PERSON> De </PERSON> <PERSON> Gracia </PERSON> said a census shows about 570 families comprising almost 4,000 people lived in the camp as of April 4. They draw water from seven faucets along a dirt road bordering the camp, which sits off <LOCATION> Avenida </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Cincuentenario </LOCATION> about five miles east of downtown. <PERSON> Elma </PERSON> <PERSON> Sierra </PERSON>, <PERSON> Olivia </PERSON> <PERSON> Ramos </PERSON> and <PERSON> Anastasia </PERSON> <PERSON> Vega </PERSON> stood around a smoky campfire in front of Ms. <PERSON> Sierra </PERSON>'s shack. <PERSON> Rice </PERSON> boiled in a blackened pot. `` Arroz ` pelado,''' -LRB- ` bald' rice -RRB-, she said disparagingly, using the slang for the grain unaccompanied by beans or meat. `` We do n't know what beans look like any more. This rice was donated by a nearby church. The three women, all on their own, have 11 children among them. They said many recent arrivals are single mothers. Ms. <PERSON> Ramos </PERSON> admitted to trying to steal a loaf of bread that morning from a nearby grocery, many of which are owned by immigrant Asians. `` The Chinaman almost took my head off,'' she said, exhibiting fingernail scratches streaking her neck. `` I know it's wrong, but my kids have to eat.'' Almost six weeks into the gravest political and economic crisis in Panamanian history, the women, like most others in the camp, are desperate. They have virtually no money, have been kicked out of the rooms they previously rented and see no prospects that things will soon improve enough to allow them to return to their menial or domestic jobs. They all cursed <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>. Told that a newspaper supportive of the regime had dubbed the settlement `` Not One Step Backward'' _ <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>'s slogan in his battle with the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> _ they all but spat their disgust. The land is owned by the <PERSON> Chanis </PERSON> family, a clan of doctors and statesmen prominent for several generations. They do not intend to sit by while it is requisitioned by the masses. `` The seizure took us by surprise,'' said Dr. <PERSON> Rolando </PERSON> <PERSON> Chanis </PERSON>. `` We await adequate action by authorities to correct the situation.'' <PERSON> De </PERSON> <PERSON> Gracia </PERSON>, whose family had been sharing his mother-in-law's two-room apartment with seven others, said he organized the takeover along with four friends with whom he regularly played volleyball `` In the first days, with just 60 families, we feared a move to dislodge us,'' he said. `` But the news circulated fast, and with the country the way it is, people poured in. It is another thing to disloge 570 families. They'd have to think twice about trying that.'' Any move against the squatters on behalf of the landowners would contradict official propaganda. <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>'s regime portrays the crisis as a confrontation between good, underpriveleged and nationalistic Panamanians and bad, wealthy `` sell-outs'' conspiring with <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> to subjugate the isthmus.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880411-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-11-88 0050EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-LiberaceAuction     04-11 0428</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Liberace Auction,0440</SECOND>
<HEAD>Liberace's License Fetches $4,150 In Second Day of Auction</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Liberace </PERSON>'s <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> driver's license, expected to garner no more than $ 200, fetched $ 4,150 in the second day of bidding for items from the late pianist's five posh homes. `` It was probably the most personal item we sold,'' said <PERSON> Jon </PERSON> <PERSON> King </PERSON>, a vice president at <ORGANIZATION> Butterfield </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; Butterfield auction house. The amount bid includes the auctioneer's 10 percent commission. The person who bid for the license Sunday was a <ORGANIZATION> Liberace </ORGANIZATION> fan who wanted to remain anonymous, <PERSON> King </PERSON> said. `` There was a tremendous amount of interest in the license because of the picture, because of his signature and because of the very personal nature of it,'' <PERSON> King </PERSON> said. `` Also because it was something that he daily used.'' About 2,500 people were present at the start of bidding Sunday. Total transactions for the day reached approximately $ 550,000, exceeding the $ 445,300 auctioneers expected. Saturday's transactions hit $ 660,045, higher than the projected $ 525,650 The auction ends Tuesday. King estimated that 25 percent of the crowd actually bid on items, which were bringing in four to five times their estimated value. `` And the flashier the clothing, the higher the bidding,'' <PERSON> King </PERSON> said. A brown-and-white spotted cowhide evening jacket with brown trousers and matching cowhide shoes was expected to fetch up to $ 750 but was purchased for $ 3,125 by a buyer who wished to remain anonymous, <PERSON> King </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Christie </PERSON>'s, the international auction house, organized the sale of 2,365 <ORGANIZATION> Liberace </ORGANIZATION> items with <ORGANIZATION> Butterfield </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; Butterfield for the sale. Among the entertainer's treasures on display at the <ORGANIZATION> Los </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Angeles </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Convention </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> was a <PERSON> Baldwin </PERSON> grand piano, almost every surface of the instrument covered with mirrored squares, going for $ 46,750 to a <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> dealer. <PERSON> Arnold </PERSON> and <PERSON> Leslie </PERSON> <PERSON> Duke </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION>, bought the first item Saturday, a pendant depicting <PERSON> Liberace </PERSON>'s profile in sculpted silver against a blue lapis lazuli background, within a silver frame. It had been estimated to sell for up to $ 100. The <PERSON> Dukes </PERSON>, who own a gem and jewelry show that tours the country, paid $ 3,850. `` He was a master showman,'' <PERSON> Arnold </PERSON> <PERSON> Duke </PERSON> said. `` Not only were we fans, but there was nobody else like him.'' While many were bidders who purchased items as investments, many were fans who had come to pay their respects to Wladziu -LRB- Walter -RRB- <PERSON> Valentino </PERSON> <PERSON> Liberace </PERSON>, who died Feb. 4, 1987, of complications of AIDS. He was 67. Proceeds of the auction will go to the non-profit <ORGANIZATION> Liberace </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION> for the Performing and Creative Arts, which provides scholarships at 28 schools and colleges nationwide.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880411-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-11-88 0053EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-MurderArrest     04-11 0202</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Murder Arrest,0209</SECOND>
<HEAD>Man Arrested in Brooklyn On Maryland Murder Charges</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A 28-year-old man wanted for five murders in <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION> has been arrested after being spotted on a television show on fugitives. <PERSON> Carl </PERSON> <PERSON> Dunstrum </PERSON> was arrested late Saturday using warrant murders issued by Prince <PERSON> George </PERSON>'s County in <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION>, said Sgt. <PERSON> Maurice </PERSON> <PERSON> Howard </PERSON>, a department spokesman. In addition to the five killings for which he was sought in <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Dunstrum </PERSON> was being questioned by <LOCATION> Brooklyn </LOCATION> detectives in connection with a sixth killing in that borough, a department spokeswoman, Sgt. <PERSON> Diane </PERSON> <PERSON> Kubler </PERSON>, said Sunday. The <LOCATION> Brooklyn </LOCATION> victim was <PERSON> Patrick </PERSON> <PERSON> Ford </PERSON>, 17, who was found shot once in the head on Nov. 26, <PERSON> Kubler </PERSON> said. About 30 police raided the basement apartment where <PERSON> Dunstrum </PERSON> was staying Saturday evening. <PERSON> Dunstrum </PERSON> was recently featured on the Fox network television show `` <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s Most Wanted,'' and the show helped lead to his arrest, <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> said. He was one of three New Yorkers wanted in the execution-style slayings of of four men and a woman Jan. 22 at an apartment complex in <LOCATION> Landover </LOCATION>, Md. Police at the time said the slayings appeared to be drug related. One woman shot in the neck survived the attack.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880411-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-11-88 0054EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-CoalTheater     04-11 0502</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Coal Theater,0519</SECOND>
<HEAD>Theater Built By Coal Miners Opens As Fine Arts School</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PAUL DE LA GARZA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>COLLINSVILLE, Ill. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 When this old mining town was booming with coal, men put aside their picks to construct a theater. Today, the miners are few but the structure still stands _ now as a school of performing arts. And as a proper salute to the people who worked underground in <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Illinois </ORGANIZATION>, organizers of the school have dedicated it to a famous coal miner's daughter, country singer <PERSON> Loretta </PERSON> <PERSON> Lynn </PERSON>. `` We want to help promote local talent,'' said artistic director <PERSON> Ilene </PERSON> <PERSON> Farrell </PERSON>. `` We want to benefit the community. That's what we're here for, to benefit everyone in the arts.'' The three-story building, named the Miners Live Theater and completed in 1918 by members of <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Workers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Local </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> 264 </ORGANIZATION>, was used for labor meetings and vaudeville shows. The theater's past is intertwined with the region's coal-mining history. According to literature about the building, the first mine in this town of 20,000 residents, 15 miles east of <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Louis </LOCATION>, was established in 1857. The industry led to the town's growth `` and by 1886 a man could walk underground through connecting tunnels between the mines from one edge of the city limits to the other,'' literature says. `` Mining and <LOCATION> Collinsville </LOCATION> were almost synonymous terms.'' The coal-mining industry slowly started to wane, however, and in 1969, Miners Live was sold to a private company, which turned it into a movie house. Two years ago, <ORGANIZATION> Bloomer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Amusement </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> closed the 700-seat theater and it sat idle until February when <PERSON> Jean </PERSON> <PERSON> Spurlock </PERSON> reopened it and decided to bring in live acts and launch a performing arts school and production company. The building still needs plenty of renovation. The seats have red strands of tape covering cracked vinyl upholstery. A walk up the stairs to the balcony shows walls with peeling paint. Elevated box seats flank each side of the stage and an orchestra pit is located in front. By starting the school and hiring big-name entertainers to perform at the site, Ms. <PERSON> Farrell </PERSON> believes Miners Live will gain recognition. `` My gut feeling is that it's doing well already, that the sky's the limit,'' she said Ms. <PERSON> Farrell </PERSON> said the fine arts school will feature instruction in dance, theater, modeling, singing, music, and playwriting. She has assembled a 25-member staff. So far, 50 students have signed up and classes could start this month at the <ORGANIZATION> Loretta </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lynn </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Artistic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Art </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION>, she said. `` It's going to be a launching pad for some professional careers _ hopefully,'' Ms. <PERSON> Farrell </PERSON> said. The town is glad to see the doors reopen. Ms. <PERSON> Lynn </PERSON> was on hand April 1 for dedication ceremonies. `` It was part of <LOCATION> Collinsville </LOCATION> culture for so long,'' Ms. <PERSON> Spurlock </PERSON> said. `` Most people think they have to go to <LOCATION> Las </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vegas </LOCATION>, or <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> or <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>. But like I said, there's nothing in the <LOCATION> Midwest </LOCATION> to compare with what's gon na' be happening here.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880411-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-11-88 0030EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Britain-Ties Bjt   04-11 0569</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Britain-Ties, Bjt,0585</SECOND>
<HEAD>Tiespeak: The Way To A Man's Psyche</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LESLIE SHEPHERD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Clothes may make the man, but his tie can reveal his innermost secrets. The color, pattern and style of a man's necktie all provide clues to his personality and lifestyle, says the Guild of British Tiemakers, representing 30 manufacturers of `` the British tie,'' that sartorial symbol of the Old Boy Network. `` As eyes are reputedly the mirrors of the soul, so ties are the talisman of the image, a statement by the wearer of their personality and individuality, an indication of their temperament and mood, a symbol of the social set in which he does or wants to belong, a guide to how the wearer sees himself or would like others to see him,'' according to the guild's survey. To help tie wearers and watchers interpret some of the subtle messages, the guild has issued a guide to `` tiespeak.'' `` If you want to come across as a strong, confident extrovert person with strong opinions, choose a brilliantly colored tie or one with an exaggerated pattern or motif,'' it says. `` A man who wears a tie in a plain light color runs the danger of being a professional Mr. <PERSON> Nice </PERSON>, someone who likes to amuse and entertain, an arranger of matters rather than a doer.'' The `` more glowing'' the color of a tie, the more money-motivated the wearer is likely to be, the guide says. A plain dark tie, on the other hand, indicates a secretive man who keeps more than his tie close to his chest. The guide says a tie with light and dark stripes of equal width is the mark of a fence-sitter. Wide, light stripes on a dark background suggest the wearer thinks the best of people and accepts them at face value, while pessimists generally go for wide, dark stripes on a light background. Multicolored, multiwidth stripes indicate someone who'd love to do something daring _ if only he dared. A striped tie also can blurt out which side of the <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ocean </LOCATION> a man hails from. American tie stripes run from the right shoulder down toward the left, the opposite of those on a European tie. A tie with dark spots on a light background indicates `` a wheeler-dealer,'' while light spots on a dark background suggest `` a sheep in wolf's clothing,'' the guide says. `` Small, neat geometric patterns are taken to indicate a planner, a man who likes to create order out of chaos, probably a good administrator,'' it says. A small paisley pattern suggests an upholder of tradition, while a large paisly print suggests a hedger of bets. Ties give away other secrets. In <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>, a man's personal history can be traced through the ties in his closet, revealing his school, club and military background. Every British school has its own design, usually striped with the school colors, which every schoolboy wears as part of his uniform. Upon graduation he moves up to an `` Old School Tie,'' identifying his alma mater. He also may collect a regimental tie, with symbolic colors and crests. The colors of the <ORGANIZATION> Royal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Military </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION>'s tie, for example, represent the ingredients of gunpowder _ yellow for sulphur, blue for saltpeter and black for carbon. The <ORGANIZATION> Royal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tank </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corps </ORGANIZATION> tie represents the brown mud, red blood and green fields of <LOCATION> Flanders </LOCATION>, the World War I battlefield.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880411-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-11-88 0108EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     04-11 0913</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0950</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in the News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>OTTAWA, Kan. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Country singer <PERSON> Johnny </PERSON> <PERSON> Cash </PERSON> completed a three-city tour in <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> that had been delayed last month because of bronchial problems, and says he's feeling fine. `` I believe they're all cleared up. I feel better than I have felt in a long time,'' Cash said. Cash's voice was resonant Saturday night in two sold-out performances at the <ORGANIZATION> Ottawa </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Municipal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Auditorium </ORGANIZATION>, which followed concerts Thursday in <LOCATION> Emporia </LOCATION> and Friday in Independence. Cash will rest for about 10 days before traveling to <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> to perform. `` A reporter for the <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mirror </ORGANIZATION> said the <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sun </ORGANIZATION> headline said, ` <PERSON> Johnny </PERSON> <PERSON> Cash </PERSON> will never sing again,''' joked Cash, who spent 10 days recovering in a hospital in <LOCATION> Palm </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Springs </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>. Cash, 56, who has been performing more than 30 years, said he plans to keep up his pace of about 100 concerts of a year `` I really enjoy it,'' he said. `` As long as people come to hear us, I'm going to be out there.''
</TEXT>
<NOTE>Eds: A version of the following moved on sports wires.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>FORT WORTH, Texas (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Dallas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cowboys </ORGANIZATION> running back <PERSON> Herschel </PERSON> <PERSON> Walker </PERSON> said tackling dance moves is tricker than dodging linebackers, but his ballet debut was an unqualified success. About 1,300 people attended the season finale of the Fort Worth Ballet's `` story series'' _ well above the usual numbers for a Sunday afternoon performance _ to see the Heisman Trophy winner perform. The 223-pound <PERSON> Walker </PERSON> received a warm reception for his part in `` Webern Pieces,'' a modern ballet performed with principal dancers <PERSON> Maria </PERSON> <PERSON> Terezia </PERSON> <PERSON> Balogh </PERSON> and <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Malbrough </PERSON>. `` When you play football you have a helmet to hide behind and nobody can see your eyes,'' <PERSON> Walker </PERSON> said. `` But it's a lot different out there on the stage. In football, you can improvise if you make a mistake, but if you do it here everyone knows it.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Pop singer <PERSON> Engelbert </PERSON> <PERSON> Humperdinck </PERSON> said in an interview published today that his career almost ended last year when he developed asthma. `` I tried singing with it and I'd be in a state of collapse _ gasping for breath,'' he was quoted as telling Woman Magazine. `` I really thought my career was over. I used to throw up because I could n't catch my breath.'' But the 51-year-old singer, who has his own show in <LOCATION> Las </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vegas </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Nev. </LOCATION>, said a course of acupuncture cured him and set him back on the road with a new album and a British tour that starts this month. <PERSON> Humperdinck </PERSON> was quoted as saying he was dealing with `` a few'' lawsuits at the moment _ one price of success in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>. `` People find it an easy thing just to sue you,'' he was quoted as saying. `` Lawyers do it on a percentage of the ` winnings.' They are ambulance chasers over there. `` That's the way they make their money _ off people who are successful, which is absolutely disgusting.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NASHVILLE, Tenn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Folk singer <PERSON> Raffi </PERSON> says he refuses to capitalize on the 12-year success of his self-produced album of children's music by endorsing toys and other kiddie products. `` I just believe that the music is important in and of itself. I do n't want its value to be diminished by doing commercial things that have nothing to do with music,'' <PERSON> Raffi </PERSON> said in an interview published Sunday in The Tennessean. `` Especially with children I have to be careful, because these children feel strongly about me and look up to me and it's so easy to exploit them in terms of what they want to be,'' he said. The former <LOCATION> Toronto </LOCATION> coffeehouse singer's 1976 `` Singable Songs for the Very Young'' made him a favorite with the Sesame Street set. He's best known for such tunes as `` Bathtime,'' `` Shake Your Sillies Out'' and `` Rise and Shine.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>CAMBRIDGE, Mass. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Good day care is expensive for working parents, admits baby guru Dr. <PERSON> Benjamin </PERSON> <PERSON> Spock </PERSON>, and he says government and industry are lagging in subsidizing child-care programs. `` There's no reason that the richest country should n't spend money -LRB- on day care -RRB- when they spend trillions of dollars on nuclear arms,'' <PERSON> Spock </PERSON> said at a forum Saturday at <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Graduate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Design </ORGANIZATION> <PERSON> Spock </PERSON>, 84, who wrote his first book about child care in the 1940s, said, `` I still emphasize the child's formative years, but I ca n't stop the tidal wave of women going to work. `` But there are things to mitigate it, to make it work out less harmful,'' he said, suggesting flexible hours and shorter work days as possible ways for parents to spend more time with their children.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>ST. PAUL, Minn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Polar explorer <PERSON> Will </PERSON> <PERSON> Steger </PERSON> and his dogsled team greeted well-wishers at a farewell picnic as he and five other adventurers prepared to begin a 2,000-mile south-to-north traverse of <LOCATION> Greenland </LOCATION> this week. <PERSON> Steger </PERSON>, 43, of Ely, is the wilderness guide who in 1986 led the first unsupported dogsled assault to the North Pole. The <LOCATION> Greenland </LOCATION> crossing, expected to take two months, will serve as a test run for his seven-month International Trans-Antarctica Expedition scheduled for August 1989. That journey will be an unprecedented 5,000-mile dogsled traverse across the width of the continent. `` <LOCATION> Greenland </LOCATION> is almost identical to the ice cap we'll have in <LOCATION> Antarctica </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Steger </PERSON> said Sunday. `` For that reason, it's perfect training.'' <PERSON> Steger </PERSON>, his crew and 32 sled dogs will fly Wednesday by cargo plane from <LOCATION> Ottawa </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>, for <LOCATION> Narssarssuag </LOCATION>, in southern <LOCATION> Greenland </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880411-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-11-88 0109EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Oscars-List     04-11 0769</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Oscars-List,0797</SECOND>
<HEAD>List of Oscar Nominees In Presentation Order</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Oscars</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here is a complete list of nominees in the order of presentation at tonight's 60th annual Academy Awards. 1. VISUAL EFFECTS: <PERSON> Dennis </PERSON> <PERSON> Muren </PERSON>, <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> George </PERSON>, <PERSON> Harley </PERSON> <PERSON> Jessup </PERSON> and <PERSON> Kenneth </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, `` Innerspace''; <PERSON> Joel </PERSON> <PERSON> Hynek </PERSON>, <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Greenberg </PERSON>, <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Greenberg </PERSON> and <PERSON> Stan </PERSON> <PERSON> Winston </PERSON>, `` Predator.'' 2. SUPPORTING ACTRESS: <PERSON> Norma </PERSON> <PERSON> Aleandro </PERSON>, `` Gaby _ A True Story''; <PERSON> Anne </PERSON> <PERSON> Archer </PERSON>, `` Fatal Attraction''; <PERSON> Olympia </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, `` Moonstruck''; <PERSON> Anne </PERSON> <PERSON> Ramsey </PERSON>, `` Throw Momma From the Train''; <PERSON> Ann </PERSON> <PERSON> Sothern </PERSON>, `` The Whales of August.'' 3. ART DIRECTION: Art Direction: <PERSON> Norman </PERSON> <PERSON> Reynolds </PERSON>, Set Direction: <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> Cordwell </PERSON>, `` Empire of the Sun''; Art Direction: <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON> <PERSON> Pratt </PERSON>, Set Direction: <PERSON> Joan </PERSON> <PERSON> Woollard </PERSON>, `` Hope And Glory''; Art Direction: <PERSON> Ferdinando </PERSON> <PERSON> Scarfiotti </PERSON>, Set Direction: <PERSON> Bruno </PERSON> <PERSON> Cesari </PERSON>, `` The Last Emperor''; Art Direction: <ORGANIZATION> Santo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Loquasto </ORGANIZATION>, Set Direction: <PERSON> Carol </PERSON> <PERSON> Joffe </PERSON>, <PERSON> Les </PERSON> <PERSON> Bloom </PERSON> and <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> DeTitta </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, `` Radio Days''; Art Direction: <PERSON> Patrizia </PERSON> <PERSON> Von </PERSON> <PERSON> Brandenstein </PERSON>, Set Direction: <PERSON> Hal </PERSON> <PERSON> Gausman </PERSON>, `` The Untouchables.'' 4. CINEMATOGRAPHY: <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Ballhaus </PERSON>, `` Broadcast News''; <PERSON> Allen </PERSON> <PERSON> Daviau </PERSON>, `` Empire of the Sun''; <PERSON> Phillippe </PERSON> <PERSON> Rousselot </PERSON>, `` Hope And Glory''; <PERSON> Vittorio </PERSON> <PERSON> Storaro </PERSON>, `` The Last Emperor''; <PERSON> Haskell </PERSON> <PERSON> Wexler </PERSON>, `` Matewan.'' 5. ANIMATED SHORT FILM: <PERSON> Eunice </PERSON> <PERSON> Macaulay </PERSON>, `` <PERSON> George </PERSON> and <PERSON> Rosemary </PERSON>''; <PERSON> Frederic </PERSON> <PERSON> Back </PERSON>, `` The Man Who Planted Trees''; <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Plymton </PERSON>, `` Your Face.'' 6. DOCUMENTARY SHORT SUBJECT: <PERSON> Deborah </PERSON> <PERSON> Dickson </PERSON>, `` <PERSON> Frances </PERSON> <PERSON> Steloff </PERSON>: Memoirs of a Bookseller''; <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION>, `` In the Wee Wee Hours ...''; <PERSON> Megan </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> `` Language Says It All''; <PERSON> Lynn </PERSON> <PERSON> Mueller </PERSON>, `` Silver Into Gold''; <PERSON> Sue </PERSON> <PERSON> Marx </PERSON> and <PERSON> Pamela </PERSON> <PERSON> Conn </PERSON>, `` Young At Heart.'' 7. DOCUMENTARY FEATURE: <PERSON> Callie </PERSON> <PERSON> Crossley </PERSON> and <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> DeVinney </PERSON>, `` Eyes on the Prize: <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s Civil Rights Years @ Bridge to Freedom 1965''; <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Junkerman </PERSON> and <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Dower </PERSON>, `` Hellfire: A Journey From <LOCATION> Hiroshima </LOCATION>''; <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Stone </PERSON>, `` Radio Bikini''; <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Herbich </PERSON> and <PERSON> Cyril </PERSON> <PERSON> Christo </PERSON>, `` A Stitch For Time''; <PERSON> Aviva </PERSON> <PERSON> Slesin </PERSON>, `` The Ten-Year Lunch: The Wit and Legend of the Algonquin Round Table.'' 8. SOUND: <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Knuson </PERSON>, <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Digirolamo </PERSON>, <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Boyle </PERSON> and <PERSON> Tony </PERSON> <PERSON> Dawe </PERSON>, `` Empire of the Sun''; <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Rowe </PERSON> and <PERSON> Ivan </PERSON> <PERSON> Sharrock </PERSON>, `` The Last Emperor''; <PERSON> Les </PERSON> <PERSON> Fresholtz </PERSON>, <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON>, <PERSON> Vern </PERSON> <PERSON> Poole </PERSON>, and <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON>, `` Lethal Weapon''; <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kohut </PERSON>, <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> DeLarios </PERSON>, <PERSON> Aaron </PERSON> <PERSON> Rochin </PERSON> and <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Wald </PERSON>, `` Robocop''; <PERSON> Wayne </PERSON> <PERSON> Artman </PERSON>, <PERSON> Tome </PERSON> <PERSON> Beckert </PERSON>, <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Dahl </PERSON> and <PERSON> Art </PERSON> <PERSON> Rochester </PERSON>, `` The Witches of Eastwick.'' 9. SUPPORTING ACTOR: <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Brooks </PERSON>, `` Broadcast News''; <PERSON> Sean </PERSON> <PERSON> Connery </PERSON>, `` The Untouchables''; <PERSON> Morgan </PERSON> <PERSON> Freeman </PERSON>, `` Street Smart''; <PERSON> Vincent </PERSON> <PERSON> Gardenia </PERSON>, `` Moonstruck''; <ORGANIZATION> Denzel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION>, `` Cry Freedom.'' 10. FILM EDITING: <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Marks </PERSON>, `` Broadcast News''; <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Kahn </PERSON>, `` Empire of the Sun''; <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Kahn </PERSON> and <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Berger </PERSON>, `` Fatal Attraction''; <PERSON> Gabriella </PERSON> <PERSON> Cristiani </PERSON>, `` The Last Emperor''; <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Urioste </PERSON>, `` Robocop.'' 11. ORIGINAL SONG: <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Fenton </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jonas </PERSON> <PERSON> Gwangwa </PERSON>, `` Cry Freedom,'' `` Cry Freedom''; Music: <PERSON> Franke </PERSON> <PERSON> Previte </PERSON>, <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> DeNicola </PERSON>, <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Markowitz </PERSON>, Lyric: <PERSON> Franke </PERSON> <PERSON> Previte </PERSON>, `` -LRB- I've Had -RRB- The Time of My Life,'' `` Dirty Dancing''; <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Hammond </PERSON> and <PERSON> Diane </PERSON> <PERSON> Warren </PERSON>, `` Nothing's Gon na Stop Us Now,'' `` Mannequin''; Music: <PERSON> Harold </PERSON> <PERSON> Faltermeyer </PERSON>, <PERSON> Keith </PERSON> <PERSON> Forsey </PERSON>, Lyric: <PERSON> Harold </PERSON> <PERSON> Faltermeyer </PERSON>, <PERSON> Keith </PERSON> <PERSON> Forsey </PERSON>, <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Seger </PERSON>, `` Shakedown,'' `` <LOCATION> Beverly </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hills </LOCATION> Cop II''; <PERSON> Willy </PERSON> <PERSON> DeVille </PERSON>, `` Storybook Love,'' from `` The Princess Bride.'' 12. ORIGINAL SCORE: <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Fenton </PERSON> and <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Gwangwa </PERSON>, `` Cry Freedom''; <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> T. </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>, `` Empire of the Sun''; <PERSON> Ryuichi </PERSON> <PERSON> Sakamoto </PERSON>, <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Byrne </PERSON> and Cong Su, `` The Last Emperor''; <PERSON> Ennio </PERSON> <PERSON> Morricone </PERSON>, `` The Untouchables''; <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> T. </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>, `` The Witches of Eastwick.'' 13. ACTOR: <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON>, `` Wall Street''; <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Hurt </PERSON>, `` Broadcast News''; <PERSON> Marcello </PERSON> <PERSON> Mastroianni </PERSON>, `` Dark Eyes''; <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Nicholson </PERSON>, `` Ironweed''; <PERSON> Robin </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>, `` Good, Morning Vietnam.'' 14. LIVE ACTION SHORT: <PERSON> Ann </PERSON> <PERSON> Wingate </PERSON>, `` Making Waves''; <PERSON> Jonathan </PERSON> <PERSON> Sanger </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jana </PERSON> <PERSON> Sue </PERSON> <PERSON> Memel </PERSON>, `` Ray's Male Heterosexual Dance Hall''; <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Katz </PERSON>, `` Shoeshine.'' 15. COSTUME DESIGN: <PERSON> Dorothy </PERSON> <PERSON> Jeakins </PERSON>, `` The Dead''; <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Ringwood </PERSON>, `` Empire of the Sun''; <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Acheson </PERSON>, `` The Last Emperor''; <PERSON> Jenny </PERSON> <PERSON> Beavan </PERSON> and <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Bright </PERSON>, `` Maurice''; <PERSON> Marilyn </PERSON> <PERSON> Vance-Straker </PERSON>, `` The Untouchables.'' 16. DIRECTOR: <PERSON> Adrian </PERSON> <PERSON> Lyne </PERSON>, `` Fatal Attraction''; <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Boorman </PERSON>, `` Hope And Glory''; <PERSON> Bernardo </PERSON> <PERSON> Bertolucci </PERSON>, `` The Last Emperor''; <PERSON> Lasse </PERSON> <PERSON> Hallstrom </PERSON>, `` My Life as a Dog''; <PERSON> Norman </PERSON> <PERSON> Jewison </PERSON>, `` Moonstruck.'' 17. MAKEUP: <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Laden </PERSON>, `` Happy New Year''; <PERSON> Rick </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON>, `` <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> and the <ORGANIZATION> Hendersons </ORGANIZATION>.'' 18. ADAPTED SCREENPLAY: <PERSON> Tony </PERSON> <PERSON> Huston </PERSON>, `` The Dead''; <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Dearden </PERSON>, `` Fatal Attraction''; <PERSON> Stanley </PERSON> <PERSON> Kubrick </PERSON>, <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Herr </PERSON> and <PERSON> Gustav </PERSON> <PERSON> Hasford </PERSON>, `` Full Metal Jacket''; <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Peploe </PERSON> and <PERSON> Bernardo </PERSON> <PERSON> Bertolucci </PERSON>, `` The Last Emperor''; <PERSON> Lasse </PERSON> <PERSON> Hallstrom </PERSON>, <PERSON> Reidar </PERSON> <PERSON> Jonsson </PERSON>, <PERSON> Brasse </PERSON> <PERSON> Brannstrom </PERSON> and <PERSON> Per </PERSON> <PERSON> Berglund </PERSON>, `` My Life as a Dog.'' 19. ORIGINAL SCREENPLAY: <PERSON> Louis </PERSON> <PERSON> Malle </PERSON>, `` Au <ORGANIZATION> Revoir </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Les </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Enfants </ORGANIZATION>''; <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Brooks </PERSON>, `` Broadcast News''; <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Patrick </PERSON> <PERSON> Shanley </PERSON>, `` Moonstruck''; <PERSON> Woody </PERSON> <PERSON> Allen </PERSON>, `` Radio Days''; <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Boorman </PERSON>, `` Hope And Glory.'' 20. FOREIGN LANGUAGE: `` Au <ORGANIZATION> Revoir </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Les </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Enfants </ORGANIZATION>,'' <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>; `` <PERSON> Babette </PERSON>'s Feast,'' <LOCATION> Denmark </LOCATION>; `` Course Completed,'' <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION>; `` The Family,'' <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>; `` Pathfinder,'' <LOCATION> Norway </LOCATION>. 21. ACTRESS: <PERSON> Cher </PERSON>, `` Moonstruck''; <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON> <PERSON> Close </PERSON>, `` Fatal Attraction''; <PERSON> Holly </PERSON> <PERSON> Hunter </PERSON>, `` Broadcast News''; <PERSON> Sally </PERSON> <PERSON> Kirkland </PERSON>, `` Anna''; <PERSON> Meryl </PERSON> <PERSON> Streep </PERSON>, `` Ironweed.'' 22. PICTURE: `` Broadcast News,'' `` Fatal Attraction,'' `` Hope And Glory,'' `` The Last Emperor,'' `` Moonstruck.''
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 Oscar recipients announced in advance: <PERSON> IRVING </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> THALBERG </PERSON>: Director <PERSON> Billy </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilder </PERSON>. SPECIAL ACHIEVEMENT: Sound effects editing team on `` Robocop.'' <PERSON> GORDON </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> SAWYER </PERSON>: Movie sound specialist <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> Hynes </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880411-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-11-88 0110EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--Italy-Warrant     04-11 0132</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Italy-Warrant,0136</SECOND>
<HEAD>Industrialist Arrested In Banco Ambrosiano Case</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MILAN, Italy (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A 77-year-old <LOCATION> Milan </LOCATION> industrialist has been served with an arrest warrant in connection with <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>'s biggest postwar banking scandal, the 1982 collapse of <ORGANIZATION> Banco </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ambrosiano </ORGANIZATION>, Italian newspapers reported. The reports on Sunday said <PERSON> Anna </PERSON> <PERSON> Bonomi </PERSON> <PERSON> Bolchini </PERSON>, financier and member of a noted Milanese family, was told that because of her age she would not be jailed while the probe continues but instead must report once a week to <LOCATION> Milan </LOCATION> police. She was reportedly charged with complicity in fraudulent bankruptcy. The reports charged that <PERSON> Roberto </PERSON> <PERSON> Calvi </PERSON>, president of the bank, transferred several million dollars into a <LOCATION> Swiss </LOCATION> bank account held by <PERSON> Bonomi </PERSON> <PERSON> Bolchini </PERSON> shortly before <ORGANIZATION> Banco </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ambrosiano </ORGANIZATION>'s collapse. <PERSON> Calvi </PERSON>'s body was found hanging under a <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> bridge in June 1982.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880411-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-11-88 0032EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p AM-PoliticalRdp 3rdLd-Writethru a0777 04-11 1273</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Political Rdp, 3rd Ld-Writethru, a0777,1,190</SECOND>
<HEAD>Jackson, Gore Conciliatory; Cuomo Still Draws Attention</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDs: INSERTS new grafs 39-40 bgng: On Sunday ..., with Cuomo
elaborating on draft.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By DONALD M. ROTHBERG</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Political Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> and Sen. <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> sounded conciliatory notes Sunday as they campaigned for support in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>'s Democratic presidential primary, a contest in which the active candidates often had to compete for attention with non-candidate <PERSON> Mario </PERSON> <PERSON> Cuomo </PERSON>. Meanwhile, the front-runner in the contest, Gov. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION>, took the day off to celebrate Greek Easter with his family. Also taking a day off was Vice President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, whose path to the Republican presidential nomination is clear of serious opposition. While <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> rival <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> remains in the race, the former television evangelist has conceded he has no chance to overcome <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s long lead in the race. <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> were interviewed on the <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> show `` Face the Nation,'' and played down their differences, which have appeared more heated as the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> campaign got under way. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> also said that if elected president he would not meet again with <PERSON> Yasser </PERSON> <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON>, the leader of the <ORGANIZATION> Palestine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION>. He said a meeting he had with <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON> several years ago was `` for the sole purpose of challenging him to change his posture and move toward a mutual recognition policy with <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>.'' That meeting with <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON> has been a focus of criticism of <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> by Jewish leaders in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> campaigned in heavily Jewish neighborhoods in <LOCATION> Brooklyn </LOCATION> Sunday and received the endorsement of state Assemblyman <PERSON> Dov </PERSON> <PERSON> Hikind </PERSON>, who told the crowd, many of them wearing the traditional black hats of the Hasidim: `` We want to understand when one of the candidates has embraced <PERSON> Yasser </PERSON> <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON>.'' At that, the crowd erupted into loud boos. <PERSON> Hikind </PERSON> described <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> as `` the only one who has had the courage to criticize <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>.'' He said that <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> supporters were `` telling us we should reward <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> for his silence.'' In his brief remarks to the crowd, <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> steered clear of comment about <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> and told the crowd that in his years in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, `` I have stood fast in support of <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> and a strong U.S.-Israeli relationship.'' <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> then took a walking tour for about 10 blocks down 13th Avenue, a street lined with kosher food shops and a variety of other small businesses. Mayor <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Koch </PERSON> said earlier in the week that Jewish voters and other supporters of <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> would `` have to be crazy'' to vote for <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> in the primary. <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> had made one of the strongest direct attacks of the campaign on <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> when he said recently that the nation was looking for leadership not `` a preacher in the White House.'' <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> supporters bristled at the comment and called it racist. Asked if he agreed, <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> said, `` That's not my basic position. There are race-based questions; his is not a race-based challenge and I accept it in that spirit, in part, because I respect <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> quite a bit as a person.'' When asked if he thought <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> was being unfair, <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> also demurred. `` No, I think <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> has too much character to be categorically unfair,'' he replied. While, <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> said he had no intention of altering the aggressive tone of his campaign, the <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> senator said he thought all the candidates `` have grown'' during the long debate. As for his approach to the campaign, <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> said, `` I have no plans to change my basic campaign posture at all.'' <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> spent Sunday morning preaching in the <LOCATION> Abyssinian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Church </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Harlem </LOCATION>, where he delivered a sermon called `` A Letter to Dr. <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Luther </PERSON> <PERSON> King </PERSON>.'' He recounted the nation's progress since the civil rights leader's assassination 20 years ago, and said much remains to be done. He concluded quoting King's wish that all people would one day join hands and and sing: `` Free at last ... Thank God Almighty, we are free at last.'' Later, <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> said he could not look up when he read the quote because there is still `` a lot of pain and passion in it all.'' `` All we can do is vow we will continue,'' he told reporters. `` It's not over.'' <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> had lunch at a soul food restaurant in <LOCATION> Harlem </LOCATION>, and walked for several blocks through the neighborhood, hand in hand with his wife <PERSON> Jacqueline </PERSON>. Residents called out to him and rushed up to shake his hand. People called down from their windows, `` Win, <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON>!'' and `` God bless you!'' as <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> gave a thumbs-up sign. Security around <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> was intense, with about 20 <ORGANIZATION> Secret </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> agents and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> police officers escorting him along the sidewalk, along with a phalanx of cameras. Limousines from the motorcade drove alongside. Later, in affluent <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rochelle </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> called for racial unity. ` Even lions and lambs ... do n't want the forest set on fire,'' he told a crowd in affluent <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rochelle </LOCATION>. `` If lions and lambs can find common ground, then blacks and Jews, Hispanics and Italians can find common ground,'' he said to cheers from the largely black audience. A young white man waved a sign that said `` Jews want peace with <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>.'' The common ground in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, as elsewhere in the nation, <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> said, lies in economnic issues and the desire to rid the streets of drugs. Meanwhile, former President <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON>, interviewed on the <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> show, `` Meet the Press,'' commented on the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> campaign, saying, `` <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> has not been on the side of Jewish issues'' while all the other candidates `` ca n't wait but line up for those issues all the way down the line.'' <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> also said <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> is `` appealing to those who are restless, despite prosperity. And that is what <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> must overcome, and that's why I think it's going to be a close election rather than a landslide.'' The former president, driven from office by the Watergate scandal, said that while he would describe <PERSON> Cuomo </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> as `` poets,'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> would better be compared to `` a word processor.'' On the other hand, <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> said of <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, `` he's cool, he's intelligent, he's tough, he's good in debates He's going to be a very formidable candidate.'' <PERSON> Cuomo </PERSON>, the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> governor whom some Democrats have urged to get into the presidential race, took the spotlight from the active candidates on Saturday by announcing he would not endorse anyone prior to the April 19 vote and calling efforts to draft him `` unproductive and unwise.'' Did that end the possibility of drafting the governor? `` I've ruled it out,'' he said in a telephone call to The Associated Press. But spokesman <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Fryer </PERSON> said the governor meant that a draft should not take place, but was not ruling out acceptance of one if it did occur. On Sunday, however, <PERSON> Cuomo </PERSON> said `` I think it is absolutely a reasonable interpretation to say that if a person says it's wrong, it's counterproductive, it's unwise, it should n't be, then that means he rejects a draft.'' When asked if his remarks mean that he would not accept a draft, <PERSON> Cuomo </PERSON> said, `` I think so.'' Former <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> Rep. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Ottinger </PERSON> said Sunday he will suspend his organized effort to draft <PERSON> Cuomo </PERSON> after receiving a letter from the governor requesting that he do so. He said, however, that if it appears there will be no front-runner at the Democratic convention, the effort would resume. `` It does n't change anything,'' said <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, responding to <PERSON> Cuomo </PERSON>'s latest comment. `` I'm going to win <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, I'm going to win <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> and I'm going to win the nomination,'' said the <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> governor who had hoped to get <PERSON> Cuomo </PERSON>'s backing before the primary.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880411-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-11-88 0110EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--Hungary-USShow     04-11 0127</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Hungary-US Show,0128</SECOND>
<HEAD>American Exhibit Draws 110,000 Visitors In Budapest</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BUDAPEST, Hungary (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An 18-day `` American Design'' exhibit staged at the Museum of Arts and Crafts drew 110,000 people, the highest number of spectators ever to attend a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> exhibit in <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>. The 250 artifacts presented were mostly everyday products ranging from household appliances to child-care items, from personal computers to farm tractors. A special unit dealt with objects of `` the motorized way of life'' and `` office work today.'' Exhibit manager <PERSON> Ursual </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> said the large turnout was due, in part, to heavy media coverage of the American product show, which closed Sunday. `` American Design'' will now travel to the cities of Miskolc in northern <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Kecskemet </LOCATION> in central <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> for 18-day stints each.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880411-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-11-88 0110EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--India-Bomb     04-11 0177</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--India-Bomb,0181</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bomb Damages Base Of Nehru Statue</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW DELHI, India (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A bomb believed planted by Tamil extremists damaged the granite base of a statue of <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>'s first prime minister, <PERSON> Jawaharlal </PERSON> <PERSON> Nehru </PERSON>, in the southern Indian city of <LOCATION> Madras </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> India </ORGANIZATION> reported. No one was reported injured in the blast on Sunday, the news agency said. There was no damage to the bronze statue of <PERSON> Nehru </PERSON>, unveiled by his grandson, Prime Minister <PERSON> Rajiv </PERSON> <PERSON> Gandhi </PERSON>, in December 1987. But chunks of granite were blown out of the base by the explosion. Police told the news agency they found two handbills signed by the <ORGANIZATION> Tamil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> near the blast site. The group was linked to a bomb blast on a train in the southern Indian state of <LOCATION> Tamil </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Nadu </LOCATION> in March 1987 that killed at least 22 people and injured 150. <LOCATION> Madras </LOCATION> is the capital of the state. Tamil speakers in southern <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> have long resisted efforts by the government to broaden the use of Hindi, the dominant language in the north.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880411-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-11-88 0111EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-HighDefinitionTV     04-11 0746</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-High Definition TV,0761</SECOND>
<HEAD>High Tech Device Has Industry Excited, Nervous</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DEBORAH MESCE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LAS VEGAS, Nev. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
