<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881203-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-03-88 0233EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-France-Iran     12-03 0373</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-France-Iran,0384</SECOND>
<HEAD>France Lifts Embargo on Iranian Crude Oil</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PARIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> has lifted its 15-month embargo on imports of crude oil from <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>, once its largest oil supplier. The Industry Ministry informed oil companies operating in <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> on Friday that imports of Iranian crude are henceforth subject to the usual French regulations governing oil imports. <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> severed its diplomatic relations with <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> following the `` Embassy War'' in the summer of 1987 when the <ORGANIZATION> Iranian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> refused to allow <PERSON> Wahid </PERSON> <PERSON> Gordji </PERSON>, an interpreter without diplomatic status, to be interrogated by a <LOCATION> French </LOCATION> judge in connection with terrorist attacks in <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> in September 1986. The French police blocked off the embassy and the Iranians retaliated by preventing French diplomats in <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION> from leaving their embassy. <PERSON> Gordji </PERSON> and the French consul in <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION> were eventually exchanged in November 1987. The embargo was partially lifted Sept. 9 when <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> resumed normal diplomatic relations with <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>. Oil industry officials said the partial lifting of the embargo did not have any practical effect because it simply involved giving authorization to French oil companies on a case-by-case basis to do barter deals involving Iranian crude. The barter deals were negotiated by French trading houses and involved exchanges of French food and farm products, notably sugar and meat, for Iranian crude. Industry sources said none of the barter deals was ever concluded, however, because the Iranian asking price was felt to be too high in view of the bearishness of the oil market at the time. Latest oil industry statistics show no imports of Iranian crude by <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> in the first nine months of this year. <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> imported 4.4 million tons of Iranian crude during the first eight months of 1987. Imports totalled 2.9 million tons in 1986. <PERSON> Jean-Louis </PERSON> <PERSON> Breuil-Jarrige </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> French </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> oil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> industry </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> association </ORGANIZATION>, wrote to Industry Minister <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> Fauroux </PERSON> in June after diplomatic relations were restored to point out that the embargo was having no real effect. He argued that French refiners were importing petroleum products made from Iranian crude imported by other European refiners. French oil companies also pointed out at the time that they had a competitive disadvantage compared with European counterparts because <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> was selling its crude relatively cheaply.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881203-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-03-88 0103EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-UN-PLO Bjt   12-03 0575</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-UN-PLO, Bjt,0594</SECOND>
<HEAD>General Assembly Votes For Historic Protest Session To Hear Arafat
In Geneva</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY12</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PETER JAMES SPIELMANN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>UNITED NATIONS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The General Assembly slapped its host country with an unprecedented rebuke by voting 154-2 to reconvene in <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> so <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Yasser </PERSON> <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON>, barred from the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, can address the delegates. The resolution adopted Friday `` deplores'' the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>' refusal to grant <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON> a visa `` Once again, within hours, the international body in this community has stood together for what is right against what is wrong,'' said <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> envoy <PERSON> Zuhdi </PERSON> <PERSON> Labib </PERSON> <PERSON> Terzi </PERSON>. Only the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> voted against the Arab-sponsored resolution. <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> abstained, having previously said the criticism in the resolution was too harsh. Members of <ORGANIZATION> Palestine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION>, `` who specialized in hijacking of airplanes and cruise ships, are expanding their efforts and hijacking the <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION>,'' said <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s acting ambassador, <PERSON> Johanan </PERSON> <PERSON> Bein </PERSON>. <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. Ambassador <PERSON> Herbert </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Okun </PERSON>, the acting <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> representative, said the move was unnecessary. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> contended that another <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> delegate could present <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON>'s viewpoints. But the highest ranking <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> official at the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> sided with critics, saying <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>'s action had done `` incalculable damage to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> credibility in the world arena.'' The comments were written by <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> V. </PERSON> <PERSON> Reed </PERSON>, undersecretary-general for <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION> affairs, in a letter to President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>. The assembly took the historic step of moving to the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION>'s European headquarters because the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> rejected <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> appeals to admit <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON>, who last visited <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> in 1974 <PERSON> Okun </PERSON> said the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> did n't object to the move and would participate in debate there. <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON> wants to address the 159-nation assembly to explain the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION>'s declaration of an independent state and its implicit recognition of <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>. The Palestinian issue will be discussed Dec. 13-15 in <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION>. It will be the first session the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> has convened outside <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> since moving into its building in <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION> in 1952. <PERSON> Okun </PERSON> said the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> was justified in denying a visa to <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON>, whom the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration called an `` accessory to terrorism.'' Critics said the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> action violated the 1947 <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> Headquarters Agreement, under which the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> is obligated to grant visas to <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> diplomats and guests. The <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> has estimated the cost of the <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> session at $ 645,500, including $ 159,000 for first-class round-trip tickets to <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> for delegates of the world's 40 poorest countries. Since 1946, the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> has paid travel expenses of the least developed nations so they can be represented in deliberations. The cost also includes travel for at least 30 <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> officials and staff, translation and documentation in six official languages and other expenses. On Wednesday, the assembly overwhelmingly denounced the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> denial of a visa to <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON> and gave the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> 24 hours to reconsider. Again, only the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> voted against the resolution. <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> abstained. On Thursday night, the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government said it would not change its position. The resolution to move to <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> was introduced early Friday. In his letter to <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, written after the Wednesday vote, <PERSON> Reed </PERSON> said the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> position `` is baffling and contradictory because Chairman <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON> has already addressed the <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION>, in 1974, and thus set a precedent for being granted an entry visa.'' <LOCATION> Dominica </LOCATION> was not present for Friday's vote, and <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> has not had voting rights since 1974 because of its policy of apartheid.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881203-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-03-88 0243EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-GSABribery     12-03 0324</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-GSA Bribery,320</SECOND>
<HEAD>Ex-GSA Official Convicted Of Receiving Bribes</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A retired <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> official faces a maximum 36-year prison term when he's sentenced Feb. 3 for receiving $ 24,185 in bribes to provide inside information to two businessmen who were found guilty of conspiracy. <PERSON> Lester </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Finotti </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, 56, a former manager in <ORGANIZATION> GSA </ORGANIZATION>'s transportation audit branch, was convicted by a <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> jury of receiving the money and the use of a luxury automobile during an 18-month period ending in September 1986 <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> White </PERSON> <PERSON> Sr. </PERSON>, 59, and <PERSON> Carmine </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> DePietro </PERSON>, 53, the former president and former executive vice president, respectively, of <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Investment </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, were convicted of conspiracy to defraud the government. The charge carries a five-year term. The three defendants were allowed to remain free on bond until their sentencing Feb. 3 by <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> Harold </PERSON> <PERSON> Greene </PERSON>. The scheme involved an effort to obtain inside information from <ORGANIZATION> GSA </ORGANIZATION> to help the <LOCATION> Fayetteville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.C. </LOCATION>, company, which purchased bills-of-lading at a discount from moving companies that hauled furniture of government employees. Under the arrangement known as factoring, the moving companies in effect paid <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Investment </ORGANIZATION> a premium to receive their money faster than if they waited for the government to pay them directly. Southern Investment, in turn, assumed total liability for any claims for damaged freight that the government filed against the trucking companies. The prosecution presented evidence that <PERSON> Finotti </PERSON> provided information about the reliability of freight haulers that enabled White and <PERSON> DePietro </PERSON> to decide whether to factor a company's bills-of-lading Such information would enable <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Investment </ORGANIZATION> to avoid purchasing moving bills from companies that would likely incur large damage claims, the prosecution contended. The indictment charged that <PERSON> Finotti </PERSON> manipulated the payment of bills-of-lading to benefit Southern Investment. Finotti, of <LOCATION> Waldorf </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Md. </LOCATION>, was convicted of conspiracy, bribery, conflict-of-interest, and filing a false government financial disclosure statement that did not report his financial arrangement with <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Investment </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881203-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-03-88 0246EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-SovietEmigres     12-03 0354</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Soviet Emigres,360</SECOND>
<HEAD>More Than 200 Soviet Jews, Armenians Denied Admission As Refugees</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BARRY SCHWEID</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Diplomatic Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> authorities have refused to grant refugee status to more than 200 Soviet Jews and Armenians, but a <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> official says they could be eligible to enter this country through a system known as parole. <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Redman </PERSON> said Friday that the would-be refugees were unable to demonstrate `` a well-founded fear of persecution.'' But one way or another, he said, `` we continue to admit all Soviet Jewish applicants who choose to come to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>.'' The issue was raised by the Union of Councils for Soviet Jews. The private group released two petitions from Soviet Jews in <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION> awaiting entrance visas to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. Most Jews who are permitted to leave the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> have exit permits to emigrate to <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>. But an overwhelming majority choose to go to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> after they reach <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION> or <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Redman </PERSON> said of more than 4,000 applications in <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION> in October and November, less than 200 were found not to qualify for refugees status. But, he said, `` if this occurs, the applicants are, without exception, given the opportunity to apply for parole.'' To be granted parole, the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> official said, applicants must show they would be supported by a relative or a sponsor in the event jobs were not found. The idea is to avoid additional <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> welfare costs. Entering as a refugee provides certain benefits that are not available under parole. These include transportation expenses, some support for resettlement and access to Medicaid. In <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>, he said, 99 applicants, most of whom were Armenians, did not qualify for refugee status during the two months. But, <PERSON> Redman </PERSON> said, they also may seek admission under the parole system. <PERSON> Redman </PERSON> said there was no change in <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> policy. `` The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> continues to call for freedom of emigration for all and continues to admit all Soviet Jewish applicants who choose to come to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>,'' he said. `` Most qualify as refugees, and in addition some enter as parolees.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881203-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-03-88 0125EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-MotelFire 1stLd-Writethru a0826 12-03 0228</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Motel Fire, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0826,0231</SECOND>
<HEAD>Fire Ravages Downtown Motel</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: LEADS with 3 grafs to UPDATE with injuries, name of motel;
picks up 4th graf, ``The fire ...''</NOTE>
<DATELINE>COLUMBUS, Ohio (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Fire raced through the attic of a downtown motel late Friday night, leaving guests homeless, causing minor injuries to three people and gutting the top floor of the two-story building, officials said. The fire was reported at 11:30 p.m., Fire Chief <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Werner </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Werner </PERSON> said he did n't know how many guests were evacuated from the Village Inn Motel, but said the fire gutted at least 26 rooms. A woman who jumped from a second-story balcony was treated for a minor ankle injury and smoke inhalation, and two people were treated for smoke inhalation, said a paramedic who refused to give his name. A number of people lost belongings to the blaze, <PERSON> Werner </PERSON> said. The fire began in a corner of the U-shaped motel, and moved through the attic around the building. All the rooms on the top floor suffered heavy fire damage, and most of the room beneath sustained water and smoke damage, officials said. About 60 <LOCATION> Columbus </LOCATION> firefighters responded to the blaze, which sent smoke over several blocks of the city's old <LOCATION> German </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Village </LOCATION> neighborhood. Residents of a nearby apartment complex were evacuated as a precaution because of the smoke, <PERSON> Werner </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881203-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-03-88 0305EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     12-03 0892</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0927</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in the News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Soviet President <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> and his wife, <PERSON> Raisa </PERSON>, have accepted an invitation from developer <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Trump </PERSON> to visit his glitzy Fifth Avenue shopping atrium when they come to town next week. The <PERSON> Gorbachevs </PERSON> are expected to spend about a half-hour next Thursday inside Trump Tower's marble-lined shopping atrium, guided by the multimillionaire, <PERSON> Trump </PERSON> spokesman <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Klores </PERSON> said Friday. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> is coming to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> to meet with President <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and President-elect <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. <PERSON> Klores </PERSON> said <PERSON> Trump </PERSON> met <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> at a White House dinner during the Soviet leader's last visit to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> earlier this year. `` They spoke and they got along, so when he knew <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> was coming, he -LRB- <PERSON> Trump </PERSON> -RRB- wrote him a note,'' <PERSON> Klores </PERSON> said. `` On Wednesday, the Soviets responded and said they'd be delighted to come.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>YORBA LINDA, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON>'s daughter and supporters broke ground for his presidential library, predicting history would treat him favorably. <PERSON> Julie </PERSON> <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> <PERSON> Eisenhower </PERSON> and others among the 1,000 dignitaries and guests at Friday's ceremony looked forward to a library that will offer a glimpse of the man who debated Soviet leader <PERSON> Nikita </PERSON> <PERSON> Khrushchev </PERSON> and went on to oversee the dawn of detente with the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> and the People's Republic of <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>. But the memory of Watergate, which drove <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> to resign under threat of impeachment in 1974, hung heavy over the festivities by the green-and-white cottage where he was born in 1913. `` Only history can be the judge'' of <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON>'s performance, his daughter said, adding that she hoped the library `` will help tear down some of the stereotypes'' regarding her father's administration. `` History will treat him far more kindly than his own time,'' added Rep. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Dannemeyer </PERSON>, R-Calif. <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON>'s other daughter, <PERSON> Tricia </PERSON> <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> <PERSON> Cox </PERSON>, was to have spoken, but stayed home with the flu, said <PERSON> Kevin </PERSON> <PERSON> Cartwright </PERSON>, spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> Richard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> M. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nixon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Presidential </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Archives </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION> <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON>, who lives in <LOCATION> Saddle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.J. </LOCATION>, stayed away to yield center stage to his daughters, <PERSON> Cartwright </PERSON> said. The <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> Presidential Library will not include his presidential papers, which remain at <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Archives </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WEST HARTFORD, Conn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Pulitzer Prize-winning playwright <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Albee </PERSON> told a group of prep school students that his troubled days in a variety of elite <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Coast </LOCATION> private schools showed him the limits of a formal education. <PERSON> Albee </PERSON> said he was thrown out of several private schools before managing to graduate from <PERSON> Choate </PERSON>, where he said he learned that `` the real function of a formal education is to teach you how to educate yourself when you're done with your formal education.'' <PERSON> Albee </PERSON>, who won Pulitzers for drama in 1967 for `` A Delicate Balance'' and again in 1975 for `` Seascape,'' recounted his prep school days Friday for about 300 students at <ORGANIZATION> Kingswood-Oxford </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION>. `` At the age of 14 for all my sins I found myself in <ORGANIZATION> Valley </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forge </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Military </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION>,'' he said. `` I have to be very careful what I say about this joint. It is my memory ... that they only offered two courses _ sadism and masochism, and these were not electives.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW HAVEN, Conn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Television's <PERSON> Mister </PERSON> <PERSON> Rogers </PERSON> got a warm reception from students at <ORGANIZATION> Yale </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, where he lectured on the role men can play in child care. `` It's a beautiful day in YOUR neighborhood,'' <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> Rogers </PERSON> said to open his talk Friday, echoing his trademark line on the popular public television children's show `` Mister <PERSON> Rogers </PERSON>' Neighborhood.'' Dressed in a suit rather than one of his his trademark cardigan sweaters, <PERSON> Rogers </PERSON> said more men are working in child care, but the turnover rate is high because of low salaries. `` Hopefully, this can change,'' he said. `` There is no greater gift you can give to someone of any age than the gift of your honest self.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>SAN LUIS OBISPO, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Gustav </PERSON> <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Hasford </PERSON>, who won an Oscar nomination for co-writing the screenplay for `` Full Metal Jacket,'' pleaded no contest to possessing thousands of books stolen from public libraries. <PERSON> Hasford </PERSON> entered the plea Friday and was ordered to pay restitution on the books in exchange for prosecutors' agreement to drop two criminal counts of grand theft. The plea was accepted by <ORGANIZATION> San </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Luis </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Obispo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Superior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> Judge <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> Woolpert </PERSON>. Deputy District Attorney <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> <PERSON> Estrada-Mullaney </PERSON> has recommended that Hasford serve six months in jail. Sentencing was set for Jan. 4 before <ORGANIZATION> San </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Luis </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Superior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> Judge <PERSON> Warren </PERSON> <PERSON> Conklin </PERSON>. <PERSON> Hasford </PERSON>'s plea covered about 2,000 books, mainly Civil War research volumes, valued at about $ 20,000 and taken from libraries in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Monica </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Sacramento </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Luis </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Obispo </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Louis </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Longview </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wash. </LOCATION>, and <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LAS VEGAS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> news </ORGANIZATION> correspondent <PERSON> Garrick </PERSON> <PERSON> Utley </PERSON> is rather distressed about the content of some television talk shows, saying they come close to inciting the public. `` It is getting close to crying fire in a crowded elevator,'' <PERSON> Utley </PERSON> said in a speech to the Radio-Television News Directors Association on Thursday. <PERSON> Utley </PERSON> lambasted shows hosted by <PERSON> Morton </PERSON> <PERSON> Downey </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> and <PERSON> Geraldo </PERSON> <PERSON> Rivera </PERSON>. <PERSON> Rivera </PERSON> recently had his nose broken when a fight broke out during filming of a show on white supremacists. `` The very presence of these shows on our TV screen gives the programs, subjects and their behavior a certain legitimacy that this is proper behavior. It is not,'' <PERSON> Utley </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881203-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-03-88 0306EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Shuttle-Military     12-03 0668</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Shuttle-Military,680</SECOND>
<HEAD>Some 200 U.S., Soviet Satellites Spying on Earth</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By NORMAN BLACK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Military Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The new military spy satellite carried into space is viewed by some experts as capable of gathering such important information that it is only a matter of time before the Soviets begin to think of ways of destroying it in the event of war. Like the roughly 200 military satellites already deployed in space by the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, the $ 500 million Lacrosse satellite reportedly aboard the space shuttle Atlantis is not armed. It is a surveillance satellite, carrying a sophisticated radar that can look down from space, piercing even cloud cover to reveal what's happening on the ground. `` As military satellites become more directly applicable to actual combat, they become much more attractive targets for destruction,'' said <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Pike </PERSON>, an expert on space systems with the Federation of American Scientists here. `` Lacrosse provides a good example of that,'' he said. `` It's going up there to find targets for the new stealth bomber and to look for long-range targets deep behind the lines in the <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION> Pact Now, if I've got all that riding on my satellites, the Soviets would be crazy not to try to shoot them down.'' `` Space is already militarized,'' agreed <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Arkin </PERSON>, an authority on nuclear weaponry with the <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Policy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Studies </ORGANIZATION>, a liberal think tank in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. `` The question is whether we're going to avoid the weaponization of space. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> now has approximately 75 to 80 military satellites in space, while roughly 125 of the 150-plus Russian satellites now in orbit are thought to have some military use. The numbers are approximate, because neither government talks about the matter. The Pentagon, for example, considers the Atlantis launch a classified military mission for which no information will be provided. It will neither confirm nor deny that the cargo is a radar-imaging satellite. As approximate as the tallies are, they demonstrate the growing reliance of the two superpowers on military space systems. It was only three decades ago _ in 1957 with <LOCATION> Russia </LOCATION>'s Sputnik _ that mankind developed the ability to put a manmade object into orbit. Now, military satellites are in orbit spying on facilities and forces, scanning the radio waves as electronic ferrets, watching for nuclear explosions or missile launches and mapping the Earth's surface Even the seemingly mundane tasks in space have become important for war-fighting. Communications is an obvious example, but there are others. For example, the latest generation of navigation satellites help provide the pinpoint accuracy now claimed for nuclear missiles like the giant MX. Among other functions, these satellites allow the military to synchronize its watches down to billionths of a second. And scrutinizing the weather becomes essential in the event of a war. Both the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> are operating advanced meteorological satellites to aid low-level bombers, detect solar flares and find holes in cloud cover for reconnaissance work. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> now has 20 military satellites of various types waiting to go into orbit _ victims of the launch hiatus forced by the Challenger disaster and unrelated problems with unmanned Titan boosters. As that backlog is slowly erased, <PERSON> Arkin </PERSON>, <PERSON> Pike </PERSON> and others suggest the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> _ and perhaps the <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION> _ will face other problems with their satellite hardware besides protecting them as tempting targets. `` The expense of these new types of satellites is not to be believed,'' says <PERSON> Arkin </PERSON>. `` We're going to have to look at a single satellite the way we look at an aircraft carrier. These satellites alone are costing $ 250 million and up.'' Such complaints do n't bother <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> officials, because they see no alternative. As outgoing <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> `` Pete'' <PERSON> Aldridge </PERSON> observed recently: `` We must put a large part of our investment ... into the satellites which meet mission needs today and tomorrow. Simply stated, we must be able to conduct operations in space, at all times, in any environment _ peace or war.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881203-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-03-88 0211EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Hijack-Hostage     12-03 0309</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Hijack-Hostage,0319</SECOND>
<HEAD>Hostage Says He Did His Duty, Gave Hijackers `A Lift' To Israel</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By SERGEI SHARGORODSKY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>TEL AVIV, Israel (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A Soviet flight engineer who was part of the crew that flew five hijackers to <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> said he was n't threatened by the armed captors and merely `` gave them a lift. <PERSON> Yuri </PERSON> <PERSON> N. </PERSON> <PERSON> Yermilov </PERSON> appeared relaxed as he spoke from the door of the jet Friday less than an hour after the hijackers surrendered to Israeli police at <LOCATION> Ben-Gurion </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION>. He signed autographs for Israeli reporters and agreed to be photographed with a Hebrew-language magazine in his hands. The hijackers were flown to <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> after seizing a bus with 30 children in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> and trading it for a plane, crew and $ 3.3 million ransom. `` They were playing cards,'' during the flight, <PERSON> Yermilov </PERSON> said. `` At some point, some of them were in the cockpit behind us, and they were watching us. They had guns, but they were not waving them around and threatening us.'' A younger crew member, who did not give his name, added: `` They were counting the money.'' <PERSON> Yermilov </PERSON>, who wore a dark blue <ORGANIZATION> Aeroflot </ORGANIZATION> uniform, said the hijackers appeared to be in their 30s. He said they never said why they chose <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> as their destination. `` They were people who wanted to fly out of the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. That's why they kidnapped the bus with children,'' <PERSON> Yermilov </PERSON> said. `` They asked for a lift for <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>, and we gave them a lift,'' he added jokingly. He said the crew was appointed for the mission by Soviet authorities. `` We are international pilots. We understood that we have a mission that has to be done,'' <PERSON> Yermilov </PERSON> said, adding that the crew was aware of the danger. `` We were told that our guarantees are zero. But they -LRB- the hijackers -RRB- seemed quite good-natured,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881203-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-03-88 0319EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-India-Crash     12-03 0121</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-India-Crash,0123</SECOND>
<HEAD>Air Force Planes Collide In The Air, 2 Killed</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW DELHI, India (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Two air force planes collided in the air in eastern <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>, killing one pilot and spewing fiery debris that killed a youth on the ground and injured four civilians, <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Trust </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> India </ORGANIZATION> reported. The report said Friday's crash seriously injured the second pilot. It did not specify where the accident occurred. The falling wreckage killed a teen-ager and burned four people on the ground, the report said. It said fire from the debris burned three houses. An air force official contacted in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Delhi </LOCATION> said he had no information on the collision. The news agency said the pilots were on a training mission.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881203-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-03-88 0534EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--BeautifulRobber     12-03 0170</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Beautiful Robber,0174</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bank Robber Dubbed `Miss America' Convicted of Five Holdups</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A 23-year-old beauty parlor employee was convicted of robbing five suburban banks during her off hours, earning her a nickname as the `` Miss America'' bandit among authorities. <PERSON> Danielle </PERSON> <PERSON> Tyece </PERSON> <PERSON> Mast </PERSON> was also known as the `` American Beauty'' bandit, because of the assorted wigs, cosmetics and sunglasses she wore during a series of heists that began July 15, Assistant <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Attorney <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Price </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Mast </PERSON>, who was convicted Friday, robbed banks in <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Culver </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Torrance </PERSON>, mostly on her lunch hour, after work and once on a day off from her job at the Touch of Elegance beauty parlor in <LOCATION> Hawthorne </LOCATION>, Price said. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> <PERSON> Hauk </PERSON> set sentencing for March 27. Sentencing was set for March 27, 1989, by <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> <PERSON> Hauk </PERSON>. <PERSON> Mast </PERSON>, who remains free on $ 50,000 bail, faces a sentence of up to 100 years in prison and a $ 1.2 million fine, Price said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881203-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-03-88 0326EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-RevolutionRemembered     12-03 0159</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Revolution Remembered,0162</SECOND>
<HEAD>French Revolution Remembered, With Guillotine</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The resort city of <LOCATION> Brighton </LOCATION> will mark the bicentennial of the French Revolution next year with an exhibit including such historical items as a working guillotine. The south coast city on Friday announced the exhibit will open in May. Portraits, costumes, documents, furniture and jewelry have been borrowed from <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Austria </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Sweden </LOCATION> and from British collections to tell the story of the revolution, which began in 1789. Visitors will walk through a series of scenes showing the lives of ordinary people as well as the court and politics, coming finally to the foot of the guillotine. `` The visitor becomes part of the mob and hears the roll of drums and the roar of the crowd as the blade crashes down _ and we will have a quick escape route there for anyone who feels nervous,'' said organizer <PERSON> Jane </PERSON> <PERSON> Cox </PERSON>. The show begins May 4.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881203-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-03-88 0346EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Spain-Jaywalker     12-03 0190</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Spain-Jaywalker,0194</SECOND>
<HEAD>Court Upholds Ruling Against Jaywalker; Damages to Britons</HEAD>
<DATELINE>FUENGIROLA, Spain (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An appeals court upheld a jaywalker's conviction and $ 163,237 in damages awarded a British couple seriously injured in an accident linked to the jaywalking, an attorney said The attorney for the couple, <PERSON> Alfredo </PERSON> <PERSON> Herrera </PERSON>, told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> the appeals court Friday also upheld the $ 176 fine imposed on <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Williamson </PERSON>, 47, of <LOCATION> Glasgow </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Scotland </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Williamson </PERSON>'s insurance company was ordered to pay damages to <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Usher </PERSON>, 54, and his wife <PERSON> Claire </PERSON>, 53, of <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>, for injuries they suffered Sept. 26, 1986, in Mijas, in southern <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Herrera </PERSON> said the decision affirmed a court ruling in May that <PERSON> Williamson </PERSON>'s jaywalking on a coastal highway caused a heavy truck to swerve to avoid him and to hit two cars. The accident killed a paramilitary <ORGANIZATION> Civil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> officer and seriously injured a second officer riding with him. The Ushers were in the second car, and both were seriously injured. The court also upheld civil damages of $ 247,700 to the widow and family of the <ORGANIZATION> Civil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> officer who died and $ 74,300 to the injured Civil Guard, <PERSON> Herrera </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881203-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-03-88 0351EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Judge-Molester     12-03 0280</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Judge-Molester,0288</SECOND>
<HEAD>Judge Who Blamed Molester's Wife Resigns</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A judge who suggested a child molester was driven to his crimes by his wife's pregnancy has resigned, the lord chancellor said, but he offered to quit before he made his controversial comments. The announcement Friday said that Judge Sir <PERSON> Harold </PERSON> <PERSON> Cassel </PERSON> submitted his resignation Monday and cited health reasons. On Tuesday, <PERSON> Cassel </PERSON> set off a furor by giving two years probation to a 30-year-old man who admitted three indecent assaults on his adolescent stepdaughter. `` It is regrettable that a judge should have expressed himself in a way that suggested that there are any circumstances that can excuse or condone indecent assault on children,'' said <PERSON> Lord </PERSON> <PERSON> Mackay </PERSON>, who as lord chancellor is chief of <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s judicial system. <PERSON> Cassel </PERSON>, 72, became a judge 12 years ago. The defendant admitted twice molesting the girl when she was 12 and a third time when the girl was 13 and the mother was in the last month of pregnancy. The mother's condition, <PERSON> Cassel </PERSON> said, led to a `` lack of sexual appetite in the lady and considerable problems for a healthy young husband.'' The judge traced the abuse to the mother's efforts to overcome the girl's resentment of the new man in the house. `` The stepmother encouraged the girl to cuddle her husband and even got into the habit of inviting her into the marital bed,'' the judge said. `` This was not an invitation to a toddler, but to a girl approaching puberty, and the cuddles began to go too far.'' The mother has filed for divorce. More than 20 members of <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION>, including lawmakers from all major parties, called for <PERSON> Cassel </PERSON>'s resignation.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881203-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-03-88 0408EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Bush 2ndLd-Writethru a0410 12-03 0742</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bush, 2nd Ld-Writethru, a0410,660</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush Defends Pace Of New Appointments, Meets With Dukakis</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: RETRANSMITTING to make it 2nd Ld; INSERTS 1 graf after 10th
graf pvs, bgng: ``Fuller said...'' to add material on U.N.
ambassador and CIA; picks up 11th graf pvs, bgng: ``Bush and...''</NOTE>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto WX6</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOAN MOWER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President-elect <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and his staff are defending the way the transition office has handled appointments in a week that produced only one announcement. All week, there was speculation that <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> would make announcements on more Cabinet members, particularly for the <ORGANIZATION> defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> department </ORGANIZATION> and other national security jobs. But the only statement was that <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> would stay on as White House spokesman. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, who met Friday with foreign leaders and former presidential rivals, including <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, seemed to bristle when reporters asked him if his appointment process was stalled. `` There's no holdup. We're way ahead of schedule,'' he said, complaining about `` early, premature, needless speculation.'' <PERSON> Craig </PERSON> <PERSON> Fuller </PERSON>, co-director of the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> transition office, said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and his aides spent part of the past week talking to experts in defense and national security about running the mammoth agency. `` The whole point of this week has been designed to try to explore how best to manage the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, what kind of challenges await the next secretary of <ORGANIZATION> defense </ORGANIZATION>,'' he said. <PERSON> Fuller </PERSON> said former Sen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Tower </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> remains a contender for the job, and the vice president has `` tremendous confidence'' in his old friend. Though <PERSON> Fuller </PERSON> said nothing to dispel reports that Tower is the leading candidate for defense secretary, he added, `` There may be others, there may be other approaches.'' <PERSON> Fuller </PERSON> also said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> is taking an overview of his Cabinet vacancies because he wants to make sure women and minorities claim some of the top jobs. To date, only white males have been named to the positions, although <PERSON> Lauro </PERSON> <PERSON> Cavazos </PERSON>, a Hispanic, has been asked to stay on as education secretary. <PERSON> Fuller </PERSON> said it could be a couple of weeks before the Cabinet is in place, but appointments will be made as they are decided upon. Meanwhile, <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> reported today that <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has decided to remove from Cabinet rank the job of ambassador to the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> and not to restore to Cabinet level the director of the <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Intelligence </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION>. The paper quoted transition officials as saying the decision reflects his belief that the two posts _ both of which he has previously held _ should be less visible in internal policy-making debates. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> met for 35 minutes Friday, and the two avoided the negative rhetoric that characterized the presidential campaign. `` I expressed my concern obviously about the deficit,'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, the former <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> candidate, said. He also stressed issues that were important to Democrats _ better health care, housing, education and the environment. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said afterward: `` I want to express my appreciation to Governor <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> for coming our way. We had good discussion of the issues that are facing the country in a spirit of good will.'' The vice president also saw <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON>, who tried unsuccessfully to gain the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> presidential nomination. <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> said he talked with <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> about <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>, a country the television evangelist recently visited. `` The time has come to recognize the South African government needs a little encouragement,'' said <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON>, an opponent of sanctions and disinvestment as a strategy for forcing change in the white-ruled country. Late in the day <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> met at his residence with Argentine President <PERSON> Raul </PERSON> <PERSON> Alfonsin </PERSON>, who had flown in from <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> for the get-acquainted session. Neither <PERSON> Alfonsin </PERSON> nor <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> commented on reports from <LOCATION> Argentina </LOCATION> that troops had moved into position to quell an insurrection at a military base outside <LOCATION> Buenos </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Aires </LOCATION>. The government said later it had put down the rebellion. Vice President-elect <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>, Secretary of State <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Nicholas </PERSON> <PERSON> Brady </PERSON> and Assistant Secretary of State <PERSON> Elliott </PERSON> <PERSON> Abrams </PERSON> attended the meeting. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> began his day seeing <LOCATION> Bermuda </LOCATION> Premier <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Swan </PERSON>, the fourth foreign leader he has met since he was elected. <PERSON> Alfonsin </PERSON> was the fifth, and Soviet leader <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> will be the sixth. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> will join President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> at a meeting with <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> on Dec. 7. So far, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s only scheduled event over the weekend is to attend a movie entitled `` My Stepmother is an Alien'' on Saturday night. The Bushes usually attend church on Sunday.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881203-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-03-88 0416EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-TrappedFilmMakers     12-03 0275</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Trapped Film Makers,0283</SECOND>
<HEAD>Film Makers Trapped In Caves</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ADELAIDE, Australia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Thirteen people filming a documentary were trapped more than 250 feet under the ground in a cave today after a sudden rainstorm caused the cave's mouth to collapse, police said. Police spokesman <PERSON> Rick </PERSON> <PERSON> Goodfield </PERSON> said the group was in no immediate danger and that rescue workers were trying to reach them. `` The rescue team has established a communications line inside the cave and they are all doing fine,'' said <PERSON> Goodfield </PERSON>. The nationalities of the film makers were not known. The group became trapped late Friday while filming in the extensive cave system under the isolated Nullarbor Plain in southwestern <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Goodfield </PERSON> said. The Nullarbor is a huge dry plain but there is an extensive cave system underneath it, containing subterranean water systems linking caves. <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Rogers </PERSON>, who left the Nullarbor group Sunday, said they were filming a documentary on the caves. He said all of those trapped were experienced cave divers but that the cave they were in was not underwater. <PERSON> Rogers </PERSON> said the group radioed for help from their ground crew which in turn notified authorities. `` It was a freak hurricane,'' he said. `` You do n't get a lot of hurricanes on the Nullarbor. So much water washed down the entrance of the cave that it washed enough rubble down to cause a blockage about 100 feet down into the cave.'' <PERSON> Rogers </PERSON> said the group was safely beyond that depth in a large chamber about 260 feet below the surface. `` No one's injured, they've got communication with the surface and they've got a reasonable amount of water and food,'' <PERSON> Rogers </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881203-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-03-88 0449EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Obit-Ferguson     12-03 0237</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Obit-Ferguson,0246</SECOND>
<HEAD>Veteran Journalist Dies At 72</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PORTLAND, Ore. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Veteran journalist <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> Ferguson </PERSON>, whose coverage of a 1948 <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION> flood for The Associated Press made national headlines, died at the age of 72. <PERSON> Ferguson </PERSON> died Wednesday of complications following brain surgery. He began his career in <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> in 1935 as a reporter for the Daily-Courier Appeal in <PERSON> Dubois </PERSON>. In 1937, he became editor of the Jeffersonian-Democrat in <LOCATION> Brookville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION>, a weekly newspaper. The following year, the newspaper won five first-place awards for news, editorials and feature reporting from the <ORGANIZATION> Pennsylvania </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Publishers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Ferguson </PERSON> joined the <LOCATION> Portland </LOCATION> bureau of <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> in 1945. Three years later, he covered the <LOCATION> Vanport </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Flood </LOCATION>, in which many residents of <LOCATION> Portland </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Vanport </LOCATION> neighborhood fled their homes when the <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION> and <PERSON> Willamette </PERSON> <PERSON> Rivers </PERSON> left their banks. In 1951, <PERSON> Ferguson </PERSON> went to The Oregonian as a copy editor. He was named business editor in the mid-1950s. <PERSON> Ferguson </PERSON> also worked as a regional correspondent for <ORGANIZATION> McGraw-Hill </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Publications </ORGANIZATION>. In 1957, he became news director for <ORGANIZATION> Pacific </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Power </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <ORGANIZATION> Light </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co </ORGANIZATION>. He was named an assistant vice president in 1962 and retired in 1981. Following his retirement, he served as chairman of the state legislative committee of the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Retired </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Persons </ORGANIZATION> and helped win passage of a bill improving the visitation rights of grandparents. A native of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bethlehem </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION>, he attended <ORGANIZATION> Pennsylvania </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Franklin </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <ORGANIZATION> Marshall </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881203-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-03-88 0509EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Peru-Crash     12-03 0325</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Peru-Crash,0336</SECOND>
<HEAD>Sabotage Intended For Other Train Blamed In Crash Involving Jersey
Mayor</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CUZCO, Peru (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A metal rod probably intended to sabotage a passenger train instead knocked another train carrying <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>'s mayor off the tracks and sent it tumbling down a ravine, officials said The mayor's wife and the wife of <LOCATION> Cuzco </LOCATION>'s mayor were killed in the crash, which occurred Thursday during an outing to the <LOCATION> Inca </LOCATION> ruins of Machu Picchu, high in the Andes. <PERSON> Jacinto </PERSON> <PERSON> Laguna </PERSON>, an employee of the state-owned railroad <ORGANIZATION> Enafer </ORGANIZATION>, told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> on Friday that railroad officials found a piece of metal wedged into the track. <PERSON> Laguna </PERSON> said the rod caused the railway car, a small bus modified to travel on tracks, to jump the track at a curve and plunge into the 200-foot deep ravine. Killed were <PERSON> Anna </PERSON> <PERSON> Cucci </PERSON>, about 60, the wife of <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> Mayor <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON> <PERSON> Cucci </PERSON>, and <PERSON> Doris </PERSON> <PERSON> Chacon </PERSON>, 58, wife of <LOCATION> Cuzco </LOCATION> Mayor <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Chacon </PERSON>. The politicians were injured. <PERSON> Cucci </PERSON>, 66, was reported in stable condition at a hospital. <PERSON> Chacon </PERSON> was reported in serious condition. Police officials said they believe the sabotage was intended for a regular passenger train carrying 300 passengers that was behind the tourist car. The vehicle carrying the politicians and their wives was making an unscheduled run. Police said they had detained one person. They were investigating a group of railroad workers who were involved in a nationwide general strike Thursday. Family members said <PERSON> Chacon </PERSON> suffered internal bleeding and at least 18 fractures to his pelvis and spinal column. The bodies of Mrs. <PERSON> Cucci </PERSON> and Mrs. <PERSON> Chacon </PERSON> were lying in state in a <LOCATION> Cuzco </LOCATION> municipal building. Doctors said the women appeared to have died from skull fractures. The Cuccis were visiting to celebrate a sister city agreement between <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Cuzco </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Cuzco </LOCATION> is a tourist area about 355 miles southeast of <LOCATION> Lima </LOCATION>. Six other people were on the vehicle but did not suffer serious injuries.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881203-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-03-88 0504EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Fernald Bjt   12-03 0690</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Fernald, Bjt,0713</SECOND>
<HEAD>Ohio Announces Fernald Cleanup Agreement</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN NOLAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CINCINNATI (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A historic agreement giving <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> the authority to regulate the federal cleanup of a uranium plant was panned by some neighbors, who plan to pursue their lawsuit against the nuclear weapons factory. Some <PERSON> Fernald </PERSON> residents complained that the agreement between the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> and <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> approved by a federal judge Friday fails to commit the agency to spending the $ 1 billion it estimates is needed for the cleanup. `` I do n't really see a commitment that cleanup will be done and I do n't see a timetable as to when it will be done,'' said <PERSON> Lisa </PERSON> <PERSON> Crawford </PERSON>, spokeswoman for <ORGANIZATION> Fernald </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Residents </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION>. Residents also pointed out that the pact provides no money for victims of alleged radioactive contamination from the plant, and that the state has agreed to give up any right to sue the <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> or factory contractors. But officials said the consent decree approved here by <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Judge </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Arthur </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Spiegel </ORGANIZATION> is a historic document allowing <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> to enforce state environmental regulatory power over the cleanup of the plant, which processes uranium for nuclear weapons assembled elsewhere. The agreement also requires the department to pay the state about $ 1 million in penalties and to reimburse <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> for overseeing the cleanup. The Energy Department has admitted that the plant emitted radioactive uranium dust into the atmosphere over three decades. The plant, known as the Feed Materials Production Center, sits on 1,050 acres 18 miles northwest of <LOCATION> Cincinnati </LOCATION> above the <LOCATION> Great </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> aquifer, a water source for 2 million people. <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON>, spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>'s <LOCATION> Oak </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ridge </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Tenn. </LOCATION>, operations, which include <PERSON> Fernald </PERSON>, said the agreement is evidence of intent to clean up the plant. He said it is not intended as an admission of wrongdoing. Sen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Ohio </LOCATION>, who announced the agreement with <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> Attorney General <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON> <PERSON> Celebrezze </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, said he hoped the decree will prompt <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to give high priority to cleanups of 17 Energy Department plants nationwide, including <PERSON> Fernald </PERSON>. <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON> said the <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> estimates it will cost $ 175 billion to clean up the 17 sites over the next 35 years. Only $ 300 million is budgeted for the job next year, he said. <PERSON> Celebrezze </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> Ohio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> Director <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Shank </PERSON> said <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> will pursue two federal lawsuits against the <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>. The agreement grew out of two years of negotiations in those cases. <PERSON> Stanley </PERSON> <PERSON> Chesley </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Cincinnati </LOCATION> lawyer for the plant's neighbors, said the settlement gives the state no authority over radioactive wastes stored at the plant. <PERSON> Chesley </PERSON> said the neighbors will proceed with their $ 300 million class-action suit at a <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> hearing Dec. 16 in <LOCATION> Cincinnati </LOCATION>. `` We have every intention of going forward,'' he said. Plant neighbor <PERSON> Marvin </PERSON> <PERSON> Clawson </PERSON>, who's represented in the class-action lawsuit, said the agreement falls short of what the Energy Department should do. `` It mainly addressed the hazardous-waste problem, not the radioactive waste problem,'' said <PERSON> Clawson </PERSON>, who lives four miles from the plant. `` They've hardly admitted to anything yet.'' <PERSON> Celebrezze </PERSON> and <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON> said the decree is historic because it gives a state a court-enforceable order with which to pressure the <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> to clean up a nuclear facility `` The decree also extends <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>'s jurisdiction over <ORGANIZATION> Fernald </ORGANIZATION> to all state and federal hazardous-waste law and regulations,'' <PERSON> Celebrezze </PERSON> said. Both men said it is the first such agreement they know of in the nation. The 37-year-old plant has supplied uranium to the <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>'s Rocky Flats plant in <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> Hanford </LOCATION> reactors in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> state, the <LOCATION> Savannah </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> plant in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Oak </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ridge </LOCATION> nuclear complex. The <LOCATION> Savannah </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> reactors are shut down because of problems there, and the closure of the Rocky Flats plant is reportedly being considered. The Fernald plant has been halted by a strike that began Oct. 7. Energy Department officials have said they expect production to resume when the strike ends, but declined to comment on the plant's long-term status A department report is due out Dec. 15 on the status of aging nuclear weapons plants nationwide.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881203-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-03-88 0510EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-India-Nudity     12-03 0152</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-India-Nudity,0156</SECOND>
<HEAD>Goa Bans Nudity On Beaches</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW DELHI, India (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Public nudity has been banned in <LOCATION> Goa </LOCATION>, whose white sandy beaches have long attracted tourists searching for the allover suntan, <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Trust </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> India </ORGANIZATION> said today. Plainclothes policemen have been posted on the beaches of the former <LOCATION> Portuguese </LOCATION> enclave, and patrol boats will keep watch to enforce the ban, <ORGANIZATION> PTI </ORGANIZATION> said. `` Nudism is not allowed and violators are liable to punishment,'' say billboards set up at all major beaches in the west coast resort. <ORGANIZATION> PTI </ORGANIZATION> did not say what the punishment would be. Tens of thousands of foreign and Indian tourists visit <LOCATION> Goa </LOCATION> every year. The ban was imposed because Indians, who usually travel in families, said they were embarrassed by the public display of nudity, <ORGANIZATION> PTI </ORGANIZATION> said. Goans who operate tourist resorts also complained that nude sunbathing was a bad influence on their children, the news agency said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881203-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-03-88 0511EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-StuckElevator     12-03 0258</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Stuck Elevator,0268</SECOND>
<HEAD>Four Stuck In Elevator Overnight</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LA CROSSE, Wis. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Four people freed from a stalled elevator after spending the night said they kept their spirits up by playing cards and imagining worse predicaments. The four were freed Friday morning after more than 14 hours in the 4-foot-square elevator in this <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> city. `` We were trying to decide what would be worse than this,'' <PERSON> Karen </PERSON> <PERSON> Nordgren </PERSON>, 34, said. `` So I asked everyone, Would you rather go into major surgery or go through this again? We all decided surgery.'' <PERSON> Nordgren </PERSON>, <PERSON> Sandra </PERSON> <PERSON> Lehmann </PERSON>, 39; <PERSON> Adeline </PERSON> `` Kitty'' <PERSON> Reinhart </PERSON>, 59; and her husband, <PERSON> Raymond </PERSON>, 59, said they shared vitamin C tablets and a common toilet made from a plastic shopping bag neatly tied and tucked in a corner. <PERSON> Nordgren </PERSON> and <PERSON> Lehmann </PERSON> are beauticians at a third-floor beauty shop in the building. `` Normally, we never take the elevator when we leave,'' <PERSON> Nordgren </PERSON> said. But she and <PERSON> Lehmann </PERSON> decided to enter the elevator because the <ORGANIZATION> Reinharts </ORGANIZATION> were already in it and were holding the door for them, she said. The elevator became stuck shortly before 6 p.m. Thursday. `` I did n't think that I was going to get out of there alive,'' <PERSON> Lehmann </PERSON> said. She said she eventually overcame her panic and tore a metal plate from a telephone box inside the elevator. She then used it to pry open the elevator door, so fresh air could enter the elevator. The four were not discovered until shortly after 7 a.m., when the owner of a business in the building arrived.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881203-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-03-88 0441EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a PM-BoardwalkPerformer Bjt   12-03 0515</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Boardwalk Performer, Bjt,0531</SECOND>
<HEAD>Quadriplegic Woman Who Plays Keyboard With Mouth Challenging
Anti-begging Law</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOYCE A. VENEZIA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ATLANTIC CITY, N.J. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A quadriplegic woman who says she makes $ 2,000 a week playing an electric organ with her mouth is challenging the city's anti-begging ordinance so she can continue her Boardwalk performances in front of casinos. <PERSON> Celestine </PERSON> <PERSON> Tate </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> Municipal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> hearing was postponed Friday, but her lawyers said they were confident they can reach an out-of-court agreement with the city. The 33-year-old woman solicits money from tourists by playing a portable electric keyboard with her tongue and lips. Birth defects left her arms and legs undeveloped, and family members move her on a gurney. Ms. <PERSON> Tate </PERSON> said she averages $ 2,000 a week, enough to send her two daughters to private school. In the past several years, she has accumulated dozens of summonses from police enforcing this gambling resort's anti-begging ordinance. On Friday, she was in court to face 23 more. Ms. <PERSON> Tate </PERSON>'s attorneys presented a motion challenging the ordinance's constitutionality on grounds that it violates her right of self-expression. `` There is a constitutional right to express oneself artistically and musically,'' argued attorney <PERSON> Justin </PERSON> <PERSON> Loughry </PERSON>. City Prosecutor <PERSON> Steven </PERSON> <PERSON> Smoger </PERSON> said he had inadequate time to review the last-minute motion, and said it should be dismissed. Judge <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Weekes </PERSON> agreed to delay the hearing to give <PERSON> Smoger </PERSON> time to go over the motion and to give Ms. <PERSON> Tate </PERSON>'s attorneys time to continue negotiating with the city. `` I feel like my head is still on the chopping block, because what they decide will determine my future and my life,'' Ms. <PERSON> Tate </PERSON> said afterward. `` I believe that the Lord knows somebody's rights were violated, so he sent me here to prove it.'' Ms. <PERSON> Tate </PERSON> said that even though the matter is unresolved, she will return to the Boardwalk today to perform. <PERSON> Smoger </PERSON> had been prepared to argue that Ms. <PERSON> Tate </PERSON> violated an agreement made with the city two years ago. After a <ORGANIZATION> Superior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> trial in 1986, a subsequent lawsuit and a lot of publicity, the city agreed to allow Ms. <PERSON> Tate </PERSON> to perform on the <LOCATION> Boardwalk </LOCATION>. The conditions were that she must stay near <LOCATION> Arkansas </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Avenue </LOCATION> and obtain a permit. <PERSON> Smoger </PERSON> said Friday that Ms. <PERSON> Tate </PERSON> had done neither. `` Apparently she became disgruntled because <PERSON> Caesar </PERSON>'s -LRB- hotel-casino -RRB- was hiring outdoor bands and it cut into her gratuities, so she moved in front of fire doors at <ORGANIZATION> Bally </ORGANIZATION>'s -LRB- Park Place Casino Hotel -RRB-,'' <PERSON> Smoger </PERSON> said Ms. <PERSON> Tate </PERSON> acknowledged that she failed to buy insurance for a permit. Her attorney, <PERSON> Joan </PERSON> <PERSON> Freedman </PERSON> <PERSON> Meyer </PERSON>, said the city offered her standard one-day <LOCATION> Boardwalk </LOCATION> permits normally used for parades, which require a $ 1 million insurance bond. `` That's an unreasonable demand on someone who just plays the keyboard with her tongue,'' Ms. <PERSON> Meyer </PERSON> said. `` The rolling chairs on the Boardwalk are only required to carry a $ 300,000 policy, and they're carrying passengers.'' <PERSON> Smoger </PERSON> agreed with Ms. <PERSON> Tate </PERSON>'s lawyers that the 1986 agreement was vaguely worded. `` But even if this is resolved, we still have to settle the charges,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881203-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-03-88 0518EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-WeatherpageWeather     12-03 0407</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Weatherpage Weather,0419</SECOND>
<HEAD>Big Chill In Deep South</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Brisk weather chilled the South today as a high-pressure system expanded from <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> into <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s southeast quarter, generating light winds and making the mercury plummet. Temperatures early this morning were in the 20s and 30s from <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> to northern <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>. Freeze warnings were in effect through southern <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION>, northern <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> and the Carolinas' coast. The only notable precipitation across the nation was in northern <LOCATION> Vermont </LOCATION>, where widely scattered snow fell. Skies were mostly clear across much of the nation, but cloudy skies covered central <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> and clouds and dense fog were reported in much of the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Northwest </LOCATION>. Today's forecast called for showers over much of <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION>, with rain turning to snow over the <LOCATION> Upper </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION>; widely scattered snow in northwest <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION>; and gusty winds through the central Plains and upper <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION>. High temperatures were forecast in the 30s in the northern <LOCATION> Rockies </LOCATION>, from <LOCATION> northeast </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION>, the upper <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION> and northern sections of the upper <LOCATION> Great </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lakes </LOCATION> and in northern <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION>; the 60s from the central <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> coast to central <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION>, southern <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, western <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION>, much of the lower <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION>, southern sections of the lower <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION> and from the central Gulf Coast to northern <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> and the middle and southern <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> coast; the 70s in <LOCATION> Southern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> and parts of the desert <ORGANIZATION> Southwest </ORGANIZATION>, central and eastern <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> and southern <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>; and in the 40s and 50s in the rest of the country. Temperatures around the nation at 2 a.m. EST ranged from 11 degrees at <LOCATION> Craig </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Colo. </LOCATION>, to 64 degrees at <LOCATION> Key </LOCATION> <LOCATION> West </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>. Other reports: _ East: <ORGANIZATION> Atlanta </ORGANIZATION> 32 fair; <ORGANIZATION> Boston </ORGANIZATION> 39 cloudy; <ORGANIZATION> Buffalo </ORGANIZATION> 37 windy; <LOCATION> Charleston </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> S.C. </LOCATION> 35 fair; <ORGANIZATION> Cincinnati </ORGANIZATION> 34 fair; <ORGANIZATION> Cleveland </ORGANIZATION> 34 fair; <ORGANIZATION> Detroit </ORGANIZATION> 34 fair; <ORGANIZATION> Miami </ORGANIZATION> 60 cloudy; <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> 38 fair; <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION> 34 fair; <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION> 31 fair; <LOCATION> Portland </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Maine </ORGANIZATION> 35 cloudy; <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> 37 _ Central: Bismarck 37 fair; <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> 41 fair; Dallas-Fort Worth 46 fair; <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION> 26 fair; <PERSON> Des </PERSON> <PERSON> Moines </PERSON> 39 fair; <LOCATION> Indianapolis </LOCATION> 37 fair; <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> 44 fair; Minneapolis-St. <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> 30 fair; <ORGANIZATION> Nashville </ORGANIZATION> 29 fair; <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION> 38 fair; <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Louis </ORGANIZATION> 47 _ West: <ORGANIZATION> Albuquerque </ORGANIZATION> 29 fair; <ORGANIZATION> Anchorage </ORGANIZATION> 19 snow; <LOCATION> Las </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vegas </LOCATION> 42 fair; <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> 60 partly cloudy; <LOCATION> Phoenix </LOCATION> 53 fair; <LOCATION> Salt </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> 24 foggy; <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Diego </LOCATION> 54 fair; <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> 52 cloudy; <ORGANIZATION> Seattle </ORGANIZATION> 40 foggy _ <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>: <ORGANIZATION> Montreal </ORGANIZATION> 36 partly cloudy; <ORGANIZATION> Toronto </ORGANIZATION> 32 fair
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881203-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-03-88 0521EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Bush-Hanukkah 1stLd-Writethru a0805 12-03 0168</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bush-Hanukkah, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0805,220</SECOND>
<NOTE>Eds: SUBS 1st graf to CORRECT beginning of Hanukkah to tonight;
picks up 2nd graf pvs, bgng: ``On Saturday...''</NOTE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here is a message from President-elect <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> on the Jewish holiday of Hanukkah, which begins tonight, as released by the office of the vice president: On Saturday night, Jewish Americans will light the first of eight candles as the eight-day Jewish holiday, Hanukkah, the Festival of Lights, begins. <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> and I extend to everyone celebrating Hannukah our best wishes for a happy holiday as we recall the words of the prophet <PERSON> Zechariah </PERSON>, `` Not by might, nor by power, but by My Spirit saith the Lord of hosts.'' The triumph of religious liberty shines like a beacon for the world to see. Our forefathers, guided by that same light, struggled to come to this land in a similar pursuit of the freedom to worship. Upon our faith in the Lord rests the great strength of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881203-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-03-88 0522EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Soviet-Exile     12-03 0476</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Soviet-Exile,0489</SECOND>
<HEAD>Soviet Official Says Internal Exile To Be Eliminated</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ANN IMSE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MOSCOW (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> will eliminate the infamous practice of forced internal exile in a planned reform of the criminal code, according to a news report. The newspaper <ORGANIZATION> Sovietskaya </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rossia </ORGANIZATION> on Friday quoted Lt. Gen. <PERSON> Ivan </PERSON> <PERSON> Katargin </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Interior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> as saying, `` Exile is being ruled out as inexpedient.'' Internal exile as a form of punishment dates to the czars and has been used against criminals, revolutionaries, political prisoners, their relatives and, during the worst of <PERSON> Josef </PERSON> <PERSON> Stalin </PERSON>'s purges, people deemed `` socially dangerous.'' Whole populations have been deported from their homes to <LOCATION> Siberia </LOCATION> and the far north, including returning prisoners of war, farmers during the period of collectivization in the 1930s and residents of the <LOCATION> Baltic </LOCATION> republics and ethnic Germans during World War II. <PERSON> Katargin </PERSON> was quoted as saying exile will be eliminated as part of a revision of the entire criminal justice system. The changes will reduce prison sentences and substitute fines, suspended sentences and other lesser punishments for many offenses. Since 1980, the proportion of convicted criminals sentenced to imprisonment has dropped from 56 percent to 32 to 34 percent, <PERSON> Katargin </PERSON> was quoted as saying. After the new criminal code is passed, it is expected to drop to 22 percent to 24 percent, according to the report. It was not clear from <PERSON> Katargin </PERSON>'s statements to the newspaper whether the reform would end deportation from the country as well as internal exile. Nobel Prize-winning author <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON> <PERSON> Solzhenitsyn </PERSON> was stripped of his citizenship and deported in 1974, while human rights activist and nuclear scientist <PERSON> Andrei </PERSON> <PERSON> Sakharov </PERSON> was sentenced to internal exile. <PERSON> Sakharov </PERSON> was exiled from his home in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> to the city of <LOCATION> Gorky </LOCATION> in January 1980 for criticizing the Soviet intervention in <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>. He was released in December 1986 after receiving a telephone call from Soviet leader <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>. Exile has often been used as a secondary punishment following a term of imprisonment. Dissident <PERSON> Yuri </PERSON> <PERSON> Orlov </PERSON>, who was sent to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> in 1986 as part of the deal that resulted in the Soviets' release of news correspondent <PERSON> Nicholas </PERSON> <PERSON> Daniloff </PERSON> and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>' release of suspected spy <PERSON> Gennady </PERSON> <PERSON> Zakharov </PERSON>, spent two years in the Arctic town of <LOCATION> Kobyai </LOCATION> after completing a term in a labor camp. Some internal exiles have been sent to a specific area, while others are simply banished from living in their hometowns or any of the six largest cities in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. In the past, some were exiled to a specific isolated settlement to find on arrival that the only place to live is a labor camp and the only food is delivered to the camp mess hall. More typically, exiles could settle and find work. But for intellectuals, scientists and artists, banishment effectively ended their careers.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881203-0025 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-03-88 0526EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Sun-TimesTalks     12-03 0323</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Sun-Times Talks,0335</SECOND>
<HEAD>Walkout Averted at Sun-Times</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CHICAGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Newsroom employees at the <ORGANIZATION> Chicago </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sun-Times </ORGANIZATION> have a tentative contract for the second time in 10 days, and union and management officials for the city's second-largest newspaper believe the new pact will win approval. `` Short of a strike, this is the best package we can bring to the membership,'' <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Gibbons </PERSON>, chief negotiator for <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Newspaper </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guild </ORGANIZATION>, said after the agreement was announced Friday. `` I feel confident they'll accept it'' in a ratification vote Monday, <PERSON> Gibbons </PERSON> said. The newspaper's chief negotiatior, <PERSON> Brian </PERSON> <PERSON> Fantl </PERSON>, also praised the agreement. `` Both sides have worked hard and hopefully the -LRB- union's -RRB- members will accept it,'' he said. `` We were able to clear up some misunderstandings and reach an agreement.'' <ORGANIZATION> Sun-Times </ORGANIZATION> workers refused to consider a tentative settlement reached Nov. 22 after a dispute developed over pension conditions. Talks resumed Thursday, with a strike deadline set for noon Friday. Shortly after the deadline, the new agreement was announced. Reporters and others in the newsroom, many of whom had their coats in hand waiting to start a picket line, returned to their desks as word of the settlement spread, said <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Lehmann </PERSON>, a union spokesman and religion reporter. About 250 reporters, editorial and other newsroom workers belong to the guild and have been working without a contract since June 1. Friday's settlement calls for a $ 500 cash bonus Jan. 1 rather than July 1, and 3 percent wage increases in the second and third years of the contract. The night city editor's position will be exempt from the union. Pension benefits were increased by about 6 percent, <PERSON> Gibbons </PERSON> said. The pay scale at the newspaper currently ranges from $ 625 a week for starting reporters to $ 895 for reporters with five years' experience The <ORGANIZATION> Sun-Times </ORGANIZATION> has an estimated circulation of 605,000 daily and 614,000 on Sundays. The <ORGANIZATION> Chicago </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tribune </ORGANIZATION>'s circulation is estimated at 765,000 daily and 1.11 million on Sundays.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881203-0026 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-03-88 0530EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-LetterstoSanta     12-03 0617</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Letters to Santa,0638</SECOND>
<HEAD>Alaskan Seeks to Restore Santa's Image With Letters</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BRIAN S. AKRE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>JUNEAU, Alaska (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Bloom </PERSON> is asking children nationwide to keep their gift lists and instead write <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> and his wife about their feelings this holiday season. <PERSON> Bloom </PERSON>, a 39-year-old author of children's books and part-time teacher in <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>'s capital, promises that <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Merry </PERSON> <PERSON> Claus </PERSON> will write back free of charge. `` I want the kids to describe their families, their preparations for Christmas, what they think the spirit of Christmas is, their hopes for world peace and, most importantly, to name somebody who's doing a good deed,'' <PERSON> Bloom </PERSON> said recently Bloom's `` Heartlight Letterline'' is not his first holiday letter-writing program. Seven years ago, while living in the western <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> town of <LOCATION> Nome </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Bloom </PERSON> invented the characters `` Bubbie and <PERSON> Zadie </PERSON>'' as a Jewish alternative to Mr. and Mrs. <PERSON> Claus </PERSON>. He invited children to write <PERSON> Bubbie </PERSON> and <PERSON> Zadie </PERSON> and share their feelings and joy about the holiday season. `` When I was a kid growing up in <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION>, I felt left out of the -LRB- Christmas -RRB- season,'' recalled <PERSON> Bloom </PERSON>, who is of Jewish descent. `` That was my main impetus to begin Bubbie and <PERSON> Zadie </PERSON>. I thought maybe there could be something for Jewish kids to participate in.'' After news articles about <PERSON> Bubbie </PERSON> and <PERSON> Zadie </PERSON> appeared across the nation, <PERSON> Bloom </PERSON> received thousands of letters from children of all faiths. `` In Yiddish, <PERSON> Bubbie </PERSON> and <PERSON> Zadie </PERSON> means <PERSON> Grandma </PERSON> and Grandpa, and basically they are everybody's <PERSON> Grandma </PERSON> and Grandpa,'' <PERSON> Bloom </PERSON> said. `` They represent the love that grandparents have for grandchildren, and I think that's why it worked. I think if I had created Father Hanukkah or something, it would n't have been as endearing.'' <PERSON> Bloom </PERSON> said he was motivated to keep the program going by the wonder and spirit of childhood reflected in the letters. `` I remember one of the first letters I got said, ` Dear Bubbie and <PERSON> Zadie </PERSON>: Do you happen to know my Bubbie and <PERSON> Zadie </PERSON>, <PERSON> Herman </PERSON> and <PERSON> Sarah </PERSON> from <LOCATION> Cincinnati </LOCATION>?' _ as if these grandparents in <LOCATION> Nome </LOCATION> know all grandparents. The children's world is an amazing world,'' he said. <PERSON> Bloom </PERSON> wrote a 1983 book about Bubbie and <PERSON> Zadie </PERSON>. Sales of the book, which includes an address, have kept dozens of letters coming to the mythical couple each year. Last fall, he decided to apply the same letter-writing idea to <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Claus </LOCATION> to open it up to more children and to counter the materialism that has become part of the season. `` There's a lot of these little mail-order things where for $ 5 you can have a Christmas letter sent from <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Claus </LOCATION> to your kid, but it's just a commercial thing and there's not much feeling to it,'' <PERSON> Bloom </PERSON> said. `` As I see <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Merry </PERSON>, they are everybody's grandparents. It fits in, I think, with the <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Claus </LOCATION> myth.'' <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION>'s wife figures prominently because `` spiritual things should be male and female whenever possible,'' <PERSON> Bloom </PERSON> said. `` A little girl, for instance, might have something personal to tell <PERSON> Merry </PERSON>,'' he said. <PERSON> Bloom </PERSON> said his Jewish background should not disqualify him from perpetuating a symbol of a Christian holiday. `` Jewish-smewish. We're all related in this world and I, myself, believe in a philosophy of universalism. I'm deeply Jewish in my background and I'm proud of it. But I'm a universalist in that I do n't really believe in any one religion per se.'' <PERSON> Bloom </PERSON> said he will answer all the letters and plans to recruit friends to help if necessary. `` I get enormous satisfaction in doing this.''
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 Editors: Letters should include a return address and be sent by Dec. 15 to: <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> and Merry Claus, P.O. Box 555, <LOCATION> Auke </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Station </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Juneau </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> 99821.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881203-0027 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-03-88 0536EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-CubanDetainees     12-03 0599</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Cuban Detainees,0618</SECOND>
<HEAD>U.S. Takes Five Cubans Home In First Deportation Since Prison
Uprisings</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By HOYT HARWELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BIRMINGHAM, Ala. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A lawyer who helped end prison riots by Cuban detainees criticized the deportation of five men who fled <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> in the 1980 Mariel boatlift as an unjustified normalization of relations with <PERSON> Fidel </PERSON> <PERSON> Castro </PERSON>'s government. A federal Marshal's Service airplane ferried five handcuffed Cuban prisoners, all convicted of crimes in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, from <LOCATION> Birmingham </LOCATION> to an airfield near <LOCATION> Havana </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION>, on Friday. They were the first Cubans deported since a repatriation agreement with the <LOCATION> Caribbean </LOCATION> island nation ignited riots at federal prisons in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Oakdale </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> La. </LOCATION>, last year. `` We hope to have many of these flights,'' said <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman <PERSON> Deborah </PERSON> <PERSON> Vurstion-Wade </PERSON>. `` It's a tragic day for the aspirations of the <LOCATION> Cuban </LOCATION> people to a free <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> without <PERSON> Castro </PERSON>,'' said <PERSON> Rafael </PERSON> <PERSON> Penalver </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> attorney who negotiated a settlement with Cuban detainees that ended the riots. `` This is normalization in criminal wrappings.'' When the men, accompanied by two <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> guards, got off the plane in <LOCATION> Havana </LOCATION>, three of them `` knelt down and kissed the ground,'' Ms. <PERSON> Vurstion-Wade </PERSON> said. She said about 20 Cuban officials met them, exchanged documents with <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials, and took the five away on a bus. She said she did not know where the bus took them. The agreement with <PERSON> Castro </PERSON> calls for up to 100 Cubans a month to be returned. About 500 are still in custody of the 2,746 <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> agreed in 1984 to take back, <PERSON> Carla </PERSON> <PERSON> Dudeck </PERSON>, coordinator for the <ORGANIZATION> Coalition </ORGANIZATION> to Support Cuban Detainees, said in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>. The others have been paroled, and some have appeals pending. A federal judge in <LOCATION> Birmingham </LOCATION> is to rule next week on a temporary injunction against the deportation of 10 other Cubans from a federal prison at <LOCATION> Talladega </LOCATION>, 60 miles east of <LOCATION> Birmingham </LOCATION>. The judge last week refused to halt deportation of three of the five who left Friday; the other two did not fight repatriation. The three unsuccessfully took their cases to an appellate court in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>, which ruled 8-1 against them Friday. `` This is a giant leap toward normalization with <PERSON> Castro </PERSON>,'' <PERSON> Penalver </PERSON> said. `` It's the normalization of our deportation laws and the application of normal deportation laws to the community. `` For 30 years it has been <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> policy to defer deportation of Cuban nationals until Cuban rights were restored in <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION>. Nothing has changed in <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> to justify a change of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> policy at this time. `` Furthermore, I think it's inconsistent and self-defeating for the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> to send human beings who have completed serving their sentences for whatever wrong they committed here to the very same jails that the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> condemns for the atrocities that take place there,'' <PERSON> Penalver </PERSON> said. The Cubans who fought deportation claimed they would face mistreatment in their homeland. In the 1980 boatlift, about 125,000 people, some of them convicts or mentally ill, sailed illegally from <LOCATION> Mariel </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION>, to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. Friday's flight was the first since a 1987 U.S.-Cuban agreement to resume deportations. When the pact became known, Cubans rioted for 11 days at <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Oakdale </LOCATION>, with 125 people held hostage, one inmate killed and massive damage to both prisons. The five returned to <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> are <PERSON> Miguel </PERSON> <PERSON> Beitia-Socarraz </PERSON>, 28, who pleaded guilty to second-degree burglary; <PERSON> Onel </PERSON> <PERSON> Calzado-Garlobo </PERSON>, 43, convicted in 1982 of attempted sexual assault charges involving a 13-year-old girl; <PERSON> Rene </PERSON> <PERSON> Maurin-Oliva </PERSON>, who pleaded guilty to theft and battery; and <PERSON> Hector </PERSON> <PERSON> Hernandez-Quesada </PERSON> and <PERSON> Angel </PERSON> <PERSON> Meneses-Hernandez </PERSON>, who did not fight deportation and about whom little was known.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881203-0028 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-03-88 0537EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Obit-Mee     12-03 0410</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Obit-Mee,0425</SECOND>
<HEAD>Botanical Artist Who Specialized In The Amazon Area Dies</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Botanical artist and explorer <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Mee </PERSON>, who braved blood-sucking gnats, malaria and drunken gold prospectors in pursuit of rare flowers in the deepest Amazonian rain forests, died in a car accident, her family said. Mrs. <PERSON> Mee </PERSON> was 79. She was killed Wednesday in an auto crash near <LOCATION> Seagrave </LOCATION> in central <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>, her family announced Friday. In 1952, she and her second husband, <PERSON> Greville </PERSON> <PERSON> Mee </PERSON>, went to live in <LOCATION> Rio </LOCATION> <LOCATION> de </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Janeiro </LOCATION>. She had recently returned to <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> to open an exhibition of her paintings at the <LOCATION> Royal </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Botanic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gardens </LOCATION> in west <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>. Mrs. <PERSON> Mee </PERSON> was also in <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> for the publication last month of her diaries, `` In Search of the Flowers of the <ORGANIZATION> Amazon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forests </ORGANIZATION>,'' and a lecture tour. Mrs. <PERSON> Mee </PERSON> was born near <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> and studied art as a child. She made the first of her 15 <ORGANIZATION> Amazon </ORGANIZATION> expeditions in 1956 to observe, collect and paint flowers. Her last trip there was in May when she traveled to the <LOCATION> Igapo </LOCATION> forest on <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Rio </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Negro </LOCATION> to paint the rare, night-blooming Amazonian moonflower. `` As I stood there with the dim outline of the forest all around, I was spellbound. Then the first petal began to move and then another as the flower burst into life,'' she wrote in her diaries. Mrs. <PERSON> Mee </PERSON> packed a gun with her brushes and watercolors. On one journey, drunken gold prospectors burst into her hut in an Indian village, she wrote. She told them it was not proper to enter a lady's hut when the lady was alone, and they left. Hours later, their leader returned, but when he found himself looking down the barrel of a .32 - caliber revolver he left, she wrote, Other hazards included snakes, poisonous spiders, blood-sucking buffalo gnats and several bouts of malaria and Mrs. <PERSON> Mee </PERSON> also became a leader in the campaign to conserve the rain forests and protect the forest Indians. In 1986, she was made a member of the <ORGANIZATION> Linnean </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION>, the prestigious botanical society named after the 18th-century Swedish botanist <PERSON> Carl </PERSON> <PERSON> von </PERSON> <PERSON> Linne </PERSON>. The recently established <ORGANIZATION> Margaret </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Amazon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Trust </ORGANIZATION> provides scholarships to help Brazilian botanists study in <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>. The trust also paid for the purchase of 60 of Mrs. <PERSON> Mee </PERSON>'s <LOCATION> Amazon </LOCATION> paintings for the Royal Botanic Gardens. Her other paintings are distributed around the world in botanical institutions and private and public collections. She is survived by her husband, <PERSON> Greville </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881203-0029 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-03-88 0554EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-CaribbeanConference     12-03 0470</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Caribbean Conference,0484</SECOND>
<HEAD>U.S. Official Praises Caribbean Initiative, Nations' Achievements</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PATRICK REYNA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MIAMI (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
