<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881230-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-30-88 0245EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Bakkers-Television     12-30 0185</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Bakkers-Television,0189</SECOND>
<HEAD>Jim And Tammy Bakker Plan To Return To Television On Monday</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CHARLOTTE, N.C. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> and <PERSON> Tammy </PERSON> <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON> begin broadcasting a new television show from their living room Monday for at least six independent television stations across the nation, according to a published report. <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON> and three of his associates were indicted this month on charges of misusing millions of dollars in <ORGANIZATION> PTL </ORGANIZATION> funds. <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON> could not be reached for comment Thursday. The Charlotte Observer in Friday's editions quoted unidentified sources as saying that the live broadcasts from the <ORGANIZATION> Bakkers </ORGANIZATION>' living room near <LOCATION> Pineville </LOCATION> will be carried on stations in <LOCATION> Albany </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Chico </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION>; and <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Diego </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON> attorney <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Toms </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Hendersonville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.C. </LOCATION>, said in a telephone interview Thursday night that the <ORGANIZATION> Bakkers </ORGANIZATION> had been preparing to return to television, but could not confirm when the return would take place. <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON> has not had a regular TV show since he resigned from <ORGANIZATION> PTL </ORGANIZATION> in March 1987 after widely publicized allegations of his 1980 sexual encounter with church secretary <PERSON> Jessica </PERSON> <PERSON> Hahn </PERSON> and payments to keep her quiet.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881230-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-30-88 0300EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-WomanTrapped     12-30 0311</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Woman Trapped,0322</SECOND>
<HEAD>Woman Spends Nearly 18 Hours In Elevator</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BEAVER DAM, Wis. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A woman says she read a prayer book and somehow managed to stay calm while trapped nearly 18 hours in a cold elevator at the high school where she works as an accountant. `` I thought it would be nice at one point to scream, rant and rave, but that would not get me anywhere,'' <PERSON> Gretchen </PERSON> <PERSON> Forrester </PERSON>, 58, said Thursday. `` So I took out my rosary and started praying. I had a beautiful prayer book with me that I read most of the night. I did n't sleep.'' Finally, at 6:30 a.m. Wednesday, <PERSON> Charlie </PERSON> <PERSON> Mann </PERSON>, interim superintendent of buildings and grounds at <ORGANIZATION> Wayland </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION> in this southeast <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION> city, asked <PERSON> Forrester </PERSON> if she was in the elevator. `` And I said, ` Yes, <PERSON> Charlie </PERSON>, get me out of here,'' she recalled. He did. <PERSON> Forrester </PERSON> was going to her office in a new building at the private school when she stepped into the elevator around 1 p.m. Tuesday. `` The elevator did n't move, but the door would n't open,'' said <PERSON> Mann </PERSON>. `` I rang the bell, I rang the bell, I rang the bell, and it did n't do me any good,'' <PERSON> Forrester </PERSON> said. `` From 1 p.m. to about 4:15 p.m. I rang the bell about every 15 minutes or when I heard a noise. After 4:30, I figured no one was coming. `` Hypothermia crossed my mind,'' she said. `` It was so cold. I had my coat on and my gloves. ... I used my purse to block vents in the walls where cold air was coming through.'' She kept ringing the bell. And she prayed. `` My faith kept me going and kept me calm,'' <PERSON> Forrester </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Forrester </PERSON> was found after a police officer told a cleaning woman at the school that a buzzer had been going off at the new building, <PERSON> Mann </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881230-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-30-88 0312EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lottery     12-30 0039</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lottery,0044</SECOND>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the winning weekly state lottery numbers picked Thursday:
</TEXT>
<HEAD>DELAWARE</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Play 4: 6-5-2-2.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>NEW JERSEY</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Pick 6 Lotto: 02; 03; 09; 20; 22; 34. Bonus: 55208.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>PENNSYLVANIA</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Big 4 Lottery: 3-4-8-8.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881230-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-30-88 0108EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Deaths 1stLd-Writethru a0750 12-30 0335</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Deaths, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0750,0342</SECOND>
<NOTE>Eds: No separates moved for the AMs cycle.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>John Mcknight</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SUMTER, S.C. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> McKnight </PERSON>, former managing editor of The -LRB- Sumter -RRB- Item, died Tuesday. He was 76. <PERSON> McKnight </PERSON> began his newspaper career at the age of 6 when he sold the The -LRB- <LOCATION> Charleston </LOCATION> -RRB- Evening Post at a railroad station in his native <LOCATION> Williamsburg </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>. He was a sports editor and wire editor at the <LOCATION> Florence </LOCATION> Morning News before moving to <LOCATION> Sumter </LOCATION> in 1936 as news editor. <PERSON> McKnight </PERSON> retired in 1967 from The Item. He also was a past president of the <ORGANIZATION> South </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Carolina </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>Julius Meier</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PORTLAND, Ore. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Julius </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> `` </PERSON> <PERSON> Jack </PERSON><PERSON> '' </PERSON> <PERSON> Meier </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, retired chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Meier </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <ORGANIZATION> Frank </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> department stores, died Tuesday of congestive heart failure. He was 76. <PERSON> Meier </PERSON> was the son <PERSON> Julius </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Meier </PERSON>, president of <ORGANIZATION> Meier </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> Frank </PERSON>, and grandson of <PERSON> Aaron </PERSON> <PERSON> Meier </PERSON>, who in 1857 founded the mercantile outlet that grew into <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION>'s largest department store chain. In 1965, <PERSON> Meier </PERSON> guided the negotiations that led to <ORGANIZATION> Meier </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> becoming part of the May Department Stores chain. He continued as president and general manager of the Portland-based <ORGANIZATION> Meier </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <ORGANIZATION> Frank </ORGANIZATION> stores until 1969, when he was elevated to board chairman. He retired in 1972.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>Charlotte Peters</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ST. LOUIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Charlotte </PERSON> <PERSON> Peters </PERSON>, the star of a popular local television show that spanned more than 20 years, died Wednesday. She was in he 70s. <PERSON> Mrs. </PERSON> <PERSON> Peters </PERSON> was a <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Louis </LOCATION> housewife when she won a talent contest in 1947 singing `` I'd Be Lost Without You'' and received a weeklong guest spot on the `` To The Ladies'' show hosted by <PERSON> Russ </PERSON> <PERSON> Severin </PERSON> on <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Louis </LOCATION>' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> affiliate, KSD, now <ORGANIZATION> KSDK </ORGANIZATION>. Because Mrs. <PERSON> Peters </PERSON> was so poplular in the weeklong stint, the station kept her on as a regular. Several years later, the show became `` The Charlotte Peters Show.'' The show later moved to the <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> affiliate, <ORGANIZATION> KTVI </ORGANIZATION> and aired until 1969.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881230-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-30-88 0316EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-ReligionStories     12-30 0419</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Religion Stories,0433</SECOND>
<HEAD>Religion Writers Vote Swaggart Scandal Top Story Of 1988</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MINNEAPOLIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The defrocking of TV evangelist <PERSON> Jimmy </PERSON> <PERSON> Swaggart </PERSON> after he allegedly paid a prostitute to pose naked and talk dirty was the top religion story of 1988, says a national poll of religion writers released today. <PERSON> Swaggart </PERSON> was also picked as the religion newsmaker of the year in the poll of the <ORGANIZATION> Religion </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Newswriter </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>'s 200-plus active members, who write for newspapers, magazines and news services. Forty-three members responded. <PERSON> Swaggart </PERSON> stayed out of the pulpit for three months after tearfully confessing to an unspecified sin. But he refused to accept a one-year suspension imposed on him by the Assemblies of God denomination and resigned from the ministry the day his defrocking was announced in April. Another television evangelist, <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON>, also figured in the news in 1988, but his indictment this month by a federal grand jury on charges he misused millions of dollars from his <ORGANIZATION> PTL </ORGANIZATION> ministry came too late in the year to be included in the poll. The protest campaign against showings of the controversial movie `` The Last Temptation of Christ'' ranked second in the poll. Evangelical and fundamentalist Christians denounced the film as blasphemous. Third was the election of <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Harris </PERSON> as suffragen -LRB- assistant -RRB- bishop of the <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Episcopal </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Diocese </LOCATION>, making her the first woman bishop in the worldwide Anglican Communion. The other top 10 religion stories, in order, were: _ Two religious leaders, <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, wage aggressive but unsuccessful campaigns for presidential nominations; <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> elected with support from the religious right. _ Reform policies help ease some religious restrictions in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> as celebrations marking the millennium of Christianity there are attended by spiritual dignitaries from 100 nations. _ Scientific tests find the Shroud of <LOCATION> Turin </LOCATION>, long venerated as the burial cloth of <PERSON> Jesus </PERSON>, to be medieval in origin. _ The Operation Rescue anti-abortion group sponsors demonstrations blocking entrances to abortion clinics, with some 2,000 protesters arrested in 27 cities. _ Rebel Roman Catholic Archbishop <PERSON> Marcel </PERSON> <PERSON> Lefebvre </PERSON> consecrates bishops in defiance of <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION> and is excommunicated. _ The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Churches </ORGANIZATION>, in a financial crisis, calls for another reorganization and hints at forming a broader ecumenical structure including <ORGANIZATION> Roman </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> and evangelical churches. _ Orthodox Jewish religious parties demanding controversial amendment to the Law of Return appear to hold balance of power after election in <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>. The poll was conducted by <PERSON> Willmar </PERSON> <PERSON> Thorkelson </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Minneapolis </LOCATION>, a past president of the <ORGANIZATION> Religion </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Newswriters </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881230-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-30-88 0317EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-HatedMaverick     12-30 0856</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Hated Maverick,0884</SECOND>
<HEAD>Union Leader Gives Thatcher Competition as Hate Figure</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By MAUREEN JOHNSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BROMLEY, England (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Other labor leaders shun <PERSON> Eric </PERSON> <PERSON> Hammond </PERSON> and he rivals <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> as a hate figure for the left, but many see the maverick union boss as a natural product of the prime minister's age of enterprise. <PERSON> Hammond </PERSON> is the polecat of organized labor, particularly since his electricians' union was expelled from the national labor federation, and he appears to enjoy the role. His eyes twinkle as he lauds laws that have emasculated the once-mighty labor movement since Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> and her <ORGANIZATION> Conservative </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> won power in 1979. `` I'm only half-joking when I say we'll be erecting statues to the <ORGANIZATION> Tories </ORGANIZATION> before the end of the century,'' he said. `` Why? Because they will have saved the trade union movement from itself.'' Labor legislation in the Thatcher decade has outlawed sympathy walkouts, forced secret-ballot membership votes before strikes are called and empowered employers to sue unions for damages resulting from illegal strikes. A revolution was wrought in British working practices, and <PERSON> Hammond </PERSON>'s 360,000-member Electrical, Electronic, <ORGANIZATION> Telecommunication </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Plumbing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION> joined it. In his office at the union's elegant headquarters, a converted mansion in commuter country 10 miles from <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Hammond </PERSON> continues the union-baiting that got him banished from the <ORGANIZATION> Trades </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, the 9 million-member British labor federation. He is accused of splitting organized labor, making cozy no-strike deals with employers, invading the territory of other unions and, through a 1986 deal with publisher <PERSON> Rupert </PERSON> <PERSON> Murdoch </PERSON> to run his high-technology presses, breaking the power of newspaper production unions. <PERSON> Hammond </PERSON>, 59, is a sharp contrast and constant provocation to left-wing leaders of old, traditional unions: <PERSON> Arthur </PERSON> <PERSON> Scargill </PERSON> and his <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mineworkers </ORGANIZATION>, for instance, and the huge <ORGANIZATION> Transport </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Workers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION> with its 1,250,000 members. `` Hard times have been forced upon the unions and the way <PERSON> Eric </PERSON> <PERSON> Hammond </PERSON> has tried to solve this is through sweetheart deals with employers,'' said <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> <PERSON> Murray </PERSON>, an official of the transport union. `` A strike is always a weapon of last resort. The question is whether union officials have the right to surrender that resort.'' In September, the <ORGANIZATION> Trades </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> expelled <PERSON> Hammond </PERSON>'s electricians for refusing to abandon single-union, no-strike deals with a Japanese electronics company in <LOCATION> Wales </LOCATION> and a British food chain <PERSON> Hammond </PERSON>, unrepentant, delivered his credo in a final speech to the federation's annual conference and walked out before the expulsion vote was taken. `` Our members,'' he thundered, `` reveal an enthusiasm for the market system and its values and infuriate the sherry-party revolutionaries with their model resolutions and conference-hall rhetoric.'' He is negotiating a merger with the <ORGANIZATION> Amalgamated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Engineering </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION>, which has 800,000 members and is the nation's second largest after the transport workers. If that goes through next year, the <ORGANIZATION> Trades </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> must either take the electricians back in their new form or risk the emergence of a rival federation of the highest-skilled workers. Although <PERSON> Hammond </PERSON> is isolated, at least for now, he sees himself as the smart kid on the block, the adapter to modern realities in a bleak time for organized labor. Membership in unions belonging to the <ORGANIZATION> Trades </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> has declined from nearly 13 million to under 9 million since 1979. Nearly 50 percent of British workers belonged to unions then, but only 35 percent do now. <PERSON> Hammond </PERSON>'s background is impeccably working class. He is the son of a paper-mill timekeeper, grew up in a modest home at <LOCATION> Gravesend </LOCATION>, 20 miles east of <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>, and became an apprentice electrician at 16. He began as a leftist, he said, but moved right. Communists took over the union but were kicked out in a 1962 ballot-rigging scandal and the right has controlled it since. <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Chapple </PERSON>, <PERSON> Hammond </PERSON>'s Cockney predecessor, was the scourge of the left in the socialist <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, which unions founded and finance. <PERSON> Chapple </PERSON>, now a life peer sitting in the non-elected <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lords </ORGANIZATION>, warned his many enemies in the <ORGANIZATION> Tredes </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> when he retired four years ago: `` You think I'm right-wing? Wait till you see <PERSON> Eric </PERSON>.'' Experience bore him out. <PERSON> Hammond </PERSON> has excoriated the <ORGANIZATION> London </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> for, as he put it, consorting with `` terrorists, lesbians and other queer folk.'' He has pushed single-union deals, with or without no-strike clauses that stipulate binding arbritration. Unions have made more than 30 such arrangements, mainly with Japanese electronic companies _ often after several unions vie to offer managers the most attractive package. <PERSON> Hammond </PERSON>'s alliance with <PERSON> Murdoch </PERSON> revolutionized the newspaper industry in less than two years. When <PERSON> Murdoch </PERSON> fired 5,000 production workers in January 1986 for striking against new high-tech machinery, <PERSON> Hammond </PERSON> and his electricians moved in to run the presses. With the production unions vanquished, the rest of the national newspaper industry quickly followed suit. `` The other unions were demanding jobs for life ... and <PERSON> Murdoch </PERSON> said, ` Get lost','' <PERSON> Hammond </PERSON> said in the interview. `` I do n't see how we could have acted any differently.'' `` These deals are what our members want, and that's what it's all about _ membership. We're operating in a tough environment.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881230-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-30-88 0317EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Soviet-Sex     12-30 0711</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Soviet-Sex,0734</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bringing Glasnost To The Bedroom: Soviets Struggle With Sex</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</NOTE>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ANDREW KATELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MOSCOW (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A nation known for its squeamishness about sex is paying for its prudishness with rampant divorce and abortions, and an increasingly frustrated and puzzled populace, a Soviet sex expert says. Despite a spirit of openness and a freer discussion of once sensitive subjects, philosopher <PERSON> Igor </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kon </PERSON> believes the Soviets desperately need to engage in some frank banter about the boudoir. `` Things that newspapers in the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> already are writing about, and which even have become sensations, are n't even known by specialists here,'' said the 60-year-old doctor of philosophy. Although the social chill on discussing sex is thawing a bit, sex is still a taboo topic in a country known for its puritanism, where even the Russian language lacks a polite word for love making. On a recent televised discussion between panels of Soviet and <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> students, the Americans spoke freely about the problems of teen-age pregnancy and other sex-related subjects. But when an American asked whether there were similar woes in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, the half-joking answer was: `` We do n't have sex.'' Evidence points to the contrary in this nation of nearly 285 million people, however. Western specialists say Soviet women average nine abortions, and the number of AIDS cases, while small, is growing. Such problems makes it necessary to deal openly with sex, said <PERSON> Kon </PERSON>, who is trying to take President <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s policy of glasnost _ or openness _ behind the bedroom doors. `` If we do n't do anything ... we will create new difficulties. The stability of marriage will suffer,'' he said at a recent lecture to an overflow crowd at <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>'s House of Actors. <PERSON> Kon </PERSON> recently returned from a 3 -LCB- - month stay in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, where he visited AIDS clinics and family planning centers He told his audience that the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> is far behind the West in discussing sex. His frank talk goes against the mainstream, and his comments raised many eyebrows among an audience that ranged from young men and women clad in jeans to people in their 80s. With little poll data available to judge the Soviet public's attitude toward sex, the audience's questions offer some clues Most expressed concern over a perceived rise in pornography and homosexuality. But <PERSON> Kon </PERSON> said he does not consider recent sexually explicit Soviet movies to be pornographic and told the audience that homosexuality is natural for some people. He noted that right-wingers in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> once condemned sex education as `` a communist plot.'' But he said that sex education is desperately needed in this bastion of communism. <PERSON> Kon </PERSON> blamed Soviet authorities for the public's ignorance about sex and the resulting health and family problems. `` If a woman comes into a clinic, even a solid one in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>, and asks how to become pregnant, they will tell her,'' <PERSON> Kon </PERSON> said in his lecture. `` But if she asks how to receive pleasure from this, they will say ` We ca n't help you, it's not our speciality.''' Traditionally, Soviet women are expected only to be good mothers and housewives. `` Sexual pleasure was considered not important to marriage,'' he said. Today, however, Soviet women are demanding happy sex lives. There have been some changes, however. This year, after a 10-year struggle with censors, <PERSON> Kon </PERSON>'s book `` Introduction to Sexology'' was finally published in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. A new book, which he says will include illustrations of sexual positions, is slated for publication early next year. Sex clinics have been opened in several Soviet cities and the <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> is beginning to realize that AIDS, the high rates of divorce and abortions can not be reduced without the help of psychologists and sociologists, <PERSON> Kon </PERSON> said. This year, the <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> newspaper <ORGANIZATION> Meditsinskaya </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Gazeta </ORGANIZATION> decried a chronic shortage of condoms and printed a reader's letter saying some people were so desperate they were using balloons as a substitute. The same newspaper called for repeal of the law making homosexuality a crime. Although <PERSON> Kon </PERSON>'s talk was largely philosophical and he did not provide many specific sex tips, one woman confided to a friend afterward: `` If I had known this before, I'd be a normal person now.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881230-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-30-88 0240EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-ChemicalWeapons Bjt   12-30 0758</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Chemical Weapons, Bjt,710</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHINGTON TODAY: Trying To Reverse The Trend</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP News Analysis</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BARRY SCHWEID</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Diplomatic Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Secretary of State <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON>, in one of his last official acts, will undertake an international effort next week in <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> to roll back the proliferation of chemical weapons technology. He will represent the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> at a multinational conference in the French capital that is expected to reaffirm a 1925 protocol banning the use of chemical weapons and to encourage completion of negotiations among 40 nations in <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> of a new agreement prohibiting production. Some 20 nations, by <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> estimate, either have produced chemical weapons or are capable of manufacturing them. Among them the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> includes <LOCATION> Libya </LOCATION>, whose leader, <PERSON> Moammar </PERSON> <PERSON> Gadhafi </PERSON>, is accused by the department of supporting terrorism. <LOCATION> Libya </LOCATION> `` is one of the more recent ones, and one of the more irresponsible ones'' to reach the edge of production, said a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> official who spoke on condition of anonymity. At one time, the civilized world abhorred poison gas. But <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> discovered in the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> war that chemical weapons were effective against numerically superior Iranian forces. And some Third World countries resent interference with their chemical industries. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> stopped production in 1969, then resumed 17 years later on the grounds the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> and other potential adversaries had chemical weapons programs. Currently, chemical components and artillery shells to contain them are being produced but stockpiled separately. President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> proposed the <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> conference in a speech to the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION> last September. President-elect <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said during the election campaign in October that the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> must take the lead in making sure that nations using chemical and biological weapons are punished. `` The barriers against chemical warfare, breached as we've seen during the Iran-Iraq war, must be repaired and raised even higher,'' he said. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> vowed to make nations that use such weapons `` pay a price.'' Realistically, though, the 1925 protocol, to which 130 nations are parties, has no enforcement provisions. <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>, which denied using the weapons, is one of them. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> proposed a global ban in 1984 while twice casting tie-breaking votes in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> to continue financing <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> production. An aide explained that <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> felt that as long as the Soviets produced chemical weapons the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> should keep up. The <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> acknowledged in 1987 possession of chemical weapons, then claimed to have ceased production. A foreign ministry spokesman said 50,000 tons would be stored, the rest destroyed. Officials of the two countries have held nine sessions in <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> to plan ways to restrict proliferation. So far, the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> are the only two countries in the world to admit possessing chemical weapons. But in recent weeks the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration has accused <LOCATION> Libya </LOCATION> of having a chemical weapons plant. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, in a recent television interview, said the government has not ruled out a military strike against the plant. The <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> conference is expected to reaffirm the 1925 ban on using the weapons and to urge adoption of a verifiable ban on production, as well, by the 40-nation disarmament conference that meets in February in <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION>. Two other steps may be taken in <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION>: authorizing the secretary-general of the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> to investigate allegations of the use of chemical weapons, and some form of assistance for victims. Nearly all the 159 nations that are members of the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> are sending their foreign ministers or ambassadors to <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION>. `` You can expect an enormous turnout,'' said the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> official, who is involved in preparations for the Jan. 7-11 conference. Whatever declaration emerges, there is no way to enforce it, although sanctions may be discussed. And, the official said, `` there is a great allergy, particularly in the Arab world, to pointing fingers at their capabilities and their emerging capabilities. So that becomes a bit sensitive.'' Assuming the 40 nations in <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION>, which do not include <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Libya </LOCATION>, decide to ban the production and possession of chemical weapons, there still will be an enormous problem. `` We recognize that verification is a very complicated problem,'' the official said. `` When you are talking about not producing chemical agents, that raises all kinds of very difficult issues. Any chemical industry which can produce pesticides to kill insects can probably produce chemical agents to kill people. And that's one of the frightening parts of this whole business. They are relatively simple to construct and to make.''
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Barry </PERSON> <PERSON> Schweid </PERSON> covers diplomacy for The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881230-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-30-88 0239EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Computers Bjt   12-30 0712</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Computers, Bjt,710</SECOND>
<HEAD>Soviets May Catch Up in Computers, But Will Look to West in
Meantime</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BARTON REPPERT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Soviet President <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s restructuring drive eventually may enable Soviet computer makers to satisfy demand, but progress will be slow and <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> can be expected to keep trying to acquire Western technology, a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> scientific advisory panel says It said the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> should take a more focused and flexible approach to export controls on computers, especially since the existing curbs on many components and systems have become virtually unenforceable. The panel urged the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> to concentrate instead on striving _ together with its <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> allies and <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> _ to control leakage to the Soviet bloc of militarily valuable supercomputers and the most advanced computer manufacturing processes. `` The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> can not afford to be complacent about its computer technology strengths or base export control decisions on an assumption of an invincible lead,'' said the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> report released Thursday. Preparing the 288-page study was a 17-member committee chaired by <PERSON> Seymour </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Goodman </PERSON>, professor of management information systems and policy at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Arizona </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Tucson </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> is the principal operating agency of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Academies </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sciences </ORGANIZATION> and Engineering. The report estimated that the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> lags about five years to 10 years behind the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> in many computer technologies. `` The lag between East and <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> is now large enough that the acquisition-diversion of certain Western technologies for direct production will help the Soviets tremendously,'' it said. Referring to <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s perestroika or restructuring drive, the report said that `` if perestroika actually fails to bring about fundamental changes in the Soviet economy, collection efforts will surely increase. `` On the other hand, if perestroika succeeds, the Soviet computing industry may finally find itself in a position to fully meet demand, and the Soviet military may find itself getting the same kind of support from its own computing industry that it now must get by using the Western computer industry as a surrogate,'' it said. But the report added that `` the full effects of perestroika will be a long time coming, and transformation of the Soviet computer industry can not happen overnight. In the meantime, the acquisition of Western technology would seem to appear even more attractive to the Soviet computer industry as it tries to close the gap.'' On <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> export controls policy, it noted that `` as the computer market becomes increasingly global, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> firms face increasing foreign competition, mostly from firms operating with fewer export barriers under the same CoCom guidelines.'' <ORGANIZATION> CoCom </ORGANIZATION> is the <ORGANIZATION> Coordinating </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Multilateral </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Export </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Controls </ORGANIZATION>, comprising the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> and all <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> countries except <LOCATION> Iceland </LOCATION>. `` Tighter <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> controls may reflect the absence of a fully effective multilateral control effort, but there is a risk that in the computer area, the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> may lock the proverbial barn door after the horse has escaped,'' the report said. It concluded that `` current technological progress will make controls harder to enforce, and technological and market developments combine to make a case for a more focused and flexible control process.'' Increasingly powerful computer hardware and software, the study said, are in effect becoming commodities in world trade. `` Commodity products are available in high volume and at low cost, they may be available in multiple and substitutable forms, and they tend to be small and easy to transport,'' it said. `` These attributes make commodities vital to the economic health of the computer industry, but also effectively uncontrollable.'' The report recommended that the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> publish a list of computer technologies that are commodities. The government then should promulgate a policy exempting such commodities from export controls, at least for trade among CoCom nations. On the other hand, it said, the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> should work with other agencies to focus export control efforts on `` computer technologies of compelling military importance'' that could enable Soviet bloc countries to make substantial gains in their technology base. In particular, the report cited advanced chip fabrication lines, supercomputers and other high-performance computing systems, computer-aided design systems, and magnetic and magneto-optical materials. The study also said the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> should involve newly industrializing countries such as <LOCATION> Singapore </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> into the CoCom program.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881230-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-30-88 0324EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Rajneesh-NameChange     12-30 0295</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Rajneesh-Name Change,0305</SECOND>
<HEAD>A Guru By Any Other Name Would Be Just As Divine</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW DELHI, India (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 You can call him <PERSON> Shree </PERSON>. And you can call him <PERSON> Rajneesh </PERSON>. But <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION>'s former self-styled guru of wealth and free love, <PERSON> Bhagwan </PERSON> <PERSON> Shree </PERSON> <PERSON> Rajneesh </PERSON>, says until further notice that you do n't need to call him God. <PERSON> Rajneesh </PERSON> announced Thursday he has dropped the honorific title of <PERSON> Bhagwan </PERSON>, a Hindi word meaning God. Many Indians resented <PERSON> Rajneesh </PERSON> calling himself <PERSON> Bhagwan </PERSON> because, in <LOCATION> Hinduism </LOCATION>, no mortal is equal to God. `` I have been calling myself ` <PERSON> Bhagwan </PERSON>' just as a challenge to this country,'' the 57-year-old who once taught philosophy in <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> said in the statement from his new commune in <LOCATION> Poona </LOCATION>, western <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>. `` I do n't want to be called ` <PERSON> Bhagwan </PERSON>.' Enough is enough. The joke is over,'' he said. <PERSON> Rajneesh </PERSON> was deported three years ago from the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> after he pleaded guilty to immigration fraud and closed his 64,000-acre commune of <LOCATION> Rajneeshpuram </LOCATION> in central Oregon. Followers had bestowed dozens of Rolls Royces on their revered guide of Eastern religion, pop psychology and free love. After roaming in search of a new sanctuary for a claimed 500,000 faithful worldwide, he moved his cult to a six-acre commune in <LOCATION> Poona </LOCATION>, a city of nearly 1 million residents about 80 miles southeast of <LOCATION> Bombay </LOCATION>. But despite Thursday's announcement, the guru did not entirely renounce claims to divinity. He told 10,000 people in <LOCATION> Poona </LOCATION>, `` From today onwards, you can look at me as ` Gautama the Buddha.' And by accepting <PERSON> Gautama </PERSON> the <PERSON> Buddha </PERSON> as my very soul, I go out of the Hindu fold completely.'' <PERSON> Gautama </PERSON> <PERSON> Buddha </PERSON>, born in <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> about 500 B.C., renounced a title too. Born a prince, he gave up nobility to launch a new religion _ Buddhism.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881230-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-30-88 0237EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lites     12-30 0480</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lites,0496</SECOND>
<HEAD>On The Light Side</HEAD>
<DATELINE>COLORADO SPRINGS, Colo. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 While a nearly all-male club is making its annual New Year's Eve trek up 14,110-foot <PERSON> Pike </PERSON>'s Peak, a group of women will be making a 1,000-foot ascent of a nearby mountain in jest of the traditional event. This year's climb will mark the 66th annual climb of <PERSON> Pike </PERSON>'s Peak by the AdAmAn club, which plans to set off fireworks at the summit. The group adds a climber each year. AdaWoman, a band founded in 1982, will make an ascent on Pyramid Mountain in Ute Pass west of <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Springs </LOCATION>, light sparklers, play <PERSON> Helen </PERSON> <PERSON> Reddy </PERSON>'s song `` I Am Woman,'' down champagne and head home for the night, organizers said. It will be the seventh climb for the AdaWoman club, which was founded almost as a lark by <PERSON> Rita </PERSON> <PERSON> Randolph </PERSON> and several other woman who train on Pyramid Mountain. `` It's really beautiful up there, and one morning we had run the mountain and decided this was the way we should start out the new year together,'' she said. The women also were prodded that year because AdAmAn, for the first time in its history, was inviting a female guest, veteran climber <PERSON> Sue </PERSON> <PERSON> Graham </PERSON>. `` One of the AdAmAn members said that the reason they had n't done it before was they did n't know any women who could make it,'' said <PERSON> Randolph </PERSON>. `` Well, I and another of our members ran the <ORGANIZATION> Pikes </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Peak </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Marathon </ORGANIZATION>, so I think we can make it.'' AdAmAn historian <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Bates </PERSON> said <PERSON> Graham </PERSON>, still the only woman invited, will make her fourth climb with the club this year. `` Of course, when we started this climb in 1922, you could n't have hired a woman to go with us It was n't until a few years ago that women got so they were into this type of thing,'' he said. <PERSON> Randolph </PERSON> said AdaWoman may add a man in 50 or 60 years, if one is found worthy.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW ORLEANS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> showed a little belated Christmas spirit when it agreed to tear up 800 parking tickets issued Monday to many car owners who thought it was a holiday. City Councilman <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Giarrusso </PERSON> argued Thursday for giving auto owners the benefit of the doubt. City Attorney <PERSON> Okla </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> countered that the <ORGANIZATION> Streets </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> had done nothing it was n't authorized to do. Several people cited for expired parking meters downtown and in the tourist-loaded French Quarter said they thought the day after Christmas was a ticket-free holiday. <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> said that Monday was a city government holiday not a public holiday, which would have been ticket free. Streets director <PERSON> Betty </PERSON> <PERSON> Jo </PERSON> <PERSON> Everett </PERSON> said she gets tired of defending the city holiday policy to irate drivers. `` We did n't gear up and lick our chops and think that we really had something to go for,'' <PERSON> Everett </PERSON> said. `` It was just a normal working day.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881230-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-30-88 0332EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-PopulationGrowth     12-30 0449</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Population Growth,580</SECOND>
<HEAD>Midwest Population Rebounds, But South and West Still Biggest Lures</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RITA BEAMISH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 More Americans are once again calling the <LOCATION> Midwest </LOCATION> their home, but <ORGANIZATION> Sunbelt </ORGANIZATION> states like <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> remain the favored places to settle down, government figures show. The <ORGANIZATION> Census </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> on Thursday released its 1988 population estimates, showing that the West and parts of the <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> continued strong population growth, while smaller growth rates were reflected in the Northeast. The <LOCATION> Midwest </LOCATION> appeared to be rebounding after a dropoff in population during the early part of the decade. The total <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> population stood at 245.8 million as of July 1, the date of the 1988 Census statistics, reflecting a 3 percent increase in population from July 1, 1985. Over the three-year period, the biggest growth rate and population loss were seen in small population states: <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION> was up 12.8 percent, topping the 1 million mark for the first time; and the energy-producing state of <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION> had a 7.6 percent decline, a loss of 39,000 people, leaving its population at 471,000. The 12 Midwestern states _ where the depressed farm economy caused a population downturn between 1981 and 1983 _ had an overall 1.2 percent population increase in the 1985-88 period, the Census estimates showed. Some Midwestern states continued to lose residents, but the <LOCATION> Midwest </LOCATION> as a region picked up slightly. Losses were estimated in 1985-1988 for <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Census </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> said in a statement, but added, `` The 1988 data indicate that the declines may be slowing, and several of these states may have grown in the past year.'' The largest state, <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, had the greatest increase in population, 1.8 million people, or 6.9 percent, boosting its total to 28.2 million. Other states that showed strong growth rates over the three years were: <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION>, 9.6 percent, bringing its total to 3.5 million people; <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION>, 9.9 percent, to 1.1 million residents; <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>, 8.9 percent, to 12.4 million people; <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION>, 7.1 percent, to 6.4 million; <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION>, 5.7 percent, to 4.6 million; and <LOCATION> Delaware </LOCATION>, 5.4 percent, to 660,000 people. Eleven states and the <LOCATION> District </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION> lost population during the three years: <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Kentucky </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>. In the regions outside the <LOCATION> Midwest </LOCATION>, the government found that population increased by 1.5 percent in the Northeast, including the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Mid-Atlantic </LOCATION> states; by 3.7 percent in the <LOCATION> South </LOCATION>; and by 5.5 percent in the West, including the <LOCATION> Mountain </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Coast </LOCATION> states. <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Sunshine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION>, continued to attract residents, with a population growth rate of 8.9 percent. That boosted its population to 12.4 million.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881230-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-30-88 0346EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Germany-FreshBeer     12-30 0120</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Germany-Fresh Beer,0121</SECOND>
<HEAD>Freshness Date, Guarantee With Each Brew After Jan. 1</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MUNICH, West Germany (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 West Germans, who lead the world in per capita consumption of beer, will be getting a guarantee of freshness next year with every brew. Beginning Jan. 1, the nation's 2,500 breweries must stamp a freshness date on each container and guarantee the product's quality until that time, the Bavarian <ORGANIZATION> Interior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> announced Thursday. Brewers violating the new consumer protection code could face fines of up to $ 14,700, the ministry reported. Bavarians, who make up nearly 20 percent of <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>'s population, consume an average of 57 gallons of beer yearly _ more than a gallon each week, the most in their country
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881230-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-30-88 0349EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Egypt-TV     12-30 0273</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Egypt-TV,0281</SECOND>
<HEAD>Provincial Court Bans `Falcon Crest' Show As Immoral</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CAIRO, Egypt (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A provincial court has ordered the television series <ORGANIZATION> Falcon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Crest </ORGANIZATION> off Egyptian TV on grounds it undermines public morals, according to a newspaper report. Falcon Crest began appearing several years ago on local television and quickly became a favorite among both poor and wealthy Egyptians, despite its depiction of a society generally foreign to the mostly conservative Egyptians. Television censors, for example, routinely cut kissing scenes from <LOCATION> Falcon </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Crest </LOCATION> that they consider too passionate. The TV series <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION>, a predecessor of <ORGANIZATION> Falcon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Crest </ORGANIZATION>, also was widely popular until it was stopped six years ago after a member of parliament complained it was corrupting the morals of Egyptian youth. The newspaper <ORGANIZATION> Wafd </ORGANIZATION>, published by a centrist opposition party of the same name, said Thursday the ruling banning the show was in a provincial court in the <LOCATION> Nile </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION> town of <LOCATION> Shibin </LOCATION> el-Kom. In the case, brought by a lawyer identified as <PERSON> Mustafa </PERSON> <PERSON> Hamed </PERSON> <PERSON> Khalifa </PERSON>, he was quoted as arguing that scenes in <LOCATION> Falcon </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Crest </LOCATION> are `` against morality and the constitution and incite debauchery,'' <ORGANIZATION> Wafd </ORGANIZATION> said. The newspaper said that in finding for the plaintiff, Chief Judge <PERSON> Radwan </PERSON> <PERSON> Mohammed </PERSON> <PERSON> Radwan </PERSON> also ordered Information Minister <PERSON> Safwat </PERSON> <PERSON> Sherif </PERSON>, in charge of state television and radio, to pay court costs. A spokesman for <PERSON> Sherif </PERSON> said Thursday that he knew nothing about the case. The director of Egyptian television's Channel 2, which airs the series, was not available for comment, but her secretary, <PERSON> Wafaa </PERSON> <PERSON> Hammad </PERSON>, said she had n't heard about the case either. `` We will be showing two more episodes next Sunday,'' she said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881230-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-30-88 0319EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-RoyalDoper     12-30 0630</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Royal Doper,0648</SECOND>
<HEAD>Charlie's Horse Fails Drug Test</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By LARRY SIDDONS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Sports Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Move over, <PERSON> Ben </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>. Make way, <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON>. Drugs have caught another sports star, this one named after a pub and owned by the heir to the British throne. Devil's Elbow, a 4-year-old gelding, tested positive for three stimulants after giving <PERSON> Prince </PERSON> <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> his first winner as a race-horse owner in a $ 1,200 steeplechase at <LOCATION> Worcester </LOCATION>. In announcing the finding this week, the <ORGANIZATION> Jockey </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Club </ORGANIZATION>, which governs horse racing in <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>, said there were no indications the prince had anything to do with the doping and in all likelihood would not be punished. Suspicions were that the drugs were contained in contaminated feed. But trainer <PERSON> Nick </PERSON> <PERSON> Gaselee </PERSON> faces an $ 1,800 fine, and Devil's Elbow, the namesake of a pub in <LOCATION> Princeton </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>, that also is owned by the prince, could be stripped of the victory if further tests showed the horse was deliberately doped. The Royal Family's longstanding love affair with horses and racing was for the first time touched by the spreading stain of drugs in sports, which have claimed such stars as <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>, the Olympic 100-meter runner from <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>, and <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON>, the all-pro linebacker from the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Giants </ORGANIZATION>. `` I am not aware of any other royal horse being disqualified for this sort of reason,'' said <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Oswald </PERSON>, manager of the <ORGANIZATION> Royal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Studs </ORGANIZATION>, the Royal Family's horse-breeding farm. <PERSON> Prince </PERSON> <PERSON> Charles </PERSON>, whose career as a steeplechase jockey ended several years ago in a series of spills, was not commenting on the drug findings. The tabloid <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Star </ORGANIZATION> quoted an unidentified friend of the prince as saying <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> was `` highly embarrassed'' by the case. `` The whole business is most upsetting for him _ it'll take some living down,'' the friend was quoted as saying. Most of <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s dozen national newspapers played the story on the front page Thursday with the kind of headlines usually reserved for sex scandals and ax murders. `` Charlie's Nag Fails Dope Test,'' the <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Star </ORGANIZATION> said. `` Charles Horse In Dope Shock,'' said the Daily Mail. The Times of <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>, using <PERSON> Charles </PERSON>' formal position in the royal household, headlined its front-page story: `` Prince of <LOCATION> Wales </LOCATION>' First Winner Fails a Dope Test.'' Like other sports, British horse racing has had trouble recently with drugs. The <ORGANIZATION> Jockey </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Club </ORGANIZATION> said that of an estimated 6,500 samples per year, 10-20 test positive, usually for legitimate medication administered too close to race day. Two days after Devil's Elbow won the Novice Stakes at <LOCATION> Worcester </LOCATION> Dec. 5, the <ORGANIZATION> Jockey </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Club </ORGANIZATION> leveled a record $ 31,500 fine against trainer <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Elsworth </PERSON> after one of his horses tested positive for steroids. Steroids are muscle-builders and their use got <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> thrown out of the Olympics in <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION>. Drug use in horse racing in <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>, where no medication is allowed in race entrants, more often involves pain-killers or stimulants, such as the caffeine, theobromine and theophylline found in Devil's Elbow. <PERSON> Gaselee </PERSON> said feed from his barn had been taken away for tests and the <ORGANIZATION> Jockey </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Club </ORGANIZATION> confirmed that processed food, known as `` horse nuts,'' was undergoing tests, which could take up to two weeks. Nevertheless, the club said, <PERSON> Gaselee </PERSON> remained in line for punishment. `` I make it quite clear that if any substance is found in a horse, which might have impaired or improved its running, the trainer will be held responsible,'' <LOCATION> Lord </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Fairhaven </LOCATION>, the club's senior steward, said Added <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Pipe </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Jockey </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Club </ORGANIZATION> spokesman: `` I do not know what sort of diet this horse was on. But stimulants are not permitted.'' On Wednesday, as the positive test of Devil's Elbow was being announced, <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s big race of the day was the Arkle Challenge Trophy at <LOCATION> Warwick </LOCATION>. The winner? A horse named Positive.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881230-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-30-88 0208EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a PM-Names     12-30 0998</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,1040</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names In The News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PALM SPRINGS, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Mayor <PERSON> Sonny </PERSON> <PERSON> Bono </PERSON> greeted President and Mrs. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> on their arrival to the desert community, but he went empty-handed. Air Force One touched down Thursday afternoon at <LOCATION> Palm </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Springs </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Municipal </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION> and taxied to a remote terminal, where the <ORGANIZATION> Reagans </ORGANIZATION> got into a limousine for the short ride to the home of millionaire publisher <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> Annenberg </PERSON>, where they traditionally spend the New Year's holiday. <PERSON> Bono </PERSON> said he did n't have much to say to the president during their brief minute on the tarmac. `` If I had a few hours with him, I'm sure we could have solved a lot of problems,'' he added. Asked if he had a gift for <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, <PERSON> Bono </PERSON> replied, `` No, he's a hard guy to buy for.'' <PERSON> Bono </PERSON> said <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> appeared on the `` <PERSON> Sonny </PERSON> and Cher Comedy Hour'' on television in the 1970s when <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> was governor of <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>. `` He's pretty interesting, a neat guy,'' the mayor said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NASHVILLE, Tenn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Country music star <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Gatlin </PERSON> and movie idol <PERSON> Patrick </PERSON> <PERSON> Swayze </PERSON> plan to record a film soundtrack duet, <PERSON> Gatlin </PERSON>'s publicist says <PERSON> Gatlin </PERSON> wrote the song `` Brothers'' for <PERSON> Swayze </PERSON>'s upcoming film `` Next of Kin,'' publicist <PERSON> Kathy </PERSON> <PERSON> Gangwisch </PERSON> said Thursday. Because the film is still in production, it is n't clear yet if the ballad will be used in the movie. Meantime, the two plan to give the number its premiere Jan. 13 at a charity event in <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION> for the Ileitis and <ORGANIZATION> Colitis </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION>, Ms. <PERSON> Gangwisch </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Swayze </PERSON> and <PERSON> Gatlin </PERSON> intend to include their performance on the record from the film. <PERSON> Gatlin </PERSON> is a member of <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Gatlin </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Brothers </ORGANIZATION>, whose hits include `` All the Gold in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>'' and `` Drunken Lady.'' <PERSON> Swayze </PERSON>, who says he's a country music fan, gained fame with the movie `` Dirty Dancing.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Valerie </PERSON> <PERSON> Harper </PERSON>, <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Farrell </PERSON>, <PERSON> Harvey </PERSON> <PERSON> Korman </PERSON>, <PERSON> Zsa </PERSON> <PERSON> Zsa </PERSON> <PERSON> Gabor </PERSON> and other celebrities joined <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION> businesses in dishing up a hot <LOCATION> turkey </LOCATION> meal for the homeless who make their way each day along the Walk of Fame. `` It was to draw attention to the homeless issue, to close out 1988 and usher in hope for 1989,'' publicist <PERSON> Deborah </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> said of Thursday's event. An estimated 10,000 to 15,000 street people make their home in the nation's entertainment capital, according to the Rev. <PERSON> Terrell </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Garret </PERSON> of the Hollywood-based Up From The Streets Good Samaritan Mission. The benefit was organized with help from <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Film </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Promotions </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> and The Hollywood Reporter, an entertainment trade publication which put on the dinner in its parking lot. `` Here in <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION>, the glamour capital of the world, our heart goes out to the thousands of people who roam its streets with no place to call home. For them, ` <ORGANIZATION> Tinsel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Town </ORGANIZATION>' does n't shine quite so brightly,'' the organizers said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Surrogate mother <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Beth </PERSON> <PERSON> Whitehead-Gould </PERSON>, pregnant with her fifth child, will travel to 22 cities this spring to promote a book she co-wrote about the Baby M case, titled `` A Mother's Story.'' The book will focus on the negative effects of surrogate motherhood on people, Mrs. <PERSON> Whitehead-Gould </PERSON>'s attorney, <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Arenstein </PERSON>, said Thursday. Mrs. <PERSON> Whitehead-Gould </PERSON>'s unsuccessful legal fight to keep the child she agreed to bear for <PERSON> William </PERSON> and <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> Stern </PERSON> under a $ 10,000 contract sparked nationwide debate on surrogacy contracts. The girl was known in court papers as Baby M. The book was written with <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> investigative journalist <PERSON> Loretta </PERSON> <PERSON> Schwartz-Nobel </PERSON> and published by <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Martin </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>. The 31-year-old Mrs. Whitehead-Gould lives in <LOCATION> Bayport </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION>, with her second husband and three of her children, <PERSON> Arenstein </PERSON> said. `` She is pregnant and she is happy about it,'' the attorney added. <PERSON> Stern </PERSON>, eventually granted custody of the girl by the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Jersey </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>, had tried to stop Mrs. <PERSON> Whitehead-Gould </PERSON> from writing the book, arguing it would exploit the child, named <PERSON> Melissa </PERSON>. But a <ORGANIZATION> Superior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> judge ruled that the book could focus on Mrs. <PERSON> Whitehead-Gould </PERSON>'s relationship with the child up until her second birthday.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>COLUMBIA, S.C. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Soul singer <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> is serving his six-year prison sentence at a minimum-security penitentiary where most of the 275 inmates are elderly or ill, a prison spokesman says. <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> was transferred Thursday to the <ORGANIZATION> Park </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Correctional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> just north of <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION> to serve his sentence for refusing to stop for police and trying to run over two officers Sept. 24. <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>, 55 and in good health, will likely work cleaning up the wards, in the kitchen or helping inmates who may need help dressing or getting around, said <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corrections </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Francis </PERSON> <PERSON> Archibald </PERSON>. He'll be allowed visitors on Sundays, <PERSON> Archibald </PERSON> said. `` At least for the present, we plan to keep him there until we release him,'' <PERSON> Archibald </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> will be eligible for parole in 1 -LCB- years, but could get out earlier through prison work or good behavior. <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> was convicted and sentenced Dec. 15 in the chase through <LOCATION> Augusta </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ga. </LOCATION>, and <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Augusta </LOCATION>, S.C. He faces trial in <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION> on 10 misdemeanor counts Jan. 23.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>CARSON CITY, Nev. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actor <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Sheen </PERSON> won a ruling from the <ORGANIZATION> Nevada </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> overturning a requirement that he post a $ 5,000 bond aimed at stopping a protest trespass at a nuclear test site. <PERSON> Sheen </PERSON>, active in the movement against nuclear testing, was forced to post the `` peace bond'' after saying on national television he would `` hopefully commit civil disobedience'' at the <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION> Test Site. The <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>, reversing a district judge's order, said Thursday that prosecutors had conceded that civil disobedience was n't a crime in <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION>. `` We conclude that -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> Sheen </ORGANIZATION>'s -RRB- remarks did not indicate an intention to commit a criminal offense in this state,'' the court added in holding that the `` peace bond'' statute does n't apply in such cases. Under <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION> law, the threat of a criminal act is enough to require a `` peace bond.'' If a violation actually occurs, the bond could be forfeited and the person could be jailed for up to six months.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881230-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-30-88 0328EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-NuclearSafety     12-30 0654</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nuclear Safety,650</SECOND>
<HEAD>Group Says Number Of Nuclear Accidents Rose Last Year</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BARTON REPPERT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The country's nuclear power plants reported 2,940 mishaps in 1987, a slight increase from the year before, according to an anti-nuclear organization. A report Thursday by <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Citizen </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Critical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mass </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Project </ORGANIZATION> said the accident figure represented incidents reported by nuclear plant owners to the <ORGANIZATION> Nuclear </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Regulatory </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> and classified by the <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION> as `` potentially significant safety events.'' The corresponding figure was 2,836 accidents in 1986, when there were 99 reactors in operation. The number of operating reactors grew to 109 in 1987, according to the report. Public Citizen, a non-profit research organization and longtime critic of nuclear power, also said Thursday that in 1987 there was a record number of more than 104,000 incidents in which nuclear workers were exposed to measurable doses of radiation. In addition, it said there were at least 430 emergency shutdowns last year and at least 492 violations of nuclear plant safety rules. The report was based on <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION> data compiled and analyzed by Public Citizen. <PERSON> Joan </PERSON> <PERSON> Claybrook </PERSON>, president of <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Citizen </ORGANIZATION>, said in releasing the report: `` Public attention has recently been focused on the poor safety conditions at the nation's nuclear weapons reactors. `` However, in 1987, badly managed commercial nuclear plants daily threatened the safety of the public, particularly the 96 million Americans who live within 50 miles of a reactor,'' she said. Public Citizen criticized the <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION> for refusing to release key safety data such as `` single-component failure'' records and a comprehensive listing of all emergency plant shutdowns. It contended that the commission's public records on safety violations are incomplete and contradictory. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Newlin </PERSON>, an <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION> spokesman, said he could not comment in detail on specific allegations without first having a chance to examine the Public Citizen report. `` I would say that in general the <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION> makes data available to the public on all safety issues,'' he said. <PERSON> Newlin </PERSON> added that based on a variety of safety and operational criteria, `` the overall performance at nuclear plants, we think, is improving.'' <PERSON> Carl </PERSON> <PERSON> Goldstein </PERSON>, a spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Awareness </ORGANIZATION>, a nuclear industry group, said in response to the Public Citizen report: `` <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s nuclear plants have just ended a record-breaking year, producing 20 percent of the nation's electricity `` The <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nuclear </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Power </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Operations </ORGANIZATION> confirm that, year by year, nuclear plants have improved their availability and reduced the number of significant events, which are an important measure of safe operation,'' <PERSON> Goldstein </PERSON> said. Here are key findings of the <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Citizen </ORGANIZATION> report: _ In 1987 a total of 430 `` scrams'' or emergency plant shutdowns were reported to the <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION> This worked out to an average of 4.4 shutdowns per operating reactor. Plants experiencing the largest number of scrams during the year were Vogtle-1, <LOCATION> Waynesboro </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ga. </LOCATION>, 27 shutdowns; <PERSON> Shearon </PERSON> <PERSON> Harris-1 </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Newhill </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.C. </LOCATION>, 21 shutdowns, and Beaver Valley-2, <LOCATION> Shippingport </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION>, 17 shutdowns. _ There were at least 2,940 mishaps at <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> power reactors in 1987 That was the tally of `` licensee event reports'' submitted to the <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION> by utilities. According to <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION> guidelines, they provide descriptions of `` potentially significant safety events'' that `` might lead to serious accidents.'' Reactors with the highest number of mishaps were Nine Mile Point-2, <LOCATION> Scriba </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION>, 79 mishaps; Perry-1, <PERSON> North </PERSON> <PERSON> Perry </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, 77 mishaps, and Vogtle-1, 75 mishaps. _ In 1987 an all-time high of 104,458 incidents occurred in which workers at nuclear reactors received measurable doses of radiation _ At least 492 violations of safety regulations at <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> power reactors were cited by the <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION> in 1987 `` Inasmuch as <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION>'s data are incomplete, the actual number is probably significantly higher,'' the Public Citizen report said. Plants at which the highest numbers of violations were reported include Sequoyah-1 and 2, Daisy, <LOCATION> Tenn. </LOCATION>, 37 violations; <ORGANIZATION> Browns </ORGANIZATION> Ferry-1, 2 and 3, <LOCATION> Decatur </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ala. </LOCATION>, 35 violations, and <LOCATION> Turkey </LOCATION> Point-3 and 4, <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>, 33 violations.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881230-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-30-88 0328EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Bush-Pintlala     12-30 0383</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bush-Pintlala,0396</SECOND>
<HEAD>Rural Crossroads Giddy Over President-elect's Visit</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KENDAL WEAVER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PINTLALA, Ala. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 It's not <LOCATION> Kennebunkport </LOCATION> <LOCATION> South </LOCATION>. It's not even Plains. But the rural crossroads of <LOCATION> Pintlala </LOCATION>, which consists of little more than a country store with gas pumps, took on the look of a presidential retreat when <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> arrived with his fishing tackle. The president-elect, accompanied by a 17-vehicle entourage of security and press, stopped by Thursday to fish for bass at <PERSON> Ray </PERSON> <PERSON> Scott </PERSON>'s 55-acre private lake in <LOCATION> Pintlala </LOCATION>'s partly rolling, partly swampy terrain 15 miles south of <LOCATION> Montgomery </LOCATION>. `` I have n't seen so much excitement since the milk truck turned over a couple of years ago,'' said area resident <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Williamson </PERSON>. `` What Camp <PERSON> David </PERSON> and <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Clemente </LOCATION> have been to other presidents, we hope <PERSON> Pintlala </PERSON> will be for the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration,'' joked the Rev. <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Burton </PERSON>, pastor of the <ORGANIZATION> Pintlala </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Baptist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION>, who gathered with a dozen other people to welcome <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. A few dozen more collected outside <PERSON> Scott </PERSON>'s guarded gate Thursday evening when the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> caravan pulled out. `` Thank you all very much,'' said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, speaking through an amplified car speaker. `` Happy New Year to everybody.'' <PERSON> Scott </PERSON>, a <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> political ally and a <LOCATION> Montgomery </LOCATION> native who founded the <ORGANIZATION> Bass </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Anglers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sportsman </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION>, arranged the afternoon of fishing in the former Creek Indian settlement. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> caught nine fish by day's end. The largest weighed three pounds, and he threw them all back. <PERSON> Scott </PERSON> and <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> played a joke on the press, with <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> holding up a huge bass as cameras rolled. The fish was actually a mounted trophy from <PERSON> Scott </PERSON>'s home. The welcoming group, with one little girl holding high a sign that read `` Good Fishing,'' cheered as <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> arrived. The group then went to <PERSON> Mosley </PERSON>'s service station, which serves as a grocery, hot dog stand and unofficial city hall for <LOCATION> Pintlala </LOCATION>. At <PERSON> Mosley </PERSON>'s, a few dozen other people had gathered, thinking <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> would pass by the junction of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> 31 and <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Road </ORGANIZATION>, which amounts to `` downtown Pintlala.'' But the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> motorcade took a faster route on Interstate 65, turning into the Scott farm from another local road. <PERSON> Pintlala </PERSON>'s population is `` less than a thousand, not counting the deer and quail,'' said Constable <PERSON> Ben </PERSON> <PERSON> Alpert </PERSON>. `` Use the word ` quail' advisedly,'' warned the Rev. <PERSON> Burton </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881230-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-30-88 0359EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--SwissSmuggler     12-30 0116</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Swiss Smuggler,0118</SECOND>
<HEAD>Dutch Arrest Man Carrying 2,200 Pieces Of Gold In His Clothing</HEAD>
<DATELINE>AMSTERDAM, Netherlands (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A Swiss man carrying 2,250 pieces of gold concealed in his clothing has been arrested on smuggling charges, <LOCATION> Dutch </LOCATION> customs officials say. Gold jewelry weighing 53 pounds and worth an estimated $ 320,000 was discovered in the suspect's clothing, a customs spokesman speaking on condition on anonymity said Thursday. The suspect, a 28-year-old resident of <LOCATION> Zurich </LOCATION>, told officers he had been planning to sell the jewelry in <LOCATION> Antwerp </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Belgium </LOCATION>, the spokesman said. The suspect, who was not identified in line with Dutch police practice, faces a $ 154,950 fine and $ 77,475 in tax and import duties, the spokesman said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881230-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-30-88 0244EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a PM-BigBookstore Bjt   12-30 0523</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Big Bookstore, Bjt,0542</SECOND>
<HEAD>Big Bookstore's Owner Seeks Place In Guinness Book</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto CD1</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DWIGHT WOODWARD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CLEVELAND (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 With 36.5 miles of shelves and more than 1.1 million different books, <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Zubal </PERSON> thinks his bookstore offers the largest collection of titles for sale in the world. He hopes the <ORGANIZATION> Guinness </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Book </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Records </ORGANIZATION> will think so, too. <PERSON> Zubal </PERSON>, 49, says he's writing the editors of the Guinness Book once he has gathered supporting evidence. And there's quite a bit of it. Four warehouses, packed with books from floor to ceiling, house <PERSON> Zubal </PERSON>'s volumes, arranged alphabetically by categories. The complex is so large that, until recently, his 49-year-old wife, <PERSON> Marilyn </PERSON>, used roller skates to retrieve customer requests. Guinness lists <ORGANIZATION> W. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <ORGANIZATION> G. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foyle </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ltd. </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> as the bookstore with the most shelving at 30 miles, while <ORGANIZATION> Barnes </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <LOCATION> Noble </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bookstore </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> is listed as the largest book building with 154,250 square feet of books, said <PERSON> Sheelagh </PERSON> <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON>, a deputy editor for Guinness in <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Zubal </PERSON> said he has 78,000 square feet of books, and more titles than any other store because he has few duplicate books, textbooks or remainders such as those sold at <ORGANIZATION> Barnes </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; Noble and <LOCATION> Foyle </LOCATION>. Bibliophiles from as far way as <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> visit his store regularly, he said. But if you want to learn how to ski or groom your pet, do n't go to <PERSON> Zubal </PERSON>'s. `` We do n't have too many -LRB- books -RRB- for the casual reader,'' <PERSON> Zubal </PERSON> said recently. `` Mostly our books are for the scholar and most are sold by mail order. We are not too concerned with what is being published now.'' Fewer than 2 percent of <PERSON> Zubal </PERSON>'s tomes were published after 1960, he said. Some of the biggest categories are literary criticism, anthropology, philosophy, theology and history. Zubal estimated he has 250 books alone about <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Dickens </PERSON> and 1,000 on <PERSON> Shakespeare </PERSON>. `` We do a lot of business in World War II books,'' said <PERSON> Zubal </PERSON>. `` We think there are about 6,000 books published on World War II, and we have 3,000.'' Zubal acquires most of his books from contacts who tell him of literary estates or bookstores for sale. `` I used to hit the flea market circuit but now I let the younger guys do it,'' said the bookseller, who travels to <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> several times a year to buy and sell. <PERSON> Zubal </PERSON> also owns autographed editions by <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Joyce </PERSON>, <PERSON> Ernest </PERSON> <PERSON> Hemingway </PERSON> and flying ace <PERSON> Eddie </PERSON> <PERSON> Rickenbacker </PERSON>. While <PERSON> Zubal </PERSON> said all his books are for sale, `` there are books I mark up to scare off the fainthearted.'' He was not ready to dicker over an autographed edition of `` Finnegan's Wake'' priced at $ 3,000. `` I'm in no hurry to sell it,'' he said. `` It's money in the bank.'' Once <PERSON> Zubal </PERSON> submits his claim to <ORGANIZATION> Guinness </ORGANIZATION>, Ms. <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> said, he will need to submit two forms from witnesses validating his claim and a color photograph. Ms. <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> said editors would have to determine if his claim to have the most individual titles would merit a separate record category. `` That is always a possibility, but we ca n't make any promises,'' she said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881230-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-30-88 0417EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-IndustrialOutlook     12-30 0679</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Industrial Outlook,675</SECOND>
<HEAD>Government Foresees Another Good Year for U.S. Industry in 1989</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARTIN CRUTSINGER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> industry, helped by continued strong demand for exports, will enjoy a seventh consecutive year of rising sales in 1989, with high-technology businesses leading the gains, according to government forecasts. The <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> on Thursday released the 30th edition of its <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Industrial Outlook, which each year picks the winners and losers among American businesses based on detailed analyses of market trends in 350 different manufacturing and service industries. `` Totaling up all the individual forecasts, you can see that we are looking for another positive year for the economy,'' Deputy <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Donna </PERSON> <PERSON> Tuttle </PERSON> said. `` Services will continue to be strong, and the majority of manufacturing industries will continue to grow, especially those producing capital equipment and exports,'' she said at a news conference where she previewed the 566-page book. <PERSON> Tuttle </PERSON> said more than 70 percent of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> manufacturing industries were expected to see higher sales in the new year, with the median growth rate, after adjusting for inflation, projected to be 2.3 percent. Those projections represented a slight drop from the current year, reflecting the belief that the non-farm economy, while not in danger of a recession, will not do quite as well in 1989, <PERSON> Tuttle </PERSON> said. Among the report's forecasts: _ Some sectors of manufacturing will be held back by a continuing slump in the construction industry, which will depress the demand for steel and other building materials _ Industries providing services instead of goods, the fastest growing portion of the economy, will continue to do well in 1989, led by firms specializing in computers _ Aerospace, one of the largest manufacturing industries, will show modest overall growth as rising demand for civilian aircraft is offset by a drop in military orders _ Car sales will decline by about 1 percent to 10.6 million units, with the share of sales held by manufacturers in <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> holding steady at about 72 percent _ The banking industry, despite continued problems with international debts and stiff competition from non-banking financial companies, will show good growth, with assets rising by about 7 percent _ Airlines will have another strong year, with revenues rising by more than 14 percent Trucking revenues will rise 7 percent, while revenues earned by railroads will increase 2 percent. _ Health and medical services, one of the fastest growing service industries, will show a sharp 10.7 percent rise in 1989 to an estimated $ 618 billion The report said the service category with the biggest projected percentage increase will be space commercialization, where revenues are expected to rise by 50 percent to $ 2.7 billion as the commercial launch industry in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> begins its first year of operation. Other service standouts will be in the fields of data processing, computer services and electronic data bases, with revenues projected to rise by between 13 percent and 20 percent. In the manufacturing sector, the star performer is expected to be the metal-cutting segment of the machine tool industry, with shipments projected to rise by 13.9 percent. That reflects the boom in capital investment as <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> industry rushes to expand production facilities to meet rising export demands. The No. 2 manufacturing industry will be semiconductors, with a projected 13.4 percent rise in shipments; followed by a 13 percent increase in paper making machinery. Paper plants are now operating at 95 percent of capacity and are trying to expand to meet the high level of demand. Many of the manufacturing sectors expected to perform the most sluggishly were tied to the construction industry. Sales of chemical preparation were projected to drop by 14.6 percent, the largest overall decrease. Sales of household cooking equipment were forecast to decline by 7.9 percent, reflecting an expected decline in construction of new homes next year. Demand for steel products are forecast to fall by 6.9 percent in 1989, reflecting a drop in demand for steel girders in construction. The Industrial Outlook can be purchased for $ 24 beginning next month at the government's 21 regional bookstores.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881230-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-30-88 0416EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Bakkers-Television     12-30 0260</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bakkers-Television,0268</SECOND>
<HEAD>Jim And Tammy Bakker Plan Return To Television</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CHARLOTTE, N.C. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON> and his wife, <PERSON> Tammy </PERSON>, will return to television for the first time in nearly two years Monday with a live show broadcast from their living room, a newspaper reported today. Six independent television stations across the nation will carry the program, said The Charlotte Observer, quoting unidentified sources. <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON>, who was indicted with three associates this month on charges of misusing millions of dollars in <ORGANIZATION> PTL </ORGANIZATION> money, could not be reached for comment Thursday. <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON> has not had a regular TV show since resigning from <ORGANIZATION> PTL </ORGANIZATION> in March 1987 after widely publicized allegations of his 1980 sexual encounter with church secretary <PERSON> Jessica </PERSON> <PERSON> Hahn </PERSON> and payments to keep her quiet. He and <PERSON> Tammy </PERSON> <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON> were co-hosts of <ORGANIZATION> PTL </ORGANIZATION>'s `` <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> and <PERSON> Tammy </PERSON> <PERSON> Show </PERSON>.'' The <ORGANIZATION> Bakkers </ORGANIZATION>' new show will be broadcast live from their living room near <LOCATION> Pineville </LOCATION> Monday through Friday and will be carried on stations in <LOCATION> Albany </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Chico </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION>; and <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Diego </LOCATION>, the Observer said. <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON> attorney <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Toms </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Hendersonville </LOCATION> said in a telephone interview Thursday night that the <ORGANIZATION> Bakkers </ORGANIZATION> had been preparing to return to television, but could not confirm when the return would take place. While at <ORGANIZATION> PTL </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Bakkers </ORGANIZATION>' show was broadcast by about 180 television stations. Asked what kind of program the <ORGANIZATION> Bakkers </ORGANIZATION> are planning, a source replied, `` The same as before.'' `` It's real important,'' the source said of Monday's show. `` It's the first day back It's not going to be any fly-by-night thing.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881230-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-30-88 0423EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-India-Bomb     12-30 0255</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-India-Bomb,0262</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bomb Explodes In Punjab Neighborhood, Kills 5</HEAD>
<DATELINE>AMRITSAR, India (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A bomb exploded in a crowded neighborhood in <LOCATION> Punjab </LOCATION> state today as police tried to defuse the device, killing at least five people and injuring 20, authorities said. The dead included a police inspector and two constables working to detach the bomb, which had been placed in a tin box and attached to a bicycle parked in a central <LOCATION> Amritsar </LOCATION> neighborhood, authorities said. No one claimed responsibility for the blast, which occurred at 7:30 a.m. But police said they suspected Sikh militants waging a 6-year guerrilla war against <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>'s Hindu majority for a separate homeland in <LOCATION> Punjab </LOCATION>, a prosperous farming state bordering <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>. According to a police spokesman, an anonymous caller warned authorities of the bomb. Police Inspector <PERSON> Bhagat </PERSON> <PERSON> Singh </PERSON> and six assistants went to the neighborhood and as they tried to defuse the bomb, it exploded, killing <PERSON> Singh </PERSON> and constables <PERSON> Bachitar </PERSON> <PERSON> Singh </PERSON> and <PERSON> Kishan </PERSON> <PERSON> Lal </PERSON>, the police spokesman said. Two men, a Sikh and a Hindu, also died. Twenty others, including several children on their way to school, were injured, the spokesman said. At least 10 were in serious condition, he said. Sikhs make up 2 percent of <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>'s 880 million people, but they are a slight majority in <LOCATION> Punjab </LOCATION>. Hindus comprise more than 80 percent of the country's population. Sikh militants, claiming discrimination by the Hindu community, have been demanding an independent nation in <LOCATION> Punjab </LOCATION> since 1982. They have been blamed for more than 2,400 killings this year alone.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881230-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-30-88 0510EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FarmScene     12-30 0664</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Farm Scene,666</SECOND>
<HEAD>Most Farmers Met Contracts Despite Drought, USDA Says</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DON KENDALL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Farm Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The summer's devastating drought caused relatively few farmers to renege on contracts for advance sales of corn, soybeans and wheat, the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> says. The report by the department's <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> said a survey of 325 elevators, or warehouses, in 13 Corn Belt and spring wheat states showed farmers would default on less than 1 percent of their contracts. `` Only about 1 percent of these elevators expected that losses from farmers failing to meet contract commitments would exceed 10 percent of the elevator's net worth,'' the report said. The report was ordered by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> in this year's Disaster Assistance Act, which provided aid to farmers hit by the drought and hot weather during the spring and early summer months. Drought raised commodity prices sharply and left many farmers with less grain and soybeans to deliver than they had counted on when they entered into forward contracts early in the year. `` Many would have liked to get out of their contracts, if that were possible, because market prices rose above the contracted prices,'' the report said. `` Some farmers produced less than they had sold forward and faced buying out their contracts at a loss.'' If farmers defaulted, that would leave elevators or other buyers to absorb the losses. The report was sent to <LOCATION> Capitol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION> but has not been distributed generally by <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION>. A copy was made available Thursday to The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>. Most of the information was based on a telephone survey of the 325 elevators in September. The report said the survey results also were consistent with information obtained in field interviews of elevator managers, telephone interviews of bankers and brokers, and from state grain marketing specialists. `` Severe drought and the associated grain and soybean price increases hit farmers who priced forward in two ways,'' the report said. `` Those who hedged by selling futures were the first to be affected. To meet margin calls during the period when prices increased, these farmers had to either tap financial reserves or obtain increased credit.'' But the study found in a `` small-scale survey of commodity brokers and bankers'' that farmers and their brokers and bankers successfully weathered the sharp commodity price increases and the resulting calls for greater margins, or deposits, that occurred in June and July. `` For farmers who entered into cash forward contracts, the financial problem hit when it became necessary to buy back contracts in lieu of making delivery,'' the report said. More than half of the elevators surveyed had forward contracts with farmers for corn, soybeans or wheat produced in 1988. The contracts covered about 15 percent of the corn, 22 percent of the soybeans and 7 percent of the spring wheat that these elevators bought this year. According to the survey, the elevators indicated that more than 95 percent of their outstanding forward contracts with farmers likely would be fulfilled as originally negotiated, with between 1 percent and 2 percent renegotiated, and less than 1 percent in default. The remainder were uncertain. Officials had expected higher rates of default and renogotiation, but the report said many farmers realized the possible intensity of the drought by early June and curtailed normal contracting activity. `` As a result, farmers incurred fewer contract obligations than they might have incurred if the drought had not become apparent until later in the season,'' the report said. Weather also was important during that period, the report said. Many areas, particularly in <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION> and parts of <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION>, received rain in late July and early August, which improved yield prospects in those areas. In those cases, improved yields helped farmers meet contract obligations, compared with the uncertainties of only a few weeks earlier. The 13 states included an eastern Corn Belt region of <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Kentucky </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION>, and a western Corn Belt region of <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881230-0025 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-30-88 0518EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Armenia-Nuclear     12-30 0216</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Armenia-Nuclear,0226</SECOND>
<HEAD>Experts Say Armenian Nuclear Plant Must be Reinforced or Shut</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MOSCOW (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A nuclear plant in <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Armenia </LOCATION> should be strengthened against earthquakes as quickly as possible or closed, experts were quoted as saying in an official report. <ORGANIZATION> Tass </ORGANIZATION>, the official Soviet news agency, said Thursday that specialists hurried to inspect the plant near <LOCATION> Yerevan </LOCATION>, the capital of <LOCATION> Armenia </LOCATION>, after the earthquake Dec. 7 that killed thousands of people. They concluded that the plant was not damaged but needed reinforcement against earthquakes `` within the shortest possible time'' or it should be closed, <ORGANIZATION> Tass </ORGANIZATION> said. The report follows an announcement by <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> nuclear power officials last week that six nuclear power projects were scrapped because of earthquake danger or because of tougher standards. New rules were imposed after the <LOCATION> Chernobyl </LOCATION> nuclear disaster in April 1986 killed at least 31 people. Speculation abounded after the earthquake earlier this month that the plant near <LOCATION> Yerevan </LOCATION> was damaged. The facility lies near a geological fault. Soviet Premier <PERSON> Nikolai </PERSON> <PERSON> I. </PERSON> <PERSON> Ryzhkov </PERSON> told reporters in <LOCATION> Yerevan </LOCATION> on Dec. 12 that the plant would be shut in two years. But the <ORGANIZATION> Tass </ORGANIZATION> story, quoting <PERSON> Yevgeny </PERSON> <PERSON> Velikhov </PERSON>, vice president of the <ORGANIZATION> Soviet </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sciences </ORGANIZATION>, mentioned no deadline. The facility generates more than one-third of the <LOCATION> Caucasus </LOCATION> mountain republic's electricity.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
