<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880612-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-12-88 2327EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Dominican-Fire     06-12 0210</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Dominican-Fire,0217</SECOND>
<HEAD>Army Called In To Help Control Blaze; Damage Estimated At $90
Million</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SANTO DOMINGO, Dominican Republic (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A fire in the country's largest shopping center burned for a second day Sunday with losses rising to $ 90 million and the army ordered to help control the blaze Lt. Gen. <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Imbert </PERSON> <PERSON> Barrera </PERSON>, armed forces minister, ordered soldiers to join the firemen immediately after visiting the Plaza <LOCATION> Naco </LOCATION> shopping center, located in the capital's upper class <LOCATION> Naco </LOCATION> district, Saturday evening. The police also helped firemen keep the blaze from spreading to neighboring buildings. Fire Department spokesman <PERSON> Buenaventura </PERSON> <PERSON> Torres </PERSON> said Sunday that the fire was under control, but that the dense smoke and lack of water and equipment such as oxygen masks and protective clothing hindered firemen's efforts. Some firemen fainted and suffered cuts and bruises, but no other injuries were reported. The fire, one of the largest recorded in this nation of 6.5 million, began early Saturday morning and destroyed most of the more than 100 shops, movie theaters, offices, banks and restaurants in the mall. Firemen said the blaze was caused by faulty wiring in an auxiliary power plant turned on during a power failure. Shopping center administrators and shop owners estimated damage at about $ 90 million.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880612-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-12-88 2351EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-WaterBearers     06-12 0842</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Water Bearers,0870</SECOND>
<HEAD>Water Crew's Kindness Taps Wellspring Of Help</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By STRAT DOUTHAT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>POMPANO BEACH, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Bertha </PERSON> <PERSON> Shefton </PERSON> closed her eyes and shuddered as she relived the moment. The 80-year-old widow owed $ 103.44 on her water bill, and city utility truck No. 986 had just arrived at her small, white stucco bungalow to cut off the water. Doing without water would be hard enough for a frail old woman in the suffocating subtropical heat and humidity of south <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>, but Mrs. <PERSON> Shefton </PERSON> also cares for a granddaughter who has lost her left leg to diabetes and must undergo kidney dialysis three times a week. `` I tried to explain that somebody had stolen my Social Security check and that I'd pay the bill as soon as my next check came in,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Shefton </PERSON> told a visiting reporter. `` They told me they were only doing their job. `` It was plain to see those boys did n't want to do it. They said they were real sorry, but it was still awful to watch them drive away and know our water had been cut off.'' But what the crew did next has made the four men local heroes and brought in donations that should make Mrs. <PERSON> Shefton </PERSON> secure for a long time: they drove back, turned the water on and scraped up enough cash to pay her bill. `` When the word got out about what happened, a local plumbing contractor volunteered to pay Mrs. <PERSON> Shefton </PERSON>'s water bill for a year. Another local company is paying her electric bills,'' said <PERSON> Benny </PERSON> <PERSON> Scott </PERSON>, who supervises city water department crews. <PERSON> Scott </PERSON> and the three members of the city's celebrated utility crew _ <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>, <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Craddock </PERSON> and <PERSON> Lyn </PERSON> <PERSON> Roberts </PERSON> _ visited Mrs. <PERSON> Shefton </PERSON> one recent steamy afternoon. They stopped by to say hello and see how she was faring. `` These are my friends,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Shefton </PERSON> said, giving <PERSON> Scott </PERSON> a hug. `` These fellows are my heroes, they're the ones who started the wheels turning for me.'' The wheels began turning Mrs. <PERSON> Shefton </PERSON>'s way almost immediately after the utility truck pulled away from the curb in front of her house on April 14. `` We decided we just could n't leave her like that,'' <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> said. `` It was the middle of the month, and that meant it would be more than two weeks before the old lady's next check would arrive. It was plain that she and her granddaughter really needed help.'' Cutting off water service in such a climate makes people desperate, the crew members said. `` Some of them get real nasty and threaten to shoot you or sic their dogs on you,'' said <PERSON> Roberts </PERSON>. `` Others get down and beg you not to do it, which only makes it worse.'' Mrs. <PERSON> Shefton </PERSON> had merely asked for enough time to fill her bathtub and a few pots and pans with water before service was shut off. `` It really touched me,'' <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> said. So the crew members called their office on the truck radio and found out how much Mrs. <PERSON> Shefton </PERSON> owed. Then they began pulling money out of their pockets. `` <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> and I each put up $ 15 and <PERSON> Willie </PERSON> <PERSON> Hargrett </PERSON>, our foreman, pitched in $ 20,'' <PERSON> Roberts </PERSON> said. `` Some other fellows at the office also contributed a few dollars, and <PERSON> Benny </PERSON> <PERSON> Scott </PERSON> put up the remaining $ 33.44.'' <PERSON> Craddock </PERSON> put in a dollar. `` But that was every penny he had,'' said <PERSON> Roberts </PERSON>. `` It was a gift from his heart.'' News media soon picked up the story. `` Since then we've gotten dozens of calls and letters from all over the place,'' <PERSON> Scott </PERSON> said. `` People from as far away as <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> have sent money and checks for Mrs. <PERSON> Shefton </PERSON>; a local guy even stopped by and gave us a check for the $ 103.44 we had put up.'' <PERSON> Scott </PERSON> said he has turned over all the contributions, including the $ 103.44 check, to Mrs. <PERSON> Shefton </PERSON>'s church, where a fund has been set up for her. `` So far, we've received more than $ 700,'' the Rev. <PERSON> Otis </PERSON> <PERSON> Sample </PERSON>, pastor of the Mt. <ORGANIZATION> Calvary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Baptist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION>, said recently. `` We'll use the money to help her pay her bills. Mrs. <PERSON> Shefton </PERSON> lost her husband, <PERSON> Izell </PERSON>, a year ago, and she and her granddaughter, <PERSON> Mercideen </PERSON> <PERSON> Pugh </PERSON>, 37, live on a monthly income of $ 952. Mrs. <PERSON> Shefton </PERSON>, a former domestic worker who cleaned the homes of <LOCATION> Pompano </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION>'s more affluent families for 40 years, said she does n't know what to make of all the help and support she has received. `` It's wonderful, but do n't forget that it all started with these boys here,'' she said, pointing to <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>, <PERSON> Roberts </PERSON>, <PERSON> Craddock </PERSON> and <PERSON> Scott </PERSON>. `` We were happy to do it,'' replied <PERSON> Scott </PERSON>, who said he, too, is somewhat flabbergasted by all the attention, including letters of commendation from the mayor. `` We did n't have no idea it would turn out like this,'' he said. `` We were just trying to help a nice old lady out of a jam.''
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Strat </PERSON> <PERSON> Douthat </PERSON> is the <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Southeast </ORGANIZATION> regional reporter, based in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880612-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-12-88 2352EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-LaurieDann'sDemons 2Takes   06-12 1124</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Laurie Dann's Demons, 2 Takes,1157</SECOND>
<HEAD>The Tragedy of Laurie Dann: `She Wasn't the Monster She Turned Out
to Be'</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Sunday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By SHARON COHEN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WINNETKA, Ill. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 At the end, she was alone, hiding from the world she'd shattered that day in wild gunfire. Outside, the tears and trauma had just begun. Inside, <PERSON> Laurie </PERSON> <PERSON> Dann </PERSON> shot one last time and her torment was over. No one saw her place the .32 - caliber revolver in her mouth or heard the shot that destroyed her demons and ended a day of Three weeks after she killed a young boy at <ORGANIZATION> Hubbard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Woods </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Elementary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> and ended her life in the house where she had held police at bay, authorities are still trying to piece together the puzzle of <PERSON> Laurie </PERSON> <PERSON> Dann </PERSON>'s life. `` We want to answer the question why,'' said <LOCATION> Winnetka </LOCATION> Police Lt. <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Sumner </PERSON>. `` What made it happen? How did it happen? We owe that to the citizens and the community. We owe it to the families of victims. If you put yourself in their spot, you'd want to know why. `` It's very possible she may have taken that to the grave with her,'' he added. `` We can hopefully come down with a position of ` This is probably why.' <PERSON> Laurie </PERSON> <PERSON> Dann </PERSON>'s road to tragedy was lined with signs of trouble ahead, most posted in the last two years. In that time, she was divorced, forced out of an apartment and charged with shoplifting. She lied about her name, age and occupation; she claimed to be a teacher or a journalism student. She was suspected of making hundreds of harassing hang-up or threatening phone calls to her ex-husband, his family and others. She was charged once, but the case was dropped due to insufficient evidence. Students and officials at two schools say she hid raw meat under seat cushions, wore knit gloves when she ate, ran her shower for hours and rode an elevator day and night in her dormitory where she was called `` psycho'' and `` elevator lady.'' `` She was definitely a very, very confused woman,'' <PERSON> Sumner </PERSON> said. Dangerous, too, her ex-husband and others feared. But even as they were contacting the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION>, prosecutors and police, several <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Shore </LOCATION> families were unwittingly hiring <PERSON> Dann </PERSON> as a babysitter. Two days before the May 20 tragedy, <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION> prosecutors were ready to charge <PERSON> Dann </PERSON> with making threatening phone calls to a former boyfriend. <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> authorities were working a similar case. The <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> was closing in, too. They moved too late. By then, <PERSON> Dann </PERSON> had killed 8-year-old <PERSON> Nicholas </PERSON> <PERSON> Corwin </PERSON>. She shot five other children at the school and a 20-year-old man who tried to disarm her when she burst into his family's house. She barricaded herself there and committed suicide. `` I do n't see why this had to happen and get this far,'' <PERSON> Susan </PERSON> <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON>, her former sister-in law, said on <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Nightline.'' <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON> said <PERSON> Dann </PERSON> called her hundreds of times, saying things like `` ` <PERSON> Susie </PERSON>, <PERSON> Susie </PERSON>, <PERSON> Susie </PERSON>, you are going to die.''' <PERSON> Dann </PERSON>, police say, left behind a trail of poison: 31 packets of juice and other foods, 29 of them contaminated with arsenic or lead, sent to her ex-husband, psychiatrist, families she worked for, two <ORGANIZATION> Northwestern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> fraternity houses and others. Police believe she may once have known someone at the frat houses but do n't know why she directed her poison at acquaintances, her gun at strangers. It was n't the only paradox in <PERSON> Dann </PERSON>'s life. Children she tended adored her, but adults came to fear her. She was raised in a world of wealth and elegant homes, but she left rotting meat behind in one apartment with urine-stained floors. Still, some say they detected no hint of growing fury. `` She really was a pleasant ... quiet person. ... She was n't this ghoulish person all her life,'' said <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Solber </PERSON>, one attorney who represented her in divorce proceedings `` She was n't the monster she turned out to be. For most of her 30 years, <PERSON> Laurie </PERSON> <PERSON> Dann </PERSON> lived an unremarkable life. <PERSON> Laurie </PERSON> <PERSON> Wasserman </PERSON>, who had an older brother, <PERSON> Mark </PERSON>, graduated from prestigious <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Trier </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> East </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> High </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION>. Her father, a successful accountant, and mother live in <LOCATION> Glencoe </LOCATION> on the <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Shore </LOCATION>, where $ 500,000 mansions, private beaches along <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION> and three-car garages are not uncommon. In high school `` she was really quiet, kind of withdrawn. She held her head low,'' said ex-classmate <PERSON> Margie </PERSON> <PERSON> Guiarelli </PERSON>. `` There was always kind of a wall in-between. ... She never really gave you eye contact. She was nervous when she talked to you.'' She took classes at four universities _ <PERSON> Drake </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Northwestern </ORGANIZATION> and <LOCATION> Wisconsin-Madison </LOCATION> _ over six years. At <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION>, she majored in home economics but did not graduate after four years. Later, she took courses in acting, dance and playwriting. At <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Dann </PERSON> pledged <ORGANIZATION> Alpha </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Delta </ORGANIZATION> Pi sorority, where sisters remembered her as introverted and recalled how she would make several dates for one night, then cancel all but one. `` I just perceived her to be a sweet little girl,'' <PERSON> Denise </PERSON> <PERSON> Shimer </PERSON> <PERSON> Janes </PERSON>, a former chapter president, told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Arizona </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Star </ORGANIZATION>. For two years, <PERSON> Dann </PERSON> dated a premed student at <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION>, who later claimed she harassed him with threatening phone calls. His identity has not been made public. However, the man's friend, <PERSON> Louis </PERSON> <PERSON> Spivack </PERSON>, an <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION> prosecutor who double-dated with them, remembers <PERSON> Dann </PERSON> as `` aloof, perhaps a little unfriendly, possessive'' but exhibiting no especially strange behavior. In 1982, two years after returning to the <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> area, she married <PERSON> Russell </PERSON> <PERSON> Dann </PERSON>, who worked in his family's insurance firm. <PERSON> Solber </PERSON> said his client, who was 5-foot-3, described herself and her husband as both `` little and cute. -LRB- She said -RRB- they looked like brother and sister. That was her perception.'' The <ORGANIZATION> Danns </ORGANIZATION> bought a $ 275,000 home, but the marriage crumbled by 1986. She saw a psychiatrist for part of their marriage. Their parting was bitter. <PERSON> Dann </PERSON>, who had taken a marksmanship course in her college days, bought a .357 - caliber Magnum, saying she needed it for A worried <PERSON> Russell </PERSON> <PERSON> Dann </PERSON> alerted police, who contacted her parents. <PERSON> Wasserman </PERSON> told officers the gun would be locked in a safety deposit box. The .357 was one of three guns she carried into the school. <PERSON> Dann </PERSON> also accused her husband of assault, breaking into their home and setting it on fire, charges never substantiated. <PERSON> Russell </PERSON> <PERSON> Dann </PERSON>, in turn, asserted she sneaked into his apartment as he slept Sept. 30, 1986, and stabbed him in the chest with an ice pick. He said he never saw his assailant and later claimed his ex-wife had admitted to the attack. But <PERSON> Russell </PERSON> failed a lie detector test and refused to take a second, while <PERSON> Laurie </PERSON> passed, said <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Waller </PERSON>, assistant <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> state's attorney.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>MORE</NOTE>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880612-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-12-88 2354EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-LaurieDann'sDemons-1stAdd     06-12 0939</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Laurie Dann's Demons - 1st Add,0966</SECOND>
<HEAD>WINNETKA: state's attorney.</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Police found packaging for an ice pick in the house the <ORGANIZATION> Danns </ORGANIZATION> had shared, but <PERSON> Waller </PERSON> said no fingerprints were on the pick itself. <PERSON> Waller </PERSON> also said reports indicated the doctor and nurse who treated <PERSON> Russell </PERSON> at the hospital noted the wound could have been self-inflicted. No charges were filed. `` There was just no case there,'' <PERSON> Waller </PERSON> said. According to divorce records, <PERSON> Dann </PERSON> was to receive a lump sum of $ 125,000 and $ 1,250 monthly for three years. After the shootings, <PERSON> Russell </PERSON> <PERSON> Dann </PERSON> appeared on `` Nightline'' at his request and phoned a radio talk show to urge tougher gun control. Since then, he has declined further comment. He did acknowledge to The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>, however, that `` some people think I was the bad guy.'' <PERSON> Laurie </PERSON> <PERSON> Dann </PERSON>'s life began unraveling faster and faster in 1986. That summer, she dated <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Childs </PERSON>, whose mother, <PERSON> Alexandra </PERSON>, lived near her parents. She was `` very pretty ... very preppy ... but very shy,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Childs </PERSON> said, and had unusual habits: she washed her hands often and touched things only with a napkin. She said her son `` noticed too many problems. ... She'd be very friendly, then it would be, ` Do n't touch me, do n't touch me.''' That fall, <PERSON> Spivack </PERSON> said his friend, now a doctor, began getting harassing calls he believed were from <PERSON> Dann </PERSON> _ six years after their breakup. <PERSON> Spivack </PERSON> said <PERSON> Dann </PERSON> somehow obtained the doctor's unlisted number; the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> said she knew where the doctor was working. <PERSON> Spivack </PERSON> said the calls stopped in 1987 after an attorney wrote a letter to her parents' home. Last summer, <PERSON> Dann </PERSON>'s father intervened when <ORGANIZATION> Northwestern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> officials, reacting to repeated harassment complaints, including reports she left raw meat under lounge cushions, moved to evict her. She left the graduate student apartment she was subletting. <PERSON> Dann </PERSON> then posted notices in local groceries, seeking babysitting jobs. Many families said she had a terrific rapport with children, but <PERSON> Wasserman </PERSON> twice made restitution to employer families after his daughter was suspected of stealing food or clothes, police say. In January, <PERSON> Dann </PERSON> moved to The Towers in <LOCATION> Madison </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wis. </LOCATION>, a dormitory one block off the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wisconsin </ORGANIZATION> campus. Most residents were freshmen, more than a decade younger than <PERSON> Dann </PERSON>. Her suitemate said <PERSON> Dann </PERSON> told her she was a journalism student from Northwestern, but she never carried books or attended classes. <PERSON> Dann </PERSON> explained to dorm neighbors she wore gloves when she ate because she was allergic or sensitive to metal objects. The suitemate, who asked not to be identified, said after several incidents she became uncomfortable and moved out. Other residents say <PERSON> Dann </PERSON> avoided sidewalk cracks, watched TV all day and rode the elevators for hours, carrying a note pad. Student <PERSON> Brian </PERSON> <PERSON> Soifer </PERSON> said he heard she wept once when some guys teased her on the elevator. `` Everybody told stories about her,'' he said. `` She must have known people were pointing at her and talking about her.'' `` She just looked like she was lost,'' said resident <PERSON> Scott </PERSON> <PERSON> Tzinberg </PERSON>. Amid mounting harassment complaints, meanwhile, the investigations continued. <PERSON> Waller </PERSON> said December phone records showed that 55 pre-dawn calls lasting a minute or less were made in 4 -LCB- hours from the <PERSON> Wasserman </PERSON> home. In March, <PERSON> Dann </PERSON> reportedly stopped seeing her psychiatrist, who had prescribed lithium carbonate to treat depression. She was also taking an experimental drug called clomipramine, used for obsessive-compulsive disorders. That month, a woman who had known the <ORGANIZATION> Danns </ORGANIZATION> when they were married and had received hundreds of hang-up calls since 1986 picked up her phone to hear: ` You are going to die.' The woman, who asked that her name not be used, suspected <PERSON> Dann </PERSON> in all the calls. On March 14, <PERSON> Dann </PERSON> was arrested in <LOCATION> Madison </LOCATION>, accused of stealing four wigs and other items, said Capt. <PERSON> Jeff </PERSON> <PERSON> Frye </PERSON>. He said <PERSON> Dann </PERSON> initially gave police a fake name and a <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION> address. Once she gave her real name, she still gave phony information on her student status and address, he said. On May 9, <PERSON> Spivack </PERSON> said his friend answered the phone and heard a female voice say `` she would come out and stab them and make it look like his wife had done it.'' The <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> was given a tape-recording of the call. The night of May 15, <PERSON> Frye </PERSON> said <PERSON> Dann </PERSON> was found in a dormitory trash room curled in a fetal position, wrapped in a plastic bag and dripping with sweat. When police arrived, however, she was asleep in her room. Aware of the <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION> investigation, the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> was called. They arrived the next morning. She was gone. After the shooting, police searched her belongings and found a picture of her with her ex-husband, scraps of paper with names, rough drafts of threatening notes to the <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION> doctor, supportive letters from her parents, four catalog cards from a library referring to books on poisoning, a list of words including `` schools'' and `` both,'' and a white smock she apparently took from a hospital where she'd been treated as an outpatient, said <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> agent <PERSON> Kent </PERSON> <PERSON> Miller </PERSON> in Madison. <PERSON> Miller </PERSON> said <PERSON> Dann </PERSON> was suspected of stealing arsenic and other chemicals from a hospital lab in March. Plans in <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION> to seek an indictment May 18 were delayed to coordinate legal action with other states. Two days later, <PERSON> Laurie </PERSON> <PERSON> Dann </PERSON>, wearing a <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Arizona </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> shirt with a skeleton on it, reached the end of her road to tragedy. `` I feel very frustrated,'' <PERSON> Spivack </PERSON> said. `` We were within a few days of averting this. We ran out of time.''
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Sharon </PERSON> <PERSON> Cohen </PERSON> is the AP <LOCATION> Midwest </LOCATION> regional reporter, based in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880612-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-12-88 2355EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-WrightDistrict     06-12 0639</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Wright District,0656</SECOND>
<HEAD>House Speaker Still Has The Wright Stuff In His Home District</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Sunday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By SCOTT ROTHSCHILD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>FORT WORTH, Texas (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Inside the beltway that circles <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Speaker <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> is the target of a barrage of charges of ethical misconduct. But inside Loop 820 that circles <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Worth </LOCATION>, his home district, it's business as usual. Aides in <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>'s <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> office are n't hearing complaints about the congressman, they say, just the usual requests from constituents seeking help with Social Security checks or a passport. And local <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> leaders say the charges alone wo n't hurt the powerful Democrat. `` Where there's a lot of smoke you ought to at least look for the fire, but I do n't think the smoke is going to cause him problems,'' said <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Ryan </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> chairman in <LOCATION> Tarrant </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Ryan </PERSON> said the ethics investigation `` may plow him under, or vindicate him and make him a hero.'' The House Ethics <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> voted unanimously Friday to investigate charges lodged by <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>'s political enemy, Rep. <PERSON> Newt </PERSON> <PERSON> Gingrich </PERSON>, R-Ga., and <ORGANIZATION> Common </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cause </ORGANIZATION>, a non-profit group that monitors government ethics They allege that <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> lobbied on behalf of oil interests in a case in which he had a financial stake, that he received unusually high royalties for a book he wrote that was published in 1985 by a longtime associate and campaign contractor, that he used a Capitol Hill staffer and office funds to help draft the book, and that he used a <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Worth </LOCATION> condominium, owned by the family of a business partner, without having to pay a monthly rent. <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Shannon </PERSON>, who directs <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>'s district office, said Thursday the office has received 12 telephone calls in the past two weeks concerning the salvo of charges fired <PERSON> Gingrich </PERSON>. Of those 12, two were negative, while the rest were encouraging, similar to comments <PERSON> Shannon </PERSON> said he received while making rounds in the conservative 12th District that stretches over the northern two-thirds of <LOCATION> Tarrant </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>. The district, about 30 miles west of <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION>, is known for its rowdy frontier image, exemplified by its Fort Worth Stockyards tourist attraction. But the city's collar has whitened with high-technology industries such as <ORGANIZATION> Tandy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, Bell Helicopter and <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dynamics </ORGANIZATION>. Local Democrats say their Republican counterparts have little to complain about because <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> has been an effective congressman for the district. Since his arrival in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> in 1955, <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> has been a prodigious provider of federal dollars for <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Worth </LOCATION>, especially in the form of defense contracts, and he has one of the most politically safe districts in the nation. He faces no Republican opponent in the November election. `` He is a supporter of his friends, even his Republican friends,'' said <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Barron </PERSON>, a longtime <LOCATION> Tarrant </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> Democrat. <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> and other Democrats say the charges are part of a <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> plot to embarrass <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> and the party before the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Convention </ORGANIZATION> next month in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> and to take pressure off Vice President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and Attorney General <PERSON> Edwin </PERSON> <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>. <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> has been named chairman of the convention. <PERSON> Shannon </PERSON> said that when he was eating at a restaurant a man approached him and said: `` They're picking on that boy of ours up there, are n't they? You tell them to leave him alone.'' Recently, constituent <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Ridgeway </PERSON> went to <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>'s <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Worth </LOCATION> office to see if the staff could help him find a certain kind of government stamp for his son's stamp collection. <PERSON> Ridgeway </PERSON>, 39, said the ethics charges do n't bother him. `` I read the newspapers every day, but the fact is I do n't think we could have a better person up there. He's done a lot for the area,'' he said. <PERSON> Ridgeway </PERSON> dismissed the ethics charges as based on politics. `` Every four years someone up there has to start slinging mud,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880612-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-12-88 2357EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-FarmAid     06-12 0740</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Farm Aid,0759</SECOND>
<HEAD>Vermont First In Nation To Enact Subsidy For Farmers</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By MEG DENNISON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>TROY, Vt. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 On a small dairy farm tucked under the Canadian border, the `` For Sale'' sign has come down. Vermonters, worried that the small farmer might become an endangered species, hope it is the beginning of a trend. What prompted <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Jacobs </PERSON> to change his mind and stay on his 100-cow farm was the promise of $ 5,000 cash this year from the state. Most of <LOCATION> Vermont </LOCATION>'s 2,700 farmers are eligible for the subsidy under the first such program ever enacted by a state. Farmers have until Wednesday to apply; a maximum of $ 5,000 will be paid each farmer. The subsidy was born out of fear that the farms that play such a large role in the heritage of one of the nation's most rural states would soon vanish from the landscape. The fear was well-founded: 10 percent of <LOCATION> Vermont </LOCATION>'s 3,000 farms went out of business in the past two years. `` It's viewed as being rather revolutionary,'' said <ORGANIZATION> Vermont </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> Commissioner <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Allbee </PERSON> of the new program. `` It's viewed as, ` I ca n't believe <LOCATION> Vermont </LOCATION> did it.' `` I think this is a ray of sunlight to all the dairy farmers in the state of <LOCATION> Vermont </LOCATION>,'' said <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Morrissette </PERSON> of <PERSON> East </PERSON> <PERSON> Randolph </PERSON>, the first to sign up for the subsidy. The problem facing dairy farmers was simple: The price of milk was falling; costs were rising. Between 1981 and 1987, the price farmers received for their milk declined, in real dollars, from $ 13.90 to $ 12.43 per hundred pounds of milk. More than 40 percent of the farms in the state were operating below the break-even point. The culprit was a federal policy designed to reduce a milk surplus in the West. The policy, farmers said, was ruining dairy farms in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>, where there was a shortage of milk. As 1988 began, <LOCATION> Vermont </LOCATION> farmers endured another reduction in the federal price support, the price the federal ensures farmers for their milk, and faced the prospect of more cuts. The state decided to step in. At first Gov. <PERSON> Madeleine </PERSON> <PERSON> Kunin </PERSON> opposed the one-year $ 7.5 million program as bad fiscal policy that would n't give farmers the long-term help they needed. But lawmakers and citizens groups _ seeing state coffers overflowing from a strong economy _ rallied around the subsidy, concerned that the loss of farmers and farmland would change the face of <LOCATION> Vermont </LOCATION> and remove land treasured for hunting, fishing, trapping and sightseeing. `` They're the custodians of the countryside,'' state Sen. <PERSON> Francis </PERSON> <PERSON> Howrigan </PERSON>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, said of the farmers. The subsidy program will pay farmers 50 cents for every hundred pounds of milk they produce up to 1 million pounds, which is more than the average farm produces. It's available to farmers who receive at least half their gross income from farming, make less than $ 32,000 a year, and belong to a milk cooperative or an 11-state dairy cartel that's trying to win a higher milk price for Northeast farmers. The program faces a legal challenge from a group of farmers who say the program discriminates against those few who do not belong to co-ops. The Legislature this year also enacted some long-term help for farmers that will give them big breaks on their property taxes in future years. The state will pay up to approximately 90 percent of farmers' local property taxes if they agree to continue farming. The tax program covers all non-dairy farmers this year; next year, when the dairy subsidy is eliminated, it will apply to dairy farmers. But lawmakers and farmers say the state can not afford to continue its $ 7.5 million subsidy and that the true solution can come only from the <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. `` It's the finger in a dike that is getting an ever-wider fissure,'' said <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hampshire </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> Commissioner <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON>. `` I think we're in a dire situation, and I do n't think the state of <LOCATION> Vermont </LOCATION> has the resources to carry that farmer for a long period of time.'' <PERSON> Jacobs </PERSON> expects to triple the value of his $ 5,000 payment from the state by using it to grow feed, one of his rapidly rising expenses. `` It's going to make a difference, and it gives you a chance,'' he said, surveying the corn field that lies in the shadow of <PERSON> Jay </PERSON> <PERSON> Peak </PERSON>, a popular ski area. `` It may turn around.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880612-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-12-88 2358EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-SeekingMunchkins     06-12 0695</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Seeking Munchkins,0712</SECOND>
<HEAD>Author Goes Down The Yellow Brick Road Looking For The Munchkins</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By LORI DODGE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ST. LOUIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> Cox </PERSON> is off to see the Munchkins, the wonderful Munchkins of Oz. But he has no Yellow Brick Road to follow in his search for the little people who greeted <PERSON> Dorothy </PERSON> in the 1939 film `` The Wizard of Oz.'' `` It may not be easy to find some of them,'' said the writer. `` I know there are some still living, but they've sort of fallen into the woodwork.'' <PERSON> Cox </PERSON> is writing a book about the little people who sang and danced with the young <PERSON> Judy </PERSON> <PERSON> Garland </PERSON> in the musical based on <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Baum </PERSON>'s magical tale of good and bad witches, a bumbling wizard and <PERSON> Dorothy </PERSON>'s lovable friends, the Scarecrow, Tin Man and Cowardly Lion. <PERSON> Cox </PERSON>'s book, `` Oz Remembered: Memoirs of the Munchkins,'' will be published by E.P. <PERSON> Dutton </PERSON> of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> and released next year to coincide with the 50th anniversary of the MGM movie classic. `` There are hundreds of thousands of people out there who are fascinated by the Munchkins,'' said <PERSON> Jeanne </PERSON> <PERSON> Martinet </PERSON>, a <PERSON> Dutton </PERSON> editor. So far, <ORGANIZATION> Cox </ORGANIZATION> has located about 30 of the 124 people who played <LOCATION> Munchkinland </LOCATION> villagers and soldiers. He has spent days poring over telephone directories and making calls with not much to go on but old address books and faded sign-in sheets from long-ago lunches on the movie's set. `` I figure it's about time to give them some credit,'' <ORGANIZATION> Cox </ORGANIZATION> said, adding that the movie credits gave them little mention. `` All it said was ` The Singer Midgets as the Munchkins.' Their scene lasts about 10 minutes, but I think it's the most enchanting part of the whole movie.'' For <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Pellegrini </PERSON>, being a Munchkin meant a chance to meet movie stars and other people of her size. She was 16 when the movie was made and is nearing 70 now, she said recently from her home in <LOCATION> Glendale </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ariz. </LOCATION> `` Meeting up with all the little people, because I had n't been around very many little people _ it was just a great experience.'' `` I did n't think it would be so popular. Of course, I was excited about it and I was thinking, ` Oh boy, I'm going to <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION>.''' `` A lot of the Munchkins think: A book on the Munchkins? Is that really going to sell?'' <PERSON> Cox </PERSON> said. `` They do n't realize how popular they are.'' Most of the men and women who played the Munchkins were recruited by two troupes of vaudeville midgets headed by <PERSON> Leo </PERSON> <PERSON> Singer </PERSON> and <PERSON> Major </PERSON> <PERSON> Doyle </PERSON>. But many of them had never acted before and some were from <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> and did n't speak English, <ORGANIZATION> Cox </ORGANIZATION> said. A few of them went on in show business, but most eventually settled into other jobs, he said. <PERSON> Mickey </PERSON> <PERSON> Carroll </PERSON> of <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Louis </LOCATION>, now 69, continued acting for a time, then returned home to the family business selling grave monuments. <PERSON> Parnell </PERSON> <PERSON> St. </PERSON> <PERSON> Aubin </PERSON> opened a tavern in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> called the <ORGANIZATION> Midget </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Club </ORGANIZATION> and walked along the bar serving drinks. <PERSON> Meinhardt </PERSON> <PERSON> Raabe </PERSON> went on to portray Little Oscar for <PERSON> Oscar </PERSON> <PERSON> Mayer </PERSON> lunchmeats and made promotional appearances around the country. They're all proud of their parts in `` The Wizard of Oz,'' <ORGANIZATION> Cox </ORGANIZATION> said. `` They're proud of being a part of one of the best motion pictures ever made. A new generation discovers ` The Wizard of Oz' every year. But for all the fond memories of working with <PERSON> Miss </PERSON> <PERSON> Garland </PERSON> and the other stars, there were problems, <ORGANIZATION> Cox </ORGANIZATION> said. <PERSON> Pellegrini </PERSON> recalled heavy, elaborate costumes and layers of makeup. <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON> <PERSON> Croft </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Falls </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION>, remembered how it smarted when the plastic `` skin'' that made the men look bald was ripped off like a piece of tape at the end of each day. <PERSON> Cox </PERSON> said he has heard a story about one Munchkin _ an actor nicknamed `` The Count'' and well-known for his drinking _ who visited the bathroom one day and wound up falling into the toilet and being stuck there for 45 minutes. `` Some of the little people are telling tall tales,'' he said. `` But some of it's good for legends.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880612-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-12-88 2359EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-StateDeficits     06-12 0782</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-State Deficits,0805</SECOND>
<HEAD>Federal Tax Reform Bringing Bad News To State Governments</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT BELLAFIORE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ALBANY, N.Y. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Gov. <PERSON> Mario </PERSON> <PERSON> Cuomo </PERSON> has a $ 900 million problem, <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Deukmejian </PERSON>'s is $ 2 billion and Democratic presidential candidate <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' just grew to more than $ 400 million in <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION>. State budget deficits are sweeping the nation as a result of what almost everyone thought was a good idea _ federal tax reform that has resulted in a slump in capital gains tax collections. <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> announced last week that he would have to pare as much as $ 60 million from his budget proposal because of a one-shot `` revenue slump'' brought on by lower-than-expected tax collections. <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION> budget chief <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON> <PERSON> Milano </PERSON> warned state agencies last week that sluggish revenue collections could mean the state will start its new fiscal year July 1 with a deficit. In <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION>, state officials say that total revenues are up but that taxes on sales of personal investments, also known as capital gains, are down about 8 percent. There are indications that other states that rely heavily on personal income taxes for revenue may have similar problems as the year goes on, said <PERSON> Dall </PERSON> <PERSON> Forsythe </PERSON>, <PERSON> Cuomo </PERSON>'s budget director. <PERSON> Cuomo </PERSON> has even proposed cutting funding for the state's <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> on </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Children </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Families </ORGANIZATION>, which is run by his wife, <PERSON> Matilda </PERSON>. Most states reaped tax revenue windfalls from 1986 when investors rushed to take advantage of tax breaks that the new federal rules were designed to erase when they took effect Jan. 1, 1987. Then the tax changes sent taxpayers running to their accountants for help in reducing their taxes, and the taking of capital gains slowed, reducing capital gains tax revenues. In some states, such as <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION>, budget officials lowered their revenue estimates forthis year in anticipation of a possible shortfall. The <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> Chamber of Business and Industry complained that Gov. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Casey </PERSON>'s administration was not liberal enough in estimating the benefits of federal tax reform. `` We had a discussion with the <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> Chamber on how much of a windfall we would get and we said, ` None,''' said <PERSON> Karl </PERSON> <PERSON> Ross </PERSON>, <PERSON> Casey </PERSON>'s deputy secretary for policy and analysis. `` That's what we budgeted for and that's what's happening.'' The fiscal problems are causing political headaches for <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> and <PERSON> Deukmejian </PERSON>. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, the likely Democratic presidential nominee, based his campaign on his abilities as a manager. He must now cut his budget because his numbers were wrong. Republican <PERSON> Deukmejian </PERSON>, who has been mentioned as a possible running mate for <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, had proposed $ 800 million in revenue raisers to help close his budget gap, estimated at about $ 1 billion this year and $ 1 billion next year. But he withdrew the proposal, angry at reporters for calling it a tax increase. Democrat <PERSON> Cuomo </PERSON> does n't have to run for re-election until 1990 and has been quick to propose some politically unpopular spending cuts. <PERSON> Cuomo </PERSON> said last week that the shortfall could present a good lesson for this year's presidential campaign by demonstrating the different approaches for dealing with it. `` The deficit he has is just the right size,'' <PERSON> Cuomo </PERSON> said of <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>. `` I think this is a break for <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>. He will now show you how he handles a deficit. He will do it swiftly, cleanly, effectively.'' <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION>' Democrat-controlled Legislature has tentatively passed a $ 40 million cigarette tax hike and a revision of state tax law to conform it to federal law that would increase personal income taxes by $ 70 million this year. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> is not yet committed to the cigarette tax. There have also been cursory discussions of other `` sin taxes'' on liquor and entertainment to close <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION>' $ 400 million shortfall. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> already has ordered that $ 233 million in spending be postponed, that state employment be frozen and that agencies prepare for possible personnel cuts through attrition. <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION>' total budget is about $ 11 billion. <PERSON> Cuomo </PERSON> last week proposed $ 406 million in program cuts and cost-savings from the $ 44.2 billion-plus budget the <ORGANIZATION> Legislature </ORGANIZATION> adopted less than two months ago. He also wants to make use of a $ 650 million fund that, ironically, was created with the 1986 tax windfall and set aside for low-income housing and highway projects. <PERSON> Cuomo </PERSON> has, among other things, ordered a hiring freeze for state agencies and proposed increasing tuition for out-of-state students at <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>'s public colleges. He's called for the elimination of the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION>'s six-horse mounted patrol, a favorite at fairs throughout <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Cuomo </PERSON> has refused to call for tax increases or even a delay of tax cuts enacted last year, even though at the time he suggested the cuts might be too generous.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880612-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-12-88 0016EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Cambodia     06-12 0263</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Cambodia,0269</SECOND>
<HEAD>Khmer Rouge Claim Victories as 10th Rainy Season Begins</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BANGKOK, Thailand (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Communist guerrillas fighting in <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION> said in a broadcast available Sunday that they killed or wounded nearly 3,000 Vietnamese soldiers during May. The claim contradicted earlier pronouncements by <LOCATION> Hanoi </LOCATION>, which said fighting had died down and it could therefore begin withdrawing troops. The clandestine <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION> radio said 2,821 Vietnamese soldiers had been killed or wounded during the first month of the 10th rainy season of the war. It said <LOCATION> Hanoi </LOCATION>'s administrative networks had been dismantled in 537 villages, 11 communes and one township. Past rainy seasons have usually favored the guerrillas, who are fighting the mechanized, conventional forces <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> has maintained in <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION> since its late 1978 invasion. `` They lack both fighting forces and food supplies, and their aggressor soldiers are increasingly demoralized,'' said the broadcast, made available in <LOCATION> Bangkok </LOCATION>. `` In sum, the Vietnamese have failed and are a complete impasse.'' <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>, however, has announced that a greatly improved security situation in <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION> would allow it to pull 50,000 troops out of <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION> over the next seven months. The partial withdrawal may begin late this month. Western analysts, who are generally skeptical of <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION> claims, say there has been a sharp drop in fighting in <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION> in recent months. They speculated that the <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION> and other guerrilla groups may be stockpiling weapons and positioning themselves for a big push when <LOCATION> Hanoi </LOCATION>'s forces are scaled down. The <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION>, ousted from power by the Vietnamese, are allied to two non-communist groups in a loose coalition.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880612-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-12-88 0132EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-Children'sHome 4thLd-Writethru a0644 06-12 1042</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Children's Home, 4th Ld-Writethru, a0644,1074</SECOND>
<HEAD>State Trying to Track Down Parents of Bethel Children</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: SUBS 6th graf, `The home's ...' with 2 grafs to UPDATE with
pastor saying he is sheltering four or five youths who fled state
officials; Picks up 7th graf, `The judge ...'</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By ALEX DOMINGUEZ</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WHITFIELD, Miss. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> state troopers and social workers Saturday were still seeking dozens of youngsters who fled a Baptist boarding school moments before authorities investigating allegations of abuse could take them into state custody. Sixty-four residents of the <LOCATION> Bethel </LOCATION> Home for Children in <LOCATION> Lucedale </LOCATION>, about 100 miles to the southeast, were taken to the <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> State </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION> here. Most arrived Friday night, while others arrived at the psychiatric hospital Saturday. Some of the children, ages 8 through 17, were found in private homes, restaurants and along the streets of <LOCATION> Lucedale </LOCATION>. Most of the 120 to 160 students at the school had fled Friday before state social workers arrived to carry out a court order assigning the state temporary custody of the children. The whereabouts of the remaining children was not known Saturday, and state welfare officials said they might be in hiding. The home's operator, The Rev. <PERSON> Herman </PERSON> <PERSON> Fountain </PERSON>, said Saturday he is sheltering four or five youngsters who fled. He also said in a telephone interview from <LOCATION> Lucedale </LOCATION> that he had taken a new teen-age boy into the <LOCATION> Bethel </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Home </LOCATION> on Saturday and would continue to take any children dropped off by parents, the <ORGANIZATION> Biloxi </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sun-Herald </ORGANIZATION> reported in its Sunday editions. `` I've still got a few soldiers left, and I'm trying to work back to what it was before,'' <PERSON> Fountain </PERSON> said. The judge who issued the order said there was reason to suspect physical and mental abuse of students. Complaints by former residents of the home ranged from severe beatings to forced labor. Some children received excessive corporal punishment and no medical care and were harassed by other children at the home, state Welfare Commissioner <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Brittain </PERSON> said Saturday. As to any new residents taken in by Fountain, <PERSON> Brittain </PERSON> said the state would await orders from the judge, <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Oswald </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Pascagoula </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Oswald </PERSON> said he would n't indicate how he'll deal with the development until Monday, when a court hearing is scheduled in the case. Fountain, 38, said in the interview that he became a minister after God saved him from heroin addiction in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> in 1972 and that he opened the <LOCATION> Bethel </LOCATION> Home for children in 1979. He denied telling the children to run away from the home when welfare officials arrived. `` The children are in here mainly for runaways, stealing, homosexuality. We have little girls who are whores,'' <PERSON> Fountain </PERSON> said, adding that strict discipline is required for such youths. `` The parents have lost control. Kids today are such manipulators. Such cons. Especially a child from a divorce. They've learned how to manipulate their parents,'' he said By Saturday evening, <PERSON> Brittain </PERSON> said he had released 10 children to their parents. He said he expected to keep interviewing parents Saturday and Sunday; by Monday, he said he hoped to arrange the return of almost all the children. <PERSON> Eric </PERSON> <PERSON> Parker </PERSON>, 16, was among the students who screamed angrily at <ORGANIZATION> Welfare </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> workers and state troopers when they arrived Friday. `` You have no right,'' he yelled. `` I want to be here with my people. I do n't want to be with all the rest of you people who hate the truth. You better check yourself and make sure you are not burning on the way to hell.'' The home is on the grounds of <ORGANIZATION> Bethel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Baptist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION>, which is not affiliated with any formal group. Authorities are not sure how many students were at the home because they have not seen its records and were not been able to contact Fountain since Friday, <PERSON> Brittain </PERSON> said. The missing children might have been moved secretly to another location by Fountain, he said. `` We have a suspicion in that direction, but do n't like to make a confirmation one way or another until we are sure,'' <PERSON> Brittain </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Brittain </PERSON> said he had met with parents or more than a dozen children but did not return children to some who refused to answer questions. `` We indicated to them that until they did, they had better make some other arrangements for their children,'' <PERSON> Brittain </PERSON> said. State officials said they hoped that the children would be released to their parents or guardians as soon as possible. Officials telephoned parents and guardians and set up a special line for them. Hospital officials reported handling calls from parents as far away as <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION>. `` We started getting calls just after lunch -LRB- Friday -RRB-,'' said spokeswoman <PERSON> Wynona </PERSON> <PERSON> Winfield </PERSON>. `` Yes, you can say it's been busy. Busy, busy.'' <PERSON> Oswald </PERSON> ruled Friday afternoon that he was turning over custody of the residents to the state. The independent Baptist boarding school has come under fire several times since 1980. A physician testified during a hearing into the welfare of one child who ran away from the home that during a 19-month stay at <LOCATION> Bethel </LOCATION> the child did not receive medical treatment for an eye condition that could have left him blind. Doctors at the state hospital helped conduct medical examinations of the children but would not comment on their condition, <PERSON> Winfield </PERSON> said. A court hearing is set for Monday in the case. The state hospital was chosen to house the children because of readily available living space, food services, recreational facilities and medical and crisis intervention services, <PERSON> Brittain </PERSON> said. The children will have no contact with patients, officials said. Boys slept Friday night on mattresses in the gymnasium, while the girls stayed in a vacant dormitory. Minutes after <PERSON> Oswald </PERSON> issued his order at 11 a.m. Friday, state <ORGANIZATION> Welfare </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> personnel arrived at the home. The youths apparently were alerted about the court order and most had fled. `` I did n't tell those kids to run,'' <PERSON> Fountain </PERSON> said Friday. Fountain had been jailed for two days for refusing to give officials a list of residents. He was released Friday without providing the information when he agreed to an orderly transfer of the children to state custody. <PERSON> Brittain </PERSON> said he did n't know what action, if any, would be taken against Fountain.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880612-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-12-88 0226EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Bangladesh 1stLd-Writethru a0632 06-12 0378</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Bangladesh, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0632,0390</SECOND>
<HEAD>Strike Begins Over Islamic State Religion Law</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDS: ADDS byline, LEADS with 9 grafs to UPDATE with strike
beginning, CORRECTS thruout that law already in effect, PICKS UP
graf 7 pvs ```They have'</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By FARID HOSSAIN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>DHAKA, Bangladesh (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Opponents of a law that made Islam the state religion closed stores and halted traffic in the capital Sunday as they began an eight-hour nationwide strike. However, the monsoon rain kept police and protesters out of the streets of <LOCATION> Dhaka </LOCATION>. The country's mainstream opposition called the strike to condemn the law passed Tuesday by the 300-seat <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION> and signed into law by President <PERSON> Hussain </PERSON> <PERSON> Muhammad </PERSON> <PERSON> Ershad </PERSON>. Foes of the law had led torchlight parades through <LOCATION> Dhaka </LOCATION> on Saturday. The government tightened security in the capital and other cities in preparation for the strike Sunday. Riot police in trucks followed several small protest parades Saturday evening, but did not interfere. Among those who called the eight-hour general strike are three major opposition political alliances. At least 30 people have been injured and 35 vehicles damaged in repeated clashes with police since Parliament approved the bill. `` We have several thousand police on constant duty in <LOCATION> Dhaka </LOCATION> and elsewhere. We are going to deploy more for tomorrow,'' a <ORGANIZATION> Home </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> source told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> on Saturday, speaking on condition of anonymity. <PERSON> Ershad </PERSON> attacked those organizing the strike. `` They have called this hartal -LRB- strike -RRB- against <PERSON> Allah </PERSON>, his prophet and his religion,'' <PERSON> Ershad </PERSON> told Moslems at a <LOCATION> Dhaka </LOCATION> mosque after Friday prayers. He denied charges that the bill was aimed at perpetuating his rule, which began with a bloodless coup by the former army general in 1982. `` None can rule unless Allah wishes it,'' <PERSON> Ershad </PERSON> said. The measure amends the nation's constitution by inserting the sentence: `` The religion of the republic is Islam, but other religions may be practiced in peace and harmony.'' Opponents of the bill, mostly opposition politicians, women, students and members of the minority <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Hindu </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> Buddhist </ORGANIZATION> religions, say they fear it will lead to imposition of harsh Islamic rule based on the Koran. More than 85 percent of the country's 105 million people are Moslems. But the government denies it plans to change the nation's British-based civil law
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880612-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-12-88 0427EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a BC-ArizonaFires 1stLd-Writethru a0650 06-12 0468</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Arizona Fires, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0650,0473</SECOND>
<HEAD>Fires Burn On Both Sides of Border</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: LEADS with 7 grafs to UPDATE that homes saved, two structures
damaged, cause of second fire; Picks up 7th graf, `About 300 ...'</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By MEL REISNER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PHOENIX, Ariz. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Hundreds of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and Mexican firefighters on Sunday battled fires that burned thousands of acres of brush and timber on both sides of the border and raced across an Apache Indian reservation, officials said. A forest fire that started in <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> charred 6,000 acres, about 3,500 on the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> side of the border near <LOCATION> Nicksville </LOCATION>, and damaged two structures in a park picnic area, said <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Payne </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Phoenix </LOCATION>. The blaze, which <PERSON> Payne </PERSON> called `` a raging monster out of control,'' also had threatened ranch homes in the <ORGANIZATION> Coronado </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Monument </ORGANIZATION>, about 50 miles south of <LOCATION> Tucson </LOCATION>, before they were saved by crews who started backfires. Nearly 200 miles north, a second fire that was sparked by lightning Friday in logging slash on a reservation near <LOCATION> Cibecue </LOCATION> had covered more than 500 acres of timber and brush by early Sunday, <PERSON> Payne </PERSON> said. South of the border, the largest fire _ more than 10,000 acres _ had been burning for more than a week in the <LOCATION> Sierra </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Pinta </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mountains </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Sonora </LOCATION> state, <PERSON> Payne </PERSON> said. Four <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> forest officials crossed the border to serve as advisers in fighting the blaze. The fire near <LOCATION> Nicksville </LOCATION> was burning mostly on state and federal land in the national monument and the <ORGANIZATION> Coronado </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> at elevations above 7,000 feet, he said. Authorities were unsure what started the blaze. The blaze damaged a restroom and a ramada, the Western version of a gazebo, in a picnic area within the national monument area, <PERSON> Payne </PERSON> said. About 300 firefighters battled the blaze on the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> side Saturday, said <ORGANIZATION> Coronado </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Dennis </PERSON> <PERSON> Brandolino </PERSON>, but another 500 to 700 firefighters were expected Sunday from <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION> and nearby states. Mexican firefighters were battling the flames on their side of the border. Three planes made a dozen runs to drop about 30,000 gallons of fire retardant on the border blaze, said <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Perea </PERSON>, the fire's air-service coordinator from <LOCATION> Moutainair </LOCATION>, N.M Intermittent high winds whipped the <LOCATION> Cibecue </LOCATION> fire, where about 280 firefighters were on the line Saturday night, said <ORGANIZATION> Apache-Sitgreaves </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Ken </PERSON> <PERSON> Palmrose </PERSON>. The blaze at the 6,000-foot level was burning `` heavy pine, fir and some -LRB- scrub -RRB- oak in the canyon bottoms,'' eating away at chaparral and other types of brush on the ridges, <PERSON> Palmrose </PERSON> said. The fire was being managed by an `` interagency overhead team'' with representatives from the federal Forest and Park services and the <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Indian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Affairs </ORGANIZATION>, with consultation from the <LOCATION> White </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Apache </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Tribe </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Palmrose </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880612-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-12-88 0524EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i BC-Khomeini     06-12 0150</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Khomeini,0156</SECOND>
<HEAD>Iran Official Denies Reports That Khomeini Dying</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NICOSIA, Cyprus (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A high Iranian official denied reports that <PERSON> Ayatollah </PERSON> <PERSON> Ruhollah </PERSON> <PERSON> Khomeini </PERSON> was terminally ill, <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'s official news agency said Sunday <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'s Interior Minister <PERSON> Ali-Akbar </PERSON> <PERSON> Mohtashemi </PERSON> was quoted by the <ORGANIZATION> Islamic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> as saying he met the national leader last week. He said the revolutionary patriarch `` is now in perfect shape'' in the broadcast monitored in <LOCATION> Nicosia </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Khomeini </PERSON>, 87, has been reported to be in frail health since he suffered a heart attack two years ago. There have also been unconfirmed reports that he has cancer. <PERSON> Mohtashemi </PERSON> called the latest report `` a Zionist scheme to cheer up <LOCATION> Iraqi </LOCATION> President <PERSON> Saddam </PERSON> <PERSON> Hussein </PERSON> and his demoralized army.'' <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> have been waging war for nearly eight years. The <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> television network reported Thursday that intelligence reports indicated that <PERSON> Khomeini </PERSON> `` may now be very close to death.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880612-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-12-88 0636EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i BC-Korea-Protests     06-12 0269</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Korea-Protests,0276</SECOND>
<HEAD>Radical Students Battle Riot Police During Funeral March</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By M.H. AHN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SEOUL, South Korea (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Police fired tear gas to drive back students who tried to storm the government party's headquarters Sunday during the funeral of a radical who committed ritual suicide. Hundreds of riot police firing volleys of tear gas pushed back waves of charging students who sought to reach the offices of the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>. The screaming students hurled hundreds of firebombs, and streets were covered with blazing gasoline as running clashes flared across the center of the city. `` Down with the military fascists,'' radical students yelled, and they hurled rocks and firebombs at police in <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION>'s main shopping district. Protesters destroyed a police truck with firebombs. But riot police quickly pushed protesters back and chased them through the city for several miles. Radicals hurled rocks at the Japanese Embassy's information office and smashed windows. The fighting broke out during a funeral procession by about 10,000 radical students and sympathizers for Park Rae-chun, who died Monday after setting fire to himself in an anti-government protest. It was the third ritual suicide by a radical student since May 15. <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> has been hit by a wave of violent radical student protests during the past month. Thousands of students trying to reach <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> for talks on reuniting the divided <LOCATION> Korean </LOCATION> peninsula battled riot police in major street clashes Friday. Some marchers shouted `` Yankee go home'' Sunday, but the protest was less anti-American than others in recent days. Instead, it was directed mainly at the government of President <PERSON> Roh </PERSON> Tae-woo.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880612-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-12-88 1101EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a BC-Obit-L'Amour 2ndLd-Writethru a0655 06-12 0262</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Obit-L'Amour, 2nd Ld-Writethru, a0655,0267</SECOND>
<HEAD>Prolific Western Novelist Dead At 80</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: SUBS 4th graf, `The author ...,' to give number of novels.
SUBS 7th graf, `Born in ...,' with 2 grafs to add more on
background. Adds byline.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By RIC LEYVA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Prolific writer <PERSON> Louis </PERSON> <PERSON> L'Amour </PERSON>, whose popular novels recreated the Old West of gunfighters and lawmen, cattle rustlers and horse thieves, has died of lung cancer, relatives said. He was 80. <PERSON> L'Amour </PERSON> died Friday night in his <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> home, said his wife, <PERSON> Kathy </PERSON>. President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> praised <PERSON> L'Amour </PERSON> in 1983 for `` having brought the West to the people of the East and to people everywhere.'' The author penned 101 books, nearly all of them Westerns, including `` Hondo,'' `` How the West Was Won,'' `` The Iron Marshal,'' `` The Quick and the Dead,'' `` <PERSON> Sackett </PERSON>'s Land,'' `` Down the <LOCATION> Long </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hills </LOCATION>,'' and `` Ride the Dark Trail.'' Several, including `` How the West Was Won,'' were made into motion pictures, Mrs. <PERSON> L'Amour </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> presented L'Amour in 1984 with the Presidential Medal of Freedom. The previous year, <PERSON> L'Amour </PERSON> received a National Gold Medal, awarded by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. Born in <LOCATION> Jamestown </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.D. </LOCATION>, in 1908, <PERSON> L'Amour </PERSON> quit school and left home when he was 15, working as a prize fighter, tugboat deckhand, longshoreman, lumberjack, gold prospector, circus roustabout, fruit picker, elephant handler and amateur archaeologist. <PERSON> L'Amour </PERSON> was self-educated, but later lectured at such prestigious campuses as the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Oklahoma </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Baylor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> L'Amour </PERSON> is survived by his wife of 32 years, and two children, <PERSON> Beau </PERSON> and <PERSON> Angelique </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880612-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-12-88 1117EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i BC-Argentina-Plane 1stLd-Writethru a0657 06-12 0235</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Argentina-Plane, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0657,0238</SECOND>
<HEAD>URGENT</HEAD>
<HEAD>Jetliner Crashes In Argentina, At Least 21 Feared Dead</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Leads with 4 grafs to UPDATE with plane crashing at 9:50 a.m.
into a plantation. Pickup 4th graf pvs, ``There were...''</NOTE>
<DATELINE>BUENOS AIRES, Argentina (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A DC-9 jetliner carrying at least 21 people crashed Sunday while trying to land at a fogbound airport in northeastern <LOCATION> Argentina </LOCATION>, authorities said. There were no immediate reports of survivors. According to the government news agency <ORGANIZATION> Telam </ORGANIZATION>, at least 15 passengers and a crew of six were on board the Austral airlines jet, which left <LOCATION> Buenos </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Aires </LOCATION>' airport at 7 a.m. and stopped at the northern river port of <LOCATION> Resistencia </LOCATION>. Local news and radio reports said the plane then headed north and crashed at 9:50 a.m. into a plantation three miles short of the Posadas airport while trying to land there in heavy fog. Posadas, the capital of <LOCATION> Misiones </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Province </LOCATION>, is 700 miles northeast of <LOCATION> Buenos </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Aires </LOCATION> and across the <LOCATION> Parana </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> from the Paraguayan city of <LOCATION> Encarnacion </LOCATION>. There were unconfirmed reports the jetliner was on fire moments before it crashed. Firefighters who rushed to the scene in the semi-tropical north of <LOCATION> Argentina </LOCATION> said it appeared unlikely there were any survivors, <ORGANIZATION> Telam </ORGANIZATION> said. Austral is a private carrier purchased last year from the state that competes with the government carrier <ORGANIZATION> Aerolineas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Argentinas </ORGANIZATION> on domestic routes across <LOCATION> Argentina </LOCATION>, the world's eighth-largest country geographically.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880612-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-12-88 1148EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-US-Nicaragua Bjt   06-12 0614</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-US-Nicaragua, Bjt,590</SECOND>
<HEAD>Summit Impact on Nicaragua: Zero</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GEORGE GEDDA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The recent Soviet-American summit, widely seen as dealing a telling blow to the Cold War, appears to have had no impact on the continuing struggle between the two countries over <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>. Just a week after President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> bade a warm farewell to Soviet leader <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>, peace talks in <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> broke down and once again there is talk of renewing <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military aid to the Contra rebels. Although the administration has made no decisions, officials seem to be laying the groundwork for a new aid request now that the negotiations between the Soviet-backed <ORGANIZATION> Sandinistas </ORGANIZATION> and the Contras have collapsed, at least for the time being. The experience at the summit suggests <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> are able to move ahead on such issues as arms control, human rights and bilateral issues, but mutual suspicions continue to run high in the so-called `` low intensity conflicts'' in the Third World. Such conflicts continue in <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, southern <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Southeast </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION>. Assistant Secretary of State <PERSON> Elliott </PERSON> <PERSON> Abrams </PERSON> acknowledged in an interview Friday that whatever progress <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> have made on other issues during their summit meetings, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> concerns about <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION> policy in <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> remain unchanged. `` The <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> has not shown any restraint in shipment of arms to Sandinistas,'' <PERSON> Abrams </PERSON> said. Estimates of Soviet military deliveries to the Nicaraguan government range between $ 250 million and $ 500 million since five <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> presidents signed a regional peace plan 10 months ago, he said. <PERSON> Abrams </PERSON> rejected out of hand a Soviet proposal to end military deliveries to the <ORGANIZATION> Sandinistas </ORGANIZATION> provided the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> terminates such shipments to <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Guatemala </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION>. He said this would make <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> coequal in an area of vital interest to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and of no historic interest to the Kremlin If the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> ceases aiding its allies in <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, `` how are they to resist Cuban subversion?'' he asked. The Kremlin view is that the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, by aiding the Nicaraguan rebels starting just months after <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> took office in 1981, bears the major responsibility for the death and destruction in <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> since then. <PERSON> Abrams </PERSON> had had little to say on <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> after <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> rejected on Feb. 3 <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s last request for military aid for the Contras. But after the peace talks broke down last Thursday, he sounded like his old combative self again, accusing the Sandinistas of engaging in bad faith. `` It's important to be clear on what happened,'' <PERSON> Abrams </PERSON> said. The rebels wanted the <ORGANIZATION> Sandinistas </ORGANIZATION> to turn `` vague promises'' of democracy for <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> into a firm timetable. But the only firm timetable the <ORGANIZATION> Sandinistas </ORGANIZATION> wanted to discuss was the one in which the rebels would be required to turn in their arms as part of a final settlement, he said. `` When the time came for the <ORGANIZATION> Sandinistas </ORGANIZATION> to make serious commitments, it was over,'' he said. That view was not shared by Nicaraguan Defense Minister <PERSON> Humberto </PERSON> <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON>, head of the Sandinista delegation, who said Thursday the Contras held `` irrational positions'' and maintained an `` anti-negotiation attitude against the peace.'' As for the prospect for a new Contra aid request, the administration is expected to discuss that issue this coming week. On <LOCATION> Capitol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION>, the main protagonists on past Contra aid votes already are staking out positions along familiar lines. `` I encourage the White House to move now ... and send up an aid package for a vote before the July recess,'' said Rep. <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-N.Y. </LOCATION> Said Rep. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Bonior </PERSON>, R-Mich., `` This is no time to be talking of military aid.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880612-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-12-88 1151EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w AM-Congressman'sCallers Bjt   06-12 0811</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Congressman's Callers, Bjt,800</SECOND>
<HEAD>A Massive Call-in Campaign Ties Up a Congressman's Office</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LARRY MARGASAK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 For a month, the telephones in the office of Rep. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Hughes </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.J. </LOCATION>, have been tied up by members of an anti-pornography group who have been urged to phone him and keep calling `` till you get through.'' Constituents have been unable to reach <PERSON> Hughes </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> speaker's staff has had to send a page to contact him and even an exasperated <PERSON> Hughes </PERSON> has been kept from reaching his secretary when he's away from the office. About 10,000 calls and nearly 20,000 letters have arrived in a campaign orchestrated by the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Family </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, of <LOCATION> Tupelo </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Miss. </LOCATION>, which told its members that an anti-pornography bill would die in a subcommittee chaired by <PERSON> Hughes </PERSON>. `` Perhaps you believe that a congressional office looks like <ORGANIZATION> Home </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Shopping </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Network </ORGANIZATION>, with dozens of operators sitting before computer terminals, ready and able to take messages,'' the congressman wrote the Rev. <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Wildmon </PERSON>, the group's executive director, on May 23, complaining about the tactic, and calling it needless. <PERSON> Hughes </PERSON>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Judiciary </ORGANIZATION> subcommittee on crime, said the bill is very much alive, and will have a second hearing on Thursday. Any delays have been caused by the diversion of staffers from the bill to work on the letters and phone calls, he said. Callers to <PERSON> Hughes </PERSON>' office are now greeted by a recorded message from the seven-term congressman that is on two answering machines. The machines were paid for by members of <PERSON> Hughes </PERSON>' staff, who decided the crisis could not wait for <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> officials to buy the devices. After advising callers on other matters to dial another number, <PERSON> Hughes </PERSON> tells those interested in the pornography bill: `` You can be certain that I and the other 200 sponsors of this important measure will do all we can to see that it becomes law in a timely fashion. `` Thank you for calling. There's no need to leave a message. Your call is being counted automatically.'' <PERSON> Hughes </PERSON> said in the interview, and in letters to <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> colleagues and <PERSON> Wildmon </PERSON>, that the family association fed its members inaccurate information, including an allegation that pornographers are twisting arms of lawmakers to kill the bill. But the most inaccurate message, <PERSON> Hughes </PERSON> said, is that the Child Protection and Obscenity Enforcement Act of 1988 is dying in the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Judiciary subcommittee on crime. `` We're in the hearing process,'' <PERSON> Hughes </PERSON> said. `` <PERSON> Wildmon </PERSON> demanded we abandon that process and pass the bill with no amendments.'' <PERSON> Hughes </PERSON> said that some provisions in the bill raise `` sensitive First Amendment concerns.'' Noting the 11-year-old association's letter asks for donations, <PERSON> Hughes </PERSON> said the money appeal may be the real message the group wants to convey. The legislation encompasses a number of recommendations from the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration's <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> on Pornography. Some of its provisions would allow government seizure of money and property derived from violation of pornography and obscenity laws; use of wiretaps in obscenity investigations; prohibition of obscenity in cable television programming; and creation of a new crime of receiving or possessing obscenity with the intent to transfer. <PERSON> Wildmon </PERSON> told his followers in early May that the legislation `` is about to die'' in <PERSON> Hughes </PERSON>' committee, and urged supporters, `` If his phone is busy, keep calling till you get through.'' The letter said pornographers are `` spending a lot of money, twisting a lot of arms and pressuring a lot of congressmen,'' and asked, `` If you can help defray these unexpected costs, I'd be grateful. You can use the enclosed envelope.'' <PERSON> Wildmon </PERSON> said in an interview that he regrets the inconvenience suffered by <PERSON> Hughes </PERSON>' staff, but contended he only wrote the letter after the crime subcommittee staff refused to tell him about plans for the bill. <PERSON> Hughes </PERSON> replied that he doubted that allegation, since the staff fields such routine inquiries all the time. Asked what evidence he had that the bill would die in committee, <PERSON> Wildmon </PERSON> said, `` I was told by a number of people who knew what they were talking about.'' Asked who they were he replied, `` No comment.'' He also declined to say how he knew pornographers were pressuring lawmakers. <PERSON> Wildmon </PERSON> denied that the purpose of his letter was to raise money, commenting, `` It cost me $ 79,000 to send the letter. To date, we raised $ 42,000. If I'm going to raise funds by losing $ 37,000 I'm going to be out of business in a hurry. `` It was a two-page letter and there were three sentences of an apology, saying I've got expenses to meet.'' <PERSON> Wildmon </PERSON> said the group had 330,000 supporters, a number based on the 170,000 ministers and 160,000 others who receive the group's publications The <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Family </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Wildmon </PERSON> said, is a group that `` promotes things that would enhance the family'' and has taken positions against pornography, abortion, and some broadcast entertainment shows.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880612-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-12-88 1152EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Soviet-Church     06-12 0505</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Soviet-Church,0519</SECOND>
<HEAD>Gromyko: Roman Catholic Church Free To Expand in Soviet Union</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MOSCOW (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Andrei </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gromyko </PERSON> said in remarks published Sunday that the government will not stand in the way of the expansion of the <ORGANIZATION> Roman </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. `` Of course we are n't making any attempts to encroach on the rights of the Catholic church,'' <PERSON> Gromyko </PERSON> was quoted as saying in the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> newspaper Pravda. `` And likewise, we are not trying to encroach on the rights of Catholics living in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>.'' <PERSON> Gromyko </PERSON> make the comments Saturday during the celebration of Christianity's arrival 1,000 years ago in what is now the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. The communist Soviet government is officially atheist. <PERSON> Gromyko </PERSON>'s comments followed a question by Cardinal <PERSON> Johannes </PERSON> <PERSON> Willebrands </PERSON> on the possibility of organizing <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> churches not only in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>'s Baltic republics, where a recognized church exists in <LOCATION> Lithuania </LOCATION>, but also in other parts of the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> where there are large <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> communities. <PERSON> Willebrands </PERSON>, who heads the <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION>'s secretariat for <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Unity </ORGANIZATION>, is a member of the largest <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION> delegation ever to visit the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. He was among several foreign dignitaries in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> for the church millennium who were invited to a <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION> meeting with <PERSON> Gromyko </PERSON>. <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION> spokesman <PERSON> Joaquin </PERSON> <PERSON> Navarro </PERSON> said large <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> communities exist in the <LOCATION> Ukraine </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Byelorussia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Kazakhstan </LOCATION>. Those republics have no fully recognized <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> churches, and the <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION> wants the right to appoint bishops there, <PERSON> Navarro </PERSON> said. Pravda's report of <PERSON> Willebrands </PERSON>' question, taken from a <ORGANIZATION> Tass </ORGANIZATION> dispatch, omitted the cardinal's specific references to the <LOCATION> Ukraine </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Byelorussia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Kazakhstan </LOCATION>, reflecting the <ORGANIZATION> Kremlin </ORGANIZATION>'s sensitivity on the issue <PERSON> Gromyko </PERSON> said <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> churches could be opened outside the <LOCATION> Baltic </LOCATION> states if local authorities agree. `` In the future, we will give the necessary attention to the wishes of Soviet Catholics regardless of where they live,'' the 78-year-old president was quoted as saying. <PERSON> Willebrands </PERSON> met Friday with clergy of the underground Ukrainian <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION>, which <PERSON> Josef </PERSON> <PERSON> V. </PERSON> <PERSON> Stalin </PERSON> ordered absorbed into the Russian Orthodox Church in 1946. Ukrainian clerics say there are 3 million to 4 million Ukrainian Catholics in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. Pope <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> II </PERSON> said in a letter in April to Ukrainian Catholics that their church should be fully recognized. The state-supported Russian Orthodox Church bitterly opposes recognition of the Ukrainian <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION>, claiming it was formed only as a result of a forced split in the <ORGANIZATION> Orthodox </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> at the end of the 16th century. The issue was discussed June 7-9 at an unofficial seminar on religious problems in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. Over the weekend, religious activists released a resolution they adopted at the meeting that called for the Russian Orthodox Church to legalize the Ukrainian church and other underground churches. The leader of the <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION> delegation in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>, Cardinal <PERSON> Agostino </PERSON> <PERSON> Casaroli </PERSON>, met Sunday with <PERSON> Konstantin </PERSON> <PERSON> Kharchev </PERSON>, head of the government's Council for Religious Affairs. <PERSON> Navarro </PERSON> said they discussed `` different questions regarding the relations between the Catholic church and Soviet government,'' but he would not give details of the talk.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880612-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-12-88 1152EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-BRF--MozambiqueRebels     06-12 0139</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Mozambique Rebels,0140</SECOND>
<HEAD>Report: Mozambique Rebels Kill Two Zimbabwe Villagers</HEAD>
<DATELINE>HARARE, Zimbabwe (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Mozambican rebels shot and killed a mother and her son in a remote village in northeastern <LOCATION> Zimbabwe </LOCATION>, a newspaper said Sunday. The attack was the second cross-border raid by <ORGANIZATION> Mozambique </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Resistance </ORGANIZATION> geurrillas into <LOCATION> Zimbabwe </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Mount </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Darwin </LOCATION> area in four weeks, said the Sunday Mail, which is published in <LOCATION> Harare </LOCATION> by the state-owned Mass Media Trust. It said the incident happened several days ago and was confirmed by <LOCATION> Harare </LOCATION> police Saturday. Police identified the dead as <PERSON> Mativenga </PERSON> <PERSON> Nyarugwe </PERSON> and her 4-year-old son, <PERSON> Karorado </PERSON>. The right-wing <ORGANIZATION> Mozambique </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Resistance </ORGANIZATION>, also known by its Portuguese acronym <ORGANIZATION> RENAMO </ORGANIZATION>, has been fighting since 1977 to topple <LOCATION> Mozambique </LOCATION>'s Marxist government. <ORGANIZATION> RENAMO </ORGANIZATION> rebels have have mounted numerous raids into <LOCATION> Zimbabwe </LOCATION> during the past year, mainly to steal food and supplies.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880612-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-12-88 1159EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-SouthKorea Bjt   06-12 0648</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-South Korea, Bjt,0668</SECOND>
<HEAD>Radical Students Battle Riot Police During Funeral March</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhotos SEL2,4,8</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BARRY RENFREW</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SEOUL, South Korea (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Waves of students yelling `` Revolution!'' and hurling firebombs tried to storm the headquarters of the governing party Sunday during a funeral march for a radical who committed ritual suicide. Thousands of riot police firing volleys of tear gas fought off attacking students and pursued them in running clashes through the center of <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION>. Protesters showered police with exploding firebombs that covered streets with blazing gasoline. Hundreds of people out for walks choked and cried with pain when they were caught in clouds of stinging tear gas. `` Down with the military fascists!'' and `` Revolution of the masses!'' the radicals screamed as they broke up sidewalk paving stones to hurl at police. The violence began when 10,000 students and sympathizers marched through the city with the coffin of <PERSON> Park </PERSON> <PERSON> Rae-chun </PERSON>, who died June 6 after setting himself on fire. It was the third protest suicide by radical students since May 15. Marchers armed with firebombs, rocks and clubs tried to attack the headquarters of the governing <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> during the march but were blocked by riot police in combat fatigues and black helmets. Protesters set fire to a police truck with firebombs and damaged the information office of the Japanese Embassy with rocks. A number of police and students were hurt and some protesters were arrested, but no figures were available. Police reported the first death from the unrest. A riot trooper died Sunday after being injured in fighting the day before in the central city of <LOCATION> Taejon </LOCATION>. The wave of student protests is the nation's worst political violence since anti-government riots in June 1987. But unlike last summer, where pro-democracy demonstrators enjoyed wide support from the masses, the radical students demonstrating now represent a small minority. Most South Koreans do not support their demands for reunification of communist <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> with the pro-Western South and the withdrawal from the South of 42,000 <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> troops. Marchers shouted `` Yankee go home!'' on Sunday, but the protest was less anti-American than other recent demonstrations. Marchers yelled slogans as they passed the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Information </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> building, but there were no incidents beyond one man hurling a soft-drink can. Students wore red headbands with anti-government slogans and beat drums and gongs as they marched through the city. The coffin, covered in yellow flowers, was carried by bearers in traditional white mourning clothes. The dead student belonged to a faction seeking creation of a revolutionary government. Marchers began arming themselves with firebombs from a truck loaded with the weapons as the procession continued after a rally in front of City Hall. Students wielding clubs, rocks and firebombs went to <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> headquarters where riot police blocked the street. They attacked police, who fired volleys of tear gas. Armored vans with multiple tear gas launchers blasted protesters. Hundreds of riot police waiting in sidestreets poured out and quickly routed the attackers. Students at one point seized a highway overpass, but special police martial arts squads hurling tear gas grenades attacked and dispersed them. The protest was aimed mainly at the government of President <PERSON> Roh </PERSON> Tae-woo. Radical leaders denounced the government as a dictatorship and called for creation of a peoples' republic. `` We are here to fight for liberation of the masses,'' said one leader. The radical students have rejected democratic reforms made by the <PERSON> Roh </PERSON> government in recent months, insisting the government is a front for dictatorial military rule. They say the presence of the American troops, stationed here under a mutual defense pact, encourages military rule. Some people watching the march expressed bewilderment and anger. An elderly man, who yelled that students were not patriots, tried to attack marchers. `` Why do these young people do this? What does it say about our country,'' one middle-aged man said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880612-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-12-88 1200EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-ErrantSpear     06-12 0163</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Errant Spear,0167</SECOND>
<HEAD>Man Hurls Spear At Bandits, Kills Wife</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NAIROBI, Kenya (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A farmer lying in wait for a gang of robbers hurled a spear from his hideout and accidentally killed one of his two wives, police said Sunday. <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Sikuku </PERSON> heard noises from where he hid outside his village of <LOCATION> Indangalaisa </LOCATION> on Friday night, thought it was a gang that had robbed his neighbors and tossed the spear, police said. His wife, <PERSON> Paustsina </PERSON> <PERSON> Nambutie </PERSON>, was hidden in some bushes nearby and was fatally wounded. Police said they were hunting the eight-man gang that had robbed four families in the village early that evening. <PERSON> Sikuku </PERSON>, fearing he might become a victim of the gang, woke his two wives and their children and told them to hide in a nearby cornfield, police said. He took cover armed with a spear. He realized he had killed his wife when he left his hideout to inspect the body of his victim, police said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880612-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-12-88 1200EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM--Soviet-ShipFire     06-12 0158</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM--Soviet-Ship Fire,0160</SECOND>
<HEAD>Soviet Probe Says Ship Fire Caused by Electric Heaters</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MOSCOW (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
