<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880417-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-17-88 2344EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-ComputerIntruder     04-17 0362</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Computer Intruder,0372</SECOND>
<HEAD>Report: West German Tapped Into U.S. Military Computers</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 For nearly two years, a West German citizen gained access to more than 30 computers belonging to the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military and military contractors, according to a published report. The <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> reported in Monday's editions that the West German searched for data related to nuclear weapons, intelligence satellites, the Strat = e Initiative, the space shuttle and the <ORGANIZATION> North </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> The Times, quoting computer security experts, said he did not gain access to any classified information or break into a `` secure'' government computer where classified information is stored. An <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> spokesman confirmed Sunday that the matter was under investigation. A West German magazine, Quick, detailed the case last week and identified the intruder as <PERSON> Mathias </PERSON> <PERSON> Speer </PERSON>, 24, a computer science student in <LOCATION> Hanover </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> would not confirm his identity, the Times said. The electronic break-ins may have gone on for a year before being discovered in August 1986, the newspaper said. They were monitored for a year and traced, the Times said, and in June 1987, the West German and an American who may have been an accomplice apparently were questioned by authorities. The break-ins stopped about the same time. `` This kind of penetration could clearly have been used for espionage,'' <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Neumann </PERSON>, a computer security expert familiar with the case, told the <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION>. `` I think most of the attacks before this have been relatively benign on a global scale. This one is much more insidious.'' Computer managers at the <ORGANIZATION> Lawrence </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Berkeley </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Laboratory </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Berkeley </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, which is involved in broad-based unclassified scientific research, discovered the intrusions, the Times said. The laboratory and its sister institution, the <ORGANIZATION> Lawrence </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Livermore </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Laboratory </ORGANIZATION>, which is involved nuclear weapons research and SDI, are operated by the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION> for the federal government. The break-ins involved a variety of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military computer systems in this country, <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, the Times said, including systems at the <ORGANIZATION> Naval </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coastal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Systems </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Command </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Systems </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Command </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Segundo </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Optimus </ORGANIZATION> data base and <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION>'s Jet Propulsion Laboratory in <LOCATION> Pasadena </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880417-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-17-88 2343EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-HelicopterCrash 1stLd-Writethru a0847 04-17 0310</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Helicopter Crash, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0847,0317</SECOND>
<HEAD>Rescuers Killed While Patient Survives</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: SUBS grafs 5-6 ``The pilot'' to UPDATE with names of victims
and age of survivor. Picks up 7th graf pvs ``There were...''</NOTE>
<DATELINE>DEVORE, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A medical evacuation xwzaking an injured motorcyclist to a hospital crashed Sunday in a fog-shrouded mountain pass, killing the pilot and a nurse, authorities said. The patient, the only other person aboard, survived, perhaps because he was strapped down in the aircraft's midsection, said county fire Capt. <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Andreas </PERSON>. The helicopter hit a power line in <LOCATION> Cajon </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Pass </LOCATION> in the <LOCATION> Lost </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> area of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bernardino </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, 60 miles northeast of <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Andreas </PERSON> said. `` When the craft came down, it hit a rock wall and went over an embankment,'' <PERSON> Andreas </PERSON> said. The pilot and nurr = wzified as <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Skala </PERSON>, 40, of <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Alamitos </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Cheryl </PERSON> <PERSON> Collins </PERSON>, 40, of <LOCATION> Hesperia </LOCATION>, sheriff's Deputy <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Cook </PERSON> They were dead when rescuers arrived. The injured motorcyclist, a 26-year-old man whose name was withheld until relatives could be contacted, was flown to <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bernardino </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> Medical Center, where he was listed in critical condition, said a nursing supervisor who would n't give her name. `` There were heavy clouds, fog and generally very bad weather in the pass,'' <PERSON> Andreas </PERSON> said. The helicopter apparently was trying to turn around to avoid the fog when it crashed, said county sheriff's Lt. <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Stodelle </PERSON>. The motorcyclist had suffered head and neck injuries in a crash in the <LOCATION> Mojave </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Desert </LOCATION> near Interstate 15 north of <LOCATION> Victorville </LOCATION>. Although <PERSON> Andreas </PERSON> said he had been strapped in, authorities found him `` sitting in a patch of sand in a creek bed'' near the downed craft, <PERSON> Stodelle </PERSON> said. `` He was alive, awake and incoherent,'' <PERSON> Stodelle </PERSON> said. The helicopter was owned by <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transport </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Riverside </ORGANIZATION>, where a spokesman said no information was available.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880417-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-17-88 2347EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Rape-Videotape     04-17 0337</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Rape-Videotape,0351</SECOND>
<HEAD>Apology, Videotape Wins Child Rapist Probation</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BIRMINGHAM, Ala. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A firefighter who pleaded guilty to raping a young girl has agreed to make of videotape of his confession in order to warn parents that respectable people can be child abusers, officials said. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Roper </PERSON> was given probation after he agreed to make the tape and to apologize for saying he had been falsely accused. `` <PERSON> Roper </PERSON> represents a typical child molester that is so difficult to convict,'' Deputy District Attorney <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> McGregor </PERSON> said. `` He's nice looking, had a good job, had children of his own, well-thought of in the community. People want to believe that the only ones who molest children are the dirty-old men in raincoats.'' <PERSON> Roper </PERSON> pleaded guilty to first-degree rape. He was charged last year with first-degree rape and first-degree sexual assault in a case involving an 11-year-old girl. Circuit Judge <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Jasper </PERSON>, who had sentenced <PERSON> Roper </PERSON> to 15 years in prison, earlier this month granted him probation. The sexual abuse charge was dropped as part of the plea bargain. <PERSON> Roper </PERSON> must make the apology tonight to his former co-workers at a fire house in suburban <PERSON> Hoover </PERSON> for saying the victim's mother fabricated the story. The videotape must be made at his expense by July and will be used by <ORGANIZATION> Prescott </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, a center for child abuse victims, to educate the public about child sex abuse. The victim's mother said her agreement to probation was based on concern about her child having to testify in a trial and her belief that the videotape would help other children. `` All children in <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION> would benefit,'' she said. Defense attorney <PERSON> Doug </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> called the case a breakthrough. `` The ultimate outcome offers a significant way to help the community with regard to these cases,'' <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> said. `` We gave up some things. They gave up some things.'' <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> said <PERSON> Roper </PERSON>, who resigned as a firefighter, already has been punished. The probation agreement requires <PERSON> Roper </PERSON> to seek psychiatric help, which <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> said <PERSON> Roper </PERSON> began receiving last year.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880417-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-17-88 2354EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-InvisiblePrimary Bjt   04-17 0771</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Invisible Primary, Bjt,760</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHINGTON WIRE: Without a Vote Cast, Dukakis Adds 105 Delegates</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP News Analysis</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JONATHAN WOLMAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 On the one hand, <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> has won all of two elections in a row and on a good day he draws maybe half the crowd and a quarter of the enthusiasm of <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>. On the other hand, over the past 12 days <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> won an invisible primary the size of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> and quietly boosted his claim on the Democratic presidential nomination. In the hiatus between <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION>'s primary almost two weeks ago and Tuesday's voting in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> picked up pledges from 105 national convention delegates, and he won another 22 in Saturday's <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION> caucuses. `` He's being called ` <ORGANIZATION> El </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nuevo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Kennedy </ORGANIZATION>' in the barrios around <LOCATION> Phoenix </LOCATION>,'' the governor's Western coordinator, <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Ybarra </PERSON>, enthused after <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> defeated <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> and shut out Sen. <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION>. All told, the <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> governor stretched his delegate margin from a measly 36 to a more substantial 134. Where did all these delegates come from? Half came from <LOCATION> Puerto </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rico </LOCATION>, where Gov. <PERSON> Rafael </PERSON> <PERSON> Hernandez-Colon </PERSON> delivered his blessing and 52 previously uncommitted delegates. But the 53 other pledges may prove more significant, for they may signify the first rumblings of an establishment bandwagon. They came from among the so-called super delegates, Democratic party leaders and officeholders who are beholden to no one and free to vote their consciences _ or to sniff the political winds. The nomination of <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> seems all but inevitable _ except when you consider that he faces a stiff test from <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> on Tuesday in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> and his 872-delegate total remains far below the 2,082 needed to win nomination in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>. `` The popular wisdom is that <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> has been a front-runner from the beginning in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> ... -LRB- but -RRB- I said 10 weeks ago that you should not take the polls too seriously and that <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> could win,'' Gov. <PERSON> Mario </PERSON> <PERSON> Cuomo </PERSON> says of the Dukakis-Jackson battle. `` I do n't think anything has changed since then. <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> is the wild card. If he does well, it could hurt <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>. `` I do n't think there's any doubt that he -LRB- <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> -RRB- is stronger now than he was a couple of weeks ago,'' <PERSON> Cuomo </PERSON> said Sunday. `` <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> is doing well because he draws crowds, they're enthusiastic and that may be the very best barometer of all.'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, concerned that his ethnic support may be soft and his backers must be motivated to vote, had some influential surrogates campaigning in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> on Sunday. He brought in one of the not-so-nuevo <PERSON> Kennedys </PERSON>, Sen. <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION>, for a bring-out-the-vote effort and after marching in a `` Salute to <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'' parade, he attended a Gaelic football game and a reception with Gov. <PERSON> Hernandez-Colon </PERSON>. <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> was touring Hispanic, Italian and <PERSON> Jewish </PERSON> neighborhoods while <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> met with community leaders in a session set up by one of his most prominent Jewish supporters. Yet for all the attention, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> is not the only election being held Tuesday _ congressional Democrats will caucus Tuesday and Wednesday to choose their super delegates to the <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> convention. Most members were `` nominated'' in closed-door party meetings last week and <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> did very well on both sides of the Capitol, even in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>, which is home to two of his remaining rivals. Most <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> delegates remain uncommitted, but nine are lined up with <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>. <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> picked up just four pledges from his colleagues, as well as his own, and Sen. <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> _ who doggedly maintains a one-state strategy _ had two pledges, his own and that of fellow <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> Sen. <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Dixon </PERSON>. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> won no pledges from the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> but fared better in the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, where 142 member-delegates are still uncommitted. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> has pledges from 26, <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> 15, <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> 12 and <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> 10 -LRB- most of them from <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> -RRB-. These super delegate pledges provide timely assistance for <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> because while he's favored to win <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, has there ever been a more invisible front-runner? The crowds drawn to <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, and the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> mayor _ <PERSON> Ed </PERSON> <PERSON> Koch </PERSON> _ drawn to <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> practically drove <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> off the local newscasts, except when he was under attack by the <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> senator. Delegate counters for the <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> governor do not expect anyone, no matter who wins, to pick up more than 150 of the 255 delegates at stake in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>. But that's a lot of delegates in the splintered <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> environment _ it would put <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> almost halfway to a nominating majority.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Jonathan </PERSON> <PERSON> Wolman </PERSON> is <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION>'s assistant bureau chief in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880417-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-17-88 2356EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Bush-Robertson     04-17 0662</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bush-Robertson,650</SECOND>
<HEAD>Robertson No Longer Contender For Nomination, But Still Holds Some
Cards</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TOM RAUM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Former television evangelist <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> insists he's not one for `` tilting at windmills,'' but his refusal to lay down his lance formally is posing a few tactical problems for Vice President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. For one thing, it may be helping to keep President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> on the sidelines, even though <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON>'s campaign poses no real obstacle to <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s march to the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> nomination. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> vowed to remain neutral in the contest so long as there was a battle among Republicans, even though his active support for <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was a foregone conclusion. After <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s main competitor, Sen. <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION>, dropped out, the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> hinted that <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> wanted to start stumping for <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. But so far he has n't scheduled any appearances. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has 922 delegates and after the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> primary on Tuesday may have as many as 970 _ within easy grasp of the 1,039 needed for the Republican nomination. By contrast, <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> has a scant 17 delegates. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> is still behaving as if he has some competition for the nomination. He campaigned last week in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, and today begins an <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> swing in anticipation of primaries in those states in the next two weeks. <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON>'s vow to `` energize people who support me'' on issues also raises the possibility of a platform battle at the GOP convention, one <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> strategists would like to avoid. For his part, <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> has made no effort to contact <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> or to try to mend fences, according to the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> camp. `` I think he's plowed under,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said in a recent conversation with reporters on Air Force II. Asked if some prominent Republican, perhaps <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>, might serve as a mediator between the two camps, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said: `` We do n't need any mediation. We need our facts clear.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> still has not spoken to <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON>, even though the two were back-to-back speakers last Friday before the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Newspaper </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Editors </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> still appears to be smarting at the drubbing he received from <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, insisting to the newspaper executives on Friday that there were `` no differences in either education or income level'' of those supporting him and those supporting <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. The major difference, <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> suggested, is that `` <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was regarded as <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> the Second, or whatever, so they were voting again for the man who they have voted for twice before _ Reagan-Bush. I do n't think anybody could have done much better.'' `` I'm not <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Quixote </PERSON>. I do n't believe in tilting at windmills. It's obvious from the delegate count that has come out that <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> is going to be the nominee ...'' But still, <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> remains the only candidate of the original five Republicans challenging <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> for the nomination to persist in the face of the vice president's steamrolling candidacy. <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>, former <LOCATION> Delaware </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Pete </PERSON> <PERSON> du </PERSON> <PERSON> Pont </PERSON>, former Secretary of State <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON> <PERSON> Haig </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> and Rep. <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> have all formally withdrawn, releasing their delegates in the process. Suggestions that <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> feels he has been unfairly treated in the process `` are absurd,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has said. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> spokesman <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Teeley </PERSON> said no efforts have been made by <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> or his advisers to try to persuade <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> to bow out gracefully. `` It would not be proper,'' <PERSON> Teeley </PERSON> said. However, the aide said, `` His campaign for the most part is dormant. He's doing very little traveling. It's almost as if his campaign is nonexistent.'' <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON>'s campaign has acknowledged he has spent nearly all the money allowed for the primary season under federal spending limits. He has laid off most of his staff and confined his campaigning to an occasional trip. As for <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s non-participation, <PERSON> Teeley </PERSON> suggested that might change `` once we have the delegates to go over the top.'' According to an Associated Press delegate count, that will come no later than May 3 _ possibly even sooner -RCB-; klZkl -LRB- C
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880417-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-17-88 2356EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-DelawareDemocrats     04-17 0419</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Delaware Democrats,400</SECOND>
<HEAD>Jackson Backers Expected To Turn Out In Force For Delaware
Caucuses</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By THERESA HUMPHREY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>DOVER, Del. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Turnout at tonight's Democratic presidential caucuses in <LOCATION> Delaware </LOCATION> is expected to hit a record high due to an organizing drive by backers of <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, the state's party chief said. At the 41 caucuses, held by state representative district, 189 delegates will be chosen to the state convention May 23. There, the party will choose 15 of its 19 delegates to the Democratic national convention. Four of the delegate slots automatically go to the state chairman, vice chairwoman, the national committeeman and national committeewoman. <PERSON> Samuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Shipley </PERSON>, state party chairman, said normal caucus turnout is about 2 percent of the state's 135,000 registered Democrats. This year, though, he predicts a 3 percent or 4 percent turnout _ which would be a record _ due to a big push by <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s backers. `` The <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> people are very organized and have been for three or four months. They've had a major presence on a local level,'' <PERSON> Shipley </PERSON> said. `` We have an inspiring and fervent and committed group of people who think this is going to be a <LOCATION> Jackson </LOCATION> state,'' said <PERSON> Vivian </PERSON> <PERSON> Houghton </PERSON>, the <LOCATION> Delaware </LOCATION> co-coordinator for <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>. Those attending the caucuses will split into groups based on their preference for president, including those uncommitted. Any candidate, including uncommitteds, who gets at least 15 percent of the vote will be awarded delegates to the state convention. Ms. <PERSON> Houghton </PERSON> said the <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> campaign has been active in <LOCATION> Delaware </LOCATION> since September. She said she expects the predominantly black 2nd and 3rd representative districts in <LOCATION> Wilmington </LOCATION> to go to <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, but she also predicted he om_Oo @ ghout the state. Organizers for <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> have been in the state for about a month. <PERSON> Cynthia </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Drucker </PERSON>, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' state director, saiw ~ @ rces caused a late start, but was upbeat about her candidate's prospects `` We have a good organization in place. We're going district by district to get the message out to <LOCATION> Delaware </LOCATION> Democrats. It's a message of a candidate that can beat <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> in November,'' she said. Sen. <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> has no organization in <LOCATION> Delaware </LOCATION>. The Republicans have been holding caucuses since April 5. On April 25, they will select delegates to the party's state convention May 14. The <LOCATION> Delaware </LOCATION> GOP had campaigned for former Gov. <PERSON> Pete </PERSON> <PERSON> du </PERSON> <PERSON> Pont </PERSON> while the state's Democrats threw their support behind Sen. <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Biden </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr </PERSON>. Both home-state candidates subsequently dropped out of their respective races.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880417-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-17-88 2358EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-HospitalOvercharges Bjt   04-17 0691</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Hospital Overcharges, Bjt,680</SECOND>
<HEAD>Study: Hospitals Made $2 Billion on Unneeded Stays</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JERRY ESTILL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Federal investigators havr evidence suggesting the nation's hospitals are making billions of dollars extra by admitting patients who could be treated better and cheaper without hospitalization. A draft report prepared by the inspector general's office of the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Human </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> concludes that hospitals probably were paid about $ 2 billion by <ORGANIZATION> Medicare </ORGANIZATION> in 1985 to treat patients who should not have been hospitalized in the first place. `` Although an estimated $ 939 million would have been spent providing care to these patients in other medical settings, reducing unnecessary admissions to hospitals is one of the most effective ways of saving Medicare dollars,'' says the report, a copy of which was obtained by The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>. The analysis was based on 7,050 patient records at 214 randomly selected hospitals from October 1984 to March 1985. It concluded that 740 admissions, or 10.5 percent, were unnecessary. There is potential financial incentive to admit patients who do not need hospitalization under a plan established by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> in 1983 which sets a fixed payment for each of 475 diagnosis related groups _ or DRGs, as they are known in the industry. A hospital receives the same payment for each admission for a particular diagnosis regardless of the actual services provided or length of time a patient spends in the hospital. `` Hospitals retain a profit when patient care costs less than the DRG payment, but must absorb losses when costs are higher than the DRG,'' the report noted. Against that background, the study found that the average length of stay for the unnecessary admissions was 4.4 days, compared with 7.6 days for necessary admissions. `` Most of the unnecessary admissions needed medical attention, but not in an acute care setting,'' the report said. It placed nearly 78 percent in that category, but concluded that almost 12 percent of the patients did not require immediate treatment of any kind when they were admitted. Most of the other medically unnecessary admissions were classed as either `` social admissions,'' such as temporarily hospitalizing an elderly person because he or she did not have any other place to stay, or instances of frail people being hospitalized when they should have been admitted to a nursing home instead. Only 25 of the 214 hospitals studies had no unnecessary admissions, according to the report, but there was wide variation in the rates of unnec? admissions for the others. For example, at least half the admissions were judged unnecessary at two hospitals and at least a third at eight other institutions. Twenty percent or more of the sampled admissions at 34 hospitals were found unnecessary. No individual hospitals were named in the study. Neither were any variations among states or regions of the country detailed. The overall 10.5 percent unnecessary admissions rate for the cases sampled is far higher than the maximum 2.5 percent unnecessary admission rate reported to the <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Care </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Financing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> by any of the state peer review organizations the federal agency pays to police hospitals. One of the major recommendations in the report is that the <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Care </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Financing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>, which oversees <ORGANIZATION> Medicare </ORGANIZATION> and Medicaid, determine why those peer review organizations identify a substantially lower rate of unnecessary admissions than the inspector general's survey found, and require them to adopt more effective screening techniques. The inspector general's report found the unnecessary admissions tended to be concentrated in five diagnostic groups: back problems, diabetes, bone cancer, digestive disorders and upper respiratory tract infections. The study methodology involved selecting hospitals at random to reflect the overall numbers of small, medium and large hospitals. Registered nurses were hired to screen records using objective screening techniques approved by the <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Care </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Financing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>. If a case looked suspect, it was referred to a physician for review. `` Reviewers ignored marginal problems or cases involving honest differences in medical judgment about appropriate case management,'' the report said. Moreover, if documentation in the record was so poor reviewers could not make a determination, it was given the benefit of doubt and considered a necessary admission.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880417-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-17-88 2358EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Dukakis     04-17 0513</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Dukakis,500</SECOND>
<HEAD>Dukakis Makes Ethnic Rounds in New York</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By WILLIAM M. WELCH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 From Hispanic and Irish wards of the <LOCATION> Bronx </LOCATION> to Jewish crowds in <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION>, Democrat <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> has reveled in this city's ethnic diversity while urging supporters not to be overconfident in Tuesday's crucial <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> primary. After a Sunday of campaigning across <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> under a brilliant spring sky, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> was skipping around the state today to deliver final arguments that he would make the strongest Democratic presidential nominee. As he did, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' organization was concluding two weeks of telephone calls to a half-million likely Democratic voters in a targeted effort to remind them to turn out when the voting begins Tuesday. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' aides were trying to spread their view of the race with <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> and Sen. <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> as tightening, although a late poll by <ORGANIZATION> Cable </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Network-USA </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Today </ORGANIZATION> put <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> ahead by 12 points. `` I never talk about polls because I do n't pay any attention to them. I did once and will never do it again,'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> said, a reference to the re-election defeat he suffered after his first term as governor of <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION>. On Saturday, standing in a blustery cold in front of chunks of ice floating on <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Erie </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Buffalo </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> offered a reminder of his crushing loss in <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION>'s caucuses, a 2-1 defeat that had not been predicted. `` What is important is that they vote,'' he said. `` I've been ahead in the polls before, in my own state, and I was way ahead in <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION>, and we all know what happened there.'' His <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> campaign director, <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Bograd </PERSON>, said volunteers had been working 500 to 600 phones a night calling voters in precincts where demographic indicators suggest <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> should be strong. After meeting his rivals in their last debate of the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> campaign Sunday morning, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> walked 25 blocks up 5th Avenue where he drew warm cheers from thousands of people who lined the streets for the city's parade honoring <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s 40th anniversary. He followed, out of sight of Mayor <PERSON> Ed </PERSON> <PERSON> Koch </PERSON> and <PERSON> Gore </PERSON>, who walked together. At Gaelic Park in the <LOCATION> Bronx </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> threw a ball during halftime of an Irish football game _ a rough sport that has elements of soccer and rugby. He moved into a dance hall at the park as a band and female singer shifted smoothly from a <PERSON> Patsy </PERSON> <PERSON> Cline </PERSON> country-blues medley to the Irish tune, `` Take Me Home To Mayo,'' and <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> and his wife <PERSON> Kitty </PERSON> waltzed for the cameras. Shifting to a Latin beat, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> traveled to another <LOCATION> Bronx </LOCATION> neighborhood where a band played rhythmically with conga drums and other instruments and the 200 people danced and sang, `` <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Du-ka-key </PERSON>, pres-i-dent-e.'' With him was Puerto Rico Gov <PERSON> Rafael </PERSON> <PERSON> Hernandez-Colon </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Puerto </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rico </LOCATION>, and each spoke in Spanish to the predominantly Hispanic audience inside the <LOCATION> Club </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Cubano </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Americano </LOCATION>, where pink paint peeled from the walls and stairwell windows were broken out. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> `` talks our own language,'' the Puerto Rican governor told them, using Spanish.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880417-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-17-88 0005EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-StudentPrank     04-17 0216</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Student Prank,0221</SECOND>
<HEAD>Principal Cries Foul Over Student Prank During Opera</HEAD>
<DATELINE>FAIRVIEW PARK, Ohio (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The assistant principal thought it a deed most foul when student pranksters released 25 clucking chickens in a school auditorium while a theater troupe recited <PERSON> Shakespeare </PERSON>. Twelve <ORGANIZATION> Fairview </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> High </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> students received 10-day suspensions for the prank Friday during the performance of `` Shakespeare on Broadway'' and `` West Side Story'' by the Cleveland Opera On Tour. `` They may feel it was a prank, but we do not consider it humorous,'' said Assistant Principal <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Kulik </PERSON>. `` It disturbed a very fine program and was not in good taste. To think the students would let loose live chickens ... it's a very embarrassing thing.'' The performers did n't realize what was happening until <PERSON> Kulik </PERSON> interrupted to apologize to the troupe and dress down the seniors. <PERSON> Betsy </PERSON> <PERSON> Clark </PERSON>, an assistant in the opera's tour department, said she did n't believe the chickens had ruined the performance. `` They -LRB- opera singers -RRB- did well under the pretty bad circumstances,'' she said. `` I saw different teachers trying to catch the chickens. One teacher caught one and headed out the door with it; the kids started giggling and clapping, and the performers could n't figure out why they were laughing and applauding right in the middle of a serious Shakespeare dialogue.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880417-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-17-88 0019EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Ireland-Prisons     04-17 0235</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Ireland-Prisons,0241</SECOND>
<HEAD>Irish Prison Guards Strike</HEAD>
<DATELINE>DUBLIN, Ireland (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 All 1,900 guards in the Republic of <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION>'s 11 prisons went on strike Saturday following the breakdown of talks with officials of Prime Minister <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Haughey </PERSON>'s government. The government said it would use 1,000 police officers, about a tenth of the nation's police force, and about 300 soldiers to staff the prisons. The prisons hold about 2,000 inmates. It is the first national walkout by prison guards in the nation's history. The prison guards' union, the <ORGANIZATION> Irish </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Prison </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Officers </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ' </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, said in a statement the strike is a protest against the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION>'s decision to impose new shift arrangements without consulting the guards The union also says it wants money used to pay for guard overtime to be used to hire more prison staff. But the department said the cause of the dispute is the guards' demand for compensation for overtime payments lost last year when extra staff was hired The department said the extra staff was added partly to meet union complaints about staff shortages. The strike comes amid reports of unrest in some prisons. Four prisoners at the high-security <LOCATION> Portlaoise </LOCATION>, 47 miles southwest of <LOCATION> Dublin </LOCATION>, were reported to have smashed up their cells to protest conditions. About 130 of the 200 prisoners at the <LOCATION> Portlaoise </LOCATION> prison are convicted guerrillas of the outlawed <ORGANIZATION> Irish </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Irish </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880417-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-17-88 0007EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Nicaragua 2ndLd-Writethru a0692 04-17 0676</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Nicaragua, 2nd Ld-Writethru, a0692,0698</SECOND>
<HEAD>Contras, Sandinistas Far Apart On Key Truce Issue</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: INSERTS 3 grafs after 4th graf pvs, `Neither side ...' to
UPDATE with demo at U.S. Embassy, details; pickup 5th pvs, `The
delegations ...</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By JUAN MALTES</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MANAGUA, Nicaragua (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Government and rebel negotiators met Saturday in search of ways to achieve peace, but the two sides remained far apart on the key issue of a permanent truce. After day-long talks they agreed to resume negotiations Sunday. <PERSON> Bosco </PERSON> <PERSON> Matamoros </PERSON>, a spokesman for the rebels, said the discussions had been frank, and Deputy Foreign Minister <PERSON> Victor </PERSON> <PERSON> Tinoco </PERSON> called the meeting `` a productive day where we advanced quite a bit.'' Neither side gave details of the talks. More than 1,000 people gathered in front of the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Embassy to protest the <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> support for the rebels known as Contras and demand that their leaders sign a cease-fire during the discussions. The demonstrators carried signs saying, `` Cease North American Support of the Contras.'' No incidents were reported. The delegations met briefly Friday night, then gathered again at the negotiating table at 9 a.m. -LRB- 11 a.m. EDT -RRB- Saturday behind closed doors and recessed at 7 p.m. The rebels are demanding the Sandinista government take the first steps toward returning <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> to freely elected democratic rule before they sign an armisice. `` If we sign a permanent cease-fire without first taking steps to lead -LRB- the country back -RRB- to democracy, it would be tantamount to surrender on our part,'' <PERSON> Adolfo </PERSON> <PERSON> Calero </PERSON>, the top Contra negotiator, told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> in a telephone interview shortly before the start of Saturday's session. Gen. <PERSON> Humberto </PERSON> <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON>, the Sandinista defense minister and head of the government delegation, said Friday the <ORGANIZATION> Sandinistas </ORGANIZATION> believe an agreement on a permanent truce comes first. `` The victory we should seek is a permanent cease-fire,'' <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON> told reporters. But both sides expressed optimism they could reach agreement. `` We came here with faith and goodwill and we hope to find the same goodwill on the other side to reach agreement that will benefit all Nicaraguans,'' <PERSON> Calero </PERSON> said. He added, however: `` We have reservations to return to <LOCATION> Costa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rica </LOCATION> on Monday afternoon. If the negotiations are on the right track, then we could prolong our stay.'' This is the first time the <ORGANIZATION> Sandinistas </ORGANIZATION> have allowed Contra leaders to come to <LOCATION> Managua </LOCATION> since the revolt began in November 1981. President <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON> has said 26,500 people have been slain in the conflict. A 60-day cease-fire has been in effect since April 1 and continued to be holding on Saturday. Even though each side has accused the other of violating the cease-fire, incidents have been few and minor. The Contra umbrella organization known as Nicaraguan Resistance said in a brief statement Saturday that Sandinista helicopter gunships have been violating the cease-fire by trying to chart rebel troop movements. It also said <PERSON> Sandinista </PERSON> `` agents'' have been trying to contact rebel commanders to discuss peace. The statement issued in <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION>, where the Contras have their headquarters, added: `` Consequently we are instructing our combatants to reject any contact with these elements, the majority of whom belong to the State Security forces, or to capture them.'' Delegates signed the 60-day cease-fire on March 23 after three days of negotiations in the tiny border post of <LOCATION> Sapoa </LOCATION>, 90 miles south of <LOCATION> Managua </LOCATION>. Agreement on the technical aspects of the cease-fire was reached during talks that ended Friday at <LOCATION> Sapoa </LOCATION>, and the two sides agreed to further technical talks at this week's high-level meetings in <LOCATION> Managua </LOCATION>. The sides have agreed on seven cease-fire zones where the rebels would gather during the temporary cease-fire until a permanent truce is negotiated. But the logistics of moving into those zones, whether the Contras would give up their weapons, and how they would be resupplied have kept the sides apart. Although details of Friday's talks were not released, a joint communique said the delegations had made `` substantial progress.'' The Soviet-supported <ORGANIZATION> Sandinistas </ORGANIZATION> have been in power since defeating the right-wing government of the late President <PERSON> Anastasio </PERSON> <PERSON> Somoza </PERSON> in 1979.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880417-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-17-88 0017EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p AM-ArizonaDemocrats 1stLd-Writethru a0555 04-17 0604</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Arizona Democrats, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0555,570</SECOND>
<HEAD>Arizona Democrats to Begin Delegate-Selection Process</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDs: TOPS with early returns; PICKS UP 8th graf pvs bgng, `Jackson
is;' Stands for AMs</NOTE>
<HEAD>With AM-Political Rdp Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LAURIE ASSEO</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PHOENIX, Ariz. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 First results from rural counties gave <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> a strong early lead over <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION>'s Democratic presidential caucus Saturday. In <LOCATION> La </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Paz </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> in southwestern <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> had 66 votes compared with 21 for <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>. Tennessee Sen. <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> got 18 votes while <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> Sen. <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Simon </PERSON>, who has suspended his candidacy, got four votes and political extremist <PERSON> Lyndon </PERSON> <PERSON> LaRouche </PERSON> had one vote. Three voters expressed no preference. In <LOCATION> Greenlee </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> in eastern <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> had 144 votes compared with 27 for <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, 13 for <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> and three each for <PERSON> Simon </PERSON>, <PERSON> LaRouche </PERSON> and no preference. `` We expected to win <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION>,'' said <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Ybarra </PERSON>, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' director for western states `` If we do, if the preliminary numbers hold up, it will be a continuation of the <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> campaign winning in the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION>.'' Backers of both <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> have insisted their candidate can capture the caucus because of the traditional low turnout. Traditionally, only about 25,000 to 30,000 of <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION>'s 680,000 Democrats turn out for the primary-style vote which is the first step toward choosing 36 delegates to the July 18-21 national convention in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>. Party Executive Director <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON> <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> said Saturday evening he did not yet have an accurate turnout projection. `` I think we can win <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> campaign coordinator <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Norris </PERSON> said earlier Saturday. `` People committed to <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> tend to be more apt to go out and vote.'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> state director <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Villarreal </PERSON> was pleased with his candidate's endorsements this week by <LOCATION> Phoenix </LOCATION> Mayor <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> <PERSON> Goddard </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Tucson </LOCATION> Mayor <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Volgy </PERSON> and a number of other state and local government leaders. `` If the word gets out, it's significant,'' <PERSON> Villarreal </PERSON> said. `` These are all very well-known and respected individuals.'' However, he acknowledged the vote Saturday could be close. <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> agreed earlier in the day, saying `` It's anybody's ball game.'' <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> is the only candidate who visited the state. <PERSON> Gore </PERSON>'s local coordinator, <PERSON> Burt </PERSON> <PERSON> Drucker </PERSON>, said he is disappointed the national campaign allocated no money or candidate visits to the <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION> campaign. `` It's not the easiest way to put on a presidential race,'' <PERSON> Drucker </PERSON> said. `` He is the kind of moderate candidate that we feel would have appealed to the Democratic voters in rural <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION>.'' Thirty-six of <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION>'s 41-member delegation are up for grabs Saturday. The other five are `` super delegates'' _ four top party officials and Gov. Rose Mofford, all of whom are uncommitted. Saturday's vote is conducted like a primary, except there are only 99 polling places statewide. Democrats will vote twice: first, for the presidential candidate of their choice, and second, for the delegates they want to represent that candidate. The top 500 potential delegates, in proportion to the candidates they represent, will go to regional caucuses May 28. At those caucuses, 23 national convention delegates will be chosen. Later, in June, another 13 delegates _ also in proportion to the candidate vote _ will be chosen by the state committee from among party and elected officials. <PERSON> Villarreal </PERSON> acknowledged that <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> has a `` distinct advantage'' in the <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION> voting system, which is similar to the process in <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION> where <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> won a few weeks ago. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> was the strong leader in a poll of Democratic voters conducted several weeks ago. It found 36 percent in his corner, compared with 17 percent for <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> and 4 percent for <PERSON> Gore </PERSON>. The poll did not screen for likely voters.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880417-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-17-88 0054EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p AM-LouisianaElection 5thLd-Writethru a0699 04-17 0554</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Louisiana Election, 5th Ld - Writethru, a0699,0566</SECOND>
<HEAD>URGENT</HEAD>
<HEAD>McCrery Wins Louisiana Congressional Race</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: LEADS with 9 grafs to UPDATE with machines placed under
guard, secretary of state saying 3,000 voters disqualified between
primary and runoff; picks up 7th graf, ``Most recent...''</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By DAN EVEN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SHREVEPORT, La. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Republican <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> McCrery </PERSON> claimed victory Saturday night in an election to fill the northwest <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION> congressional seat vacated by Gov. <PERSON> Buddy </PERSON> <PERSON> Roemer </PERSON>, but his opponent refused to concede. With all 371 precincts reporting from the 4th Congressional District, unofficial returns gave <PERSON> McCrery </PERSON> 63,481 votes, or 51 percent, to 61,900 votes, or 49 percent, for Democratic state Sen. <PERSON> Foster </PERSON> <PERSON> Campbell </PERSON>. The winner will serve the remaining months of <PERSON> Roemer </PERSON>'s 1987-89 congressional term. <PERSON> Roemer </PERSON> was inaugurated governor in March. `` To be a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> congressman and help ensure the future of this great nation ... has long been a dream of mine. I will be a good congressman,'' <PERSON> McCrery </PERSON> told supporters. He also said he will run for a full two-year term in the fall. `` This race is razor-thin. I'm not ready to concede,'' said <PERSON> Campbell </PERSON>. `` I think the race is too close to call. I think we'll wait We'll know more about it when the voting machines are opened. ... I still think we can win this.'' The governor's office, <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION> and private security guards will guard all of the district's voting machines until the results can be certified, <PERSON> McCrery </PERSON> quoted <PERSON> Roemer </PERSON> as saying. There was confusion about the exact vote in <LOCATION> Caddo </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Parish </LOCATION>, as officials checked and rechecked computer readouts. In addition, Secretary of State <PERSON> Fox </PERSON> <PERSON> McKeithen </PERSON> said in <LOCATION> Baton </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rouge </LOCATION> that he had talked with federal voting officials about the disqualification of 3,000 Caddo Parish voters between the March 8 primary and Saturday's runoff. <PERSON> McKeithen </PERSON> said he was told voters can not be disqualified less than six weeks before an election. Most recent polls had given <PERSON> McCrery </PERSON>, a former <PERSON> Roemer </PERSON> aide, a slight advantage over <ORGANIZATION> Campbell </ORGANIZATION>. The last precincts to report were from the most populous <LOCATION> Shreveport-Bossier </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> area, and the narrow edge they gave <PERSON> McCrery </PERSON> was just enough to offset the support <PERSON> Campbell </PERSON> received in the seven rural parishes. Turnout was predicted at about 45 percent, said <PERSON> Darrell </PERSON> <PERSON> Cobb </PERSON>, director of the elections division of the secretary of state's office
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> McCrery </PERSON>, 38, is a former lobbyist for <ORGANIZATION> Georgia-Pacific </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> and a former congressional aide to both <PERSON> Roemer </PERSON> and his predecessor. <PERSON> Campbell </PERSON>, 41, is serving his fourth term in the <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>. His ability to campaign actively had been hampered because he was seriously injured in an auto accident March 13. <PERSON> Roemer </PERSON> vacated the 4th District seat March 14, the day he was inaugurated. The governor, a conservative Democrat, made no public endorsements in the runoff. <PERSON> McCrery </PERSON> was also a Democrat until he switched parties last fall in anticipation of running for <PERSON> Roemer </PERSON>'s seat, saying he disagreed with some aspects of the national <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> platform. In the March 8 primary, <PERSON> McCrery </PERSON> led a field of 10 candidates with 31 percent of the vote, followed by <PERSON> Campbell </PERSON> with 19 percent. <PERSON> McCrery </PERSON> was the only Republican in the race. In <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION>, non-presidential primaries are `` open,'' with all candidates running against one another regardless of party. If no one gets a majority, a runoff is held between the top two vote-getters.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880417-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-17-88 0057EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p AM-PoliticalRdp 6thLd-Writethru   04-17 1253</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Political Rdp, 6th Ld-Writethru,1288</SECOND>
<NOTE>EDs: INSERTS 1 graf after 29th graf pvs bgng, `While the,' to
UPDATE with early returns from Arizona</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By DONALD M. ROTHBERG</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democratic presidential candidates set aside their differences during a one hour-debate Saturday and concentrated their fire on the Republican administration, criticizing President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and Vice President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> on issues ranging from the sale of arms to <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> to the handling of the AIDS epidemic. `` I do n't see any intensity out there for <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>,'' said <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, entering the final weekend of the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> presidential primary as the front-runner in the polls. Sen. <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> said the administration had `` a disgraceful record'' in its handling of AIDS. `` We can not just manage Reaganomics, we're going to have to reverse Reaganomics,'' <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> said at the debate in <LOCATION> Rochester </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION> Before flying to the western <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> city, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> met with black businessmen in <LOCATION> Harlem </LOCATION> and toured an <LOCATION> Italian </LOCATION> neighborhood in <LOCATION> Queens </LOCATION>. Asked why he has spent so little time campaigning in black neighborhoods, the <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> governor said, `` I understand <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON>'s going to get the lion's share of the votes in this community and that's understandable.'' But, said <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, he had `` always had good support in the black community.'' <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, in a campaign appearance in <LOCATION> Niagara </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Falls </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION>, urged Indians, who generally do not vote as a matter of principle, to get involved in the nation's political process to improve life on the reservation. `` We want to reach out to them and urge them to vote,'' <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> said at a rally at an Indian museum. `` So many Native Americans have simply been broken-hearted. They've been hurt so long they feel a sense of betrayal. We have to get them involved.'' <PERSON> Gore </PERSON>, falling deeper in debt and trailing badly in the polls, began running commercials featuring <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> Mayor <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Koch </PERSON> urging voters to `` Vote positive. Vote <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> Gore </PERSON>.'' <PERSON> Koch </PERSON> also planned to march with <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> on Sunday in a Salute to <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> parade, a gesture <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> hopes will help him capture some of the Jewish voters who generally comprise 25 percent of the Democratic primary turnout. The three Democratic candidates, seated on stage at the Eastman Theater on Saturday for the League of Women Voters-sponsored debate, appeared determined to set aside their differences and concentrate on the vulnerabilities of their <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> opponent _ virtually certain to be <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> defended his meetings with <ORGANIZATION> Palestine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> leader <PERSON> Yasser </PERSON> <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Syrian </LOCATION> president <PERSON> Hafez </PERSON> <PERSON> Assad </PERSON> and <LOCATION> Cuban </LOCATION> president <PERSON> Fidel </PERSON> <PERSON> Castro </PERSON>. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> said he had appealed to <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON> to recognize <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> and had thanked <PERSON> Assad </PERSON> for releasing a <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> flier. As for <PERSON> Castro </PERSON>, <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> said he got the <LOCATION> Cuban </LOCATION> leader to release political prisoners and said, `` If we have diplomatic relations with <LOCATION> Chile </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> on the one hand and <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Russia </LOCATION> on the other, we should not reduce our influence in our own hemisphere with <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION>.'' Not even a discussion of the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION>, which has produced the sharpest differences between the candidates during the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> campaign, could shake their congeniality. <PERSON> Gore </PERSON>, who has taken the firmest pro-Israel stand, said the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> should not talk to the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> until that group renounces terrorism `` such as blowing up school buses with innocent children on them, renouncing that kind of act as an instrument of policy.'' <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, who has been the most sympathetic toward the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION>, quickly responded, `` You are right.'' Then he pointed out that <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> Prime Minister <PERSON> Yitzhak </PERSON> <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON> `` said he would n't recognize the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> even if they recognized him.'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, recalling the step the late Egyptian President <PERSON> Anwar </PERSON> <PERSON> Sadat </PERSON> took to end his country's state of war with <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>, said, `` I do n't see why it's so difficult for the other Arab leaders to do what <PERSON> Sadat </PERSON> did.'' <PERSON> Sadat </PERSON> eventually signed a peace treaty with <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>. The candidates greeted each other warmly after the debate with <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> standing on the stage's wing while <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> answered questions from reporters, and <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> watched from behind a crowd of journalists. `` I was going to ask you, ` when are you going to get off that stage,''' <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> joked to <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> when he finally stepped down. Every published poll of likely <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> primary voters showed <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> leading <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> by margins ranging from 6 to nearly 17 percentage points. All the surveys said <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> was running a distant third. In a <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post-ABC </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> poll published Sunday, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> was supported by 43 percent, <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> 37 percent and <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> 13 percent. The survey calculated the responses of 179 likely voters among 392 Democrats interviewed Thursday and Friday. The margin of error for the poll was plus or minus 8 percentage points. <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> toured a market in the heart of a Polish neighborhood in <LOCATION> Buffalo </LOCATION> and conceded that he is running behind in the state. `` At a minimum we have to have a strong finish to demonstrate continued momentum,'' <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> said. `` But I'm not going to put specific numbers on it.'' He said he thought he had time to improve his standing and added, `` It's a very volatile race.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was expected to sweep the 96 Republican delegates at stake on Tuesday. Half of the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> delegates were running unopposed. His only remaining opponent for the nomination, <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON>, did not campaign in the state and has said that <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was `` going to be the nominee of the <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> absent any unexpected eventuality.'' While the Democratic candidates were campaigning and debating in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, where 255 delegates are at stake, <ORGANIZATION> Arizona </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democrats </ORGANIZATION>, whose favorite son, former Gov. <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Babbitt </PERSON>, was an early casualty in the Democratic race, held caucuses on Saturday to allocate 36 delegates. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> held a strong lead over <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> in the earliest results from two rural counties in <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION>. Those results involved about 300 votes reported by late Saturday night, while an estimated 25,000 to 30,000 people were expected to participate in the caucuses. <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION>, which use a three-step process to select delegates, on Saturday held state conventions. <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION> Democrats gave two-thirds of their 15 delegates to the uncommitted while <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> got three and <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> two. The state convention was the final step in <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION>'s delegate selection process which began with precinct caucuses last month. In <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>, where the party completed its delegate-selection process begun with precinct caucuses March 12, <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> picked up almost two-third of the delegates on Saturday. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> came up with 28 delegates, while <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> won eight and <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> got seven. Allocation of the <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION> delegates will be determined by the outcome of a presidential preference vote at the caucuses. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> was the only candidate to campaign in <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION> and his state campaign coordinator <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Norris </PERSON> said, `` I think we can win <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION>. People committed to <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> tend to be more apt to go out and vote.'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> had the backing of many top state Democrats and was the leader in a poll taken several weeks ago. <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> spent neither time nor money in the state. <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> borrowed another $ 100,000 from banks in his home state of <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION>, bringing his total campaign debt to $ 1.6 million. Winless since Super Tuesday, when he demonstrated support across the <LOCATION> South </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> was spending $ 700,000 on advertising in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> in a bid to get back into contention. The Democratic candidates were scheduled to debate again on Sunday, a televised appearance on <ORGANIZATION> WNBC </ORGANIZATION>. All three also planned to appear at a senior citizen forum sponsored by city council president <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> <PERSON> Stein </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880417-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-17-88 0105EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Honduras-Deport     04-17 0226</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Honduras-Deport,0234</SECOND>
<HEAD>Colombian Adviser To Alleged Drug Trafficker Reportedly Deported</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TEGUCIGALPA, Honduras (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Honduran authorities deported a Colombian who managed the business affairs of an alleged international drug trafficker being held by <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> authorities, government sources said late Saturday. The sources in the <ORGANIZATION> Immigration </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION>, who spoke on condition of anonymity, said <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Ruiz </PERSON> and two other unidentified Colombians were deported to <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION> on Friday. <PERSON> Ruiz </PERSON> was a business manager of <PERSON> Juan </PERSON> <PERSON> Ramon </PERSON> <PERSON> Matta </PERSON>, the alleged drug trafficker who was hustled out of <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION> on April 5 and wound up in a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> prison. Authorities had detained <PERSON> Ruiz </PERSON> on April 6. <PERSON> Matta </PERSON>'s arrest sparked violent anti-American demonstrations that resulted in the burning and sacking of the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Consulate </ORGANIZATION> and offices of the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Information </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> in the capital of <LOCATION> Tegucigalpa </LOCATION>. Five Hondurans were reported killed in the protests. Honduran officials took <PERSON> Matta </PERSON> from his <LOCATION> Tegucigalpa </LOCATION> home in a pre-dawn raid and shuttled him onto a plane to the <LOCATION> Dominican </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Republic </LOCATION> without a passport. <LOCATION> Dominican </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Republic </LOCATION> officials put <PERSON> Matta </PERSON> on a New York-bound flight and he was arrested aboard the jetliner by <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> marshals, according to <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> law enforcement officials. <PERSON> Matta </PERSON>, held at a maximum-security federal prison in <LOCATION> Marion </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ill. </LOCATION>, was wanted by <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials on drug trafficking charges and for questioning in the 1985 slaying in <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> of a <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Drug </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Enforcement </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> agent.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880417-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-17-88 0108EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-AliensSweep     04-17 0270</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Aliens Sweep,0279</SECOND>
<HEAD>Eight-City Sweep Results In Record Arrests</HEAD>
<DATELINE>DUBLIN, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Immigration and <ORGANIZATION> Naturalization </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> agents on Saturday arrested 211 people suspected of being illegal aliens in eight cities in northern and central <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, the federal agency announced. All of those apprehended were men from <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, and all but 15 returned voluntarily Saturday afternoon, said <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Carter </PERSON>, chief patrol agent of the <LOCATION> Livermore </LOCATION> sector of the <ORGANIZATION> INS </ORGANIZATION>' Border Patrol. The arrests were the most made in the sector in one day since passage of the Immigration Reform and Control Act of 1986, <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> said. The sector stretches from the <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION> border south to <LOCATION> Oxnard </LOCATION> and includes 13 counties in northern <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION>. The sweep began shortly after midnight in <LOCATION> Fresno </LOCATION>, where 90 people were arrested. The others were captured in or near <LOCATION> Oxnard </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Salinas </PERSON>, <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Luis </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Obispo </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Bakersfield </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Livermore </PERSON>, <PERSON> Stockton </PERSON> and <LOCATION> Sacramento </LOCATION> by noon, <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> said. Some of the suspected illegal aliens were found in an apparent smuggling operation north of <LOCATION> Livermore </LOCATION>, he said. `` Anybody that had any documentation at all was immediately released from custody,'' <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> said. Acceptable documentation included proof of application for amnesty. The arrests were made at bus stations and highways. The Border Patrol has focused on undocumented workers at farms and ranches, but no one was arrested at his workplace on Saturday, <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> said. Those who agreed to return to <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> and had no criminal records were loaded on buses late Saturday afternoon. The 15 others were being held at the <ORGANIZATION> INS </ORGANIZATION> detention facility in <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Centro </LOCATION> and were expected to appear before an immigration judge early next week unless bail is posted.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880417-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-17-88 0139EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Israel 2ndLd-Writethru   04-17 0849</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Israel, 2nd Ld - Writethru,a0644,0871</SECOND>
<HEAD>Israelis Kill 15 in Protests over PLO Killing</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: LEADS with six grafs to UPDATE with Israel radio report of 15
dead, total Palestinians killed now 164 sted 162; pickup 6th graf
pvs, `Most of ...</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By JOCELYN NOVECK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>GAZA CITY, Occupied Gaza Strip (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Arabs enraged by the slaying of <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> chief <PERSON> Yasser </PERSON> <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON>'s top aide fought street battles Saturday with <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> soldiers who killed 15 rioters and wounded scores, Israeli radio reported. Hospital officials put the death toll at 14, with eight killed in <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> and six in the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Bernard </PERSON> <PERSON> Mills </PERSON>, head of the U.N. Relief and <ORGANIZATION> Works </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION>, said of the <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> soldiers: `` From reports we have, they used no warning shots, no tear gas, no rubber bullets. They just opened fire.'' A military spokesman said the soldiers fired because their lives were in danger. He described the clashes as `` breaking out spontaneously and with force'' and said demonstrators had thrown many firebombs at troops. Hospitals, <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> officials and <PERSON> Arab </PERSON> journalists said up to 90 Palestinians were wounded. The army imposed curfews on 10 refugee camps. It was the highest one-day death toll reported since violence began Dec. 8 in the occupied <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> strip </LOCATION>, bringing the number of Palestinians reported killed to at least 164. An <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> soldier and civilian also have been slain. Most of the violence was in the <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strip </LOCATION>, where <PERSON> Khalil </PERSON> <PERSON> al-Wazir </PERSON>, military commander of the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION>, lived until 1963 and close relatives remain. He was killed early Saturday at his home in <LOCATION> Tunis </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Tunisia </LOCATION>, by seven commandos who escaped. Palestinian leaders blamed <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> for the assassination. `` <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> is the only party that could have carried out such an act,'' said <PERSON> Hanna </PERSON> <PERSON> Siniora </PERSON>, editor of the newspaper <ORGANIZATION> Al </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fajr </ORGANIZATION> in Arab east <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION>. `` His -LRB- al-Wazir's -RRB- portfolio is the occupied territories. This is an attempt to crush the uprising by force.'' Spokesmen for the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> refused comment. <PERSON> Avi </PERSON> <PERSON> Pazner </PERSON>, who speaks for Prime Minister <PERSON> Yitzhak </PERSON> <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON>, said it was `` natural for the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> to blame <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>. They always blame <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>.'' <PERSON> Ariel </PERSON> <PERSON> Merari </PERSON>, an expert on terrorism at <ORGANIZATION> Tel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aviv </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, said the death of al-Wazir _ also known as <PERSON> Abu </PERSON> <PERSON> Jihad </PERSON> -LRB- Father of the Holy War -RRB- _ might have been the result of <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> infighting and that <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> chairman, probably approved it. Riots began in the occupied territories as soon as news of the assassination was broadcast. Hospital officials said seven Palestinians were shot to death in <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> and six in the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION>. The previous highest death toll was on April 2, when six Palestinians were killed. The Israeli army command confirmed 12 Arab deaths and said troops killed five Palestinians in the <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strip </LOCATION>. It said seven other Palestinians were slain and it was investigating the circumstances. Black flags of mourning fluttered in <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, home of five families related to <PERSON> al-Wazir </PERSON>, over streets blocked every few yards by barriers of stones and flaming tires. Mobs of angry young Arabs clutching rocks, blocks of cement, empty tear gas canisters and anything else that could be thrown crowded around approaching cars. Many masked their faces with shirts or Arab headscarves. `` <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> has not been this tense since the beginning of the uprising,'' said a woman who would not given her name. Outside the home of <PERSON> Ahmed </PERSON> <PERSON> al-Wazir </PERSON>, the dead man's brother-in-law, about 100 mourners sat under a tent as loudspeakers from a nearby mosque blared mourning verses from the Koran, holy book of Islam <LOCATION> Palestinian </LOCATION> flags, outlawed by <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>, were draped over the home's entrance and balcony. More of the red, green, white and black banners hung from poles in the street, obscured occasionally by thick smoke from burning tires. The service was interrupted when mourners spotted Israelis armed with rifles and tear gas at a nearby street corner. `` Come here if you are men!'' the Palestinians shouted, hurling stones. The troopers responded with tear gas, and gunfire was heard. Women in long black mourning dresses screamed at the soldiers. Some carried onions, bottles of cologne or buckets of chlorine, all thought to be remedies for tear gas inhalation. Mourners suddenly rushed at the Israelis, carrying <LOCATION> Palestinian </LOCATION> flags and shouting `` <PERSON> Allahu </PERSON> <PERSON> Akbar </PERSON>!'' -LRB- God is Great -RRB-. About 30 soldiers charged the protesters, firing tear gas and some live ammunition. The Arabs dispersed in a thick white cloud of tear gas and no casualties were evident. Inside the house, <PERSON> Ahmed </PERSON> <PERSON> al-Wazir </PERSON>, the widow's brother, said he had `` no doubts'' of who the killers were and denied allegations of a feud with <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON>. Most of the deaths in <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> were at refugee camps. Three people were reported killed in the <PERSON> Khan </PERSON> <PERSON> Younis </PERSON> camp in the southern <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strip </LOCATION>, two at the nearby <LOCATION> Rafah </LOCATION> camp, and one each at the Bureij refugee camp in the central <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strip </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Abssan </PERSON> village near <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. In the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION>, hospital officials said three people were killed in the town of <LOCATION> Jenin </LOCATION> and one each at <LOCATION> Silwad </LOCATION> near <LOCATION> Ramallah </LOCATION>, Habla near <LOCATION> Qalqilya </LOCATION>, and <LOCATION> Qabatiyeh </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880417-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-17-88 0206EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-Sea-TacCrash 6thLd-Writethru a0709 04-17 0875</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Sea-Tac Crash, 6th Ld - Writethru, a0709,0896</SECOND>
<HEAD>Investigation Begins In Seattle Commuter Plane Crash</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: SUBS 2nd graf to CORRECT that two in serious condition, sted
one.</NOTE>
<HEAD>LaserPhotos SE2,3, LaserColor SE4</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KATIA BLACKBURN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SEATTLE (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The pilot of a commuter plane that caught fire in flight was `` either very lucky, very brave, probably very skilled,'' officials said after a crash-landing that barely missed a crowded airport bar and injured 19 people. Two passengers and their seats were thrown through the side of the <ORGANIZATION> Horizon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> de </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Havilland </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dash </ORGANIZATION> 8 in the crash Friday night at <LOCATION> Seattle-Tacoma </LOCATION> <LOCATION> International </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION>. Two of the 40 people aboard were in serious condition Saturday. No one on the ground was hurt. `` Everyone was holding hands. I do n't know who the man was next to me, but I sure must have broke his arm holding onto it,'' said passenger <PERSON> Wilma </PERSON> <PERSON> Swartzwelder </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Spokane </LOCATION> nurse. She said the plane flew five or 10 minutes before she saw the right engine on fire. The propeller-driven plane narrowly missed the airport control tower. Then it made a hard landing and careened into a boarding ramp. The plane crashed through baggage carts `` like a bowling alley,'' then headed for the busy B Concourse Bar, said <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON> <PERSON> Chadd </PERSON>, 29, manager of a restaurant overlooking the B Concourse. `` If it would have been a few feet the other way, the nose would have went right into the bar, and this is their busiest night,'' <PERSON> Chadd </PERSON> said. However, a wing punched through a passenger ramp at an empty <ORGANIZATION> Delta </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lines </ORGANIZATION> gate where <PERSON> Chadd </PERSON> said a flight had departed about 10 minutes earlier. Eight investigators were sent from the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION>, along with board member <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Nall </PERSON>, to handle the investigation, said <PERSON> Ted </PERSON> <PERSON> Lopatkiewicz </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> NTSB </ORGANIZATION>. `` Obviously, the focus -LRB- of the probe -RRB- is centered in the right engine,'' <PERSON> Nall </PERSON> said. A 2-by-3-foot panel from the ravaged right engine was found Saturday about a mile and a half from the airport, <PERSON> Nall </PERSON> said. The panel, used to gain access to the engine for maintenance or repairs, was the only piece of the plane found outside the airport. Horizon President <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Kelly </PERSON> said the accident resulted in the first passenger injuries in the airline's seven-year history. He said the incident was the third in 19 months involving the turboprop engines on the Dash 8. In June, an engine fire was detected shortly after takeoff, and in 1986 a plane returned to <LOCATION> Sea-Tac </LOCATION> when an engine malfunctioned, he said. The incidents involved different aircraft among the airline's 10 Dash 8s, <PERSON> Kelly </PERSON> said. Officials at the de Havilland division of <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Canada </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pratt </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <LOCATION> Whitney </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>, manufacturer of the engines on the Dash 8, said in telephone interviews they knew of no recurrent problems with the aircraft or its engines. Horizon Flight 2658 had just taken off on a flight from <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Spokane </LOCATION> with a full load of 37 passengers, plus three crew members, said <ORGANIZATION> Horizon </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> <PERSON> Hamilton </PERSON>. The plane was about three miles from the airport when pilot <PERSON> Carl </PERSON> <PERSON> Carlson </PERSON> reported `` a hot engine,'' radio jargon for a fire, said <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Meyer </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aviation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> regional office in <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION>. The plane `` almost hit the -LRB- <LOCATION> Sea-Tac </LOCATION> -RRB- control tower,'' said <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Fryer </PERSON>, duty officer at the <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> air traffic control center in <LOCATION> Auburn </LOCATION>. `` The controllers thought he was going to hit it.'' `` They had a fire truck waiting and the flames were out in about 15 seconds,'' <PERSON> Fryer </PERSON> said. `` It could have been a lot worse,'' said air traffic controller <PERSON> Marvin </PERSON> <PERSON> K. </PERSON> <PERSON> Tobosa </PERSON>. `` We consider the pilot either very lucky, very brave, probably very skilled. It was pretty quick.'' Before the plane hit the ground, `` there was very little talking,'' said <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Lowenstam </PERSON>, 42, of <PERSON> Eugene </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Ore. </LOCATION> `` I heard someone in front comforting someone else, but there were no screams.'' When the plane hit, `` I heard the boom. They told us to put our heads down and shield our faces. Everybody was real calm,'' said Ms. <PERSON> Swartzwelder </PERSON>. The flight attendant `` did a good job'' of explaining how passengers should hold their heads down, said <PERSON> Todd </PERSON> <PERSON> Weber </PERSON>, 32, of <LOCATION> Clarkston </LOCATION>. The plane came down hard, careened across a runway, some grass and the tarmac, then hit the boarding ramp. What passengers heard was `` basically a piece of metal scraping concrete, a lot of bumps, a lot of noise,'' <PERSON> Weber </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Carol </PERSON> <PERSON> Watt </PERSON>, 43, of <PERSON> Eugene </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Ore. </LOCATION>, and <PERSON> Lowenstam </PERSON> said two passengers and their seats were ejected from the plane on impact. `` After we crashed, the whole seat to our right was thrown out the side of the plane,'' <PERSON> Lowenstan </PERSON> said. `` The whole right side of the aircraft basically came apart in several places,'' said <PERSON> Weber </PERSON>. In addition to the man in serious condition after chest surgery at <ORGANIZATION> Harborview </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>, officials said at least 18 were injured. Four people in all remained hospitalized Saturday. None of the injuries was considered life-threatening. <PERSON> Carlson </PERSON>, 38, of <LOCATION> Portland </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ore. </LOCATION>, was treated at <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mason </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION> for back pain and released, a nursing supervisor said. He declined to discuss the crash Friday night. <PERSON> Tina </PERSON> <PERSON> Mankowski </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Harborview </LOCATION>, where most of those aboard the plane were taken, said most passengers were from north-central <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880417-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-17-88 0740EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i BC-Israel-PLO     04-17 0490</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Israel-PLO,0504</SECOND>
<HEAD>Shamir Spokesman Denies Israeli Leaders Approved PLO Assassination</HEAD>
<DATELINE>JERUSALEM (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A spokesman for Prime Minister <PERSON> Yitzhak </PERSON> <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON> refused comment Sunday on reports that <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON> and two other high Israeli officials approved the assassination of the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION>'s deputy commander. <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> television, quoting unidentified sources, reported Saturday's assassination of <ORGANIZATION> Fatah </ORGANIZATION> military leader <PERSON> Khalil </PERSON> <PERSON> al-Wazir </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Tunisia </LOCATION> was a joint operation of <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s intelligence service, the Mossad, and naval and army units. The report, aired Saturday night, said the attack was approved by <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON>, Foreign Minister <PERSON> Shimon </PERSON> <PERSON> Peres </PERSON> and Defense Minister <PERSON> Yitzhak </PERSON> <PERSON> Rabin </PERSON> after <ORGANIZATION> Fatah </ORGANIZATION> guerrillas hijacked a bus and killed three Israelis in southern <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Negev </LOCATION> desert last month. `` This story has the same status as all the other stories like it which have been published, and we do n't relate to any of them,'' spokesman <PERSON> Avi </PERSON> <PERSON> Pazner </PERSON> told The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>. <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> said <PERSON> Mossad </PERSON> had asked three times for permission to kill <PERSON> al-Wazir </PERSON>, but that each time <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> officials refused to give permission. That changed after the bus attack, the network reported. The former head of a <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> intelligence unit praised the assassination and suggested in an interview Sunday with <ORGANIZATION> army </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> radio </ORGANIZATION> that al - <PERSON> Wazir </PERSON> had been an Israeli target in past years <PERSON> Rafael </PERSON> <PERSON> Eytan </PERSON>, who stepped down from the unit over the <PERSON> Pollard </PERSON> spy scandal in 1985, said, `` I have always honored doing justice to those people responsible for terrorist attacks.'' Israeli experts say <PERSON> al-Wazir </PERSON> was responsible for a list of bloody attacks such as the 1975 takeover of the Savoy Hotel in <LOCATION> Tel </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Aviv </LOCATION> in which 11 hostages were slain and a March 1978 bus hijacking in which 33 Israelis were killed and 82 wounded. His assassination touched off a wave of protests in the occupied <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strip </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> Saturday. At least 15 people were killed and up to 90 wounded in the bloodiest single day of Palestinian rioting since protests began Dec. 8. <PERSON> Eytan </PERSON> also said `` there is no doubt there is a parallel'' between the methods of Saturday's assassination and the 1973 slaying of <PERSON> al-Wazir </PERSON>'s predecessor, <PERSON> Kamel </PERSON> <PERSON> Adwan </PERSON>, by Israeli commandos in <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>. Palestinian officials have cited the similarity between the two commando raids as showing <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> was involved in <PERSON> al-Wazir </PERSON>'s assassination <PERSON> Eytan </PERSON> headed `` The <ORGANIZATION> Scientific </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liaison </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION>,'' an intelligence unit which <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> said it dismantled in 1985 for its involvement in recruiting former <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> analyst <PERSON> Jonathan </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Pollard </PERSON> to spy for <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Pollard </PERSON> is serving a life sentence after being convicted of selling <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> hundreds of secret American intelligence documents, including information about Arab targets. In an interview published this week by an army weekly, the head of <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> military intelligence, Gen. <PERSON> Amnon </PERSON> <PERSON> Shahak </PERSON>, who commanded the 1973 <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> raid, said <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> had a policy of striking at <LOCATION> Palestinian </LOCATION> guerrilla leaders. `` In my opinion whoever leads acts of terror is a proper target for liquidation. Whoever uses terrorism against us, should be a target,'' <PERSON> Shahak </PERSON> told the magazine `` Bamahane.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880417-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-17-88 0755EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i BC-Iran-Iraq 1stLd-Writethru a0712 04-17 0412</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Iran-Iraq, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0712,0421</SECOND>
<HEAD>Iraq Reports Firing Six Missiles Into Tehran</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: LEADS throughout to UPDATE with another missile fired, land
attack against Faw, Iranian confirmation. No pickup</NOTE>
<DATELINE>NICOSIA, Cyprus (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> reported firing seven missiles against <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION> and another Iranian city Sunday and said it had launched an offensive to recapture the Iranian-occupied port of Faw. <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> confirmed the attacks but said Iraqi troops were retreating from the <LOCATION> Faw </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Peninsula </LOCATION>. Iraqi forces `` are engaged in an epic battle to liberate Faw,'' said the official <ORGANIZATION> Iraqi </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> in an urgent dispatch, monitored in <LOCATION> Nicosia </LOCATION>. It gave no other details of the attack except that the operation launched on the first day of the monthlong Moslem feast of <LOCATION> Ramadan </LOCATION> was named `` Blessed Ramadan.'' <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> said Iraqi troops suffered `` hundreds of casualties'' in the land attack. The official <ORGANIZATION> Islamic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> said the Iraqis retreated after trying to infiltrate Iranian positions. The <LOCATION> Iraqi </LOCATION> port of Faw, in the northernmost reach of the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION>, was captured by Iranian forces that thrust across the wide Shatt-Al-Arab estuary in a major offensive in January and February 1986. The seizure of <LOCATION> Faw </LOCATION>, 55 miles south of <LOCATION> Basra </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>'s second largest city and major port, has been regarded as the most important Iranian victory in the 7 -LCB- - year-old war Earlier, <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> reported firing six long-range missiles into the Iranian capital of <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION> at 11.30 a.m. -LRB- 3:30 a.m. EDT -RRB-. It said a seventh missile was fired later in the day against the city of <LOCATION> Shiraz </LOCATION>, in southern <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION> radio, also monitored in <LOCATION> Nicosia </LOCATION>, confirmed the missile strikes against <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION>, saying these were fired `` at different intervals before noon.'' The radio added that `` several civilians were killed or wounded in these attacks,'' which also caused `` substantial damage to commercial and residential buildings, shops and vehicles.'' <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> has fired at least 120 missiles on <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> since Feb. 29, when the two nations intensified bombings of cities. <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> said it responded to the Saturday attacks by firing two missiles into the Iraqi capital of <LOCATION> Baghdad </LOCATION>. The Iraqi news agency also reported Sunday that one of two Iranian warplanes raiding cities in the Kurdish region of northeastern <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> the previous day was shot down by <LOCATION> Iraqi </LOCATION> defenses. The agency said the raids were directed against residential areas in the cities of <LOCATION> Erbil </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Dohuk </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Dukan </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> IRNA </ORGANIZATION> said Saturday's air raids were in retaliation for Iraqi missile strikes and air raids against `` civilian areas'' of Iranian cities.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880417-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-17-88 0926EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i BC-Hijack     04-17 0429</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Hijack,0446</SECOND>
<HEAD>Gunmen Extend `Departure Warning' To Pursue Talks</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MICHAEL GOLDSMITH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ALGIERS, Algeria (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Shiite Moslem gunmen who have threatened to fly a hijacked Kuwaiti jet and about 35 hostages out of <LOCATION> Algeria </LOCATION> said Sunday they were extending their `` departure time warning'' to pursue negotiations. Airport personnel were preparing to fill the plane's tanks with about 6,600 gallons of fuel to maintain conditions inside the plane, where the hostages were being held for a 13th day. The hijackers did not set a new deadline. <LOCATION> Kuwait </LOCATION> Airways Flight 422, with 112 people on board, was hijacked April 5 on a flight from <LOCATION> Bangkok </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Kuwait </LOCATION>. The plane spent three days in <LOCATION> Mashhad </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>, five in <LOCATION> Larnaca </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Cyprus </LOCATION>, and arrived here early Wednesday. The gunmen killed two passengers in <LOCATION> Cyprus </LOCATION>. They released 57 hostages at <LOCATION> Mashhad </LOCATION>, 13 at <LOCATION> Larnaca </LOCATION> and one on Friday in <LOCATION> Algiers </LOCATION>. The hijackers earlier asked for the fuel by 11 a.m. -LRB- 6 a.m. EDT -RRB-. In a brief statement in Arabic to the control tower, the hijackers said, `` At the request of our brothers the Algerians we announce that we have agreed to extend the departure time warning to give an opportunity for the efforts by the Algerians.'' An Algerian negotiator boarded the blue and white <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> 747 for 15 minutes, leaving the aircraft at 11:10 a.m. -LRB- 6:10 a.m. EDT -RRB-. Inside the airport terminal building, Algerian Interior Minister <PERSON> Hedi </PERSON> <PERSON> Khediri </PERSON> pursued negotiations with a high-level <LOCATION> Kuwaiti </LOCATION> delegation. On Saturday, the hijackers said they would ask that the plane be refueled `` to settle our score with <LOCATION> Kuwait </LOCATION> somewhere else.'' `` We do not want the massacre to take place here in friendly <LOCATION> Algeria </LOCATION>, which welcomed us and which tried to settle the problem,'' they said Saturday. The hijackers are demanding freedom for 17 terrorists imprisoned in <LOCATION> Kuwait </LOCATION> for the 1983 bombings of the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and French embassies there. Shortly after the threat, <LOCATION> Kuwaiti </LOCATION> government asked Algerian authorities to prevent the plane from leaving. The new activity came as Moslems prepared to observe <PERSON> Ramadan </PERSON>, the month-long period of fasting when Islamic values are particularly stressed. It starts here on Monday. It was not immediately clear how the holiday might affect negotiations or the fate of the hostages. Three members of the <LOCATION> Kuwaiti </LOCATION> royal family are among the hostages. There are believed to be about eight hijackers, one or two of whom may have boarded in <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Algeria </LOCATION> has a record of negotiating solutions to hostage situations. It successfully gained the release in 1981 of Americans held at the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION> for 444 days.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880417-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-17-88 1128EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-CharityDrives     04-17 0269</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Charity Drives,0277</SECOND>
<HEAD>Door-To-Door Charity Drives Falling Out Of Step</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BOSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
