<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880519-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-19-88 2339EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-BusAccidents     05-19 0228</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Bus Accidents,0234</SECOND>
<HEAD>Dozens Hurt when School Buses Overturn</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 A school bus overturned on a curve and plunged down an embankment Thursday, injuring 60 people returning from a church outing in <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION>, and more than 20 fifth-graders were injured in a school bus crash in <LOCATION> Albion </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>, authorities said. No one was killed in either accident, and authorities said most injuries apparently were bruises, cuts and broken bones. Police said the bus carrying a group from the <ORGANIZATION> Walnut </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Street </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Shore </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Penn. </LOCATION>, was returning from an outing in <LOCATION> Harrisburg </LOCATION> when it overturned on a sharp curve known in <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Shore </LOCATION> as `` Devil's Elbow.'' At least two adults and one child were admitted to a hospital after the 4:45 p.m. accident. Children on the bus appeared to be between the ages of 6 and 12, observers at the scene of the accident said. Twelve ambulances took them, their chaperones and the bus driver to three hospitals. In <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>, 58 fifth-graders from <ORGANIZATION> Lowell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Elementary </ORGANIZATION> school in <LOCATION> Waterloo </LOCATION> and several chaperones were returning from a field trip near <LOCATION> Des </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Moines </LOCATION>, when their bus slipped onto a soft shoulder and overturned south of <LOCATION> Albion </LOCATION>. `` The injuries do n't appear to be that serious,'' said <PERSON> Omar </PERSON> <PERSON> Voran </PERSON>, administrator of the <ORGANIZATION> Marshalltown </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> and Surgical Center, where at least 20 students were treated in the emergency room.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880519-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-19-88 2340EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-BabyKidnapping     05-19 0336</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Baby Kidnapping,330</SECOND>
<HEAD>Woman Convicted of Kidnapping Baby, Keeping Him Four Months</HEAD>
<DATELINE>UPPER MARLBORO, Md. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A woman who admitted causing `` a lot of hurt and pain'' was convicted Thursday of kidnapping a baby from a hospital last summer and keeping him for four months. The Prince <PERSON> George </PERSON>'s County jury deliberated an hour before reaching its verdict against <PERSON> Linda </PERSON> <PERSON> Stancil-Lewis </PERSON>, 34, for the kidnapping of <PERSON> Jeremiah </PERSON> <PERSON> Thate </PERSON>. <PERSON> Stancil-Lewis </PERSON>, who stood silently as the verdict was ready, faces up to 30 years in prison for kidnapping, child abduction and false imprisonment when she is sentenced June 17. In an eight-page statement written by <PERSON> Stancil-Lewis </PERSON> and presented at trial, she said she saw the infant's mother on television pleading for his return, but she could n't give him back because she loved him. The boy, who was kidnapped in June when he was 3 weeks old, was found in <LOCATION> Stancil-Lewis </LOCATION><LOCATION> ' </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Southeast </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> apartment Oct. 28. `` I took a sweet little baby boy,'' Detective <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Davidson </PERSON> quoted <PERSON> Stancil-Lewis </PERSON> as saying as he read her statement in court. `` My heart went out to her,'' she wrote of the baby's mother, <PERSON> Theresa </PERSON> <PERSON> Thate </PERSON>, adding she `` could n't give him back. I loved him, too.'' <PERSON> Stancil-Lewis </PERSON>, who had suffered a miscarriage shortly before the baby was abducted, recounted in her statement that she found <PERSON> Jeremiah </PERSON> lying unattended in a hospital crib last June 11, smuggled him out of the hospital in a canvas sports bag and took him home. As the statement was read, Mrs. <PERSON> Thate </PERSON>, left the courtroom in tears. Seconds later, she was followed by her shaken husband, <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Thate </PERSON>. In the statement, <PERSON> Stancil-Lewis </PERSON> said: `` I caused this lady a lot of hurt and pain.'' She said she had begun thinking about giving the baby back to the <LOCATION> Hyattsville </LOCATION> couple. Prosecutors completed their case Wednesday after Assistant State's Attorney <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Harvey </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> called 10 witnesses to the stand. <PERSON> Stancil-Lewis </PERSON>' public defender, <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Allen </PERSON> <PERSON> Shepherd </PERSON>, did not call any witnesses and did not have <PERSON> Stancil-Lewis </PERSON> testify on her own behalf.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880519-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-19-88 2341EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Korea-Protests 2ndLd-Writethru a0756 05-19 0726</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Korea-Protests, 2nd Ld-Writethru, a0756,0748</SECOND>
<HEAD>Tens of Thousands Protest in South Korean Cities</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Leads with 8 grafs to UPDATE with students attacking U.S.
Embassy compound. Pickup 4th graf pvs ``Student protesters...'';
SUBS 7th graf pvs ``It was...'' with one graf to conform.</NOTE>
<HEAD>With AM-Korea, Bjt</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto KWJ4</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PAUL SHIN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SEOUL, South Korea (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Radical students tossed up to five small explosive devices into the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Embassy compound after scaling the walls Friday during a demonstration, police said. Police said the devices exploded but did not cause any injuries or damage. Rioters fought police with rocks and firebombs Thursday after the funeral of a dissident student. They attacked a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> cultural center and burned an <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> flag in front of City Hall. The protesters demanded that President <PERSON> Roh </PERSON> <PERSON> Tae-woo </PERSON>'s government be removed and the 40,000 <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> troops stationed in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> go home. About five students who climbed over the wall of the embassy in downtown <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION> were arrested, police said. Two other students were arrested later when they rushed through the gates of the compound. Eyewitnesses said the devices that exploded appeared to be homemade. Radical students set off similar devices in February whey they briefly seized the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Information </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> building in <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION>. Protesters broke windows and hurled firebombs at the <ORGANIZATION> Information </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> building in <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION> during clashes with riot police Thursday in the center of the city. Protesters burned the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> flag as speakers denounced the government following a march Thursday by about 25,000 people to City Hall. When the crowd did not disperse, police fired tear gas from armored vans and about 5,000 riot police attacked. Student protesters fled into nearby streets and hurled firebombs at police that set fire to several shops and part of a subway station. Terrified pedestrian fled, many choking from thick clouds of tear gas. Skirmishes between police and protesters broke out around luxury hotels. Tourists looked on in astonishment or ran for cover. Gasoline bombs set a roof garden ablaze at the <LOCATION> Lotte </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hotel </LOCATION> and fire trucks forced their way through the rioters to reach it. The street protests this week were the worst in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> since last summer, when demonstrations forced the government to agree to elections and democratic reforms. The Yonhap news agency said 32,000 people took part in anti-government protests Thursday at 34 places throughout <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>, but its tabulation appeared incomplete. In the southern opposition stronghold of <LOCATION> Kwangju </LOCATION> alone, about 100,000 people surged into the central district. Tens of thousands clashed with police. Police in <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION> arrested 22 people during street battles after the funeral of dissident student <PERSON> Cho </PERSON> <PERSON> Sung-man </PERSON>, who committed suicide Sunday in a protest against the government. `` Down with the military dictatorship!'' and `` Drive out the <ORGANIZATION> Yankees </ORGANIZATION>!'' the protesters in <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION> screamed, hurling rocks, bricks and firebombs. Dozens of windows were broken in attacks on City Hall and the nearby <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> cultural center. Gasoline bombs burst into flames amid squads of riot police during the struggle for control of the city's main shopping area. While street battles raged in <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION> and elsewhere, <PERSON> Cho </PERSON>'s body was buried at a cemetery in <LOCATION> Kwangju </LOCATION> after a five-hour procession that included stops for memorial services at his school in <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION> and home in <LOCATION> Chonju </LOCATION>, another southern city. The funeral procession in <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION>, which police did not try to stop, moved through the center of the capital, snarling traffic in the morning rush hour. `` Down with the murder regime!'' marchers shouted as others in white mourning clothes beat drums and cymbals. Singers chanted dirges and students in white performed a ghost dance. `` We will never end our struggle until we destroy <PERSON> Roh </PERSON>'s regime! one young woman shouted. Protests began Tuesday to honor <PERSON> Cho </PERSON> and mark the eighth anniversary, on Wednesday, of the 1980 <LOCATION> Kwangju </LOCATION> uprising in which at least 191 people were killed. In <LOCATION> Kwangju </LOCATION>, 100,000 people packed a major traffic circle for a rally demanding a full accounting of the uprising. Thousands of riot police fired tear gas, starting hours of street battles. Protesters shouted `` Execute <PERSON> Roh </PERSON> Tae-woo!'' and `` Unite the motherland by driving out <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. imperialists!'' <PERSON> Roh </PERSON> helped his fellow army general <PERSON> Chun </PERSON> <PERSON> Doo-hwan </PERSON> seize power in 1980 and succeeded him as president in February. Opposition groups in <LOCATION> Kwangju </LOCATION> say both men should be held responsible for the harsh military suppression of the 1980 revolt.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880519-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-19-88 2350EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-PoliceFire 1stLd-Writethru a0832 05-19 0257</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Police Fire, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0832,0257</SECOND>
<HEAD>Fire Erupts In 8-Story Police Headquarters Downtown</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: UPDATES throughout with fire out, casualties, police phone
service still available; no pickup.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>KANSAS CITY, Mo. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Fire broke out Thursday night at the eight-story downtown headquarters of the <ORGANIZATION> Kansas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, knocking out 911 emergency service and forcing evacuation of the building, officials said. At least seven people were taken to hospitals and several others were treated for smoke inhalation at the scene, officials said. Firefighters brought the blaze under control about 9:55 p.m., two hours after it was reported. About 60 people were working in the building, police spokeswoman Sgt. <PERSON> Laura </PERSON> <PERSON> Mulloy </PERSON> said. About 40 prisoners were evacuated from the city jail on the eighth floor of the building and taken to the basement of <ORGANIZATION> Municipal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>, she said. The city's 911 emergency service was out of order because of the blaze, officials said, but four phone lines were open to the public to reach police in case of emergency. The four-alarm blaze was reported about 7:45 p.m. on the building's fifth floor, said fire department spokesman Capt. <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Galetti </PERSON>. The office of Police Chief <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Joyner </PERSON> is located on the fifth floor. `` There was some redecorating going on in the chief's office, I'm told,'' <PERSON> Galetti </PERSON> said, adding that the blaze was reported by construction workers. floor. Smoke poured from windows of the fifth, sixth and seventh floors, witnesses said, and several firefighters trapped by fire on the fifth floor were rescued by ladder, officials said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880519-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-19-88 0121EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-TeedOff     05-19 0235</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Teed Off,0241</SECOND>
<HEAD>Car Dealership Sues Golf Course After Errant Swings Damage Cars</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SUNNYVALE, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The owners of a car dealership that sells expensive sports cars are teed off about their neighbors, a miniature golf course where they say some players take too-hefty swings. Golf balls have been clearing a 30-foot-high net between <LOCATION> Golfland </LOCATION> <LOCATION> USA </LOCATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Porsche </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Motorsport </ORGANIZATION> for years, said <PERSON> Ken </PERSON> <PERSON> Boswell </PERSON>, the car dealership's general manager. But the last straw, he said, was when a brass putter also flew over the fence and smashed the windshield of a Porsche 911 convertible. The putter, which also scratched a Porsche 928 on the rebound, caused $ 3,000 in damage, <PERSON> Boswell </PERSON> said. As a result, the dealership filed a lawsuit Tuesday against <ORGANIZATION> Golfland </ORGANIZATION> in <ORGANIZATION> Santa </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Clara </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Superior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>. It asks for unspecified damages, contending <ORGANIZATION> Porsche </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Motorsport </ORGANIZATION> has suffered thousands of dollars in losses because of the errant golfers. The manager on duty at <LOCATION> Golfland </LOCATION> on Wednesday referred phone calls to owner <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Kenney </PERSON>, who could not be reached for comment. <PERSON> Kenney </PERSON>'s wife, <PERSON> Geri </PERSON>, said Wednesday the couple had not seen the lawsuit, but added that they had done everything possible to prevent balls from going onto adjacent property. <PERSON> Boswell </PERSON> believes most of the wayward balls come from a hole where golfers must hit up a ramp to reach the cup. `` They must treat the hole like they're on a driving range,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880519-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-19-88 0727EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--McKinleyDeath     05-19 0119</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--McKinley Death,0121</SECOND>
<HEAD>Woman Dies on Mount McKinley</HEAD>
<DATELINE>DENALI MEDICAL CAMP, Alaska (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A woman whose guided party was pushing for <LOCATION> Mount </LOCATION> <LOCATION> McKinley </LOCATION>'s summit has become the first fatality of the 1988 climbing season on <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s tallest peak, the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Park </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> said. The agency said it learned early Wednesday that <PERSON> Lynn </PERSON> <PERSON> Salerno </PERSON>, 31, of <LOCATION> Anchorage </LOCATION>, had died of apparent hypothermia and exposure at the mountain's 19,500-foot level. Rangers did not know the circumstances or time of death. <PERSON> Salerno </PERSON> was in a party led by <PERSON> Vern </PERSON> <PERSON> Tejas </PERSON>, 35, an Alaskan whose solo winter ascent of 20,320-foot <PERSON> McKinley </PERSON> this year made mountaineering history. The party is believed to have begun its climb on or about May 1.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880519-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-19-88 0123EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--Pravda     05-19 0125</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Pravda,0130</SECOND>
<HEAD>German-Language Edition Of Pravda Goes On Sale In Vienna</HEAD>
<DATELINE>VIENNA, Austria (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A German-language edition of the <ORGANIZATION> Soviet </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> newspaper Pravda has gone on sale in <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION>. The paper, which appeared on newstands on Wednesday, will have an initial daily circulation of 15,000, <PERSON> Christoph </PERSON> <PERSON> Raabe </PERSON>, who heads the company issuing the newspaper in German-speaking countries, was quoted as saying. According to the <ORGANIZATION> Austria </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Raabe </PERSON> expects a deficit of $ 590,000 by the end of the year but hopes to break even by the end of 1989. Pravda is to appear daily, but Sunday and Monday editions will be combined. Prospective readers include companies doing business with <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Europe </ORGANIZATION> as well as institutions and associations interested in Soviet bloc events.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880519-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-19-88 0123EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--Vietnam-China     05-19 0139</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Vietnam-China,0143</SECOND>
<HEAD>Vietnam Frees 22 More Chinese Fishermen</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BANGKOK, Thailand (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> has freed 22 more Chinese fishermen who were caught poaching in Vietnamese waters, the official <ORGANIZATION> Radio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hanoi </ORGANIZATION> reported. The captives were turned over to Chinese officials on Wednesday at <PERSON> Huu </PERSON> <PERSON> Nghi </PERSON> border post in the northern province of <LOCATION> Lang </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Son </LOCATION> bordering <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Guangxi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Province </LOCATION>, according to a text of the broadcast obtained in <LOCATION> Bangkok </LOCATION> today. On Monday, 68 Chinese fishermen were reportedly freed from the central coastal province of <PERSON> Quang </PERSON> <PERSON> Nam-Danang </PERSON>. The releases follow repeated official Vietnamese requests that <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> free nine sailors captured during a brief clash in the Spratlys islands in March and a pilot whose plane strayed across the northern border into <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> last year. The clash in the <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sea </LOCATION> islands was over which country had sovereignty over the chain.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880519-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-19-88 0140EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Iran-Elections     05-19 0857</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Iran-Elections,0883</SECOND>
<HEAD>Radicals Gain In Parliament, Indicating More Anti-West Militancy</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</NOTE>
<HEAD>An AP Analysis</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ED BLANCHE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NICOSIA, Cyprus (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Strong gains by radicals in <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'s parliamentary elections signal even greater militancy against the West and more state control of the economy Results from the second round of voting Friday confirmed the advantage radicals gained in the first round five weeks earlier. There were reports of violence in some cities during the bitterly contested election. The breakdown of the new 270-seat parliament between the power blocs is not yet known, but announced results show radicals clearly in the ascendancy after a prolonged struggle with conservatives in the leadership. Parliament has had little say in foreign policy, but Western analysts believe the new radical strength will affect foreign relations, conduct of the war with <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> and the course of <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'s fundamentalist Shiite Moslem revolution They feel the radical gains, at a time of increasing political uncertainty and military setbacks, herald a tougher stand against the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> accuse <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> of aiding <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> in the war, which began in September 1980. `` The Iranians will likely prosecute the war more vigorously. They're already rethinking their strategy, which was based on attrition,'' <PERSON> Hans-Heino </PERSON> <PERSON> Kopietz </PERSON> said in an interview from the <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Strategic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Studies </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>. `` But much will depend on how quickly they can improve the economy,'' <PERSON> Kopietz </PERSON> said. `` This is their first priority. If they can get credit abroad, to get more military hardware as well as alleviate domestic hardship, they will be more aggressive.'' New alliances that have emerged in the <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION> hierarchy are sure to affect the struggle over who will run the country after the death of <PERSON> Ayatollah </PERSON> <PERSON> Ruhollah </PERSON> <PERSON> Khomeini </PERSON>, the 87-year-old revolutionary patriarch. He has named <PERSON> Ayatollah </PERSON> <PERSON> Hussein-Ali </PERSON> <PERSON> Montazeri </PERSON>, 66, as his successor. <PERSON> Montazeri </PERSON> has no significant power base, however, and is opposed by such key figures as <PERSON> Hashemi </PERSON> <PERSON> Rafsanjani </PERSON>, the parliament speaker, who regularly leads Friday prayers at <ORGANIZATION> Tehran </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Montazeri </PERSON> is expected to become a figurehead, with real power held by <PERSON> Rafsanjani </PERSON> and two or three others. <PERSON> Rafsanjani </PERSON>, who is allied with the radicals on several issues, scored a personal triumph in the election by winning 1.3 million votes. Other radical winners include <PERSON> Mohammad </PERSON> <PERSON> Salamati </PERSON>, former agriculture minister; <PERSON> Hojatoleslam </PERSON> <PERSON> Mehdi </PERSON> <PERSON> Kharroubi </PERSON>, who heads the <ORGANIZATION> Pilgrimage </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> and is believed to have directed riots last year in the holy city of <LOCATION> Mecca </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Saudi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arabia </LOCATION>, and <PERSON> Ateqe </PERSON> <PERSON> Sediqi </PERSON> <PERSON> Rajai </PERSON>, widow of President <PERSON> Mohammad </PERSON> <PERSON> Ali </PERSON> <PERSON> Rajai </PERSON>. Leftist opponents of the <PERSON> Khomeini </PERSON> regime assassinated <PERSON> Rajai </PERSON> in 1981. Of 208 incumbents who ran, only about 100 were re-elected to the new Majlis, as <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'s parliament is known. Its term is four years. The main group of conservative clerics, the <ORGANIZATION> Militant </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Clergy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION>, was weakened just before the elections when a radical faction led by <PERSON> Kharroubi </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Pilgrimage </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> broke away over political and economic issues. Diplomatic sources with contacts in <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION> said the split was encouraged by <PERSON> Khomeini </PERSON> and the prosecutor-general, <PERSON> Mohammed </PERSON> <PERSON> Khoeiniha </PERSON>, a leader of the `` followers of the Imam's line'' who stormed the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Embassy in November 1979 and held 52 Americans hostage for 444 days. <PERSON> Serajeddin </PERSON> <PERSON> Mousavi </PERSON>, a cleric who heads the security apparatus, said in the <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION> daily <ORGANIZATION> Kayhan </ORGANIZATION>: `` Being in a state of war and at this sensitive juncture, we must not allow a bunch of obstructionists to waste parliament's time.'' <PERSON> Khomeini </PERSON> spent years playing referee between the rival factions, but moved clearly to the radical side before the elections. He decreed wider state powers, opening the way for economic reforms that were blocked by the conservative-dominated Council of Guardians. The council can veto legislation it decides is a violation of Islamic tenets. Since the late <PERSON> Shah </PERSON> <PERSON> Mohammad </PERSON> <PERSON> Reza </PERSON> <PERSON> Pahlavi </PERSON> was overthrown in February 1979, the radicals have sought to nationalize industry and trade, distribute land held by wealthy families and liberalize social laws. Conservatives, supported by the merchant class, advocate a more capitalist economy. `` The radicals' success is significant because it gives impetus to their efforts to achieve state control not just of the economy, but the whole revolutionary apparatus,'' <PERSON> Kopietz </PERSON> said. A major radical figure to emerge recently is Interior Minister <PERSON> Ali-Akbar </PERSON> <PERSON> Mohtashemi </PERSON>, former ambassador to <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION>. Western Intelligence agencies have linked him closely to Shiite extremists in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> who kidnapped Westerners and carried out suicide bomb attacks. <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION> told <PERSON> Mohtashemi </PERSON> from <LOCATION> Damascus </LOCATION> in June 1985 after two Americans were kidnapped in <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>. Shortly before that, <PERSON> Mohtashemi </PERSON> lost his right eye and two fingers of his right hand when he opened a booby-trapped parcel in <LOCATION> Damascus </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION> claimed the <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> sent it. As interior minister, <PERSON> Mohtashemi </PERSON> was in charge of the elections. Several months ago he replaced 20 provincial governors, who are responsible for screening candidates. He became interior minister in August, replacing <PERSON> Ali-Akbar </PERSON> <PERSON> Nategh-Nouri </PERSON>, conservative head of the Hojati Islamic faction. <PERSON> Nategh-Nouri </PERSON> did not win a majority in his <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION> district in the first election round April 8, but made it May 13.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Ed </PERSON> <PERSON> Blanche </PERSON> is <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> news editor of The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>. He has covered <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> and the region since 1985.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880519-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-19-88 0144EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-MojaveCounty     05-19 0712</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Mojave County,0729</SECOND>
<HEAD>Secessionists Want To Carve Out Biggest U.S. County In Desert</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By E. SCOTT RECKARD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WRIGHTWOOD, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Pines </PERSON> dot snowy peaks outside as <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Pinard </PERSON> sits in his rustic office in a peach cowboy shirt, crusading to carve away 90 percent of the nation's largest county to create <LOCATION> Mojave </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>. At 18,160 square miles of mostly desert north of the <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gabriel </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bernardino </LOCATION> mountains, the new county would still be the nation's largest, bigger than <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Rhode </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Delaware </LOCATION> combined. Both it and what remained of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bernardino </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> would have better-focused government if voters agree to a `` divorce'' by passing Measure A, said <PERSON> Pinard </PERSON>, who publishes a local newspaper from this 6,000-foot-high ski resort town. His allies gathered 15,000 signatures to get the issue on the June 7 ballot. If approved by a majority vote, <LOCATION> Mojave </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> would begin operating after a Board of Supervisors is elected in November. Four-fifths of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bernardino </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>'s 1.1 million residents are jammed into the far eastern edge of the <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> megalopolis, and <PERSON> Pinard </PERSON> says they deserve a county government that concentrates on urban woes: air and water pollution, gangs, gridlock. But the 205,000 people in the proposed new county confront other problems. The area encompasses military and Indian preserves, mining regions, wilderness, a slice of <LOCATION> Death </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> resorts and the mountains near <LOCATION> Wrightwood </LOCATION>. `` You come up over the mountains and you have people with an entirely different set of problems,'' said <PERSON> Pinard </PERSON>, who would like to be elected a <LOCATION> Mojave </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> supervisor. `` We've got snow; they've got gutters and curbs. Residents of such <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> basin cities as <LOCATION> Ontario </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Fontana </PERSON> and <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bernardino </LOCATION> are `` just not conscious of our concerns,'' he said. But opponents of the `` divorce'' contend a new, 2,000-square-mile <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bernardino </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> would really be `` <LOCATION> Podunk </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>,'' the second-smallest in <LOCATION> Southern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, stripped of money and influence. They belittle promises by <PERSON> Pinard </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Steering </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> of more efficient and responsive government, better roads and law enforcement. Opponents say it instead would skirt bankruptcy from the outset, with too little industry for its size. Its far-flung voters would be unlikely to approve bonds to fund a jail, hospitals or other public works; and services would suffer, they contend. `` They say <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bernardino </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> government is too fat and unresponsive, and maybe that's true,'' said <PERSON> Nelda </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Wrightwood </LOCATION>, coordinator of the NO on Mojave committee. `` But I think we should work at changing it before jumping off a cliff.'' A key point of contention is a report by a special governor's commission that found <LOCATION> Mojave </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> to be economically feasible, with an $ 88,000 surplus on a yearly budget of more than $ 137 million, assuming current service levels The commission, mandated by law after Measure A qualified, sketched a division of assets and liabilities and organization of the new county. It said current <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bernardino </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> employees would be able to work for Mojave with no cuts in pay or benefits. As part of the settlement, it said, the old county would owe the new $ 11.8 million, to be paid in three yearly payments. But late last month, the <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bernardino </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> Supervisors sued, contending the study failed to account for unfunded pension liabilities that would mean the new, smaller <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bernardino </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> would be owed as much as $ 33.6 million by <LOCATION> Mojave </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> San </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Diego </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Superior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> Judge <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Milliken </PERSON> ruled May 11 that he had no authority to invalidate the proposal. The supervisors' appeal will not be heard until after the election. Most of the proposed county now is represented by Supervisor <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Joyner </PERSON>, who cast the sole vote against filing the suit. <PERSON> Joyner </PERSON>, who is running for re-election against a former aide, has not said how he will vote on the measure. If <LOCATION> Mojave </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> is created, <PERSON> Joyner </PERSON>'s district would be reduced to most of the <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bernardino </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mountains </LOCATION>, including the Big Bear and <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arrowhead </LOCATION> resorts, and the <LOCATION> Morongo </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Basin </LOCATION> desert area. <PERSON> Pinard </PERSON> said he had believed odds for passage of Measure A were slightly better than 50-50; but with the supervisors' suit, he said, `` I just do n't know _ the chances have to be revised downward.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880519-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-19-88 0146EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-FarewellParty     05-19 0446</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Farewell Party,0459</SECOND>
<HEAD>Man Getting Wish Posthumously: A Piano Dropped From The Sky</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SANTA ROSA, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 In his lifetime, <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Cameron </PERSON> <PERSON> Young </PERSON> had a secret wish, an unusual fantasy: He wondered what an airborne piano would sound like crashing to earth. Now, a bit late, his friends will find out. The <LOCATION> Marin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> man was 44 when he died three years ago, leaving an $ 800,000 estate. In his will, <PERSON> Young </PERSON>, whose life was full of adventure and fun-loving behavior, left $ 15,000 to three buddies who were instructed to toss one last party for their departed friend. The professional guitar player told his friends to `` give a party for themselves and as many of my friends as they can find that desire to attend.'' As told by <PERSON> Young </PERSON>'s friends, the <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> native moved to the <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION> area in 1972. He sang Delta blues and found time to be a parachutist, pilot, storyteller and business success with six furniture stores. It took three years to straighten out <PERSON> Young </PERSON>'s will, and on May 28, hundreds of folks are expected to gather for the memorial celebration. They will indulge Young's strange fantasy _ listening to a 300-pound piano crash to the ground from a hovering helicopter. `` He talked about that all the time,'' said <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON>, 53, a <LOCATION> Fairfax </LOCATION> graphic designer who met Young in a <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Anselmo </LOCATION> saloon 10 years ago. `` He'd sit here and say, ` <PERSON> Harry </PERSON>, we've got to have a piano drop. Can you hear it? ... You take an old upright piano about 1,000 feet in the sky ...''' <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON> mused over that, and added fondly, `` ... I think he'll be able to hear it.'' <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON> said a helicopter will drop an inlaid walnut upright from 50 to 100 feet near <LOCATION> Sonoma </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION>. `` It's an arrogant, outrageous, playful, childish thing to do,'' said <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON>. `` That embodies J.C.'' About four hours after the smash, the celebration will turn to a more sedate mood with food, drink and music in <LOCATION> Marin </LOCATION>. Friends said the sendoff fits in with <PERSON> Young </PERSON>'s life. He once drove a motorcycle into a bar and ordered a beer with an olive. However, <PERSON> Young </PERSON> was far from a clown. He had a master's degree in mathematics, and often dragged bar patrons into conversations about negative numbers and mind-twisting theorems. His death was as unusual as his life. His body was discovered in his black Cadillac in a ravine below a steep highway near <LOCATION> Stinson </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION>. Authorities said he may have been beaten to death. `` He was full of life and I miss him,'' said real estate broker <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Catlett </PERSON>, who met young in a bar in <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION> in 1972.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880519-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-19-88 0150EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Autos-Future     05-19 0724</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Autos-Future,0744</SECOND>
<HEAD>Automakers' Crash Diets Leading To Lasting Changes</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By JANET BRAUNSTEIN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Auto Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>DETROIT (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Big Three automakers are replacing their crash diets of the early'80s with more lasting changes to prepare for challenge of the next decade: overproduction. By 1990 there could be 5.6 million more new cars and trucks than buyers worldwide, according to industry estimates. `` First, obviously, cost-cutting was the major concern ... But in the long term it's the products they're coming out with'' that will determine who survives, said <PERSON> Kathleen </PERSON> <PERSON> Heaney </PERSON>, an analyst with <ORGANIZATION> Nikko </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Securities </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>. Having modernized their factories and corporate structures, the Big Three are marshaling their resources with the aim of making American cars that are better engineered and sell like Japanese cars. The dollar's slide against the Japanese yen and <LOCATION> European </LOCATION> currencies two years ago has made some imports more expensive and temporarily helped level the playing field for <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Motors </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Motor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Chrysler </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp </ORGANIZATION>. So has a new <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Auto </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Workers </ORGANIZATION> pattern contract that stresses job security over wage increases and gives the companies needed flexibility. The auto industry tumult of the past 15 years _ fuel crises, a recession and the shock of Japanese entry _ has given way to a more stable market where winners and losers no longer are determined by national origin. <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION>, losing $ 1 million a day at the beginning of the decade, has made big adjustments already, closing excess plants and running the rest on overtime while grabbing styling leadership from <ORGANIZATION> GM </ORGANIZATION> with a sleek, aerodynamic new lineup. `` People who go into a <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> dealership have a car in mind. They say ` I want that Thunderbird, Taurus, <ORGANIZATION> Continental </ORGANIZATION>','' <PERSON> Heaney </PERSON> said. `` People are not doing that for <ORGANIZATION> GM </ORGANIZATION>. ... They're going to a <ORGANIZATION> GM </ORGANIZATION> dealer and saying: ` I've got $ 13,000. What can I get?''' <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> led <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> automakers in earnings in 1986 and went on to set the world auto industry record with $ 4.6 billion in 1987 profits and again with $ 1.6 billion in earnings in the first quarter of 1988. It also has a comfortable $ 10 billion cash cushion it is saving for a major electronics acquisition. At its annual meeting last week, <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Petersen </PERSON> said the second largest <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> automaker has no intention of giving up its edge and will substantially increase spending on new product development over the next few years. <ORGANIZATION> Chrysler </ORGANIZATION>, under Chairman <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Iacocca </PERSON>, also has switched its focus from trimming costs to investing in new products. <ORGANIZATION> Chrysler </ORGANIZATION> had been shedding weight gained in its August acquisition of ailing <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Motors </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>. After squeezing more Jeeps out of a former <ORGANIZATION> AMC </ORGANIZATION> assembly plant in <LOCATION> Toledo </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Chrysler </ORGANIZATION> decided to close <ORGANIZATION> AMC </ORGANIZATION>'s other <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> assembly plant, in <LOCATION> Kenosha </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wis. </LOCATION>, by year's end It also settled its <ORGANIZATION> UAW </ORGANIZATION> contract five months early, eliminating the chance of a costly strike in September when its factories will be pushing out 1989 models. <ORGANIZATION> Chrysler </ORGANIZATION>'s strategy of aggressive pricing to gain market share at the expense of immediate profits has boosted sales during 1988, including a 72 percent jump for Jeeps and a 55 percent increase for minivans. <PERSON> Iacocca </PERSON>, who faces his shareholders Thursday in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, already has injected extra money into research and development for new models and advanced engineering this year and plans more. <ORGANIZATION> GM </ORGANIZATION>, which spent $ 50 billion since the early 1980s to modernize or replace its factories, is also channeling resources into new product development, but analysts say it has more problems to solve. The world's largest automaker is barely breaking even on its <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> car and truck business despite cost-cutting, which may make additional plant closings necessary. Analysts also question Chairman <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>'s pledge to regain lost market share. To move eight points to 45 percent of the market, <ORGANIZATION> GM </ORGANIZATION> would have to increase sales by at least 1.2 million cars and trucks a year. <ORGANIZATION> GM </ORGANIZATION> lost market share in 1986 to <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Chrysler </ORGANIZATION> as well as to foreign makers. And the field of competitors only grows thicker. <ORGANIZATION> Mazda </ORGANIZATION>, which joined the ranks of Japanese makers with <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> plants, has sold out its <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION> plant's production through October. <ORGANIZATION> Toyota </ORGANIZATION>'s huge <LOCATION> Kentucky </LOCATION> plant will begin making Camry sedans this summer and a Chrysler-Mitsubishi plant in <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> soon will be churning out sporty 1989 models.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880519-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-19-88 0151EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-EconomicAnxiety     05-19 0769</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Economic Anxiety,0793</SECOND>
<HEAD>Why The Seers Say `Bah, Humbug' To Strong Economy</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</NOTE>
<HEAD>An AP News Analysis</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN CUNNIFF</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Business Analyst</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 When the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> trade deficit for March improved beyond all expectations, many economists and big investors responded with a chorus of `` Bah, humbug.'' Funny they should pan what would seem like fabulous news. But they've done it before and most likely they'll do it again. They responded that way to news of a lower jobless rate, to increases in factory use, even to the dollar's new stability. It is a strange, discomfiting world in which good is bad, happy is sad, up is down, square is round, best is worst, last is first, strong is weak, bottom is peak, rich is poor and less is more. And if the sages are being spooked by the `` good'' news _ news for which they've waited months and which they deemed necessary for economic survival _ it's no wonder they're exaggerating `` bad'' news, of which they've found plenty. Late last year, for instance, the pessimists said consumers would reduce spending, forcing the economy into recession. It did n't happen. Then they said an inventory glut might produce recession in 1988. But the glut disappeared. `` It is ironic that the pessimistic crowd see a boom just as bloated inventories are starting to cool things off,'' said economist <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Yardeni </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Prudential-Bache </ORGANIZATION> investment firm, who fears neither a boom nor a bust. Throughout, there has been wide disagreements among economists, some of whom believed the biggest threat was from recession, others that inflation would turn out to be the big problem. Whatever the interpretation, however, the conclusion has been the same, i.e., bad news. If the economy expanded it would strain production facilities and produce inflation. Should expansion cease, recession would follow. The dramatic improvement in the nation's trade deficit _ a $ 4 billion reduction to $ 9.7 billion in March _ provides the most vivid example of the syndrome. Nothing economic has been more eagerly awaited in recent months, since a shrinkage of the deficit means <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> goods, especially manufactured items, are becoming more competitive abroad. In fact, many economists and investors made the latest trade figures the fulcrum of their analyses. When the deficit grew in February, the stock market plunged. Would a gain in March make the market rise? It did n't happen. Once again the news, though opposite to that of February, produced a negative reaction. Both the bond and stock markets interpreted the news as indicative of an economy about to overheat and produce inflation. `` It seems the better things get, the worse they're going to be,'' quipped <PERSON> Malcolm </PERSON> <PERSON> Forbes </PERSON>, the publisher, who was addressing a business luncheon group shortly after hearing the news. Why the mood? Economists themselves have been asking that question, and most have defended their positions with data and theories that to the layman seem thorough, reasonable and even sagacious. While recognizing that pessimism may be justified _ and that inflation, high interest rates and perhaps recession lie ahead _ some economists believe there is a large psychological element involved. In fact, with so many disproportions and dislocations in the economy _ big budget and trade deficits, uncollectable Third World loans, and the crash of the securities markets in October _ no matter how poor or inaccurate an analysis might be, a negative forecast stands a chance of being correct. There are also the awful memories of the 1970s to contend with. Economists back then could n't believe what was happening _ that inflation and interest rates were not just high but in the double digits. They can not forget. And, finally, anxiety is produced by the very expansion itself. Now in its 66th month, it has lived far beyond the usual lifespan of expansions, and inevitably will turn down. But when? And will inflation or recession end it? <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Erich </PERSON> <PERSON> Heinemann </PERSON>, chief economist for <ORGANIZATION> Ladenburg </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> , </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Thalmann </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ; </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, a securities broker-dealer, remains optimistic, at least about inflation. He notes that major inflation indicators rose less in the first quarter of 1988 than in the final quarter of 1987. His forecast contrasts with that of most economists. `` We're convinced that with just a little bit of luck, the expansion could continue into 1991 or 1992,'' he says, adding the caveat: `` However, this will be a respite, not a reprieve. If <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> can not deal with its problems -LRB- mainly the budget deficit -RRB-, we will all have to live with the consequences.''
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 EDITOR'S NOTE: <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Cunniff </PERSON> has covered business and economic issues for <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> since 1964.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880519-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-19-88 0154EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-HastingsProfile     05-19 0490</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Hastings Profile,0503</SECOND>
<HEAD>Hastings Takes Fighting Image To Impeachment Hearings</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Hastings-Impeach, Bjt</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By JAMES MARTINEZ</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MIAMI (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> Alcee </PERSON> <PERSON> Hastings </PERSON> and his supporters see him as a courageous, outspoken fighter now taking unfair shots from those who can not accept him as the first black federal judge in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Hastings </PERSON>, whose impeachment hearing began Wednesday in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, has been battling bribery and conspiracy charges for the last seven years. But he has remained a popular figure in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>'s black community, which has held impassioned demonstrations in his support and contributed $ 65,000 to his legal defense. `` He's never been the kind to back down from a fight; he's had to pull himself up from his bootstraps from day one,'' said Dr. <PERSON> Gordon </PERSON> <PERSON> Merritt </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lauderdale </LOCATION> dentist and longtime friend who helped raise funds for <PERSON> Hastings </PERSON>. `` Most federal judges are the placating type, but <PERSON> Alcee </PERSON> speaks out _ he's a maverick.'' The flamboyant <PERSON> Hastings </PERSON> has proclaimed his innocence ever since he was indicted on bribery charges in 1981 and then acquitted two years later. The case did n't end there. Fellow judges accused <PERSON> Hastings </PERSON> of obstructing justice and lying under oath, and issued a report recommending his impeachment. `` I'm not going to be impeached and I'm not going to be removed,'' <PERSON> Hastings </PERSON> said in a recent interview. `` It's pure unadulterated politics.'' <PERSON> Hastings </PERSON>, in sermon-like speeches around the country, has blasted the secret judicial investigation after his acquittal as a `` witchhunt'' and an unconstitutional `` throwback to Star Chamberism.'' He has suggested his race has had something to do with the effort against him, and said he really angered <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> officials with his 1981 rulings blocking deportation of Haitian immigrants. Complaints were filed against him in 1984 for his alleged improper political statements, including harsh criticism of the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration. <PERSON> Hastings </PERSON> said his position on the federal bench does not mean he ca n't speak his mind. `` I do n't have any organized effort,'' said <PERSON> Hastings </PERSON>, who added he has also spent much of his own money. `` It's draining me financially. It's impacting me from an emotional standpoint _ I'm tired from all this mess. His 70-year-old mother <PERSON> Mildred </PERSON>, with whom <PERSON> Hastings </PERSON>, 51, has shared a <LOCATION> Lauderhill </LOCATION> apartment since his second divorce, said her son would come out of the hearings fine and `` he does n't need me to talk for him.'' The only child of a maid and butler in <LOCATION> Altamonte </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Springs </LOCATION>, a small town north of <LOCATION> Orlando </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Hastngs </PERSON> earned his law degree at predominantly black <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> A & amp; <ORGANIZATION> M </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, became a civil rights leader, and ran unsuccessfully for office several times. In 1970, he was the first black man to run for the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> from <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>, but failed to win nomination. He returned to his private law practice, where he did much free work in civil rights cases, until 1979, when President <PERSON> Jimmy </PERSON> <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> appointed him to the federal bench.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880519-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-19-88 0154EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--NorthKorea     05-19 0153</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--North Korea,0155</SECOND>
<HEAD>Korean Students Favor Talks Between North and South</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 More than 50,000 North Korean students attended a rally in that country to support proposed talks between student leaders from north and <LOCATION> south </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>, an official news report said. Students from more than 150 colleges and universities in the <LOCATION> Pyongyang </LOCATION> area attended the rally in a stadium in that capital on Tuesday, according to a report by the north's <ORGANIZATION> Korean </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION>, which was monitored in <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION>. The report said the students formed a preparatory committee for north-south student talks comprised of 30 representatives of different schools. At a rally in <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>, on Saturday, 10,000 students proposed that student leaders from the south and north meet June 10 to discuss national unification and co-hosting of the Olympic Games in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> in September. South Korean officials have said they would not allow such a meeting.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880519-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-19-88 0204EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     05-19 0968</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,1009</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names In The News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>AIKEN, S.C. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Soul music legend <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> spent the night in jail on charges of drug possession and fleeing from police after his wife again complained he was abusing her. The 55-year-old singer, known to fans as the `` Godfather of Soul,'' was charged Wednesday with failure to stop for police, resisting arrest, assault against an officer and illegal possession of a revolver, police said. Later in the day, <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> was charged with possession of the drug PCP after tests on a substance found in his car. Deputies were dispatched to <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>'s <LOCATION> Beech </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> home Wednesday after his wife, <PERSON> Adrienne </PERSON>, went to a neighbor's house and said he was abusing her, said <LOCATION> Aiken </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> Sheriff <PERSON> Carrol </PERSON> <PERSON> Heath </PERSON>. When officers arrived, <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> sped away in his car but was overtaken 1 -LCB- miles away, <PERSON> Heath </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> told officers he was late for an appointment, the sheriff said. A scuffle ensued, but no injuries were reported. <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> remained jailed Wednesday night. On April 4, <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> was charged with assault with the intent to murder, aggravated assault and battery after allegedly beating his wife with a pipe. He also was charged with firing a gun into a car while she was inside.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>BURBANK, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Lisa </PERSON> <PERSON> Bonet </PERSON>, who plays Cosby kid college student in <ORGANIZATION> NBC-TV </ORGANIZATION>'s `` A Different World'' but has raised eyebrows by posing nude, is pregnant, a network spokesman said. Six months ago, Miss <PERSON> Bonet </PERSON> married musician <PERSON> Romeo </PERSON> <PERSON> Blue </PERSON>, also known as <PERSON> Lenny </PERSON> <PERSON> Kravitz </PERSON>. There was no immediate word on how the pregnancy of the 20-year-old actress would affect her role in the series, according to a statement Wednesday from <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Meyers </PERSON>. The show, a spinoff of `` The Cosby Show,'' was rated No. 2 for the season, according to the <ORGANIZATION> A.C. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nielsen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>. During her career on `` The Cosby Show'' and `` A Different World,'' Miss <PERSON> Bonet </PERSON> has raised eyebrows by twice posing nude in magazines and starring in the movie `` Angel Heart,'' which barely escaped an `` X'' rating for its torrid love scenes
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>TORONTO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Conductor <PERSON> Gunther </PERSON> <PERSON> Herbig </PERSON>, saying money problems have cramped his style as music director of the <ORGANIZATION> Detroit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Symphony </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Orchestra </ORGANIZATION>, is heading north to take over the same job with the <LOCATION> Toronto </LOCATION> Symphony. Wednesday's announcement was seen as a serious blow to <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION>'s cultural community and a coup for <LOCATION> Toronto </LOCATION>'s <PERSON> Herbig </PERSON>, 56, has been music director in <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION> since 1984. During that time, he appeared as guest conductor with major orchestras in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. He said lack of money for expansion, recordings and tours led him to leave <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION>, where the orchestra went on strike last year.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>Eds: A version moved on sports wires.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>HIALEAH, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Miami </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dolphins </ORGANIZATION> quarterback <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Marino </PERSON> became a father for the second time when his wife gave birth to a son at <LOCATION> Hialeah </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION>. The healthy boy, born Wednesday, weighed in at 9 pounds, 3 ounces, and measured 21 -LCB- inches, said <PERSON> Eddie </PERSON> <PERSON> White </PERSON>, spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> Dolphins </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Marino </PERSON>, 26, and his wife, <PERSON> Claire </PERSON>, have not yet picked out a name, <PERSON> White </PERSON> said. The baby's big brother, <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Charles </PERSON>, is 20 months old. <PERSON> Marino </PERSON> has been an All-Pro at quarterback each of his five years in the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Football </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> League </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Yankees </ORGANIZATION> second baseman <PERSON> Willie </PERSON> <PERSON> Randolph </PERSON> says he has regular conferences with his kids, while actor-singer <PERSON> Kris </PERSON> <PERSON> Kristofferson </PERSON> modestly claims he only had the good taste to pick the right mothers. Whatever their secrets, the two were among eight men honored Wdnesday as 1988's outstanding fathers by the National Father's Day Committee. <PERSON> Randolph </PERSON>, who spends half the baseball season on the road, says he has to work at keeping communication lines open with his four children. `` We have conferences,'' <PERSON> Randolph </PERSON> said. `` We dim the lights and just talk. You'd be amazed at the off-the-wall stuff. They can say whatever they want.'' <PERSON> Kristofferson </PERSON>, who has six children by three wives and three adopted Salvadoran orphans, said, `` I had the good taste to select mothers who would raise them. All I've done is love them.'' Apparently love was enough, because all nine children now live with him and his current wife, <PERSON> Lisa </PERSON>, at their <LOCATION> Malibu </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, home. Other fathers honored were <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> correspondent <PERSON> Chris </PERSON> <PERSON> Wallace </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> Director <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Sessions </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Fox </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Television </ORGANIZATION> sportscaster <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Mazer </PERSON>, Tennis Hall of Famer <PERSON> Arthur </PERSON> <PERSON> Ashe </PERSON>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> police officer <PERSON> Steven </PERSON> <PERSON> McDonald </PERSON>, who was left paralyzed in a shooting, and broadcast personality <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> King </PERSON>. Father's Day is June 19th.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>GRAND FORKS, N.D. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 To journalist <PERSON> Rick </PERSON> <PERSON> Reilly </PERSON>, <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION> conjurs up images of `` desolation, tundra, one two-lane highway.'' But movie reviewer <PERSON> Judith </PERSON> <PERSON> Crist </PERSON> says she thinks of a state full of `` bright, no-nonsense people.'' <PERSON> Reilly </PERSON>, a writer for Sports Illustrated, and <PERSON> Crist </PERSON>, a reviewer for TV Guide, were among notables who responded recently to a questionnaire about <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION> sent by the tiny senior class of <ORGANIZATION> Willow </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> High </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION>. The eight seniors were miffed when <PERSON> Kellye </PERSON> <PERSON> Cash </PERSON> said her Miss America 1987 title gave her the chance to visit places `` you never thought people actually lived _ like <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION>.'' So they decided to find out what other celebrities thought of <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION>. `` It's fun to see what other people's impressions are, but I do n't think it changed -LRB- the class members' -RRB- minds,'' said their teacher, <PERSON> Peggy </PERSON> <PERSON> Gregg </PERSON>. `` They're all proud to live in <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION>.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>PALM SPRINGS, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Congressman <PERSON> Nick </PERSON> <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Rahall </PERSON> has pleaded guilty to reduced charges stemming from a drunken driving arrest, the city district attorney's office said. <PERSON> Rahall </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> Democrat, was arrested Jan. 14 after giving a speech to the <ORGANIZATION> Tobacco </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> near this resort community. He opted for the reduced charges at a pretrial conference Wednesday.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880519-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-19-88 0025EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p AM-Jackson-Threat 6thLd-Writethru a0994 05-19 1019</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Jackson-Threat, 6th Ld-Writethru, a0994,980</SECOND>
<HEAD>Authorities Search Background of Missouri Couple Charged in
Jackson Threat</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDs: SUBS 12th graf pvs, bgng: Jail officials, with 2 grafs to
UPDATE with more Williams comment in newspaper interview</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By ED SCHAFER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ST. LOUIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Federal law officers searched Wednesday for any `` shred of evidence'' that might link a <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION> couple charged with plotting to kill presidential candidate <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> to violent white supremacist groups. <PERSON> Londell </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>, 30, and his wife, <PERSON> Tammy </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>, 26, of <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mo. </LOCATION>, were in custody on charges of conspiring to kill <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, threatening an informer and possessing an automatic rifle. A Secret Service agent testified at a hearing Tuesday that agents had taped a conversation in which <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> said the Covenant, the Sword and the Arm of the Lord was planning the assassination of <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>. `` We are out seeking every shred of evidence and talking to every person we can who might know something,'' <PERSON> Rich </PERSON> <PERSON> Adams </PERSON>, a spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> Secret </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, said Wednesday. The Secret Service is responsible for protecting <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>. Meanwhile, the <ORGANIZATION> Secret </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> on Wednesday found a bullet under a seat in the <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> campaign plane. But <PERSON> Adams </PERSON> later said it was determined the 9mm bullet belonged to the Secret Service. `` It's one of ours,'' he said <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, campaigning in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, suggested that comments by some public officials had helped set the stage for the alleged plot against him. He was apparently referring to strong criticism of him during the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> primary campaign by <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> Mayor <PERSON> Ed </PERSON> <PERSON> Koch </PERSON>, who at one point said Jews would have to be `` crazy'' to vote for <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>. `` The climate for this kind of antagonism and violence, of course, has been set by many irresponsible public leaders -LRB- whose -RRB- attacks based on race have set a divisive and dangerous climate, such as the one ... in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> in April, for example,'' <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> told reporters in <LOCATION> Fresno </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Den </PERSON> <PERSON> Ouden </PERSON>, the agent in charge of the <LOCATION> Springfield </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mo. </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> office, located in an area that has become known for attracting members of extremist groups, said he had done some checking into the Williamses background and found no evidence the pair belonged to The Order or CSA Papers filed in federal court indicated <PERSON> Londell </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> told an informer that he was a member of The Order and other white supremacist groups and that <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> was to be killed. A <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Louis </LOCATION> television station, <ORGANIZATION> KSDK </ORGANIZATION>, reported that <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> had telephoned from jail on Wednesday to say he had not been involved in any plot against the Democratic presidential contender. `` I did not conspire to kill the man,'' the station quoted <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> as saying. `` If <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> makes it to the presidency, well, fine.'' And in an interview with the <LOCATION> Belleville </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Ill. </LOCATION> -RRB- News-Democrat, published in Thursday's editions, <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> admitted he is a racist but said he is not affiliated with any group. `` If there was a crime done, I've done it all on my own,'' he told the newspaper in a telephone interview from jail on Wednesday. `` I deny that there is a crime done. I did not conspire with anyone to kill any presidential candidate, especially <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>. `` I do have prejudices ... against anything that is n't white,'' he added. Lawyers for the couple said each denied belonging to a white supremacist group. And after the hearing Tuesday, Mrs. <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> said as she was escorted out of the courtroom: `` We're not part of the CSA.'' According to the criminal complaint filed in <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>, an unidentified person contacted the <LOCATION> Franklin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> sheriff's office earlier this month, claiming that the <ORGANIZATION> Williamses </ORGANIZATION> were conspiring to assassinate <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>. The information was relayed to the <ORGANIZATION> Secret </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> and agents met with the informant, who agreed to wear a hidden microphone and meet again May 10 with <PERSON> Londell </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>, this time with law enforcement officials listening in, the complaint said. The complaint said the informant later received a death threat from the <ORGANIZATION> Williamses </ORGANIZATION> for informing on them. At the hearing, <ORGANIZATION> Secret </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> agent <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Christopher </PERSON> <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON> testified that the informant led sheriff's deputies to a wooded area in <LOCATION> Franklin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> where they found an AR-15 Colt semi-automatic rifle and a bag the informant said belonged to the <ORGANIZATION> Williamses </ORGANIZATION>. The complaint said the bag contained a postcard addressed to <PERSON> Londell </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> and maps, one of which had his fingerprints. The rifle had been reported stolen from <LOCATION> Springfield </LOCATION>, according to the agent. <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON> said that during the recorded conversation with the informant, <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> said he wanted to get the rifle back because it had been issued to him by the CSA. <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> also said the organization wanted it returned because it had been used to kill a law enforcement officer, <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON> said that the informant brought up the assassination plot during the conversation and <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> said `` the <ORGANIZATION> CSA </ORGANIZATION> was planning to assassinate candidate <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> on the Fourth of July.'' <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON> said that after the <PERSON> Williamses </PERSON> were arrested, <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> told authorities about the individual who provided him with the rifle and also made statements about a plan to kill <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>. <ORGANIZATION> Secret </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> agent <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Northcutt </PERSON> testified that he had interviewed Ms. <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> after her arrest. At that time, she said she was present when her husband discussed the CSA and other groups. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, who is seeking the Democratic presidential nomination and has been the target of hundreds of death threats in his 1984 and 1988 campaigns, said Wednesday he would not be deterred. `` We will not surrender to the dream-busters,'' <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> said in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>. `` The Secret Service will handle the dream-busters, and I will keep -LRB- articulating -RRB- the dream and keep hope alive.'' The Williamses were being held without bond in the federal detention facility in <LOCATION> Belleville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ill. </LOCATION>, across the <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> from <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Louis </LOCATION>. Records in <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Circuit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> show <PERSON> Londell </PERSON> and <PERSON> Tammy </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> were both arrested in Ozark Dec. 7, 1986. He was charged with unlawful use of a weapon and she was charged with possession of marijuana. Both ended up serving short sentences in the <LOCATION> Christian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> jail and are on probation, according to records.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880519-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-19-88 0154EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF-Ethiopia-War     05-19 0171</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF-Ethiopia-War,0175</SECOND>
<HEAD>Ethiopians To Pay Month's Salary To Finance Attack On Rebels</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ADDIS ABABA, Ethiopia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 All adult Ethiopians, including pensioners and nationals living abroad, have been ordered to pay the government one month's salary to help finance an offensive against two rebel groups. A special decree, signed by President <PERSON> Mengistu </PERSON> <PERSON> Haile </PERSON> <PERSON> Mariam </PERSON> on Tuesday, said the government also will levy a war tax on private enterprises. The decree, described by a <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> statement on Wednesday, did not say how much money would be raised or when the offensive would be launched. According to the <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Ethiopia </LOCATION>'s 42.2 million people are among the world's poorest with a per capita annual income of $ 120. During the 1984-85 famine, which killed an estimated 1 million Ethiopians, <ORGANIZATION> Mengistu </ORGANIZATION> imposed a similar tax for drought relief. The offensive will be launched against the <ORGANIZATION> Eritrean </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Tigrean </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION>, two northern rebel groups that have been fighting for a separate homeland for more than 14 years
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880519-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-19-88 0030EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-UniversityPresident     05-19 0242</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-University President,0249</SECOND>
<HEAD>Candidate Back In After Plagiarism Apology</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MINNEAPOLIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An educator who acknowledged using plagiarism in his bid to become president of <ORGANIZATION> North </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dakota </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> said Wednesday he has accepted a request to renew his candidacy. <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Minnesota </ORGANIZATION> interim President <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Sauer </PERSON> withdrew as a candidate earlier this month after he admitted lifting part of a presentation for the <ORGANIZATION> NDSU </ORGANIZATION> job from a magazine article without crediting it. He said Wednesday night that <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Richardson </PERSON>, <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION>'s commissioner of higher education, asked him Wednesday afternoon to again become a candidate for the position `` I think I have something to offer, I think I can do that job and I'm interested in it,'' <PERSON> Sauer </PERSON>, 48, said when asked why he accepted the offer. <PERSON> Richardson </PERSON> said he first asked <PERSON> Sauer </PERSON> Tuesday to resubmit his name at the behest of the higher education board. He would not comment on why the board members wanted to consider <PERSON> Sauer </PERSON>. Board President <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Pfister </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Wahpeton </LOCATION> could not be reached for comment Wednesday night. <PERSON> Richardson </PERSON> said the action merely follows the original recommendation of the president's search committee, which put forth <PERSON> Sauer </PERSON>'s name as a possible candidate even though it knew of the plagiarism allegations against him. <PERSON> Sauer </PERSON> will be interviewed by the board Sunday night at <ORGANIZATION> NDSU </ORGANIZATION>, the higher education commissioner said. <PERSON> Sauer </PERSON> last week apologized to the Univesity of <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION> Regents, and they gave him a unanimous vote of confidence.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880519-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-19-88 0211EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-HospitalCost     05-19 0209</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Hospital Cost,0214</SECOND>
<HEAD>Admission Review Can Cut Hospital Costs 8 Percent</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BOSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Insurance companies can cut medical expenses 8 percent if they require people to get approval from a review board before being treated in the hospital, says a study published today. Such `` utilization review'' progams are intended to hold down medical expenses by checking to make sure hospitalization is necessary. The study found that the controls save money, although it did not determine whether they have any effect on health. Utilization review programs generally require that hospital admissions be approved by a review panel before or at the time of admission. The study, directed by Dr. <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Feldstein </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION> at <LOCATION> Irvine </LOCATION>, was published in the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> England </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Journal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medicine </ORGANIZATION> and was based on a review of 222 groups of employees and dependents who were covered by a large private insurance company that required utilization review. The study concluded that utilization review reduced hospital admissions by 12 percent and total medical expenditures by 8 percent. For a typical company with 1,000 employees, this could mean saving $ 636,000 over five years, the study said. For a similar company with a high rate of hospital use, the savings could total $ 2.2 million.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880519-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-19-88 0232EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-TVRules Bjt   05-19 0684</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-TV Rules, Bjt,680</SECOND>
<HEAD>`Massive Blackouts' on Cable TV Predicted from New Policy</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DEBORAH MESCE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The nation's cable television subscribers will face `` massive blackouts'' in service under a new federal policy allowing local stations to buy exclusive rights to syndicated programs, cable industry officials say. Under the policy approved 3-0 by the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Communications </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> on Wednesday, cable TV systems that broadcast the same programs in a local station's viewing area will have to black out the shows or substitute other programs. Some in the cable industry are predicting dark screens and the demise of some TV superstations as a result. <PERSON> Ted </PERSON> <PERSON> Turner </PERSON>, chairman of <ORGANIZATION> Turner </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Broadcasting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, which owns nationally distributed <ORGANIZATION> WTBS </ORGANIZATION>, said the new rules `` do not give the cable industry a realistic chance to avoid massive blackouts.'' <ORGANIZATION> FCC </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Dennis </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Patrick </PERSON> said the new rules will result in less duplication of programs and will provide an incentive to produce new programs. `` Blackouts will only occur if cable operators seek to cause turmoil for short-term political advantage, which I can not believe they will do,'' he said. The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cable </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Television </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> said it will challenge the rules in court. `` The <ORGANIZATION> FCC </ORGANIZATION> pulled the plug on the favorite TV programs of millions of people,'' <ORGANIZATION> NCTA </ORGANIZATION> President <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Mooney </PERSON> said. `` People whose favorite programs disappear will be angered and bewildered'' and the cost of syndicated programming will rise, he added. The rules will likely reduce how often TV viewers can see syndicated reruns of shows like `` M-A-S-H,'' `` Taxi'' and `` My Three Sons.'' A cable subscriber now can see one of these shows several times a day if it is aired by a local broadcaster and by out-of-town superstations whose signals are carried by the local cable operator. `` The rule of reruns is what prevails today,'' <PERSON> Patrick </PERSON> said. He said that by giving broadcasters a measure of programming protection, the rules will increase the value of their programs to advertisers. More ad revenue, in turn, will foster production of new programs, he said. In addition, cable systems will be forced to be come up with more programming, he said. He also said cable systems should not have to resort to blackouts to comply with the rules because of a one-year transition period, a variety of exceptions that will be allowed and the amount of substitute programming that is available, <PERSON> Patrick </PERSON> said. But the cable industry expects that at least some screens will go dark and that some of the smaller TV superstations may return to being just local stations. That view was expressed by <PERSON> Jeff </PERSON> <PERSON> Treeman </PERSON>, senior vice president of <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Video </ORGANIZATION>, the <LOCATION> Tulsa </LOCATION>, Okla.-based cable carrier that distributes superstation signals including WGN. He said cable systems in some large markets, where independents can afford to buy exclusive rights to programming, may have to black out or substitute shows for as much as 40 percent of a superstation's programming `` That's enough for the cable operator to drop the signal,'' he said. Similar rules were dropped by the <ORGANIZATION> FCC </ORGANIZATION> in 1980. Since then, cable systems have been able to carry the signals of out-of-town stations such as <ORGANIZATION> WTBS </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> WWOR </ORGANIZATION> in the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> area and <ORGANIZATION> WGN </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>, which have become known as superstations, even when those stations transmit programs whose rights were bought by a local TV station. Superstations also have become popular for the local sporting events they carry. Under the new exclusivity rules, TV stations will be able to negotiate for exclusive rights to a syndicated program and will be able to force a cable system to honor that contract by blacking out that show when it is aired by a superstation on the system. The rules also allow broadcasters to negotiate rights with cable systems. Superstations also will be able to buy exclusive rights for syndicated shows on a nationwide basis. The rules wo n't apply to cable systems with fewer than 1,000 subscribers. About half of all cable systems fall into this category, though they serve only about 5 percent of the nation's 45 million cable subscribers, the <ORGANIZATION> FCC </ORGANIZATION> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880519-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-19-88 0239EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-LandTrade     05-19 0620</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Land Trade,610</SECOND>
<HEAD>House Committee Approves Swap Of Downtown Real Estate For
Swampland</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID GOELLER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Leaders of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Interior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> are split over whether a proposed swap of 92.5 U.S.-owned acres in downtown <LOCATION> Phoenix </LOCATION> for 118,000 acres of swampland in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> is fair to taxpayers, but the committee approved the arrangement. `` This is a good deal ... everybody wins,'' says longtime <ORGANIZATION> Interior </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Morris </PERSON> <PERSON> Udall </PERSON>, D-Ariz., who helped put the proposal together Strongly disagreeing is Rep. <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Miller </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Calif </LOCATION>., an Interior subcommittee chairman who is first in line to eventually succeed <PERSON> Udall </PERSON> as chairman and who normally is aligned with <PERSON> Udall </PERSON> on issues before the panel <PERSON> Miller </PERSON> says the deal could find taxpayers trading the <LOCATION> Phoenix </LOCATION> acreage for `` a bargain basement price'' because nobody knows just how much the property will be worth when it is rezoned for commercial development. <PERSON> Udall </PERSON> on Wednesday had the clout that normally flows to a chairman, easily winning voice-vote approval for legislation authorizing completion of what <PERSON> Miller </PERSON> says would be the biggest interstate land trade in <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> history. The proposed deal involves the 104-acre site that now houses the <ORGANIZATION> Phoenix </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Indian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION>, a federal facility that is slated to close next month. <PERSON> Miller </PERSON> says the property is one of the most valuable undeveloped urban tracts in the West. An <ORGANIZATION> Interior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> appraisal values the parcel at $ 122 million. On the <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> end are 118,000 acres owned by the <PERSON> Collier </PERSON> family, although <PERSON> Miller </PERSON> says that 4,236 of them are under tidal water and possibly owned by the state of <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>. This land would be used to enlarge the Big Cypress National Preserve and the <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> panther refuge in the southwest part of the state, but the government would not own the subsurface mineral rights. The deal worked out by the <ORGANIZATION> Interior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> and the <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION> congressional delegation values the <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> land at $ 45.1 million. The proposal also calls for the <PERSON> Collier </PERSON> family to pay the government $ 34.9 million. Under the plan, the Colliers would get 68 of the 104 acres in <LOCATION> Phoenix </LOCATION>. The city of <LOCATION> Phoenix </LOCATION> would be given 20 acres for a park and the <ORGANIZATION> Veterans </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> 11.5 to expand a hospital, with the state of <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION> possibly getting the other 4.5 acres. <PERSON> Miller </PERSON> challenged the appraisal on the <LOCATION> Phoenix </LOCATION> property, citing a report by the congressional <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Accounting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> that says the real value of the land wo n't be known until the 68 acres are rezoned for commercial use. By a 36-3 vote, he lost an attempt to amend the bill to delay completion of the deal until after <LOCATION> Phoenix </LOCATION> substantially completed the rezoning process, new appraisals were submitted to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION> ruled that what the government was getting was equal to what it was trading away. `` My intention is to make this exchange look a little more like a business transaction,'' <PERSON> Miller </PERSON> said. `` We owe this to the taxpayers. ... There is no private individual who would get rid of these lands under these circumstances.'' <PERSON> Udall </PERSON> and other supporters argued that the legislation could bring a higher price for the 68 acres because it requires the tract to be offered to the highest bidder once rezoning is completed. Under the plan, the <ORGANIZATION> Colliers </ORGANIZATION> could get the land by matching the high bid. <PERSON> Miller </PERSON> said, however, that there is little likelihood another buyer could quickly put together the financial package to satisfy the bill's requirement that the buyer pay cash for the property within 30 days of the bidding. Defending the legislation, Rep. <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Young </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Alaska </LOCATION>, said that `` it's a good package for what we're all trying to do. Forget the value of the <LOCATION> Phoenix </LOCATION> land. ... We're not in the moneymaking business.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880519-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-19-88 0240EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-CheckCashing     05-19 0421</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Check Cashing,420</SECOND>
<HEAD>Poor, Elderly Would Cash Government Checks At Any Bank Under
Proposal</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TOM SEPPY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Banks should be required to cash government checks for the elderly and the poor even if they have no accounts with the financial institutions, an advocacy group told lawmakers. <PERSON> Peggy </PERSON> <PERSON> Miller </PERSON>, representing the <ORGANIZATION> Consumer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION>, told a <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> subcommittee on Wednesday that people on Social Security and welfare would be willing to pay a fee of $ 2 for the check cashing service by banks, even though legislation does not call for it. Ms. <PERSON> Miller </PERSON> provided the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Banking </ORGANIZATION> subcommittee on consumer affairs with statistics showing that check cashing outlets, including liquor stores, often charge exorbitant fees for the service because of the unwillingness of banks to provide it. She said check cashing outlets and unlicensed community locations often charge as high as 20 percent to 30 percent for personal checks, 10 percent for money orders and 6 percent for government checks. `` They can do so because they are vendors of last resort,'' she said. `` Many of their customers, including our elderly, have no where else to go.'' Ms. <PERSON> Miller </PERSON> said her group supported legislation introduced in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> by Sen. <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> <PERSON> Metzenbaum </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Ohio </LOCATION>, and in the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> by Rep. <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Schumer </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.Y. </LOCATION>, which would require banks to cash government checks of customers with no accounts once their identification has been verified. August <PERSON> Zinsser </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>, representing the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bankers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, told the committee that the legislation would subject banks to large fraud losses and `` is premature, inappropriate and unfair to depository institutions.'' Proponents of the legislation, including Ms. <PERSON> Miller </PERSON>, denied that fraud would be a problem. Ms. <PERSON> Miller </PERSON> said currently 54,000 government checks out of 482 million are forged each year. `` This represents less than the normal bounce level of all checks cashed in banks,'' she said. Another witness, assistant Comptroller General <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Fogel </PERSON>, released a prelimary report done by the <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Accounting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> which indicates that Social Security and welfare recipients in the nation's urban areas have the most difficulty cashing their government checks in banks where they have no accounts. He said: `` The unbanked population of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> is at the lower end of the income scale, relies relatively heavily on government benefit programs, includes a significant percentage of the unemployed, and most have 12 years or less of education. `` Some individuals do not have depository accounts and are not able to cash their checks at local banks or thrifts,'' <PERSON> Fogel </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880519-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-19-88 0248EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-PovertyPrograms     05-19 0614</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Poverty Programs,620</SECOND>
<HEAD>Study Says Higher Standards Needed To Improve State `Safety Nets'</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By NANCY BENAC</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The federal government needs to set higher standards for state poverty programs so that the assistance available to poor people wo n't vary so widely from state to state, a private research group says. At the same time, states need to do more on their own to improve programs for the disadvantaged, said the Center on Budget and Policy Priorities. The center, which analyzes government spending and its impact on the poor from a liberal perspective, reported Wednesday that most states fail to provide adequate `` safety nets'' for the poor. The center's report, `` Holes in the <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nets </ORGANIZATION>,'' found broad differences among the states in the quality of assistance provided to the poor. It concluded that shortcomings exist in all regions of the country and even in some states with sound economies and above-average personal income. `` The extent of variations in state poverty policies makes a strong case for an enhanced federal role, both in setting standards and providing funds,'' the researchers said. `` Assistance to many poor families would not then depend so much on where in this nation they happen to live.'' But center Director <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Greenstein </PERSON> said that because budget constraints probably will prevent sweeping changes at the federal level, `` we believe that the principal choices made in determining the quality of the state safety nets are likely to be those made in each state capital.'' `` To narrow some of these holes in the safety net, state action is crucial,'' he said. The center studied government programs that provide cash, medical and other assistance to the poor, and found that none of the states nor the <LOCATION> District </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION> met all 10 standards in a `` reasonable adequacy'' test developed by the center. Twenty-nine states meet three or fewer of the criteria, including <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, which meet none; just 14 states meet more than half the criteria, including <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION>, which did the best by meeting nine of the 10. The study found, for example: _ In 32 states, maximum benefits from Aid to Families with Dependent Children are below half the poverty line for a family of three with no other income _ Twenty-eight states impose state income taxes on working families living below the poverty line, and 10 tax the income of families living below half the poverty line _ In 26 states, fewer than one in three jobless workers received unemployment insurance in an average month in 1986 <PERSON> Greenstein </PERSON> told reporters that some of the states that are the most stingy with benefits `` turn around and extract significant amounts of the income of poor families through the tax system in their states.'' He said that because the assistance gaps are present in all regions of the country and in states with both low and high personal income, `` this indicates that really you're talking about political questions'' in determining benefits. `` I think what you're seeing reflected ... on the most part is the political weakness ... of low-income families,'' <PERSON> Greenstein </PERSON> said. Here is a breakdown of which states met how many standards in the 10-point adequacy test: _ Zero: <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> _ One: <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION> _ Two: <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Arkansas </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Kentucky </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION> _ Three: <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> _ Four: <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Delaware </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> _ Five: <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION> _ Six: <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> _ Seven: <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Vermont </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION> _ Eight: <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Rhode </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> _ Nine: <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION>
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880519-0025 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-19-88 0624EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Meese Bjt   05-19 0586</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Meese, Bjt,580</SECOND>
