<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880421-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-21-88 2337EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-Meese-Reagan Advisory   04-21 0032</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Meese-Reagan, Advisory,</SECOND>
<HEAD>URGENT</HEAD>
<HEAD>EDITORS: Upcoming within 10 minutes is a 2nd Ld-Writethru to
AM-Meese-Reagan, a0401, saying Weld laid out in meeting
incriminating evidence against Meese, Justice Department
no-comment.</HEAD>
<HEAD>The AP</HEAD>
<TEXT>

</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880421-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-21-88 2348EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Hijack 4thLd-Writethru a0899 04-21 0883</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Hijack, 4th Ld - Writethru, a0899,0906</SECOND>
<HEAD>Former Hostages Return Home to Kuwait</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: LEADS with 3 grafs to UPDATE with report hijackers flown to
Damascus, then went over land to Beirut. Picks up 2nd graf pvs,
`The emir ...</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By ALY MAHMOUD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>KUWAIT (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Hostages freed in <LOCATION> Algiers </LOCATION> from a hijacked <ORGANIZATION> Kuwait </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airways </ORGANIZATION> jet came home Thursday to a tumultuous reception by thousands of people after being released by nine <ORGANIZATION> Shiite </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Moslem </ORGANIZATION> gunmen, who slipped away. Western diplomatic sources said they had clear evidence the hijackers had reached <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> after Algerian officials allowed them to go free, ending the 15-day siege. In its Friday editions, <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> quoted unnamed Arab officials as saying the hijackers had been flown on a private Algerian jet to <LOCATION> Damascus </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION> and were believed to have then traveled over land to <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>. The emir of <LOCATION> Kuwait </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Sheik </PERSON> <PERSON> Jaber </PERSON> <PERSON> al-Ahmed </PERSON> <PERSON> Al-Sabah </PERSON>, and Crown Prince <PERSON> Sheik </PERSON> <PERSON> Saad </PERSON> <PERSON> Abdullah </PERSON> <PERSON> Al-Sabah </PERSON> led a group of government officials and relatives who were at the <LOCATION> Kuwait </LOCATION> airport to meet the former captives. Flocks of doves soared over the airport as the <ORGANIZATION> Kuwait </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airways </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> 707 carrying the 22 passengers and seven crew members touched down Thursday night after a six-hour flight from <LOCATION> Algiers </LOCATION>. Two other hostages released early Wednesday were Saudi Arabian citizens and were flown home in a private executive jet. Bedouin men danced and clapped at the Kuwaiti airport, and children waved flags and sang, `` God bless our father, <PERSON> Jaber </PERSON>,'' referring to the emir. The Kuwaiti passengers traveled by motorcade to the city center. Thousands of people lining the route, tossing roses and confetti. Hundreds of others followed in cars and limousines, honking their horns and singing, `` We sacrifice blood and souls for you, O <LOCATION> Kuwait </LOCATION>.'' The gunmen, who killed two hostages while the hijacked jumbo jet was in <LOCATION> Cyprus </LOCATION> last week, disappeared before dawn Wednesday after abandoning their attempt to force <LOCATION> Kuwait </LOCATION> to release 17 pro-Iranian terrorists jailed for bombing the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and French embassies in <LOCATION> Kuwait </LOCATION> in 1983. Both slain captives were Kuwaitis. <LOCATION> Kuwait </LOCATION> refused any concessions to the hijackers but <LOCATION> Algeria </LOCATION> apparently promised them passage to a country of their choice if they freed the hostages unharmed. <LOCATION> Algeria </LOCATION>, criticized by the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and other <LOCATION> Western </LOCATION> governments, has refused to acknowledge making a deal with the hijackers. There was no reference to them Thursday in any of the North African country's state-controlled media. Several of the returning Kuwaiti passengers accused <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> of complicity in the hijacking, saying one gunman was replaced by two others when the craft landed in <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>. `` One of the two was obviously a military pilot. He was ordering other gunmen around and telling them lots of things about the aircraft and supervising the wiring of explosives to most parts of the plane,'' said passenger <PERSON> Khaled </PERSON> <PERSON> Nasser </PERSON> <PERSON> Al-Zaferi </PERSON>. In <LOCATION> Algiers </LOCATION>, a brief farewell was held at the <LOCATION> Houari </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Boumedienne </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION> before the former hostages were flown to <LOCATION> Kuwait </LOCATION>. The former captives included three cousins of <PERSON> Sabah </PERSON> <PERSON> Jaber </PERSON> <PERSON> Sabah </PERSON>, ruler of the sheikdom. Compared with their tense, trembling appearance when they had emerged from the hijacked <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> 747, the former captives looked rested and relaxed. <PERSON> Anware </PERSON> <PERSON> Sabah </PERSON>, second cousin of the emir, said the hijackers treated her and her sister `` with deference and without brutality.'' Their brother, <PERSON> Fadel </PERSON> <PERSON> Khaled </PERSON> <PERSON> Sabah </PERSON>, said he was `` psychologically fatigued'' when he made a statement by radio to the control tower asking that the gunmen's demands be met. After their release, the hostages spent 30 hours at the <LOCATION> Algiers </LOCATION> military hospital being examined. A Kuwaiti doctor said all were in good physical condition but the psychological effects of the long, terrifying confinement may be felt for weeks or months. Algerian authorities would not permit journalists to inspect the hijacked plane, which awaited a relief crew to return it to <LOCATION> Kuwait </LOCATION>. One <ORGANIZATION> Kuwait </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airways </ORGANIZATION> official said the hijackers deliberately damaged the radio equipment before leaving. A member of the airport cleanup crew said trash was strewn through the aircraft, ropes had been used to divide the seating area and a large world map had been pinned to the wall of the forward cabin. He said the stench of rotting fruit filled the plane. Other Arab countries, including <LOCATION> Kuwait </LOCATION>, praised <LOCATION> Algeria </LOCATION> for achieving freedom for the hostages without additional violence. Algerian media called it a `` victory'' but Secretary of State <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON>, Prime Minister <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> and other Western leaders criticized <LOCATION> Algeria </LOCATION> for allowing the hijackers to get away. `` The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> will not rest until the terrorists, the murderers, the hijackers are brought to justice,'' said <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman <PERSON> Phyllis </PERSON> <PERSON> Oakley </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. She declined to say what steps might be taken but said officials are checking to see whether laws apply that allow charges against hijackers when a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> citizen is involved. At least one passenger carried an American passport. An international convention calls for sanctions against any country allowing hijackers to escape unpunished, including an end to direct air service to the offending nation. <LOCATION> Algeria </LOCATION> is not a signatory. An Soviet-built Antonov transport of the Algerian air force was seen taking off before dawn Wednesday, shortly before the hostages left the hijacked plane. It was widely assumed the hijackers were aboard the Antonov, which can land on a grassy field.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880421-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-21-88 2353EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-Meese-Reagan 2ndLd-Writethru a0401 04-21 1021</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Meese-Reagan, 2nd Ld-Writethru, a0401,970</SECOND>
<HEAD>URGENT</HEAD>
<HEAD>Meese Summoned To White House Meeting With Officials Who Resigned</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDs: UPDATES with Weld comments to Reagan on hypothetical
indictment, adds Justice, White House comment. Picks 16th graf pvs
bgng: The source ...</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By MICHAEL J. SNIFFEN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Embattled Attorney General <PERSON> Edwin </PERSON> <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON> was summoned to a private meeting with President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> at the White House on Wednesday after <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> met with two <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> officials who resigned in protest over <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>'s continued tenure, a department source said Thursday night. The source, who declined to be identified, said Deputy Attorney General <PERSON> Arnold </PERSON> <PERSON> Burns </PERSON> and former Assistant Attorney General <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Weld </PERSON>, who headed the department's criminal division, met at the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> with <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and Vice President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and some White House staff members. During that 45-minute meeting, <PERSON> Burns </PERSON> told the president, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, White House chief of staff <ORGANIZATION> Howard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Baker </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> counsel A.B. <PERSON> Culvahouse </PERSON> that `` <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>'s behavior was hurting the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION>,'' another administration source said. <PERSON> Weld </PERSON>, meanwhile, `` laid out the facts'' in a hypothetical indictment he said he would have brought against <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> if he were the special prosecutor investigating the attorney general. <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> has been under investigation for nearly a year by independent counsel <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> McKay </PERSON>, who is looking into a handful of incidents to see if <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> violated conflict-of-interest or other federal laws. It was not immediately known what occurred during <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>'s meeting at the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, which immediately followed the <LOCATION> Burns-Weld </LOCATION> meeting, but <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> said in an interview Thursday with <ORGANIZATION> USA </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Today </ORGANIZATION> that the president has continued to express his `` total support ... and total confidence. During the earlier White House meeting with the departing <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> officials, <PERSON> Burns </PERSON> `` laid out the reasons why <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> should leave,'' said the source, who also spoke on condition of anonymity. He added that <PERSON> Burns </PERSON> never specifically suggested that <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> should resign. <PERSON> Burns </PERSON> told <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> that <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> had violated the standards of ethical conduct for executive branch employees spelled out in a 1965 executive order. Those standards, among other things, say that employees should avoid any action which could create the appearance of using public office for private gain, giving preferential treatment to any organization or person and making a government decision outside official channels. <PERSON> Burns </PERSON> specifically mentioned longtime <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> friend <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Wallach </PERSON>, who is under indictment in the <ORGANIZATION> Wedtech </ORGANIZATION> scandal, as having taken advantage of his relationship with the attorney general to promote his own business interests. Burns, while not using these specific words, in effect told <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> that `` <PERSON> Wallach </PERSON> was selling the office of the attorney general,'' said the source. Another administration source familiar with the Wednesday meetings was asked about the outcome. `` As you can see, there was no change,'' he responded. A <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> spokesman, <PERSON> Dean </PERSON> <PERSON> St. </PERSON> <PERSON> Dennis </PERSON>, had no immediate comment. <PERSON> Roman </PERSON> <PERSON> Popadiuk </PERSON>, a White House spokesman, said late Thursday that he was unfamiliar with either of the meetings Wednesday. `` I have no idea what you're talking about,'' he said. `` I ca n't confirm or deny. He noted, however, that <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said this week that <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> has `` full confidence'' in <LOCATION> Meese </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Burns </PERSON> and <PERSON> Weld </PERSON> have not discussed publicly their reasons for submitting their resignations March 29, but sources close to them have said they felt that <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>'s continued tenure in the department while he is under investigation by an independent counsel was hampering department operations. During the White House meeting, <PERSON> Weld </PERSON> told <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> that if he were the special prosecutor in the criminal investigation of <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>, he would seek an indictment of the attorney general, said the administration source. <PERSON> Weld </PERSON> had made similar comments to <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> on March 29 when <PERSON> Weld </PERSON> and <PERSON> Burns </PERSON> announced to the attorney general that they were resigning. According to the source, <PERSON> Weld </PERSON> in the meeting with the president `` laid out the facts'' in a hypothetical indictment. `` The president was very attentive, listened to the story, got up and <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> came in'' after <PERSON> Burns </PERSON> and <PERSON> Weld </PERSON> left, said the administration source. In the past, said several sources, speaking on condition of anonymity, <PERSON> Weld </PERSON> has told <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> associates that he feels a number of felony charges could be lodged against <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> based on the factual evidence known to date in the nearly year-long probe of <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>. These include conspiracy counts involving the acceptance of illegal gratuities, a violation of Ethics in Government Act provisions spelling out conflicts of interest and a violation of the Foreign Corrupt Practices Act barring bribes to foreign officials. One knowledgeable source said that <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> had been summoned to the White House and met privately with <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and possibly <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> after <PERSON> Weld </PERSON> had met with <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> on the day he resigned. The source was unable to provide any details of that conversation. <PERSON> McKay </PERSON> is looking into <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>'s ties to the scandal-plagued <ORGANIZATION> Wedtech </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> and a $ 1 billion Iraqi oil pipeline project. <PERSON> McKay </PERSON> is also known to be looking into Mrs. <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>'s $ 40,000-a-year job with the Multiple Sclerosis Society Mrs. <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>'s salary is underwritten by <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bender </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION>, a tax-exempt philanthropy run by a <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> real estate family. The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> reported last week that a partnership headed by <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bender </PERSON>, the foundation's vice president, owned a building for which the government signed a $ 50 million lease for a <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> office building in May 1987. Thirteen days after signing the lease, the <PERSON> Bender </PERSON> partnership sold the building for a $ 22.6 million profit. <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> has denied any wrongdoing and said he did n't have anything to do with the lease. The attorney general said Thursday that he meets the highest ethical standards expected of public officials and knows of no factor `` right now that would cause me to resign.'' In the interview published in Friday's editions of <ORGANIZATION> USA </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Today </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> said the president has continued to express his `` total support ... and total confidence.'' However, he did not rule out resigning before <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s term ends. `` I've never set a particular limit of how long I would stay or how long I would n't stay. A lot would depend upon my own post-federal service employment situation and so on,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880421-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-21-88 0639EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Jackson-PUSH 2-Takes   04-21 0808</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Jackson-PUSH, 2-Takes,0834</SECOND>
<HEAD>CANDIDATE CLOSE-UP: Jackson Left PUSH With Debts and Auditors'
Questions</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also moved in advance for Thursday AMs as b0333. This is</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 one in an intermittent series of AP Candidate Close-up stories exploring the careers and backgrounds of the remaining presidential contenders. This story focuses on <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s record running Operation PUSH.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>By WILLIAM C. HIDLAY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CHICAGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 `` I like everything you said,'' the old man told <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> on the campaign trail, `` but ... wo n't the Republicans be able to clobber you and the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> on the basis of your lack of governmental experience?'' <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> looked around the hall. He was in a <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> suburb, addressing senior citizens who had just listened to a litany of legislative accomplishments from Sen. <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, one of his rivals for the presidential nomination. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> was ready for this often asked question. In the first place, he said, the Reagan-Bush administration has experience and look what they've done _ a record trade deficit, a record debt, a mess in <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> and `` the most sleaze and corruption in ... American history.'' Then he launched into his own record of leadership in civil rights and labor strife. `` Of those of us who are running _ if you were about to lose your farm, had to face the banker _ which one would you choose to argue your case? ... If you needed a scholarship for your child who would you want to argue your case? If you had a relative in a foreign jail, who would you send to bring your relative back home?'' Now the punchline _ `` Some office holders are not leaders and some leaders are not office holders ... I am a leader.'' <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> has never been elected to office or run a business, but he has headed a nationwide organization, the Chicago-based Operation PUSH _ <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> to </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Serve </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Humanity </ORGANIZATION> _ and its education-oriented affiliate, PUSH for Excellence, or PUSH-Excel. His handling of things at PUSH has come under scrutiny for signs of how he might run the government. Over the years, <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> has used PUSH to keep himself in the spotlight with his crowd-stirring oratory, media-wise instincts and ability to capitalize on the latest public issues. Although he stepped down as head of PUSH when he ran for president in 1984, he often returns to lead its Saturday morning meetings. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> was the architect of PUSH's campaign to pressure corporations to expand hiring and business opportunities for minorities. However, <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> left PUSH with a record of improper use of government money, high staff turnover and dwindling revenues. His supporters point to PUSH's achievements in strengthening black economic power as examples of <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s ability and say he was a genius at keeping the organization afloat despite a chronic cash shortage. They dismiss administrative problems as mstakes made by well-meaning volunteers and low-paid staff members. `` I think he managed incredibly well given the resources he had. All civil rights organizations have always operated at a deficit,'' said <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> <PERSON> Tidmore </PERSON>, a founding member of PUSH's board. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s critics maintain that PUSH operated like a personality cult, built around <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, rather than a well-managed organization. `` <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> just does n't have the ability to keep things together,'' said the Rev. <PERSON> Hosea </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>, a longtime civil rights activist and <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> critic. `` When it comes to building and motivating people, <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> is a genius. But he ca n't sustain an effort and that is evidenced by PUSH.'' In the past decade, PUSH has been beset by troubles: _ PUSH for Excellence either misspent or failed to account for $ 1.2 million out of an estimated $ 6.6 million in federal grants from the departments of <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION>, Education, <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Human </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION>, federal auditors found The government still is trying to collect the money without having to take PUSH to court. _ The <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> concluded in a 1980 audit that PUSH-Excel's `` accounting system and internal controls are not adequate to safeguard its assets,'' or ensure reliable accounting and operating efficiency _ PUSH-Excel and Operation PUSH were hit in the 1970s and early 1980s with more than a dozen lawsuits by businesses seeking payment of overdue bills for such things as telephone service, printing and paper supplies _ In <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s 1984 campaign it was revealed the PUSH organizations had received a $ 10,000 donation from <LOCATION> Libya </LOCATION> and $ 200,000 from the League of <LOCATION> Arab </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> The contributions were made after <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> toured the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> in 1979 and was photographed embracing <PERSON> Yasser </PERSON> <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON>, head of the <ORGANIZATION> Palestine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Clovis </PERSON> <PERSON> Maksoud </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> Arab </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> League </ORGANIZATION>'s ambassador to the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION>, said recently that the contribution was made because of `` a growing affinity between the Arab-American and black communities'' at that time. <PERSON> Maksoud </PERSON> said the <ORGANIZATION> Arab </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> League </ORGANIZATION> has not donated any money since then to the PUSH network.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>MORE</NOTE>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880421-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-21-88 0723EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--Diamonds     04-21 0163</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Diamonds,0169</SECOND>
<HEAD>London Jewelry Dealer Bought Largest Diamond Ever Sold At Auction</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> jewelry dealer was identified as the person who paid $ 9.13 million for the largest diamond ever to be sold at auction, a Sotheby's spokeswoman said. <PERSON> Laurence </PERSON> <PERSON> Graff </PERSON> purchased the 85.91-carat, pear-shaped diamond by telephone during Tuesday's auction, spokeswoman <PERSON> Jennifer </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> said Wednesday. The sale set a record for any gem sold at auction, she said. The diamond, which was perfectly cut and flawless, was part of an auction that brought $ 36 million, a record for a jewelry sale in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. The auction included gems belonging to the late <PERSON> Clare </PERSON> <PERSON> Boothe </PERSON> <PERSON> Luce </PERSON>, a former congresswoman and ambassador to <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>. Also Wednesday, <PERSON> Christie </PERSON>'s announced the sale of a 52.59 carat diamond ring for $ 7.8 million, the highest price ever paid per carat at auction, said spokeswoman <PERSON> Lily </PERSON> <PERSON> Zimmerman </PERSON>. She said $ 132,000 was paid per carat by a private Saudi Arabian collector bidding by telephone.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880421-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-21-88 0204EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Jackson-PUSH 1stAdd a0409 04-21 0838</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Jackson-PUSH, 1st Add, a0409,0862</SECOND>
<HEAD>CHICAGO: PUSH network.</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 On the other side of the ledger, PUSH improved business opportunities for blacks by persuading corporations to sign `` covenants'' promising jobs and franchises to minorities _ often after PUSH threatened or carried out boycotts of a company's product From the start, on Christmas 1971, <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> vowed the group would `` picket, vote and if necessary engage in civil disobedience'' to achieve its goals. <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>, now a member of the <ORGANIZATION> Atlanta </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>, recalled <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> had quit as head of a similar group, Operation Breadbasket, an arm of the <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Leadership </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conference </ORGANIZATION>, after clashing with <ORGANIZATION> SCLC </ORGANIZATION> leaders over expenditures and <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s independent streak <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> built PUSH into a network with chapters in 32 cities, taking in $ 16.8 million from 1975 to 1986, the last year for which state financial records were filed. He also used the PUSH platform to take on the administrations of several presidents and the city hierarchy of <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> on a range of issues, from <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> policy in <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> to contracts for minority-owned businesses. PUSH's Saturday meetings are part of <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>'s political landscape, mixing the gospel flavor of a Southern church revival with <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s stirring speeches on the day's hot issues. From the PUSH pulpit, <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> pressured companies, such as Burger King and <ORGANIZATION> Coca-Cola </ORGANIZATION>, to sign minority opportunity compacts. `` <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> was instrumental in making a lot of opportunities available _ by that I mean distributorships, getting blacks placed in jobs in chain stores,'' said <PERSON> Dempsey </PERSON> <PERSON> Travis </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> businessman and <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> supporter. PUSH officials have long been secretive about the group's sources of money, other than to say it is supported by individual memberships that now cost $ 20 a person and donations from businesses Some of the corporations that signed covenants with PUSH also contributed money to help sponsor its annual convention or other activities. Coors Brewery, for example, gave $ 20,000 last year to a major PUSH scholarship fund-raising event in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>. In 1977, <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> broadened PUSH's mission by starting PUSH-Excel to get inner-city youths to study harder. He spoke in packed school gymnasiums nationwide, with students joining in his trademark chant: `` I am ... somebody!'' After <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> fired up the students, PUSH-Excel worked with local school officials to set up special clubs and programs to help keep the youths motivated. But federal auditors later contended that government money received from 1979 to 1982 went for such layouts as $ 211 for music and flowers for a 1979 press party in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>; `` $ 650 for Christmas cards purchased for a related organization''; $ 28 for funeral flowers, and $ 15 for a parking ticket. The government has referred PUSH-Excel's $ 1.2 million debt to the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> for collection. `` As of now, we have n't been able to resolve it,'' said Justice spokesman <PERSON> Amy </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>. PUSH-Excel dramatized <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s strengths, and weaknesses, said <PERSON> Ernest </PERSON> <PERSON> House </PERSON>, an education professor who has just finished writing a book about <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> and the student-motivation program. `` <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> had a lot of very good ideas. He has trouble carrying them through _ that has been his problem,'' said <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, who is director of the policy studies laboratory at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Colorado </ORGANIZATION> at <LOCATION> Boulder </LOCATION>. `` They went through three or four directors, one right after the other, and this was part of his difficulty in administering the program,'' House said. By 1986, PUSH-Excel's revenues, which peaked at $ 2.6 million in 1980, had dropped to $ 209,071 and the group ended the year with a $ 1.5 million debt, including the money owed to the government. Operation PUSH was n't much better off. It started 1986 with a $ 339,056 deficit, but took in enough money to reduce the debt to $ 84,914 by the end of the year, according to its annual report filed with the state. The Rev. <PERSON> Willie </PERSON> <PERSON> Barrow </PERSON>, PUSH's national executive director, did not return repeated telephone calls asking for information about the organization's current financial status. <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON>, <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s longtime aide and spokesman, said he understood the group had succeeded this year in nearly erasing its deficit. Although <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> was PUSH's driving force, his supporters say he should n't be blamed for organizational problems in areas delegated to subordinates. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> himself has said he did n't get involved in mechanical details. `` If there was anything sloppy about <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON>'s management, it was that he could not afford paid, competent people to deal with the various functions of accounting and management of government programs,'' said <PERSON> Bishop </PERSON> <PERSON> H.H </PERSON>. <PERSON> Bookins </PERSON>, a leader in the African Methodist Episcopal church and a <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> supporter. `` <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON>'s main thrust was at raising funds to keep the organization afloat. So it was impossible for him to be a hands-on manager of things,'' he said. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> supporters point to the success of his 1988 presidential campaign as evidence he can recruit able people to assist him. <PERSON> Leon </PERSON> <PERSON> Davis </PERSON>, who worked as PUSH's national executive director in 1972, said he sees a different <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> today. `` From the time I worked with <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON>, it seems to me he has grown tremendously and his campaign points out one thing _ he has delegated authority.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880421-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-21-88 0723EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--StateDance     04-21 0146</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--State Dance,0150</SECOND>
<HEAD>Calif. Senate Swinging Into Action</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SACRAMENTO, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A state <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> panel agreed that swing is the thing. Sen. <PERSON> Quentin </PERSON> <PERSON> Kopp </PERSON> persuaded the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rules </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> on Wednesday to approve a bill that would designate the West Coast Swing Dance as the official state dance. <PERSON> Kopp </PERSON> said the dance, also known as swing, whip, or jitterbug, is the only dance native to the state of <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> that has survived. It originated in the early 1930s, he said, adding that devotees of the art come from every ethnic, religious, racial or economic background. The committee's 4-0 vote sent swing over its first legislative hurdle. It faces further votes in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION> before it would go to the governor for his signature. The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> several years ago rejected a bill that would have made the square dance the official state dance.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880421-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-21-88 0645EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-WelfareReform Bjt   04-21 0615</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Welfare Reform, Bjt,610</SECOND>
<HEAD>Finance Committee Clears Bill To Overhaul Welfare System</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JILL LAWRENCE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> is likely to join the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> in approving major changes in the nation's welfare system, despite the near certainty that a presidential veto lies at the end of the long road to congressional consensus. The 25-year drive to overhaul welfare took a significant step forward Wednesday when the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Finance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> voted 17-3 to send a comprehensive reform measure to the floor. The five-year, $ 2.8 billion `` Family Security Act'' reflects a hard-won bipartisan consensus that welfare parents should work to support their children, that the goverment should help make this possible and that government aid should be a last resort. The bill was shaped during months of negotiations and had garnered 56 co-sponsors by the time the committee acted. Most of the Republicans on the <ORGANIZATION> Finance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, including <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Minority Leader <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION>, voted in favor of it. `` For all the troubles, in the end, we agree,'' said Sen. <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Patrick </PERSON> <PERSON> Moynihan </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.Y. </LOCATION>, chief sponsor and architect of the plan. `` We learned to talk to each other and listen and learn.'' While a majority of <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Democrats and Republicans may have reached a fragile consensus, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration officials have raised numerous objections to the bill and have said they will recommend a veto. But <PERSON> Moynihan </PERSON> said the support of the <ORGANIZATION> Finance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, which has killed many reform efforts in the last two decades, is evidence that welfare reform has come too far to fail. `` If the president vetoes it, the next president will sign it,'' he said. Both <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Majority Leader <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON>, D-W. <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, and <ORGANIZATION> Finance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Texas </LOCATION>, have said they want to complete <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> action on the <PERSON> Moynihan </PERSON> bill and achieve a compromise with the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> before the end of the The <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> passed a broad plan last year that, according to rough, preliminary estimates by the <ORGANIZATION> Congressional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Budget </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION>, would cost $ 7.1 billion over five years. Unlike the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> bill, the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> would give states financial incentives to raise their benefits until 1991. In many states, welfare payments amount to less than half the federal poverty standard. Both bills would require states to take stronger steps to establish paternity and collect child support from absent parents. The provisions include automatic wage-withholding from paychecks in some cases. States would also have to set up education, training and job programs for welfare recipients and spend half their money on those considered most difficult to help, such as teen-age mothers. Child care, transportation and Medicaid assistance would be provided. And states would have to allow cash benefits for two-parent families in which the principal wage-earner is unemployed. Only 26 now do so. The bill says the assistance would only have to be available for six months of each year. Voting against the bill were Sens. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Armstrong </PERSON>, R-Colo.; <PERSON> Malcolm </PERSON> <PERSON> Wallop </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Wyo </LOCATION>; and <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Roth </PERSON>, R-Del. <PERSON> Armstrong </PERSON>, echoing the administration's objections, said the bill would increase rather than decrease welfare dependency. He said the two-parent welfare provision would add 130,000 families to the rolls while transitional child care and medical benefits for recipients moving into the workforce would add another 500,000. <PERSON> Armstrong </PERSON> and the administration support a less expensive $ 913 million plan that has been introduced in the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> by Republicans. The money for the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> bill would be raised by extending the <ORGANIZATION> Internal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Revenue </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>'s debt collection program and phasing out child-care tax credits for high-income families. In holding hearings and making arguments for his bill, <PERSON> Moynihan </PERSON> often noted that one out of three <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> children is on welfare before the age of 18.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880421-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-21-88 0209EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-BicoastalEconomy Bjt   04-21 0683</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bicoastal Economy, Bjt,670</SECOND>
<HEAD>Farm Belt, Mountain States' Income Catching Up With Coastal States</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVE SKIDMORE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Government statistics may be signaling the beginning of the end of a mid-1980s trend that saw booming growth in coastal states outstrip the rest of the country, economists say. Residents of densely populated coastal states like <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Massachussets </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> continued to have the highest average incomes in the nation last year, the <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> said Wednesday. States like <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION> that are dependent on farming, mining or oil were at or near the bottom. <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION> was the highest-income state in the nation, with an average of $ 20,980 earned for every man, woman and child in 1987. That was more than double the $ 10,204 income in <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION>, the perennial last-place finisher. Also as in the recent past, income growth was strongest in the <LOCATION> Northeast </LOCATION> and weakest in energy and mining states. But, <PERSON> Rudolph </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> DePass </PERSON>, an analyst with the <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, says the figures show growth is accelerating in the <LOCATION> Southwest </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Rocky </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mountain </LOCATION> regions and slowing elsewhere. The national average in 1987 was $ 15,340, up 4.8 percent from a year earlier. Taking the 4.4 percent inflation rate into account, it was the worst gain since the recession year of 1982. That was reflected in even the healthiest regions. The growth of income in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> fell from 7.6 percent in 1986 to 6.7 percent last year. Income growth slipped from 6.5 percent to 6 percent in the <LOCATION> Mid-Atlantic </LOCATION> states. However, income growth in the tottering <ORGANIZATION> Southwest </ORGANIZATION> increased from 0.9 percent to 2.2 percent. It improved in the Mountain states from 3.5 percent to 3.6 percent. `` I think it's signaling the end of the bicoastal economy,'' said <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Zandi </PERSON>, an economist with the <ORGANIZATION> Wefa </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Group </ORGANIZATION>, a Philadelphia-area forecasting service. `` The bicoastal trend came to the forefront in 1984 and continued on through most of the first half of 1987. Since last summer ... the bicoastal phenomenon has been on the wane,'' <PERSON> Zandi </PERSON> said. `` As we move into 1989 and 1990, it will become a thing of the past, almost as the Sun Belt-Frost Belt phenomenon waned in the middle 1980s,'' he said. <PERSON> Zandi </PERSON> cited these reasons: _ The increase in exports, which are growing as the falling dollar makes <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> goods cheaper overseas, will boost manufacturing in the <LOCATION> Midwest </LOCATION> and in parts of the <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> _ Oil and commodity prices are on the way up, brightening prospects for the Oil Patch, Farm Belt and mining states _ Growth in the economy's service sector _ which had benefited financial centers like <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> _ is slowing The effects of the October stock market collapse are more severe there than elsewhere. _ Eastern states and <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, which rode the growth of high technology firms, are running into a tight labor market, making it likely that companies will look to expand elsewhere `` We can expect to see slower growth in the bicoastal states and stronger growth in the states in the middle,'' <PERSON> Zandi </PERSON> said. <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION>, with income of $ 20,067, ranked second in 1987 and <LOCATION> Masschussetts </LOCATION>, with income of $ 18,926, was third. The District of <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION>, with income of $ 20,303, would have been second if it was included in the rankings. <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>, which took over the No. 1 spot from <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION> at the start of the oil boom in 1973 and held it until 1985, fell to fifth in 1987 Its average income actually fell 0.7 percent last year to $ 17,886. Rounding out the top 10 were <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>. Seven of the 10 states with the lowest per capita income were in the South. In addition to <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION>, they were <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Arkansas </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Kentucky </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION> _ energy and mining states _ were also in the lowest 10. Other than <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION> was the only state where average income declined in 1987, by 0.1 percent to $ 12,759. But the shrinkage was not as bad as the state's 1.1 percent decline in 1986.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880421-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-21-88 0650EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-TornadoAftermath     04-21 0456</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Tornado Aftermath,0469</SECOND>
<HEAD>Florida Town Unbowed by Tornado Disaster</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ED BIRK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MADISON, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The steeple stands upright amid the tornado-tossed rubble of <ORGANIZATION> Grace </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Presbyterian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION>, but it is on the floor, not the roof _ a symbol of the damage to this rural town and its determination to rebuild. `` We are going to have a prayer meeting,'' church member <PERSON> Charlotte </PERSON> <PERSON> Hollingsworth </PERSON> said Wednesday as she searched the debris for church records and hymn books. `` We are dragging out chairs to have a service on the lawn, or somewhere.'' The roof was torn out from underneath the steeple by Tuesday's predawn tornado, which left a 12-mile path of destruction in this <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> town of 3,500 residents Four people were killed and at least 18 injured. Preliminary damage estimates ranged up to $ 27 million. `` No event, with the exception of World War II, affected people like yesterday,'' said T.C. <PERSON> Merchant </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, 72, editor of The Madison Enterprise-Review. `` It looked like some 500-pound bombs dropped out there.'' State damage-assessment teams surveyed the area 50 miles east of <LOCATION> Tallahassee </LOCATION> to support a state application for federal aid, and damage figures were expected today, said <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Morgan </PERSON>, spokesman for the state <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Community </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Affairs </ORGANIZATION>. Insurance adjusters took pictures and videotapes of the damage, and utility crews replaced damaged power lines and poles. The <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION> reported 17 homes destroyed and 30 heavily damaged by the tornado. <PERSON> Chris </PERSON> <PERSON> Floyd </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION> damage assessment coordinator, said residential damage ranged from $ 600,000 to $ 700,000. But <PERSON> Hugh </PERSON> <PERSON> Ross </PERSON>, claims manager with the <ORGANIZATION> Florida </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Farm </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> insurance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> office </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Gainesville </LOCATION>, said he thought residential damages would be at least $ 2 million. `` We have n't found anything yet that could be called salvageable,'' said <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Rowe </PERSON>, 53, whose home was demolished. `` We've got basic coverage. I'm sure, like everybody else, we do n't have enough to cover everything `` The good Lord helped us accumulate what little we did have, and he will help us again. ... We're so glad to be out of this alive,'' <PERSON> Rowe </PERSON> said. Meanwhile, <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> McCoy </PERSON>, president of <ORGANIZATION> North </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Florida </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Junior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION>, said the campus lost at least three buildings and nine were heavily damaged. He estimated fixing or replacing them, including a nearly completed regional library, could cost $ 20 million to $ 25 million. Damage at a shopping mall, chicken farm, utilities and other property had n't been calculated. A disaster declaration signed by Gov. <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Martinez </PERSON> on Tuesday allowed state agencies to provide equipment and cleanup crews. More than 100 inmates from the region's jails were organized into road gangs, said <LOCATION> Madison </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> Sheriff <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Peavy </PERSON>. The state's worst tornado since 1966 killed four people in a minutes. Three others remained hospitalized Wednesday night.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880421-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-21-88 0701EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-HijackGetaways     04-21 0468</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Hijack Getaways,0477</SECOND>
<HEAD>Terrorists Have Slipped Away in Past Hijackings, Too</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Hijack Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 The deal struck by <LOCATION> Algeria </LOCATION> promising safe conduct to the hijackers of the <ORGANIZATION> Kuwait </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airways </ORGANIZATION> flight was not the only time hijackers have gone free. Here is a list of earlier skyjackings in which the terrorists were not arrested:
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 JULY 23-SEPT. 1, 1968 _ <ORGANIZATION> El </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Al </ORGANIZATION> flight from <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Tel </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Aviv </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>, is diverted to <LOCATION> Algeria </LOCATION> by <PERSON> Arab </PERSON> nationalists Forty days later, <LOCATION> Algeria </LOCATION> releases last 12 Israelis held hostage. There is no word on what happened to the hijackers. SEPT. 6-30, 1970 _ Palestinians seeking freedom for imprisoned comrades hijack four <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and West European jetliners, land them in <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Jordan </PERSON>, and blow them up. Hostages are eventually freed unharmed, in exchange for seven Palestinian prisoners. The hijackers rejoin Palestinian militants engaged in civil war with Jordanian troops. OCTOBER 1977 _ Japanese <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> terrorists hijack <ORGANIZATION> Japan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lines </ORGANIZATION> jet to <LOCATION> Algeria </LOCATION>. Negotiators secure release of hostages in exchange for $ 6 million ransom payment and release of six <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> members in Japanese jails. Officials later indicate hijackers were allowed to leave country. DEC. 4, 1984 _ Five Arabs hijack Kuwaiti airliner and demand release of 17 pro-Iranian terrorists held in <LOCATION> Kuwait </LOCATION>. They fly to <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION> and kill two <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> passengers. Iranian security men storm plane after five days and capture hijackers, who later vanish. Western intelligence officials believe Iranians let them go. JUNE 11, 1985 _ Six Shiite Moslem militiamen hijack <ORGANIZATION> Royal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Jordanian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> jet on the ground at <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> airport. They order jet to fly to <LOCATION> Cyprus </LOCATION>, but eventually return to <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>. Passengers and crew are released in <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>, and hijackers blow up cockpit and rejoin comrades in <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>. A suspect, <PERSON> Fawaz </PERSON> <PERSON> Younis </PERSON>, was arrested in September 1987 in international waters in <LOCATION> Mediterranean </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sea </LOCATION> and flown to <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, where he awaits trial. He has also been implicated in the <ORGANIZATION> TWA </ORGANIZATION> hijacking days later, but has not been charged. JUNE 15-JULY 1, 1985 _ <ORGANIZATION> Shiite </ORGANIZATION> gunmen hijack <ORGANIZATION> TWA </ORGANIZATION> Athens-to-Rome flight to <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>. Some passengers are released but 40 men are held hostage. One, <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> diver <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Stethem </PERSON>, is shot dead; 17 days later remaining 39 are released after Syrian intervention. Hijackers are not arrested in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> after the incident. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> authorities later name <PERSON> Mohammed </PERSON> <PERSON> Hamadi </PERSON>, <PERSON> Hasan </PERSON> <PERSON> Izz-Al-Din </PERSON>, and <PERSON> Ali </PERSON> <PERSON> Atwa </PERSON> in an indictment as suspected hijackers. <PERSON> Imad </PERSON> <PERSON> Mughniyeh </PERSON> is suspected of masterminding the hijacking. He and <PERSON> Izz-Al-Din </PERSON> are also believed to have taken part in the latest <ORGANIZATION> Kuwait </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airways </ORGANIZATION> hijacking, and <PERSON> Mughniyeh </PERSON> to have masterminded the 1984 <ORGANIZATION> Kuwait </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airways </ORGANIZATION> hijacking. <PERSON> Mohammed </PERSON> <PERSON> Hamadi </PERSON> was arrested at <LOCATION> Frankfurt </LOCATION> airport Jan. 13, 1987. <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> rejected extradition request from <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and decided <PERSON> Hamadi </PERSON> will be tried in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>. No trial date has been set.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880421-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-21-88 0234EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Immigration-Amnesty     04-21 0683</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Immigration-Amnesty,680</SECOND>
<HEAD>Deadline Extension Clears First Of Three Hurdles</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LARRY MARGASAK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A measure extending the deadline for illegal aliens to apply for amnesty faces a difficult fight in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> and a possible presidential veto after clearing the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> by a narrow margin. The 213-201 <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> vote Wednesday would move the deadline from May 4 to Nov. 30. The extension would represent the first change in the landmark immigration law signed by President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> in November 1986. But the Immigration and <ORGANIZATION> Naturalization </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> issued a warning late Wednesday to potential applicants that they should heed the current May 4 deadline. `` INS is concerned that this misguided legislation will create confusion among potential applicants and cause them to delay filing beyond the May 4 cutoff date,'' the service said in a statement. It said legalization offices will remain open on May 4 until midnight to process applications and that aliens should `` continue to expect that the last date'' to apply will be May 4. The immigration law enacted in 1986 was finely tuned legislation that carefully balanced a legalization program for illegal aliens with penalties for employers who knowingly hire undocumented workers. The narrow margin of Wednesday's vote demonstrated that amnesty for those who came to this country illegally remains an emotional issue. In 1986, the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> approved the amnesty program as part of the immigration bill by only seven votes. The extension is opposed by Sen. <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> K. </PERSON> <PERSON> Simpson </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Wyo </LOCATION>., the chief <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> author of the 1986 law, and other conservatives The immigration law is a delicately balanced bill that uses a carrot and stick approach to stop illegal aliens from pouring across <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> borders. Aliens who came to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> illegally, but have lived here continuously since before Jan. 1, 1982, were given one year to apply for temporary residency as the first step toward permanent status. The 12-month deadline is May 4. On the enforcement side, the law established severe fines for employers who knowingly hire undocumented workers. Those favoring the extension argue the <ORGANIZATION> Immigration </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Naturalization </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> reacted too slowly at the onset of the amnesty period, and did not get out the word to the immigrant communities to apply for temporary residency. In addition, many illegal aliens were thought to fear appearing at an office of the <ORGANIZATION> INS </ORGANIZATION>, the agency that is also in the business of deporting those here illegally. In fact, the law prohibits the <ORGANIZATION> INS </ORGANIZATION> amnesty employees from sharing their records with enforcement agents. Those opposing the amnesty extension in the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> were basically the same members who never liked the idea. They said that aliens who refused to come forward were simply procrastinators, and that the carefully structured bill should not be changed to accommodate them. With the deadline approaching, the chief <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> advocate of the extension, Sen. <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, D-Mass., plans to have a vote scheduled quickly in that chamber He is chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Judiciary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> immigration </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> subcommittee </ORGANIZATION> and sponsored the chamber's extension proposal If the bill should get through the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>, there could be additional problems at the White House. The commissioner of the <ORGANIZATION> INS </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON>, and Office of Management and Budget officials, have already said they would recommend a presidential veto if the bill reaches <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s desk. <PERSON> Simpson </PERSON> commented Wednesday, `` Our numbers are right on target with the projections we used when we passed the bill. I do not honestly see a need or justification for extending the signup period.'' During House debate, the chief sponsor of the extension, Rep. <PERSON> Romano </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Mazzoli </PERSON>, D-Ky. said 1.2 million aliens have applied for the general amnesty program, and 729,000 have received temporary residency cards Another 400,000 have applied for a separate agricultural amnesty program that is not affected by the extension legislation. Before the final vote, the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> approved by voice vote an amendment designed to cut down on fraud during any extension period. The <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> also defeated 167-246 an amendment that would have only accepted applications after May 4 from aliens who could demonstrate `` good cause'' for missing the deadline.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880421-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-21-88 0235EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--Nigeria-Gas     04-21 0111</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Nigeria-Gas,0112</SECOND>
<HEAD>Nigeria Won't Lower Gas Prices</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ABIDJAN, Ivory Coast (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Nigeria </LOCATION>'s military government will not rescind gasoline price increases despite violent protests that have killed six people and forced the closure of more than 20 colleges, <LOCATION> Lagos </LOCATION> radio reported. The government radio on Wednesday quoted Col. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Mark </PERSON>, a member of the <ORGANIZATION> Armed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forces </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ruling </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>, as saying the decision to eliminate government gasoline subsidies was in the best interests of <LOCATION> Nigeria </LOCATION>'s battered economy. The price increases resulted in widespread rioting April 13 that left six people dead, including two police officers who were beaten to death by a mob of protesters in the northern city of <PERSON> Jos </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880421-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-21-88 0236EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--Kenya-Everest     04-21 0148</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Kenya-Everest,0152</SECOND>
<HEAD>Kenya Plans Everest Climb</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NAIROBI, Kenya (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Kenya </LOCATION> plans to become the first African country to send an expedition to <LOCATION> Mount </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Everest </LOCATION>, the world's highest peak. <PERSON> Kenneth </PERSON> <PERSON> Matiba </PERSON>, minister for transport and communications, said a team of 15 to 20 climbers will attempt to scale the mountain in autumn of 1990. `` As a sporting nation, this is one sport I feel we must increase our participation in,'' <PERSON> Matiba </PERSON> said on Wednesday. He led a five-man Kenyan expedition up the 20,500-foot Island Peak of the Himalayas in Ocotober 1986. `` At that time we were happy to climb anything higher than what we have in <LOCATION> Kenya </LOCATION>,'' said <PERSON> Matiba </PERSON>. `` But I got the idea that we should send a team up <LOCATION> Mount </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Everest </LOCATION> and approached the Nepalese authorities.'' <LOCATION> Mount </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kenya </LOCATION>, this East African nation's highest mountain and the second highest on the continent, is 17,156 feet high.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880421-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-21-88 0237EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--Sweden-Heiress     04-21 0115</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Sweden-Heiress,0118</SECOND>
<HEAD>Wife Inherits Estate After Killing Husband</HEAD>
<DATELINE>STOCKHOLM, Sweden (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A 22-year-old woman who murdered her husband with a hammer shortly after her wedding will inherit his estate, a court has ruled. The <ORGANIZATION> Svenska </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dagbladet </ORGANIZATION> newspaper, reporting the case Wednesday, said the court ruled that murder committed while under temporary insanity does not disqualify the killer from inheriting the victim's estate. The victim's handicapped mother challenged the bequest of family heirlooms to the widow. `` I understand the law _ in principle _ but in this case it's twisted,'' the mother was quoted as saying. Under Swedish press laws, the people involved can not be identified. The wife was committed to a mental institution.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880421-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-21-88 0038EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-AutoTalks     04-21 0400</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Auto Talks,0409</SECOND>
<HEAD>UAW Wants Japanese-Style Pay For Japanese-Style Production</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JANET BRAUNSTEIN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Auto Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>HIGHLAND PARK, Mich. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 If <ORGANIZATION> Chrysler </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> wants its workers to accept Japanese-style production, its executives should accept markedly lower, Japanese-style pay, the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Auto </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Workers </ORGANIZATION>' chief negotiator said Wednesday. The remarks by <ORGANIZATION> UAW </ORGANIZATION> Vice President <PERSON> Marc </PERSON> <PERSON> Stepp </PERSON> came in the third day of <ORGANIZATION> Chrysler </ORGANIZATION> contract talks and a day after <ORGANIZATION> Chrysler </ORGANIZATION> disclosed that Chairman <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Iacocca </PERSON> earned $ 17.9 million in 1987 in salary, cash and stock bonuses and money earned exercising stock options granted when <ORGANIZATION> Chrysler </ORGANIZATION> stock was a fraction of its present value. <PERSON> Iacocca </PERSON>'s 1987 earnings made him the highest-paid auto executive for the second year in a row. In 1986, when he earned $ 20.6 million, <PERSON> Iacocca </PERSON> also was the nation's highest-paid executive. `` Executive compensations have gotten completely out of hand. ... It makes it extremely difficult for us to sit down in a rational manner and try to negotiate a decent contract,'' <PERSON> Stepp </PERSON> said, adding that after hearing about <PERSON> Iacocca </PERSON>'s pay, workers called union officials demanding higher pay and other benefits. <ORGANIZATION> Chrysler </ORGANIZATION> Vice President <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON> <PERSON> St. </PERSON> <PERSON> John </PERSON>, the company's chief negotiator, said Tuesday that <ORGANIZATION> Chrysler </ORGANIZATION> has asked union leaders to support a company push for adoption of so-called Modern Operating Agreements at all plants. The Japanese-style MOA system organizes workers into teams, uses them for a variety of jobs instead of a single defined task and reduces the number of workers needed to fill in for absentees, inspect products and correct mistakes. `` We think it is only fair that since they ask us to go to a Japanese production system such as MOAs and team concept ... it is fair for them to go to the Japanese system in terms of compensation,'' <PERSON> Stepp </PERSON> said. Japanese managers earn six to eight times more than Japanese workers, while American managers earn about 18 times more than their workers, and in <PERSON> Iacocca </PERSON>'s case, 27 times, <PERSON> Stepp </PERSON> said. <ORGANIZATION> Chrysler </ORGANIZATION> workers earn $ 14.43 an hour including cost-of-living adjustments, or gross base pay of about $ 30,000. <PERSON> Stepp </PERSON> also said that before Japanese workers are laid off or their pay is cut, Japanese managers take a pay cut. The Chrysler contract expires Sept. 14. It covers 59,000 active workers and 7,000 on layoff in 15 states and 65,000 retirees. Negotiators return to the table Monday prepared to bargain continuously until a contract is reached, <PERSON> Stepp </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880421-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-21-88 0043EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-TigerCageIntruder 3rdLd-Writethru a0427 04-21 0520</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Tiger Cage Intruder, 3rd Ld - Writethru, a0427,0529</SECOND>
<HEAD>Man Enters Tiger Cage, Threatens To Release Animal</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: SUBS grafs 7-9 bgng `There was ...' to UPDATE with no charges
filed as of late Wednesday and CORRECT name to Vonnie sted Bonnie.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By GUY COATES</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BATON ROUGE, La. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A man demanding to talk with <ORGANIZATION> Louisiana </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>'s basketball coach entered the outer cage of <ORGANIZATION> LSU </ORGANIZATION>'s <LOCATION> Bengal </LOCATION> tiger mascot Wednesday but gave up after a five-hour standoff, authorities said <ORGANIZATION> LSU </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Ballard </PERSON> said that the intruder had threatened to free the 13-year-old, 500-pound tiger but that marksmen with tranquilizer guns were nearby. The man had also claimed to have a bomb in a bag, <PERSON> Ballard </PERSON> said. At one point, students who came to watch chanted: `` Tiger bait! Tiger bait!'' _ the cry raised at <ORGANIZATION> LSU </ORGANIZATION> sporting events when the opposing team enters. The man was recognized by students as <PERSON> Moacyr </PERSON> `` Bruno'' Cezar, an ardent fan of the basketball team who lives in <ORGANIZATION> LSU </ORGANIZATION>'s athletic dormitory in return for doing work around the place. `` He wants a job. He has some sort of problem with his temporary visa. He says he wants a work permit,'' said <PERSON> Ballard </PERSON>. At one point, negotiators passed a document through the bars to him. <PERSON> Ballard </PERSON> said it was `` an application for employment.'' Cezar surrendered at 10:10 p.m. after talking with <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Vargas </PERSON>, the Spanish-speaking <ORGANIZATION> LSU </ORGANIZATION> center who is from the <LOCATION> Dominican </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Republic </LOCATION>. Accompanied by a priest and two detectives, <PERSON> Cezar </PERSON> was taken to the police station. No charges had been filed by late Wednesday night. `` He's upset, man. He's going to be all right. He'll talk to you tomorrow,'' <PERSON> Vargas </PERSON> said. The coach, <PERSON> Dale </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>, was in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>, but his wife, <PERSON> Vonnie </PERSON>, and some of <ORGANIZATION> LSU </ORGANIZATION>'s Spanish-speaking basketball players were among those trying to talk Cezar out. Cezar is a Brazilian who speaks mainly Portugese. <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> was told of the incident but had no immediate plans to return, <PERSON> Ballard </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Cezar </PERSON> had entered a cage surrounding the one in which the tiger is kept by taking the keys from the animal's trainer, who was cleaning the cage, said <PERSON> Ballard </PERSON>. `` This individual walked up and demanded the keys to the cage. He threatened the trainer. The trainer thinks he had a gun, but he's not sure,'' <PERSON> Ballard </PERSON> said. No weapons or bomb were found when the standoff ended, he said. <PERSON> Ballard </PERSON> said the intruder for a time held both the trainer and an unidentified young woman inside the cage as his hostages. A police SWAT team stood about 100 yards away during the standoff. By nightfall, hundreds of students, <ORGANIZATION> LSU </ORGANIZATION> officials and reporters had flocked to the cage between the football stadium and the arena where the basketball team plays. <ORGANIZATION> LSU </ORGANIZATION> spokesmen said the intruder had been befriended by <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> and had become one of the <ORGANIZATION> LSU </ORGANIZATION> basketball team's most enthusiastic fans. <PERSON> Ballard </PERSON> said the man also had been enrolled in an LSU program to improve his English. `` He's been a volunteer observer of <ORGANIZATION> LSU </ORGANIZATION> basketball for the past two years and has been quite close to Coach <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>,'' said <PERSON> Ballard </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880421-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-21-88 0655EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     04-21 0945</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0989</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in the News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Trump </PERSON>, who scored a public relations coup over City Hall by rebuilding the <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Park </LOCATION> skating rink, has been invited to try again. This time, the federal government is suggesting that the mega-developer show the city how to fix the closed-down <LOCATION> Williamsburg </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bridge </LOCATION>. At the invitation of <PERSON> Alfred </PERSON> <PERSON> Dellibovi </PERSON>, head of the federal <ORGANIZATION> Urban </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mass </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Trump </PERSON> plans to bring his engineers to the deteriorated span today to study how to get it back into operation. There was no immediate reaction from Mayor <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> I. </PERSON> <PERSON> Koch </PERSON>, who in recent years has been trading insults with <PERSON> Trump </PERSON> regularly over how the city is run. In a letter to <PERSON> Trump </PERSON>, <PERSON> Dellibovi </PERSON> lauded him as a builder whose projects come in `` on time, under budget and built to last.'' In 1987, <PERSON> Trump </PERSON> showed up <PERSON> Koch </PERSON> and the city bureaucracy when he took over repair of the skating rink and finished the job in five months and under budget. The city had spent 7 -LCB- years and $ 12 million on what was supposed to take 2 -LCB- years and $ 4.5 million.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>MOREHEAD, Ky. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Miss America <PERSON> Kaye </PERSON> <PERSON> Lani </PERSON> <PERSON> Rae </PERSON> <PERSON> Rafko </PERSON> and pageant finalist <PERSON> Laurie </PERSON> <PERSON> Keller </PERSON> have some advice for up-and-coming pageanteers: Do n't worry about your wardrobe when a good belly dance can do the trick. `` Just remember, the people in the audience do n't have the guts to do what you're doing,'' Miss <PERSON> Rafko </PERSON> told the 18 contestants in the <ORGANIZATION> Miss </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Morehead </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pageant </ORGANIZATION> on Tuesday night. `` Do n't be intimidated by the others' wardrobes,'' said <PERSON> Miss </PERSON> <PERSON> Keller </PERSON>, who was Miss Kentucky 1985 and a top-10 finalist for Miss America. `` I've seen some girls go out in a $ 50 suit and win the whole thing.'' Miss Rafko, the special guest of the pageant, performed the belly dance act that helped her win the title. `` They all told me, ` Just be <PERSON> Kaye </PERSON> <PERSON> Lani </PERSON> and you'll do fine,'' she said of her seven-year quest for the crown. `` Then they said, ` Hawaiian Tahitian dancing will never make it to <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>.'''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>MONTICELLO, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Broadcast executive <PERSON> Ted </PERSON> <PERSON> Turner </PERSON>, who has tried in the past to tame the broadcast industry, pleaded no contest to illegally importing wild mountain lions and was fined $ 1,500. <PERSON> Turner </PERSON>, 49, also was ordered to produce public service announcements for two wildlife groups after entering the plea Tuesday in <ORGANIZATION> Jefferson </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> to three counts of importing the animals to his plantation near here without a permit. The charges were filed last month after one of the lions brought from a plantation in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> was hit by a vehicle on Interstate 10.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Bess </PERSON> <PERSON> Myerson </PERSON>, the former Miss <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> and former city official who is under indictment, may have developed a keen interest in the law. According to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Newsday </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Miss </PERSON> <PERSON> Myerson </PERSON> is among the students taking a preparation class for the Law School Admission Test at the <ORGANIZATION> Stanley </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> H. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Kaplan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Educational </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> here. `` We're not allowed to divulge who our students are. We promise confidentiality,'' <PERSON> Kaplan </PERSON> said Wednesday. <ORGANIZATION> Newsday </ORGANIZATION> reported that <PERSON> Miss </PERSON> <PERSON> Myerson </PERSON> _ who goes on trial in September for allegedly trying to fix the divorce trial of her boyfriend, convicted felon <PERSON> Carl </PERSON> `` <PERSON> Andy </PERSON><PERSON> '' </PERSON> <PERSON> Capasso </PERSON> _ indicated she was interested in going to law school.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Merv </PERSON> <PERSON> Griffin </PERSON>, responding to a plea by <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, has asked `` every mover and shaker in this part of the world'' to a $ 5 million breakfast to help make the first lady's anti-drug dream come true The former talk show host and entrepreneur will be host of a May 2 gathering at his <LOCATION> Beverly </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hills </LOCATION> home. He hopes to raise half the $ 10 million needed to start up the <ORGANIZATION> Nancy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reagan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> for drug abuse. In addition to Mrs. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, the 50 guests at the `` power breakfast'' will include oilmen <PERSON> Marvin </PERSON> <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> and <PERSON> Armand </PERSON> <PERSON> Hammer </PERSON>, publisher <PERSON> Rupert </PERSON> <PERSON> Murdoch </PERSON>, developer <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Murdock </PERSON>, and producer Grant Tinker. <PERSON> Griffin </PERSON>, describing the group as `` every mover and shaker in this part of the world,'' said he wants to have the center ready for the <ORGANIZATION> Reagans </ORGANIZATION>' move back to <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> after they leave the White House in January.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>BERLIN (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Herbert </PERSON> <PERSON> von </PERSON> <PERSON> Karajan </PERSON>, the world-famous maestro of the <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Philharmonic </LOCATION>, has canceled a weekend concert appearance because he is ill, a spokeswoman for the orchestra said. <PERSON> Karajan </PERSON>, who celebrated his 80th birthday on April 5, had been scheduled to conduct the orchestra in a concert on Sunday in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION>. Also on his schedule is a concert tour next week in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>. `` He wo n't appear at the Sunday concert, but we are assuming he will be traveling to <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> since he has not canceled out on that,'' spokeswoman <PERSON> Birgit </PERSON> <PERSON> Alter </PERSON> said Wednesday. <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Schaefer </PERSON>, director of the Philharmonic, said the flamboyant maestro is suffering from a stomach flu.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>SANTA FE, N.M. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Gov. <PERSON> Garrey </PERSON> <PERSON> Carruthers </PERSON> is taking a look at the effects of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>'s speed-limit increase from 55 mph to 65 mph with the help of a radar gun installed on the dash of his state car. <PERSON> Carruthers </PERSON> said he used the radar gun Tuesday on a drive on Interstate 25 from <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Fe </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Albuquerque </LOCATION>. `` I find the lion's share -LRB- of the drivers -RRB- are content with 65,'' he said. `` But 65 does n't give you license to go 85.'' <PERSON> Carruthers </PERSON> was one of the first governors to order the replacement of 55 mph signs with 65 mph signs on rural stretches of interstate highways after <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> approved the change a year ago. The governor said he was only conducting research, not handing out citations.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880421-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-21-88 0244EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-PresidentialMoney     04-21 0634</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Presidential Money,620</SECOND>
<HEAD>Jesse Jackson Notches Best Fund-Raising Month Ever</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RITA BEAMISH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> is moving up to the fund-raising league of Gov. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, who has consistently outpaced all other Democratic presidential candidates, new financial reports show. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> last month raised a total of $ 3.4 million, including $ 621,098 in federal matching funds. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> reported raising $ 2.8 million, including $ 330,189 from the federal matching account. It was <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s biggest ever fund-raising month. In money that came directly from contributors, <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> took in $ 2 million, to <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' $ 2.4 million. Meanwhile, Sen. <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, who was expected to suspend his campaign today, ran up a debt of $ 1.6 million during March. He took out $ 1.5 million in loans, including $ 40,000 in a personal loan to the campaign. <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> borrowed the money to spend on the March 8 Super Tuesday series of 20 primaries, on which he had pinned his hopes. He then borrowed another $ 100,000 more this month before Tuesday's <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> primary, where he pulled a disappointing 10 percent of the vote, trailing far behind <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> has taken no loans. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> borrowed $ 250,000 during March. <PERSON> Gore </PERSON>'s overall receipts for March were $ 3.4 million, of which $ 336,312 was matching funds, his report showed. Because he received less than 10 percent of the vote in two previous successive primaries, <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> lost his eligibility for federal matching funds under election law. He would have to get an unlikely 20 percent of the vote in <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION>'s primary next week in order to re-establish his eligibility. Among Republicans, former TV evangelist <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> borrowed $ 410,000 to keep his campaign afloat during March, including a $ 25,000 loan from himself to the campaign. He has had to lay off most of his staff and almost totally eliminate other campaign expenditures because he was up against the maximum $ 27 million spending cap that the <ORGANIZATION> FEC </ORGANIZATION> imposes on candidates who receive federal matching funds. He ended March with $ 1.4 million in debts and only $ 61,890 in cash on hand. <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> spent $ 7.8 million during March repaying some of his previous bank loans. He has conceded that Vice President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> will win the nomination but <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> technically remains a candidate. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s fund-raising crew has closed up shop, having raised the maximum $ 27 million that primary candidates can spend. During March, he raised $ 1.7 million, of which $ 247,118 was in the form of federal matching funds. He ended the month with $ 3.6 million in the bank to cover close to $ 1 million in outstanding obligations. At the end of March he had spent $ 18.9 million against the base spending cap of $ 23 million, plus the maximum $ 4.6 million allowed for fund-raising expenses. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s treasurer, <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, said earlier this month that overall fund raising for the campaign had hit $ 30 million. That included $ 3 million for legal and accounting costs, which are not subject to the spending limit. <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> reported raising $ 2.3 million during March, of which $ 896,551 was federal matching funds, and $ 873,444 was money from contributors. With the expensive June 7 <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> contest still down the road and a handful of others before it, the remaining Democrats will be refocusing on fund-raising efforts. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> ended March with $ 1.7 million in cash on hand to cover $ 697,162 in bills. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> had $ 865,946 in the bank and $ 678,973 in debts. <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> ended the month with a debt of $ 1.6 million, and $ 416,603 in cash on hand. <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> contender <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON>, the congressman from <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> who dropped out of the race during March, was left with a debt. He ended the month $ 672,826 in the red, but was anticipating more than $ 500,000 in federal matching funds to help retire that. He had only $ 57,741 in the bank, after raising $ 604,586 during the month.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880421-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-21-88 0055EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Chile-Crusade Bjt   04-21 0911</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Chile-Crusade, Bjt,0940</SECOND>
<HEAD>Church-Backed Project Prepares Chile For First Election In 15
Years</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KEVIN NOBLET</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PUNTA DE TRALCA, Chile (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A volunteer program backed by the local <ORGANIZATION> Roman </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> has been launched to prepare Chileans for their first election in 15 years and, organizers hope, calm the country's stormy political waters. However, the effort already has stirred up controversy of its own, drawing fire from backers of the right-wing military government which charges that it favors the opposition. Leaders of the program, called the Crusade for Citizen Participation, say they hope to recruit 200,000 volunteers across the country for a door-to-door campaign starting in July. They say the aim is to promote voter registration and to provide electors with non-partisan information about their options. `` Most people want a peaceful transition to democracy,'' the crusade's director, <PERSON> Monica </PERSON> <PERSON> Jimenez </PERSON>, said in an interview. `` It's our task to see that this happens. She said the crusade's participants also will monitor the election's outcome to ensure that it is `` respectable and respected.'' The government plans a yes-or-no ballot later this year on a single presidential candidate to be picked by the chiefs of the armed forces and national police. No date has been set. President <PERSON> Augusto </PERSON> <PERSON> Pinochet </PERSON>, the right-wing army commander who seized power in a 1973 coup, is seen as the most likely candidate. In order to win, the candidate must garner 50 percent of the yes vote plus one. If the candidate wins, he will begin an eight-year term in March 1989. If he loses, an open election will be held in early 1990 and <PERSON> Pinochet </PERSON> will remain in power in the meantime, according to <LOCATION> Chile </LOCATION>'s 1980 Constitution The country's last election was in March 1973. The military government has held, and won, two referendums on political or constitutional questions. Mrs. <PERSON> Jimenez </PERSON>, a university professor and social worker active in church affairs, said she came up with the idea for the crusade a year ago. Under the auspices of a church-run foundation, she studied similar projects in other countries. They included <LOCATION> Argentina </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Uruguay </LOCATION>, which have returned to civilian rule in recent years, as well as the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. `` I had trouble crystallizing the idea, so it helped a great deal to visit and study similar programs elsewhere,'' she said. She obtained a $ 1 million grant from the <ORGANIZATION> Inter-American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Human </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rights </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION>, based in <LOCATION> Costa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rica </LOCATION>, to print educational material, train volunteers and pay for television and radio publicity. The training manuals for volunteers quickly prompted charges of bias from pro-government sectors for instructing that, in part, a `` yes'' vote means `` giving support to the operation of a presidentialist, authoritarian regime characterized by ... a regime of limited citizen participation.'' A `` no'' vote means `` re-establishing a balance of powers'' and `` eliminating the control by the armed forces over civilian authorities,'' the instructions say. Citing the material, a commentary in the government-run newspaper <ORGANIZATION> La </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nacion </ORGANIZATION> complained of the crusade's `` slanted, tendentious and partisan spirit.'' `` Its leaders do n't even bother to disguise their opposition tendencies,'' the commentary said. Mrs. <PERSON> Jimenez </PERSON> responded: `` Because we live in such a polarized atmosphere, to talk of democracy is to already take a side. This is the difficulty we are facing.'' She said describing the <PERSON> Pinochet </PERSON> government as authoritarian `` is a fact, not a value judgement. I'm not using it in the pejorative sense.'' The crusade appears highly organized. Several supervisors said they took part in organizing Pope <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> II </PERSON>'s April 1987 tour of <LOCATION> Chile </LOCATION> and were drawing on that experience. At a Roman Catholic retreat in <LOCATION> Punta </LOCATION> <LOCATION> de </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Tralca </LOCATION>, a coastal community 60 miles west of <LOCATION> Santiago </LOCATION>, hundreds of `` first-level'' volunteers from across the country receive intensive training in three-day sessions. They are required to recruit other volunteers in their regions, who in turn will seek out more participants in each community. When the voting takes place, the crusade will be out to try to ensure `` that there is no undue pressure from any sector,'' she said. The Punta de Tralca training sessions have a distinct Catholic, missionary flavor. Upon graduation, the trainees sing a religious hymn and are given neckerchiefs of yellow and white, the <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION> colors. The crusade's logo, of the same colors, is in the shape of a cross. <LOCATION> Chile </LOCATION>, like other <LOCATION> Latin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> countries, is overwhelmingly <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION>. At the end of one recent training session, a <LOCATION> Santiago </LOCATION> priest, the Rev. <PERSON> Pedro </PERSON> <PERSON> Arregui </PERSON>, told the volunteers they were `` like lights, small and fragile, that are going to light up <LOCATION> Chile </LOCATION> from end to end.'' `` You are carriers of a great message, a message that should change this nation,'' he said. Above him a broad banner quoted Pope <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> II: `` <LOCATION> Chile </LOCATION> has a vocation of comprehension, not confrontation.'' Mrs. <PERSON> Jimenez </PERSON> said a central goal of the crusade is to inject some reason into <LOCATION> Chile </LOCATION>'s highly impassioned political arena, where pro- and anti-government sectors wildly sling charges at each other. For the opposition, <PERSON> Pinochet </PERSON> is a bloodstained tyrant, while he calls opposition leaders the selfish pawns of international communism. `` An important number of people have already decided whether to vote yes or no,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Jimenez </PERSON> said. `` But when you talk to them, you realize that often they are decisions of an emotional, not rational, basis.'' The more rational the political debate, the less likely it is that turmoil will break out when the election is decided, she said. `` We are trying to promote proper civic behavior.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880421-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-21-88 0246EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a BC-Dance     04-21 0395</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Dance,0409</SECOND>
<HEAD>Ballet Theater's New `Gaite Parisienne' Is Kaleidoscopic</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: No PMs Planned</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By MARY CAMPBELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 American Ballet Theater's new production of `` Gaite Parisienne'' is more extravagantly colorful than a kaleidoscope. The dancing and ebullient Offenbach music hold their own so it's really a spirit-lifting ballet and not just a theatrical fashion show Still, on first viewing Wednesday, one was primarily dazzled by the costumes of the cancan girls _ black hose and shoes with white polka dots, bright skirts with fuzzy pastel linings, blouses with huge polka dots and full sleeves gathered at the elbows above black gloves. <PERSON> Hilary </PERSON> <PERSON> Ryan </PERSON> as <PERSON> La </PERSON> <PERSON> Lionne </PERSON>, the celebrity of the hour, appeared in a lavish red headdress and gown _ the train had a train sewn on piggyback. <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> couturier <PERSON> Christian </PERSON> <PERSON> Lacroix </PERSON> was the designer and in the spirit of the occasion some women in the benefit audience wore <PERSON> Lacroix </PERSON> gowns. It was said that the ballet's lavish costumes cost more than $ 500,000, paid for by a private donor. <PERSON> Zack </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>'s scenery, with a pink polka-dotted bow holding up the chandelier, was the perfect setting The Leonide Massine ballet premiered in April 1938 in <LOCATION> Monaco </LOCATION>. It was staged for American Ballet Theater by <PERSON> Massine </PERSON>'s son <PERSON> Lorca </PERSON> and premiered in January in <LOCATION> Tampa </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Lorca </PERSON> <PERSON> Massine </PERSON> has gone for character more than plot in staging this ballet set in a late 1880s French cabaret. And there is much going on in this production; there are no quiet moments. Somebody _ waiters, maids, ladies of the evening, billiard players, soldiers and dandies or just the busboy _ is always dancing. It's as fizzy as French champagne. <PERSON> Susan </PERSON> <PERSON> Jaffe </PERSON> danced the glove seller on Wednesday, <PERSON> Amy </PERSON> <PERSON> Rose </PERSON> the flower girl, <PERSON> Johan </PERSON> <PERSON> Renvall </PERSON> the Peruvian and <PERSON> Victor </PERSON> <PERSON> Barbee </PERSON> the Baron. <PERSON> Eugenia </PERSON> <PERSON> Delarova </PERSON> <PERSON> Doll </PERSON> and <PERSON> Frederic </PERSON> <PERSON> Franklin </PERSON>, who danced the flower girl and <PERSON> Baron </PERSON> at the 1938 premiere, and <PERSON> Alexandra </PERSON> <PERSON> Danilov </PERSON>, who danced the glove seller at the American premiere at the Metropolitan Opera later that year, watched the ballet from a center box after being introduced from the stage. The evening began with <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Balanchine </PERSON>'s `` Stravinsky Violin Concerto,'' led by <PERSON> Leslie </PERSON> <PERSON> Browne </PERSON>, <PERSON> Susan </PERSON> <PERSON> Jaffe </PERSON>, <PERSON> Ricardo </PERSON> <PERSON> Bustamante </PERSON> and <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Hill </PERSON>. The stark music and movements and black leotards with white T-shirts provided a perfect prelude to a joyful burst of Parisian light, color and gaity.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880421-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-21-88 0247EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--China-Toxic     04-21 0140</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--China-Toxic,0145</SECOND>
<HEAD>Two Killed As Toxic Waste Escapes Reservoir</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Two people were killed and the livelihoods of 40,000 were threatened when a reservoir holding toxic chemical waste burst last week in central <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Shaanxi </LOCATION> province, the official <ORGANIZATION> China </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> said today. The newspaper said that on April 14 a gate collapsed of a molybdenum waste reservoir of the <ORGANIZATION> Jinduicheng </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Molybdenum </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mining </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, sending poisoned water surging into the nearby <LOCATION> Liyu </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION>. Molybdenum is a metallic substance used chiefly in strengthening steel. The deluge also flowed into two other rivers, washing away 137,000 trees, swamping 52 wells, toppling 25 wooden bridges and damaging 15 miles of river embankment, the paper said. Two villagers drowned when caught in the flood while crossing a river. The daily said villagers were warned not to drink from contaminated rivers and wells.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880421-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-21-88 0247EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--AuschwitzConvent     04-21 0160</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Auschwitz Convent,0163</SECOND>
<HEAD>Rabbi Says Convent at Auschwitz Being Renovated</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PARIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Roman Catholic Carmelite convent on the grounds of <LOCATION> Auschwitz </LOCATION> is being renovated, French Rabbi <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Fahri </PERSON> said after visiting the World War II Nazi death camp in <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>. Jews by the hundreds of thousands died in <LOCATION> Auschwitz </LOCATION>'s gas chambers. The international Jewish community opposed plans to establish a convent there and an agreement was signed Feb. 22 in <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> to move the convent to a nearby location within two years. <PERSON> Fahri </PERSON> said on Wednesday, `` During a pilgrimage I organized at <LOCATION> Auschwitz </LOCATION> on April 17, I could see that the building housing the convent had been completely sandblasted, both inside and outside. `` The facade and the roofing of the convent have been completely redone. Last year, the building was simply falling apart.'' He said a deputy archbishop at <LOCATION> Krakow </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>, seemed `` embarrassed'' when asked about the renovations and `` ended up by saying he did n't know anything.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880421-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-21-88 0248EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-POW-MIAs     04-21 0610</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-POW-MIAs,620</SECOND>
<HEAD>POW-MIA Groups Debate Need To Release Secret Government Data</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TIM AHERN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
