<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880719-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-19-88 2330EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p BC-CVN--JacksonText 6thadd   07-19 0428</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-CVN--Jackson Text, 6th add,430</SECOND>
<HEAD>ATLANTA: the people.</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 We must defend the poor and deliver the needy. Today in <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> there are more poor people than ever Most poor people are not black or brown. Most poor people are young, white and female. But what does it matter? Red, white, black or brown. A hungry baby's belly turned inside out _ color it hunger, color it pain. Most poor people are not on welfare, they work hard every day that they can. They sweep the streets. They work. They catch the early bus. They work. They pick up garbage. They work. They feed our children in school. They work. They take care of other people's children and can not care for their own. They work. They make the beds in the hotels we sleep in. They wear uniforms. No one refers to them by name. Hey you, here, go, do. They work every day that they can. They work in hospitals. They mop the floors. They wipe the fevered bodies of the sick. They empty their bed pans. They clean out their commodes. No job is beneath them. And yet, when they get sick, they can not lie in the bed they made up every day. <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> is a better nation than that. We are a better nation than that. Leadership must address the high moral challenges of our day. In the nuclear age, war is irrational. Strong leadership can never let the desire to look tough stand in the way of the pursuit of peace. Leadership. We can take the lead to reverse the nuclear arms race. At the very least, we should pledge _ a pledge the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> has already made _ that we will not be the first to start a nuclear war. First use leads to first retaliation and to mutual annihilation. Suicide is not a rational defense policy. We must choose another way. Leadership. We can build common security with the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. Shared efforts to work for peace. Joint ventures to wipe out malnutrition in the world, to explore the heavens, to develop them for peaceful purposes. Star Wars or a space development initiative. Redeem scientists held hostage by this mad arms race. Leadership. We must change our policy towards the Third World. Support international law. Respect self-determination. Defend human rights. Foster economic growth. Be consistent. Leaders must address the critical struggles in the world today. We can have peace in <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>. Stop the illegal war on <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>, and join the regional peace process that offers dialogue and hope.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>MORE</NOTE>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880719-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-19-88 2336EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p AM-CVN--Scene 1stLd-Writethru a0857 07-19 0489</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-CVN--Scene, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0857,490</SECOND>
<HEAD>Kennedys, Nephew and Uncle, Bring Crowd to Its Feet</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: TOPS with 6 grafs to UPDATE with reax to Jackson at
convention; PICKS UP 2nd graf pvs bgng, `The delegates'</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By HARRY F. ROSENTHAL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ATLANTA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The young man once known to the country as `` John-John,'' son of the Democrats' martyred president, brought convention delegates to their feet cheering Tuesday night and told them: `` Because of you, he is with us still.'' And later, the five children of <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> introduced their father, the candidate, to a hall so crowded they locked the doors. Hundreds of delegates, reporters, and convention guests were stopped by a police line after the fire marshal ordered that The Omni arena could hold no more. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> shared his big moment before the convention with the woman whose refusal to give up her seat on a bus in <LOCATION> Montgomery </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ala. </LOCATION>, more than a quarter century ago began the turnaround in American race relations. `` All of you think you are seated,'' he said as he introduced <PERSON> Rosa </PERSON> <PERSON> Parks </PERSON>. `` But you're really standing on someone's shoulders.'' The convention hall was a waving sea of red `` <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON>!'' signs as the runner-up in the nominee race appeared, after his children introduced him one-by-one. Not a single blue sign for <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, the Democratic nominee-to-be, could be seen. The delegates to the Democratic National Convention had been a rather undemonstrative lot until they welcomed <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> with a two-minute standing ovation. `` Over a quarter century ago, my father stood before you to accept the nomination for president,'' said the 27-year-old <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>. And then he introduced his uncle, who he said inspired his generation. As if to show that the <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> name still carries magic, the delegates stood and cheered again, for Sen. <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, the dead president's brother and <PERSON> John-John </PERSON>'s Uncle Teddy. It was a fitting prelude for the big show yet to come, <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s closing speech of his long campaign for the presidency <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, a spellbinding speaker, did n't disappoint the convention. Until he arrived, many seats were still empty. Like magic, they filled. `` Where was <PERSON> George </PERSON>?'' he asked repeatedly. And the delegates responded with a cascading chant, `` Where was <PERSON> George </PERSON>? Where was <PERSON> George </PERSON>?'' Said Kennedy: `` We all know the answer to all these questions. <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> is the man who is never there. And he wo n't be there after the clock strikes noon on Jan. 20, 1989.'' In fact, Sen. <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> was the second speaker of the evening to bring up `` Where was <PERSON> George </PERSON>?'' Earlier in the evening, Rep. <PERSON> Tony </PERSON> <PERSON> Coelho </PERSON> of <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> recited a similar litany and got a similar response. The two speakers may have been telegraphing a battle cry for the campaign to come. The question caused banners to bob up and down in the hall. The red `` <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON>!'' signs as well as the red-white and blue posters saying `` <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> for President,'88.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880719-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-19-88 2345EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p BC-CVN--JacksonText 7thadd   07-19 0430</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-CVN--Jackson Text, 7th add,440</SECOND>
<HEAD>ATLANTA: and hope.</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 We can have peace in the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION>. Mutual recognition for mutual security, land for peace. We must know that <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> security and Palestinian self-determination are two sides of the same coin. Security for <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> and its borders, its people. Justice for Palestinians _ peace for both. Reopen and expand Camp David. Help rebuild <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>. And pursue peace in the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION>. Seek the release of <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> and hostages. We reach out to them tonight. We must have freedom in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>. Enforce comprehensive sanctions against the terrorist state. Get <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> out of <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION>, free <LOCATION> Namibia </LOCATION>, support the front-line states in their struggle against South African aggression. We can act to end the austerity and desperation that burdens <LOCATION> Latin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>. Engage our allies, relieve their debt, offer a Marshall Plan for growth and development. Their debt is a factor in our deficit. To do all of this we need bold leadership and a new direction. Our challenge is put forth in the words of a poem: We have mastered the air, conquered the sea, annihilated distance and prolonged life, but we are not wise enough to live on this earth without war and without hate. I am tired of sailing my little boat Far inside the harbor bar I want to go out where the big ships float Out on the deep where the great ones are. And should my frail craft prove too slight For waves that sweep those billows o'er, I'd rather go down in the stirring fight Than drowse to death by the sheltered shore. Author unknown. We can win. But we must not gain the whole world and lose our own soul. Our soul is our youth. We must not lose them to drugs, violence, premature pregnancy, suicide, cynicism, pessimism and despair. We must challenge our youth with high visions, hope and dreams. They must not be put in an environment or taught to submerge their dreams. Young people, I challenge you this night, exercise the right to dream. Face reality, but do n't stop with the way things are, dream of things as they ought to be. Face pain, but love, hope, faith and dreams will help you to rise above pain. Use hope and imagination as weapons of survival and progress. Use hope to motivate you and love to obligate you to serve the human race. Dream. Dream of peace. Choose the human race over the nuclear race. We must bury the weapons and not burn the people.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>MORE</NOTE>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880719-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-19-88 2348EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p BC-CVN--Platform-Text 1stLd-Writethru a0688-a0689-a0691-a0692-a0694
07-19 1139</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-CVN--Platform-Text, 1st Ld-Writethru,</SECOND>
<TEXT>
 a0688-a0689-a0691-a0692-a0694, 5 Takes,990-up
</TEXT>
<NOTE>Eds: Updates with final version; no pickup</NOTE>
<DATELINE>ATLANTA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here is the text of the platform approved Tuesday night by the Democratic National Convention. The delegates added nine compromise amendments to the final platform. Five involved additional language on health care, the Cold War, a moratorium on flight testing of nuclear missiles, and <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> incorporated in the passages below. Four others _ dealing with a `` comprehensive budget'' plank; pre-natal care, the <ORGANIZATION> Womens </ORGANIZATION>, Infants and Children program and Head Start; <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION>; and education _ were contained in separate paragraphs that appear at the bottom. Democratic party officials said they were not yet certain where those four paragraphs will appear in the document.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>The Restoration of Competence and the Revival of Hope</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 We the people of the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, in order to initiate the changes necessary to keep <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> strong and make <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> better, in order to restore competence, caring and incorruptibility to the federal executive branch and get it working again fairly for all Americans, and in order to secure for our children a future of liberty and opportunity, hereby pledge our party, our leaders, our elected officials and our every individual effort to fulfilling the following fundamental principles for all members of the American family. We believe that all Americans have a fundamental right to economic justice in a stronger, surer national economy, an economy that must grow steadily without inflation, that can generate a rising standard of living for all and fulfill the desire of all to work in dignity up to their full potential in good health with good jobs at good wages, an economy that is prosperous in every region, from coast to coast, including our rural towns and our older industrial communities, our mining towns, our energy producing areas and the urban areas that have been neglected for the past seven years. We believe that, as a first-rate world power moving into the 21st century, we can have a first-rate full employment economy, with an indexed minimum wage that can help lift and keep families out of poverty, with training and employment programs _ including child care and health care _ that can help people move from welfare to work, with portable pensions and an adequate Social Security system, safeguarded against emasculation and privatization, that can help assure a comfortable and fulfilling old age, with opportunities for voluntary national public service, above and beyond current services, that can enrich our communities, and with all workers assured the protection of an effective law that guarantees their rights to organize, join the union of their choice, and bargain collectively with their employer, free from anti-union tactics. We believe that the time has come for <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> to take charge once again of its economic future, to reverse seven years of `` voodoo economics,'' `` trickle down'' policies, fiscal irresponsibility, and economic violence against poor and working people that have converted this proud country into the world's largest debtor nation, mortgaged our children's future by tripling our national debt, placed home ownership out of reach for most young families, permitted the rise of poverty and homelessness on the streets of <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, reduced the buying power of working men and women, and witnessed the decline of our industrial, natural resource and mining base, the unending tragedy of family farm foreclosures, an unhealthy dependence on foreign energy and foreign capital, and the increasing foreign ownership of our land and natural resources We believe that it is time for <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, within a strong commitment to fiscal responsibility, to reassert progressive values and reinvest in its people, to invest in new priorities, in lifelong education and training, in targeted economic development, in a healthy small business community and in retooled <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> industry; that it is time for the broad revitalization of home town <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, involving financial institutions in the provision of crucial credit by encouraging special commitments in exchange for bailing out those that are failing, reforming and expanding community reinvestment laws, and reversing the trend of financial concentration and deregulation, all combining to reverse the insecurity that has increasingly troubled our workers and their families in this rapidly changing society that has left some communities and regions behind. There is no good reason why the nation we love, the greatest and richest nation on earth, should rank first among the industrialized nations in output per person but nearly last in infant mortality, first in the percentage of total expenditures devoted to defense but nearly last in the percentage devoted to education and housing. We believe that government should set the standard in recognizing that worker productivity is enhanced by the principle of pay equity for working women and no substandard wage competition for public contracts; by family leave policies that no longer force employees to choose between their jobs and their children or ailing parents; by safe and healthy work places, now jeopardized by seven callous years of lowered and unenforced occupational safety standards for American workers; and by major increases in assistance making child care more available and affordable to low-and middle-income families, helping states build a strong child care infrastructure, setting minimum standards for health, safety, and quality, and thereby enabling parents to work and their children to get an early start on their education and personal fulfillment. We believe that the strength of our families is enhanced by programs to prevent abuse and malnutrition among children, crime, dropouts and pregnancy among teen-agers and violence in the family; by aggressive child support enforcement; and by emphasizing family preservation and quality foster care. We believe that <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> needs more trade, fair trade, an administration willing to use all the tools available to better manage our trade in order to export more American goods and fewer American jobs, an administration willing to recognize in the formulation and enforcement of our trade laws that workers' rights are important human rights abroad as well as at home, and that advance notice of plant closings and major layoffs is not only fundamentally right but also economically sound. We believe that we can and must improve our competitiveness in the world economy, using our best minds to create the most advanced technology in the world through a greater commitment to civilian research and development and to science, engineering and mathematics training, through more public-private and business-labor cooperation and mutual respect, through more intergovernmental partnerships, and through a better balance between fiscal and monetary policy and between military and civilian research and development. We further believe in halting such irresponsible corporate conduct as unproductive takeovers, monopolistic mergers, insider trading, and golden parachutes for executives by reinvigorating our antitrust and securities laws, reviewing large mergers, and discouraging short-term speculation taking place at the expense of long-term investment.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>MORE</NOTE>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880719-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-19-88 2351EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p BC-CVN--Platform-Text 1stld-Writethru 1stadd 07-19 0976</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-CVN--Platform-Text, 1st ld-Writethru, 1st add,990</SECOND>
<HEAD>ATLANTA: long-term investment.</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 We believe that the education of our citizens, from <ORGANIZATION> Head </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Start </ORGANIZATION> to institutions of higher learning, deserves our highest priority, and that history will judge the next administration less by its success in building new weapons of war than by its success in improving young minds. We believe that this nation needs to invest in its children on the front side of life by expanding the availability of preschool education for children at risk; to invest in its teachers through training and enrichment programs, including a <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Teacher </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corps </ORGANIZATION> to recruit teachers for tomorrow, especially minorities, with scholarships today; to commit itself for the first time to the principle that no one should be denied the opportunity to attend college for financial reasons; to ensure equal access to education by providing incentives and mechanisms for the equalization of financing among local school districts within each state; to reverse cuts made in compensatory reading, math and enrichment services to low-income children; and to expand support for bilingual education, historically black and Hispanic institutions, the education of those with special needs, the arts and humanities, and an aggressive campaign to end illiteracy. We believe that illegal drugs pose a direct threat to the security of our nation from coast to coast, invading our neighborhoods, classrooms, homes and communities large and small; that every arm and agency of government at every federal, state and local level _ including every useful diplomatic, military, educational, medical and law enforcement effort necessary _ should at long last be mobilized and coordinated with private efforts under the direction of a national drug `` czar'' to halt both the international supply and the domestic demand for illegal drugs now ravaging our country; and that the legalization of illicit drugs would represent a tragic surrender in a war we intend to win. We believe that this effort should include comprehensive programs to educate our children at the earliest ages on the dangers of alcohol and drug abuse, readily available treatment and counseling for those who seek to address their dependency, the strengthening of vital interdiction agencies such as the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Customs </ORGANIZATION>, a summit of Western hemispheric nations to coordinate efforts to cut off drugs at the source, and foreign development assistance to reform drug-based economies by promoting crop substitution. We believe that the federal government should provide increased assistance to local criminal justice agencies, enforce a ban on `` cop killer'' bullets that have no purpose other than the killing and maiming of law enforcement officers, reinforce our commitment to help crime victims, and assume a leadership role in securing the safety of our neighborhoods and homes. We further believe that the repeated toleration in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> of unethical and unlawful greed among too many of those who have been governing our nation, procuring our weapons and polluting our environment has made far more difficult the daily work of the local policemen, teachers and parents who must convey to our children respect for justice and authority. We believe that we honor our multicultural heritage by assuring equal access to government services, employment, housing, business enterprise and education to every citizen regardless of race, sex, national origin, religion, age, handicapping condition or sexual orientation; that these rights are without exception too precious to be jeopardized by federal judges and <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> officials chosen during the past years _ by a political party increasingly monolithic both racially and culturally _ more for their unenlightened ideological views than for their respect for the rule of law. We further believe that we must work for the adoption of the Equal Rights Amendment to the Constitution; that the fundamental right of reproductive choice should be guaranteed regardless of ability to pay; that our machinery for civil rights enforcement and legal services to the poor should be rebuilt and vigorously utilized; and that our immigration policy should be reformed to promote fairness, nondiscrimination and family reunification and to reflect our constitutional freedoms of speech, association and travel. We further believe that the voting rights of all minorities should be protected, the recent surge in hate violence and negative stereotyping combated, the discriminatory English-only pressure groups resisted, our treaty commitments with native Americans enforced by culturally sensitive officials, and the lingering effects of past discrimination eliminated by affirmative action, including goals, timetables, and procurement set-asides. We believe that the housing crisis of the 1980s must be halted _ a crisis that has left this country battered by a rising tide of homelessness unprecedented since the Great Depression, by a tightening squeeze on low - and moderate-income families that is projected to leave 7 million people without affordable housing by 1993, and by a bleak outlook for young working families who can not afford to buy their first home We believe that steps should be taken to ensure a decent place to live for every American. We believe that homelessness _ a national shame _ should be ended in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>; that the supply of affordable housing should be expanded in order to avoid the projected shortfall; that employer-assisted housing and development by community based nonprofit organizations should be encouraged; that the inventory of public and subsidized housing should be renovated, preserved and increased; that foreclosed government property should be restored to productive use; and that first-time home buyers should be assisted. We believe that we can rebuild <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, creating good jobs at good wages through a national reinvestment strategy to construct new housing, repair our sewers, rebuild our roads and replace our bridges. We believe that we must pursue needed investment through innovative partnerships and creative financing mechanisms such as a voluntary program to invest a portion of public and private pension funds as a steady source of investment capital by guaranteeing security and a fair rate of return and assuring sound project management.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>MORE</NOTE>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880719-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-19-88 2353EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p BC-CVN--Platform-Text 1stLd-Writethru 2ndadincemay21st.
07-19 1179</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-CVN--Platform-Text, 1st Ld-Writethru, 2nd add,990</SECOND>
<HEAD>ATLANTA: project management.</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 We believe that all Americans should enjoy access to affordable, comprehensive health services for both the physically and mentally ill, from prenatal care for pregnant women at risk to more adequate care for our <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> and other veterans, from well-baby care to childhood immunization to <ORGANIZATION> Medicare </ORGANIZATION>; that a national health program providing federal coordination and leadership is necessary to restrain health care costs while assuring quality care and advanced medical research; that quality, affordable, long-term home and health care should be available to all senior and disabled citizens, allowing them to live with dignity in the most appropriate setting; that an important first step toward comprehensive health services is to ensure that every family should have the security of basic health insurance; and that the HIV-AIDS epidemic is an unprecedented public health emergency requiring increased support for accelerated research on, and expedited <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> approval of, treatments and vaccines, comprehensive education and prevention, compassionate patient care, adoption of the public health community consensus on voluntary and confidential testing and counseling, and protection of the civil rights of those suffering from AIDS or AIDS-Related Complex or testing positive for the HIV antibody. We believe that the last seven years have witnessed an unprecedented assault on our national interest and national security through the poisoning of our air with acid rain, the dumping of toxic wastes into our water, and the destruction of our parks and shores; that pollution must be stopped at the source by shifting to new, environmentally sound manufacturing and farming technologies; that the federal government must promote recycling as the best, least costly way to solve the trash crisis, aggressively enforce toxic waste laws and require polluters to be responsible for future cleanup costs; that this nation must redouble its efforts to provide clean waterways, sound water management and safe drinkable ground water throughout the country; that our national parks, forests, wildlife refuges, and coastal zones must be protected and used only in an environmentally sound manner; that all offshore oil drilling in environmentally sensitive areas should be opposed; and that regular world environment summits should be convened by the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> to address the depletion of the ozone layer, the `` greenhouse effect,'' the destruction of tropical forests and other global threats and to create a global action plan for environmental restoration. We believe that all Americans, producers and consumers alike, benefit when food and fiber are produced not by a few large corporations and conglomerates but by hundreds of thousands of family farmers obtaining a fair price for their product; that the disastrous farm policies of the last seven years, despite record federal spending, have forced hundreds of thousands of families from their farms while others are struggling to survive; and that a workable agricultural policy should include supply management, reasonable price supports, soil conservation and protection of rural water quality, credit and foreclosure relief, the return of federally held foreclosed lands to minority, beginning and restarting farmers, the development of new uses and markets for American farm products, improved disaster relief, and the revitalization of rural <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> through new sources of capital for rural business and new federal support for rural health care, housing, education, water supply and infrastructure. We further believe that no person should go to bed hungry and that we must renew the fight against hunger at home and abroad, make food available to those nations who need it and want it, and convene an international conference of food producing nations. We believe that a balanced, coherent energy policy, based on dependable supplies at reasonable prices, is necessary to protect our national security, ensure a clean environment, and promote stable economic growth and prosperity, both nationally and in our energy producing regions; that the inevitable transition from our present, nearly total dependence on increasingly scarce and environmentally damaging nonrenewable sources to renewable sources should begin now; that such a policy includes increased cooperation with our hemispheric neighbors, filling that <ORGANIZATION> Strategic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Petroleum </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reserve </ORGANIZATION>, promoting the use of natural gas, methanol and ethanol as alternative transportation fuels, encouraging the use of our vast natural gas and coal reserves while aggressively developing clean coal technology to combat acid rain, and providing targeted new incentives for new oil and gas drilling and development, for the development of renewable and alternative sources of energy, and for the promotion of energy conservation. We believe that with these changes the country could reduce its reliance on nuclear power while insisting that all plants are safe, environmentally sound and assured of safe waste disposal. We believe that this country's democratic processes must be revitalized: by securing universal, same day and mail-in voter registration as well as registration on the premises of appropriate government agencies; by preventing the misuse of at-large elections, the abuse of election day challenges and registration roll purges, any undercounting in the national census, and any dilution of the one-person, one-vote principle; by ending discrimination against public employees who are denied the right to full political participation; by supporting statehood for the <LOCATION> District </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION>; by treating the offshore territories under our flag equitably and sensitively under federal policies, assisting their economic and social development and respecting their right to decide their future in their relationship with the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>; by empowering the commonwealth of <LOCATION> Puerto </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rico </LOCATION> with greater autonomy within its relationship with the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> to achieve the economic, social and political goals of its people, and by giving it just and fair participation in federal programs; by assuring and pledging the full and equal access of women and minorities to elective office and party endorsement; and by minimizing the domination and distortion of our election by moneyed interests. We believe in a stronger <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> ready to make the tough choices of leadership in an ever-dangerous world: militarily stronger in our overall defense and anti-terrorist capabilities and in the cohesion of our military alliances; economically stronger at home and in the global marketplace; intellectually stronger in the advances of our schools, science and technology; and spiritually stronger in the principles we exemplify to the world. We believe in a clearheaded, tough-minded, decisive <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> foreign policy that will reflect the changing nature of threats to our security and respond to them in a way that reflects our values and the support of our people, a foreign policy that will respect our Constitution, our <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and our traditional democratic principles and will in turn be respected for its quiet strength, its bipartisan goals, and its steadfast attention to the concerns and contributions of our allies and international organizations. We believe that we must reassume a role of responsible active international leadership based upon our commitment to democracy, human rights and a more secure world; that this nation, as the world power with the broadest global interests and concerns, has a greater stake than any in building a world at peace and governed by law; that we can neither police the world nor retreat from it; and that to have reliable allies we must be a reliable ally.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>MORE</NOTE>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880719-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-19-88 2355EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p BC-CVN--Platform-Text 1stLd-Writethru 3rdadd 07-19 1416</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-CVN--Platform-Text, 1st Ld-Writethru, 3rd add,990</SECOND>
<HEAD>ATLANTA: reliable ally.</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 We believe that our national strength has been sapped by a defense establishment wasting money on duplicative and dubious new weapons instead of investing more in readiness and mobility; that our national strength will be enhanced by more stable defense budgets and by a commitment from our allies to assume a greater share of the costs and responsibilities required to maintain peace and liberty; and that as military spending and priorities change, government should encourage the conversion of affected military facilities and the retraining of workers to facilitate the creation of new forms of communication, space development and new peacetime growth and productivity. We believe in an <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> that will promote peace and prevent war _ not by trading weapons for hostages, not by sending brave Americans to undefined missions in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION>, not by relaxing our vigilance on the assumption that long-range Soviet interests have permanently changed, not by toasting a tyrant-like <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> as a disciple of democracy, but by maintaining a stable nuclear deterrent sufficient to counter any <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> threat, by standing up to any <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> adversaries whenever necessary and sitting down with them whenever possible, by making clear our readiness to use force when force is required to protect our essential security commitments, by testing the intentions of the new Soviet leaders about arms control, emigration, human rights and other issues, and by matching them not merely in rhetoric but in reciprocal initiatives and innovation, which takes advantage of what may be the greatest opportunity of our lifetime to establish a new, mutually beneficial relationship with the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, in which we engage in joint efforts to combat environmental threats, explore peaceful uses of space and eradicate disease and poverty in the developing world, and in a mutual effort to transform the arms race that neither side can win into a contest for people's minds, a contest we know our side will win. We believe in following up the INF Treaty, a commendable first step, with mutual, verifiable and enforceable agreements that will make significant reductions in strategic weapons in a way that diminishes the risk of nuclear attack by either superpower; reduce conventional forces to lower and equivalent levels in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, requiring deeper cuts on the <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION> Pact side; ban chemical and space weapons in their entirety; promptly initiate a mutual moratorium on missile flight testing and halt all nuclear weapons testing while strengthening our efforts to prevent the spread of these weapons to other nations before the nightmare of nuclear terrorism engulfs us all. We believe in an <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> that recognizes not only the realities of East-West relations but the challenges and opportunities of the developing world; that will support and strengthen international law and institutions, promote human and political rights and measure them by one yardstick, and work for economic growth and development. We believe that we must provide leadership, compassion and economic assistance to those nations stunted by overwhelming debt, deprivation and austerity, and that we must work to promote active agreements between developing and industrial countries, and the major public and commercial lenders, to provide debt relief and rekindle and sustain economic growth and democracy in <LOCATION> Latin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION>, and the poorest continent, <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>, which deserves special attention. We further believe that we must enlist the trade surplus nations to join with us in supporting new aid initiatives to fuel growth in developing countries that, though economically depressed, are rich in human and natural potential. We believe this country should work harder to stop the supplies of arms, from both East and West, that fuel conflict in regions such as the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION>. Deeply disturbed that the current administration has too long abandoned the peace process in the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> and consistently undermined it in <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, we believe that this country, maintaining the special relationship with <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> founded upon mutually shared values and strategic interests, should provide new leadership to deliver the promise of peace and security through negotiations that has been held out to <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> and its neighbors by the Camp David Accords and to <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> by the <ORGANIZATION> Arias </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Peace </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Plan </ORGANIZATION>, which calls for an end to the fighting, national reconciliation, guarantees of justice, freedom, human rights and democracy, an end to support for irregular forces, and a commitment by the <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> governments to prevent the use of their territory to destabilize others in the region. Instead of the current emphasis on military solutions we will use negotiations and incentives to encourage free and fair elections and security for all nations in the region. We will cease dealing with drug smugglers and seek to reconcile our differences with countries in <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, enabling the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and other countries to focus on the pressing social and economic needs of the people of that region. We further believe in pursuing a policy of economic cooperation instead of confrontation with <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> and our other hemispheric friends; in helping all developing countries build their own peaceful democratic institutions free from foreign troops, subversion and domination and free from domestic dictators and aggressors; in honoring our treaty obligations; and in using all the tools at our disposal, including diplomacy, trade, aid, food, ideas, and ideals, to defend and enlarge the horizons of freedom on this planet. We believe in an <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> that will promote human rights, human dignity and human opportunity in every country on earth; that will encourage free speech and association and decry oppression in nations friendly and unfriendly, communist and non-communist, that will encourage our European friends to respect human rights and resolve their longstanding differences over <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Cyprus </LOCATION>; that will encourage wherever possible the forces of pluralism and democracy in <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> and that will support the struggle for human rights in <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION>. We believe the apartheid regime in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> to be a uniquely repressive regime, ruthlessly deciding every aspect of public and private life by skin color, engaging in unrelenting violence against its citizens at home and promoting naked aggression against its neighbors in <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>. We believe that the time has come to end all vestiges of the failed policy of constructive engagement, to declare <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> a terrorist state, to impose comprehensive sanctions upon its economy, to lead the international community in participation in these actions, and to determine a date certain by which <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> corporations must leave <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>. We further believe that to achieve regional security in <LOCATION> Southern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>, we must press forcefully for <LOCATION> Namibia </LOCATION>'s independence by calling for the end of <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>'s illegal occupation, a cease fire and elections, must end our counterproductive policy in <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION> and must offer support and further assistance to <LOCATION> Mozambique </LOCATION> and other frontline states. In sum, we believe it is time for <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> to change and move forward again in the interest of all its families _ to turn away from an era in which too many of <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s children have been homeless or hungry and invest in a new era of hope and progress, an era of secure families in a secure <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> in a secure world. We believe the <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> dream of opportunity for every citizen can be a reality for all Americans willing to meet their own responsibilities to help make it come true. We believe that governments at the national, state and local level, in partnerships between those levels and in partnerships with the private sector, exist to help us solve our problems instead of adding to them. We believe in competent, pragmatic governments, accountable to the people, led by men and women dedicated not to self interest but to service, motivated not by ideology but by American ideals, governing not in a spirit of power and privilege but with a sense of compassion and community. For many years, in state and local capitals across this nation, Democrats have been successfully solving problems and helping people with exactly this kind of innovative government. Therefore, the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> in convention assembled and united, the party of hope and change and fairness for all, hereby declares its readiness to end the stalemate in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> by challenging, encouraging and inviting the <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> people _ challenging them to do their patriotic best to meet their community responsibilities, encouraging them to protect and preserve their families, our most precious assets, and inviting them to join with us in leading the land we love to a brighter and still greater future of opportunity and justice for all.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>MORE</NOTE>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880719-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-19-88 2356EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p BC-CVN--Platform-Text 1stLd-Writethru 4thad</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-CVN--Platform-Text, 1st Ld-Writethru, 4th add,250</SECOND>
<HEAD>ATLANTA: for all.</HEAD>
<TEXT>

</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 Here is the text of the four other amendments added to the platform Tuesday night:
</TEXT>
<HEAD>COMPREHENSIVE BUDGET</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 We believe that it is time for <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> to meet the challenge to change priorities after eight years of devastating Republican policies, to reverse direction and reassert progressive values, to reinvest in its people within a strong commitment to fiscal responsibility. If we are seriously to pursue our commitments to build a secure economic future for all Americans we must provide the resources to care for our newborns, educate our children, house the homeless, heal the sick, wage total war on drugs and protect the environment. Investing in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> and reducing the deficit requires that the wealthy and corporations pay their fair share and that we restrain <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> spending.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>PRE-NATAL CARE, WIC, HEAD START</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 We further believe that our nation faces a crisis of underinvestment in our children, particularly in the early years of life. Strong, healthy babies with early opportunities that foster intellectual, emotional and physical growth begin school with an enhanced foundation for learning. There are few better investments for this country than prenatal care, infant nutrition and preschool education, and there are few more successful programs than WIC, <ORGANIZATION> Head </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Start </ORGANIZATION>, and prenatal care. We know what works; yet these successful programs have been starved for funds. The <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> pledges to meet this urgent need by providing the funding necessary to reach those unserved children who are _ and must be _ our national priority.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>LEBANON AND THE PERSIAN GULF</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 We support the sovereignty, independence, and territorial integrity of <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> with a central government strong enough to unite its people, maintain order and live in peace in the region. We are committed to <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> security and freedom of navigation of international waters, and to an end to the Iran-Iraq war by promoting <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> efforts to achieve a cease-fire and a negotiated settlement, through an arms embargo on the combatants.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>EDUCATION</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 We now spend only two cents of every federal dollar for education. We pledge to better balance our national priorities by significantly increasing federal funding for education.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880719-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-19-88 0111EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w AM-AIDEmployee     07-19 0112</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-AID Employee,110</SECOND>
<HEAD>Embezzlement Suspect Released On $500,000 Bond</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION> employee charged in the embezzlement of $ 1.2 million in government funds was released Monday on $ 500,000 bond. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Burns </PERSON>, an AID financial officer, was arrested last week on allegations of diverting unused government travel funds. <PERSON> Burns </PERSON>' brother and sister put up their homes as collateral to arrange for his release. Government prosecutors opposed releasing <PERSON> Burns </PERSON>, calling him a `` very serious flight risk.'' The government has put a restraining order on <PERSON> Burns </PERSON>' bank account, his home in suburban <LOCATION> Burtonsville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Md. </LOCATION>, as well as five cars and luxury goods allegedly bought with stolen government funds.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880719-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-19-88 0028EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Philippines 1stLd-Writethru   07-19 0580</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Philippines, 1st Ld-Writethru,a0876,0596</SECOND>
<HEAD>Rebels Reject Aquino Peace Talks Offer</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: INSERT one graf after 11th pvs, About five ... ADDING
Sunday's conditional agreement by guerrilla group to talks. Picks
up 12th graf pvs, In a ...</NOTE>
<TEXT>
.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>By CLARO CORTES</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MANILA, Philippines (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Communist rebels rejected new peace talks with President <PERSON> Corazon </PERSON> <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON> as a `` farce'' Monday, charging her government and the military merely wanted to trap leaders of the 19-year-old insurgency. Self-styled communist rebels meanwhile killed a provincial official Monday and a guerrilla spokesman warned of more killings as long as the government fails, he said, to prosecute human rights violators in the military. The general command of the communist <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>, in a statement sent by courier to news agencies, claimed Mrs. <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON>'s government lost its credibility following the collapse of peace talks last year Mrs. <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON> has said she would agree to new peace talks if the rebels made the first move. <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Fidel </PERSON> <PERSON> Ramos </PERSON> said the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> and the 250,000-member armed forces would abide by her decision. <PERSON> Ramos </PERSON> earlier turned down the possibility of reviving the talks, saying it would only give the rebels time to regroup. `` The president has spoken,'' <PERSON> Ramos </PERSON> told reporters. `` I do n't think there is anyone that will oppose any objective such as obtaining peace, but it must be peace with justice and honor. The rebel statement was in response to a call last week by the influential <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bishops </ORGANIZATION>' Conference of the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION> for the government and the guerrillas to call for a new cease-fire and revive peace talks. `` History repeats itself twice: the first as tragedy, the second as farce,'' the statement said. `` We can not ... respond positively to a call for a new cease-fire that will mean the annihilation of the revolutionary movement and its mass base. We have learned our lessons well from the duplicity of the Aquino government and its military establishment.'' The rebels accused the government of insincerity and charged that `` what the government and the military establishment sought to lay down was a trap that played on the good faith of the leaders of the revolutionary movement.'' About five members of the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> and dozens of its regional leaders were captured by the military in raids after the 60-day cease-fire lapsed in February 1987. On Sunday, the rebels' southern <LOCATION> Luzon </LOCATION> command said it was agreeable to peace talks in principle but claimed the government was setting unacceptable conditions. In a related development, police said two men who claimed to be communist guerrillas barged into a government office on Monday in <LOCATION> Lucena </LOCATION>, 60 miles southeast of <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION>, and shot dead city councilor <PERSON> Donaldo </PERSON> <PERSON> Alfaro </PERSON>, 54. <PERSON> Alfaro </PERSON> belonged to a government group organized to help the military curb rebel infiltration of local neighborhoods. <PERSON> Arnel </PERSON> <PERSON> Sandoval </PERSON>, spokesman of the <ORGANIZATION> Alex </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Boncayao </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Brigade </ORGANIZATION>, justified the guerrillas' continuing attacks on police, soldiers and government officials by claiming the government failed to prosecute `` notorious police and military human rights violators.'' The brigade is a Manila-based unit of the rebel army that has claimed responsibility for killing more than 100 police, soldiers and officials during the past year. In <LOCATION> Bulacan </LOCATION> province, police Monday arrested two suspected rebels who killed a policeman a day earlier in <LOCATION> Baliwag </LOCATION>, just north of <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION>. A gunman Monday fatally shot Vice Mayor <PERSON> Daud </PERSON> <PERSON> Talib </PERSON> on the island of <LOCATION> Jolo </LOCATION>, about 600 miles south of <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION>, police said. The area is a stronghold of Moslem separatist guerrillas.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880719-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-19-88 0035EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p AM-CVN--AthenianMiracle 2ndLd-Writethru a0859 07-19 0813</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-CVN--Athenian Miracle, 2nd Ld-Writethru, a0859,800</SECOND>
<NOTE>Eds: INSERT 19th graf with Jackson not presenting transition issue
during meeting bgng ``Sources said...</NOTE>
<HEAD>An AP News Analysis</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JONATHAN WOLMAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ATLANTA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 On the Sabbath, at <LOCATION> Salem </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Baptist </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Church </LOCATION>, the Rev. <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> considered the week to come and led a crowd of 1,300 in a chant that had become his convention rallying cry. `` Never surrender,'' he implored. `` Never surrender.'' That was Sunday. On Monday the convention dawned and <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> unveiled a new, more conciliatory chorus. He did not surrender, but with the gavel about to fall, he faced reality and _ to use <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' language _ agreed to let the quarterback call the plays. Following the unity news conference between <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> led 2,000 supporters and delegates in quite a different cadence: `` Discipline, Details, Hope.'' The summit allowed both men to declare victory, and for once <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> got in the final word. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, looking ahead to Wednesday night's presidential roll call, could not yet endorse <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, explaining gracefully, almost sorrowfully, `` I'm still looking for a <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> miracle.'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' gentle rejoinder: `` I do n't think we're going to have a <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> miracle ... we're going to have an Athenian miracle. Actually, it was something of a miracle to finally see these two fellows together after more than a month of <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s patented `` creative tension.'' As expected, precious little was being said publicly about Monday's meeting. Were <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> chatting friendly-like about the <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> dream and the need for Democratic unity, as <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> suggested, or were they simply splitting up the spoils of Democratic patronage? Either way, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> said, `` There's no deal.'' No deal is a good deal for <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>. Maybe it's even true _ although that seems farfetched. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> provided only one hint of his meeting-of-the-minds with <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, saying `` When the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> meets on Friday, it will be more reflective of the new <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>.'' <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> has said _ maybe a dozen times a day for the last few days _ that he wanted equity and `` shared responsibility'' with <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>. To put flesh on the bone, his aides put a handful of demands on the table, according to reliable party sources who declined to be identified by name. The sources described several of the <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> requests as pretty routine stuff: A greater role at the <ORGANIZATION> DNC </ORGANIZATION>. An expense-paid presence during the fall campaign. New language on some platform planks. `` If the man's got to travel, we're not going to let him fly commercial,'' said <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Warren </PERSON>, a longtime <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> supporter who has been involved in the negotiations. `` Make no mistake about it. What <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> needs, <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> will get.'' But then there was the explosive issue of transition guarantees. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> negotiators want the <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> team to hire <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> supporters for a hefty number of positions in the transition effort should <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> be elected in November. How many? One source shrugged and said, perhaps in joking, `` Half?'' Said <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>: `` It's not right to be in the seats on the floor tonight and not in the budget next January.'' This might not sit well with many <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> voters who will want to think they are pulling the lever for Dukakis-Bentsen in November. `` Is <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> going to call the shots? If he is, there are a lot of Americans who are n't going to vote for this ticket,'' said Republican strategist <PERSON> Ed </PERSON> <PERSON> Rollins </PERSON> on Monday. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> knows <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> could make hay with an agreement to share the transition with <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> would never mention the Dukakis-Bentsen ticket; he'd call it the <PERSON> Dukakis-Jackson </PERSON> ticket at his first campaign stop in the morning and he'd add a last stop in the evening to do it again. He'd say, I'll tell you who's going to set up a <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration _ me. Sources said <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> did not present the transition issue in the face-to-face meeting; he knew, surely, that whether or not the <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> demands were routine or outrageous, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> could not be seen as giving in to them. He needs to exhibit leadership, not timidity _ it's a fact of life as the campaign moves from the Democratic convention to the general election campaign. Oddly enough, <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> probably was in no particular hurry to sign onto a public deal with <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> anyway. He has 1,100 partisans at this convention, many of them more ideologically motivated than he, and bargaining for spoils is not exactly something <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> wants to explain. A deal. No way, suggested <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>. Using the same words he did in 1984 as he headed for a platform fight, he said on Monday: `` If you negotiate away your self respect, you lose before you get to the floor. We can afford to lose a vote. We can not afford to lose our self-respect.''
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Jonathan </PERSON> <PERSON> Wolman </PERSON> is assistant bureau chief for the <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880719-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-19-88 0209EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-ToyPistol     07-19 0162</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Toy Pistol,0165</SECOND>
<HEAD>Woman Realizes Pistol Is Fake, Hits Robber With Stapler</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PITTSBURGH (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 When dry cleaning shop owner <PERSON> Janet </PERSON> <PERSON> Castiglione </PERSON> realized the robber shooting at the ceiling Monday was firing a harmless cap gun, she got in a few licks of her own. She hit the man repeatedly on the face and shoulders with a stapler before he fled. `` I was fed up,'' said Ms. <PERSON> Castiglione </PERSON>, 48, who has been robbed before. `` And when he shot the gun and I realized it was a cap gun, I became very angry.'' The man brandishing what looked like a real revolver entered the R.J. Valet Cleaners in downtown <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION> shortly after noon. Ms. <PERSON> Castiglione </PERSON> said the man demanded money and began firing the cap gun. She pounded on him with the stapler, but when she slammed the cash register shut, some bills flew into the air. The man grabbed between $ 30 and $ 50 and fled, escaping in a car, she said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880719-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-19-88 0208EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-US-Gulf Bjt   07-19 0642</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-US-Gulf, Bjt,630</SECOND>
<HEAD>Iranian Move Could Lead to Reduction in US Gulf Presence</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GEORGE GEDDA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The prospect of an end to the Iran-Iraq war is raising the possibility that the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> will be able to reduce its military presence in the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION>, administration officials say. White House spokesman <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> alluded to that possibility Monday after <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> agreed to accept a <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> resolution calling for a cease-fire in its eight-year war with <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>. `` We have always said that as hostilities end and as the war ends, we were willing to consider a withdrawal,'' <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> told reporters in <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Barbara </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, where President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> is on a weeklong vacation. Undersecretary of State <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Armacost </PERSON> spoke in a similar vein last week when he said the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> presence will revert to more `` normal and traditional levels'' as tensions in the area abate. It was just a year ago this week that the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> began escorting Kuwaiti tankers operating as <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> flag vessels in the gulf, the key element of what has been a substantial <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military buildup in the waterway. According to official figures, the number of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military personnel in the region has increased from 2,000 to more than 15,000, while <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> ships now total 27, compared with six less than three years ago. The deployment has stirred intense controversy in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and elsewhere, particularly after the extensive loss of lives in two instances of mistaken identity. When an Iraqi jet fired on the USS Stark in May 1987, 37 <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> servicemen were killed. And 290 passengers died on July 3 when a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> warship shot down an Iranian civilian aircraft. As a show of regret, <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> offered to pay compensation following the Stark incident, and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> did the same after the downing of the Iranian plane. The American commitment to the gulf has been costly in other ways. The deployment has forced the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> to postpone ship overhauls and to reduce some forces normally assigned elsewhere, including <LOCATION> Western </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>. Both <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> deputy spokeswoman <PERSON> Phyllis </PERSON> <PERSON> Oakley </PERSON> called the Iranian acceptance of the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> resolution a `` major breakthrough'' that opens the way for an end to what has been the longest running large-scale war of the 20th century. They also said the Iranian decision could restore stability to the gulf region. But <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials `` do n't have a reading with any real definition'' on <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'s intentions, and he cautioned that ending the war `` is not going to occur overnight.'' An end to the conflict would remove one of three impediments to a more normal relationship between the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>. Diplomatic ties were broken in April 1980 during the <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> hostage crisis, five months before the Iran-Iraq war broke out. The other conditions the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> has said are necessary for a friendlier relationship are the release of the Americans being held hostage by pro-Iranian militants in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> and an end to <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'s alleged promotion of international terrorism. Iranian officials have made several inquiries of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> in recent months about improving diplomatic ties but the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration has not followed up on them except to ask whether the overtures were made by officials in positions of authority. Secretary of State <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> has said no response has been received. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials, speaking only on condition of anonymity, said <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> apparently decided to accept a cease-fire because of the country's declining economy and fading popular support for continuation of the war. Beyond that, <LOCATION> Iraqi </LOCATION> troops have scored major gains in recent months, leaving the forces of the two sides deployed roughly along the international border of the two countries. The officials said this would enable the combatants to reach a final settlement without either being forced to surrender territory to the other.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880719-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-19-88 0232EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Bush-Meese     07-19 0694</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bush-Meese,690</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush Aides Say Meese Ethics Report Won't Hurt Politically</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Meese Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TOM RAUM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Independent counsel <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> McKay </PERSON>'s conclusion that Attorney General <PERSON> Edwin </PERSON> <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON> probably violated tax and conflict-of-interest laws wo n't hurt <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> politically, a top aide to the vice president says. `` I would n't go as far as to say it's a dead issue, but it's not going to be a central concern, in my judgment, when voters go vote in November,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s campaign manager, <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Atwater </PERSON>, said Monday. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> aides contend that, for all practical purposes, <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> ceased to be a major political liablity for the vice president, the certain Republican presidential nominee, when <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> on July 6 announced he would resign. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, troubled by the accusations against <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>, previously had sought to make ethics in government a major campaign theme, calling for a tougher conflict-of-interest standard for all officials. However, the vice president had insisted he would not comment on the <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> matter until the release of <PERSON> McKay </PERSON>'s report. When that report was delivered on Monday, the vice president was not available for comment. He was in a remote part of <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION> on a 4 -LCB- - day fishing trip with <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON> that began on Saturday Speaking on <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s behalf, <PERSON> Atwater </PERSON> said of the newly released report: `` It's not going to have anything to do with this election.'' <PERSON> McKay </PERSON> concluded that <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> probably willfully filed a false income tax return, failed to pay taxes on time and broke a criminal conflict-of-interest law. The independent counsel said he would not seek criminal charges against the attorney general, however. Meanwhile in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>, one of <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>'s more outspoken Democratic critics in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> said he did n't believe <PERSON> McKay </PERSON>'s report would have any effect on <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' candidacy. `` I do n't think there is any partisan advantage or should there be a partisan advantage,'' said Sen. <PERSON> Carl </PERSON> <PERSON> Levin </PERSON>, D-Mich., whose <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> governmental oversight subcommittee investigated <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>'s involvement with the scandal-plagued <ORGANIZATION> Wedtech </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> `` I do n't think <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> is a partisan Republicans called for his resignation as well as Democrats,'' said <PERSON> Levin </PERSON>, who was attending the Democratic National Convention. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> in the past has said that the attorney general should be held to `` a high ethical standard'' and that he found some of the allegations against <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> particularly troubling. A <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> campaign aide who spoke on the condition of anonymity said <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>, by resigning, took away the McKay report as a campaign issue. The official said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> had n't been bombarded by questions on <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> since the attorney general announced he would step down. Before then, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> had been asked at nearly every campaign stop whether <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> should resign. When <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> announced he would step down as attorney general and said he was vindicated by <PERSON> McKay </PERSON>'s report, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said in a terse statement: `` <PERSON> Ed </PERSON> did the right thing and I wish him well.'' <PERSON> Atwater </PERSON> said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> would deliver a major speech on ethics in government within the next few weeks. `` I do n't want to upstage him on it. The speech is n't complete.'' Campaign sources said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s ethics proposals, long in the works, had been delayed to await the McKay report. In the past, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has said the new code he will outline `` will help us avoid the excesses of the past.'' `` People should come to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> to serve, not to profit,'' the vice president said in a recent campaign appearance. `` When a congressman goes bad, or a member of the executive branch betrays the public trust, you know and I know that it hurts.'' Before <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> announced his plans to resign, two top <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> campaign aides _ pollster <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Teeter </PERSON> and former communications director <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Teeley </PERSON> _ said publicly that the attorney general had become a major campaign liability for <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> campaign aides said they had not heard from the presumptive Republican presidential candidate since before he began the fishing trip. `` He must be catching a lot of fish,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> spokeswoman <PERSON> Sheila </PERSON> <PERSON> Tate </PERSON> said. He planned reappear on Wednesday _ the next-to-last day of the Democratic convention _ with campaign appearances in the <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION> area, and also was to campaign daily at least through Sunday.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880719-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-19-88 0232EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-OilWastes     07-19 0598</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Oil Wastes,600</SECOND>
<HEAD>EPA Said To Bow To Political Pressure In Oil Wastes Ruling</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JENNIFER DIXON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> relied on `` solely political reasons'' to reject a staff recommendation that some oil and gas drilling wastes be more strictly regulated, an agency employee says. `` Politics overrode science and we've never done that before,'' said <PERSON> Hugh </PERSON> <PERSON> Kaufman </PERSON>, assistant to the <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION>'s director of the hazardous site control division. `` This is the first time in the history of environmental regulation of hazardous wastes that the <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> has exempted a powerful industry from regulation for solely political reasons, despite a scientific determination of the hazardousness of the wastes,'' he said in an interview. <PERSON> Kaufman </PERSON> and another staff member, who spoke on condition of anonymity, said Sens. <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Texas </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Phil </PERSON> <PERSON> Gramm </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Texas </LOCATION>, and <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Nickles </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Okla </LOCATION>., pressured the agency, as did the <ORGANIZATION> Interior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> departments and some states <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> administrators deny their call was swayed by political pressure. The majority of an <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> working group that studied the issue had recommended that a small volume of drilling wastes come under stringent regulation as hazardous. But EPA Administrator <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> and <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Winston </PERSON> <PERSON> Porter </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION>'s assistant administrator for solid waste and emergency response, said in a June 30 report to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> they had decided that all oil and gas drilling wastes would remain exempt from hazardous waste rules <PERSON> Porter </PERSON> said it was `` certainly a close call ... not an easy decision,'' but that his `` conscience is clear.'' So-called `` associated wastes'' account for 1 percent of the total volume of drilling wastes but contain highly toxic materials such as benzene, heavy metals and corrosive acids that are regulated as hazardous in other industries, the <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> staff said. It concluded the wastes pose a threat to the environment if not handled properly and that states are largely doing a poor job of enforcing existing regulations. A draft staff report said the cost to the industry to regulate those materials as hazardous wastes would have ranged from $ 200 million to $ 500 million a year. `` However, relative to total production and the total volume of product, the overall impacts on the industry should not be unduly burdensome,'' the report said. `` It would have been a fly in the economic health of that industry,'' said <PERSON> Kaufman </PERSON>, a frequent public critic of top-level agency decisions. <PERSON> Kaufman </PERSON> and officials responding to his accusations spoke in interviews last week. <PERSON> Porter </PERSON> agreed with the staff position that many states do not adequately regulate drilling wastes, but said another layer of regulation was not the answer. Hazardous waste laws can be inflexible and are not necessarily appropriate for the nation's hundreds of thousands of oil and gas wells, he said <PERSON> Porter </PERSON> wrote <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> that although the working group had wanted to regulate the low-volume wastes as hazardous, `` we now feel that removing any portion of the exemption would be too disruptive and burdensome to both the regulated industry and the regulating agencies.'' <PERSON> Gramm </PERSON> spokesman <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Neal </PERSON> said the costs would have posed a huge economic burden on an industry staggered by three years of low prices. Of the senator's push against the regulations, <PERSON> Neal </PERSON> said: `` If we'd do it again tomorrow, we'd do it just as strong.'' <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>, tapped by Democratic presidential candidate <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> to be his running mate, said the <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION>'s decision was `` by and large sound, though there are some areas that may require further clarification and explanation.'' <PERSON> Nickles </PERSON> said additional regulations would have hurt people `` already on their backs economically'' and that states are doing a decent job.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880719-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-19-88 0233EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Estuaries     07-19 0305</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Estuaries,300</SECOND>
<HEAD>EPA Names Six Sensitive Coastal Areas For Study</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JENNIFER DIXON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> has added six major estuaries to a list of ecologically sensitive coastal areas targeted for study on ways to improve their health and clean them up. Placed on the list Monday were <LOCATION> Galveston </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Delaware </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Delaware </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Inland </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Del </PERSON>.; the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York-New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Harbor </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Sarasota </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>; and <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Monica </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>. Estuaries _ where rivers meet the sea, and fresh water mixes with salt water _ serve as the principal spawning grounds and nurseries for at least two-thirds of the nation's commercial fisheries and are home to valuable and diverse species of fish, shellfish and wildlife, the <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> said They also are sources of `` irreplaceble recreation and aesthetic enjoyment,'' the agency said. `` Estuaries are clearly in trouble, threatened by toxic and bacterial contamination, industrial and municipal sewage discharges, agricultural runoff, oxygen-depleted waters and loss of fish and wildlife habitat,'' said <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> regional administrator <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Layton </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION>. Under the National Estuary Program, the bay studies are designed to come up with recommendations for long-term strategies for pollution control and resource management, <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> officials said. <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Dave </PERSON> <PERSON> Ryan </PERSON> said the studies, which can take as long as five years, are a joint effort of the agency and state and local officials, with states contributing 25 percent of the costs. The estuary program was established as part of the Water Quality Act of 1987 to identify and protect significant estuaries. A dozen estuaries are targeted for priority in the program, including the six named Monday. The other six were included in the program last year _ Albemarle-Pamlico Sound, <LOCATION> N.C. </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Buzzards </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mass. </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Long </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sound </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Narragansett </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> R.I. </LOCATION>; Puget Sound, <LOCATION> Wash. </LOCATION>; and <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880719-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-19-88 0233EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-US-EgyptAid     07-19 0414</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-US-Egypt Aid,400</SECOND>
<HEAD>Effectiveness of U.S. Aid To Egypt Questioned</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CARL HARTMAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Two government reports question the effectiveness of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> assistance to <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION> and cast doubt on whether the aid has brought about policy changes sought by the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration. A <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Accounting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> study of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> aid to seven countries, of which <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION> is the most populous, concluded that the <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION> has had `` mixed success'' in encouraging foreign policy reforms. Another report, from AID Inspector General <PERSON> Hebert </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Beckington </PERSON>, criticized the use of $ 1.5 billion worth of machinery and equipment sent to <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION> between 1975 and 1986. <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION> got $ 819.7 million in `` economic support funds'' from the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> in fiscal 1987, second only to <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>. AID spokesman <PERSON> Timothy </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Leary </PERSON> said Monday that $ 115 million of the aid was transferred in cash to the government of President <PERSON> Hosni </PERSON> <PERSON> Mubarak </PERSON>. Most of the rest was spent on projects designed to raise the country's standard of living. The <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION> report said the cash transfer to <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION> was based on a document that described broad policy changes that the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government expected from <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION> but gave no details on how progress would be measured. The report, dated June 29 and made public this month, added that while the document listed Egyptian policy reforms since the previous transfer, it did not explain their meaning or how they related to what the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> sought. `` <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION> has not moved quickly enough to adopt the economic reforms necessary to address the numerous and costly inefficiencies that pervade the Egyptian economy,'' it said. The <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, in a comment included in the <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION> report, said there are countries where setting reform targets in advance will fuel political opposition on the grounds that foreigners are dominating economic policy. `` In some situations a less specific economic reform program ... may be preferable to a highly specific program with unrealistic expectations,'' <PERSON> Eugene </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> McAllister </PERSON>, assistant secretary of state for economic affairs, stated in the report. The AID report on <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION>'s use of U.S.-financed machinery and equipment blamed the inability of the Egyptian government, AID and contractors to coordinate procurement with actual construction. `` Large amounts were either not being used or used at levels much below what was anticipated,'' the report said of the equipment. The report, issued about the same time as the <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION> document, also cited `` the limited capability of government of <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION> entities to operate and maintain machinery and equipment.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880719-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-19-88 0234EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-StrattonProfile     07-19 0828</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Stratton Profile,830</SECOND>
<HEAD>Stratton: A Career Devoted to Strengthening Defense</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Stratton Retires</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KIM I. MILLS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> Democratic Rep. <PERSON> Samuel </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Stratton </PERSON> devoted his 30-year congressional career to working for a stronger defense, but it was n't until a Republican administration came into power that he saw his hawkish philosophy return to political vogue. `` I think that a lot of the difficulties that we have today on the subject of defense -LRB- are -RRB- primarily a matter of a generation gap,'' he once said. `` Those of us who ... watched the rise of <PERSON> Hitler </PERSON> recognize that military power is something that is very necessary to protect a free society. Costly and dangerous, but absolutely necessary.'' <PERSON> Stratton </PERSON> strongly backed the Vietnam War and believed the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> should have made a firmer commitment there. After the war, when defense became politically unpopular, <PERSON> Stratton </PERSON> stuck to his guns, going so far as to become the only <ORGANIZATION> Yankee </ORGANIZATION> among the `` boll weevils,'' a group of <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democrats </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> in </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> pushing for stronger defense. `` I've found in the last couple of terms that whenever I'm trying to get support on a particular measure, like not withdrawing troops from <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> or providing a more active response to the hostage situation, it was usually the Southerners who would line up in support,'' <PERSON> Stratton </PERSON> said in 1980 <PERSON> Stratton </PERSON>'s position got a boost with the 1980 election of President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> as federal spending shifted toward military buildup after years of what the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> Democrat considered overemphasis on social spending. <PERSON> Stratton </PERSON>'s son-in-law announced Monday that the 71-year-old congressman, a long-time asthma sufferer, wo n't seek a 16th term. The family spokesman, <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> Mott </PERSON>, cited <PERSON> Stratton </PERSON>'s health. Throughout his career, <PERSON> Stratton </PERSON> has favored most proposed increases in defense spending and new weapons systems, including the B1 bomber, MX missile and neutron bomb. He was a leading congressional opponent of a nuclear freeze proposal and has been wary of arms control agreements. But he considers himself a middle-of-the-road Democrat, and has voted for such `` liberal'' causes as a national minimum welfare payment, against an anti-busing amendment to the Constitution and, more recently, for economic sanctions against the South African government. `` The liberals think I'm too conservative and the conservatives think I'm too liberal,'' he once said. But <PERSON> Stratton </PERSON>'s defense positions have overshadowed his other work in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. Perhaps <PERSON> Stratton </PERSON>'s biggest disappointment was in never achieving his ambition to be chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Armed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>. In 1984, the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Caucus </ORGANIZATION> voted out the armed services committee's elderly chairman, Rep. <PERSON> Melvin </PERSON> <PERSON> Price </PERSON>, D-Ill., but chose the much younger and less senior Rep. <PERSON> Les </PERSON> <PERSON> Aspin </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Wis </LOCATION>., over <PERSON> Stratton </PERSON>, who was then the second-ranking In 1986, <PERSON> Stratton </PERSON> was among those who opposed <PERSON> Aspin </PERSON> as the caucus voted not to make him chairman again. However, <PERSON> Aspin </PERSON> won the chair back in 1987, and <PERSON> Stratton </PERSON> had to content himself with heading the subcommittee on procurement and military nuclear systems. Because of his role in procurement, <PERSON> Stratton </PERSON> was among those congressmen recently rumored to be targets of the ongoing <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> probe. He has not been charged with any crime, however, and has denied any involvement in the investigation. <PERSON> Stratton </PERSON> was born in 1916 in <LOCATION> Yonkers </LOCATION>, N.Y. He attended school in <LOCATION> Rochester </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Schenectady </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION>, and graduated from the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rochester </ORGANIZATION>. He holds masters degrees from <ORGANIZATION> Haverford </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. He was commissioned as an ensign in the <ORGANIZATION> Naval </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reserve </ORGANIZATION> in 1942, and served in the <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> during World War II as a naval combat intelligence officer on the staff of Gen. <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON> <PERSON> MacArthur </PERSON>. He was twice awarded the Bronze Star and retired from the <ORGANIZATION> Naval </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reserve </ORGANIZATION> at the rank of captain. A former mayor of <LOCATION> Schenectady </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Stratton </PERSON> was first elected to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> in 1958. He was the first Democrat since 1916 to be sent to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> from what was then <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>'s 32nd Congressional District. Despite several redistrictings by the Republicans to force him out, <PERSON> Stratton </PERSON> has returned to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> with ease every two years from what is now the 23rd Congressional District. He has been dean of the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> delegation since 1978. As <LOCATION> Schenectady </LOCATION> mayor in the 1950s, <PERSON> Stratton </PERSON> fulfilled a campaign promise to clean up the city by leading a police raid on a gambling den in the shadow of City Hall. He also sparked an investigation that led to the resignation of the police chief. But because the pay from his official post was small, <PERSON> Stratton </PERSON> supplemented his income by becoming an announcer and newscaster for several local radio and television stations. He also appeared on TV as the character `` <PERSON> Sagebrush </PERSON> <PERSON> Sam </PERSON>,'' who dressed as a cowboy and played harmonica. In 1962, <PERSON> Stratton </PERSON> attempted to shift his focus to statewide politics, seeking the gubernatorial nomination. But party leaders gave the nod to then-U.S. Attorney <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Morgenthau </PERSON>. In 1964, <PERSON> Stratton </PERSON> thought he had a better shot at <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> senator, but his effort was thwarted when <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> entered the fray.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880719-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-19-88 0237EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Meese-WarofWords     07-19 0675</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Meese-War of Words,650</SECOND>
<HEAD>End of Meese Investigation Looses War of Words</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID BRISCOE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Attorney General <PERSON> Edwin </PERSON> <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON> has nothing but angry words for a $ 1.7 million investigation into his ethics that he believes both vindicates him and will allow him to ask the government to pay his legal fees. Independent counsel <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> McKay </PERSON> ended a 14-month investigation of <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> by issuing a lengthy report Monday while making no formal charges. But the report precipitated an immediate war of words between <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> and his lawyers and <PERSON> McKay </PERSON>. After court personnel handed out 6-inch-thick piles of documents to more than 100 journalists who had waited in line as long as 2 -LCB- hours at the federal court building, the combatants began a string of news conferences at the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Club </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> lawyer <PERSON> Nathan </PERSON> <PERSON> Lewin </PERSON> compared <PERSON> McKay </PERSON> to a `` hit-and-run'' driver for accusing the attorney general of crimes and then running away from filing charges. `` It was a cheap shot,'' <PERSON> Lewin </PERSON> said. He called the investigation `` a total bust, a colossal blunder'' and scoffed at the prosecutor's 814-page report, downplaying the length of his own filing which was nearly as thick but printed on only one side of each page. <PERSON> Lewin </PERSON> said his rebuttal, with sections titled `` Fishing in Foreign Policy Water,'' `` The Empty Net'' and `` Procrastination is not Willfulness,'' was more readable than <PERSON> McKay </PERSON>'s. <PERSON> Lewin </PERSON> accused <PERSON> McKay </PERSON> of stretching statutes `` beyond what any reasonable prosecutor would do,'' of trying to make an <LOCATION> Iraqi </LOCATION> pipeline project look like `` the opening of a McDonald's franchise in <LOCATION> Baghdad </LOCATION>'' and of making groundless accusations to justify the high cost of his fruitless investigation. An hour later, <PERSON> McKay </PERSON> held his own news conference and repeated for television cameras the accusations made against <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> in his report: that <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> filed a false tax return, missed a tax filing deadline and dealt with two separate matters that might affect the telephone industry while holding stock in a local telephone company. In addition, <PERSON> McKay </PERSON> accused <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>, both in the report and at the news conference, of insensitivity in dealings as a government official with his close friend, <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Wallach </PERSON>. But <PERSON> McKay </PERSON> said he was using his `` prosecutorial discretion'' not to bring formal charges against <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> because such offenses ordinarily would not lead to prosecution of a person who was not attorney general. He said neither <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> nor his wife, <PERSON> Ursula </PERSON>, had a history of tax evasion and he had no evidence that the attorney general took any of the illegal actions for personal gain or that he deliberately lied. <PERSON> McKay </PERSON> defended the high cost of the investigation. `` I did n't spend it personally,'' he quipped `` I feel confident we have not wasted any government funds, any of the taxpayers' money.'' Asked how he would respond to a lawsuit from <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> if one were filed, he said, `` I've been sued before.'' Finally, <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> strode into the same hall where <PERSON> McKay </PERSON> had just appeared, angrily defending all his actions _ and attacking <PERSON> McKay </PERSON>. `` I'm glad that finally the long ordeal is over,'' <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> said. `` But I'm outraged at the tarnishing of our system of justice that has gone on this afternoon and with the filing of this report by the independent counsel. `` I am appalled that <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> McKay </PERSON> came in front of you and violated every principle of fairness and decency.'' `` I've always acted legally, ethically and properly,'' <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> said, `` and any implication by the independent counsel that I have in any way violated any law is absolutely false.'' <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> said it went against the American judicial system for a court official to publicly accuse someone of a crime and then not file charges. `` If anybody did that in the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, they'd be fired,'' he said. <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> said he would not disclose whether he would take any legal action against <PERSON> McKay </PERSON>, but he said he would ask the government to pay his legal expenses which lawyer <PERSON> Lewin </PERSON> said were approaching $ 250,000 six months ago. <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> said he did n't know how much the total bill would be.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880719-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-19-88 0237EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Reagan     07-19 0724</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Reagan,700</SECOND>
<HEAD>Reagan Remains Pleased With Meese</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MERRILL HARTSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SANTA BARBARA, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
