<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881025-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-25-88 2329EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p AM-Dukakis 1stLd-Writethru a0672 10-25 0690</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Dukakis, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0672,660</SECOND>
<HEAD>Dukakis, Stung By Tank Ad, Says Democrats Favor Strong Defense</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: SUBS 15th graf, Dukakis aides..., to CORRECT Dukakis aides'
statement on polls.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By WILLIAM M. WELCH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PLEASANT HILL, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrat <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> on Tuesday denounced a new Republican campaign commercial ridiculing him for riding in an Army tank and asserted that `` we Democrats are for a strong defense.'' The <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> governor toured friendly territory in the <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> suburbs in a state where h found discouraging polls showing GOP rival <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> leading in the presidential race. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> responded by taking virtually every opportunity to appear on network television, while refusing to hold a news conference or take questions from reporters traveling with him. He was appearing on <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Nightline'' program Tuesday night for a 90-minute interview with <PERSON> Ted </PERSON> <PERSON> Koppel </PERSON>, who was meeting him in <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' wife and children appeared on <PERSON> Phil </PERSON> <PERSON> Donahue </PERSON>'s program Aides said <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> would be interviewed by <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Rather </PERSON> on Thursday's <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Evening </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> program in a session expected to last 14 minutes _ extraordinarily long for an evening news show. His running mate, Sen. <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, was to be interviewed on the same program for eight minutes Wednesday. `` Now they've got a tank ad _ has all kinds of misstatements and outright falsehoods,'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> said Tuesday. `` We Democrats are for a strong defense.'' The <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> campaign's tank ad uses videotape of <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> wearing a helmet and riding in the turrent of an M-1 tank at a defense contractor's plant in <LOCATION> Sterling </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Heights </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mich. </LOCATION>, last month, and suggests that he is weak on defense. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> said the tank ad is part of `` the distortions, the lies and the misrepresentations we've had in this campaign _ and there have been many.'' His campaign advisers vigorously denied the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> ad's contention that <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> opposes virtually every new weapons system. Campaign manager <PERSON> Susan </PERSON> <PERSON> Estrich </PERSON> said <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> favors the Trident II missile, the advanced cruise missile, the Seawolf attack submarine, the C-17 transport aircraft and the YF-22 A @ 23A advanced tactical fighter. `` There are lies, damn lies and <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s commercials,'' she said. Press secretary <PERSON> Dayton </PERSON> <PERSON> Duncan </PERSON> said the ad wrongly claims that <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> opposes the Stealth bomber. `` That's a lie,'' he said. He also said the governor was wrongly accused of opposing several missile systems. On the second day of <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' tour of <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, a new front-page poll by the <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> showed him falling further behind <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> in this state whose 47 electoral votes are crucial to the Democrats' chances of victory on Nov. 8. The poll showed <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> leading <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> among likely voters by 53 percent to 42 percent, with only 4 percent undecided. The survey of 1,376 people had a margin of error or plus or minus four percentage points. Some <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> campaign staffers and advisers privately acknowledged the Times survey was within a few points of their own figures. Battling the perception that <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> was slipping beyond his grasp, the Democratic nominee campaigned in the <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION> area, one of his strongest pockets of support, before large, enthusiastic crowds. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> addressed about 2,500 people at <ORGANIZATION> Diablo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Valley </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> and toured a day care center affiliated with the two-year community college. He spoke Monday night at a town meeting in another suburb and before a raucus crowd of precinct workers crowded into a gymnasium near <LOCATION> Berkeley </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> delivered stump speeches laced with populist appeals and denunciations of <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> campaign tactics. <PERSON> Duncan </PERSON> said internal campaign polling showed the complaints about <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s campaign tactics were beginning to register among voters. `` Our polling shows by overwhelming margins people are blaming <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> for the negative campaign,'' <PERSON> Duncan </PERSON> said. In addition to personal TV appearances by the Democratic candidates, the campaign bought five minutes of air time on <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> starting at 9:55 p.m. EDT on Tuesday and repeated a five-minute commercial aired Saturday night accusing <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> of waging a fear-and-smear campaign. Emerging Tuesday from a 20-minute meeting with local black ministers and political figures, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> dismissed reporters' questions about the polls `` We're just going to work hard, and we're going to win,'' he shouted.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881025-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-25-88 2335EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Peru-Crash 2ndLd-Writethru a0726 10-25 0662</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Peru-Crash, 2nd Ld-Writethru, a0726,0681</SECOND>
<HEAD>Aeroperu Plane Crashes, 12 People Killed</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: LEADS throughout with new death toll now at 12; American and
Europeans reported among dead; US Embassy comment; EDITS to TRIM. No
Pickup.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By MONTE HAYES</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LIMA, Peru (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An Aeroperu plane carrying 69 people crashed seconds after takeoff Tuesday from an Andes airport and airline officials said 12 people were killed, including an American and three Europeans. Aeroperu spokesman <PERSON> Freddy </PERSON> <PERSON> Chirinos </PERSON> said 56 people were injured and one person could not be accounted for. Survivors said there was an explosion aboard the Dutch-built <ORGANIZATION> Fokker </ORGANIZATION> F-28 just after it departed from the <LOCATION> Manco </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Capac </LOCATION> airport at <LOCATION> Juliaca </LOCATION>, 540 miles southeast of <LOCATION> Lima </LOCATION>. In a brief communique the state-operated airline said an American was among the dead and identified him as <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON> <PERSON> Harris </PERSON>, but listed no hometown. It said other foreigners killed were <PERSON> Kurt </PERSON> <PERSON> Lenz </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Switzerland </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Ervert </PERSON> and <PERSON> Ingeborg </PERSON> <PERSON> Psiller </PERSON> of <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>, but did not provide hometowns. Transportation Minister <PERSON> Camilo </PERSON> <PERSON> Carrillo </PERSON> told reporters in <LOCATION> Juliaca </LOCATION> that <PERSON> Fernando </PERSON> <PERSON> Bellina </PERSON>, the pilot of Flight 771, swerved the stricken craft in an effort to return to the runway but it crashed in a pasture. Witnesses said the twin-jet plane broke in two and the rear section burst into flames, and many of the injured suffered burns. Officials said an investigation was underway to determine the cause of the accident. In its list of people who perished, the communique said the bodies of three victims had not been identified and five Peruvians were killed, including an airline hostess. <PERSON> Chirinos </PERSON> said the four dead foreigners were among at least 19 non-Peruvians aboard. He did not have the hometowns of any of the foreigners. He said <PERSON> Caroline </PERSON> <PERSON> Dunning </PERSON> and <PERSON> Katherine </PERSON> <PERSON> Kraus </PERSON> of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Luana </PERSON> and <PERSON> Rafael </PERSON> <PERSON> Gianinazzi </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION> were hospitalized in <LOCATION> Lima </LOCATION> with grave injuries. The identified the 11 foreigners treated at the <LOCATION> Juliaca </LOCATION> hospital as <PERSON> Francois </PERSON> <PERSON> Savoir </PERSON>, <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Reilly </PERSON>, <PERSON> Bernard </PERSON> <PERSON> Mahoney </PERSON> and <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Krankin </PERSON>, all with <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> passports; <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Koyson </PERSON> and <PERSON> Brigitte </PERSON> <PERSON> Kahson </PERSON> of <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>; <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> Kabin </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Great </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>; <PERSON> Joacy </PERSON> <PERSON> Borge </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION>, and <PERSON> Esther </PERSON> and <PERSON> Ana </PERSON> <PERSON> Lopez </PERSON> and <PERSON> Gina </PERSON> <PERSON> Garfias </PERSON> all of <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION>. Officials at the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> said they had no information about the <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> victims. The plane was en route from <LOCATION> Juliaca </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Arequipa </LOCATION>, 120 miles southwest of <LOCATION> Juliaca </LOCATION>. Tourists often take the flight to return from visits to <LOCATION> Bolivia </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Titicaca </LOCATION> near <LOCATION> Juliaca </LOCATION> Airline and Puno state officials earlier had given different casualty figures, saying as many as 22 people had been killed. Aeroperu president <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Guerra </PERSON> had said 19 people died. <PERSON> Aeroperu </PERSON> said the plane had a capacity load of 65 passengers and four crew members. Police in <LOCATION> Juliaca </LOCATION> said four Peruvian legislators _ a sentator and three congressmen _ were among the victims. One of the lawmakers, Congressman <PERSON> Rolando </PERSON> <PERSON> Avila </PERSON> told reporters in <LOCATION> Juliaca </LOCATION> that the aircraft had traveled only about 400 yards after takeoff when the lights went out and there was an explosion. `` I thought our hour had arrived,'' <PERSON> Avila </PERSON> said. `` Everyone panicked. The pilots apparently tried to level off to land and the plane scraped the roofs of some adobe homes before falling near a small river.'' <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Guerra </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Aeroperu </ORGANIZATION> president, said the plane crashed one minute after taking off at 10:45 a.m. The airline said that within seconds after takeoff the pilot radioed the Juliaca tower saying the plane was losing altitude, he was returning and asked for emergency crews to stand by. Two months ago the <ORGANIZATION> Pilots </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aeroperu </ORGANIZATION> issued a statment claiming the airline's planes were in bad shape because of shortages of spare parts. <LOCATION> Peru </LOCATION> is virtually out of foreign currency reserves because of its economic crisis and is unable to import equipment for many of its industries. <LOCATION> Peru </LOCATION>'s last major air accident occurred Dec. 9 when a twin-engine <ORGANIZATION> Fokker </ORGANIZATION> F-27 crashed off the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> coast, killing 44 people including most of the members of the <LOCATION> Lianza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lima </LOCATION> soccer team.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881025-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-25-88 2342EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Egypt-U.S.Military     10-25 0407</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Egypt-U.S. Military,0417</SECOND>
<HEAD>Attorney Says Engineer Recruited By Egyptian Defense Minister</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SACRAMENTO, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An attorney for a rocket expert accused in a $ 1 million scheme to smuggle American missile technology to <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION> said Tuesday that <LOCATION> Cairo </LOCATION> officials claimed the operation had been approved by the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government. <PERSON> Marcus </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Topel </PERSON>, an attorney for <PERSON> Abdelkader </PERSON> <PERSON> Helmy </PERSON>, an Egyptian-born <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> citizen who was a rocket specialist at the <ORGANIZATION> Aerojet </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Solid </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Propulsion </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Company </ORGANIZATION> near <LOCATION> Sacramento </LOCATION>, said the American government possesses a report from <LOCATION> Egyptian </LOCATION> officials making that claim. <PERSON> Topel </PERSON> said he is attempting to obtain the document as part of his defense for <PERSON> Helmy </PERSON>, 40, who is jailed on a no-bail warrant pending a trial expected to begin next spring. <PERSON> Topel </PERSON> said <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> government documents also support his contention that his client was recruited by <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION>'s defense minister, Lt. Gen. <PERSON> Abdel-Halim </PERSON> <PERSON> Abu-Ghazala </PERSON>. In papers filed Monday in federal <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Sacramento </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Topel </PERSON> said <PERSON> Helmy </PERSON> met twice with <LOCATION> Abu-Ghazala </LOCATION> _ in <LOCATION> Cairo </LOCATION> in September 1987 and in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> last March. The papers said the general asked for <PERSON> Helmy </PERSON>'s aid in buying material for an Egyptian military research and development program. <PERSON> Topel </PERSON> identified the program as a joint effort with <LOCATION> Argentina </LOCATION> and perhaps other countries to develop medium-range missiles. `` Our investigation has shown these meetings did occur,'' <PERSON> Topel </PERSON> said in a telephone interview from <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION>. `` We expect at an appropriate time in trial to provide more than sufficient evidence that the meetings occurred. ... The appropriate time is not now.'' <PERSON> Helmy </PERSON>, his wife and another <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> were charged last June with money laundering and conspiring illegally to export technology for sophisticated weapon systems. Two colonels in the Egyptian army also were accused in the case but claimed diplomatic immunity. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> authorities claim <PERSON> Helmy </PERSON> received $ 1 million in payments from Egyptians for his role involving the illicit export of a substance called carbon-carbon or carbon composite. The material is a low-radar-visibility compound used in missile nose cones and Stealth aircraft. They accuse <PERSON> Helmy </PERSON> of belonging to an international export ring illegally sending sensitive material to <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION> has said it is cooperating with the investigation, but President <PERSON> Hosni </PERSON> <PERSON> Mubarak </PERSON> has said the Egyptian defendants were guilty only of procedural errors and had committed no crimes. Federal prosecutors have declined comment on the defense allegations. They have until Nov. 7 to file a formal response in District Court. A hearing is scheduled for Dec. 1.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881025-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-25-88 2343EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Nielsens     10-25 0380</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nielsens,0391</SECOND>
<HEAD>World Series Tops Week; `Roseanne' Joins Top 10</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KATHRYN BAKER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Television Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 As baseball wrapped up its season, the new television season started taking place, as evidenced by a weekly Nielsens list that sported more entertainment shows and few reruns. The last three games of the five-game World Series joined `` The Cosby Show'' to give <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> the top four spots in the <ORGANIZATION> A.C. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nielsen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> rankings and a substantial victory last week. But everybody got a share of the top 10, with <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> adding its new sitcom `` Roseanne,'' the highest-rated premiere of an <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> comedy since `` Joanie Loves Chachi'' 6 -LCB- years ago. <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> won the Sunday movie battle and got a top 10 rating from the conclusion of the two-part movie `` Jack the Ripper.'' The final game between the <ORGANIZATION> Los </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Angeles </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dodgers </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Oakland </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> A </ORGANIZATION>'s was the week's highest-rated program with a 26.3 rating and 43 share. <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> won the week with an average prime-time rating of 18.8 to <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s 13.9 and CBS' 12.7. A rating point equals 904,000 homes with televisions. The share is a percentage of sets in use. The average rating for <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s coverage of the Series was 23.7, one point higher than the first five games of last year's series between <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Louis </LOCATION>. The top-rated shows of the week were: `` World Series _ Game 5,'' `` The Cosby Show,'' `` World Series _ Game 3'' and `` World Series _ Game 4,'' all on <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>; `` Roseanne'' and `` Who's the Boss?'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>; `` NBC Monday Night Movie _ Double Standard;'' `` 60 Minutes,'' `` CBS Sunday Movie _ Jack the Ripper, Part Two'' and `` Murder, She Wrote,'' CBS. <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` World News Tonight'' and the `` CBS Evening News'' tied for first place in the news category with an average 10.2 and 20 share. `` NBC Nightly News,'' pre-empted by baseball, had an 8.9 and 18. <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s limited-run remake of `` Mission Impossible'' made its debut at 24th. <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s new `` Empty Nest'' was 16th. But `` Something Is Out There,'' based on last season's successful <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> miniseries, ranked only 42nd. The lowest-rated shows of the week were: `` Bugs Bunny: Battle of the Video Stars,'' `` Wiseguy special,'' `` 48 Hours,'' `` Incredible Sunday,'' `` <ORGANIZATION> Smothers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Brothers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Special </ORGANIZATION>,'' `` MacGyver,'' `` West 57th,'' `` High Risk,'' `` Live! <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Clark </PERSON> Present'' and `` <ORGANIZATION> Simon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> Simon </PERSON>.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881025-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-25-88 2349EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-NielsensList     10-25 0482</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nielsens List,0535</SECOND>
<HEAD>List of Week's Top-Rated TV Shows</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Year-to-date and FOX rankings not available.</NOTE>
<HEAD>With PM-Nielsens</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the prime-time television ratings as compiled by the <ORGANIZATION> A.C. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nielsen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> for the week of Oct. 17-23. Top 20 listings include the week's ranking, rating for the week, and total homes. A rating measures the percentage of the nation's 90.4 million TV homes. 1. `` World Series Game 5,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 26.3 rating, 23.8 million homes. 2. `` The Cosby Show,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 25.9, 23.4 million homes. 3. `` World Series Game 3,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 24.7, 22.3 million homes. 4. `` World Series Game 4,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 24.0, 21.7 million homes. 5. `` Roseanne,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 23.7, 21.4 million homes. 6. `` Who's the Boss?'', <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 21.8, 19.7 million homes. 7. `` Double Standard'' _ `` <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> Monday Night Movies,'' 21.1, 19.1 million homes. 8. `` 60 Minutes,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 20.7, 18.7 million homes. 9. `` Jack the Ripper,'' Part 2, _ `` CBS Sunday Movie,'' 20.3, 18.4 million homes. 10. `` Murder, She Wrote,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 20.1, 18.2 million homes. 11. `` Golden Girls,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 19.2, 17.4 million homes. 12. `` Growing Pains,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 19.1, 17.3 million homes. 13. `` Head of the Class,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 18.8, 17.0 million homes. 14. `` ALF,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 18.6, 16.8 million homes. 15. `` The <PERSON> Hogan </PERSON> Family,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 17.7, 16.0 million homes. 16. `` Empty Nest,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 16.5, 14.9 million homes. 17. `` Dance Til Dawn'' _ `` NBC Sunday Night Movie,'' 15.8, 14.3 million homes. 18. `` Fatal Judgment'' _ `` CBS Tuesday Movie,'' 15.4, 13.9 million homes. 19. `` Full House,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 15.2, 13.7 million homes. 20. `` <ORGANIZATION> NFL </ORGANIZATION> Monday Night Football: Buffalo vs. N.Y. Jets,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 15.1, 13.6 million homes.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 21. `` North and South,'' Part 5, <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 14.9. 21. `` 60 Minutes: Retrospective II,'' CBS, 14.9. 23. `` Jack the Ripper,'' Part 1, _ `` CBS Friday Movie,'' 14.8. 24. `` Mission: Impossible,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 14.5. 25. `` Amen,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 14.2. 25. `` Mr. <PERSON> Belvedere </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 14.2. 27. `` Perfect Strangers,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 14.1. 27. `` Glitz'' _ `` Friday Movie of the Week,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 14.1. 29. `` North and South,'' Part 2, <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.8. 30. `` 227,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.7. 31. `` 20-20,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.4. 32. `` World Series Pre-game 3,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.3. 33. `` Just the Ten of Us,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.8. 33. `` North and South,'' Part 1, <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.8. 33. `` North and <LOCATION> South </LOCATION>,'' Part 3, <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.8. 33. `` Goonies,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.8. 37. `` Out of <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>,'' Part 2, _ `` CBS Monday Movie,'' 12.7. 38. `` World Series Pre-game 4,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.3. 39. `` North and South,'' Part 4, <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.0. 40. `` Secrets Men Never Share,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.3. 41. `` Something Is Out There,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.2. 42. `` Something in Common'' _ `` CBS Thursday Movie,'' 11.0. 43. `` This Is <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Charlie </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>,'' CBS, 10.5. 44. `` Bugs Bunny Special,'' CBS, 9.9. 45. `` Wiseguy Special,'' CBS, 9.8. 46. `` 48 Hours,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 9.6. 47. `` Incredible Sunday,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 8.4. 48. `` Smothers Brothers Comedy Special,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 8.2. 49. `` MacGyver,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 8.0. 50. `` West 57th,'' CBS, 7.9. 51. `` High Risk,'' CBS, 7.3. 52. `` Live! <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Clark </PERSON> Presents,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 7.0. 53. `` <ORGANIZATION> Simon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> Simon </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 6.3.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881025-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-25-88 2351EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Killer'sAppeal     10-25 0350</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Killer's Appeal,0360</SECOND>
<HEAD>Mass Killer Gets Some More Privileges</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CAMDEN, N.J. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A mass killer confined to a psychiatric hospital since his 1949 rampage in which he gunned down 13 people can attend music and horticultural therapy sessions in a geriatric unit, a judge has ruled. <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> <PERSON> Unruh </PERSON>, 67, has been hospitalized since Sept. 7, 1949, the day after he opened fire on motorists and his east <LOCATION> Camden </LOCATION> neighbors, dashing through homes and buildings in a murderous rampage. Psychiatrists who have periodically reviewed <PERSON> Unruh </PERSON>'s case found him incompetent to stand trial. Each year, courts have considered <PERSON> Unruh </PERSON>'s hospitalization at <ORGANIZATION> Trenton </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Psychiatric </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION>. In 1980, <PERSON> Unruh </PERSON>'s attorney sought dismissal of the indictment to permit <PERSON> Unruh </PERSON>'s transfer to a less restrictive facility. Three years later, he was transferred from the Vroom Building for the criminally insane to an intensive treatment unit. In 1986, he was granted walking privileges around the grounds. In documents submitted Monday, defense attorney <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Klein </PERSON> asked the court to transfer <PERSON> Unruh </PERSON> to a nearby geriatric unit. But during Tuesday's <ORGANIZATION> Superior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> hearing, <PERSON> Klein </PERSON> withdrew his request, asking only that <PERSON> Unruh </PERSON> be permitted to attend the special therapy sessions. Judge I.V. <PERSON> DiMartino </PERSON> granted the request. <PERSON> Unruh </PERSON> attended the hearing, appearing to be more alert than in past court visits. He receives medication to keep his schizophrenia under control, said his psychiatrist, Dr. <PERSON> Manolo </PERSON> <PERSON> Mempin </PERSON>. <PERSON> Mempin </PERSON> said <PERSON> Unruh </PERSON> is the oldest patient in the unit, which houses 29 people, most in their 20s and 30s. <PERSON> Audrey </PERSON> <PERSON> Holland </PERSON>, program coordinator in the geriatric unit, suggested that the violent nature of other patients in the intensive treatment unit could endanger <PERSON> Unruh </PERSON>. `` He's out of place,'' she said. `` The patients are all very young and aggressive.'' <PERSON> Dennis </PERSON> <PERSON> Wixted </PERSON>, first assistant prosecutor in <LOCATION> Camden </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, opposed any change in <PERSON> Unruh </PERSON>'s hospitalization. He called the staff at the psychiatric hospital `` well-meaning, well-intentioned therapists who are firmly committed to the belief that no one is beyond help.'' `` Some demon went into <PERSON> Unruh </PERSON>'s head and locked his mind at a point where it can no longer be reached,'' <PERSON> Wixted </PERSON> said. `` We're faced with that reality.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881025-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-25-88 2352EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-APArts:BritishPublishing     10-25 1062</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AP Arts: British Publishing,1095</SECOND>
<HEAD>British Publishing Wrestles With The Age Of The Big Buck</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By MATT WOLF</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The genteel world of British publishing is awakening to the age of the conglomerate and wrestling with the question of whether books can be sold like bars of soap. `` Publishing has become a pitiless world, the stuff of boardroom battles and heart-rending drama. No place for gentlemen,'' writes <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Pringle </PERSON> in The Independent newspaper. `` Publishing was very much a cottage industry here. It's now a business,'' says <PERSON> Joanna </PERSON> <PERSON> Goldsworthy </PERSON>, a publishing director at prestigious <PERSON> Victor </PERSON> <PERSON> Gollancz </PERSON>. `` Business people forget that without authors, they're nothing.'' Such comments have sparked a heated debate about the place of corporations, especially American ones, in British publishing, where dreamy images of a gaslighted Dickensian era linger. The big guns deny they are cheapening literature, and few top authors are complaining about the vastly fatter advances being offered. `` You can find a Dickensian publisher, -LRB- but -RRB- no one wants to,'' observes London-based American agent <PERSON> Ed </PERSON> <PERSON> Victor </PERSON>. `` It's no good looking back and being wistful. The old days are gone. You're not going to go out and buy a Remington typewriter when you can buy a word processor.'' The trend toward conglomerates has encouraged some small quality imprints to take wing, rather as a neighborhood supermarket will spawn high-quality delicatessens around it. `` Were the good old days really all that good?'' said <PERSON> Ian </PERSON> <PERSON> Chapman </PERSON>, chairman of <ORGANIZATION> Collins </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Publishers </ORGANIZATION>, one of <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s most acquisitive houses. `` Conditions of employment, wages, and salaries were appalling,'' he said at a recent publishers' seminar. `` Since the mid -'70s, we've had to look to our laurels and become much more We're having to recognize that books should make a return on investment ... -LRB- but -RRB- they can still have the same love and care,'' he said. There's no shortage of books. In 1987, 59,837 titles were published in <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>, compared to 36,322 a decade before. But the increase is in output rather than quality _ hobby and special interest books rather than in exciting new fiction. Meanwhile, the gentleman publisher is becoming a thing of the past. In February 1986, <PERSON> Macmillan </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> bought the small British house of <LOCATION> Sidgwick </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> for 1.75 million pounds -LRB- about $ 2.5 million -RRB-. One year later, <ORGANIZATION> Random </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> bought the publishing consortium <ORGANIZATION> CVBC </ORGANIZATION> for 17.5 million pounds -LRB- about $ 31 million -RRB-. That purchase ended the independence of four noted British imprints _ <PERSON> Chatto </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> Windus </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Virago </PERSON>, <PERSON> Bodley </PERSON> <PERSON> Head </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jonathan </PERSON> <PERSON> Cape </PERSON> _ and gave <ORGANIZATION> Random </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> a long-sought British foothold. <PERSON> Virago </PERSON>, which specializes in feminist literature, bought its way out six months later and is now 90-percent independent. Takeover fever is not exclusively American. Over the past four years, British-owned Octopus has purchased <LOCATION> Methuen </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Secker </PERSON> and <PERSON> Warburg </PERSON> and <PERSON> Heinemann </PERSON>, three <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> houses esteemed for their independence and the attention they lavished on their authors. British publisher <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Maxwell </PERSON> has bid unsuccessfully for <ORGANIZATION> Harcourt </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Brace </ORGANIZATION> <PERSON> Jovanovich </PERSON> and is now trying to buy <PERSON> Macmillan </PERSON> in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. The two <ORGANIZATION> Macmillans </ORGANIZATION> have common ancestry but are now separate companies. Meanwhile, the prices paid for books have skyrocketed. <PERSON> Chatto </PERSON> and <PERSON> Windus </PERSON> bought <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Holroyd </PERSON>'s three-volume biography of <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bernard </PERSON> <PERSON> Shaw </PERSON> for 625,000 pounds -LRB- about $ 1 million -RRB-. Novelist <PERSON> Salman </PERSON> <PERSON> Rushdie </PERSON> left <PERSON> Jonathan </PERSON> <PERSON> Cape </PERSON> for Viking Penguin and a two-book deal reported at 850,000 pounds -LRB- about $ 1.43 million -RRB-. Penguin, a pioneer of British paperbacks, has also become an important publishing outlet in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. Bookshops reflect the changing status in the business. Sleek chain stores with shopping carts and glaring lights are supplanting those quiet, musty, idiosyncratic establishments of `` 84 <LOCATION> Charing </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Cross </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Road </LOCATION>,'' where one could browse and lose oneself for an entire day. If literature now represents lucre, some are wondering at what price. `` Authors at the moment are getting rather a raw deal,'' said <PERSON> Gollancz </PERSON>'s <PERSON> Goldsworthy </PERSON>. `` Publishing is becoming so much more of a business ... -LRB- that -RRB- publishers are forgetting at their peril that they need authors.'' Novelist <PERSON> Malcolm </PERSON> <PERSON> Bradbury </PERSON> agreed that practices had changed since his first novel, `` Eating People Is Wrong,'' appeared in 1959. `` I'm worried,'' the author said in an interview. `` These changes in ownership may result in remote companies whose prime interest is not in publishing, but in publishing balance sheets. `` The danger will be if we reach a point where commercial pressures become so intense that publishers can only afford to go with books that can sell in very large quantities.'' Octopus' purchase of <PERSON> Secker </PERSON> and <PERSON> Warburg </PERSON>, the imprint that gave <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Orwell </PERSON>, <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Mann </PERSON> and <PERSON> Italo </PERSON> <PERSON> Calvino </PERSON>, prompted an anguished open letter from literary agent <PERSON> Giles </PERSON> <PERSON> Gordon </PERSON> to Punch Magazine. `` Most of our significant literary houses are now shackled and restricted in the hands of managers, bureaucracies, corporate strategies,'' <PERSON> Gordon </PERSON> wrote. `` Your shareholders may be pleased. We readers are appalled. ... I beseech you, think it possible you may be mistaken.'' Calls to Octopus for comment were not returned. <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON> <PERSON> Burgess </PERSON>, author of `` A Clockwork Orange,'' argued in The Observer that the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> had set the precedent, and he saw a dilemma for authors. `` The impersonality of the whole proceeding is mitigated, for the author, by money. But money, strangely enough, can not easily compensate for the author's sense of being reduced to a commodity like soap or peanut butter,'' he wrote. <PERSON> Bradbury </PERSON> said that whatever the problems, the changes have advantages. `` The greater commercialization in the system has improved book-selling no end,'' he said. `` More books are bought, and newish writers are acquiring audiences through this distribution system at a far greater speed than they would have done when I started writing.'' Meanwhile, bucking the prevailing trend are a few new publishing houses seeking to fill the void created by the takeovers. In September 1986, <PERSON> Nigel </PERSON> <PERSON> Newton </PERSON> launched <ORGANIZATION> Bloomsbury </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> with 2 million pounds -LRB- then about $ 3 million -RRB- in capital, saying the surge in conglomerates spurred him on. <PERSON> Newton </PERSON> said <PERSON> Bloomsbury </PERSON> offered authors a tailor-made service increasingly unavailable elsewhere. Its fiction list includes both acclaimed newcomers such as <PERSON> Jeanette </PERSON> <PERSON> Winterson </PERSON> and <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Flanagan </PERSON>, and such veterans as <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Atwood </PERSON>, <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Irving </PERSON> and <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Bailey </PERSON>. One of its first commercial coups was the purchase of British rights to `` Presumed Innocent,'' <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> novelist <PERSON> Scott </PERSON> <PERSON> Turow </PERSON>'s best seller But might Bloomsbury itself be taken over? `` No, it wo n't,'' said <PERSON> Newton </PERSON>. `` We've received offers, but are committed to autonomy.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881025-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-25-88 2346EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Canada 1stLd-Writethru a0722 10-25 0579</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Canada, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0722,0596</SECOND>
<HEAD>U.S.-Canada Free Trade Pact Dominates Debate</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Editing and new material throughout, UPDATING with debate
finale. No pickup</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By SOLL SUSSMAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>TORONTO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The U.S.-Canada free trade agreement negotiated by Prime Minister <PERSON> Brian </PERSON> <PERSON> Mulroney </PERSON> dominated the debate Tuesday among leaders of the three major parties in a critical prelude to the Nov. 21 election. <PERSON> Mulroney </PERSON> said the agreement achieved by his <ORGANIZATION> Progressive </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conservative </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> was central to <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>'s future and he described his rivals' attacks against the pact as `` scare mongering.'' <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Turner </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Liberal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> and <PERSON> Ed </PERSON> <PERSON> Broadbent </PERSON> of the socialist <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> criticized <PERSON> Mulroney </PERSON> and then argued about who had most effectively opposed the agreement. The three-hour, English-language debate was broadcast nationally from <LOCATION> Ottawa </LOCATION> and followed a three-hour French-language debate Monday night. <PERSON> Mulroney </PERSON> said the agreement, scheduled to take effect Jan. 1, will allow <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> to move ahead and compete internationally to assure future prosperity. He challenged his foes to outline an effective alternative. `` They would tear up the free trade agreement and then what? They offer you nothing but the poverty of protectionism,'' he said. Turner again vowed to battle the pact. `` This election is not a popularity contest. The issue is the future of <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>,'' he said. `` He -LRB- <PERSON> Mulroney </PERSON> -RRB- now wants to turn us into a pale replica of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>.'' Polls early in the campaign that began Oct. 1 generally placed the Conservatives first, with at least 40 percent of the vote usually needed for a majority government. <PERSON> Mulroney </PERSON> called the election Oct. 1 after serving four years of his maximum five-year term. He won a landslide victory in 1984 and is seeking to put together a second consecutive majority government, which has not happened in <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> since 1953. The New Democrats pushed the Liberals to third in most polls before the debates. That would be a stunning setback for the party of former Prime Minister <PERSON> Pierre </PERSON> <PERSON> Elliott </PERSON> <PERSON> Trudeau </PERSON>. <PERSON> Broadbent </PERSON> also strongly attacked the free trade agreement. `` This deal must be stopped because it takes away our right to make decisions about our own country in our own way,'' he said. Critics of the trade pact say the huge population and economic power of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> would force <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> to renounce social welfare programs and regional development plans. `` What we have here is a deal that touches virtually every aspect of Canadian life,'' <PERSON> Broadbent </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Turner </PERSON> said, `` I hope Canadians defeat this deal by defeating Mr. <PERSON> Mulroney </PERSON>.'' <PERSON> Mulroney </PERSON> responded by saying Canadians are fully capable of competing internationally and there was `` not the slightest justification'' for raising fears of loss of identity or social protections. `` You've been scare mongering,'' he said. The <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> voted, 83-9, in September in favor of the trade agreement signed in January by <PERSON> Mulroney </PERSON> and President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>. In <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>, however, only the elected House of Commons controlled by the Conservatives passed it. Liberals in the non-elected <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> balked and kept the agreement bottled up. A <PERSON> Mulroney </PERSON> win with a parliamentary majority would let the world's two largest trading partners proceed to form a North American free trade zone on Jan. 1, eliminating all tariffs over a 10-year period and dismantling barriers to investment and competition. A Gallup poll published Tuesday by the <ORGANIZATION> Toronto </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Star </ORGANIZATION> found support for the agreement slippng, with 42 percent of Canadians opposed and 34 percent in favor. The others said they had no opinion or neither supported nor opposed the proposal.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881025-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-25-88 2354EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-FleetStreet     10-25 0908</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Fleet Street,0938</SECOND>
<HEAD>Newspaper Future Murky On The `Street Of Ink'</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</NOTE>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LESLIE SHEPHERD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Journalist <PERSON> Colin </PERSON> <PERSON> Webb </PERSON> says he is steeling himself for the day when someone says to him at a cocktail party: `` Oh, so you're in Fleet Street, are you? Banking or insurance?'' For <PERSON> Webb </PERSON>, editor-in-chief of <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, the domestic British news agency, this ignominy may be close at hand. As one newspaper after another flees Fleet Street for modern plants elsewhere, banks and other financial institutions are moving in along the thoroughfare and the narrow lanes wending south to the <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Thames </LOCATION> and north to <LOCATION> Holborn </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Street </LOCATION>. The short, crowded street and adjoining warren of crooked alleys and hidden courtyards, the haunt of <PERSON> Dickens </PERSON>, <PERSON> Pepys </PERSON> and Dr. <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>, was once synonymous with the newspaper industry _ noisy, grubby and exuberant. `` The man must have a rare recipe for melancholy, who can be dull in Fleet Street,'' observed the Victorian essayist <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Lamb </PERSON>. Now, as the capital's fulcrum moves east to the <LOCATION> Docklands </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>'s biggest urban renewal program, Fleet Street is gradually being absorbed into the neighboring <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>'s financial district. The shells of the newspaper buildings remain, largely because the entire street has been designated a conservation area to retain its Dickensian character. Behind the facades, however, the presses and newsrooms are being ripped out and replaced with trading floors and computers. Instead of printers and reporters rushing to meet deadlines, the street is full of construction workers and lawyers, stockbrokers and dealmakers. Property values and rents have soared as the conglomerates created by <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>'s blossoming financial markets compete for office space on the old `` street of ink.'' The first newspaper to capitalize on the property boom was the <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> Evening Standard. Its former home on Shoe Lane was torn down to make way for the head offices of accountants <ORGANIZATION> Coopers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lybrand </ORGANIZATION>. In 1984, the <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Telegraph </ORGANIZATION> sold its 1.15 acre site at 135 Fleet Street, complete with art deco lobby and penthouse lawn and garden. It is being developed into the European headquarters of <ORGANIZATION> Goldman </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sachs </ORGANIZATION>, the American investment banking firm. News International, which publishes the Sun and News of the World tabloids, will turn its Bouverie Street site into an office development. The Financial Times' Bracken House headquarters went to the Japanese construction firm <LOCATION> Ohbayashiin </LOCATION> in June 1986 for about $ 230 million. The <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Express </ORGANIZATION>, whose black-facaded building still frowns imposingly over Fleet Street, also is moving out. Only <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Maxwell </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> Mirror </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Group </ORGANIZATION>, publishers of the <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mirror </ORGANIZATION>, the Sunday Mirror and the Sunday People, has not yet announced plans to leave. Keeping <PERSON> Maxwell </PERSON> company are the news agencies _ The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>, directly behind the Mirror Building, and <ORGANIZATION> Reuters </ORGANIZATION>, which shares the <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> building. <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> <PERSON> Saint </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Historic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Buildings </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Monuments </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> said the newspaper industry is the last major one to move out. Fleet Street proper begins at <ORGANIZATION> Temple </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bar </ORGANIZATION>, an ancient boundary marker for the City of <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>, and until the 18th century the spot where the severed heads of traitors were displayed. Named after the nearby Fleet River that now runs underground, it was one of medieval <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>'s main east-west routes for travel between the government at <LOCATION> Westminster </LOCATION> and commerce in the City. To this day, whenever the monarch makes a state visit to the City, she pauses at <ORGANIZATION> Temple </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bar </ORGANIZATION> for a ceremony with the Lord Mayor. The first recorded printer, <PERSON> Wynkyn </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Worde </PERSON>, arrived about 1500 and set up shop near Shoe Lane where bookbinders worked. The first newspaper, The Daily Courant, arrived in 1702. Before that, Fleet Street had been a showplace for freaks, fire-eaters and wild animals. Diarist <PERSON> Samuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Pepys </PERSON> reputedly was born in <LOCATION> Salisbury </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Court </LOCATION>, just off Fleet Street, in 1633. <PERSON> Samuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>, the great writer and lexicographer, lived and worked in the area in the mid-18th century, and his house in <LOCATION> Gough </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Square </LOCATION> is a museum. Fleet Street also is home to the <ORGANIZATION> Middle </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Temple </ORGANIZATION>, one of four sets of offices and apartments for senior lawyers known as the Inns of the Court. Above its entrance at No. 17 Fleet Street the partly timbered building is one of the few domestic buildings in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> to survive from <PERSON> Shakespeare </PERSON>'s time. For centuries, journalists have worshipped at <PERSON> Christopher </PERSON> <PERSON> Wren </PERSON>'s splendid St. Bride's church at the foot of the street <PERSON> Pepys </PERSON> was baptized in the church, and the parents of <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> Dare, the first English child born in colonial <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, were married here. So were the parents of <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Winslow </PERSON>, a leader of the Pilgrim Fathers. Lightning knocked eight feet off <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bride </LOCATION>'s steeple in 1764, and among those King <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON> called in to advise him on repairs was <PERSON> Benjamin </PERSON> <PERSON> Franklin </PERSON>. The church was gutted by World War II bombs and rebuilt with donations from <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> newspapers. Although some newspapers have moved to new, high-tech premises, `` Fleet Street'' is still used to describe <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s national press. `` I do n't think one will have ` off-Fleet Street,' like you have Broadway, off-Broadway,'' <PERSON> Webb </PERSON> said. Certain other things never change. Ye <ORGANIZATION> Olde </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cheshire </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cheese </ORGANIZATION>, the pub and restaurant with sawdust covered floors, rebuilt in 1667 after the great fire of <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> and later frequented by Dr. <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>'s crowd, still sells a traditional roast beef and <ORGANIZATION> Yorkshire </ORGANIZATION> pudding dinner for about $ 8.75. And at <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vino </LOCATION>'s, men still must wear ties and women are not served at the bar.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881025-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-25-88 2355EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-NavyLessons     10-25 1054</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Navy Lessons,1085</SECOND>
<HEAD>Navy Learns Many Lessons In Gulf's `Do-It-Yourself War'</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</NOTE>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 The writer has covered the <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> involvement in the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> from its inception and traveled the gulf from one end to the other with convoys and aboard <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> warships. Here is his report on what the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> has learned:
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>By RICHARD PYLE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MANAMA, Bahrain (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Emerging from what a senior commander calls a `` do-it-yourself war'' in the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> is absorbing and, in some cases, already applying lessons learned in a year of unrelenting tension and sudden bursts of combat. Although not a direct participant in the war between <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> sent warships to ensure freedom of shipping in the gulf. The <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> found itself committed to its biggest, costliest mission since <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> and by some measures since World War I. Between July 24, 1987 _ when the <LOCATION> Kuwaiti </LOCATION> supertanker <LOCATION> Bridgeton </LOCATION> struck a mine while under <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> escort _ and the Iraq-Iran cease-fire on Aug. 20, 1988, <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> ships and aircraft engaged in more than a dozen armed clashes with Iranian forces and encounters with <LOCATION> Iraqi </LOCATION> warplanes. Officers say the gulf experience, which included the first combat use of many computer and weapons systems, could lead to many changes in operating procedures, shipboard equipment and even a revived emphasis on survivability in warship design. It also is prompting a serious look at more subtle questions such as stress. Sailors in the gulf were living under a constant state of high alert and performing the technical tasks of missile warfare. Officers often had only seconds to make major decisions. Official concern about stress was given special impetus by the July 3 disaster in which the missile cruiser USS Vincennes mistook an Iranian jetliner for a military attack plane and shot it down, killing all 290 aboard. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> investigators said the pressure of first-time combat caused <LOCATION> Vincennes </LOCATION> radar operators to misinterpret crucial computer data, and recommended that stress and the `` human factor'' be studied for future training purposes. Although investigators said the ship's `` Aegis'' radar-weapons system worked as intended, the system is being modified to feed more precise information on aircraft threats. The <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> also has made or is planning changes in shipboard emergency procedures, damage control and fire-fighting methods as a result of the near-sinking of the missile frigates USS Stark and USS <PERSON> Samuel </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Roberts </PERSON>. Thirty-seven crewmen were killed on the Stark when it was hit by two <LOCATION> Iraqi </LOCATION> missiles on May 17, 1987, and 10 <PERSON> Roberts </PERSON>' crewmen were hurt when it was almost ripped in half by an Iranian mine last April 14. The gulf inspired the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>'s first use of computer systems to train officers and crews for a specific combat zone. The computers simulated gulf geography and tactical situations, with tapes of actual radio traffic for added realism. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> had kept a small flotilla in the gulf since 1949 but it quadrupled after President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> agreed in mid-1987 to reflag and escort <LOCATION> Kuwaiti </LOCATION> oil tankers menaced by <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>, which considered <LOCATION> Kuwait </LOCATION> an <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> ally. The buildup ultimately reached more than 30 warships in the region, spurring similar moves by five West European governments. Gen. <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Crist </PERSON>, head of <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Command </ORGANIZATION> and architect of the operation, said the 600-mile-long gulf, crowded with ships, oil rigs and besieged by warring neighbors, was a `` learning experience'' for the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>, whose strategies are built on long-range ocean warfare. `` It was a real do-it-yourself, come-as-you-are operation,'' said <PERSON> Crist </PERSON>, whose Florida-based command controls <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military activities in the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION>. `` There were no books, no doctrine.'' The <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>, for example, had not run an ocean convoy since World War II, and the only officers trained for the task were civilian reservists. Teachers, accountants and merchant mariners were recalled to active duty as liaison officers aboard the Kuwaiti tankers. Improvising for `` guerrilla warfare at sea,'' <PERSON> Crist </PERSON> hired tugboats as temporary mine sweepers and leased two huge barges as floating combat bases after <PERSON> Arab </PERSON> states rejected <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> pleas to use their territory. He said the barges, an idea borrowed from <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> where American forces patrolled from bases in enemy-held areas, showed it was possible to range far afield `` without a tremendous base infrastructure ... and still project our power.'' <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officers say the `` mobile sea bases'' were instrumental in discouraging Iranian shipping raids in the northern gulf for seven months before the cease-fire. Their secret, night-flying Army helicopters also caught an Iranian minelayer, proving that <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION> was mining gulf sea lanes. <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> ships, built to fight submarines and aircraft, were ill-equipped to combat <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'s armed speedboats and Chinese-made Silkworm missiles, considered the main threats to <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> convoys. Gulf-bound warships soon were being fitted with new firepower _ machine guns, a laser-sighted Army tank cannon, and the radar-guided <PERSON> Phalanx </PERSON> <PERSON> Gatling </PERSON> gun that hurls a storm of shells at incoming missiles. Even before the July 3 <ORGANIZATION> Airbus </ORGANIZATION> tragedy, some <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officers had criticized the choice of the billion-dollar <LOCATION> Vincennes </LOCATION> as being too much ship for the gulf. Aides say, however, that <PERSON> Crist </PERSON> stands by the decision, which was aimed at countering an Iranian missile threat. Some other ideas fizzled or never got started. <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> helicopter mine sweepers toiled six months in the gulf's grueling heat and dust without finding a mine Vietnam-era river patrol boats proved useless. Officials twice considered and abandoned the idea of calling in the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION>. Five dolphins trained in a top-secret <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> project to guard against underwater sabotage were sent to the gulf, but returned home after one died from a virus. <PERSON> Crist </PERSON> said one of his biggest problems was a command structure in which the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>'s gulf commander answered to him, while some carrier groups in the <LOCATION> Arabian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sea </LOCATION> remained under <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> fleet jurisdiction. To solve the command split, <PERSON> Crist </PERSON> created a unified Joint Task Force <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION>, directly under his headquarters. He said that decision could serve as a model for avoiding future interservice rivalries in time of crisis. `` If you look at it, this low intensity -LRB- warfare -RRB- is probably where we're going to be for a long time, and commanders have to be able to ` think joint,' worry about the best the services can make available, not the parochialism,'' <PERSON> Crist </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881025-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-25-88 2357EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Fashion     10-25 0736</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Fashion,0755</SECOND>
<HEAD>Ungaro Summer Offerings Mostly A Variation Of Last Year</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By SUZY PATTERSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Fashion Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PARIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Summer sirens in sizzling colors and clinging short skirts ambled down the runway at <ORGANIZATION> Emanuel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ungaro </ORGANIZATION>'s summer ready-to-wear show. While the rest of <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> is easing up on summer profiles with many dropped hemlines, <PERSON> Ungaro </PERSON> went his own way _ fitting, draping and adding little bows to sexy outfits. Most of the dozens of looks in Tuesday's long and somewhat monotonous show were variations on last year's. There were countless gorgeous but familiar nipped-waist spencer jackets with long points, plus plenty of peplums above the body-hugging skirts. The newer flowing babydoll jackets in hot colors are easier toppers. Varied fabrics were mixed in an outfit, another Ungaro forte. His new short skirt is shiny red, burgundy or brown patent leather, teamed up with flowered blouses and jackets. <PERSON> Ungaro </PERSON>'s flower garden sprouted all kinds of posies, in every spring color imaginable from pink to robin's egg blue to lime, fuchsia and amethyst. The decorator's dream prints were heavily charged with big peonies and roses, but the best flower jackets were simpler _ white pique sprigged with wild flowers. <PERSON> Ungaro </PERSON>'s pants are original. Instead of the favorite wide pantskirt, he chose droopy drawers, long or short fluid harem or bloomer pants, teamed up with the showy, flowered fitted tops. Evening wear with plenty of lace and lame was predictably flounced and elaborate looking, as most of the show did, a dead-ringer for couture. <PERSON> Guy </PERSON> <PERSON> Douvier </PERSON>'s styles for <PERSON> Guy </PERSON> <PERSON> Laroche </PERSON> were much simpler and undoubtedly will be less expensive. This clean-cut collection featured short skirts, smart pea jackets and long, straight pants or shorts in red, white and navy nautical lines. Careful cut and finish gave blue or gray denim skirts and shorts suits smooth city elegance. Big color prints burst out here, too, on flowered strapless bustier sheaths with puff-sleeved boleros. Other feminine lines in turquoise, fuchsia and yellow were paneled and wrapped like flower petals. And with all this color, <PERSON> Douvier </PERSON> was dotty over black polka dots on the hot colors. <PERSON> Jean-Louis </PERSON> <PERSON> Scherrer </PERSON> showed a huge group of navy-and-white nautical outfits, beautifully cut with flowing trousers, and neat variations on the pea jacket, as well as lots of stripes. <PERSON> Scherrer </PERSON> showed full shorts and a striped mini-jersey, but he usually preferred less leggy looks. A white pique sundress with a long, swirling skirt and little blue jacket could be a winner. There were enough safari outfits and jungle prints here to make a planter pleased as punch. In desert shades of sand and burnt orange, or printed in green and violet, they ranged from sexy tulip-draped skirts to belted but full light cotton bush jackets over ample long pants. For after-hours, <PERSON> Scherrer </PERSON> opted for flowered, draped sheaths or lacy inspiration in short or long evening dresses of expensive lingerie inspiration. The froths of lace bubbled all over like champagne, including the soft peach and sky blue dressy evening pyjamas, and bustier dresses with silk chiffon blazers. <PERSON> Scherrer </PERSON> ended the show with navy lame and lurex sailor suits, quite handsome indeed for the skipper or first mate on the night watch. <PERSON> Valentino </PERSON> also was big on lace. But he did n't seem to know where to stop, pairing it with chiffon prints and huge swaths of rhinestone embroidery. On some outfits it looked demure; on others, it was rather heavy-handed. Day wear was more successful, especially the suits _ lean, short and sleek as only <PERSON> Valentino </PERSON> knows how to make them. He showed very pure lines in battle-jacket tops, or easily fitted glen plaid or checked jackets over white pique vests, silk blouses underneath. <PERSON> Valentino </PERSON>'s favorite trouser line still looked new, straight and not too full, with a cuff at the ankle. Other trousers included short, full culottes, lean pedal pushers _ topped by boxy plaid jackets. <PERSON> Erik </PERSON> <PERSON> Mortensen </PERSON> at <LOCATION> Balmain </LOCATION> was applauded for a collection that looked both simple and elegant. His idea of the trapeze pants was a suit in awning stripes of red or green, topped with a neat little bolero. Suits were lean, dressy and short, sometimes cut in diagonal, two-colored combinations. And <PERSON> Mortensen </PERSON>'s clinging ribbed knit dresses in hot shades of red, orange and yellow were intriguingly textured with panels of the ribbed knit cut so the ribbing was placed at several angles all over the dress.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881025-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-25-88 2359EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-IndianLogging     10-25 1170</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Indian Logging,1204</SECOND>
<HEAD>Alaska Forest Falls To Native Corporations' Saws</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</NOTE>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID FOSTER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>HYDABURG, Alaska (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Adrian </PERSON> <PERSON> LeCornu </PERSON> leaned against the stump of a 400-year-old spruce and surveyed the remains of the ancient forest on a hill near his Indian village. Where trees 6 feet in diameter once towered over the mossy forest floor, acres of stumps and rotten wood now litter the scarred earth. `` They say war is hell,'' said <PERSON> LeCornu </PERSON>, <PERSON> Hydaburg </PERSON>'s city administrator. `` Well, logging is not a pretty sight, either.'' Timber-cutting is nothing new here. A 700-mile web of logging roads connects this Haida Indian village to the rest of <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>'s Prince of <LOCATION> Wales </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> But <PERSON> LeCornu </PERSON> and others who depend on the region's dark forests and cool waters for subsistence hunting and fishing find it ironic that the region's most aggressive and destructive logging is being done by the natives themselves. What is worse, <PERSON> LeCornu </PERSON> said, is that it may be too late to do anything about it. National environmental groups have been crying foul for years over logging in the old-growth spruce and hemlock forests of <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>'s 16 million-acre <ORGANIZATION> Tongass </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION>, several islands to the north of Prince of <LOCATION> Wales </LOCATION>. But little is heard about native logging, even though cutting on native land in <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>'s panhandle has outstripped the Tongass harvest in each of the last two years. This year, an estimated 15,000 acres of native lands will be cut, compared to about 9,000 acres in the Tongass. Leaders of the native corporations say the logging has boosted the region's economy and caused little environmental damage _ claims disputed by other natives who say the logging provides temporary profit and long-term harm. Commercial fishermen, environmentalists and state wildlife biologists also voice concerns but say little can be done to control native logging. The federal regulations that govern cutting in the Tongass do not apply to native corporations, the panhandle's major private landowners. Clearcutting, which fells all trees in an area, is the norm here. But Tongass clearcuts are limited to 100 acres, while cuts on native lands may stretch across thousands. In addition, native loggers are not required to leave buffer strips of trees along salmon streams or to consider the effects of logging on wildlife habitat. They may also cut on steeper slopes, increasing the chance for stream-clogging silt and landslides, said <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Gustafson </PERSON>, a biologist for the <ORGANIZATION> Alaska </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fish </ORGANIZATION> and Game. `` We've got a new kind of logging,'' <PERSON> Gustafson </PERSON> said. `` A lot of the long-term effects are not fully known. We have concerns, but we do n't have the authority to change it.'' The stage was set for native logging with passage of the 1971 <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> Native Claims Settlement Act, which awarded natives 44 million acres and nearly $ 1 billion to be managed by 12 regional corporations and 200 village corporations. Logging began eight years ago as southeastern <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>'s one regional corporation and 12 village corporations started receiving the 470,000 acres promised them in the act. Even corporate leaders were surprised at how fast the trees fell. When the timber export market declined sharply in 1981, some corporations had to log heavily to pay off start-up loans. When timber prices rose in 1986, logging intensified as corporations converted assets to cash. Perhaps the strongest incentive to keep cutting down trees was the 1986 Tax Reform Act, under which native corporations could sell their operating losses to profitable corporations in need of tax write-offs. The results of accelerated logging are plain to see. Twenty miles south of <LOCATION> Hydaburg </LOCATION>, a 30,000-acre island is being shaved of old-growth timber. Near the <LOCATION> Chichagof </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> village of <LOCATION> Hoonah </LOCATION>, hillsides `` look like they've been nuked,'' according to <PERSON> Ernestine </PERSON> <PERSON> Hanlon </PERSON>. The angry villager said logging had destroyed her favorite spot for collecting the spruce roots she weaves into baskets. The rush to cut has overwhelmed <PERSON> Gustafson </PERSON> and other state inspectors, who enforce the state's Forest Practices Act and try to protect salmon streams. This summer, in one of the most serious violations, <ORGANIZATION> Klukwan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Products </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> was fined $ 7,500 and ordered to restore a 500-foot stretch of a salmon stream it had buried under tons of logs, branches and organic debris. Besides noting the potential damage to salmon runs by such careless logging practices, environmentalists also say clearcuts _ and the young, same-height forests that follow _ threaten <LOCATION> Sitka </LOCATION> black-tailed deer, which depend on old trees for protection from deep snow. But the environmentalists have not pressed their concerns, concentrating instead on the <ORGANIZATION> Tongass </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION>. `` You have to pick your fights,'' said <PERSON> Bart </PERSON> <PERSON> Koehler </PERSON>, director of the <ORGANIZATION> Southeast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Alaska </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conservation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>. `` There is a better chance of changing things on public lands than on native lands.'' That's as it should be, said <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Harris </PERSON>, a vice president for <ORGANIZATION> Sealaska </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, the regional native corporation and southeastern <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>'s biggest private landowner. Private land should not be subject to the same constraints as public land, he said. Like any corporation, <ORGANIZATION> Sealaska </ORGANIZATION> has a responsibility to its shareholders to maximize profits, he said. Not surprisingly, attitudes toward logging in native villages depend at least partly on how much the villages have gained from logging. Complaints are few in the Prince of <LOCATION> Wales </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> village of <LOCATION> Kasaan </LOCATION>, whose corporation sold its timber rights, invested the money and now pays an annual $ 10,000 dividend to each of its 119 shareholders. In <LOCATION> Hydaburg </LOCATION>, the rewards have been smaller, and the opposition to logging has been greater. When land was being handed out, the village's <ORGANIZATION> Haida </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> received mostly scrub timber and is just now struggling out of bankruptcy court. Meanwhile, <ORGANIZATION> Sealaska </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Klukwan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, a village corporation based 300 miles to the north, are heavily cutting more productive lands near <LOCATION> Hydaburg </LOCATION>. When <ORGANIZATION> Sealaska </ORGANIZATION> sought to cut trees above <LOCATION> Hydaburg </LOCATION>'s reservoir, the city council forced one delay after another, worried that logging would silt up streams and foul its water supply. <ORGANIZATION> Sealaska </ORGANIZATION> had planned to cut up to 700 acres in the watershed. It stopped in May 1987, after cutting only 100 acres. `` Sealaska probably will never touch the watershed again _ too much trouble,'' said <PERSON> Hydaburg </PERSON> Mayor <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Sanderson </PERSON>. Recent efforts to regulate native logging have concentrated on putting more teeth in the state's Forest Practices Act. This summer, Gov. <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Cowper </PERSON> appointed a panel to review the law. But any changes will come too late to affect most native land. Several village corporations have exhausted their commercial timber stands, and the others are expected to run out of trees within three years. <ORGANIZATION> Sealaska </ORGANIZATION> can log for eight to 10 more years. The forest will take 100 years to grow back to commercial size, at least 300 years to become the old-growth forest that environmentalists are now trying to protect. `` How do you manage the land now?'' asked Mayor <PERSON> Sanderson </PERSON>. `` It's already stripped All you can do now is let the trees grow back.''
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Foster </PERSON> is the <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Northwest </ORGANIZATION> regional reporter, based in <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION>
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881025-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-25-88 0001EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Iran-Contra     10-25 0790</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Iran-Contra,790</SECOND>
<HEAD>Prosecutors Ridicule North's Defense That Lies Were OK</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JAMES ROWLEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> <PERSON> North </PERSON> offers a `` shocking and cynical'' view of democracy by arguing that his lies to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> were n't crimes because other high officials deliberately misled lawmakers, Iran-Contra prosecutors say Responding to <PERSON> North </PERSON>'s motions to dismiss charges he lied about his covert assistance of Nicaraguan rebels, prosecutors said the former <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> aide's arguments are `` incompatible with the aspirations of our system of government'' and `` inconsistent with any but the most jaundiced view of the realities of politics and government.'' The spirited attack on <PERSON> North </PERSON> was offered Monday by independent counsel <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Walsh </PERSON>, who consented to a defense motion to dismiss a charge that the former <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> officer and <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> aide obstructed an investigation of who paid for a $ 13,800 security fence outside his house. Lawyers for the retired <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> lieutenant colonel said any alleged fabrication of documents in December 1986 to conceal payments for the fence by arms dealer <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> V. </PERSON> <PERSON> Secord </PERSON> was n't obstruction of justice because the Iran-Contra grand jury did not begin its work for another month While conceding a legal deficiency in one of 16 charges against <PERSON> North </PERSON>, <PERSON> Walsh </PERSON>'s office urged the court to reject a series of defense motions to dismiss other counts of the indictment. Prosecutors disclosed new details about <PERSON> North </PERSON>'s destruction of key <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> documents in November 1986 as the Iran-Contra affair was unraveling. North destroyed original copies of so-called `` System IV'' documents at the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> that prosecutors called `` the most sensitive records in the <ORGANIZATION> NSC </ORGANIZATION>'s carefully constructed system of document control.'' There is also evidence he purposely withheld from <ORGANIZATION> NSC </ORGANIZATION> files original copies of documents that were the `` sole record of the events and activities described therein,'' prosecutors said. They also ridiculed <PERSON> North </PERSON>'s defense that he was not warned that lying to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> in unsworn statements could result in criminal prosecution. The defense had claimed that <PERSON> North </PERSON> was the first government official to be prosecuted for alleged falsehoods in unsworn statements to lawmakers. North's lawyers recounted a history of lies to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> by top government officials, including Secretary of State <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Foster </PERSON> <PERSON> Dulles </PERSON>' false denial of <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> involvement in a 1958 plot to overthrow <LOCATION> Indonesian </LOCATION> President <PERSON> Sukarno </PERSON>. Prosecutors said such a rebuttal `` reflects a shocking and cynical view of the relations between the people's elected representatives in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and officials of the executive branch.'' North's defense, in effect, is an argument that `` lying is so ingrained and pervasive a practice in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> that _ despite laws clearly making it a crime for ordinary non-office-holding citizens to make false statements to government agencies _ executive officers lack fair notice that there is not an implicit exception putting them above such laws,'' prosecutors said in papers filed in <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>. Among the charges against <PERSON> North </PERSON> is that he drafted false letters in 1985 to the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Permanent </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Select </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> on </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Intelligence </ORGANIZATION> and a House Foreign Affairs subcommittee. North also is charged with making similarly false statements during a 1986 briefing to members of the intelligence committee. The three 1985 letters, which were signed by then-national security advisor <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> McFarlane </PERSON>, falsely stated that <PERSON> North </PERSON> and other <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> officers were not involved in any covert efforts to raise money to arm the Contras. <PERSON> McFarlane </PERSON> has pleaded guilty to misdemeanor charges of withholding information from <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> about covert Contra aid by sending the letters and in testimony in 1986. The congressional queries were made following news reports linking <PERSON> North </PERSON> to covert assistance to the Contras at a time such aid was banned by the Boland Amendment. `` North responded with calculated falsehood, intending to derail further investigation and generally succeeding,'' prosecutors said of charges that the former <ORGANIZATION> NSC </ORGANIZATION> aide drafted letters that falsely denied his involvement in covert aid and fund-raising. `` North could foresee that, when the committees received false denials and explanations which he intended to offer them, their predictable responses would be to cease further inquiries in this area,'' prosecutors said. `` North himself was enabled to continue his secret support of the Contras, which culminated in the illegal corruption of the <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> initiative,'' prosecutors said, referring to charges that <PERSON> North </PERSON> conspired to illegally divert U.S.-Iran arms-sale profits to the Contras. Prosecutors dismissed <PERSON> North </PERSON>'s argument that the diversion was not illegal on the ground that the government weapons had become the property of <PERSON> Secord </PERSON> and his former partner, <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Hakim </PERSON>, when they were sold to <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Secord </PERSON>, a co-defendant along with <PERSON> Hakim </PERSON> and former national security adviser <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Poindexter </PERSON>, was a `` sham middleman,'' in a `` classic fraud,'' prosecutors said. Separate trials have been ordered for each defendant. No date has been set for North's trial to begin.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881025-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-25-88 0004EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-BoxOffice     10-25 0379</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Box Office,0394</SECOND>
<HEAD>`Halloween' Returns To Scare More Money From Moviegoers</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RICHARD DE ATLEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>HOLLYWOOD (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Weekend moviegoers spent more than $ 6.2 million to see the sequel of a movie that would n't die, `` Halloween 4, The Return of <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Myers </PERSON>.'' In second place of the weekend box office rankings was `` The Accused,'' which earned more than $ 4 million, followed by `` Alien Nation'' with $ 2.6 million. `` Punchline,'' which drew $ 2.3 million was in fourth place, followed by `` Gorillas In The Mist'' with $ 2.1 million. `` Without A Clue,'' starring <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Caine </PERSON> and <PERSON> Ben </PERSON> <PERSON> Kingsley </PERSON> as a stupid <PERSON> Sherlock </PERSON> <PERSON> Holmes </PERSON> and a patient Dr. <PERSON> Watson </PERSON>, respectively, came in sixth with $ 1.1 million. `` Mystic Pizza,'' a teen romance film in its first week of release, followed with $ 1.1 million. `` A Fish Called Wanda'' was eighth with more than $ 1 million, edging `` Crossing Delancey.'' In 10th was `` Bat 21,'' starring <PERSON> Gene </PERSON> <PERSON> Hackman </PERSON> as an <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> colonel downed behind enemy lines during the Vietnam War. The movie was released at 248 theaters and earned more than $ 980,000, enough to get it into the top 10. Here are the top movies for the weekend as tallied by <ORGANIZATION> Exhibitor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Relations </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, with distributor, weekend gross, number of theater screens, average per screen, total gross and number of weeks in release. 1. `` Halloween 4, The Return of <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Myers </PERSON>,'' Galaxy, $ 6.2 million, 1,679 screens, $ 3,710 per screen, $ 6.2 million, one week. 2. `` The Accused,'' Paramount, $ 4 million, 930 screens, $ 4,327 per screen, $ 9.9 million, two weeks. 3. `` Alien Nation,'' 20th Century <PERSON> Fox </PERSON>, $ 2.6 million, 1,436 screens, $ 1,815 per screen, $ 17.6 million, three weeks. 4. `` Punchline,'' <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION>, $ 2.3 million, 916 screens, $ 2,613 per screen, $ 13.2 million, four weeks. 5. `` Gorillas In The Mist,'' Universal, $ 2.1 million, 1,073 screens, $ 2,039 per screen, $ 15.6 million, five weeks. 6. `` Without A Clue,'' <ORGANIZATION> Orion </ORGANIZATION>, $ 1.2 million, 280 screens, $ 4,452 per screen, $ 1.2 million, one week. 7. `` Mystic Pizza,'' <PERSON> Goldwyn </PERSON>, $ 1.1 million, 401 screens, $ 2,902 per sceen, $ 1.1 million, one week. 8. `` A Fish Called Wanda,'' <ORGANIZATION> MGM-UA </ORGANIZATION>, $ 1.044 million, 747 screens, $ 1,398 per screen, $ 56.2 million, 15 weeks. 9. `` Crossing Delancey,'' <ORGANIZATION> Warner </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bros. </ORGANIZATION>, $ 1.042 million, 302 screens, $ 3,451 per screen, $ 10.2 million, eight weeks. 10. `` Bat 21,'' Tri-Star, $ 982,080, 248 screens, $ 3,960 per screen, $ 982,080, one week.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881025-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-25-88 0026EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-USInvestment     10-25 0363</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-US Investment,350</SECOND>
<HEAD>US Government to Invest in African, Caribbean Businesses</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CARL HARTMAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The government is preparing to buy into small, private businesses in some Third World countries as part of an effort to boost <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> exports. The $ 10 million to be invested by the <ORGANIZATION> Overseas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Private </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Investment </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corporation </ORGANIZATION> -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> OPIC </ORGANIZATION> -RRB- was authorized in a little-noticed bill signed by President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> to extend the agency's life and give it some new roles. `` A vital key to increasing our efforts, righting the -LRB- <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> -RRB- trade deficit and creating new domestic job opportunities will be the rate at which we gain footholds in the developing countries by establishing a physical presence through direct investment,'' <ORGANIZATION> OPIC </ORGANIZATION> President <PERSON> Craig </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Nalen </PERSON> said in a statement Monday. <ORGANIZATION> OPIC </ORGANIZATION>'s main role is to insure <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> industry abroad against the risk of hostile action by other governments, with the aim of encouraging American business to invest in the Third World. It is one of the few government agencies to operate at a profit. `` The legislation will permit the corporation to take an equity position in small-scale projects in sub-Saharan <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Caribbean </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Basin </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Nalen </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Rick </PERSON> <PERSON> Hornberg </PERSON>, in charge of <ORGANIZATION> OPIC </ORGANIZATION>'s contacts with <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, said the investments can help fledgling businesses by buying some of their stock and lending money to their owners. The <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government will be allowed to buy no more than 30 percent of the stock in any company. `` When the sponsor of a new business ca n't raise enough money to get started, it may be too much of an interest burden for a new company to borrow it all,'' he said. `` The new law enables the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government to supply some of the capital as an investment, with the expectation that in 10 years or so, it can sell its shares and get out,'' <PERSON> Hornberg </PERSON> said. The program is authorized for four years and <PERSON> Hornberg </PERSON> said he hoped it would be renewed if successful. There is no list of specific countries where the government will be permitted to invest, but it will be limited to those where <ORGANIZATION> OPIC </ORGANIZATION> already operates, he said. That would eliminate <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881025-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-25-88 0031EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-TreasuryBills     10-25 0173</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Treasury Bills,170</SECOND>
<HEAD>Yields Mixed on Short-Term T-Bills</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Interest rates on short-term <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> securities were mixed in the latest auction. The <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> sold $ 7.0 billion in three-month bills Monday at an average discount rate of 7.45 percent, up from 7.36 percent last week. Another $ 7.0 billion was sold in six-month bills at an average discount rate of 7.54 percent, down from 7.55 percent last week. The three-month rate was the highest since the bills sold for 7.69 percent on May 13, 1985. The six-month rate was the lowest since the bills averaged 7.46 on Oct. 11. The new discount rates understate the actual return to investors _ 7.70 percent for three-month bills with a $ 10,000 bill selling for $ 9,811.70 and 7.95 percent for six-month bills selling for $ 9,618.80. In a separate report, the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reserve </ORGANIZATION> said the average yield for one-year <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> bills, the most popular index for making changes in adjustable rate home mortgages, rose to 8.12 percent last week after averaging 8.07 percent the week before.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881025-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-25-88 0038EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Treasury-Dollar     10-25 0709</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Treasury-Dollar,690</SECOND>
<HEAD>Administration Planning Currency Talks With Taiwan, South Korea</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVE SKIDMORE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration is preparing for a new round of talks with <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> about what it considers unfair efforts to bolster their trade balances by manipulating the value of their currencies. The omnibus trade bill passed by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> this summer required the <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> to determine if four newly industrialized <LOCATION> Asian </LOCATION> countries _ <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Singapore </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> _ are artificially holding down value of their currencies relative to the dollar. The report, delivered to the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> banking committees on Monday, found that <LOCATION> Singapore </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION>, while running large trade surpluses, impose few restrictions on trade. <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>, however, keep their currencies artificially low and impose tariffs and other barriers to free trade, the report said. The failure of the <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION> dollar and Korean won to appreciate significantly against the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> dollar keeps prices of American exports to those countries high and the price of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> imports of Taiwanese and South Korean products low. A senior <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> official, who spoke on condition of anonymity, noted that the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has discussed the exchange rate issue with <LOCATION> Tawian </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> before, but said the trade bill represented `` a very significant change in terms of perception.'' Although it does not specify penalties against countries manipulating their currencies, the bill requires the administration to assess the result of the negotiations in six months. `` If there's a lack of progress, we will have to report that,'' the official said. The new talks will begin `` as soon as we can effectively commence the dialogue,'' he said. In general, the <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> said it was pleased by the progress of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and its economic allies in stabilizing exchange rates since the Louvre Accord in February 1987. Members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and economists have expressed alarm at the 14 percent rise, at an annual rate, in the value of the dollar from lows nine months ago, saying it will hamper progress on whittling down the trade deficit. However, the report said the dollar, by rising this year, had simply rebounded from a drop it characterized as a temporary overreaction to the October stock market crash and that the dollar was still lower than before the crash. `` It seems unlikely that movements in the dollar so far this year will significantly alter the outlook for sustained trade ... improvement,'' it said. The report strongly endorsed efforts by <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, which had the largest trade surplus with the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, to stimulate its economy in an effort to increase import buying. It said <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, which had the second largest trade surplus with the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, has also moved in the right direction, but said, `` its performance is less striking.'' Overall, the official predicted the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> current account, which includes trade in merchandise and the flow of investment dollars across borders, will shrink by $ 20 billion this year, from a peak in 1987 of $ 154 billion. The official said the improvement should continue next year, but declined to say by how much. Many private economists maintain the deficit will not shrink further without an additional drop in the dollar. Economists worry that the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>' status as the world's biggest debtor nation _ it owed $ 368 billion at the end of last year _ makes it vulnerable to a sharp drops in the value of the dollar or skyrocketing interest rates should foreigners decided to pull their money out But the <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> said `` such concerns are exaggerated or unwarranted.'' It said the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> debt in comparison to the size of its economy is modest by international standards and said the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> `` remains an extremely attractive place to invest.'' In another part of the report, the administration said its policy of coordinating intervention in currency markets with other major industrial nations has proved `` more helpful than previously thought'' in stabilizing exchange rates even though the interventions were small relative to total currency trading. It said the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> spent $ 8.5 billion to prop up the value of the dollar as it was falling in 1987 and sold $ 1.4 billion in dollars to curb its appreciation this year.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881025-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-25-88 0150EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a BC-UNDayConcert     10-25 0440</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-UN Day Concert,0459</SECOND>
<HEAD>Joan Sutherland, Sydney Symphony in U.N. Day Concert</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: No PMs Planned</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By MARY CAMPBELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Two jewels in <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION>'s musical crown, the <LOCATION> Sydney </LOCATION> Symphony and coloratura soprano <PERSON> Dame </PERSON> <PERSON> Joan </PERSON> <PERSON> Sutherland </PERSON>, presented a brilliant concert for this year's United Nations Day celebration on Monday night. The concert in the <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> the </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> is an annual event commemorating the birth of the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> on Oct. 24, 1945, and Secretary General <PERSON> Javier </PERSON> <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Cuellar </PERSON> greeted the audience with a brief statement before the performance. The appearance by the <LOCATION> Sydney </LOCATION> Symphony, <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION>'s oldest musical institution, came as it makes its first <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> tour, which began Oct. 16 and continues through Nov. 6, part of <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION>'s Bicentennial celebrations PBS has televised U.N. Day concerts for 20 years. This year the concert will air on Wednesday at 9:30 p.m. EDT. After three instrumental pieces, conducted by <PERSON> Stuart </PERSON> <PERSON> Challender </PERSON>, <PERSON> Dame </PERSON> <PERSON> Joan </PERSON> sang some music from the first act of `` La Traviata,'' concluding with `` Sempre libera.'' Her husband, <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Bonynge </PERSON>, conducted for her. A month before her 63rd birthday, her voice was glorious. Singing in the opera's original key, she hit every coloratura note squarely and with apparent ease, hit high notes without scooping up to them. After intermission, she sang the title character's entrance in `` The Merry Widow'' and `` Vilia,'' beautifully sustaining the mood of that haunting song. The concert ended with her singing from `` <LOCATION> La </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sonnambula </LOCATION>,'' one of the bel canto operas which introduced her to American audiences. She spun the melodic lines, made perfect delicate trills and was altogether thrilling. The concert began with `` Till Eulenspiegel's Merry Pranks'' by <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Strauss </PERSON>. <PERSON> Challender </PERSON> emphasized the lyricism of the music. The <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION>, with its wood strips on the walls and wooden desks, is acoustically warm, abetting the conductor's approach of making the music sing. Till's rudest pranks were not depicted in vulgar tones in this presentation. Next came `` The Display Suite,'' which Australian composer <PERSON> Malcolm </PERSON> <PERSON> Williamson </PERSON> took from his 1963 score for the Australian Ballet about a bird's wooing its mate. The suite is accessible and pleasing, beginning with an atonal introduction and the bird represented by a piccolo. A remarkably cheery waltz, sounding almost Viennese, follows. After that comes rich music for an unhurried love duet and a mildly percussive finale. The orchestra also played <PERSON> Ravel </PERSON>'s `` La Valse'' with <PERSON> Challender </PERSON> emphasizing the shimmer, while keeping tension and flow, and again downplaying any ominous undercurrents. The orchestra sounded fine. Not overwhelmed by the strings, the brass especially, and also woodwinds and percussion, made the most of their moments to shine.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881025-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-25-88 0013EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Nicaragua-Recovery Bjt   10-25 0526</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nicaragua-Recovery, Bjt,0547</SECOND>
<HEAD>Nicaraguans In Battered Coastal Town Start Rebuilding</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BRYNA BRENNAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BLUEFIELDS, Nicaragua (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
