<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880228-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-28-88 2337EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Israel-Brutality     02-28 0470</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Israel-Brutality,0485</SECOND>
<HEAD>Commander Warns Officers Against `Rabble' Army</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAN IZENBERG</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>JERUSALEM (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A senior commander ordered his officers Sunday to view film footage of troops brutally beating Arab prisoners and said the Israeli army must not become `` a rabble army.'' Maj. Gen. <PERSON> Amram </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitzna </PERSON>, head of the Central Command that is in charge of the occupied <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> of the <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION>, gathered all officers over the rank of platoon commander Sunday and showed them the footage shot by <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> in the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> town of <LOCATION> Nablus </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> radio reported. `` I'm against those who think we can sweep internal problems under the carpet just because they're not pretty,'' <PERSON> Mitzna </PERSON> said earlier on <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> radio. `` We have to make sure we do n't become a rabble army.'' The film, which showed four soldiers in <LOCATION> Nablus </LOCATION> kicking and beating two Palestinians last Thursday, shocked many Israelis who believed violence by soldiers during three months of Palestinian demonstrations had receded after new army orders last week limited the use of force. Some members of Prime Minister <PERSON> Yitzhak </PERSON> <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON>'s right-wing <ORGANIZATION> Likud </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bloc </ORGANIZATION> defended the soldiers. `` I'm against the lynch atmosphere,'' said <ORGANIZATION> Likud </ORGANIZATION> legislator <PERSON> Pinchas </PERSON> <PERSON> Goldstein </PERSON>. `` There was no need to arrest the soldiers.'' Transport Minister <PERSON> Chaim </PERSON> <PERSON> Korfu </PERSON>, also of <ORGANIZATION> Likud </ORGANIZATION>, told the Cabinet Sunday the press should be barred from the occupied lands for three months. `` We are in a confrontation,'' <PERSON> Korfu </PERSON> later told <ORGANIZATION> Israel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> army </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> radio </ORGANIZATION>. `` We must take these minimal measures when we know for certain -LRB- the media -RRB- is responsible for some of the violence.'' According to <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> figures, 74 Arabs have been killed by the Israelis during the violent in the occupied <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strip </LOCATION> since Dec. 10. Hundreds have been wounded and there have been many cases of soldiers severely beating Palestinians. The CBS film showed four soldiers, members of a tank unit, kicking the <LOCATION> Palestinians </LOCATION> whose hands were tied behind their backs and smashing them on the legs and arms with fist-sized rocks. The four were arrested and their deputy unit commander, a captain, was suspended. It was announced Saturday that the four soldiers would be tried by a military court. <PERSON> Mitzna </PERSON> ordered the release of the two Arabs. <PERSON> Amalia </PERSON> <PERSON> Harpaz </PERSON>, the mother of one of the four soldiers filmed by <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, said her son <PERSON> Saguy </PERSON> had changed since he began serving in the occupied territories 10 weeks ago. `` I educated my son to go the army, take responsibility and defend the country,'' she told <ORGANIZATION> Israel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> radio </ORGANIZATION>. `` What has happened is that he has turned into a beater of women and children.'' She is a resident of <ORGANIZATION> Kibbutz </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Gesher </ORGANIZATION>, a communal settlement. <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> radio said several lawyers have offered to represent the soldiers without charge. It reported the lawyers said if anyone was responsible for a crime, it is <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s leaders.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880228-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-28-88 2343EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-OilSpill 1stLd-Writethru a0828 02-28 0523</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Oil Spill, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0828,0532</SECOND>
<HEAD>Sunken Barge Raised, Minor Oil Spill Detected</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: LEADS with 9 grafs to UPDATE with oil pumping under way,
increased estimate on surface oil spill, updated figure on amount
of this spill cleaned up. Picks up 7th graf pvs, `Western
Washington ...'</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By DOUG ESSER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ANACORTES, Wash. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A salvage crew raised a sunken oil barge Sunday from the murky depths of <LOCATION> Guemes </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Channel </LOCATION>, one month after it sank and spilled some 70,000 gallons of heavy bunker oil into <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>'s inland waters. With the inverted barge held at the surface by thick cables strung from two giant cranes, crews began pumping the more than 300,000 gallons of oil that remained in the vessel into a second barge. Officials said they wanted to get the stricken barge floating on its own before they attempted to slowly roll it right side up. A helicopter hovered overhead to track the movement of an oil sheen that appeared as the barge was raised. The sheen was caused by 500 to 1,000 gallons of lighter oil that was detected after the barge broke the surface about 7 a.m., said <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Stewart </PERSON> of the state Division of Emergency Management. The barge initially held about 22,000 gallons of light oil in addition to the heavy oil. <PERSON> Stewart </PERSON> said surface skimmer boats had cleaned up about 160 gallons, while absorbent pads collected an additional, undetermined amount. The oil sheen moved about two miles south. <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> Lt. <PERSON> Eldo </PERSON> <PERSON> DeLong </PERSON> said the sheen reached some kelp beds near <LOCATION> Burrows </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION>, but did not touch any beaches. <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ecology </ORGANIZATION> workers said three seabirds were contaminated, but they did not appear badly injured and were not captured for cleaning. Marine biologists and state environmental experts were assessing the damage from the bunker oil spill, which had been difficult to determine because the heavier-than-water oil had sunk. But <PERSON> Ats </PERSON> <PERSON> Kiuchi </PERSON>, a DOE spokesman, said it appeared the fragile, inner coastal environment had avoided a disaster that, if the barge had spilled its entire cargo, would have been the worst oil spill in the state's history. <ORGANIZATION> Western </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Shannon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Point </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Laboratory </ORGANIZATION> has found some oil in sea cucumbers, said <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Cassidy </PERSON>, the lab's director of operations The <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> tug `` Spike'' used absorbent pads to clean up some oil after the barge was raised while a second boat was positioned near <LOCATION> Shannon </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Point </LOCATION>, 100 yards away, to prevent any oil from reaching shore. The 176-foot-long barge, operated by Olympic Tug and Barge of <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION>, sank Jan. 31 in about 130 feet of water four miles west of <LOCATION> Anacortes </LOCATION> and about 100 yards off <PERSON> Shannon </PERSON> <PERSON> Point </PERSON>. The barge had been loaded at an oil refinery at <LOCATION> Anacortes </LOCATION> and was being towed by a tug to <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION> when it began listing and capsized. The cause of the sinking remained undetermined. <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> Lt. <PERSON> Eldo </PERSON> <PERSON> DeLong </PERSON> said the barge will be taken to the <LOCATION> Anacortes </LOCATION> city dock where a boom would be put around it and any remaining holes would be patched. Eventually it will be taken to <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION>, he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880228-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-28-88 2350EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-US-Iran     02-28 0163</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-US-Iran,0167</SECOND>
<HEAD>Newspaper: United States Has Sent Envoy To Iran For Talks</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> newspaper said Sunday that the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has sent a secret envoy to <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> to discuss re-establishing diplomatic links. The Observer, in an unattributed story, did not identify the official but said he is apparently a close friend of President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and went to <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION> two weeks ago. It said the envoy was traveling under the name of <PERSON> Clark </PERSON>. The Observer said the envoy met middle-ranking Iranian officials, who asked for assurances that any arms embargo against them as proposed by the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> should be delayed until early this summer. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> is seeking a <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> ban on arms sales because <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> has not accepted a cease-fire agreement in its eight-year war with <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>. There have been no diplomatic relations since the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> embassy in <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION> was stormed Nov. 4, 1979, and held for 444 days with diplomats and others kept hostage inside.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880228-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-28-88 2351EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-SuperPooch     02-28 0532</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Super Pooch,0552</SECOND>
<HEAD>Nosey Narcotics Pooch Puts Pinch On Sneaky Smugglers</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DONALD W. SWINTON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MIAMI (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Leaping luggage and sniffing out sneaky smugglers, the latest addition to <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> <LOCATION> International </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION>'s K-9 corps has racked up impressive credits in his first two months on the beat, his human colleagues say. King, a romping 2-year-old cross between a black Labrador retriever and a German short-haired pointer, has a nose that makes news. Since the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Customs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> gave King to <ORGANIZATION> Metro-Dade </ORGANIZATION> police, he has sniffed out $ 86,000 in drug-scented cash, 347 pounds of cocaine and helped collar four suspects, said police Lt. <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Martin </PERSON>. The beloved rookie, one of three canines used by <ORGANIZATION> Metro-Dade </ORGANIZATION> police at the airport, has all but matched the 400-pound career total of <PERSON> Ringo </PERSON>, who just retired after about a decade, <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> said. `` He's an up-and-coming dog,'' <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> said of the enthusiastic pooch, who with handler Detective <PERSON> Ken </PERSON> <PERSON> Buzzi </PERSON>, graduated from the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Customs </ORGANIZATION> dog training school in Front Royal, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>. King and <PERSON> Buzzi </PERSON> were still getting used to the domestic flight areas of <ORGANIZATION> Miami </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> after their December graduation when they made their first score Dec. 17 A man carrying Christmas presents on a flight from <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION> fit the profile of a smuggler. <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION> police had been suspicious. The man agreed to a search and King `` alerted'' to a drug odor in his packages. More than $ 40,000 in drug-tainted cash was discovered, <PERSON> Buzzi </PERSON> said. The fact that a specially trained dog identified the money as having been associated with narcotics was probable cause to seize it, <PERSON> Buzzi </PERSON> said. Soon afterward, King found a similar amount of drug-tainted cash packed in a <ORGANIZATION> Mercedes </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Benz </ORGANIZATION>. The two occupants of the car were arrested and are awaiting trial in <ORGANIZATION> Dade </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Circuit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Buzzi </PERSON> said. King's abilities also led to the discovery of 185 pounds of cocaine and the arrest of two <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> employees on Feb. 1. The next day, he sniffed out 155 pounds of cocaine concealed underneath the floor in the belly of an L-1011 aircraft. He detected 7 pounds of cocaine on an earlier search to bring his total to 347 pounds, <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> said. `` I worked mostly narcotics for the last 16 years,'' said <PERSON> Buzzi </PERSON>. `` The biggest seizure I made was 600 pounds and it took me almost 10 years. But working with a detector dog, we've found almost 400 pounds in the first two months we were back from school. `` We're both still a green team. I've been a police officer for 18 years but I feel like a rookie again. It's like a whole new career,'' he said. While King has a `` super-fine nose,'' he is not perfect, <PERSON> Buzzi </PERSON> said. King gets tired sometimes while working his eight-hour shift, `` but so far he's been on the money,'' he said. Detector dogs can not sniff the enormous volume of luggage, freight and planes used to smuggle narcotics and money through this primary port of entry for drugs, <PERSON> Buzzi </PERSON> said. Any dog and its handler are only as good as the watchful authorities who suggest likely targets. `` It was mostly luck and being in the right place at the right time,'' <PERSON> Buzzi </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880228-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-28-88 2358EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-MilitaryCourts     02-28 0844</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Military Courts,0866</SECOND>
<HEAD>Israel's Military Court System Under Hail Of Criticism</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By MASHA HAMILTON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LOD, Israel (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Mohammed </PERSON> <PERSON> Ali </PERSON> <PERSON> Abu </PERSON> <PERSON> Leban </PERSON>, accused of hurling a firebomb at <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> soldiers, saw his lawyer for the first time five minutes before he appeared in military court. The 19-year-old signed a confession written in <LOCATION> Hebrew </LOCATION>, a language he does not know, and said interrogators abused him. As authorities round up growing numbers of Arab suspects in an effort to quell nearly three months of unrest, <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s methods of detaining and trying Palestinians has drawn a hail of criticism. `` I feel totally helpless in this sham of a system,'' said <PERSON> Abu </PERSON> <PERSON> Leban </PERSON>'s attorney, <PERSON> Jonathan </PERSON> <PERSON> Kuttab </PERSON>, a Palestinian who graduated from the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Virginia </ORGANIZATION> law school in <LOCATION> Charlottesville </LOCATION>. `` In 98 percent of the cases, lawyers can not see Palestinian clients until after they ` confess,' and judges will accept the ` confession' at face value, no matter what you say,'' <PERSON> Kuttab </PERSON> told The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Abu </PERSON> <PERSON> Leban </PERSON>, shackled and dressed in a blue-jeans jacket, flashed a V-for-victory sign as he entered the tiny courtroom in a closed army base. He waved to his father, whom he was seeing for the first time since his arrest. <PERSON> Abu </PERSON> <PERSON> Leban </PERSON> had been held incommunicado for 18 days, until he signed a four-page confession. He said he signed only after interrogators beat him, deprived him of sleep and forced him to squat in a corner for hours. <PERSON> Kuttab </PERSON> said it was unlikely his client's contentions would be accepted in court. Allegations of unfairness in the military court system prompted the attorneys' association in the <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strip </LOCATION> to decide to boycott all military court proceedings. But Israeli officials argue the system is fair. `` There are some exceptions. But a defendant who feels he was mistreated during interrogation can raise the issue in court, where due process of law is ensured,'' army prosecutor <PERSON> Amos </PERSON> <PERSON> Giora </PERSON>, a native of <PERSON> Ann </PERSON> <PERSON> Arbor </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Mich. </LOCATION>, said in an interview. <PERSON> Giora </PERSON> and other Israelis argue the only obvious shortcoming in the military court system was redressed by Defense Minister <PERSON> Yitzhak </PERSON> <PERSON> Rabin </PERSON> earlier this month when he announced that <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>, after 20 years of occupation, would establish army appeal courts. <PERSON> Kuttab </PERSON> said figures assembled by Palestinian lawyers show the total number of Arab detainees, normally about 3,000 at any one time, has doubled and the army has set up four new prisons with tent barracks in the occupied <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION>. According to the army, 1,927 Palestinians were arrested and 93 placed in jail for six months without trial under emergency regulations from Dec. 8 to Feb. 9. The Arab-owned <ORGANIZATION> Palestine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> puts the number of Arabs jailed without trial at 147. The process from arrest to trial in the military court system is well documented. A Palestinian suspected of participating in anti-Israeli activities is usually detained in the middle of the night because soldiers fear their presence in Arab towns or refugee camps during the day might spark protests. The detainee is handcuffed, often blindfolded, and taken to a military prison. No arrest warrant is ever shown and family members are not told where the suspect is being taken. It often takes a lawyer several weeks to track down his new client, who can be held incommunicado for up to six months. A judge is required to order a detention extension after the first 18 days. `` During the period of interrogation, the detainee is routinely subjected to beatings, forced to spend long hours in uncomfortable positions, threatened and submitted to other psychological measures,'' <PERSON> Kuttab </PERSON> said. `` Usually before the first 18-day period is up, the defendant breaks down and confesses to a variety of illegal activities,'' <PERSON> Kuttab </PERSON> said. `` Only after this is he permitted to see an attorney, and only then is the attorney told what charges his client faces.'' <PERSON> Abu </PERSON> <PERSON> Leban </PERSON> entered court with five other Arab defendants, four of whom had no attorney present. <PERSON> Kuttab </PERSON> was able to see his client and the charge sheet against him only minutes before the court session began. <PERSON> Kuttab </PERSON> argued in court that <PERSON> Abu </PERSON> <PERSON> Leban </PERSON> signed the confession only after being abused. He asked for, and was granted, a separate hearing about the admissiblity of the evidence. <PERSON> Kuttab </PERSON> said he did not intend actually to present a case on whether the evidence should be admitted, but only to use the extra time to try to plea bargain a shorter sentence. `` If I protest, his interrogator will deny it and he will just end up getting a tougher sentence,'' <PERSON> Kuttab </PERSON> said. `` What hurts most about the process is the pretense of propriety,'' he said. `` With a judge and a prosecutor and a defense attorney, it looks all right from the outside. But in fact, on a certain level, I feel I am a collaborator in the evil system.'' `` At least I brought him some cigarettes,'' <PERSON> Kuttab </PERSON> said of <PERSON> Abu </PERSON> <PERSON> Leban </PERSON>, shaking his head as he left court. `` I've turned into a social worker more than a lawyer in this system.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880228-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-28-88 2359EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-TribalClaim     02-28 0716</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Tribal Claim,0738</SECOND>
<HEAD>Tribes See Chance To Settle Longstanding Dispute Over Water
Project</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By PHILIP BRASHER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW TOWN, N.D. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The fertile <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> bottom lands where the <LOCATION> Arikara </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Hidatsa </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> Mandan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Indians </ORGANIZATION> thrived for seven centuries are gone forever, buried beneath the waters of <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sakakawea </LOCATION>. The 200-mile-long reservoir drove the Indians onto higher, less productive land, sliced their reservation into isolated sections and is blamed for precipitating soaring unemployment and alcoholism. The three tribes, who say they were coerced into surrendering the bottom lands without just compensation as the lake filled behind <LOCATION> Garrison </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dam </LOCATION>, believe they have a chance this year to get $ 178.4 million that they and a special federal commission think they deserve. `` The problem has been with us for 40 years. The time is right for a resolution,'' said <ORGANIZATION> Tribal </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> Lone Fight. The tribes, which total about 7,700 people, are asking the state's congressional delegation to introduce legislation that would give them $ 3.6 million a year for 50 years plus 4 percent interest on the unpaid balance of the settlement. The money would come from federal hydropower revenues, rather than the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION>, which tribal leaders believe should make the legislation more palatable to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. The bill also would fund municipal water projects on the reservation and authorize, but not pay for, replacement of a hospital and other facilities destroyed by the reservoir. Lone Fight says the bill `` is something that's supportable'' in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. But the federal <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Indian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Affairs </ORGANIZATION> opposes further compensation for the tribes. Rural electric cooperatives do n't like the idea of dipping into hydropower revenues. And members of the state's congressional delegation have yet to support the bill. `` We hope that something can be introduced this session. But until we can find something that everyone feels comfortable with, nothing can be introduced,'' said <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Jo </PERSON> <PERSON> Vrem </PERSON>, an aide to the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Select </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> on Indian Affairs. The tribes accepted $ 12.6 million from <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> in 1950, but <PERSON> Garrison </PERSON> <PERSON> Dam </PERSON> was already built and <PERSON> Lake </PERSON> <PERSON> Sakakawea </PERSON> was forming when the money was offered. The tribes and their supporters say the Indians had no choice but to take the settlement. `` When the <LOCATION> Indian </LOCATION> people were negotiating for the best possible deal, the water was up to their ankles ... and the offers were going down,'' Lone Fight said. When dam construction began in the 1940s, 90 percent of the Indians lived and farmed in the river valley, as their ancestors had for seven centuries. Unemployment on the reservation was negligible. Today, unemployment exceeds 50 percent and alcoholism is rampant, problems that have been linked to the disruption caused by Garrison Dam. About 3,400 Indians live on the reservation; another 4,300 tribal members live elsewhere. <PERSON> Lake </PERSON> <PERSON> Sakakawea </PERSON> is named for a Shoshone guide who worked for the <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON> and <PERSON> Clark </PERSON> expedition up the <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> in 1804. `` In my 66 years, I have seen a drastic change from being self-sufficent to being a very desperate economic situation,'' said <PERSON> Luther </PERSON> <PERSON> Grinnell </PERSON>, a tribal judge. <ORGANIZATION> Grinnell </ORGANIZATION> grew up on a family farm near <LOCATION> Elbowoods </LOCATION>, the reservation's main town before it was inundated. The tribes grew their own vegetables and cattle, cut firewood from trees along the river and mined nearby coal deposits, <ORGANIZATION> Grinnell </ORGANIZATION> said. `` We never heard of unemployment because everyone had their farms, and those who had jobs did n't farm,'' <ORGANIZATION> Grinnell </ORGANIZATION> said. A five-member panel appointed by <ORGANIZATION> Interior </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Hodel </PERSON> concluded in 1986 that the tribes were owed $ 178 million to $ 412 million in compensation. The <ORGANIZATION> Joint </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tribal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Advisory </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> agreed with Indian claims that the lake destroyed their self-sufficient way of life and precipitated the tribes' continuing social problems. If the tribes get the settlement, the money would be earmarked for programs, such as work projects and alcohol treatment, that would attack the reservation's social ills, Lone Fight said. However, in a recent meeting with tribal leaders, Assistant Secretary for <ORGANIZATION> Indian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Affairs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ross </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Swimmer </ORGANIZATION> claimed that the tribes have been adequately compensated through the federal services they receive. Swimmer's position was characterized by <PERSON> Ray </PERSON> <PERSON> Cross </PERSON>, an attorney for the tribes, as `` disingenuous.'' Bureau of Indian Affairs officials will meet soon with members of <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION>'s congressional delegation to discuss the tribes' proposal, <ORGANIZATION> BIA </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Carl </PERSON> <PERSON> Shaw </PERSON> said
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880228-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-28-88 2357EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p PM-US-Deleg-Sum     02-28 0836</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-US-Deleg-Sum,200</SECOND>
<NOTE>Eds: Includes results from Maine Democratic caucuses; note that
Democratic totals include ``super delegates'' in addition to
results from Iowa, New Hampshire and Maine.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here is the current breakdown of the presidential preference of the delegates to the Democratic and Republican national conventions. The preferences are based on delegates' public statements or binding state laws or party rules.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>DEMOCRATIC</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Total Changes Today 7 days 30 days <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> 54.50 10 0 22 <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> 39 0 0 26 <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> 10.55 0 0 0 <ORGANIZATION> Hart </ORGANIZATION> 0 0 0 0 <ORGANIZATION> Jackson </ORGANIZATION> 17.80 8 0 0 <ORGANIZATION> Simon </ORGANIZATION> 33 0 0 20 Others 0 0 0 0 Uncommitted 283.40 5 0 6
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 Needed to nominate: 2,082 Total delegate votes: 4,162 Chosen thus far: 438.25 Yet to be chosen: 3,723.75
</TEXT>
<HEAD>REPUBLICAN</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Total Changes Today 7 days 30 days <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> 61 0 0 61 <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> 60 0 18 42 <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> 35 0 0 35 <ORGANIZATION> Robertson </ORGANIZATION> 8 0 0 8 <ORGANIZATION> Others </ORGANIZATION> 0 0 0 0 <ORGANIZATION> Uncommitted </ORGANIZATION> 10 0 0 10
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 Needed to nominate: 1,139 Total delegate votes: 2,277 Chosen thus far: 174 Yet to be chosen: 2,103
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880228-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-28-88 2359EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-FiskUniversity     02-28 0825</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Fisk University,0847</SECOND>
<HEAD>Enrollment, Endowment Improve At Black University</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By VICKI BROWN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NASHVILLE, Tenn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Enrollment is up and the debt is down at <ORGANIZATION> Fisk </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, where only a few years ago students shivered in unheated dormitories because the historically black private institution could not pay its gas bill. As Fisk winds down its celebration of Black History Month, which included the dedication of a stamp honoring author <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Weldon </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>, faculty and students also celebrated the university's return from the brink of financial disaster When the <ORGANIZATION> Nashville </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Gas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> cut off service in early 1984 until <PERSON> Fisk </PERSON> paid a $ 170,000 debt, students brought space heaters to class and joined with faculty and staff members to raise funds to ensure the university's survival. The overall debt mounted to $ 4.1 million, but classes continued. <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> Ponder </PERSON>, appointed <PERSON> Fisk </PERSON>'s president in July 1984, led the school on a course of austerity programs and aggressive fund-raising. When Ponder was told, for example, that boiler repairs would cost $ 350,000, he found a Fisk alumnus, a maintenance expert, who did it for only $ 60,000. Ponder acknowledged in a recent interview that things are better at <LOCATION> Fisk </LOCATION>, but added `` you have to get the public to understand that help is still needed to get the resources to move this institution ... to the forefront of educational institutions in this country. `` I do n't say that lightly. That's where we've been and we will get back,'' said Ponder, who said the school did not lower its academic standards during its financial troubles. Today, debt at <PERSON> Fisk </PERSON> has been reduced to $ 200,000 and its endowment has reached $ 3.9 million. An unrestricted gift of $ 1.3 million by entertainer <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Cosby </PERSON> in December 1986 gave the school a boost, but officials say they have received substantial grass-roots support, too. However, three of the university's 23 trustees announced Friday that they will resign at the end of the school year. One trustee said the resignations were related to the accountability of those charged with day-to-day administration. <PERSON> Fisk </PERSON>'s financial aid director and assistant director were fired in December for allegedly failing to fill out forms to receive financial aid. Faculty salaries have increased 30 percent over the last three years to an average of $ 32,000 for a tenured professor, although still below the $ 35,000 to $ 40,000 Ponder said is appropriate. Aggressive recruiting of students brought enrollment, which dipped to 500 at one point, up to 644 students in the 1988 spring semester, an increase of 27 percent over the 1987 spring semester, said <PERSON> Harrison </PERSON> <PERSON> DeShields </PERSON>, director of the office of admissions and records. <PERSON> Bryon </PERSON> <PERSON> Cobb </PERSON>, a student from <LOCATION> Huntsville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, said <PERSON> Fisk </PERSON>'s role in black history in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> was important to him. `` <PERSON> Fisk </PERSON> introduced the black spiritual to the world, it was active in the civil rights movement, W.E.B. <PERSON> DuBois </PERSON> went to college here,'' <PERSON> Cobb </PERSON> said. In addition, he said, `` My understanding is that a degree from <PERSON> Fisk </PERSON> is as respected as one from <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION>.'' The financial crisis at the school had some positive benefits for the Fisk community, said <PERSON> Roland </PERSON> <PERSON> Hayes </PERSON> <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON>, now a graduate student. `` The student body handled the crisis well, we shared space heaters. It united us. We were able to confront a problem and come through it,'' <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> sid. The university, founded in 1867 by the Freedmen's <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> during Reconstruction, is no stranger to struggle. In fact, the campus was purchased with $ 150,000 raised by the college's Jubilee Singers during a European tour in the 1870s. The earnings of the singers, whose tours still bring $ 60,000 a year to <PERSON> Fisk </PERSON>, also paid for building Jubilee Hall, whose exterior was recently restored with a $ 150,000 federal grant. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Weldon </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>, a poet who was a diplomat and an early organizer of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> for the Advancement of Colored People, was a professor at <LOCATION> Fisk </LOCATION> in the early 1930s. W.E.B. <PERSON> DuBois </PERSON>, a philosopher and writer who graduated from <PERSON> Fisk </PERSON> in 1888, also helped found the <ORGANIZATION> NAACP </ORGANIZATION> and was the first black to earn a doctorate from <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION>. `` I think students are attracted here because it has the reputation of a good community. When they get here, they find out we have a dynamic science faculty and many of our students go to medical and dental schools,'' Ponder said. About 60 percent of <PERSON> Fisk </PERSON> graduates enroll for postgraduate study. <PERSON> Revais </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON>, executive assistant to the president and a history professor, said <PERSON> Fisk </PERSON>'s financial problems mirrored those of other liberal arts college, but were worse. `` In the 1960s and 1970s the philosophy of supporting a liberal arts education dried up and the interest shifted to business degrees,'' <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON> said. But <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON> said the quality of education at <PERSON> Fisk </PERSON> has never suffered and that peeling paint and cold classrooms do n't mean poor academics. `` I try to tell my students that there has always been an element of suffering in the tradition of black education,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880228-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-28-88 0145EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Britain-Students     02-28 0145</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Britain-Students,0149</SECOND>
<HEAD>Students March Against Proposed Education Bill</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Thousands of students marched through <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> Saturday, waving banners, chanting and banging drums to protest the government's proposed Education Reform Bill. Police, who closed several main roads to traffic, estimated about 10,000 demonstrators participated but the <ORGANIZATION> Nationl </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Students </ORGANIZATION> put the figure at 15,000-20 ,000 At one point, some 200 students sat down for several minutes at the entrance to 10 Downing Street, official residence of Prime Minister <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON>. Police said there were no arrests during the demonstration. Student leaders say Education Secretary <PERSON> Kenneth </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON>'s measure will result in less student representation on college governing bodies and give industrial and commercial organizations too much influence in higher education and education for adults. <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> claims his bill will raise standards and improve the quality of state education. The bill is now before <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880228-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-28-88 0212EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-MurderPlot     02-28 0380</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Murder Plot,0388</SECOND>
<HEAD>Three Mexican Nationals Convicted In Murder Of U.S. Customs Agent</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Three Mexican nationals, including a former Mexican police detective charged in the torture-murder of a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> drug agent, were convicted of conspiring to murder a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Customs agent. The charges grew out of a series of meetings with an undercover investigator in which defendant <PERSON> Raul </PERSON> <PERSON> Lopez </PERSON> <PERSON> Alvarez </PERSON> offered to murder the Customs agent for a $ 25,000 fee. No killing took place. <PERSON> Lopez </PERSON>, 29, who also faces charges in the 1985 slaying of <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Drug </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Enforcement </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> agent <PERSON> Enrique </PERSON> <PERSON> Camarena </PERSON>, was convicted Friday of conspiracy to murder a federal agent and conspiracy to kidnap a federal agent. Two men <PERSON> Lopez </PERSON> hired in <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> to assist him, <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Quintero </PERSON> <PERSON> Maldonado </PERSON>, 25, and <PERSON> Fabian </PERSON> <PERSON> Jimenez </PERSON> <PERSON> Martinez </PERSON>, 22, also were convicted in the conspiracy. <PERSON> Quintero </PERSON> was acquitted on a charge that he traveled to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> from <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> to carry out the murder plot. The men could receive life imprisonment. Sentencing was scheduled for April 18 before <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> Pamela </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Rymer </PERSON>. Lawyers for the defendants had argued that <PERSON> Lopez </PERSON> and the two men he hired never intended to carry out the murder, but had planned all along to stage a `` rip-off'' of the undercover drug agent with whom they were negotiating. They believed that the undercover agent was a narcotics dealer. <PERSON> Lopez </PERSON>, a former homicide investigator for the Mexican state judicial police, told undercover agents he was an `` enforcer'' for the powerful narcotics organization of <PERSON> Rafael </PERSON> <PERSON> Caro </PERSON> <PERSON> Quintero </PERSON> and <PERSON> Ernesto </PERSON> <PERSON> Fonseca </PERSON> <PERSON> Carrillo </PERSON> and had a direct role in <PERSON> Camarena </PERSON>'s abduction and torture In 12 hours of government tapes presented as evidence, <PERSON> Lopez </PERSON> bragged about his knowledge of <PERSON> Camarena </PERSON>'s torture and promised to repeat it on the Customs agent. `` If it was part of a scam, they oversold it too much,'' said jury foreman <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Armas </PERSON>, 28, a postal worker from <LOCATION> Alhambra </LOCATION>. `` Especially when they talked about killing someone _ you looked at their faces, and they showed no remorse.'' Nine people have been indicted in the <PERSON> Camarena </PERSON> case, two of whom will be tried with <PERSON> Lopez </PERSON>. <PERSON> Caro </PERSON> and <PERSON> Fonseca </PERSON> are jailed in <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> in connection with the case. <PERSON> Lopez </PERSON> had been charged in <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> with the <PERSON> Camarena </PERSON> murder, but was later released.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880228-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-28-88 0011EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-MissUSA-Assault 1stLd-Writethru a0624 02-28 0353</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Miss USA-Assault, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0624,0357</SECOND>
<HEAD>Suspect Rearrested In Assault Of Miss USA Co-Host</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: LEADS with 6 grafs to UPDATE with man freed on bond again,
real name determined, picking up 6th graf pvs, `I'm shocked...'.
SUBS penultimate graf, `If convicted...', to give suspect's real
name.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>EL PASO, Texas (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A man accused of attempting to sexually assault actress <PERSON> Tracy </PERSON> <PERSON> Scoggins </PERSON>, a co-host of the Miss <LOCATION> USA </LOCATION> pageant here, was rearrested Saturday after a judge's decision to set him free on $ 100 bond sparked protests. He later was freed again after posting a much higher bond. The man, <PERSON> Pedro </PERSON> <PERSON> Concepcion </PERSON> <PERSON> Padilla </PERSON>, 35, of <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Paso </LOCATION>, was initially arrested Thursday night after the assault in a hotel elevator. He was released early Friday on $ 100 bond set by associate municipal magistrate <PERSON> Rodolfo </PERSON> <PERSON> Romero </PERSON>. But the low bond infuriated State District Judge <PERSON> Brunson </PERSON> <PERSON> Moore </PERSON>, as well as Miss <PERSON> Scoggins </PERSON>, and <PERSON> Moore </PERSON> ordered him arrested again. <PERSON> Padilla </PERSON> turned himself in at 9:35 a.m. Saturday and jailed again on $ 100,000 bond. He posted the required 15 percent of that amount later in the day and was freed after spending about five hours in custody. Officials said the man originally gave authorities a false name, <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Garcia </PERSON>. He was re-arrested through the help of his attorney, according to sheriff's Capt. <PERSON> Paco </PERSON> <PERSON> Aguirre </PERSON>. `` I'm shocked and I'm outraged,'' Miss <PERSON> Scoggins </PERSON> said Friday after the suspect's release. `` What this says to me is that a man like this can save himself a whole expensive night of dinner and dancing and just pay $ 100 to assault the woman of his choice. That's a pretty good deal.'' Miss <PERSON> Scoggins </PERSON>, who starred in the <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> television series `` The Colbys,'' suffered minor bruises during the attack. Security guards and other guests who heard her screams came to her aid and subdued the attacker, she said. If convicted, <PERSON> Padilla </PERSON> could be sentenced to up to 10 years in prison and fined up to $ 5,000. Miss <PERSON> Scoggins </PERSON>, who lives in <LOCATION> Malibu </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, is in <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Paso </LOCATION> to be co-host of the Miss <LOCATION> USA </LOCATION> pageant, which will be broadcast live Tuesday nationwide.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880228-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-28-88 0006EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-US-Panama 3rdLd-Writethru a0669 02-28 1116</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-US-Panama, 3rd Ld-Writethru, a0669,1,050</SECOND>
<HEAD>U.S. Officials Say Delvalle Decided on His Own To Go Into Hiding</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDs: INSERTS new 3rd graf and INSERTS 9 grafs after 5th graf pvs
bgng, `President Reagan' to UPDATE with OAS debate, playing of tape
of Mrs. Delvalle; PICKS UP 9th graf pvs bgng, `Chewning said
questions'</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By HENRY GOTTLIEB</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration officials said Saturday that <PERSON> Eric </PERSON> <PERSON> Arturo </PERSON> <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON>, recognized by the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> as <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s president, decided on his own to go into hiding, but that he remained in telephone contact with <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> diplomats in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON> is `` safe and in high spirits'' after escaping arrest, and the struggle against the country's military leader will continue, <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON>'s envoy to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> said. The permanent council of the <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> States </ORGANIZATION>, after a lengthy and at times heated debate Saturday night on the situation in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>, took no position on the turmoil there. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration officials denied participating in <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON>'s escape, though they said the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> ambassador to <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Arthur </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Davis </PERSON>, was in contact with <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON> by telephone. They said they were not sure what <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON>'s next move would be. President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, who usually spends weekends at Camp David, <LOCATION> Md. </LOCATION>, was at the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> receiving reports on the fast-moving situation. The 30-member <ORGANIZATION> OAS </ORGANIZATION> council sidestepped a decision on whether to seat as <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s ambassador to the organization <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Leyton </PERSON>, the current envoy who is loyal to <LOCATION> Panamanian </LOCATION> military chief <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>, or <PERSON> Larence </PERSON> <PERSON> Chewning </PERSON> <PERSON> Fabrega </PERSON>, <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON>'s delegate. There had been indications from officials of the <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> delegation that the council would seat neither man, chosing instead to recognize <PERSON> Soraya </PERSON> <PERSON> Cano </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Panamanian </LOCATION> career diplomat who is a member of the <LOCATION> Panamanian </LOCATION> delegation to the OAS. The start of the formal council debate had been delayed for five hours while the envoys wrangled in private over the question of whom to credential as <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s representative. But when the debate commenced, shortly after 9 p.m. EST, no resolutions were offered dealing with that sticky question. Instead, <PERSON> Leyton </PERSON> was admitted to take part in the debate, at least for the time being, and he launched into a tirade against the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, accusing it of trying to destabilize his government. `` I wish to somehow resolve the crisis in the government of <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Leyton </PERSON> said. `` But this is not the forum.'' <PERSON> Leyton </PERSON> steadfastly denied <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> charges that <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> has been involved in drug trafficking, although the former <LOCATION> Panamanian </LOCATION> ambassador to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Gabriel </PERSON> <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON>, told the council, `` We are suffering a new phenomenon _ narco-militarism. This narcotic militarism knows no frontier.'' <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> T. </PERSON> <PERSON> McCormack </PERSON>, the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> ambassador to the <ORGANIZATION> OAS </ORGANIZATION>, said the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> could not accept the decision by the <ORGANIZATION> Panamanian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION> in which <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON> was deposed `` in a 10-minute rump session.'' In a riveting moment, <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON> had <ORGANIZATION> OAS </ORGANIZATION> technicians play an audio-cassette in which he had tape-recorded the telephone conversation with <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON>'s wife, <PERSON> Mariela </PERSON>, as Panamanian military personnel surrounded her house after her husband had fled. Mrs. <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON>, in a trembling voice, described how she had told the officers `` My husband is n't here, nor are you going to find him.'' A member of the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> mission, declining to be identified publicly, indicated that a part of the problem for the <ORGANIZATION> OAS </ORGANIZATION> ambassadors in deciding which Panamanian representative to credential was that they had doubts about what stance they should take. `` They're afraid of doing something which might prejudice the position their government has taken'' on <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>, the official said. <PERSON> Chewning </PERSON> said questions also had been raised about whether <PERSON> El </PERSON> <PERSON> Salvador </PERSON>'s ambassador, <PERSON> Ernesto </PERSON> <PERSON> Rivas </PERSON> <PERSON> Gallont </PERSON>, had the right to request the special session, with some ambassadors who support <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> opposing it. <PERSON> Chewning </PERSON> said those who oppose having the issue debated in the <ORGANIZATION> OAS </ORGANIZATION> `` simply do n't want the rest of the world to know what's going on in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>.'' He said the ambassadors had not allowed him or Leyton to address the gathering. <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Sosa </PERSON>, the <LOCATION> Panamanian </LOCATION> ambassador accredited to the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government, said in an interview on <ORGANIZATION> Cable </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Network </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Newsmaker Saturday'' that he was in touch with <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON> supporters in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> and `` we understand he is physically all right, he's safe and in high spirits,'' `` The struggle that President <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON> is leading now is a struggle to get the country back to civilian rule and get the country into democratic process and that's what the <LOCATION> Panamanian </LOCATION> people want,'' <PERSON> Sosa </PERSON> said `` That's why we feel we are going to carry the struggle, carry this fight.'' `` The Panamanian people are going to rally behind the constitutional president, he is going to win this out,'' <PERSON> Sosa </PERSON> said. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials, speaking on condition of anonymity, said the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> had nothing to do with <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON>'s decision to leave his house to avoid arrest, but that the Panamanian had been in touch with <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> by telephone. They denied initially that the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> knew <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON>'s whereabouts, but later in the day, when asked if <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials knew where <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON> had gone, they said, `` he is at an undisclosed location. According to the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials' account, soldiers came to <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON>'s house at 8 a.m. and were met at the door by <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON>'s wife While the soldiers were telling her they wanted to take <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON>, the president escaped out a back door, the officials said. `` It was his own decision, we did not do this,'' said one official, when asked if the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> had participated in <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON>'s escape. Several of <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON>'s family members, including several children and grandchildren, stayed overnight at the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, the officials said. The officials reaffirmed a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> decision to continue recognizing <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON> as <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s president, despite his replacement by a cabinet minister loyal to <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>. <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON>'s flight posed a dilemma for <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> policy-makers because his departure for the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> or another country would remove a key anti-Noriega symbol around which opposition to military rule could gather. Administration officials said on Saturday they hoped to marshal international support behind <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON>'s presidency, notably among Central American nations. High-level meetings continued at the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, where officials described the situation in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> as calm. They said the 10,000 American troops in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> _ assigned to protection of the <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Canal </LOCATION> _ were continuing to keep a low profile. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> policy toward <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> has grown increasingly hostile in recent months and the sentiment intensified after Feb. 5, when two federal grand juries returned indictments portraying him as a key conspirator in an international drug trafficking operation. <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON> had been viewed by the administration as little more than a front man for <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>, but that all changed Thursday evening when he broke with the military chieftain.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880228-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-28-88 0009EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-OlympicsNewspage     02-28 0387</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Olympics Newspage,0398</SECOND>
<HEAD>Debi Thomas A Disappointing Third In Figure Skating</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CALGARY, Alberta (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Debi </PERSON> <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON>' dream of Olympic gold turned into disappointment Saturday as <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>'s <PERSON> Katarina </PERSON> <PERSON> Witt </PERSON> won her second straight Olympic championship and Canadian <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> Manley </PERSON> took home the silver before a crowd of cheering countrymen. `` It's over. Back to school,'' said <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON>, who won the bronze medal despite three faulty landings. `` I'm not going to make any excuses. I was really skating well this week. It was n't supposed to happen, I guess. But I tried.'' While the top two skaters in the world staged a shootout to music from <PERSON> Bizet </PERSON>'s `` Carmen,'' <PERSON> Manley </PERSON> was so sensational in the freestyle that she finished first with seven judges. Combined with a fourth in the compulsory figures and a third-place finish in the short program earlier in the week, the performance put <PERSON> Manley </PERSON> in second place. <PERSON> Witt </PERSON>, a three-time world champion from <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, became the first repeat singles champion since <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Button </PERSON> took Olympic gold in 1948 and'52. <PERSON> Sonja </PERSON> <PERSON> Henie </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Norway </LOCATION> was the only woman to do it before <PERSON> Witt </PERSON>, winning in 1928, 1932 and 1936. <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON>, of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jose </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, the first black to win a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> figure skating crown and the 1986 world champion, skated poorly Saturday after doing well earlier in the Games. By contrast, <PERSON> Manley </PERSON> had the sellout crowd at the Olympic Saddledome enraptured. They cheered, hooted and stamped their feet when she finished hitting every element of her program. <PERSON> Jill </PERSON> <PERSON> Trenary </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Minnetonka </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Minn. </LOCATION>, finished fourth. She was fifth heading into the long program, worth 50 percent of the overall score. <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON>' bronze was the third figure skating medal here for the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Brian </PERSON> <PERSON> Boitano </PERSON> won the men's crown, and a bronze in pairs went to <PERSON> Jill </PERSON> <PERSON> Watson </PERSON> and <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Oppegard </PERSON>. In addition to the three figure skating medals, the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> team had three speed-skating medals: one each gold, silver and bronze. Speed skater <PERSON> Bonnie </PERSON> <PERSON> Blair </PERSON>, <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s only double medalist, tried again Saturday in the 1,500 meters but finished fourth, well off the pace. She won the gold in the 500 and the bronze in the 1,000 meters. As the Olympics winded up its next-to-last day, the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> had 27 medals, including 11 golds, while <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> in second place had 22, including nine golds.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880228-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-28-88 0114EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-TransplantDeath     02-28 0375</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Transplant Death,0385</SECOND>
<HEAD>Amy Hardin, 5, Dies Five Years After Liver Transplant</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CAHOKIA, Ill. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Amy </PERSON> <PERSON> Lynn </PERSON> <PERSON> Hardin </PERSON>, the infant who won the hearts of supporters from <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Illinois </ORGANIZATION> to the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> when she became the youngest liver transplant recipient five years ago, died Saturday at her home here. She was 5 years old. The transplanted liver <PERSON> Amy </PERSON> received on May 10, 1983, had begun to fail around Thanksgiving, said her mother, <PERSON> Robin </PERSON> <PERSON> Hardin </PERSON>. On Dec. 11, the family took <PERSON> Amy </PERSON> to the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Minnesota </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Minneapolis </LOCATION>, where the transplant had been performed. But the girl returned home Jan. 16 after doctors said her chances for recovery were not good. `` She could n't stand it anymore,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Hardin </PERSON> said. `` We made a promise that we would n't take her back to the hospital. We brought her home and the family took turns being with her.'' `` She's at peace now,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Hardin </PERSON> said. People throughout the region rallied in late 1982 and early 1983 to raise more than $ 260,000 through a variety of fund-raisers to pay for what then was considered an experimental transplant operation. The rock group Kiss performed a benefit concert for <PERSON> Amy </PERSON> in 1983 at <LOCATION> Kiel </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Auditorium </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Louis </LOCATION>. That same year, <PERSON> Amy </PERSON> received a letter of support from President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>. `` If it was n't for the community getting together, we would n't have had five years,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Hardin </PERSON> said `` She was the joy of our life. She was very strong. She fought all the way to the end.'' <PERSON> Amy </PERSON> was 11 months old at the time of the transplant. At that time, she was believed to be the world's youngest liver transplant patient. That record since has been broken, said <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Stanik </PERSON>, media relations director for <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Minnesota </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION>. Ms. <PERSON> Stanik </PERSON> said the survival rate of most liver transplant patients improves with time. `` Usually, but not always, doctors like to say that you are over the hump after five years, but one can never say never. There are just too many complications,'' she said. <PERSON> Amy </PERSON> died nearly four years and 10 months after her transplant. She would have turned 6 years old June 1. Besides her parents, <PERSON> Amy </PERSON> is survived by two brothers. Funeral services were set for Monday.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880228-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-28-88 0314EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Obit-Douglas     02-28 0242</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Obit-Douglas,0251</SECOND>
<HEAD>Former Air Force Secretary James H. Douglas Dead at 88</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LAKE FOREST, Ill. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Memorial services were held Saturday for <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, former secretary of the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON>, an attorney and investment banker, died Wednesday at his home in this northern <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> suburb. He was 88. <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON>, undersecretary and later secretary of the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> under President <PERSON> Dwight </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Eisenhower </PERSON>, presided over planning and construction of the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Springs </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Colo. </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON> is credited with persuading the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> to approve the design of the academy's chapel, which was controversial at the time, but which has since been hailed as an architectural triumph The Cedar Rapids, <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>, native graduated from <ORGANIZATION> Princeton </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> after serving as an <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> officer in World War I. He later spent a year at <ORGANIZATION> Cambridge </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> before attending <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Law </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION>. After earning his law degree in 1924, <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON> moved to <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON> held a high post in the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> under presidents <PERSON> Herbert </PERSON> <PERSON> Hoover </PERSON> and <PERSON> Franklin </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Roosevelt </PERSON>. He returned to the <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> during World War II. By 1945, he was chief of staff of the <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transport </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Command </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Eisenhower </PERSON> appointed <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON> undersecretary of the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> in 1953, and secretary in 1957. In 1959, <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON> began a two-year stint as deputy secretary of defense. He was awarded the Medal of Freedom in 1960. Survivors include his wife, <PERSON> Elinor </PERSON>, four sons and nine grandchildren.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880228-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-28-88 0117EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-PrisonHostage 1stLd-Writethru a0672 02-28 0445</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Prison Hostage, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0672,0456</SECOND>
<HEAD>Prison Hostage Situation Over; Staff Member, Inmates Apparently
Safe</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: UPDATES throughout with situation over, all hostages
apparently safe. No pickup.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>McALESTER, Okla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION> <LOCATION> State </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Penitentiary </LOCATION> inmate who had armed himself with a screwdriver and took three hostages gave up late Saturday after he was apparently overpowered by a hostage staff member. <ORGANIZATION> Correction </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Massie </PERSON> said the hostage situation ended shortly after 11 p.m. Saturday, more than 12 hours after it began. `` There was some kind of a scuffle'' inside the office where inmate <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON> was holding two prisoners and a staff counselor, <PERSON> Massie </PERSON> said. The four men then came walking out. `` Everyone seems to be fine,'' <PERSON> Massie </PERSON> said. `` There appears to be no serious problems.'' He said the hostages, identified as prison counselor <PERSON> Chuck </PERSON> <PERSON> Ryden </PERSON> and inmates <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> King </PERSON> and <PERSON> Allen </PERSON> <PERSON> Livingston </PERSON>, were taken to the prison's medical unit to be examined for injuries. `` We do n't know exactly what happened yet,'' <PERSON> Massie </PERSON> said. `` It looks like the officer -LRB- <PERSON> Ryden </PERSON> -RRB- was able to overpower the inmate.'' <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON>'s only weapon was apparently a screwdriver, authorities said. <PERSON> Linda </PERSON> <PERSON> Morgan </PERSON>, a public information officer at the prison, said <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON> grabbed <PERSON> Ryden </PERSON>, a correctional counselor, at about 10:20 a.m. after they went together to an office to discuss a problem. `` The other two inmates were out cleaning and painting and entered the office to get more supplies at which time they became hostages themselves,'' she said. Saturday afternoon, <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON>'s request for a pitcher of tea was granted in exchange for allowing a prison doctor to examine <PERSON> Ryden </PERSON>. The counselor had his blood pressure checked and `` seemed fine,'' Ms. <PERSON> Morgan </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON> had demanded that the warden contact the governor's office and that he be allowed to have an attorney present when he presented his grievances Ms. <PERSON> Morgan </PERSON> declined to say what the grievances were, other than to say that he originally approached the counselor with a complaint about his prison diet. Ms. <PERSON> Morgan </PERSON> said <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON> is serving a 15-year sentence for second-degree burglary and had been an inmate at the prison since 1986. Warden <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Saffle </PERSON> had said he would n't meet with <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON> or contact the governor's office until the situation has ended, Ms. <PERSON> Morgan </PERSON> said. Ms. <PERSON> Morgan </PERSON> said that approximately80 prisoners live in the cells in the section of the prison where the incident took place, and `` all are in their cells.'' The McAlester penitentiary was the site of an uprising in December 1985 when inmates protesting prison conditions held seven hostages for nearly 17 hours before releasing them unharmed. The institution has been under a 23-hour-a-day lockdown since that episode, officials said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880228-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-28-88 0122EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>b i AM-Panama 6thLd-Writethru a0703 02-28 0842</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Panama, 6th Ld-Writethru, a0703,0867</SECOND>
<HEAD>URGENT</HEAD>
<HEAD>Ousted President Flees House; Ordered Out of Panama</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: LEADS with 2 grafs to RESTORE attribution. Picks up 3rd graf
pvs, ```I'm going ...</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By REID G. MILLER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PANAMA CITY, Panama (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Eric </PERSON> <PERSON> Arturo </PERSON> <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON> fled his house hours after government agents warned him to leave the country, a relative said. The deposed president later vowed from hiding Saturday to fight any attempt to expel him. <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON> slipped away on foot `` to protect himself'' _ to avoid arrest and deportation by military strongman Gen. <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>, the ousted president's brother-in-law, <PERSON> Raul </PERSON> <PERSON> Diaz </PERSON>, told reporters. `` I'm going to stay here and I'm going to stick it out. I'm going to fight it all the way,'' <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON> later told ABC News by telephone `` I want you to let the world to know that I'm in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>, that you spoke to me, that I'm not leaving anywhere.'' He refused to disclose his whereabouts. The <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> also said <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON> remained in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> and had been in contact with <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. Ambassador <PERSON> Arthur </PERSON> <PERSON> Davis </PERSON>. <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> said it had been contacted by the ousted president, and quoted the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> as saying <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON> was not at a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> installation. <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s canal zone is headquarters to the 10,000-troop <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Command </ORGANIZATION>, which runs <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military operations in <LOCATION> Latin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>. The National Assembly, with opposition lawmakers boycotting, ousted <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON> Friday, a day after he tried to fire <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> as Defense Forces chief. <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>, who controls the 15,000-strong military and police and is the power behind the civilian government, is under <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> indictment on drug trafficking charges and claims the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> was behind the attempt to fire him. <PERSON> Diaz </PERSON> said security agents under <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>'s command had on Friday told <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON> to leave <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON> refused to accept his ouster. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> also continued to recognize him. <PERSON> Ana </PERSON> <PERSON> Raquel </PERSON> <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON>, sister of the ousted president, said family members had visited him and found, `` He is well, calm, in a secure place and continues carrying out his functions as president of <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>.'' Deposed Vice President <PERSON> Roderick </PERSON> <PERSON> Esquivel </PERSON> and his family also dropped out of sight Saturday. Top officials of his <ORGANIZATION> Liberal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> said they had talked to him by telephone, but said he would not reveal his whereabouts out of concern for his safety. <PERSON> Esquivel </PERSON> was dismissed early Friday along with <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON>. Meanwhile, a national strike called by the main opposition group got off to a slow start Saturday. Soldiers came to <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON>'s house at 8 a.m. and were met at the door by <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON>'s wife, <PERSON> Mariela </PERSON>. While the soldiers were telling her they wanted to take <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON>, the president escaped out a back door, according to <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> sources, speaking on condition of anonymity, said <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON> had been in telephone contact with <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> and that members of his family were at the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION>. Diplomats said they expected <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>'s government would file criminal charges against the deposed president. Bereft of power, <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON> told reporters Friday night: `` I do n't have a seat of government, nor military support, but I do have 2 million Panamanians who are tired and bored of living under a regime that one man has governed capriciously, and because of that I call for national resistance to paralyze the entire country starting Monday. He also urged a worldwide trade embargo against <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>. The opposition National Civic Crusade called an immediate general strike. The coalition of 200 groups has been calling since last June for the ouster of <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>, who has run the country since 1983. <PERSON> Aurelio </PERSON> <PERSON> Barria </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> Panamanian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chamber </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Industry </ORGANIZATION>, said the Crusade hoped to `` totally paralyze'' the nation by early next week. Still, most shops and other businesses were open Saturday morning, although they traditionally close their doors at noon for the remainder of the weekend. Police threw up barricades Friday and blocked the short street in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> where <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON>'s modest but modern home is located, refusing to allow <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> and Rep. <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Burton </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Ind </LOCATION>., to visit <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON> Other policemen could be seen in the front yard of the small house. At noon Saturday, the barricades where withdrawn. <PERSON> Diaz </PERSON> then came out and spoke to reporters. <PERSON> Diaz </PERSON> said a police officer called at the <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON> home Saturday morning and told family members the former president should leave <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>. Later, he said security agents had also contacted <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON> Friday, warning him to leave the country. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has called for <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>'s removal since he was indicted in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> on Feb. 5 on drug trafficking charges. The indictment says <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> allegedly let <LOCATION> Colombian </LOCATION> narcotics traffickers use <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> as a base for smuggling cocaine and marijuana into the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, receiving kickbacks from drug profits. <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> has blamed protests that began last summer and the indictment on efforts by <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> conservatives to prevent transfer of the <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Canal </LOCATION> to this country by the end of 1999. American military personnel in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> were on alert and civilians were told to keep a low profile.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880228-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-28-88 0125EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-DonorBabies     02-28 0421</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Donor Babies,0432</SECOND>
<HEAD>Life Support Pulled From Texas Infant With Almost No Brain</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOMA LINDA, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> infant born with almost no brain was taken off life-support equipment that was intended to help preserve her tiny heart and other organs for transplantation, a doctor said Saturday. `` Baby <PERSON> Evelyn </PERSON> continues to breathe on her own, but shows signs of gradual deterioration,'' Dr. <PERSON> Joyce </PERSON> <PERSON> Peabody </PERSON>, chief of neonatology at <ORGANIZATION> Loma </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Linda </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>, said in a statement late Saturday. <PERSON> Evelyn </PERSON> <PERSON> Keys </PERSON> was born with a fatal genetic birth defect known as anencephaly, in which much of the upper brain and skull are missing. <PERSON> Loma </PERSON> <PERSON> Linda </PERSON> has developed the nation's first guidelines using such infants as organ donors. However, little <PERSON> Evelyn </PERSON> never met the hospital's criteria for brain-death since she was born seven days ago, and machine-assisted breathing was stopped Saturday, with her parents' consent, <ORGANIZATION> Peabody </ORGANIZATION> said. Although three newborns needing healthy livers had been identified during the week, the likelihood of a vital organ transplant dropped to nil, hospital spokesman <PERSON> Anita </PERSON> <PERSON> Rockwell </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Baby </PERSON> <PERSON> Evelyn </PERSON> will be allowed to die naturally, she said. `` It is highly unlikely that she will be able to donate organs such as liver and heart, because without continuation of assisted breathing, oxygen deprivation of these organs will occur prior to her death,'' Ms. <PERSON> Rockwell </PERSON> said. Details about the potential liver recipients were n't disclosed, but Ms. <PERSON> Rockwell </PERSON> said they were n't at <LOCATION> Loma </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Linda </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Evelyn </PERSON> was born Feb. 20 in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Antonio </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, to <PERSON> Judy </PERSON> <PERSON> Keys </PERSON>, 22, and Airman <PERSON> Todd </PERSON> <PERSON> Keys </PERSON>, 21, stationed at <ORGANIZATION> Lackland </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Base </ORGANIZATION>. The infant was flown to <LOCATION> Loma </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Linda </LOCATION> that same day to be used in the donor program. Anencephalic babies usually die within days after birth. <PERSON> Loma </PERSON> <PERSON> Linda </PERSON>, a pioneer in infant heart transplants, has sought to establish a practice of sustaining anencephalic babies so vital organs can be used after brain death is certified by two independent physicians. Under the hospital's rules, however, no baby is kept on life-support longer than a week, whether brain death has occurred during that time or not. <PERSON> Loma </PERSON> <PERSON> Linda </PERSON> doctors anticipate that <PERSON> Baby </PERSON> <PERSON> Evelyn </PERSON>'s heart valves, and perhaps corneas will be donated after her heart stops, Ms. <PERSON> Rockwell </PERSON> said. The same day <PERSON> Evelyn </PERSON> was born, another anencephalic baby, identified only as <PERSON> Baby </PERSON> <PERSON> John </PERSON>, died at <LOCATION> Loma </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Linda </LOCATION> after efforts find a suitable liver or heart recipient were unsuccessful. He had been declared brain dead two days earlier. In his case, doctors were able to use a heart valve after he died.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880228-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-28-88 0239EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Sikhs     02-28 0404</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Sikhs,0416</SECOND>
<HEAD>Wanted Sikh Militant Killed In Gunfight With Police</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CHANDIGARH, India (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A Sikh extremist wanted in the 1986 murder of former army chief <PERSON> Arun </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Vaidya </PERSON> was killed Saturday in a gunbattle with police, the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> India </ORGANIZATION> reported. The news agency quoted <LOCATION> Punjab </LOCATION> state police chief <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Ribeiro </PERSON> as saying <PERSON> Surindra </PERSON> <PERSON> Singh </PERSON> was killed after he was challenged by a police patrol in <LOCATION> Chandigarh </LOCATION>, the state capital. One of the militant's accomplices, identified as <PERSON> Harjinder </PERSON> <PERSON> Singh </PERSON>, was also killed while another was injured, <PERSON> Ribeiro </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Surindra </PERSON> <PERSON> Singh </PERSON> is one of the more than 20 militants believed to be involved in the Aug. 10, 1986 assassination of <LOCATION> Vaidya </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Pune </LOCATION>, in western <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>. Two others, <PERSON> Ranjit </PERSON> <PERSON> Singh </PERSON> <PERSON> Gill </PERSON> and <PERSON> Sukhminder </PERSON> <PERSON> Singh </PERSON>, were arrested in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> last year and are facing extradition proceedings. Another eight suspects have been arrested in <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Vaidya </PERSON> was the army chief when soldiers stormed the <ORGANIZATION> Golden </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Temple </ORGANIZATION> in the Sikh holy city of <LOCATION> Amritsar </LOCATION> in 1984 to dislodge <ORGANIZATION> Sikh </ORGANIZATION> extremists who were using it as a base. Prime Minister <PERSON> Indira </PERSON> <PERSON> Gandhi </PERSON> was assassinated by two of her Sikh bodyguards later in the year. Meanwhile, police in <LOCATION> Amritsar </LOCATION>, 130 miles northwest of <LOCATION> Chandigarh </LOCATION>, blamed Sikh extremists for the killing of seven members of a Sikh family in a nearby village. <LOCATION> Amritsar </LOCATION> <LOCATION> District </LOCATION> police chief <PERSON> Izhar </PERSON> <PERSON> Alam </PERSON> said the family was slain Friday night by six Sikhs armed with automatic rifles. The killings occurred in <LOCATION> Talwandi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Chamchuk </LOCATION> <LOCATION> village </LOCATION>, 25 miles west of <LOCATION> Amritsar </LOCATION>. UNI quoted unnamed police sources as saying the family apparently refused to pay extortion money to the <ORGANIZATION> Khalistan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION>, one of several Sikh militant groups active in <LOCATION> Punjab </LOCATION>. In other militant-related violence in the state, a Hindu policeman was killed by Sikh radicals early Saturday near the town of <LOCATION> Ludhiana </LOCATION> in central <LOCATION> Punjab </LOCATION>, police said. The killings raised to at least 304 the numkber of people killed this year in attacks blamed on Sikh militants. Nearly two-thirds of the victims have been Sikhs. Sikh militants have been waging a guerrilla war since 1983 for a separate state in <LOCATION> Punjab </LOCATION>, which they propose to call <LOCATION> Khalistan </LOCATION>. Last year, more than 1,000 people were killed in <LOCATION> Punjab </LOCATION> by the militants. Sikhs, whose religion is an offshoot of <LOCATION> Hinduism </LOCATION>, claim they are discriminated against by <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>'s Hindu majority. Sikhs comprise about 2 percent of <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>'s 800 million population but are a majority in <LOCATION> Punjab </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880228-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-28-88 0740EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i BC-Israel-Violence     02-28 0555</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Israel-Violence,0570</SECOND>
<HEAD>Two Arabs Shot To Death, Cabinet Debates Barring Media From
Occupied Lands</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JEFFREY ULBRICH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ABUD, Occupied West Bank (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Arab reports said <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> soldiers opened fire to quell riots sparked by Jewish settlers who tried to enter a <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> village at night. The army on Sunday confirmed two Arabs were shot to death. Meanwhile, <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> navy </ORGANIZATION> sank a boat carrying guerrillas who were en route from <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> to launch an attack on <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>. Lebanese police said two Palestinian fighters were killed in the incident Saturday night and three swam to shore. Also, three Arab guerrillas were killed in southern <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> early Sunday after they stormed an outpost of pro-Israeli Lebanese militiamen in <LOCATION> Beit </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Yaoun </LOCATION> near <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s border, the army said. The violence came as Secretary of State <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> arrived in <LOCATION> Cairo </LOCATION> for talks with President <PERSON> Hosni </PERSON> <PERSON> Mubarak </PERSON>, continuing his efforts aimed at starting Arab-Israeli peace talks and helping restore calm in the occupied <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strip </LOCATION>. But the bloodshed has increased since he arrived Thursday on the five-day mission. At least 11 Palestinians have been killed and dozens more wounded in the occupied lands in the period. <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s 24-member Cabinet debated the violence on Sunday, and <ORGANIZATION> Israel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> radio </ORGANIZATION> said Transportation Minister <PERSON> Chaim </PERSON> <PERSON> Corfu </PERSON> proposed closing the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> to media coverage. No decision was reported on the issue. Israeli soldiers on Sunday sealed the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> village of <LOCATION> Abud </LOCATION>, 20 miles northwest of <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION>, where the two Arabs were killed Saturday night. They twice turned away a reporter who tried to talk to witnesses. Army spokesmen said the shootings were being investigated. The Arab-run <ORGANIZATION> Palestinian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> said Jewish settlers had tried to enter the village after nightfall and were turned away by the 3,000 residents. Soldiers arrived about 8 p.m. and clashed with villagers who hurled stones. They fired flares to provide light and later opened fire with live ammunition, the agency said. <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> radio said <PERSON> Arab </PERSON> demonstrators blocked a main highway outside the village and stoned <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> soldiers. It said a number of Jewish settlers also arrived on the scene. Shots were fired, and the army was investigating the source of the gunfire, <ORGANIZATION> Israel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> radio </ORGANIZATION> added. The Palestine Press identified the two dead as <PERSON> Raed </PERSON> <PERSON> Mahmoud </PERSON> <PERSON> Awad </PERSON> <PERSON> Barghouti </PERSON>, 17, who was shot in the head, and <PERSON> Ahmed </PERSON> <PERSON> Ibrahim </PERSON> <PERSON> Mustafa </PERSON> <PERSON> al </PERSON> <PERSON> Barghouti </PERSON>, 22, who was wounded in the stomach. The deaths brought to 74 the number of Arabs killed by Israeli gunfire and beatings since anti-occupation rioting erupted Dec. 8, according to <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> figures. Hundreds more have been wounded. Before flying to <LOCATION> Cairo </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> met separately with <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON> and Foreign Minister <PERSON> Shimon </PERSON> <PERSON> Peres </PERSON>, who told reporters the negotiations were complicated `` but not hopeless'' despite rejections by <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION> on Saturday. `` Nothing is dead, and nothing is at a dead end. It is a very complicated issue. It may take time,'' <PERSON> Peres </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON>' peace plan envisions accelerationg negotiations on Palestinian self-rule in the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION>, which <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> seized in the 1967 <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> war, with the eventual goal of trading land for peace with the Arabs. Jordanian and Syrian leaders told <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> any peace talks would have to include the participation of the <ORGANIZATION> Palestine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> in an international conference. <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> does not recognize the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880228-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-28-88 1121EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-FishingorLiving     02-28 0285</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Fishing or Living,0294</SECOND>
<HEAD>Muskegon: To Live, Or Fish?</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MUSKEGON, Mich. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 If you care more about fishing than living, come to <LOCATION> Muskegon </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Muskegon </LOCATION> was second to last in Money magazine's ranking of places to live in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. But Field and Stream magazine's special edition, the `` 1988 Guide to the Best in Freshwater Sport,'' lists <LOCATION> Muskegon </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Muskegon </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> together as one of the `` 25 Favorite Fishing Trips for'88.'' The special edition, which wo n't go on sale until April, offers anglers tips and tactics for taking big fish. `` Bass -LRB- largemouths and smallmouths -RRB- and walleyes are two gamefish species anglers will find in particularly good supply on <LOCATION> Muskegon </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION>,'' the article says. `` The <LOCATION> Muskegon </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> ... features one of the finest river fisheries in the state.'' An article in the July 1987 issue of Money magazine put <ORGANIZATION> Muskegon </ORGANIZATION>, a city of about 40,000 on the western side of <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Lower </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Penninsula </LOCATION>, next to last among the ten worst cities to live in the country Most vacationing anglers come to <LOCATION> Muskegon </LOCATION> after salmon, steelhead, bass and walleye, Field and <PERSON> Stream </PERSON> says. Walleye _ and <PERSON> Muskegon </PERSON> <PERSON> Lake </PERSON>'s reputation as a trophy spot for them _ are fast approaching salmon as the area's top tourist draw, it adds. The <ORGANIZATION> Manufacturers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Walleye </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>, a group of touring professional anglers, has chosen <LOCATION> Muskegon </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> as the site for its final regular-season points tournament for 1988. As many as 200 two-person teams will pay $ 200 each to vie for the $ 7,000 first prize in the Aug. 27-28 tourney, which offers a purse of $ 32,000. <LOCATION> Muskegon </LOCATION> professional walleye guide <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> said that last year he took more than 60 walleyes weighing more than 9 pounds.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880228-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-28-88 1121EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a AM-BRF--ChurchDeficit     02-28 0178</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Church Deficit,0182</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bishop: U.S. Catholics Should Help Pay Vatican Deficit</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PITTSBURGH (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Roman Catholic Bishop <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Wuerl </PERSON> says <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Catholics should help pay the <ORGANIZATION> Vatican </ORGANIZATION>'s $ 56.7 million operating deficit. <PERSON> Wuerl </PERSON>, named head of the Diocese of <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION> on Feb. 12, said the deficit was created when <PERSON> Pope </PERSON> <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> II </PERSON> `` raised salaries substantially,'' to help employees keep up with the cost of living. `` How do we pay for this?'' he said Friday. `` In the past we have always said to the pope, `` Good Luck.''' Considering the size of the church, the deficit is not a large one and could be paid off with an endowment, <PERSON> Wuerl </PERSON> said. Details of the 1986 deficit were made public at the insistence of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> bishops. <PERSON> Wuerl </PERSON> said the bishops told <ORGANIZATION> Vatican </ORGANIZATION> officials that <LOCATION> Americans </LOCATION> must `` see balance sheets'' before they would help pay. The bishop also said the <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION>'s administration costs have increased considerably since 1965, when reforms by the <ORGANIZATION> Second </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Vatican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> added commissions, secretariats and other boards. Church officials also have increased their missionary work, he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880228-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-28-88 1121EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a AM-BRF--FordProfit-Sharing     02-28 0149</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Ford Profit-Sharing,0153</SECOND>
<HEAD>County Sues to Hold Ford Profit-Sharing Checks for Some</HEAD>
<DATELINE>DETROIT (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Wayne </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> has gone to court seeking an order to seize profit-sharing checks for <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Motor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> employees who are behind in child support payments. The suit, filed Friday, would force the company to withhold profit-sharing checks, averaging about $ 3,700 per worker, for 3,369 employees who are more than $ 500 behind in payments. The checks are to be handed out March 8. `` If we learn of any payments to potential child support payers who are in arrears, we are going to make every effort to get the portion that the custodial parents are entitled to,'' said <ORGANIZATION> Wayne </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Circuit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> Administrator <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kent </PERSON> <PERSON> Batty </PERSON>. <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman <PERSON> Kim </PERSON> <PERSON> Adler </PERSON> said the company could not withhold the checks without a court order. Circuit Judge <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Kaufman </PERSON> has scheduled a hearing for Tuesday on the suit.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880228-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-28-88 1127EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w AM-ContraAid Bjt   02-28 0737</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Contra Aid, Bjt,790</SECOND>
<HEAD>Congress Faces New Battle on Contra Aid</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JIM DRINKARD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> faces a confusing choice this week between two rival versions of a plan to help the Nicaraguan rebels. A vote is scheduled for Thursday to decide whether the U.S.-backed Contras will get an aid package drafted by <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Democrats, a similar one drawn up by House Republicans, or nothing at all. Current authority to aid the Contras expires at midnight Monday, and the rebels are said to be rapidly running out of items like food, clothing and medicine that the new aid plans would provide. Both versions of the new aid package would keep non-lethal supplies flowing to the rebels at their positions inside Nicaraguan territory. Neither would provide new weapons. And both would set up a $ 14 million program to help war-injured children on all sides of the conflict. But while similar in what they would do for the rebels in the short term, the two versions set starkly different ground rules for an impending rematch between the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration and the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> over military aid for the rebels. The Democratic version, which <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> leaders say they are confident will pass, holds out the possbility that a new military aid package could be considered sometime after June 1. But the conditions for such consideration are strict: it could happen only if the Democrat-controlled <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Intelligence </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> certifies that the Contras and the leftist Sandinista government have not reached a cease-fire and that it is the Sandinistas' fault. Then, the proposal would allow _ but not require _ the party's leadership to bring forth an aid proposal of its own design, and would allow amendment of the package on the floor The <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> aid proposal would give the president, rather than <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, the right to design the military aid package, and would leave to him the determination whether a cease-fire is in effect, and whether any failure to reach a truce is the fault of the Sandinista regime. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> could make such a request as soon as April 16, and it would have to be acted on by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> without delay. A similar expedited procedure was followed when the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> on Feb. 3 rejected <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s previous aid request, which included weapons and other military supplies, by a vote of 219 to 211. Another difference between the two packages is that the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> version would leave authority to deliver the aid in the hands of the <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Intelligence </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION>, which has been supervising a fairly successful airdrop program. Democrats, many of whom are suspicious of the spy agency, would turn the delivery program over to the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> to supervise, keeping the same private contractors, planes and crews now doing the work. The showdown over the two competing aid packages was supposed to have occured last week, but Democrats postponed action at the last minute, citing confusion among lawmakers over the differences between the two bills. Republicans said the real reason for the delay was that the majority feared it was losing supporters to their competing version. Part of the difficulty Democrats have faced is division among outside peace groups which lobbied hard to defeat <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s military aid proposal earlier this month and were reluctant to now turn around and support a Contra aid package, no matter how `` humanitarian'' its terms. Some groups, including Presbyterians, Lutherans, Quakers and <PERSON> Catholics </PERSON>, were supporting the Democratic package in hopes it would lessen the pressure for a future request for Contra weapons. But representatives of the Unitarian, Methodist, <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Baptist </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Brethren </ORGANIZATION> churches wrote lawmakers last week that `` we believe it is important that no aid in any form be provided that would assist the Contras in maintaining an armed force to wage war against the government and the people of <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>.'' House leaders were meeting with such outside groups to try to persuade them to unite behind the Democratic proposal before Thursday's vote, and Rep. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Obey </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Wis </LOCATION>., a supporter the party's package, expressed impatience with the groups' all-or-nothing `` Any theology student will tell you the first thing you learn is that the greatest enemy of morality is moralism,'' Obey said. `` If your goal is to save lives and wind the war down, then you have to have tactics and strategy as well as good wishes. I wish liberals could count -LRB- votes -RRB- as well as they can feel.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880228-0025 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-28-88 1128EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w AM-DietStudy     02-28 0421</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Diet Study,440</SECOND>
