<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881202-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-02-88 0034EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--Germany-Exorcism     12-02 0161</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Germany-Exorcism,0165</SECOND>
<HEAD>Woman Sentenced In Exorcism Death</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CONSTANCE, West Germany (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A 74-year-old woman was convicted of killing another woman by trying to exorcise the devil from her and was sentenced to six years in a psychiatric institution. The Constance regional court convicted <PERSON> Magdalena </PERSON> <PERSON> Maria </PERSON> <PERSON> Kohler </PERSON> on Thursday of causing the death of a 66-year-old widow over five years of exorcism rites. Mrs. <PERSON> Kohler </PERSON> told the court she believed the victim was possessed by the devil. <PERSON> Anna </PERSON> <PERSON> Wermuthaeuser </PERSON>'s bruised body was found at Mrs. <PERSON> Kohler </PERSON>'s home in February. An autopsy revealed she had been beaten for years. Mrs. <PERSON> Kohler </PERSON> admitted during testimony that she had locked the victim in her room, saying Mrs. <PERSON> Wermuthaeuser </PERSON> had `` gone crazy'' and that the devil had spoken through her. She denied beating the victim. Mrs. <PERSON> Kohler </PERSON> was convicted in <LOCATION> Zurich </LOCATION> in 1969 and sentenced to 10 years in prison in connection with another exorcism rite that claimed the life of a teen-age girl.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881202-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-02-88 0035EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Britain-Wine     12-02 0244</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Britain-Wine,0250</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bottle of Wine Sells For $30,000</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A 177-year-old bottle of French wine sold for $ 30,525. `` The buyer has n't told me what he's going to do with it, but if he has any sense he will probably drink it,'' said <PERSON> Christie </PERSON>'s auctioneer <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Broadbent </PERSON> The buyer at Thursday's auction was a Swiss bidding by telephone who did not want his name published. The seller was <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Gerlach </PERSON> <PERSON> Hansen </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Vedbaek </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Denmark </LOCATION>. The wine in an old green bottle was a Sauterne dated 1811 from the Chateau Yquem vineyards south of <LOCATION> Bordeaux </LOCATION>. `` We expected to get over 10,000 pounds -LRB- $ 18,500 -RRB- for it,'' said <PERSON> Broadbent </PERSON>. `` The 1811 vintage was highly successful in every European wine district and as there was a comet that year, it is known as the comet vintage. It is as celebrated as the vintages of 1784 and 1847, and arguably is the most renowned of all time,'' the auctioneer said. <PERSON> Broadbent </PERSON> said <PERSON> Christie </PERSON>'s had not sold a similar bottle but that he had tasted one two years ago. `` It had a lovely color with a warm glow and a raisiny bouquet, full of flavor and life _ a beautiful drink and a rare experience,'' the auctioneer said. The record price paid for a bottle of wine is 105,000 pounds, then about $ 150,000, for a 1787 Chateau Lafite red, sold Dec. 5, 1985. The bottle had been initialed for dispatch to <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Jefferson </PERSON>, but it was never delivered.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881202-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-02-88 0012EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-SpaceShuttle 4thLd-Writethru a0836 12-02 0798</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Space Shuttle, 4th Ld - Writethru, a0836,0813</SECOND>
<HEAD>NASA Gives Go-Ahead for Friday Launch Attempt</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: SUBS 2nd graf, `Officials were ..., to UPDATE with refueling
begun; picks up 3rd graf: `NASA spokesman ...</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By HARRY F. ROSENTHAL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CAPE CANAVERAL, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Acting on an optimistic weather report, <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> decided to try again Friday to send <LOCATION> Atlantis </LOCATION> on the secret military mission that was scrubbed Thursday because of violently shifting 104 mph winds in the shuttle's flight path. Officials were briefed by weather experts late Thursday and shortly before midnight workers began refueling the spacecraft for a launch Friday during a three-hour period beginning at 6:32 a.m. EST. <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Young </PERSON> said the launch management team was `` very upbeat'' about prospects for Friday because the weather system that postponed liftoff Thursday `` has left the area.'' `` The upper winds are essentially more benign than they were today,'' <PERSON> Young </PERSON> said. He added that surface winds were expected to be an acceptable 10 knots out of the north at the opening of the window but would `` tend to become more marginal at the end of the period.'' Earlier, <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> weathermen had said there was a 70 percent chance that winds would not interfere again if Atlantis could be launched soon after sunrise. Should Friday's launch have to be scrubbed, <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> would have to wait until Sunday to try again. The space agency's policy prohibits putting work crews through the hectic launch schedule three days in a row. <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> Cmdr. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gibson </PERSON> and his four-man military crew, dressed in uncomfortable, bulky escapet suits, had been lying on their backs in cabin seats for nearly five hours Thursday when the decision was made to scrub. `` They took it in stride, so did the rest of the team,'' said launch director <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Sieck </PERSON>. `` We've been talking about the threat of this ... so it came as no surprise.'' The astronauts themselves were not heard from publicly because <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION>, operating under strict <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> secrecy requirements, did not carry the usual shuttle-to-launch control conversations over its radio circuit. Using all the resources at its command _ high-altitude weather balloons, radar, and a shuttle pilot flying through the clouds _ <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> continuously sampled the weather before finally calling it quits. `` We were watching the weather all the way and finally scrubbed due to the winds aloft,'' <PERSON> Sieck </PERSON> said. `` There was no hope we were going to get out of the situation.'' Rain had left the area and skies had begun clearing, but eight miles above the <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ocean </LOCATION> winds exceeded hurricane force. <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> engineer, said the blasts were so powerful and erratic that the shuttle's computer could not be programmed to safely adjust its flight path. Such winds could cause serious damage to the shuttle's wings. Col. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Madura </PERSON>, an <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> weatherman, said the storm front that caused the problems would be offshore Friday but could be followed by strong ground winds that might affect a launch. Sources said the countdown, blacked out publicly for security reasons, had been held twice for one-hour periods. It was allowed to proceed to the nine-minute-to-launch mark so that quick advantage could be taken of a break in the weather. None came. After the scrub, technicians immediately started draining the half-million gallons of supercold fuel that feed the shuttle's three main engines. <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION>'s practice is to go through the loading and unloading cycle only twice in a 48-hour period, then calling a two-day break to give technicians a rest. So if weather interfered again with a fueled shuttle on Friday, the liftoff would be delayed at least until Sunday. The scrub extended <PERSON> Gibson </PERSON>'s unenviable shuttle record for suiting up and getting ready to fly, only to be disappointed. As commander of the 24th space shuttle mission, he had boarded his ship, <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION>, six times before it finally made the flight. <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> had known for days that bad weather was expected at this seaside space port Thursday morning, but it gambled on beating the one-in-five odds that weathermen gave for acceptable conditions. The scrub cost of fueling-draining-refueling, of having ships waiting to retrieve the booster rockets and a myriad of other launch activities has been estimated at $ 250,000. Atlantis' mission is only the second since the Challenger explosion on Jan. 28, 1986, that killed seven astronauts. Though neither <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> nor the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> will discuss the caro, sources said the shuttle is to launch a $ 500 million spy satellite called Lacrosse. The sources said the satellite carries a powerful new radar that is able to penetrate clouds and gather images of military targets in <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. Lacrosse is expected to act as the radar `` eye in the sky'' for the new B-2 stealth bomber.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881202-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-02-88 0103EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Castro-Mexico     12-02 0811</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Castro-Mexico,0836</SECOND>
<HEAD>Castro's Old Haunts Gone, But Nostalgia Remains</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: First available for Friday AMs</NOTE>
<HEAD>With PM-Mexico, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ISAAC A. LEVI</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MEXICO CITY (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Many of the bars, cafes and hotels where <PERSON> Fidel </PERSON> <PERSON> Castro </PERSON> lived and plotted his successful invasion of <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> three decades ago are gone, but a few people still remember the bearded revolutionary _ or think they do. <PERSON> Castro </PERSON> lived here for 18 months as an exile, but where he took his meals and hung out are questions that only he, or maybe his younger brother <PERSON> Raul </PERSON>, can say for certain. <PERSON> Castro </PERSON> returned to <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> on Wednesday for the first time in 32 years, this time for Thursday's inauguration of <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Salinas </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Gortari </PERSON>. It was clear he had fond memories as he strode off his plane to a red-carpet welcome and saluted the crowd jovially. `` This is my second homeland, I'm thrilled to be back,'' said <PERSON> Castro </PERSON>, 61. When he first arrived here on July 8, 1955, <PERSON> Castro </PERSON> was an almost penniless young lawyer. His sister, <PERSON> Lidia </PERSON>, had to sell her refrigerator to raise money for the trip from <LOCATION> Havana </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Fidel </PERSON> and his brother, <PERSON> Raul </PERSON>, had just spent almost two years in a <LOCATION> Cuban </LOCATION> prison for leading an unsuccessful but now legendary attack on the <PERSON> Moncada </PERSON> barracks in a first effort to overthrow dictator <PERSON> Fulgencio </PERSON> <PERSON> Batista </PERSON>. The brothers quickly set to work organizing a network of Cuban exiles into a secret invading force. They lived as inconspicuously as possible, although the <ORGANIZATION> Cuban </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> naval attache did take notice and made several inquiries about them with Mexican authorities. `` They were n't important people and there were a lot of exiles here in those days. So there was no reason for anyone to take much notice of them,'' said a retired military officer who worked in security for a time. He asked to remain anonymous. One of the few who remembers <PERSON> Castro </PERSON> is <PERSON> Filiberto </PERSON> <PERSON> Clemente </PERSON>, the cashier at the Bar Latino, a block from the <ORGANIZATION> Inter-American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Regional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION>. `` They used to sit there,'' <PERSON> Clemente </PERSON>, 52, said in a recent interview, pointing to a corner table. `` I was very young then, a sort of waiter's helper.'' `` <PERSON> Castro </PERSON> _ Fidel, I mean _ used to eat Spanish food. He drank little, cognac sometimes. And also manzanilla, a -LRB- sherry-like -RRB- <LOCATION> Spanish </LOCATION> drink,'' <PERSON> Clemente </PERSON> said. `` He used to live a few blocks from here, at the Hotel Oxford.'' At Hotel Oxford's seedy bar, a white-haired barkeeper in her mid-60s also said she remembered <PERSON> Castro </PERSON>. `` He used to come here often because a lot of Cuban girls were living here at the time. But he did not live here,'' said the woman, who refused to give her name. `` He lived around the corner, at the Hotel Mariscala, which used to be known before as <ORGANIZATION> La </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Casa </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> de </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> la </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Zorra </ORGANIZATION>,'' she added. The Hotel Mariscala is gone. <PERSON> Castro </PERSON> is supposed to have had breakfast often at the Cafe Habana, around the corner from a gym where the conspirators worked out daily. The Habana still stands on the corner of <LOCATION> Morelos </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Avenue </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Bucarelli </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Street </LOCATION>, but the last owner and the old cook both died recently. At the <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Castro </PERSON> used to chat with other Latin American exiles, among them <PERSON> Luis </PERSON> <PERSON> Alberto </PERSON> <PERSON> Monge </PERSON>, the organization's general secretary, and <PERSON> Romulo </PERSON> <PERSON> Betancourt </PERSON> <PERSON> Monge </PERSON> later became as president of <LOCATION> Costa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rica </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Betancourt </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Venezuela </LOCATION>. As his movement grew to about 60 fighters, <PERSON> Castro </PERSON> split them into secret cells of 10 each and moved them to separate safe-houses. Among those <PERSON> Castro </PERSON> enlisted was <PERSON> Alberto </PERSON> <PERSON> Bayo </PERSON>, a Cuban-born officer who fought with the Republican army during the Spanish Civil War. In his memoirs, <PERSON> Bravo </PERSON> wrote the Cubans trained by jogging along <LOCATION> Insurgentes </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Avenue </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>'s main north-south thoroughfare, and by climbing Iztaccihuatl and <PERSON> Popocatepetl </PERSON>, two volcanoes to the southeast. The Cubans moved to a rundown ranch near <LOCATION> Chalco </LOCATION>, a town 21 miles southeast of the capital, and continued training while disguised as workmen. On June 20, 1956, <PERSON> Castro </PERSON> and two of his men were arrested, and on July 2 police raided the ranch and arrested a dozen fighters. They were released with help from former Mexican President <PERSON> Lazaro </PERSON> <PERSON> Cardenas </PERSON>, a leftist sympathizer and a power in Mexican politics. <PERSON> Cardenas </PERSON> was the father of <PERSON> Cuauhtemoc </PERSON> <PERSON> Cardenas </PERSON>, the man <PERSON> Salinas </PERSON> beat in a disputed election July 6. Many Mexican leftists feel <PERSON> Castro </PERSON> is lending support to an illegitimate government by attending the <PERSON> Salinas </PERSON> inauguration. <PERSON> Castro </PERSON> and his men ended up on the <LOCATION> Yucatan </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Peninsula </LOCATION>, 122 miles from <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION>, where they bought a battered 38-foot yacht, the <PERSON> Granma </PERSON>, from an <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> named <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Erickson </PERSON>. The small band of Cubans repaired the boat and set off on a stormy nine-day trip to <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> and into history on Nov. 16, 1956. A 25-month guerrilla war followed, until <PERSON> Batista </PERSON> fled and <PERSON> Castro </PERSON> seized power on Jan. 1, 1959.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881202-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-02-88 0115EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Thousand-DollarTicket     12-02 0348</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Thousand-Dollar Ticket,0357</SECOND>
<HEAD>Suburban Philadelphia Residents Say $1,000 Parking Tickets Are A
Crime</HEAD>
<DATELINE>HORSHAM, Pa. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Ricci </PERSON> was incredulous when a policeman slapped his son with a $ 1,000 parking ticket for illegal parking in front of the family home. `` I flipped,'' <PERSON> Ricci </PERSON>, a retired policeman himself, said recently. But neither he nor others ticketed under a new ordinance are getting sympathy from officials in this suburban <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION> township, where an ordinance passed Sept. 13 specifies the fine _ and court costs of $ 23 _ in an effort to keep narrow cul-de-sacs clear for emergency vehicles. `` If a fire engine can not get in there because of the way cars are parked, there is a danger to the lives of the people,'' said township Solicitor <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Del </PERSON> <PERSON> Ricci </PERSON>. `` When you consider the value of human life, I do n't think $ 1,000 is unreasonable.'' <PERSON> Ricci </PERSON>'s 25-year-old son, <PERSON> Ken </PERSON>, was tightening battery cables under the hood when an officer approached him Nov. 22. Moments later, he was showing his father the citation. The elder <PERSON> Ricci </PERSON>, who retired to <ORGANIZATION> Horsham </ORGANIZATION> from <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION> `` because I wanted peace and tranquility,'' has company in his disbelief. `` We were astounded,'' said <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Cowgill </PERSON>, an insurance agent who was ticketed that same night when he and his wife, <PERSON> Betty </PERSON>, were visiting their grandchildren. `` I thought it was ridiculous, but talk to my wife and you'll hear a different story They were scraping her off the wall.'' At least 11 car owners have received thousand-dollar tickets so far. <PERSON> Del </PERSON> <PERSON> Ricci </PERSON> said judges have discretion to suspend part of the fine. But District Justice <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Price </PERSON>, who expects to be hearing the cases, said the way the ordinance was written requires him to assess the full $ 1,000. The first court hearings are scheduled for the end of December, but Price said he expects the <ORGANIZATION> Township </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>, which meets Tuesday, to change the ordinance and give him some flexibility. `` I hope this comes out as funny as it seems,'' said <PERSON> Cowgill </PERSON>, `` because I'm not going to pay that $ 1,000. You might have to visit me in jail at Christmas.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881202-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-02-88 0116EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Chun     12-02 0702</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Chun,0723</SECOND>
<HEAD>Former President in Exile Chops Wood, Reads, Prays, to Pass Time</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: First available for Friday AMs</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By KELLY TUNNEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SEOUL, South Korea (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Former President <PERSON> Chun </PERSON> <PERSON> Doo-hwan </PERSON> spends his days in exile in an isolated Buddhist temple living the way his ancestors might have _ sleeping on a mat, reading by candlelight, chopping wood for heat and praying. While many Koreans are riveted by televised parliamentary hearings probing corruption and human rights abuses under his presidency, <PERSON> Chun </PERSON> passes his days in the timeless pattern of <ORGANIZATION> Buddhist </ORGANIZATION> monks, sharing a solitude that is centuries old. In the isolated 14th century temple <PERSON> Chun </PERSON> and his wife sought as refuge, there is no television, no telephone, and the toilet is a temporary latrine set up outside his room. `` I made a great mistake,'' <PERSON> Chun </PERSON> was quoted as telling monks at Paektam-sa mountain retreat, five hours drive east of <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION>. `` I hope that future generations learn a lesson and do not repeat the same mistakes.'' The former president left <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION> to go into internal exile Nov. 23 after apologizing to the nation on national television for abuses of power. Dissatisfied dissidents and students have staged mass protests demanding his arrest and return to <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION> for punishment. Rural exile is a traditional form of repentance for disgraced Korean officials. President <PERSON> Roh </PERSON> Tae-woo hopes <PERSON> Chun </PERSON>'s banishment will persuade Koreans to forgive the former general who took power with military backing in 1980. <PERSON> Chun </PERSON> has denied any personal wrongdoing, but took moral responsibility for widespread corruption and abuses under his tough rule. Many Koreans detest the man who ruled with an iron fist for more than seven years. The temple is in a northeast region called Sorak, or `` Snow Hills,'' a tourist idyll of picturesque mountains, forests, waterfalls and deep ravines. There, temples such as Paektam-sa have sheltered many political refugees in <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>'s turbulent 5,000-year history. Makeshift guard posts for <PERSON> Chun </PERSON>'s bodyguards and about 200 security police dot the perimeter of the grounds. Police increased security after several dozen radical students tried to storm the gate. Head monk <PERSON> Kim </PERSON> <PERSON> Do-kong </PERSON> said he did not know the former president was coming until a few hours before his arrival. <PERSON> Kim </PERSON> said he has been told his guests want to avoid contact with outsiders, and with few exceptions they have. <PERSON> Chun </PERSON> and his wife talked with reporters the day they arrived, but since have kept to themselves and have not left the temple grounds. A daughter, her husband and several friends have visited. Korean reporters say visitors usually arrive with faces covered to hide their identity. Meals, cooked by the monks, are vegetarian dishes such as boiled rice, soybean soup, sesame leaves and the spicy, pickled Korean cabbage called kimchi. Reading is by candlelight. <PERSON> Chun </PERSON> reportedly has at least 15 books in his room including some on Buddhism and one called `` Leadership and Politics in <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>.'' He was seen in fur cap and parka chopping wood for fuel. Temperatures in the mountains have been below freezing and heavy snowfalls in January and February usually cut off Paektam-sa. Monks at the temple rise before dawn and say 4:30 a.m. prayers, kneeling before a statue of <PERSON> Buddha </PERSON>. They say <PERSON> Chun </PERSON> and his wife, <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Soon-ja </PERSON>, have joined them. The monks say <PERSON> Chun </PERSON> told them he sleeps `` peacefully, without insomnia'' and appreciates the time to walk in the wooded grounds. Reporters given a tour of the Chun quarters said the bare 71-square-feet room is a traditional temple accommodation for guests with a small mahogany table and Korean floor bedding. Two black leather cushions and a small vinyl dresser were added specially for the Chuns. Three white towels and a set of winter underwear hung from a string on the wall, the <ORGANIZATION> Korea </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> said, and some cosmetics were on the dresser. While <PERSON> Chun </PERSON> stays in rural isolation, a major drive is underway in <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION> to expunge him from the nation's life and even its history books. In the last week, <PERSON> Chun </PERSON> has resigned formally from the ruling <ORGANIZATION> Democatic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> which he founded in 1981. And the <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Education </ORGANIZATION> announced his photographs and some material lauding achievements of his government would be deleted from school textbooks.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881202-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-02-88 0148EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-US-UNObservers     12-02 0607</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-US-UN Observers,600</SECOND>
<HEAD>US Orders American Soldiers Out Of UN Group In Lebanon</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By NORMAN BLACK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Military Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration has ordered all American military officers out of the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> unit that patrols southern <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>, saying the risk to <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> soldiers has risen too high despite their affiliation with the international peacekeeping group. The decision, disclosed Thursday by senior administration officials who asked not to be named, was attributed to a recent internal review that concluded the risk to <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> soldiers had `` simply grown too great.'' `` The situation inside <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> is not improving and wearing a <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> badge does n't mean anything,'' said one source. The administration's decision affects a unit known as the Observer Group Lebanon of the U.N. Truce Supervision Organization, or <ORGANIZATION> UNTSO </ORGANIZATION>. It was not immediately clear Thursday whether any single recent development in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> had prompted the withdrawal order. Two officials insisted not, saying the order stemmed from `` a comprehensive review of the situation that was just completed.'' Nine months ago, a <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> officer assigned to the group was kidnapped. Marine Lt. Col. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Higgins </PERSON>, at the time the senior American officer assigned to the group, disappeared last Feb. 17 while driving on a coastal road between the <LOCATION> Lebanese </LOCATION> city of Tyre and the border town of <LOCATION> Naqoura </LOCATION>. He became the ninth American to be seized as a hostage in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>, all apparently by pro-Iranian Moslem fundamentalists. The administration sources said Thursday the Americans assigned to <ORGANIZATION> Observer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Group </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lebanon </ORGANIZATION> were ordered out over the past week. `` They are no longer in southern <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>,'' said one source. `` They've been withdrawn over the last several days.'' `` It's too risky,'' said another official. `` The risk to our people is now considered too high and we do n't want them traveling inside <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>.'' <ORGANIZATION> UNTSO </ORGANIZATION> has an authorized strength of 299 military personnel, who are drawn from 17 nations. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> each provide 36 men. Of the 36 Americans assigned to <ORGANIZATION> UNTSO </ORGANIZATION>, 16 have normally been assigned to the Observer Group <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>. Neither the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> nor the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> would discuss the matter publicly Thursday. The sources said, however, the decision had been coordinated between the two departments and the White House and that the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> had informed the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> it hoped to resume participation in the Observer Group <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> `` when conditions in southern <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> permit.'' The administration also made clear it would continue to support all other <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> operations in the region, the sources said. <ORGANIZATION> UNTSO </ORGANIZATION> was organized to observe and maintain the cease-fire ordered by the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> in July 1948 following <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s creation and supervise the general armistice agreements between <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> It serves as the focal point for all <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> peacekeeping operations and monitors cease-fire violations along the Israeli borders. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has quietly reduced the number of Americans actually patrolling with the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> unit inside <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> since <PERSON> Higgins </PERSON>' kidnapping But the administration had adamantly denied having any plans to withdraw <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> soldiers from the team entirely, stressing the need to demonstrate <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> support for the peacekeeping efforts. A third source noted that under normal rotation procedures, an <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> would be expected to assume command of Observer Group <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> in January and `` that timetable might have played a role.'' The <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, in response to the continuing civil strife in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> and the fighting between Christians and Moslems, long ago ordered all American civilians out of <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> and trimmed the staff of the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Embassy in <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>. Only between 10 and 30 people now are assigned to the embassy, officials say.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881202-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-02-88 0150EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Bush-List     12-02 0541</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bush-List,540</SECOND>
<HEAD>Defense Appointment Still On Hold</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOAN MOWER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President-elect <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> acknowledges his selection of a <ORGANIZATION> defense </ORGANIZATION> secretary has been moving at a slower pace than expected, saying apparent front-runner <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Tower </PERSON> `` knows that the process takes a while.'' Last week, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s designated chief of staff, <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Sununu </PERSON>, indicated the president-elect would name his defense team this week. But the only appointment <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has made in five days is that of <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON>, who will keep the job he now holds. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was also expected to move swiftly on his secretary of commerce, with most bets on <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Mosbacher </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION> oilman who is close to the vice president. Sources at the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> transition office, speaking on condition they not be named, said <PERSON> Mosbacher </PERSON>'s appointment has been slowed because of the background checks required for him and his numerous businesses. In the case of Tower, the former <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> senator, there has reportedly been infighting in the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> camp over his appointment. Speculation is that <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> wants to get his defense team in place before he names Tower. `` We're trying to be prudent and do the proper work required to back up appointments at all levels,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said Thursday. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was asked about the reports that Tower is a paid consultant to several major defense contractors. `` Any time there seems to be stories that may be hurtful to somebody it concerns me no matter who it is,'' he said. `` Senator Tower's a friend of mine but he knows that the process takes a while to go forward.'' _ In other transition news, the name of former <ORGANIZATION> Wyoming </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Speaker <PERSON> Warren </PERSON> <PERSON> Morton </PERSON> has surfaced as a possible secretary of the interior. Environmentalists object to <PERSON> Morton </PERSON>, whom they consider too pro-development. Another possibility is <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Broadbent </PERSON>, director of the <LOCATION> Las </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vegas </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Nev. </LOCATION>, airport and former commissioner of the bureau of reclamation. Sen. <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Evans </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> has also been mentioned, as has <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Milliken </PERSON>. Some conservatives are also pushing <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Teeter </PERSON>, the co-director of the transition office, for the post at interior. <PERSON> Teeter </PERSON> has been offered the position of deputy White House chief of staff, but he has n't accepted it yet. _ <PERSON> Evans </PERSON> is also mentioned for energy secretary, but former <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION> Rep. <PERSON> Henson </PERSON> <PERSON> Moore </PERSON>'s name is heard more often. _ <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Deland </PERSON>, the regional <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> administrator in <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>, is still the leading candidate. <PERSON> Francis </PERSON> <PERSON> Blake </PERSON>, former agency general counsel, is also a possiblity. _ The <ORGANIZATION> Heritage </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION>, a conservative think tank, is pushing former <ORGANIZATION> Transporation </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> to become the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> ambassasdor. She is the wife of Senate Minority Leader <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>, R-Kan. _ Rep. <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, a failed <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> presidential candidate, is reportedly eyeing the job as secretary of Housing and Urban Development Both <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> attended a testimonial dinner for <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> Thursday night. _ Rep. <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dornan </PERSON>, a hard-line conservative from <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, has let it be known that he'd like to be the new drug czar in the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration. A new name also surfaced for that post, former baseball commissioner <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Ueberroth </PERSON>. <PERSON> Ueberroth </PERSON> was once mentioned for the job at <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION>, but that's apparently <PERSON> Mosbacher </PERSON>'s for the taking.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881202-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-02-88 0151EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-LaRouche     12-02 0551</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-LaRouche,540</SECOND>
<HEAD>Witness Says Rent Payments Did Not Substitute For Royalties</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Trial recessed until Monday; no top planned.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By LARRY MARGASAK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ALEXANDRIA, Va. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Lyndon </PERSON> <PERSON> LaRouche </PERSON>'s rent for two residences was paid by a publishing company that considered the perennial presidential candidate its `` prime asset,'' according to testimony at his tax fraud trial. <PERSON> Marielle </PERSON> <PERSON> Kronberg </PERSON>, former chief operating officer of the publishing house, told jurors Thursday that she made the payments as an expression of gratitude for the firm's best-selling author _ not as a substitute for taxable royalties. The prosecution contends that the rent payments should have been declared as taxable income, along with household and personal services purchased for <PERSON> LaRouche </PERSON> by his organizations over the last decade. The political eccentric is charged with conspiring to defraud the <ORGANIZATION> Internal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Revenue </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> by failing to declare personal financial assistance as income, and by failing to file income tax returns beginning in 1979. In addition, <PERSON> LaRouche </PERSON> and six associates are charged with conspiring to defraud people who lent LaRouche organizations some $ 30 million, by intentionally failing to repay the bulk of the money. Two other witnesses told jurors in <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> on Thursday that <PERSON> LaRouche </PERSON> was waited upon hand-and-foot by employees who cooked for him, his wife and his dogs, bought his clothes, cleaned his house and performed concerts for him. Before the two-week-old trial recessed until Monday, Ms. <PERSON> Kronberg </PERSON> identified a $ 900 rent check for a residence used by <PERSON> LaRouche </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION> in 1980, and a $ 5,100 rent check for an apartment he used in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> the next year. The checks came from the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Benjamin </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Franklin </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Publishing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. Ms. <PERSON> Kronberg </PERSON> said <PERSON> LaRouche </PERSON> was not involved in the company's operation. The indictment identifies the firm as a company established `` ostensibly for the purpose of publishing the work of LaRouche'' and members of his political movement. Asked by Assistant <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Attorney <PERSON> Kent </PERSON> <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> why she made the rent payments, Ms. <PERSON> Kronberg </PERSON> said, `` Because he was our principal author and in that sense our prime asset.'' `` I did n't think it was in lieu of paying'' royalties to <PERSON> LaRouche </PERSON>, she testified, adding that many others also used the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> apartment. Ms. <PERSON> Kronberg </PERSON> said the publishing firm did write checks to <PERSON> LaRouche </PERSON> totaling $ 6,000 for royalty payments, but said she learned they were never cashed. The indictment says <PERSON> LaRouche </PERSON> signed a 1980 federal tax return showing $ 7,963 in taxable income, including the $ 6,000 in uncashed royalty checks. But the return was never filed. Another witness, <PERSON> Pam </PERSON> <PERSON> Cowdery </PERSON>, testified that she played the violin and sang at LaRouche's <LOCATION> Leesburg </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, estate when he and his wife `` just wanted to hear some music.'' The former employee of a LaRouche graphic company also said she cooked for the LaRouches, helped clean the house and even prepared `` very special meals'' of boned chicken breasts for the couple's dogs <PERSON> LaRouche </PERSON>'s security chief, <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Magraw </PERSON>, testified that <PERSON> LaRouche </PERSON> carried no money, and said he would buy suits, underwear, tobacco and even haircuts for his balding boss from a `` security'' fund. <PERSON> Magraw </PERSON> testified under a grant of limited immunity from prosecution. On trial with <PERSON> LaRouche </PERSON> are his chief fund-raiser <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Wertz </PERSON>; his legal adviser, <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Spannaus </PERSON>; and four fund-raisers: <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Billington </PERSON>, <PERSON> Dennis </PERSON> <PERSON> Small </PERSON>, <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Greenberg </PERSON> and <PERSON> Joyce </PERSON> <PERSON> Rubinstein </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881202-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-02-88 0158EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Fauntroy-Savage     12-02 0469</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Fauntroy-Savage,470</SECOND>
<HEAD>Illinois Candidate Says D.C. Job was Stuffing Envelopes</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RICHARD KEIL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A congressman's son who was running for office in <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> while on the payroll of the <LOCATION> District </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION>'s delegate to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> says his House job consisted of little more than stuffing envelopes on a part-time basis <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Savage </PERSON>'s job came under scrutiny after The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> reported Tuesday that he claimed residency in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> and was running for an <ORGANIZATION> Illinois </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> seat while on the payroll of Del. <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> Fauntroy </PERSON>, the district's non-voting delegate to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. Savage, son of Rep. <PERSON> Gus </PERSON> <PERSON> Savage </PERSON>, D-Ill., earned $ 21,398 while on <PERSON> Fauntroy </PERSON>'s payroll between September 1987 and June 1988 In order to run for state representative in <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION>, he had filed a sworn statement declaring that he had lived continuously for two years in the district he sought to represent. House rules, meanwhile, say employees may work only in the member's office or district _ in <PERSON> Fauntroy </PERSON>'s case, the nation's capital When the issue was raised, <PERSON> Fauntroy </PERSON> said <PERSON> Savage </PERSON> worked diligently on behalf of a bill that would have granted statehood to the district. But on Thursday, <PERSON> Savage </PERSON> told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> that he did no work on statehood, and only showed up for work on a part-time basis. `` We did n't call out much -LRB- on statehood issues -RRB-,'' <PERSON> Savage </PERSON> told the <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION>. He said he spent most of his time at work `` putting packages -LRB- of statehood material -RRB- together and getting them out.'' The rest of the time, <PERSON> Savage </PERSON> said, he spent `` working around the Hill,'' occasionally attending a hearing or dropping by the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION> offices. <PERSON> Fauntroy </PERSON> was not immediately available to comment on the apparent contradiction between his and <PERSON> Savage </PERSON>'s assessment of <PERSON> Savage </PERSON>'s job duties. The latest disagreement followed statements by <PERSON> Savage </PERSON> that he had lobbied congressmen on the statehood effort; <PERSON> Fauntroy </PERSON> had said <PERSON> Savage </PERSON> had been working with grassroots organizers. <PERSON> Fauntroy </PERSON> also said <PERSON> Savage </PERSON> used <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> offices and phones to do his lobbying work, but <LOCATION> Capitol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION> staffers said Thursday that <PERSON> Savage </PERSON> did not use their offices. City officials active in the statehood movement said they had never met or heard of him. <ORGANIZATION> D.C. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Clarke </PERSON> and council members <PERSON> Hilda </PERSON> <PERSON> Mason </PERSON> and <PERSON> Betty </PERSON> <PERSON> Ann </PERSON> <PERSON> Kane </PERSON>, all three of whom are active on statehood issues, said they did not remember meeting Savage. Others have placed Savage in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> at the time he was on <PERSON> Fauntroy </PERSON>'s payroll and living in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. House rules require employees to regularly report to work in the member's <LOCATION> Capitol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION> or district offices. <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> election laws require candidates to live continuously for two years in the district they intend to represent. <PERSON> Savage </PERSON> signed an affidavit three months after he went to work for <PERSON> Fauntroy </PERSON> verifying his residency in <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881202-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-02-88 0208EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-NursingHomes-Standards     12-02 0769</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nursing Homes-Standards,850</SECOND>
<HEAD>With PM-Nursing Homes</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the 32 `` selected performance indicators'' included in the <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Care </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Financing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>'s national nursing home scorecard and the percentage of nursing homes not meeting the requirements 1. The facility ensures that its written procedures regarding the rights and responsibilities of residents are followed: 2.1 percent. 2. The facility uses a system that assures full and complete accounting of residents' personal funds. An accounting report is made to each resident in a skilled nursing facility every three months: 5.5 percent. 3. Each resident is free from mental and physical abuse: 1.8 percent. 4. Drugs to control behavior and physical restraints are only used when authorized by a physician in writing for a specified period of time or in emergencies: 8.5 percent. 5. Each resident is given privacy during treatment and care of personal needs: 17.1 percent. 6. Each resident is allowed to communicate, associate and meet privately with individuals of his or her choice unless this infringes upon the rights of another resident: 0.4 percent. 7. Each resident is allowed to retain and use his or her personal possessions and clothing as space permits: 2.2 percent. 8. Except in a medical emergency, a resident is not transferred or discharged, nor is treatment changed radically, without consultation with the resident or, if the resident is incompetent, without prior notification of next of kin or sponsor: 0.3 percent. 9. The facility ensures that the health care of each resident is under the continuing supervision of a physician: 1.5 percent. 10. Emergency services from a physician are available and provided to each resident who requires emergency care: 0.5 percent. 11. Nursing services are provided at all times to meet the needs of residents: 5.4 percent. 12. Each resident receives daily personal hygiene as needed to assure cleanliness, good skin care, good grooming and oral hygiene, taking into account individual preferences. Residents are encouraged to take care of their own self-care needs: 29.8 percent. 13. Each resident receives care necessary to prevent skin breakdown: 18.3 percent. 14. Each resident with a bed sore receives care necessary to promote the healing of the bed sore, including proper dressing: 11.1 percent. 15. Each resident who has problems with bowel and bladder control is provided with care necessary to encourage self-control, including frequent toileting and opportunities for rehabilitative training: 16 percent. 16. Each resident with a urinary catheter received proper routine care, including periodic evaluation: 17.6 percent. 17. Each resident receives proper care for injections, fluids supplied through tubes, colostomy @ ileostomy, respiratory and tracheotomy care, suctioning and tube feeding: 11.9 percent. 18. Each resident receives rehabilitative nursing care to promote maximum physical functioning to prevent loss of ability to walk or move freely, deformities and paralysis: 21.6 percent. 19. Each resident needing assistance in eating or drinking is provided prompt assistance. Specific self-help devices are available when necessary: 17.6 percent. 20. Drugs are administered according to the written orders of the attending physician: 29 percent. 21. Menus are planned and followed to meet the nutritional needs of each resident in accordance with physicians' orders, and to the extent medically possible, based on the recommended dietary allowances of the <ORGANIZATION> Food </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nutrition </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> the </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sciences </ORGANIZATION>: 14.7 percent. 22. Therapy is provided according to orders of the attending physician in accordance with accepted professional practices by qualified therapists or qualified assistants: 6.2 percent. 23. Services are provided to meet the residents' social and emotional needs by the facility or by referral to an appropriate social agency: 8.6 percent. 24. An ongoing program of meaningful activities is provided, based on identified needs and interests of each resident. It is designed to promote opportunities for engaging in normal pursuits, including religious activities of the resident's choice, if any: 11.6 percent. 25. Appropriate staff develop and implement a written health care plan for each resident according to the instructions of the attending physician: 13.4 percent. 26. Toilet and bath facilities are clean, sanitary, and free of odors: 12.9 percent. 27. All common resident areas are clean, sanitary and free of odors: 11 percent. 28. All essential mechanical and electrical equipment is maintained in safe operating condition: 14.9 percent. 29. Resident care equipment is clean and maintained in safe operating condition: 14.9 percent. 30. Isolation techniques to prevent the spread of infection are followed by all personnel: 24.7 percent. 31. The facility has available at all times a quantity of linen essential for proper care and comfort of residents: 7.4 percent. 32. Food is stored, refrigerated, prepared, distributed, and served under sanitary conditions: 42.8 percent.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881202-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-02-88 0211EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-NursingHomes-Profile     12-02 0168</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nursing Homes-Profile,180</SECOND>
<HEAD>With PM-Nursing Homes</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are 13 `` selected resident characteristics'' included in the <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Care </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Financing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>'s national report on nursing homes. 1. Bathing. Residents requiring some or total assistance in bathing: 81.5 percent. 2. Dressing. Residents requiring some or total assistance in dressing: 83.2 percent. 3. Toileting. Residents requiring some or total assistance in toileting: 73.8 percent. 4. Transferring. Residents requiring some or total assistance moving from bed to chair or to tub or toilet: 77.2 percent. 5. Continence. Residents with catheters or partial or total loss of bowel or bladder control: 68.2 percent. 6. Continence. Residents on individually written bowel and bladder retraining program: 4.6 percent. 7. Eating. Residents receiving tube feedings or requiring assistance with eating: 37.7 percent. 8. Completely bedfast residents: 3.4 percent. 9. Residents confined to chairs: 50.8 percent. 10. Residents requiring restraints: 41.3 percent. 11. Confused or disoriented residents: 58.4 percent. 12. Residents with bed sores: 7.1 percent. 13. Residents receiving special skin care: 31.2 percent.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881202-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-02-88 0222EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-WashingtoninBrief     12-02 0600</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Washington in Brief,620</SECOND>
<HEAD>Inauguration Committee Plans Five Days of Events</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A ceremony at the Lincoln Memorial on Jan. 18 will open five days of official events for President-elect <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s inaugural, the organizing group says. The inauguration itself will take place Jan. 20 at the Capitol. It will be followed by the traditional inaugural parade down <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Avenue </LOCATION> and inaugural balls at eight locations. Two days before the inauguration, there will be an <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> presidential pageant and an inaugural dinner, the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bicentennial </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Presidential </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inauguration </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> said Thursday. On Jan. 19, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s wife, <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON>, will be saluted, and a reception will be held for Vice President-elect <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>. The inaugural gala will take place that night. Jan. 21 will feature a children's inaugural festival titled, `` George-to-George _ Two Hundred Years.'' There also will be a presidential pageant and a celebration for young Americans. Sunday, Jan. 22, the final day of the official events, will be a national day of prayer and thanksgiving with events at the <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> Cathedral.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>___</HEAD>
<HEAD>Pentagon Breaks Link Between Computer Systems After `Hacker'</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Invades
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> severed the electronic links between two of its computer networks this week after an unknown `` hacker'' gained entry to a contractor's computer, the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> said. Neither of the computer networks involved handled classified data or information, but the links between the two were `` temporarily severed ... in order to provide a barrier to protect users,'' the department said Thursday. The connections between the Arpanet network, which links academic and corporate computer centers, and the so-called Milnet system, which links thousands of military computers, were severed Monday. The Pentagon said the connection was broken after `` an unidentified hacker penetrated a VAX computer belonging to a defense contractor on the night of Nov. 27-28, 1988.'' `` The hacker used a weakness in the end user's computer software. The ` fix' for this problem has been developed by the vendor and is available electronically to users of the software,'' the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> said. The <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> did not identify the contractor, but a spokeswoman for the <ORGANIZATION> Mitre </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Bedford </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mass. </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Marcia </PERSON> <PERSON> Cohen </PERSON>, said one of the company's computers had been entered. Arpanet is the same unclassified computer network that was crippled last month when someone slipped a `` virus'' into the system _ an incident that is being investigated by a federal grand jury in <LOCATION> Syracuse </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>___</HEAD>
<HEAD>More than 40 Jewish Dissidents Notified Barrier To Emigration Being</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Removed
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 At least 42 Jews have been told by Soviet authorities that the barrier to their emigration is being removed, according to the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conference </ORGANIZATION> on Soviet Jewry. The Jews had previously been denied exit permits on grounds of state secrecy. Assistant Secretary of State <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Shifter </PERSON> said Thursday he heard of the barrier being lifted from Jewish sources. He said he had no official confirmation from <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>. The move followed the apparent ending of Soviet jamming of American-financed Russian language broadcasts. Together, the two steps represent a major improvement in human rights by Soviet President <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> before his meeting next week with President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and President-elect <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. Among the `` refuseniks'' informed of the change was <PERSON> Yuli </PERSON> <PERSON> Kosharovsky </PERSON>, who has been waiting for more than 17 years for permission to go to <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>. He had been denied a visa for classified work he performed as an electronics engineer until 1968. The Jewish group announced, meanwhile, that 2,334 Soviet Jews had been granted exit permits in November _ the largest monthly total this year. Permits this year total 15,640, making the exodus the biggest since 1980.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881202-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-02-88 0150EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i BC-Japan-Stocks     12-02 0025</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Japan-Stocks,0025</SECOND>
<HEAD>Nikkei Down</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Nikkei Stock Average closed at 29,532.25 points, down 9.21 points, on the <ORGANIZATION> Tokyo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Stock </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Exchange </ORGANIZATION> Friday.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881202-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-02-88 0231EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Peru-Crash     12-02 0523</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Peru-Crash,0542</SECOND>
<HEAD>Train Crash Kills Wives of Jersey City Mayor, Peruvian Mayor</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CUZCO, Peru (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Police said they were investigating whether steel rods found near railway tracks caused a train crash that killed the wives of the <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Cuzco </LOCATION> mayors and injured the politicians. A railway car carrying the couples careened off tracks in the Andes and tumbled down a ravine Thursday. Officials of the state railroad company <ORGANIZATION> Enafer </ORGANIZATION> and police said steel rods were found near the derailment site. Police said they were looking into reports someone might have planted the rods to cause an accident during a daylong nationwide strike Thursday. They said the likely target was a passenger train that was behind the tourist train, which was making an unscheduled trip. Mayor <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON> <PERSON> Cucci </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.J. </LOCATION>, and Mayor <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Chacon </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Cuzco </LOCATION>, their wives and six other people were on an outing to the <LOCATION> Inca </LOCATION> citadel of Machu Picchu when the crash occurred Thursday, officials said. Authorities said <PERSON> Anna </PERSON> <PERSON> Cucci </PERSON>, about 60, and <PERSON> Doris </PERSON> <PERSON> Chacon </PERSON>, 58, died in the 3:30 p.m. crash. The suvivors were treated at <LOCATION> Cuzco </LOCATION>'s Regional Hospital. Dr. <PERSON> Luis </PERSON> <PERSON> Garcia </PERSON>, hospital director, said <PERSON> Cucci </PERSON>, 66, was suffering from multiple bruises but was in stable condition and appeared to be out of danger. <PERSON> Garcia </PERSON> said <PERSON> Chacon </PERSON> was in serious condition with multiple fractures and internal bleeding. <PERSON> Chacon </PERSON> underwent surgery late Thursday, the hospital said. Jersey City Councilman <PERSON> Jaime </PERSON> <PERSON> Vasquez </PERSON>, who was also on board, told reporters he suffered minor injuries. The Cuccis arrived in <LOCATION> Cuzco </LOCATION> on Thursday morning and planned to participate in a sister city celebration honoring <LOCATION> Jersy </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Cuzco </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Vasquez </PERSON> said. Officials said the conditions of the five other people in the car were not immediately available, but they were not believed to have been seriously injured. The vehicle, a modified version of an 11-passenger bus outfitted for rail travel, crashed about six miles outside <LOCATION> Cuzco </LOCATION>, a tourist area 355 miles southeast of <LOCATION> Lima </LOCATION>, police said. The rail car had left <LOCATION> Cuzco </LOCATION> about 2:45 p.m. on a specially scheduled trip to <LOCATION> Machu </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Picchu </LOCATION>, 60 miles northwest of <LOCATION> Cuzco </LOCATION>. Police said the vehicle derailed and traveled about 30 feet along the tracks before going over a hill and tumbling 250 feet down a ravine. Some passengers apparently were able to escape before the car began rolling. <PERSON> Garcia </PERSON> said preliminary indications were that the women died of skull fractures. They said the likely target of possible sabotage was a passenger train that uses the same tracks to carry residents between <LOCATION> Cuzco </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Quillabamba </LOCATION>, 20 miles beyond <LOCATION> Machu </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Picchu </LOCATION>. That passenger train left the <LOCATION> Cuzco </LOCATION> station shortly after the tourist car, officials said. In an effort to paralyze business activity, strikers Thursday blocked a mountain road between the cities with logs and rocks, officials said, adding possible saboteurs might have wanted to completely severe transportation by derailing the passenger train. <PERSON> Machu </PERSON> <PERSON> Picchu </PERSON> is a citadel hidden on a jungle mountaintop. In June 1986, a bomb exploded on a train headed for Machu Picchu. Eight people, including an American, were killed. Guerrillas of the Maoist Shining Path were suspected of planting the bomb.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881202-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-02-88 0221EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-Universal-Shots 3rdLd-Writethru a0408 12-02 0290</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Universal-Shots, 3rd Ld-Writethru, a0408,0295</SECOND>
<HEAD>URGENT</HEAD>
<HEAD>Suspect In Studio Gunbattle Wanted in Albuquerque Shopping Mall
Slayings</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: UPDATES throughout with man in Universal shootings is suspect
in bagel shootings in Albuquerque, i.d. of shot guards, other
details; no pickup.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>UNIVERSAL CITY, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A man wanted in a <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> rampage that claimed three lives was arrested Thursday night after a security guard at <ORGANIZATION> Universal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Studios </ORGANIZATION> was shot to death and another was wounded, authorities said. <PERSON> Nathan </PERSON> <PERSON> Nick </PERSON> <PERSON> Trupp </PERSON>, 42, the subject of a nationwide manhunt following the shooting deaths Tuesday at a bagel shop in an <LOCATION> Albuquerque </LOCATION> shopping mall, was shot and wounded Thursday by <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> sheriff's deputies, said Deputy <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> Hom </PERSON>. The gunman walked up to a guard shack at an employees entrance to <ORGANIZATION> Universal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Studios </ORGANIZATION> shortly before 6 p.m. and opened fire, officials said. Minutes later, deputies and a third guard spotted a man they believed to be the gunman about a block away and `` engaged in a gunbattle,'' wounding the man, said <PERSON> Van </PERSON> <PERSON> Mosley </PERSON>, a sheriff's spokesman at the scene What provoked the shooting was not immediately known. `` We have absolutely no clues,'' said <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Slusser </PERSON>, general manager of the studio, a popular tourist attraction. <PERSON> Trupp </PERSON> was in critical condition at <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Joseph </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in nearby <LOCATION> Burbank </LOCATION> after surgery for gunshot wounds to his chest and arm, said nursing supervisor <PERSON> Eric </PERSON> <PERSON> Chew </PERSON>. Home identified the dead guard as <PERSON> Jason </PERSON> <PERSON> Beeks </PERSON>, 27, of <LOCATION> La </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Crescenta </LOCATION>. The wounded guard, 20-year-old <PERSON> Armando </PERSON> <PERSON> Torres </PERSON>, was in critical condition with a gunshot wound to the head at <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Joseph </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Chew </PERSON> said. Universal Studios, 10 miles northwest of downtown <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>, is home to the <ORGANIZATION> Universal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Studios </ORGANIZATION> amusement park, and movie and television studios and offices.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881202-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-02-88 0222EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Mexico Bjt   12-02 0713</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Mexico, Bjt,0735</SECOND>
<HEAD>New Mexican President Takes Office As Protests Flare In Congress,
Streets</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto MO1</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CHRIS ANGELO</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MEXICO CITY (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Inaugural day protests in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and in the streets of this restive capital marred the beginning of President <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Salinas </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Gortari </PERSON>'s six-year term. <PERSON> Salinas </PERSON>, promising political and economic reforms, said Thursday in his inaugural speech to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> that `` my administration will respond to the citizens' demand for respect for -LRB- political -RRB- plurality and effective participation.'' <PERSON> Salinas </PERSON>' July 6 presidential victory, the narrowest in the 59-year history of the governing <ORGANIZATION> Institutional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Revolutionary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, or <ORGANIZATION> PRI </ORGANIZATION>, has been clouded by allegations the election was fraught with fraud and vote-tampering. Defying heavy deployment of army troops, police and plainclothes security guards, thousands who claim the <ORGANIZATION> PRI </ORGANIZATION> deprived <PERSON> Cuauhtemoc </PERSON> <PERSON> Cardenas </PERSON> of victory in the election held scattered demonstrations. Unlike previous demonstrations, many protesters carried sharpened sticks. Police used tear gas to break up a demonstration by 1,500 people in Zocalo Plaza outside the National Palace, where <PERSON> Salinas </PERSON> went after the inauguration. About 150 people, including some police and soldiers, were injured but none were hospitalized, <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION> paramedic <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Ramirez </PERSON> said. As <PERSON> Salinas </PERSON> spoke, a crowd of several thousand threw rocks at police outside the Legislative Palace. Several demonstrators and policemen were reported injured. One police department employee said there were `` many'' arrests, but police spokesmen refused to give figures. A crowd of 6,000 marched about 1 -LCB- miles cheering <PERSON> Cardenas </PERSON>, who defeated <PERSON> Salinas </PERSON> in populous <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> but finished second nationally to the president. According to the official tally, <PERSON> Salinas </PERSON> won just over 50 percent of the vote, with <PERSON> Cardenas </PERSON> getting 31 percent, and <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Clouthier </PERSON> of the conservative <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Action </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> a distant third with 17 percent. `` It falls to us to create the conditions so that this government ... leaves the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Palace </ORGANIZATION> and that it is occupied by the people,'' <PERSON> Cardenas </PERSON> told the crowd. <PERSON> Cardenas </PERSON> supporters occupied at least 19 city halls in his home state of <LOCATION> Michoacan </LOCATION> last week to demand the ouster of the <LOCATION> Michoacan </LOCATION> governor and staged protests outside 20 others. Protesters outside the <ORGANIZATION> Legislative </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Palace </ORGANIZATION> said police removed 200 to 300 people early Thursday and left them outside city limits. <PERSON> Alberta </PERSON> <PERSON> Torres </PERSON> <PERSON> Sanchez </PERSON>, 75, claimed police put her on a bus to <LOCATION> Puebla </LOCATION>, 65 miles southeast of the capital. She said she took another bus back to rejoin demonstrators. Just before <PERSON> Salinas </PERSON>, 40, was sworn in, about 140 congressmen from the four parties making up <ORGANIZATION> Cardenas </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ' </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION> walked out. `` Only the vote can legitimize him!'' shouted one congressman as the group filed out. The congressional delegation of the conservative <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Action </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, which has not recognized <PERSON> Salinas </PERSON>' victory but says he can redeem himself by performing well in office, remained through the speech. At the end of his speech, however, the delegation of 40 raised signs telling <PERSON> Salinas </PERSON> to `` show with actions your pledge to democracy.'' Under an agreement with the <ORGANIZATION> PRI </ORGANIZATION>, leaders of the two opposition blocs were allowed to make televised pre-inaugural speeches critical of <PERSON> Salinas </PERSON>' election in return for a promise not to interrupt the ceremony. `` I take office in a complex hour: between collective hope and the weight of accumulated sacrifices; between the need for building for the future and the pressure for immediate accomplishments,'' <PERSON> Salinas </PERSON> said. `` It is a singular moment in our history, heavy with risks but rich in opportunity.'' Six years of austerity under a program <PERSON> Salinas </PERSON> designed as budget secretary under <ORGANIZATION> Miguel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> de </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> la </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Madrid </ORGANIZATION> cut workers' buying power by more than half. It combined with years of slowly mounting discontent with government corruption and elections where the result was a foregone conclusion _ victory for the <ORGANIZATION> PRI </ORGANIZATION>. To recover the economic initiative, <PERSON> Salinas </PERSON> said he had given orders to <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Pedro </PERSON> <PERSON> Aspe </PERSON> to begin negotiating new terms with international banks on its $ 102 billion foreign debt, second highest in the developing world behind <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Secretary of State <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON>, who represented the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, applauded <PERSON> Salinas </PERSON>' address. `` Here was a man who loved his country with a passion and has a clear understanding of the opportunities and the problems ahead and is ready to roll up his sleeves and go to work,'' <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> said after meeting with <PERSON> Salinas </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881202-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-02-88 0249EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     12-02 0862</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0895</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names In The News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhotos NY14, NY95</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actress <PERSON> Lisa </PERSON> <PERSON> Bonet </PERSON>, who stars as the college-age daughter on `` The Cosby Show,'' has given birth to a healthy baby girl, says a spokesman for her husband, musician <PERSON> Lenny </PERSON> <PERSON> Kravitz </PERSON>. `` All are well and are resting comfortably at home,'' publicist <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> said Thursday. <PERSON> Zoe </PERSON> <PERSON> Kravitz </PERSON>, weighing 7 pounds, 2 ounces, was delivered at 2 a.m. Thursday at the couple's canal-front home in suburban <LOCATION> Venice </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> said. Miss <PERSON> Bonet </PERSON> rose to fame as <PERSON> Denise </PERSON> <PERSON> Huxtable </PERSON> on <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s family-oriented `` The Cosby Show. She gained notoriety by posing semi-nude for `` Rolling Stone'' and `` Interview'' magazines, and for a torrid love scene in the film `` Angel Heart.'' She married <PERSON> Kravitz </PERSON>, a singer and musician also known as <PERSON> Romeo </PERSON> <PERSON> Blue </PERSON>, in <LOCATION> Las </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vegas </LOCATION> in November 1987.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Landon </PERSON> took his final trip on `` Highway to Heaven'' as the <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> show completed its last day of filming after five seasons. The film crew on the show has been with <PERSON> Landon </PERSON> for nearly 30 years. The crew, which began working with him on `` Bonanza'' in 1959, also worked with him on `` Little House on the Prairie'' and `` Father <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON>.'' `` It's sad after every show ends,'' <PERSON> Landon </PERSON> said Thursday. `` But this is like another hiatus. I'm sure we'll all be back together again soon. We're the best unit in town.'' <PERSON> Landon </PERSON> stars in `` Highway to Heaven'' as an angel whose good works are assisted by an ex-policeman played by <PERSON> Victor </PERSON> <PERSON> French </PERSON>. The show's 100th episode will be telecast Dec. 7. The final episode will be aired early next year.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President-elect <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s wife, <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON>, has put the crowning touch on the national Christmas tree for the eighth year in a row. Mrs. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> ascended 35 feet aboard a bumpy hydraulic boom Thursday and placed the ornament atop the <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION> blue spruce just beyond the back fence of the White House. `` It's the only thing I've done more than anyone else,'' she told a guest in a reception line afterwards. `` I love it.'' The vice president's wife becomes the first lady next year. Does that mean <PERSON> Marilyn </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>, wife of Vice President-elect <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>, will get the job? `` I would be offended if someone else did it,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> told another guest Thursday. President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> will light the tree for his last time Dec. 15.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>AUGUSTA, Ga. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Only 41 tickets have been sold for the wrestle-and-rock music extravaganza that soul singer <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> was required to produce as part of his probation, but the show will go on Sunday, organizers say. The Augusta-Richmond Civic Center can hold up to 7,500 people for an event like `` Wrestle-Rock'88.'' But by 5 p.m. Thursday only 41 of the $ 10 tickets, which went on sale Nov. 22, had been sold, said the center's general manager, <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Rogers </PERSON>. `` It's probably the worst advance ticket sales I've seen since I've been in <LOCATION> Augusta </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Rogers </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>'s lawyer, <PERSON> Buddy </PERSON> <PERSON> Dallas </PERSON>, said the show featuring his client would go on despite the poor sales. Proceeds will go to the <LOCATION> Aiken </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> S.C. </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Fraternal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Order </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION>, which accepted the show to fulfill a condition of <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>'s probation. Money will also go to Helping Hands, a shelter for abused children, and the <ORGANIZATION> Leukemia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> was placed on probation last summer and given a suspended sentence of 2 -LCB- years after he pleaded guilty to carrying a pistol, resisting arrest and possession of PCP in a May 18 incident near his <LOCATION> Beech </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> S.C. </LOCATION>, home.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The outlook for <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> fans went from bad to better when concerts postponed because of the Gloved One's swollen vocal cords were rescheduled for January Officials said Thursday that the <ORGANIZATION> Los </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Angeles </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sports </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Arena </ORGANIZATION> also would offer a refund on the $ 27.50 tickets through Jan. 10. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> had to postpone the Nov. 14-22 shows because of the throat ailment he came down with while performing in <LOCATION> Irvine </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Gregory </PERSON> <PERSON> Peck </PERSON> says he learned early in life that he was the key to his own success. `` I was reticent and I had no self-confidence,'' said <PERSON> Peck </PERSON>, 72. `` Little by little, though, I was learning to be on my own. I realized that if I did n't make things happen myself, no one else was going to.'' In the Dec. 4 issue of Parade magazine, <PERSON> Peck </PERSON> recalls how he became a truck driver at age 18, then quit to attend <ORGANIZATION> San </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Diego </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION>, where he earned grades good enough to get into the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> California-Berkeley </ORGANIZATION>. `` From time to time I used to stop in at the Little Theatre. One day, out of the blue, a fellow came over and said he needed a tall actor and did I want to give it a try? I was terrible at first _ awkward and stiff and self-conscious. `` In one way, I hated it, and it was agonizing. But in another and more important way, I loved it. ... -LRB- Acting -RRB- gave me the chance to make friends with people, something that would make up for having been a loner for so long.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881202-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-02-88 0257EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Britain-Shooting     12-02 0482</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Britain-Shooting,0495</SECOND>
<HEAD>Police Shoot And Wound Gunman In Central London, Free Hostage</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Police shot and wounded a gunman in the busy theater district today after he grabbed a bystander and held him hostage 2 -LCB- hours, dragging him through streets lined with crowded restaurants and pubs, <LOCATION> Scotland </LOCATION> Yard said. The hostage, who was seized in a scuffle after the gunman apparently tried to mug someone else, was unharmed, police said. They said the gunman was taken to a hospital with a chest wound. His condition was not immediately known. More than 200 police, many carrying rifles, rushed to the <LOCATION> Trafalgar </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Square </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Martin </LOCATION>'s lane area late Thursday where crowds of theatergoers were either heading home or dining in restaurants. <PERSON> Jane </PERSON> <PERSON> Chandler </PERSON>, a radio producer with the <ORGANIZATION> British </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Broadcasting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, said she was in a pub and ran to a room upstairs to telephone her office. She found herself sharing the room with two police marksmen. `` I looked out of the window and I could see this skinhead holding a dark-haired man around the neck and shoving a gun near his head. The police were calling out: ` Stop it, give it up.' `` The hostage was in a complete daze and the gunman kept dragging him up and down the street from the Strand to <LOCATION> Chandos </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Place </LOCATION> and into <LOCATION> Maiden </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lane </LOCATION> ... `` There were still people from the restaurants wandering about and the police were trying to clear them but they were like helpless chickens because they did n't know where he was going to go next. `` -LRB- Later -RRB- they -LRB- the police -RRB- had the man cornered in the alley and I heard over the police radio an order to engage and saying they should open fire if they had a clear shot. Then I heard the bang and it was all over.'' Neither the gunman nor the hostage was identified. Police trailed the gunman and his hostage through side roads lined with theaters and restaurants as other officers sealed the area, ordering pedestrians and traffic off the streets. An officer with a bullhorn appealed to the gunman to surrender and release his hostage, a <LOCATION> Scotland </LOCATION> Yard statement said. The gunman ignored the plea so the marksman shot him, the statement said. Police said the incident began at about 10.30 p.m. Thursday and ended just after 1 a.m. on <LOCATION> Maiden </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lane </LOCATION>, a narrow road near <LOCATION> Trafalgar </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Square </LOCATION> in central <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Brian </PERSON> <PERSON> Last </PERSON>, manager of Rules restaurant on <LOCATION> Maiden </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lane </LOCATION>, said armed police told the 50 diners and staff there to stay inside with the doors locked and keep away from the windows. Free-lance journalist <PERSON> Edmond </PERSON> <PERSON> Hall </PERSON>, said, `` We could see a man ... holding what looked like a small caliber revolver at a man lying between his legs.'' The British domestic news agency <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> said the gunman was thought to have tried to fire the gun several times but that it misfired each time.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881202-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-02-88 0308EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-RJRNabisco-Billions     12-02 0165</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-RJR Nabisco-Billions,0169</SECOND>
<HEAD>$24 Billion Buys A Lot Of Oreos, Triscuits, Del Monte Peaches</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-RJR Nabisco-Reax, Bjt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Rivers of sliced peaches, mountains of cookies and forests of filter-tipped cigarettes could be bought with the more than $ 24 billion being spent to acquire <ORGANIZATION> RJR </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nabisco </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc </ORGANIZATION>. If all the money were spent on Oreo cookies, they would overflow every grain elevator in <LOCATION> Toledo </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Buffalo </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>; and <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Worth </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>. The $ 24 billion would buy enough <ORGANIZATION> Del </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Monte </ORGANIZATION> sliced peaches to keep <LOCATION> Niagara </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Falls </LOCATION> going at full flow for more than half an hour. If every dime went into Winston cigarettes, there would be enough so <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Ross </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>, the chief executive of <ORGANIZATION> RJR </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nabisco </ORGANIZATION> who lost the bidding, could chain-smoke for 70,000 centuries. Viewed another way, the $ 22 billion in debt that <ORGANIZATION> RJR </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nabisco </ORGANIZATION> will carry under its new ownership is greater than the combined foreign debts of <LOCATION> Burma </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> Congo </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Cyprus </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mali </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Nepal </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Niger </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Oman </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881202-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-02-88 0433EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Mexico-Scene     12-02 0281</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Mexico-Scene,0290</SECOND>
<HEAD>Shouts Of Angry Demonstrators Drown Out Salinas' Inaugural
Supporters</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Mexico, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ANITA SNOW</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MEXICO CITY (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Shouts from thousands of angry demonstrators drowned out the cheers of the few supporters who greeted <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Salinas </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Gortari </PERSON> on his presidential inauguration. Even uniformed police and army soldiers outnumbered the handful of citizens who showed up Thursday along the inaugural parade route to welcome President <PERSON> Salinas </PERSON>. The protesters claim <PERSON> Salinas </PERSON>, of the governing <ORGANIZATION> Institutional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Revolutionary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, stole the presidency in a July 6 fraud-tainted election from <PERSON> Cuauhtemoc </PERSON> <PERSON> Cardenas </PERSON>, leader of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION>, an organization of four leftist parties. `` We know that in this country an electoral fraud was committed and today an illegitimate presidency has been consummated,'' <PERSON> Cardenas </PERSON> told 6,000 people who gathered for the afternoon march, the largest protest of the day. <PERSON> Cardenas </PERSON> urged his supporters to avoid violence and organize to work for fair elections and nationwide democracy. Before dawn, authorities removed protesters from the plaza in front of the Legislative Palace, site of the inauguration, and bussed 200 to 300 of them out of the city, demonstrators said. Most were back within hours for a demonstration at the <LOCATION> Zocalo </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>'s central plaza, where police used tear gas to disperse them again. A police blockade around the legislative chamber failed to prevent angry protesters from throwing rocks at the building during the ceremony. Protesters then gathered at Independence Monument for what was planned as a silent protest, but was marked by drumbeats, catcalls at security forces and shouts of `` Death to <PERSON> Salinas </PERSON>!'' Many marchers carried sticks. Others wore black bows to mourn what they called `` the death of democracy.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881202-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-02-88 0459EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Lebanon 1stLd-Writethru a0448 12-02 0291</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lebanon, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0448,0298</SECOND>
<HEAD>Explosion Rocks Syrian-Policed West Beirut, At Least Two Injured</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: LEADS throughout with details, quotes. No pickup.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>BEIRUT, Lebanon (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An explosion rocked a Syrian-policed west <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> neighborhood today during the morning rush hour. At least two people were wounded, police said. A police spokesman said the 8 a.m. bomb was planted under a car only 50 yards from a Syrian army checkpoint in the <LOCATION> Lower </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mossaitbeh </LOCATION> district. The spokesman, who can not be named in line with standing regulations, said the explosion shattered glass in the neighborhood. A witness said a private car evacuated `` two wounded men from the scene.'' Police could not say if the wounded were Syrian soldiers. Syrian troops, according to the witness, `` fired their automatic rifles in the air to make way for the car carrying the wounded men,'' then sealed off the area. The Moslem-run Voice of the Nation radio station, based in west <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>, said the explosion was caused by `` a small bomb planted under a car parked in an empty lot near the Syrian checkpoint.'' <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION>, the main powerbroker in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>, maintains about 40,000 troops in eastern and northern provinces as well as west and south <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>. The explosion may have been part of a campaign to discredit the Syrians as peacekeepers. Scores of such attacks have been reported since the Syrians moved into <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> in 1986 to end militia rule. The blast came after a series of house raids mounted by the Syrians to halt renewed violence between rival Shiite Moslem factions. The pro-Iranian <ORGANIZATION> Hezbollah </ORGANIZATION>, or Party of God, and the Syrian-backed Amal, Arabic for hope, fought for six days late last month. By police count, 40 people were killed and 87 wounded in the confrontation.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881202-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-02-88 0500EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--China-Burgers     12-02 0091</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--China-Burgers,0092</SECOND>
<HEAD>South Korean Company To Build Hamburger Factory In China</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SEOUL, South Korea (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A fast-food company said today it has reached a tentative agreement with the Chinese to build a factory in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> that would produce 18 million hamburgers a year. <ORGANIZATION> Big </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Boy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, a South Korean firm, said the joint venture agreement calls for the factory to be built in <LOCATION> Heilongjiang </LOCATION> province in northeastern <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>. It would be the first South Korean fast-food supplier in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>. Construction is scheduled to start in May, the company said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881202-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-02-88 0458EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-GuthrieTribute Bjt   12-02 0601</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Guthrie Tribute, Bjt,0619</SECOND>
<HEAD>Hometown Pays Homage To Dust Bowl Balladeer Woody Guthrie</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto KO2</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GIL BROYLES</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>OKEMAH, Okla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Woody </PERSON> <PERSON> Guthrie </PERSON>'s songs rang out in a packed theater at a long-delayed tribute to the composer of `` This Land Is Your Land'' in his hometown, where some still maintain the folk-singing great was no folk hero. About 50 schoolchildren and adult accompanists Thursday sang and played fiddle, guitar, banjo, harmonica and piano in <LOCATION> Okemah </LOCATION>'s 450-seat Crystal Theater as the audience whistled and clapped along `` I sat there with chill bumps and with tears,'' said <PERSON> Guthrie </PERSON>'s 65-year-old sister, <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Jo </PERSON> <PERSON> Edgmon </PERSON>, who represented the <PERSON> Guthrie </PERSON> family His singer son, <PERSON> Arlo </PERSON>, did not attend the tribute just a few blocks from the overgrown lot where the <PERSON> Guthrie </PERSON> family's house once stood. Shows honoring the `` Dust Bowl Balladeer,'' who died in 1967, have been held in such grand auditoriums as Carnegie Hall. But Thursday's was the first in <LOCATION> Okemah </LOCATION> because people like city councilman <PERSON> Bart </PERSON> <PERSON> Webb </PERSON> think <PERSON> Guthrie </PERSON> was more of a subversive than a star. <PERSON> Webb </PERSON>, seething over the first of three tribute performances, said he would ask the council Monday to paint over the `` Home of <PERSON> Woody </PERSON> <PERSON> Guthrie </PERSON>'' sign painted on one of the central <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION> town's three water towers facing Interstate 40. The ramshackle house where <PERSON> Guthrie </PERSON>'s family lived before he left <LOCATION> Okemah </LOCATION> at age 17 had been vandalized. Some of the graffiti scrawled on the building called him a communist, a label his family rejects. When the house started falling down, local officials did nothing. Leaders of this community of 3,300 also once opposed a move to proclaim a national Woody Guthrie Day. Mrs. <PERSON> Edgmon </PERSON>, a resident of <LOCATION> Seminole </LOCATION> about 75 miles southwest of here, bristled at any suggestion her brother lacked patriotism, saying he championed the downtrodden and jabbed the well-to-do. `` If you'd read what <PERSON> Woody </PERSON> wrote, you'd know how he felt,'' she said. <PERSON> Guthrie </PERSON>'s `` This Land is Your Land'' has become a patriotic standard, frequently played at political rallies. His songs provided a mournful but optimistic rhythm for <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> as it endured the Dust Bowl and the Great Depression. Among the 1,000 songs he wrote from 1932 to 1952 were classics like `` <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hills </LOCATION>,'' and `` This Train is Bound for Glory.'' The 1976 motion picture `` Bound For Glory'' chronicled his vagabond life. <PERSON> Guthrie </PERSON>, stricken with the degenerative brain disease <LOCATION> Huntington </LOCATION>'s chorea, had indicated he wanted <LOCATION> Okemah </LOCATION> to be his final resting place. The town 72 miles east of <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, is a quiet agricultural town surrounded by cattle-grazing land dotted with oil wells. But when <PERSON> Guthrie </PERSON> died in 1967 at age 55, his ashes were scattered over the <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ocean </LOCATION>. The <LOCATION> Okemah </LOCATION> tribute was put together by musician <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Long </PERSON>, 37, of <LOCATION> Minneapolis </LOCATION>, who got a hug from Mrs. <PERSON> Edgmon </PERSON> after Thursday's concert `` He could double for <PERSON> Woody </PERSON>,'' she said, smiling and crying. `` It took somebody to come in and put it together.'' Some of the songs performed at the Crystal Theater were composed by youngsters under Long's tutelage. The tunes were faithful to <PERSON> Guthrie </PERSON>'s credo, read by young narrator <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON>: `` I'm out to write songs that'll make you take pride in yourself.'' Long said the performance, recorded both for an album and by a crew from <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Today'' show, should help <PERSON> Guthrie </PERSON>'s memory `` burn a little brighter.'' `` I've been to tributes from <LOCATION> Carnegie </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hall </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Beverly </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hills </LOCATION>,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Edgmon </PERSON> said. `` None of them can top this. We're instilling a positive <PERSON> Woody </PERSON> <PERSON> Guthrie </PERSON> in the minds of these little ones And they're going to be his fans.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881202-0025 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-02-88 0501EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-China-BrideSelling     12-02 0195</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-China-Bride Selling,0198</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bride Selling Still Prevalent in Rural China</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Bride selling is still prevalent in poorer areas of rural <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> and more must be done to stop the practice, according to a women's organization quoted in today's official <ORGANIZATION> China </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION>. The All-China Women's Federation said the selling of young women as brides, common in pre-Communist <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, still takes place in inland provinces such as <LOCATION> Anhui </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Sichuan </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Yunnan </LOCATION> where economies are less developed and education levels are lower, the <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> Daily reported. It said some farmers have given up their land to go into the business of abducting and selling brides. Some have lured women away from villages with the promise of jobs. In one county of coastal <LOCATION> Shandong </LOCATION> province, more than 3,200 women, including farmers, factory workers and a post-graduate, have been sold in the past few years, the federation was quoted as saying. It said a group of agents in a city in coastal <LOCATION> Jiangsu </LOCATION> province made $ 65,000 selling about 100 brides from October 1987 to January this year. The All-China Women's Federation is a government-supported organization that to some extent acts as an advocate for women's rights
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881202-0026 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-02-88 0504EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--Britain-Food     12-02 0126</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Britain-Food,0128</SECOND>
<HEAD>Changing Global Weather Pattern Brings Threat of Famine</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Crop failures and famine will become more widespread unless action is taken immediately to curb emission of `` greenhouse gases'' from burning fossil fuels and tropical rain forests, a report said today. `` The delicate balance of gases in the atmosphere is changing,'' the <ORGANIZATION> Economist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Intelligence </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Unit </ORGANIZATION> said in its annual report on food and beverage trends. `` This is leading to significant changes in global weather patterns and hence in crop yield patterns.'' This year's drought in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, which reduced the cushion of stocks against poor grain crops next year, was one of several climatic anomalies in 1988, the report said. Another drought would reduce stocks to `` dangerously low'' levels, it said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881202-0027 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-02-88 0525EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Osteoporosis Bjt   12-02 0521</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Osteoporosis, Bjt,0535</SECOND>
<HEAD>Study Says Calcium Intake, Sex Hormone Production Prevent
Osteoporosis</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By SARAH NORDGREN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CHICAGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
