<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880725-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-25-88 1545EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>rs have complained they spend weeks tracking down clients
because of sloppy army records and indifferent officials. The</FIRST>
<SECOND>nglish-language daily Jerusalem Post quoted army officials as</SECOND>
<TEXT>
 saying information on prisoners can now be obtained within two days. But <PERSON> Felicia </PERSON> <PERSON> Langer </PERSON>, an Israeli lawyer who represents Palestinian prisoners, said problems persisted. She said prison officials often did not notify her about the whereabouts of her clients. Curfews remained in effect Monday in <LOCATION> Beit </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jalla </LOCATION>, where 10,000 Palestinians live, nearby <LOCATION> Beit </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sahur </LOCATION>, home to 12,000, and <LOCATION> Nablus </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION>'s largest city with 120,000 residentsn can-born anti-Arab Rabbi <PERSON> Meir </PERSON> <PERSON> Kahane </PERSON>, meanwhile, began car patrols of Arab east <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION> looking for stone-throwers. The group, calling itself `` The Committee For Safe Roads,'' already patrols the area around the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> city of <LOCATION> Hebron </LOCATION>. The leftist Peace Now group called on the <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> to ban the civilian patrols. But Police Minister <PERSON> Chaim </PERSON> <PERSON> Bar-Lev </PERSON> said as long as the <PERSON> Kahane </PERSON> backers carried licensed weapons and broke no laws, they could not be stopped.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880725-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-25-88 2356EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Iran-Iraq-Interviews     07-25 0392</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Iran-Iraq-Interviews,0402</SECOND>
<HEAD>U.N. Secretary General Hopes to Set Date in 10 Days</HEAD>
<HEAD>With AM-UN-Iran-Iraq</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> Secretary-General <PERSON> Javier </PERSON> <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Cuellar </PERSON> said Monday he hoped a date for a cease-fire between <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> could be set within 10 days, but said this would be only a first step toward resolving the 8-year-old war. In a televised interview, <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Cuellar </PERSON> said he wanted a cease-fire declared `` as soon as possible.'' He is scheduled to meet Wednesday with the foreign ministers of <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> in separate talks on setting up a U.N.-supervised truce. `` The ceasefire is not an end in itself. It's the first very important step. We want a total solution of the problem,'' <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Cuellar </PERSON> said in the interview on <ORGANIZATION> PBS </ORGANIZATION>'s `` The MacNeil-Lehrer News Hour.'' <PERSON> Mohammad </PERSON> <PERSON> Ja </PERSON> <PERSON> Afar </PERSON> <PERSON> Mahallati </PERSON>, the <LOCATION> Iranian </LOCATION> ambassador to the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION>, said on the same program that <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> was continuing to use chemical warfare against his country, even though <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> has said it is ready for an immediate suspension of the conflict. <PERSON> Ismat </PERSON> <PERSON> Kittani </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> ambassador, did not deny that his country had used chemical weapons but added that `` people should have learned by now not to take allegations by <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> at their face value.'' `` We have said, and I ca n't go beyond that, that we will use every means available at our disposal to repel this aggression, this persistent aggression by the Iranians against our country,'' <PERSON> Kittani </PERSON> said. `` Nobody should blame us after they have seen how these people behave,'' he said. `` We want to see genuine signs that <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> is really coming back to the ranks of civilized countries, and abiding by the rules.'' <PERSON> Vernon </PERSON> <PERSON> Walters </PERSON>, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> ambassador to the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION>, also appeared on the program and said he sees <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> making a serious effort to end the war. `` I think they both made a decision to go for peace. Eight years is a long time, you get weary. It's unbelievable, eight years, how they could stand it,'' he said. <PERSON> Walters </PERSON> said the war's casualties have taken their toll on both nations. `` It's the flower of their youth. It's their coming generation that they're going to be losing and I think that's why they have both come to the conclusion that this is the time to stop that kind of activity,'' he added.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880725-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-25-88 2356EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Deaths 1stLd-Writethru a0695 07-25 0427</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Deaths, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0695,0437</SECOND>
<NOTE>Eds: ADDS Pagels; An AMs separate moved as a0598 on McClory as
a0562 on Phillips and a0725 on Silver.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Robert McClory</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> N. </PERSON> <PERSON> McClory </PERSON>, former Representative and <ORGANIZATION> Illinois </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> thrust into the national spotlight for his role in impeachment proceedings against President <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON>, died Sunday. He was 80. <PERSON> McClory </PERSON> was elected to the <ORGANIZATION> Illinois </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Representatives </ORGANIZATION> in 1950. He served in the state <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> from 1952 to 1962. He was the second-ranking Republican on the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Judiciary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> during congressional hearings on the break-in at the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> headquarters in the Watergate complex in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. <PERSON> McClory </PERSON> was one of the leading House supporters of an article of impeachment in 1974 charging <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> with abusing his constitutional powers in the Watergate matter. He drafted another article charging the president with contempt of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> for resisting subpoenas.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>Ann Phillips</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BRISTOL, England (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Ann </PERSON> <PERSON> Phillips </PERSON>, Princess <PERSON> Anne </PERSON>'s mother-in-law, died Monday of a pancreas ailment at the age of 62 Mrs. <PERSON> Phillips </PERSON> was the mother of Capt. <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Phillips </PERSON>, who in 1973 married <PERSON> Anne </PERSON>, the only daughter of Queen <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> II </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>James Silver</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>TAMPA, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Wesley </PERSON> <PERSON> Silver </PERSON>, 81, whose book critical of white supremacy in <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> led to his dismissal from the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Missisippi </ORGANIZATION> faculty in the 1960s, died Monday. Silver came to Ole Miss as a history professor in 1936 and left in 1965 at the request of the university's board of trustees following publication of `` <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION>: A Closed Society.'' The book explored the racial divisions in <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> and sharply criticized the state's white political establishment for hanging on to visions of Confederate glories. Silver wrote five other books: `` <PERSON> Edmund </PERSON> <PERSON> Pendleton </PERSON> <PERSON> Gaines </PERSON>,'' `` <ORGANIZATION> Confederate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mississippi </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Propaganda </ORGANIZATION>,'' `` A Life for the Confederacy,'' `` <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> in the Confederacy'' and `` Running Scared: Silver in <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION>.''
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>Heinz Pagels</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ASPEN, Colo. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Heinz </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Pagels </PERSON>, physicist, executive director of the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sciences </ORGANIZATION> and adjunct professor at The <ORGANIZATION> Rockefeller </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, was killed Saturday in a mountain-climbing accident. He was 49. <PERSON> Pagels </PERSON> began his academic career at The <ORGANIZATION> Rockefeller </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> in 1966 and left as an associate professor in 1983 to become the executive director and chief executive officer of the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sciences </ORGANIZATION>. He was a theoretical physicist working in the area of relativistic quantum field theory and cosmology and the author of three books, including `` The Cosmic Code,'' `` Perfect Symmetry,'' and `` Dreams of Reason.'' <PERSON> Pagels </PERSON> was also a former board member of the <ORGANIZATION> Aspen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Physics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880725-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-25-88 2355EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Philippines-BelgianShot 1stLd-Writethru   07-25 0164</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Philippines-Belgian Shot, 1st Ld-Writethru,a0709,0164</SECOND>
<HEAD>Belgian Diplomat Reported Shot</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: LEADS thruout with Belgian Embassy correcting date of
shooting to Sunday sted Monday, ADDS location of incident, details
on robbery. No pickup</NOTE>
<DATELINE>MANILA, Philippines (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A gunman wounded a Belgian diplomat and killed a woman companion in an apparent robbery attempt at a resort south of <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION>, the Belgian Embassy said Tuesday. Spokeswoman <PERSON> Marie </PERSON> <PERSON> Louise </PERSON> <PERSON> Vanherk </PERSON> said <PERSON> Benoit </PERSON> <PERSON> Standaert </PERSON> suffered two gunshot wounds in the incident, which occurred Sunday, and was in stable condition at a suburban <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION> hospital. She said his companion, <PERSON> Adorata </PERSON> <PERSON> Capistrano </PERSON>, died of her wounds. Ms. <PERSON> Vanherk </PERSON> quoted police in nearby <LOCATION> Batangas </LOCATION> province as saying they suspected robbery was the motive because the gunman fled with Ms. <PERSON> Capistrano </PERSON>'s purse. The incident occurred at <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Taal </LOCATION>, 35 miles south of <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION>, the spokeswoman said. The daily newspaper Tempo identified <PERSON> Standaert </PERSON> as the second secretary of the Belgian Embassy in <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION>. Newspapers earlier had reported the shooting took place Monday.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880725-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-25-88 0001EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Gulf-Soviets Bjt   07-25 0663</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Gulf-Soviets, Bjt,0678</SECOND>
<HEAD>Soviet Navy Escorts Too, But Secretively</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RICHARD PYLE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MANAMA, Bahrain (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> has been escorting <LOCATION> Kuwaiti </LOCATION> oil through the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> for about as long as the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has, but its secretive, low-key operation has attracted far less notice. While criticizing <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> for escalating tensions in the region and calling for a U.N.-sponsored force to replace foreign navies in the gulf, the Soviets have maintained their own flotilla in the waterway since late 1986. Five European countries _ <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Belgium </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Netherlands </LOCATION> _ also have kept warships in the gulf in the past year. All of these forces, along with those of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, are expected to be reduced or removed if a U.N.-sponsored cease-fire takes hold. There are usually about 25 to 30 foreign warships in the strategic gulf, most of them American. The total in the region is around 60, including <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>'s sizable <LOCATION> Indian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ocean </LOCATION> fleet, based at <LOCATION> Djibouti </LOCATION>. The exact number of Soviet vessels in the gulf and nearby waters is difficult to pin down, but <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials say it has hovered at about seven to nine for the past year. The force normally includes two destroyers, plus oceangoing mine sweepers, tugboats and supply vessels. The Soviet convoys, with one or two warships escorting small groups of cargo vessels flying the flags of the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> and other East Bloc countries, are often seen in the gulf. Their convoys sail without the air cover available to the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> warships that escort U.S.-flagged Kuwaiti tankers, and their radio traffic is limited to routine exchanges and greetings with the warships of other nations. The only known example of direct cooperation between the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and Soviet forces occurred Jan. 5, when a Soviet minehunter advised a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> cruiser in the gulf that it had found a mine, and <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> helicopters took part in a search for others. The mine eventually was destroyed by the Soviets, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials say. <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>'s naval operations are run from a coastal anchorage near the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arab </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Emirates </LOCATION> port of <PERSON> Khor </PERSON> <PERSON> Fakkhan </PERSON>, in the <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Oman </LOCATION>, close to the staging area for the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>'s Kuwaiti tanker convoys. The Soviets have long maintained a naval base at <LOCATION> Socotra </LOCATION> island off the <LOCATION> Horn </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> that is owned by <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Yemen </LOCATION>, the Arab world's only Marxist state. After the Iraq-Iran war broke out in September 1980, they posted one or two warships outside the <LOCATION> Strait </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hormuz </LOCATION>, gateway to the gulf. The deployment of Soviet warships to the gulf was never announced but became apparent when two destroyers turned up in the waterway shortly after Iranian gunboats intercepted two Soviet cargo ships in September 1986. In early 1987, <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> agreed to lease three Soviet tankers to <LOCATION> Kuwait </LOCATION> and provide them with armed escort. The move, seen by some <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials as part of efforts by <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> to expand its influence in the oil-rich region, spurred the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration's decision to reflag 11 Kuwait-owned tankers with the Stars and Stripes. One of the Soviet tankers, the 67,9870-ton Marshal <PERSON> Chuikov </PERSON>, hit a mine off <LOCATION> Kuwait </LOCATION> on May 16, 1987. The incident was quickly obscured the next day when the frigate USS Stark was blasted by errant <LOCATION> Iraqi </LOCATION> missiles, killing 37 sailors. Except for the Marshal <PERSON> Chuikov </PERSON> mining and a few reports of Soviet warships finding mines, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials say they are not aware of any incidents involving the Soviet forces in the past 1 -LCB- years. `` The Iranians probably know that if they ever tried to interfere with a Soviet tanker, they'd be blown to bits and nothing would ever be explained one way or another,'' a <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> officer said several months ago. The Soviets' gulf force consists of destroyers, of the 7,900-ton Sovremenny class or the 8,000-ton Udaloy class, and <PERSON> Natya </PERSON> or Yurka class mine sweepers. Foreign naval sources have said the ships are difficult to identify because the Soviets change hull numbers periodically.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880725-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-25-88 0006EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--MarathonTVWatcher     07-25 0138</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Marathon TV Watcher,0140</SECOND>
<HEAD>Unemployed Carpenter Claims World Record For Television Watching</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SYDNEY, Australia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A 24-year-old unemployed carpenter claimed a world record for continuous television watching today after spending 168 hours gazing at the small screen. `` Most of the shows were pretty good. In fact, I could have gone on for days and days,'' said <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Woods </PERSON>, who completed his record attempt in a box 20 yards above one of <LOCATION> Sydney </LOCATION>'s busiest thoroughfares. The <LOCATION> Sydney </LOCATION> man said a masseur and an electric nerve stimulator helped him keep alert during the marathon stint. <PERSON> Woods </PERSON>, who was filmed by an Australian television show that concentrates of wierd and wacky achievements, said after the weeklong marathon effort that television programs `` really are n't that bad. The Guinness Book of Records does not list a current record for television watching.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880725-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-25-88 0013EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-StateTaxes     07-25 0526</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-State Taxes,490</SECOND>
<HEAD>More States Lowered Taxes Than Increased Them in 1988</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 More states decreased taxes than raised them this year, and the total increase among the 27 states was an unusually low $ 600 million, according to the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conference </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Legislatures </ORGANIZATION>. The organization, in a survey of state tax policies, said 13 states raised taxes and 14 lowered them, with most revisions relatively minor. Traditionally, a tax change is considered `` large'' only if it results in at least a 5 percent increase or decrease in revenue. By this standard, the only `` large'' increases this year were reported in <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION>, and the only `` large'' decreases came in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION>, according to the conference. The survey is part of a broader report to be released this week at the conference's annual meeting in <LOCATION> Reno </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Nev. </LOCATION> `` To a considerable extent, 1988 tax actions are related to the tax policy followed last year,'' the conference said. `` The large number of tax increases last year helped to improve financial conditions and thereby avoided the need to increase taxes this year.'' The organization also said the $ 600 million tax increase this year is smaller than those in most recent years. In 1985, the survey said, there was a tax reduction of $ 1.3 billion. All other years since 1981 had tax increases of at least $ 1.1 billion, which came in 1986. The next smallest increase in this decade was a $ 2.3 billion rise in 1984. State tax collections exceed $ 260 billion per year, according to the conference. The survey said income taxes were reduced in 10 states and increased in two; motor fuel taxes were hiked in nine states; and sales taxes _ either through a higher rate or broader base _ went up in five states while being lowered in three others. The most significant tax increases this year came in <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>, although they were spared major tax hikes in 1987. Citizens in <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> saw the biggest tax reductions after seeing taxes increase in 1987. <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> were the only two states to increase income taxes. <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION> also hiked a number of other taxes including property and motor fuel taxes. <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> were the only states to increase their sales taxes significantly. <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION>'s sales tax went up 2 cents on food, utilities and drugs; and <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>'s rate jumped 1 cent for a 13-month period. While the most frequent tax changes involved motor fuel, sales or income taxes, some states found other sources of revenue. <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Rhode </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> increased their cigarette tax, joining 11 states that did the same in 1987, and <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> for the first time imposed such a tax. A recent trend of taxing mail order sales continued this year, with <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> joining 11 other states in enacting such a tax, which still faces court tests. <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION> and parts of <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> state increased taxes on hotel-motel rooms. <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> also increased its tax on hazardous waste while lowering a tax on aluminum casting. The property transfer tax increased in <LOCATION> Vermont </LOCATION> and insurance premium taxes were lowered in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880725-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-25-88 0016EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-GangViolence     07-25 0400</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Gang Violence,0411</SECOND>
<HEAD>Four Dead, 10 Injured Over Weekend</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RIC LEYVA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Planned truce talks between youth gang leaders did little to slow weekend bloodshed on inner-city streets as a wave of violent conflicts left four people dead and 10 others injured. The weekend violence erupted in the wake of announced plans by city church leaders to stage a truce summit this week between members of the city's major black street gang factions. <PERSON> Alfredo </PERSON> <PERSON> Guillen </PERSON>, 34, was critically wounded when an unknown assailant wearing gang-style clothing approached on foot outside a bar and shot him in the head after a brief argument, said Detective <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Bunch </PERSON>. A brawl Saturday night between about 30 gang rivals in a <LOCATION> Boyle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Heights </LOCATION> alley left a 17-year-old admitted gang member nursing a minor stab wound at <ORGANIZATION> County-USC </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>, said police Sgt. <PERSON> Dave </PERSON> <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON>. Police also were investigating the discovery of a man's body on the street in gang-ridden south-central <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> after a shooting Sunday afternoon. Another man was wounded by gunfire Sunday in what he initially told police was a drive-by attack, Officer <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Derek </PERSON> <PERSON> Grant </PERSON>, 22, of <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> later revealed he apparently was shot in self-defense by his landlord following an argument and fistfight, <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> said. Earlier, <PERSON> Louis </PERSON> <PERSON> Canales </PERSON>, 18, of <LOCATION> Maywood </LOCATION>, died after being shot with a .357 - caliber Magnum pistol following a confrontation between rival gangs, said county sheriff's Deputy <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> A 15-year-old <PERSON> Cudahy </PERSON> youth, whose name was withheld, was in custody for investigation of the fatal shooting, <ORGANIZATION> Cox </ORGANIZATION> said. A shouting match with gang members escalated into gunfire that killed <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Marcus </PERSON>, 18, of <LOCATION> Palmdale </LOCATION>, who was fatally shot in a shopping center parking lot early Saturday morning, said police Detective <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Humphry </PERSON>. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Mora </PERSON>, also 18, of <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>, was struck by a single bullet in the attack, and was listed in stable condition at a <ORGANIZATION> UCLA </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Humphry </PERSON> said. The alleged gunmen, known to police as active gang members, evaded capture, the detective said. And in <LOCATION> Atwater </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Benjamin </PERSON> <PERSON> Rivas </PERSON>, 17, was killed by shotgun blasts from assailants who yelled gang slogans from a moving car before opening fire late Friday, said police Lt. <PERSON> Dave </PERSON> <PERSON> Waterman </PERSON>. Five teen-agers were wounded in another apparent gang attack, and an unidentified 17-year-old was hit by gunfire late Friday as he walked on the street with friends, police said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880725-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-25-88 0033EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Drought-Okefenokee Bjt   07-25 0630</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Drought-Okefenokee, Bjt,0645</SECOND>
<HEAD>Drought Necessary For Survival Of Okefenokee Swamp</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ELLIOTT MINOR</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>FOLKSTON, Ga. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The drought that has forced Okefenokee Swamp's wildlife to gather near deeper pools and its alligators to engage in cannibalism, is necessary for the survival of the swamp, a parks official says. `` The swamp has tolerated drought for thousands of years. Drought is a part of the biological process that creates open water areas and marsh areas,'' said <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Schroer </PERSON>, manager of the <ORGANIZATION> Okefenokee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wildlife </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Refuge </ORGANIZATION>. Swamp vegetation dries out during a drought, increasing the chance of wildfire ignited by lightning. But, <PERSON> Schroer </PERSON> said, wildfires are necessary because they burn off floating islands of peat, which eventually can turn into dry land. Indians dubbed the swamp `` the land of the trembling earth'' because of the undulating peat. In 1954 and 1955, fires raged for 12 months, burning 80 percent of the swamp, and fires in the 1840s created some of the Okefenokee's lakes by burning large holes in the peat. `` If it were n't for the natural wildfires that have occurred throughout history, the swamp would not be a swamp,'' said <PERSON> Schroer </PERSON>. `` It would be a forest.'' The peat floats to the surface of the swamp's reflective tea-colored water, forming islands that support vegetation. Eventually trees begin growing in the peat, sinking their roots into the swamp's sandy bottom. The islands get larger and larger, and without fires, they could be transformed into forests. The 700-square-mile swamp in southeastern <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION> and northeastern <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> is home to many types of animals, including rare birds, fish, poisonous snakes and alligators. Many exotic plants also thrive, including orchids, lilies, cypress trees and carnivorous pitcher plants. President <PERSON> Franklin </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Roosevelt </PERSON> designated most of the swamp a national wildlife refuge in 1937. The drought has caused wildlife to congregate near water holes, <PERSON> Schroer </PERSON> said. Game officials recently counted nearly 1,000 alligators along a 5-mile spillway on the swamp's western side. `` When they get concentrated, predators have more prey,'' he said. `` Alligators start eating other alligators. We've seen some cannibalistic activity, but this is nature's way of keeping populations in check. The big males typically try to keep other males out of their territory.'' <PERSON> Schroer </PERSON> said water levels are 8 to 10 inches below normal on the east side of the swamp, near the <LOCATION> Suwannee </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Canal </LOCATION>. Levels are about a foot below normal near the 80-acre <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Foster </PERSON> <LOCATION> State </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Park </LOCATION> on the swamp's western edge near <LOCATION> Fargo </LOCATION>. And the water is 5 to 6 feet below normal near the spillway. Visitors can still take two-day canoe trips into the swamp from the <LOCATION> Suwannee </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Canal </LOCATION>, but the longer trips of up to five days have been canceled because boats have trouble navigating some of the shallow trails, <PERSON> Schroer </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Metts </PERSON>, assistant superintendent at <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION>'s Foster State Park, said anglers can still reach <PERSON> Billy </PERSON>'s <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION>, a popular fishing spot, but canoe trails to <PERSON> Minnie </PERSON>'s and Big Water lakes are closed because of low water. <PERSON> Jimmy </PERSON> <PERSON> Walker </PERSON>, general manager of the privately run Okefenokee Swamp Park near <LOCATION> Waycross </LOCATION>, said his park continues to offer 4-mile boat tours but has discontinued 10-mile tours deeper into the swamp to avoid damaging boat motors in the shallow water. `` The water is low, but it's not critically low like it was two years ago,'' he said. During the 1986 drought, <PERSON> Walker </PERSON> had to cancel all boat tours and was able to walk along trails that normally carried boatloads of visitors. Ms. <PERSON> Metts </PERSON> said she went fishing recently with her mother, and the woman's brightly colored bobber attracted an 8-foot alligator. `` The gators are plentiful and they love to visit the fishermen,'' she said. `` One of the gators fell in love with her bobber. Needless to say, we did n't catch anything.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880725-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-25-88 0026EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-TrainDerailment     07-25 0165</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Train Derailment,0169</SECOND>
<HEAD>Derailed Tanker Dumps Chemical</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WHITE BLUFF, Tenn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 About 20 railroad cars derailed Sunday, dumping a chemical that can kill fish into a creek, authorities said. About 20,550 gallons of a petroleum refinery waste product drained from an overturned tanker, said <PERSON> Millie </PERSON> <PERSON> McGuigan </PERSON>, operations officer for the <ORGANIZATION> Tennessee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Emergency </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Management </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION>. It was not known how much of the substance actually went into <LOCATION> Indian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Camp </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Creek </LOCATION>, which eventually flows to the <LOCATION> Harpeth </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION>, Ms. <PERSON> McGuigan </PERSON> said. There were no injuries and no evacuations, and the spill should not threaten any drinking water supplies because of purification, she said. But she added, `` It is harmful to aquatic life. When it gets in the water it takes out oxygen.'' The <ORGANIZATION> CSX </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> rail cars were expected to be righted Monday, she said. Officials from the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION>, the <LOCATION> Dickson </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> sheriff's department and the <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> were investigating, but the cause of the derailment was unknown, Ms. <PERSON> McGuigan </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880725-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-25-88 0034EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     07-25 0825</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0858</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names In The News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Comic <PERSON> Phyllis </PERSON> <PERSON> Diller </PERSON> says she's had a habit of dressing as a nun in public for the past decade to avoid being recognized, especially when she's out shopping. `` People tend to leave nuns alone, so I'm able to do my shopping dressed that way. It prevents people from asking me for my autograph,'' <PERSON> Diller </PERSON> said in this week's People magazine. `` I'm able to buy all the crazy things I like to wear because I pretend to be the nun in charge of the drama department at <ORGANIZATION> Marymount </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION>, so they think it's for our little play,'' said the 71-year-old <PERSON> Diller </PERSON>, who is appearing in the musical `` Nunsense'' at <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION>'s Marines Memorial Theater.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>MONTREAL (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Comedian <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Candy </PERSON> may make his living making people laugh but he's dead serious about hockey. `` I ca n't leave this town until I see the shrine _ the Forum,'' said the 37-year-old <LOCATION> Toronto </LOCATION> native, referring to <ORGANIZATION> Montreal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Canadiens </ORGANIZATION>' hockey arena. Candy, a `` long-suffering'' <ORGANIZATION> Toronto </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Maple </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Leafs </ORGANIZATION> fan, would rather talk about hockey heroes like <PERSON> Eddie </PERSON> <PERSON> Shack </PERSON> and <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Duff </PERSON> than about movie colleagues such as <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> and <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Aykroyd </PERSON>. Or himself for that matter. `` People put far too much importance on what actors say,'' Candy said in an interview. `` Who cares what celebrities think?'' Candy, whose latest film is `` Who's <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> Crumb </PERSON>?,'' was in <LOCATION> Montreal </LOCATION> to be host of last weekend's Just for Laughs international comedy festival, a $ 4-million show that featured 215 comic acts from 10 countries.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Failure has its reward, according to humorist <PERSON> Jackie </PERSON> <PERSON> Mason </PERSON>, who says it kept him unknown for so long that now he can enjoy being an overnight success. <PERSON> Mason </PERSON>, who has a one-man Broadway show `` The World According to Me!'' also stars in the film `` Caddyshack II,'' which made its premiered Friday. `` I've been doing this for a hundred thousand years,'' he said of his acting, according to Sunday's editions of <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION>. `` But it's like I was born last Thursday. They see me as today's comedian. Thank God, I stunk for such a long time and was invisible, so I could be discovered.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NASHVILLE, Tenn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Honky-tonk singer <PERSON> Keith </PERSON> <PERSON> Whitley </PERSON> credits a hit record for saving his life. `` I have no doubts in my mind that I would not be sitting here today had it not been for ` <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> My Amy.' That song saved my life,'' <PERSON> Whitley </PERSON> said. The country tune he wrote and recorded in 1986 made the top-10 and helped him break his heavy drinking. `` It gave me confidence; it gave me work,'' said <PERSON> Whitley </PERSON>, whose single, `` Do n't Close Your Eyes,'' topped the country charts this month. <PERSON> Whitley </PERSON>, 33, began playing the guitar at age 6, and was on a <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> radio station within three years. At 15, he toured with country singer <PERSON> Ricky </PERSON> <PERSON> Skaggs </PERSON> and bluegrass great <PERSON> Ralph </PERSON> <PERSON> Stanley </PERSON>'s Clinch Mountain Boys band.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actor <PERSON> Terence </PERSON> <PERSON> Knox </PERSON>, who appears in the <ORGANIZATION> CBS-TV </ORGANIZATION>'s Vietnam War series `` Tour of Duty,'' is concerned the show's authentic look could be lost when its filming moves from <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Southern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>. `` One of the great things about the show was that it looked so right,'' <PERSON> Knox </PERSON> said recently. `` <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION> was a good substitute for Nam. And I do n't want to lose that.'' <PERSON> Knox </PERSON>, 37, said he recently learned the show will begin shooting in the <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> area next season. It had been on permanent location in <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION>. `` It may just be that there's jungle up in <LOCATION> Saugus </LOCATION> -LRB- near <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> -RRB- that could pass for <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Knox </PERSON> said. `` But I do n't know of any. `` Tour of Duty'' is about a platoon of combat soldiers in <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>, and <PERSON> Knox </PERSON>, who plays the tough Army Sgt. <PERSON> Zeke </PERSON> <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON>, says the response from veterans has been positive. `` I figure that if we keep our truth and integrity, and see that what the guys went through over there is n't mutilated, there's no problem.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NASHVILLE, Tenn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Stewart </PERSON>, who walked 1,500 miles in three months to publicize his dream of appearing in the Grand Ole Opry, finally had his moment in the spotlight _ six of them, in fact. <PERSON> Stewart </PERSON> took center stage Saturday night and sang his song, `` In the Wings of the Grand Ole Opry.'' `` I'm just proud to be here. I want to thank you folks for taking part in this trip with me. This has been my dream,'' <PERSON> Stewart </PERSON> told the crowd. <PERSON> Stewart </PERSON>, 37, got a rousing ovation after his six-minute fling with fame. Opry announcer <PERSON> Charlie </PERSON> <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON> invited <PERSON> Stewart </PERSON> to perform an encore, `` Jambalaya,'' with veteran <PERSON> Hank </PERSON> <PERSON> Snow </PERSON>. <PERSON> Stewart </PERSON> was invited Friday to appear on the Opry cable television show. The offer came a few hours after he completed the walk from his home in <ORGANIZATION> Gillette </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Wyo. </LOCATION>, to <LOCATION> Nashville </LOCATION> to show how much he wanted to perform on the 63-year-old Opry.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880725-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-25-88 0035EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-SpaceShuttle     07-25 0327</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Space Shuttle,0335</SECOND>
<HEAD>NASA Begins Test Aimed at Firing Space Shuttle Engines</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CAPE CANAVERAL, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A practice space shuttle countdown was under way here today in a test leading to a firing of Discovery's three main engines on the launch pad Saturday. The launch team started the count at 11:33 p.m. Sunday. On Wednesday, it planned to load more than a half million gallons of liquid hydrogen and liquid oxygen propellant into the shuttle's external fuel tank It will be the first time a shuttle has been fueled since the Challenger explosion, which killed seven astronauts on Jan. 28, 1986. When the countdown reaches 10 seconds before a mock lift-off on Wednesday, a problem will be simulated to force a launch postponement. Then launch crews will rehearse what's called a 72-hour turnaround. They will empty the fuel tank, start another countdown, refill the tank and aim for a 20-second test firing of Discovery's main engines at 7:30 a.m. Saturday. The firing, with the shuttle bolted firmly on the pad, will check modifications made to the engines and is considered critical to Discovery being certified for the first post-Challenger shuttle flight. The launch, with a five-man crew, is scheduled for early September, but the date is in doubt as engineers continue to puzzle over how to fix a small gas leak in a steering engine system that is separate from the main engines. They hope to make the repair on the pad and avoid rolling Discovery back to a hangar, a move that could delay the flight as much as two months. Experts are considering several ways to reach the inaccessible leak, including cutting a hole through the shuttle's cargo bay wall and running a snake-like tube through the gas line in an effort to plug it. The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aeronautics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Space </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> said it will not make a decision on whether to move Discovery off the pad until after the main engine test firing.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880725-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-25-88 0050EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-BestCity     07-25 0623</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Best City,0646</SECOND>
<HEAD>Danbury Ranked Top Place To Live</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NXJ1</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LINDA STOWELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>DANBURY, Conn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Carbide </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>'s chairman was delighted that a national magazine named <LOCATION> Danbury </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s best place to live, but another resident says she was stunned because she finds the city boring. In its second-annual rating of 300 <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> areas, Money magazine's current issue ranked the <LOCATION> Danbury </LOCATION> metropolitan area as the most livable <LOCATION> Danbury </LOCATION>, about 60 miles northeast of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> in southwestern <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION>, once was known as the `` hat city'' because hatters plied their trade here starting before the American Revolution The last hat factory closed in 1987. Today, the city of about 70,000 people is the home of <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Carbide </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Danbury </LOCATION>'s largest employer. `` We are very happy here,'' said <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, chairman and chief executive officer of the giant chemical company. And the company, which moved its headquarters from <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> to an innovative suburban complex in 1980-81, is here to stay, he added. `` There's no better place to be. We came at a time when the city of <LOCATION> Danbury </LOCATION> was beginning the sort of comeback they've since enjoyed,'' <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> said. But a shopper on Main Street said she was surprised about the honor. `` I do n't know why,'' said the woman, who identified herself only as <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON>. `` It's boring. When we want to do something, we go into the -LRB- <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> -RRB- city.'' She said she hopes to move soon. Money magazine said <PERSON> Danbury </PERSON> unseated last year's No. 1 area, <LOCATION> Nashua </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.H. </LOCATION>, because of a lower crime rate, slightly better schools and its proximity to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Everett </PERSON>, an aide to <LOCATION> Nashua </LOCATION> Mayor <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Donchess </PERSON>, said the mayor, who was unavailable for comment, would not be upset about losing the top spot because <LOCATION> Nashua </LOCATION> remained in the top 10. <PERSON> Everett </PERSON> said last year's top ranking gave the city more exposure. `` I'd go somewhere and say I'm from <LOCATION> Nashua </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION>, and people would say they'd heard of it,'' he said. `` The old saying used to be you go to <LOCATION> Nashua </LOCATION> on the way to somewhere else.'' The magazine said its staffers studied government and private data on the 300 largest metropolitan areas, ranking their crime rates, housing, health care, economy, arts, education, transit system, weather and leisure activities. <LOCATION> Danbury </LOCATION> Mayor <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Sauer </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> said he was `` very proud.'' `` I'm not naive to think this took place in the last eight months,'' said <PERSON> Sauer </PERSON>, who became mayor in November. `` The reasons are the objects of our concentrated efforts _ low crime rate, medical facilities, parks and recreation _ we've worked on all of it.'' <PERSON> Sauer </PERSON> and Money magazine acknowledged that <LOCATION> Danbury </LOCATION> has its problems. For example, a three-bedroom house typically costs between $ 175,000 and $ 250,000. <LOCATION> Danbury </LOCATION> has had other troubles. The administration of former Mayor <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Dyer </PERSON> is the target of an <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> probe that resulted in the confiscation of city expense and payroll records last year. And a former part-time probate judge and <LOCATION> Danbury </LOCATION> lawyer allegedly embezzled more than $ 3 million from trust funds under his care before committing suicide last year. But many business owners who have worked and lived here their entire lives would n't live anywhere else. <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Cappiello </PERSON>, who runs a card shop on Main Street, said she and her seven siblings were born in <LOCATION> Danbury </LOCATION>. Today, her 15 nieces and nephews all live and work here. `` I would say it is -LRB- the best place to live -RRB-,'' she said. `` I think we have a lot going for us.'' Her brother, <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Cappiello </PERSON>, who runs a jewelry shop down the street, said he was a little surprised by the top ranking. `` Palm Springs has got to be a better place,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880725-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-25-88 0052EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-SpeedTrapFlap     07-25 0254</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Speed Trap Flap,0260</SECOND>
<HEAD>German Politicians Reported Angered By New Italian Speed Limits</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BONN, West Germany (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Some West German politicians are calling lowered speed limits on Italian highways downright inhospitable, saying they appear aimed at catching unsuspecting German vacationers unawares. `` The purpose of this law is apparently to take money from vacationers,'' the mass-circulation newspaper <ORGANIZATION> Bild </ORGANIZATION> quoted federal lawmaker <PERSON> Ernt </PERSON> <PERSON> Hinken </PERSON> as saying. `` Many Germans will be caught without knowing the law has been changed,'' <PERSON> Hinken </PERSON>, a federal lawmaker for the governing <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democrats </ORGANIZATION>, reportedly told the paper. Under new rules that took effect on Sunday, the maximum speed permitted on <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>'s superhighways has been lowered to 110 kilometers per hour -LRB- 68 mph -RRB- from 140 kilometers per hour -LRB- 87 mph -RRB-. The maximum speed on <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>'s regular highways fell to 90 from 110 kilometers per hour. Italian authorities said the speed limits were lowered because of an increase in highway deaths. Thousands of West Germans are now taking to the road _ many of them en route to <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION> and other southern points _ to start their summer vacations. There are no maximum speed limits on some sections of <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>'s autobahns. <PERSON> Erwin </PERSON> <PERSON> Huber </PERSON>, a high-ranking politician with the <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Social </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> CDU </ORGANIZATION>'s Bavarian sister party, also criticized the lowered Italian speed limits. `` <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION> is a much-beloved vacationland with a reputation for hospitality. But I do not think these measures are hospitable,'' <ORGANIZATION> Bild </ORGANIZATION> quoted him as saying. <ORGANIZATION> Bild </ORGANIZATION>'s report, appearing it today's editions, was telexed to other news organizations in advance.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880725-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-25-88 0054EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-Drought-Fires 1stLd-Writethru a0777 07-25 0849</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Drought-Fires, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0777,0866</SECOND>
<HEAD>Forest Fires Around And Inside Yellowstone Park</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: INSERTS one graf after 4th graf `Hot, dry' to UPDATE with
Spokane fire under control. SUBS grafs 11-15 bgng `On the western'
with six grafs to UPDATE with North Fork blaze doubling in size,
sending up huge smoke column. UPDATES percentage of Sawtooth fire
contained. Picks up 16th graf pvs `The fire.'</NOTE>
<HEAD>With AM-Mink Creek Fire, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 A big <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION> forest fire edged into Yellowstone National Park on Sunday but appeared to be slowing down, and firefighters fought to keep a separate fire inside the park from burning into <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION>. The south entrance to <LOCATION> Yellowstone </LOCATION>, along with the <ORGANIZATION> Grant </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Village </ORGANIZATION> hotel and two campgrounds, remained closed Sunday because of other fires in the park, but officials stressed that all major park attractions remained open. Two fires that burned together over some 10,800 acres in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>'s Gold Rush country were contained Saturday and 80 percent controlled Sunday, officials said. A fire is considered contained when a fire break is built around it, and controlled when it is reduced to smoldering patches. Hot, dry weather remained a factor as hundreds of acres of trees and brush also burned Sunday in smaller fires in parts of <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION>. Despite temperatures that reached 94 degrees on the fire lines, about 210 firefighters Sunday afternoon brought a 2,420-acre blaze on the <ORGANIZATION> Spokane </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Indian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reservation </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> under control, said <PERSON> Norm </PERSON> <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Wenatchee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> official. The 22,650-acre Mink Creek fire in the <ORGANIZATION> Bridger-Teton </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION>'s Teton Wilderness grew by only 150 acres overnight but it crossed the boundary of <LOCATION> Yellowstone </LOCATION> into a rugged backcountry area, <PERSON> Dave </PERSON> <PERSON> Steinke </PERSON>, a fire information officer said Sunday. `` It pushed past <LOCATION> Falcon </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Creek </LOCATION> last night and moved just slightly into the park, probably one-quarter of a mile,'' he said. `` We have a few spots in the <LOCATION> Yellowstone </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Meadows </LOCATION> area. But we have a crew up there mopping that up and it looks pretty good on the north end.'' A lack of wind during the night helped the fire stay within containment lines on its southern end, where it was within a few miles of private property. `` We think it's calmed down,'' <PERSON> Steinke </PERSON> said. He said 737 firefighters were strengthening firebreaks and mopping up hot spots. `` We made very good progress -LRB- Saturday -RRB-, and one reason was that we did n't get the predicted adverse weather,'' said <PERSON> Dale </PERSON> <PERSON> Jarrell </PERSON>, incident commander. `` Also, the crews are doing an outstanding job.'' On the western side of <ORGANIZATION> Yellowstone </ORGANIZATION>, a 1,300-acre blaze threatening grizzly bear habitat in the park more than doubled in size by nightfall Sunday, sending a column of smoke more than seven miles into the air, authorities said. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Quackenbush </PERSON>, a helicopter pilot helping dump water on the fire, said it was one of the biggest columns of smoke he had seen in 14 years of such work. <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Fox </PERSON> said earlier that 200 firefighters, assisted by nine fire engines, a helicopter and two bulldozers, withdrew to construct a fire line running roughly adjacent to the park's boundary to keep the North Fork fire from crossing into the <ORGANIZATION> Targhee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> in eastern <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION>. `` Basically, we've decided to allow nature to take its course,'' he said. The blaze began Friday about a quarter mile inside the Targhee, and then spread eastward into <LOCATION> Yellowstone </LOCATION> six miles south of the point where the <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION> borders meet. Elsewhere in southern <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION>, in the <ORGANIZATION> Sawtooth </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> southeast of <LOCATION> Twin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Falls </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> Poison </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Creek </LOCATION> fire was about 40 percent contained at more than 2,000 acres, authorities said. The fire was threatening a cutthroat and rainbow trout fishery along with valuable deer habitat and recently transplanted bighorn sheep and wild turkeys. In <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, firefighters fought shifting wind, high temperatures and a threat of lightning Sunday in an effort to extinquish twin blazes in <LOCATION> Calaveras </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> that caused $ 11 million in damages. Fire crews hoped to put them out by Monday night. `` We're holding our breath, waiting to find out what the weather's going to do to us,'' said <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Dashiell </PERSON>, a spokeswoman for the <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forestry </ORGANIZATION> in the Mother Lode community of <LOCATION> Rail </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Road </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Flat </LOCATION>, 150 miles east of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION>. Six homes, nine other buildings and eight vehicles have been lost since the arson-suspected blazes broke out Tuesday. There were 1,700 firefighters and support personnel on hand Sunday, down from a maximum of 3,400 Friday. In <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION>, 160 firefighters worked to contain a 250-acre blaze in the Selway-Bitterroot Wilderness that threatened to spread into an area filled with dead and dying trees, said <PERSON> Deanna </PERSON> <PERSON> Riede </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman in <LOCATION> Missoula </LOCATION>. At least 120 firefighters battled summer heat and wind at a blaze that scorched more than 250 acres of brush and timber near Flaming Gorge Dam on the Utah-Colorado border, <ORGANIZATION> Ashley </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman <PERSON> Merle </PERSON> <PERSON> Young </PERSON> said. `` It's still an uncontrolled fire,'' <PERSON> Young </PERSON> said. No injuries or property damage were reported from the blaze, which is believed to have been ignited by fireworks.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880725-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-25-88 0057EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-SpielbergFire 1stLd-Writethru a0417 07-25 0259</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Spielberg Fire, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0417,0261</SECOND>
<HEAD>Steven Spielberg's Beach Home Destroyed in Fire</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: CORRECTS to damaged sted destroyed in 1st graf, INSERTS one
graf with damage figures after 5th graf, ADDS one graf with film
credits.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>MALIBU, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Director <PERSON> Steven </PERSON> <PERSON> Spielberg </PERSON>'s multimillion-dollar home was damaged Sunday in a fire that spread to another oceanfront estate, authorities said <PERSON> Spielberg </PERSON>, his actress-wife <PERSON> Amy </PERSON> <PERSON> Irving </PERSON> and their son, <PERSON> Max </PERSON>, were n't home at the time of the blaze and there were no injuries, authorities said. Arson investigators were dispatched to help determine the fire's cause, Deputy <PERSON> Eric </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> of the <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> Sheriff's Department <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> confirmed that <PERSON> Spielberg </PERSON>'s home was involved. It took 40 firefighters about 40 minutes to extinguish the blaze, authorities said. `` The first home -LRB- <PERSON> Spielberg </PERSON>'s -RRB- was fully involved when we arrived, then the second home caught fire,'' said county fire Capt. <PERSON> Derek </PERSON> <PERSON> Reyna </PERSON>. Damage to the <LOCATION> Spielberg </LOCATION> home was estimated at $ 210,000, and the neighboring residence sustained $ 120,000 in damage, said <PERSON> Reyna </PERSON>. Firefighters arrived at 6:41 p.m. and the fire was out by 7:18 p.m., <PERSON> Reyna </PERSON> said. He did n't know the name of the other homeowner. Other residents of the exclusive <LOCATION> Broad </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION> celebrity enclave include <PERSON> Sylvester </PERSON> <PERSON> Stallone </PERSON>, <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Redford </PERSON>, <PERSON> Carroll </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Connor </PERSON> and Goldie Hawn. The homes generally are valued at $ 3 million to $ 10 million. Among <PERSON> Spielberg </PERSON>'s hit films were `` Jaws,'' `` Close Encounters of the Third Kind,'' `` Raiders of the Lost Ark,'' `` E.T. _ The Extra-Terrestrial,'' `` Empire of the Sun,'' `` The Color Purple'' and the recently released `` Who Framed <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> Rabbit </PERSON>.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880725-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-25-88 0115EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Bush Bjt   07-25 0771</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bush, Bjt,740</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush Proposes Child-Care Program, Starts Considering Running Mates</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TOM RAUM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Republican <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, after outlining a $ 2.2 billion child-care program designed to help close his gender gap with women, is turning his attention to selecting a running mate. The vice president says he expects to have `` some kind of a list'' of potential running mates prepared by sometime this week, although he hopes to delay announcing his choice until the GOP convention next month. The certain Republican presidential candidate was expected to spend much of this week mulling over his vice presidential selection and had few campaign events scheduled. Meanwhile, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was drawing mixed reviews for his proposal for child-care tax credits of up to $ 1,000 per child for low-income families. For the neediest families _ those earning less than $ 10,000 a year _ the `` credit'' would become a direct government payment of the maximum $ 1,000 for each child of four or younger. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> made the proposal Sunday in a speech to the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Business </ORGANIZATION> and Professional Women's Clubs in <LOCATION> Albuquerque </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.M. </LOCATION>, ending a five-day burst of campaigning in seven states. `` It was a gutsy move on the part of the vice president,'' said <PERSON> Deborah </PERSON> <PERSON> Steelman </PERSON>, domestic affairs director for <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s presidential campaign. The vice president's plan was a sharp departure from the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration's past policies on child care, and bears a price tag similar to a $ 2.5 billion Democratic plan now before <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. The Democratic proposal chiefly sponsored by Sen. <PERSON> Christopher </PERSON> <PERSON> Dodd </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Conn </LOCATION>., which Democratic presidential nominee <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> has endorsed `` in concept,'' would provide the money to child-care providers instead of to individual families as under the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> plan <PERSON> Betty </PERSON> <PERSON> Wray </PERSON>, president of the federation to which <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> spoke, called the plan `` one of the first concrete gestures that the vice president has made'' on issues concerning women. But, she added, `` We know that <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has a problem right now with women voters in this country. So until the Republican party starts to very seriously take a look at those kinds of things that are making a difference, it could pose real problems. ... `` There are simply not enough Republican men to get him -LRB- <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> -RRB- elected without the woman's vote,'' she said. At the conclusion of his speech, many members of the audience of 2,500 women chanted `` E-R-A'' over and over, for the equal rights amendment which <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> opposes and which he did not mention in his talk. `` We would have liked to have him address the equal rights amendment, which continues to be this organization's top priority,'' federation president-elect <PERSON> Betty </PERSON> <PERSON> Forbes </PERSON> said. The organization's leaders said <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> and <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> also had been invited to address the convention, but had conflicting plans. There would be no strings attached to how the proposed <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> tax credit-payment could be spent. To qualify, at least one adult family member would have to be employed. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> arrived in <LOCATION> Albuquerque </LOCATION> on Sunday on Air Force Two with former <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> Hanford </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>, a frequently mentioned vice presidential possibility whose speech to the group followed the vice president's. Mrs. <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>, wife of former <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> rival, <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Republican leader <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION>, helped worked on the final draft of <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s speech, according to her aides <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> spokeswoman <PERSON> Sheila </PERSON> <PERSON> Tate </PERSON> said there was no discussion of the vice presidential selection process on the plane. The vice president told reporters that screening of potential running mates _ to look into backgrounds and financial histories _ would begin this week. Prospective candidates will be asked to fill out financial disclosure statements, he indicated. `` So by sometime next week, there will have to be some kind of a list,'' he said. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> told his <LOCATION> Albuquerque </LOCATION> audience his `` Children's Tax Credit'' would range up to $ 1,000 per child under age 4 and would be `` refundable'' _ meaning families could receive something from the government even if they did n't earn enough to pay taxes. The vice president said the credit would be phased out as income rises. He gave no details on exactly how this would be done. Background information provided by <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s staff said the tax credit would cost $ 1.5 billion a year. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s four-point program also included: _ Expansion of the existing child-care tax credit to cover more low-income families, for a cost of $ 400 million a year _ Creation of workplace child-care centers for all government employees and a federally underwritten liability insurance program for private centers, $ 50 million a year _ More federal assistance to help states and local governments set up programs such as sick child care and before-and-after school care, $ 250 million
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880725-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-25-88 0132EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Reagan     07-25 0642</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Reagan,610</SECOND>
<HEAD>White House Sidesteps Questions About Baker</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MERRILL HARTSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> returned from a midsummer's vacation amid heightened expectations that <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON> will resign soon to run <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s presidential campaign Neither <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> nor <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> officials would confirm publicly that <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> will be leaving the <ORGANIZATION> Cabinet </ORGANIZATION> soon, although presidential spokesman <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> did not flatly deny it. Given the opportunity Sunday to say <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> would not leave the treasury post, <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said only: `` He's still treasury secretary. Put it that way.'' But an administration official, declining to be named publicly, said <PERSON> Baker </PERSON>'s resignation likely will be submitted to <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> in early August, possibly as soon as next Monday, with plans to hook up with <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> in mid-August. A Baker move to the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> campaign would not be shocking since there has been speculation for months that the longtime <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> confidant eventually would move from the <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> to the campaign. <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> managed <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s unsuccessful run for the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> presidential nomination in 1980. <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> accompanied <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and his wife, <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON>, on the flight from <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> on Sunday, although the treasury secretary was not observed boarding the plane with the <ORGANIZATION> Reagans </ORGANIZATION> at Point Mugu Naval Air Station. <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> evidently had boarded before the contingent of reporters arrived to greet the Reagans, who had flown to the military base from their ranch in the <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ynez </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mountains </LOCATION>. The secretary also spurned a request by a pool of reporters on Air Force One to come chat with them. Instead, he sent back a folder that contained a dollar bill. <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> wrote, `` Please note the title under the signature is secretary of the treasury.'' <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said only that <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and <PERSON> Baker </PERSON>, who had been the president's chief of staff from 1981-85, merely had a `` very brief chat.'' An official who discussed the situation on grounds of anonymity said the secretary had spoken at a fund-raiser Saturday night for Sen. <PERSON> Pete </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON>, R-Calif., and `` essentially, he is hitching a ride. But another official said <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> would not have needed to inform <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> of his plans on the Air Force One trip, saying the secretary's decision to take over the vice president's campaign had been known for some time. When <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> got off the plane at <ORGANIZATION> Andrews </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Base </ORGANIZATION> just outside <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, a reporter asked the secretary, `` Can you share the news with us?'' <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> replied, `` There's no news to share.'' Asked if he had spoken with <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> about quitting, <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> said he had not. <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> has been an unofficial adviser to the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> campaign for some time, and had accompanied the vice president to <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION> last week for a fishing trip. If <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> were to leave, it would be the second major <ORGANIZATION> Cabinet </ORGANIZATION> change in recent weeks. Attorney General <PERSON> Edwin </PERSON> <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>, a longtime <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> friend, has resigned effective late this month or early next month. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> nominated former <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON> as <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>'s replacement. While <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> vacationed last week at his ranch near <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Barbara </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, senior aides discussed the administration's agenda for the remainder of the president's term. This week <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> will assess the prospects for new <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military aid to the Nicaraguan rebels _ a subject that is on the agenda for a Tuesday morning meeting with Republican congressional leaders. He also plays host Wednesday to Hungarian Premier <PERSON> Karoly </PERSON> <PERSON> Grosz </PERSON> in the first such visit by a high-ranking Hungarian official since the country came under <ORGANIZATION> communist </ORGANIZATION> rule 40 years ago. Since becoming premier in June 1987, <PERSON> Grosz </PERSON> has sought improved economic and political ties with the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Grosz </PERSON> began an 11-day <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> tour last week. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> will receive an updated report on the drought from <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Lyng </PERSON>, who took a 10-state tour last week. The administration's midyear budget review also is due this week.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880725-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-25-88 0138EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-CampaignNotebook     07-25 0626</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Campaign Notebook,590</SECOND>
<HEAD>Would There Be a Tomato Garden in a Dukakis White House?</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By STEVEN KOMAROW</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 As the <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> people try to figure out whether to put <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> in the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, the candidate reveals that his daydreams about 1600 <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> Avenue leave him with a perplexing question: Where do you put the tomato garden? `` I'm trying to figure it out _ wherever there's full sun, right?'' he told reporters traveling with him over the weekend. The <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> governor says he grows three varieties of tomatoes in his back yard in <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>, along with some cucumbers and peppers. He says he worries about them when he's on the campaign trail, although his neighbor is watering them. Maybe it was the swing through <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION> farm areas that got him thinking about moving that vegetable garden to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. It would n't be good to cut down any of the famous White House trees. And do n't worry about the Rose Garden. No point planting there, he says, because it's too close to the building. `` A good tomato garden with cukes, peppers, has got to be right out there'' in the open, `` Right?''
</TEXT>
<HEAD>___</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> is mindful that keeping ahead in the polls sometimes requires placing things on your head. On his first post-convention campaign swing last weekend he posed for pictures with a Scottish tam-o' - shanter and an Assyrian headpiece and some No doubt, before campaign's end he'll be donning an American Indian headdress, a cowboy had, hard hat and others. Although he's not usually a hat man, he was taking it all in stride until, at a rally in <LOCATION> Erie </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION>, Mayor <PERSON> Lou </PERSON> <PERSON> Tullio </PERSON> showed up with the special hat he built for the Democratic convention. The boater had a stuffed animal attached to the top holding up a torch, sort of like a furry statue of liberty. It was the kind of hat usually worn only at political conventions -LRB- last week's featured such beauties as <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION>'s cheese hats -RRB- But <PERSON> Tullio </PERSON> has been ailing and could n't make it to <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>. So he obviously figured that having the party's new nominee in town was a great time to show it off. But when he brought it out on the stage, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> made no move to touch it, looking at it as if the furry thing might bite. Finally, <PERSON> Tullio </PERSON> balanced it on his own head, the crowd cheered with approval, and <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> smiled.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>___</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 One of the most exciting moments for reporters covering the <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> campaign swing came Friday when the press plane, landing in <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION>, slammed into the runway, bounced up, and then several seconds later landed again. The Secret Service, which had several of its agents on the plane, called for an inspection and on Saturday it appeared the plane would be pulled out of service. However, repairs were completed on time and the press plane continued to follow <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> and running mate <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> to <LOCATION> Minot </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.D. </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Louis </LOCATION>, and Erie, <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION>. After Erie, <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> and wife B.A boarded the press charter flight back to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, instead of continuing to <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> with <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>. `` I've heard about this plane,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> said. `` I did n't want to get on this one until we tested it with you guys,'' the senator quipped. Meanwhile, as the campaign moves into full swing, there are tentative plans for <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> to take over <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> 737 and for the governor to charter a larger plane. <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> will be inheriting a plane that once was Republican <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>'s campaign jet. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> had the <ORGANIZATION> Presidential </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airways </ORGANIZATION> plane's exterior spruced up and its interior redone with a little office up front separated by a curtain from the press and federal agents in the back
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880725-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-25-88 0139EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Poll-SpaceProgram Bjt   07-25 0703</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Poll-Space Program, Bjt,0716</SECOND>
<HEAD>Poll: Challenger Cost NASA Much Public Confidence</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserGraphic NY4</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GARY LANGER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Americans overwhelmingly favor maintaining or increasing the federal budget for space exploration, even while three in 10 doubt <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION>'s competence, a <ORGANIZATION> Media </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> General-Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> poll has found. The national survey of 1,223 adults found that nearly half those questioned lost confidence in the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aeronautics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Space </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> after the space shuttle Challenger exploded in January 1986, and 60 percent of those, or 28 percent of all questioned, say they still lack faith in the agency. However, 40 percent of the respondents said the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> was doing too little in space exploration, and majorities supported the initiatives of building a space station and sending manned flights to <LOCATION> Mars </LOCATION>. The space shuttle program also won support, with 40 percent saying it should be expanded and as many saying it should be maintained. The first shuttle flight since the Challenger disaster is scheduled for September, although a leak in a gas line is threatening to delay it. <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> was rated positively overall. Fifty-five percent said the agency has done a good or excellent job, while 37 percent rated it only fair or poor. Only 18 percent said the space budget should be decreased, while almost half said <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION>'s budget should remain the same and 30 percent said it should be increased. Of those who favored an increase, 74 percent said they would be willing to pay higher taxes to accomplish it. The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> this month approved $ 200 million for <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION>'s space station program, only enough to phase it out or put it on hold. The <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> approved $ 700 million, and a joint committee is to resolve the issue. Fear of falling behind in space may be one reason for the public's support for <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION>'s funding. Just 23 percent of respondents said the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> is ahead of the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> in space exploration, while the remainder were split on whether the Soviets are ahead or the two countries are about even. In any case, a plurality of respondents favored superpower cooperation in space: 49 percent favored last month's proposal by the Soviets for a U.S.-Soviet joint effort to send astronauts to <LOCATION> Mars </LOCATION>. Fifteen percent said the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> should work alone to reach Mars. Together, 64 percent favored some program to land astronauts on Mars, while 30 percent were opposed. The rest had no opinion. Support for a space station was nearly as high, with 55 percent in favor and 34 percent opposed. The rest had no opinion. On the space shuttle, 40 percent said work should be expanded and the same number said it should be kept at the same level. Fewer than a fifth said the shuttle program should be cut back. The poll found a striking split between the sexes, with men far more likely than women to favor space programs. Fifty-six percent of men said the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> was doing too little in space exploration; only a quarter of women agreed. Forty-one percent of men supported increasing the space exploration budget, compared with just 19 percent of women. Overall, 40 percent of respondents said the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> was doing too little in exploring space and 36 percent said it was doing about enough. Nearly a fifth said the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> was doing too much in space exploration, the remainder had no opinion. <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> created the <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> 30 years ago to pursue civilian exploration of space. In recent years, the agency increasingly has carried military payloads as well. A slim plurality in the survey opposed that development: 48 percent said <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> should be involved in non-military projects only, while 41 percent approved including military work. The split was narrowly outside the poll's margin of error of plus or minus 3 percentage points. The Media General-AP poll consisted of telephone interviews June 22-July 2 with a randomly selected sample of 1,223 adults across the nation. <ORGANIZATION> Media </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, a communications company based in <LOCATION> Richmond </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, publishes the Richmond Times-Dispatch, the Richmond News Leader, the Tampa -LRB- <LOCATION> Fla </LOCATION> -RRB-. Tribune and the <LOCATION> Winston-Salem </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> N.C. </LOCATION> -RRB- Journal, and operates TV stations <ORGANIZATION> WXFL </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Tampa </LOCATION>, WCBD in <LOCATION> Charleston </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> S.C. </LOCATION>, and <ORGANIZATION> WJKS </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Jacksonville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880725-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-25-88 0145EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Karabakh-Glance     07-25 0394</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Karabakh-Glance,0411</SECOND>
<HEAD>Karabakh at a Glance</HEAD>
<BYLINE>With PM-Soviet-Dispute
^By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are some facts and figures on <LOCATION> Nagorno-Karabakh </LOCATION>, the region at the heart of an ethnic dispute between Armenians and Azerbaijanis:
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 GEOGRAPHY _ Located in the <LOCATION> Caucasus </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mountains </LOCATION> in the southern <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> north of <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Nagorno-Karabakh </LOCATION>'s area is 1,760 square miles, slightly smaller than <LOCATION> Delaware </LOCATION>. It is surrounded by <LOCATION> Azerbaijani </LOCATION> territory and has no border with <LOCATION> Armenia </LOCATION>. Its two main cities are <LOCATION> Stepanakert </LOCATION>, the region's administrative center, and <PERSON> Shusha </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 ECONOMY _ A largely agricultural region with fields of cotton, grapes, wheat and rye, it has extensive dairy and meat production. Industries produce construction materials, furniture and electrical supplies. Its communications and transport links are mostly with <LOCATION> Azerbaijan </LOCATION>, not <LOCATION> Armenia </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 POLITICAL STATUS _ The region is officially known as the <LOCATION> Nagorno-Karabakh </LOCATION> Autonomous Region of <LOCATION> Azerbaijan </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 POPULATION _ The 1979 Soviet census put <LOCATION> Nagorno-Karabakh </LOCATION>'s population at 162,000, of which 76 percent were ethnic Armenians and 23 percent ethnic Azerbaijanis More than half the region's people live in rural areas
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 HISTORY _ <LOCATION> Nagorno-Karabakh </LOCATION>, one of the earliest areas settled in what is now the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, was part of a region called Artsakh in the year 1. In Soviet times, according to some reports, the area was assigned to <LOCATION> Armenia </LOCATION> under an agreement signed in December 1920 but not put into effect. In 1923, the <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION> made the region part of <LOCATION> Azerbaijan </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 GOAL OF THE ANNEXATION MOVEMENT _ Armenians, who are mostly Christians, complain of cultural and social discrimination under Azerbaijani rule. Most Azerbaijanis are Moslem. Armenians began campaigning in February for <LOCATION> Nagorno-Karabakh </LOCATION> to be annexed to <LOCATION> Armenia </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 TACTICS _ Armenians have held general strikes and mass demonstrations to press their demand. The legislature of <LOCATION> Nagorno-Karabakh </LOCATION> requested secession from <LOCATION> Azerbaijan </LOCATION> and annexation to <LOCATION> Armenia </LOCATION>. The legislature of the Armenian republic agreed to the request, but the <LOCATION> Azerbaijani </LOCATION> leadership refused to give its consent.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 THE <ORGANIZATION> KREMLIN </ORGANIZATION>'S RESPONSE _ The Presidium of the Supreme Soviet, the nation's highest legislative body, rejected the annexation demand and instead approved a package of remedial measures to improve cultural and social conditions in <LOCATION> Nagorno-Karabakh </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 EFFECTS _ The strikes have caused millions of rubles in lost production. The dispute led to violence Feb. 28 in the <LOCATION> Azerbaijani </LOCATION> city of <LOCATION> Sumgait </LOCATION>, where 32 people, including 26 Armenians, were killed in a riot.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880725-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-25-88 0153EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-StripMining     07-25 0583</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Strip Mining,590</SECOND>
<HEAD>Panel Abandons Idea of Taking Mine Inspectors Out of Interior
Department</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GUY DARST</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> subcommittee has quietly given up the idea of transferring strip mine regulators out of the <ORGANIZATION> Interior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>. Leaders of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> subcommittee on environment, energy and natural resources of the <ORGANIZATION> Government </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Operations </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, long critical of the department's Office of Surface Mining, made the decision earlier this month after a discouraging report from the <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Accounting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>' research arm, said such a move `` could disrupt and destabilize the program for two or more years'' and would not necessarily mean improvements. Rep. <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Synar </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Okla </LOCATION>., the subcommittee chairman, and Rep. <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Clinger </PERSON>, R-Pa., wrote other members that in light of the report, `` we think that a transfer at this time is not the way to solve the existing problems The letter, provided last week by subcommittee aides, said no members had expressed disagreement with the conclusion. `` We plan to urge that the incoming administration, whether <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> or Democratic, give top priority to making the fundamental changes necessary,'' <PERSON> Synar </PERSON> and <PERSON> Clinger </PERSON> said. A year ago <PERSON> Synar </PERSON> asked <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION> to investigate transferring the <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Surface </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mining </ORGANIZATION> to some other agency. He first raised the idea two years ago following a subcommittee report that documented difficulties the office had in getting states to enforce their own regulations and in collecting fine and penalties. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Duffus </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION> associate director, said in a report dated June 9 that only one of 16 people consulted from environmental groups, the coal industry and state governments favored moving the office out of interior. `` After 10 years of struggle to implement -LRB- the act -RRB-, stability is needed,'' was the consensus. The dissenter, <PERSON> Hope </PERSON> <PERSON> Babcock </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Audubon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION>, argued that `` moving this function would eliminate the institutional conflict that exists at interior between developing mineral resources and protecting the environment and would send a clear signal to the receiving agency that it should given additional attention'' to the mission of the office, <ORGANIZATION> Duffus </ORGANIZATION> reported. <PERSON> Babcock </PERSON> said in the report that the <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> should take over the regulatory role `` because of its experience with water pollution and runoff, water expertise and good reputation as a regulatory agency, and experience dealing with citizens' concerns and involvement in pollution problems.'' Another view came from former Deputy Undersecretary of Interior <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Quarles </PERSON>, now a staff member at the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sciences </ORGANIZATION>, who suggested grouping all of interior's regulatory programs under one assistant secretary. He said the mining industry did not believe <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> would `` provide a proper balance between -LRB- the act's -RRB- stated goals of energy production and environmental protection.'' `` We have also reported problems in <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION>'s management with respect to cleaning up hazardous waste and enforcing air standards,'' the report said. The <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION> also said there would be a long period of adjustment to any change. `` Substantial problems during initial periods of reorganization are inevitable,'' such as `` delays in obtaining key agency officials, inadequate staffing, insufficient funding, inadequate office space and difficulties in establishing support functions such as payroll and accounting systems,'' the report said. `` We found that solving these start-up problems resulted in delays ranging from nine to 30 months and distracted agency officials from concentrating on their new missions during the critical first year of operations,'' <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION> said. <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Cole </PERSON>, spokesman for the Office of Surface Mining, said, `` We agree that it would be counterproductive to transfer the -LRB- office -RRB- to another agency.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880725-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-25-88 0158EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Cambodia Bjt   07-25 0660</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Cambodia, Bjt,0681</SECOND>
<HEAD>Rivals Parley For Future Of Cambodia</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto BOGOR2</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PETER ENG</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BOGOR, Indonesia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Sitting stiffly and avoiding eye contact, the leaders of four groups fighting for <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION> began their first talks today to try to fashion a political settlement. Their host, <LOCATION> Indonesian </LOCATION> Foreign Minister <PERSON> Ali </PERSON> <PERSON> Alatas </PERSON>, said they would discuss such difficult issues as national reconciliation, forming a provisional government and building a neutral <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION>, which has been at war almost continuously since 1970. `` We of course realize that on these aspects ... there are divergences of views among you and that many years of conflict and contention have caused estrangment that may impede a quick convergence of positions,'' he said in an opening speech. <PERSON> Alatas </PERSON> said such a complex problem could n't be solved through a single meeting, but a solution will never be found unless a start is made to replace war with dialogue. The four Cambodian leaders gathered in a chandeliered room in the old palace of the late President <PERSON> Sukarno </PERSON> for informal `` cocktail party'' talks that have raised hopes for peace in <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION>. In large easy chairs around a thick, circular table sat <PERSON> Hun </PERSON> <PERSON> Sen </PERSON>, prime minister of <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION>'s Vietnamese-installed government, and leaders of three guerrilla groups opposing him. They were <PERSON> Khieu </PERSON> <PERSON> Samphan </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Son </PERSON> <PERSON> Sann </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION>, and Prince <PERSON> Norodom </PERSON> <PERSON> Ranariddh </PERSON>, who is representing his father, Prince <PERSON> Norodom </PERSON> <PERSON> Sihanouk </PERSON>. As they gathered, three saffron-robed <ORGANIZATION> Cambodian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Buddhist </ORGANIZATION> monks who had traveled from the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> filed into the palace to pray for success. <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>, which invaded <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION> in late 1978 and by Western count maintains more than 100,000 troops there, was to meet the Cambodians in a second stage of talks in the afternoon. That meeting was also to be attended by <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>'s Communist ally, <LOCATION> Laos </LOCATION>, and by members of the <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Southeast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Asian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION>, which backs the guerrillas. At a photo session just before the morning talks, the leaders smiled at photographers and <PERSON> Khieu </PERSON> <PERSON> Samphan </PERSON> waved, but they studiously avoided making eye contact with one another. Instead they gazed at huge Western-style oil paintings on the walls. <PERSON> Hun </PERSON> <PERSON> Senn </PERSON> and <PERSON> Sihanouk </PERSON> have held two previous rounds of talks without success, and the current meeting represents the first gathering of all four <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION> parties. <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> has never talked with the <LOCATION> Cambodian </LOCATION> resistance factions. <PERSON> Sihanouk </PERSON>, meanwhile, was visiting <LOCATION> Jakarta </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> Indonesian </LOCATION> capital just 40 miles from <LOCATION> Bogor </LOCATION> but had no known plans to attend the talks. A Indonesian source said the former <LOCATION> Cambodian </LOCATION> monarch might make an appearance in <LOCATION> Bogor </LOCATION>, depending on progress in the talks. Earlier this month <PERSON> Sihanouk </PERSON> resigned as president of the guerrilla coalition, charging the <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION> were killing his men. The tentative schedule called for two days of talks with the second day having the same format as the first _ the <LOCATION> Cambodian </LOCATION> factions talking in the morning, then the Vietnamese and others joining in the afternoon. The talks are based on a July 1987 <LOCATION> Vietnam-Indonesia </LOCATION> agreement that calls for informal discussions to encourage the various antagonists to participate and allay <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>'s refusal to negotiate directly with the guerrillas. Disputes between <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Southeast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Asian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> delayed the talks, which were not confirmed until the last minute. The association includes the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Thailand </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Brunei </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Malaysia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Singapore </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Indonesia </LOCATION>. Since 1970, <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION> has suffered a devastating five-year civil war, a reign of terror by the Chinese-backed <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION> from 1975 to 1978, a 1978 Vietnamese invasion and a continuing guerrilla war against the Vietnamese-backed government. Millions of people have been killed in the turmoil. <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> has announced it will withdraw 50,000 troops, or about half its force in <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION>, this year and the rest by early 1990. Though Son <PERSON> Sann </PERSON> and <PERSON> Sihanouk </PERSON> are allied with the <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION> in a resistance coalition, they strongly distrust the <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION> because it killed hundreds of thousands of people when it ruled <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880725-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-25-88 0204EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lites     07-25 0581</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lites,0605</SECOND>
<HEAD>On The Light Side</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CASTLE SHANNON, Pa. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
