<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880723-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-23-88 0214EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-BRF--WindsurferArrested     07-23 0167</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Windsurfer Arrested,0171</SECOND>
<HEAD>Woman Arrested For Fleeing Marine Patrol On Sailboard</HEAD>
<DATELINE>STUART, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A 54-year-old windsurfer was arrested and booked into jail in a wet bathing suit after she allegedly tried to use her board to make a getaway from a <ORGANIZATION> Florida </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Patrol </ORGANIZATION> officer. <PERSON> Jean </PERSON> <PERSON> Felicia </PERSON> <PERSON> Kuznar </PERSON>, of <LOCATION> Jensen </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION>, was charged with careless operation of a vessel, interfering with navigation, resisting arrest without violence, and fleeing and eluding law officers. Her problems with Officer <PERSON> Leslie </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> began when Mrs. <PERSON> Kuznar </PERSON> was windsurfing Wednesday near the <PERSON> Stuart </PERSON> <PERSON> Causeway </PERSON> and a powerboat entered the channel. Ms. <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> said the powerboat had to `` take evasive action to avoid an accident,'' so she approached Mrs. <PERSON> Kuznar </PERSON> in her patrol boat to discuss the matter. Ms. <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> said Mrs. <PERSON> Kuznar </PERSON> refused orders that she bring her windsurfer to shore and `` told me to get lost.'' Mrs. <PERSON> Kuznar </PERSON> said she was trying to get to shore, and complained that the officer swamped her with the patrol boat's wake.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880723-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-23-88 0246EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-BRF--McKinleyRecord     07-23 0161</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--McKinley Record,0165</SECOND>
<HEAD>Connecticut Lawyer Sets McKinley Record</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ANCHORAGE, Alaska (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A 71-year-old lawyer has become the oldest climber on record to reach the summit of <LOCATION> Mount </LOCATION> <LOCATION> McKinley </LOCATION>, the highest peak in <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Park </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> said. <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Middlebury </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Conn. </LOCATION>, reached the top of the 20,320-foot peak Sunday in an unusually fast eight days from <PERSON> Kahiltna </PERSON> <PERSON> Glacier </PERSON>, at <PERSON> McKinley </PERSON>'s 7,000-foot level, rangers said Friday. Records show the oldest climber prior to <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> was 68. <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> said he learned of the potential for a mountaineering milestone when he checked in with rangers before the climb. `` So I said, ` Thank you very much,''' <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> climbed </PERSON> <PERSON> McKinley </PERSON> with a guide, <PERSON> Marty </PERSON> <PERSON> Schmidt </PERSON>, and another mountaineer, <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Landry </PERSON>, 24, who suffered altitude sickness and did n't reach the summit until Monday. The three returned to <PERSON> Kahiltna </PERSON> <PERSON> Glacier </PERSON>, and on Wednesday, they flew back to <LOCATION> Anchorage </LOCATION>. `` I found it extremely arduous above 14,000 feet,'' <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> said. `` It's heavy work.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880723-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-23-88 0022EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Japan-Markets     07-23 0244</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Japan-Markets,0252</SECOND>
<HEAD>Nikkei Rises Slightly After Worst Trading Week This Year</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The main market barometer recouped early losses by the close of half-day trading Saturday, but still finished lower at the end of its worst trading week so far this year. The Nikkei Stock Average of 225 selected issues, a sharp 391.13-point loser Friday, lost nearly 80 points shortly after trading started, but claimed back lost ground to close the day at 27,301.34 points, up 16.33 points, or 0.059 percent. `` The index moved up mainly on profit-taking,'' said <PERSON> Michio </PERSON> <PERSON> Katsumata </PERSON>, a spokesman for <ORGANIZATION> Nomura </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Securities </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s largest brokerage. `` <ORGANIZATION> Hitachi </ORGANIZATION> and IC-related companies moved higher up,'' but otherwise `` the market was very quiet,'' the spokesman added. Shares from <ORGANIZATION> Sony </ORGANIZATION>, a leading consumer electronics maker, closed at a historic high 6,460 yen, up 430 yen, surpassing its previous record close reached Friday. Volume on the first section during the half-day session totaled 600 million shares. Despite Saturday's slight gain, the <ORGANIZATION> Nikkei </ORGANIZATION> index closed the week down 612.45 points, or 2.19 percent, from a 27,913.79-point close July 15. It had lost 513.09 points during Tuesday trading alone. `` People are anxious about higher interest rates,'' said <PERSON> Katsumata </PERSON>. Banks in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> have all raised their rates, `` but only <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> is sticking to a lower rate,'' he added. The market next week will just move `` up and down, up and down,'' the spokesman predicted. The foreign exchange market is closed on Saturdays.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880723-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-23-88 0050EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-SwaggartCrusade 2ndLd-Writethru a0831 07-23 0783</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Swaggart Crusade, 2nd Ld - Writethru, a0831,0802</SECOND>
<HEAD>Swaggart Holds First Crusade Outside Louisiana Since Scandal</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Recasts 1st graf and subs 9th graf ``We set' with 8 grafs to
UPDATE with crowd size, color, quotes and protesters. Picks up 10th
graf pvs `Swaggart said...'</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By BETH HARRIS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>INDIANAPOLIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Evangelist <PERSON> Jimmy </PERSON> <PERSON> Swaggart </PERSON> received a standing ovation from about 2,500 followers Friday at his first crusade outside his home state of <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION> since he was defrocked amid reports he had hired a prostitute. The three days of revival meetings were not supported by the national or local offices of the Assemblies of God, <PERSON> Swaggart </PERSON>'s former denomination But crowds lined up at the door and sales of <PERSON> Swaggart </PERSON>'s albums and tapes were brisk. `` I'm forgiving to him. He's not exempt from sin or temptation,'' said <PERSON> Etta </PERSON> <PERSON> Mae </PERSON> <PERSON> Martin </PERSON>, 57, of <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mo. </LOCATION>, who arrived with her husband two hours before the arena doors opened to grab front-row seats. She said <PERSON> Swaggart </PERSON> should put his troubles behind him and get on with his life. `` I wanted to show that men make mistakes, and he's forgiven,'' said <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Randle </PERSON>, 24, of <LOCATION> Indianapolis </LOCATION>. `` Since he told the truth, everyone wants to get on him.'' In February, <PERSON> Swaggart </PERSON> tearfully confessed on television that he had committed an unspecified sin against <PERSON> God </PERSON> and his family. The confession was followed by allegations that he had hired a prostitute to perform lewd acts while he watched. Assemblies of God pastors were told `` not to be supportive or cooperative with <PERSON> Jimmy </PERSON> <PERSON> Swaggart </PERSON> Ministries any longer,'' said the Rev. <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Shank </PERSON>, district superintendent of the nation's largest Pentecostal denomination. `` He has been disciplined by the church and is n't part of our fellowship.'' Nevertheless, organizers planned for at least 8,000 followers, including Assemblies of God members, to attend the crusade each night. As the band struck up an upbeat religious song, <PERSON> Swaggart </PERSON> and his wife, <PERSON> Frances </PERSON>, kneeled to greet the outstretched hands of members of the audience who walked up to the stage. `` I thank you for your kindness and your love,'' <PERSON> Swaggart </PERSON> said. `` I thank you for literally opposing every force of darkness and saying, ` We love you.''' `` It's such a thrill to be here. We love you more than we can express,'' <PERSON> Frances </PERSON> <PERSON> Swaggart </PERSON> told the crowd. <PERSON> Swaggart </PERSON>, singing and playing the piano, appeared in good humor as he kidded his wife about her fervent address to the audience. `` She's always complaining about those women creatures throwing their hands up. I'm going to show her that on television in a few weeks, and we'll see.'' The crusade is being videotaped for the relatively few television stations that have not canceled <PERSON> Swaggart </PERSON>'s program. <PERSON> Swaggart </PERSON> did n't refer directly to his troubles Friday night, but he urged the audience to write checks or give cash totaling $ 100 or more to save his television ministry. `` We desperately, desperately need that help,'' he said. `` I do not ask it for me, I ask it for souls.'' Outside the 17,000-seat downtown Market Square Arena, a handful of protesters carried signs reading, `` Ban the Bible'' and `` Ban Christianity.'' <PERSON> Swaggart </PERSON> said he viewed the crusade in <LOCATION> Indianapolis </LOCATION> as a fresh start. `` I've changed an awful lot,'' he said after a dress rehearsal. `` I'm more keenly aware of the hurt and pain of other people. I'm more aware of their weaknesses and despair. <PERSON> Swaggart </PERSON> returned to the pulpit May 22, but was defrocked by the Assemblies of God for refusing to abstain from preaching for a year while undergoing professional counseling. <PERSON> Swaggart </PERSON>, 52, said his multimillion-dollar global ministry could not survive such an absence. <PERSON> Jozette </PERSON> <PERSON> Ausbury </PERSON>, a spokeswoman for the Assemblies of God in its <LOCATION> Springfield </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mo. </LOCATION>, headquarters said members could not be punished for attending the crusade. `` They can go if they want to. That's fine,'' she said. The church had not decided whether ministers who attend the crusade could be punished. The church has not ruled what sanctions it would apply to local ministers who might help the crusade, but it has given ministers at <ORGANIZATION> Jimmy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Swaggart </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministries </ORGANIZATION> until Oct. 1 to leave or be defrocked. No local Assemblies of God ministers are known to be assisting the crusade. <PERSON> Baldock </PERSON>, who heads the <ORGANIZATION> Compassion </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>, Mission on Wheels and Ark of the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Covenant </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION>, recruited about 300 volunteers to serve as ushers, security guards and support staff. `` I preach just like most of my brothers preach _ forgiveness, love and mercy, restoration,'' <PERSON> Baldock </PERSON> said. `` That's not only with Reverend <PERSON> Swaggart </PERSON>. That's with anyone accepting the message of <PERSON> Jesus </PERSON> <PERSON> Christ </PERSON> that has a problem. And because I'm forgiven. `` The scriptures teach us that if we expect to be forgiven we must forgive ourselves.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880723-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-23-88 0052EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-Fires-Prisoners 1stLd-Writethru a0770 07-23 0656</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Fires-Prisoners, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0770,0670</SECOND>
<HEAD>Inmates Bolster Firefighting Forces</HEAD>
<HEAD>Retransmitting to add writethru designation</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: SUBS grafs 3-4, `Rojas was...', to UPDATE with reward
offered, state of emergency declared, and to put fire acreage at
nearly 11,000, sted more than 12,500, reflecting official change
downward</NOTE>
<HEAD>With AM-Forest Fire Rdp</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By STEVE GEISSINGER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>RAIL ROAD FLAT, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 They live by a brutal code of each man for himself in prison, but in the middle of the woods they learn to stand together against a fiery enemy that is not affected by their crimes, color or gangs. `` We ca n't bring our problems with us to the fire lines,'' said <PERSON> Rafael </PERSON> <PERSON> Rojas </PERSON>, 20, of <PERSON> Hollister </PERSON>, who is serving time in the <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> Youth Authority for burglary. <PERSON> Rojas </PERSON> was among hundreds of state prisoners battling a pair of arson-linked wildfires in heavy timber and brush near the <LOCATION> Calaveras </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> town of <LOCATION> Rail </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Road </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Flat </LOCATION>, 150 miles east of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION>. Gov. <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Deukmejian </PERSON> on Friday offered a $ 10,000 reward for the capture of the arsonist and declared a state of emergency in the county. Nearly 11,000 acres and six homes had been charred by Friday as firefighters neared containment of the blazes, which have caused an estimated $ 3.8 million damage to the drought-parched region since Tuesday. Wielding shovels, saws and other hand tools, state fire Capt. <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Segura </PERSON>'s strike team of inmates stood guard Thursday when the fire burned out to a section of the more than 18 miles of bare-earth control lines that firefighters had carved around the fires. `` Let it burn right to the edge,'' <PERSON> Segura </PERSON> bellowed at the inmates, clad in orange jumpsuits. Some of the inmates had to use ladders off a nearby state pumper truck to climb up the near-vertical mountain toward the advancing flames. Within minutes, he told his crew from the <ORGANIZATION> DeWitt </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nelson </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> CYA </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Camp </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Stockton </LOCATION> that it seemed the line would hold for the time being. A few of the inmates slid down the slope hand over hand on a fire hose. Others descended on the ladder. Hours after being dumped off from a stifling personnel truck, it was finally break time. `` This is better than being behind walls,'' <PERSON> Rojas </PERSON> said in an idle moment. Added team member <PERSON> Stevie </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>: `` Every time they ask, ` You want to go on a fire?' everybody stands up and says ` Yeah.''' <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>, 19, of <LOCATION> Vallejo </LOCATION>, is serving a sentence for possession of cocaine. Inmates in the <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Youth </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Authority </LOCATION> or state prison systems can volunteer to train as firefighters, but candidates are screened to determine that they are suited and that they are low security risks. Supervisors are unarmed, but even so there are very few escape attempts. Correctional officer <PERSON> Alex </PERSON> <PERSON> Castillo </PERSON>, supervising state prisoners in line for food at the Rail Road Flat fire camp after coming off the lines, said most of the inmate firefighters are proud of what they do. `` They like getting outside and later you hear them say things like ` Hey, we saved a house there,''' <PERSON> Castillo </PERSON> said. Added prisoner <PERSON> Myron </PERSON> <PERSON> Bright </PERSON>, with a sincere expression on his face: `` It's a good way to pay my debt to society.'' Bright, 36, who is serving time for insurance fraud, works out of the <LOCATION> Green </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION> camp near Folsom Prison. <PERSON> Castillo </PERSON> said he and other crew supervisors make allowances because of the nature of the work. `` If you're out there for more than a week at a time, they get antsy. If you're real strict, they wo n't respond in a good way, and you do n't need tension on a fire,'' he said. The inmates said they realize the work is dangerous, but trust the supervisors to keep them alive. One prisoner said the work has changed the direction of his life. `` I'd like to become a professional firefighter,'' said <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>. `` The first week I get out, I'm going to put in an application somewhere.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880723-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-23-88 0053EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-FoodPoisoning     07-23 0160</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Food Poisoning,0162</SECOND>
<HEAD>Contaminated Hose Blamed For Academy Food-Poisoning</HEAD>
<DATELINE>AIR FORCE ACADEMY, Colo. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A contaminated water hose in the kitchen of the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION>'s cadet dining hall apparently caused the outbreak of food poisoning that affected 673 people, academy officials said Friday. Officials said a floor drain had backed up in the kitchen of <ORGANIZATION> Mitchell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hall </ORGANIZATION> on July 12, and the hose was placed in the drain in an effort to clear it. The hose then was used to rinse celery that was put in the chicken salad served at lunch that day. Bacteriological tests shows the hose was contaminated with E. coli bacteria. Tests were still being conducted on the food to confirm that the bacteria in the hose caused the outbreak of gastroenteritis. Academy officials said they planned to have civil engineers examine the 30-year-old drain system. They also said they planned to review kitchen procedures, including how food handlers are trained and supervised.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880723-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-23-88 0231EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-BiologicalWarfare Bjt   07-23 0735</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Biological Warfare, Bjt,750</SECOND>
<HEAD>Scientists Say Pentagon Starting Dangerous Germ Warfare Research</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PAUL RECER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Science Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A group called the <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Responsible </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Genetics </ORGANIZATION> has announced a campaign to persuade university biologists to turn aside <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> requests for additional research into germ warfare. At a news conference Friday, four scientists on the committee said the Pentagon is asking for $ 300 million to conduct research into biological warfare techniques and the researchers said this work could lead to the development of weapons for a war nobody could win. <PERSON> Christin </PERSON> <PERSON> Anfinsen </PERSON>, a Nobel Prize-winning biologist at <ORGANIZATION> Johns </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hopkins </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, said biotechnology has advanced so rapidly that `` the production of biological weapons is relatively simple.'' `` We could develop warheads to spread anthrax -LRB- disease -RRB- within six months and so could the Soviets,'' said <PERSON> Anfinsen </PERSON>. No nation, he said, could win a war with biological weapons because a counterattack would be swift and deadly. Army Lt. Col. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Chapla </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> spokesman, confirmed that the military is seeking funds to conduct biological research, but he said the effort is aimed at developing a defense against germ weapons, not at making the weapons themselves. <PERSON> Chapla </PERSON> said a hearing will be held Monday on the environmental impact of a planned $ 5.4 million biological aerosol test facility at the Dugway Proving Ground in <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION>. In a telephone interview, <PERSON> Chapla </PERSON> said the <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> has let more than 100 biological research contracts to private research groups. The <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>, he said, plans to research defensive measures, such as protective clothing, and detection and decontamination equipment. He said <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> researchers also will attempt to develop vaccines that would protect against germ warfare agents. But he said none of this work was aimed at producing weapons. <PERSON> Chapla </PERSON> also said that for germs to be used as weapons, the Army would have to develop a delivery system, a way to manufacture the germs, and a doctrine for the use of such weapons. He said no work is being done in any of these areas. At the scientists' news conference, <PERSON> Jonathan </PERSON> <PERSON> King </PERSON>, a professor of biology at the <ORGANIZATION> Massachusetts </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Technology </ORGANIZATION>, said the same techniques needed to develop a defense against biological weapons can be used to develop the weapons themselves. `` In an offensive biological warfare program, the first thing you do is develop a vaccine to protect your own troops,'' he said. King also said the most serious danger of biological weapons is that they could lead to uncontrolled contamination of vast populations if they are released. `` Biological weapons are not like gunpowder or nuclear bombs,'' he said. `` Biological agents can spread and reproduce.'' <PERSON> Anfinsen </PERSON> said new laboratory techniques, in which the genetic pattern of bacteria and viruses can be changed, makes a defense unlikely against germ weapons. `` Since you can make any number of variables, the defense against them is impossible,'' he said. `` The inability to defend against such an attack is universal.'' <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Novick </PERSON>, director of the <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION>, said biological weapons are `` neither a threat nor a deterrent'' for major powers because all the technically advanced nations can equally develop such weapons. What he fears instead, <PERSON> Novick </PERSON> said, is that the germ weapons developed by the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> could be used secretly to assert American will in small countries. King and <PERSON> Novick </PERSON> said the Pentagon is actively recruiting biologists to conduct germ warfare research. `` I have been approached and most of us have,'' <PERSON> King </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Jane </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Koretz </PERSON>, a researcher at <ORGANIZATION> Rensselaer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Polytechnic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION>, said advances in genetic engineering are `` a two-edged sword.'' `` It can be used to improve the quality of human life or it can be used for its destruction,'' she said. Using the new biological techniques to develop weapons, Ms. <PERSON> Koretz </PERSON> said, would be `` a perversion'' of the reasons that most scientists conduct the research. She said genetic manipulation techniques could be used to develop a germ or virus that could spread like small pox. `` You can understand why we are so horrified,'' she said. The <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Responsible </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Genetics </ORGANIZATION> is circulating a petition among university biologists that contains a pledge not to engage knowingly in research that would further develop biological warfare agents. A day before the news conference, <PERSON> Kathleen </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bailey </PERSON>, assistant director of the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Arms </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Control </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Disarmament </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> the </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, announced that the government believes there now are at least 10 countries conducting research into biological weapons.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880723-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-23-88 0058EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-UN-Iran-Iraq Bjt   07-23 0754</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-UN-Iran-Iraq, Bjt,0778</SECOND>
<HEAD>Iran And Iraq Agree To Peace Talks At U.N.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By VICTORIA GRAHAM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>UNITED NATIONS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> agreed to hold crucial peace talks with the secretary-general early next week on a cease-fire and a political settlement to end their eight-year war. A <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> cease-fire team planned to leave for <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> this weekend after <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> finally agreed Friday to accept it. <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> agreed earlier to welcome the mission. <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> formally protested <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>'s latest ground offensive and said <LOCATION> Iraqi </LOCATION> chemical warfare attacks had killed dozens and injured hundreds. On Monday, <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> finally accepted Resolution 598, the <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>'s year-old plan to end the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> war. <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> accepted it earlier. Iranian Foreign Minister <PERSON> Ali-Akbar </PERSON> <PERSON> Velayati </PERSON> and his <LOCATION> Iraqi </LOCATION> counterpart <PERSON> Tariz </PERSON> <PERSON> Aziz </PERSON> agreed to hold separate, intensive talks in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> with Secretary-General <PERSON> Javier </PERSON> <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Cuellar </PERSON> on implementing the plan. After more than a dozen rounds of fruitless <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> talks, this round will be the most crucial, diplomats said. <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Cuellar </PERSON> said Wednesday he hoped to have a cease-fire in a week or 10 days. It was not immediately known whether the belligerents would hold direct talks, as urged by <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>; whether they would hold proximity talks with Perez de Cuellar shuttling between delegations, or whether the talks would take place at different times. Iranian Ambassador <PERSON> Mohammad </PERSON> <PERSON> Ja'afar </PERSON> <PERSON> Mahallati </PERSON> told reporters that <PERSON> Velayati </PERSON> might agree to a face-to-face meeting with <PERSON> Aziz </PERSON>. Earlier in the week <PERSON> Mahallati </PERSON> rejected direct talks. `` <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> is ready to go along without any limitations whatsover in the implementation of Resolution 598 if the secretary general requires it,'' he said. <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Cuellar </PERSON> says he prefers direct talks, but diplomats said he was not likely to force the issue. <PERSON> Velayati </PERSON> is expected to be here Monday, and <PERSON> Aziz </PERSON> also is expected to arrive early next week. Previously, Iranian envoys from <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION> refused to be here while ranking <LOCATION> Iraqi </LOCATION> officials met the secretary-general. The decision by <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>, militarily battered and politically isolated, to accept a cease-fire was a surprise. <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>, after a string of battlefield victories, initially called <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'s move a trick and said it would accept a cease-fire only after direct talks with <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>. But <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> came under intense diplomatic pressure from many nations, including the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, its major arms supplier, and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, to come to terms quickly and agree to a cease-fire, said informed diplomatic sources who spoke on condition of anonymity. When the secretary-general agreed to call both envoys to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> agreed to allow the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> cease-fire mission to go to <LOCATION> Baghdad </LOCATION>. `` I am very optimistic now because the confusion and misunderstandings have been removed,'' said <PERSON> Ismat </PERSON> <PERSON> Kittani </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>'s ambassador to the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> `` The two foreign ministers will come and discuss with the secretary-general how to get the peace process going full-blast at the technical level and political level. <PERSON> Mahallati </PERSON> said the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> team will arrive in <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION> on Sunday. The team then planned to travel to <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> in its week-long mission before reporting back to the secretary-general. <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Cuellar </PERSON> said that after the team returns, he will be able to put Resolution 598 into motion by setting dates for a cease-fire, troop withdrawal, prisoner exchange and formal peace talks and establishing an impartial panel to decide which nation started the war. <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> has insisted that <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> must be branded the aggressor. Diplomats say <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> needs international condemnation of <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> to persuade Iranians to accept a cease-fire. But Resolution 598 is vague on a panel that would determine responsibility for the war, and diplomatic observers said they expected <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> to try to undercut that provision. <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> invaded <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> in September 1980 after several border skirmishes. The <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> technical team will include five officers from the U.N. Truce Supervision Organization based in <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION>, two <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> observers already in both <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Baghdad </LOCATION> and a civilian political officer. <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Cuellar </PERSON> said the cease-fire would be monitored by about 250 <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> observers. But he said funding would be a serious problem for a new <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> peacekeeping or observer force. `` Now that the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> is engaged in a very major operation, there soon will be a lack of financial stability and, in fact, almost bankruptcy of the organization,'' he said in a statement. `` This will impair very seriously these new operations.'' The <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> is facing a crisis of unpaid dues, largely because the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has not paid $ 467 million, or about two-thirds of the total owed to the world organization by its member states.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880723-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-23-88 0303EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-BudgetDeficit     07-23 0660</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Budget Deficit,690</SECOND>
<HEAD>Outlook Brighter for Reducing Federal Budget Deficit This Year</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVE SKIDMORE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Strong tax collections from businesses and individuals are brightening the outlook for reducing the federal budget deficit in 1988, with red ink for the fiscal year through June running 2 percent lower than 1987. The <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> on Friday reported a rare $ 9.5 billion surplus last month, trimming the gap between what the government has spent and what it has taken in during the first nine months of the fiscal year to $ 118 billion, $ 2.4 billion less than during the same period last year. If the deficit continued building at the same rate, it would total $ 147.4 billion when the fiscal year ends Sept. 30, down slightly from the $ 150.4 billion budget gap of last year and substantially below the $ 221.1 billion record high set in 1986. `` Right now it looks like the chances are pretty good that we can beat last year,'' said <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Lasky </PERSON>, an economist with <ORGANIZATION> Data </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Resources </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, a <LOCATION> Lexington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mass. </LOCATION>, forecasting firm. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> K. </PERSON> <PERSON> Evans </PERSON>, president of <ORGANIZATION> Evans </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Economics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, said higher-than-expected collection of individual income taxes in both May and June are making projections earlier this year by private economists of about a $ 160 billion deficit look pessimistic. Quarterly individual tax payments due in June totaled $ 46.2 billion, up 14.1 percent from the same month in 1987. In May, tax payments totaled $ 18 billion, nearly double the collections in May 1987. Corporate tax payments also rose, bolstered by strong profits of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> companies. They totaled $ 18.3 billion in June, 18.6 percent more than the same month a year ago. `` Nobody's really sure, including the <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION>, how this new tax reform law works. My view is that the law actually is collecting taxes that were going into tax shelters, which is what it's supposed to do In 1989, we'll see even more of this,'' <PERSON> Evans </PERSON> said. The major uncertainty remaining for this year, he said, is how much the government will have to spend to help drought-stricken farmers. Higher grain prices caused by drought-induced shortages could lower government price support payments, but special aid to farmers with shriveled crops could more than make up for that, he said. The <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> said federal spending last month totaled $ 89.9 billion, a 7.7 percent increase over June 1987. However, revenues surged a greater 19.8 percent above last year's level to $ 99.3 billion. It was only the third surplus posted since the fiscal year began in October. There was a surplus in January because Social Security checks for the month were mailed at the end of December and another in April as individual income tax payments poured in. For the first nine months, revenue totaled $ 681.1 billion, up 6.9 percent from last year, while spending was $ 799.1 billion, up 5.5 percent. The administration is forecasting a deficit of $ 146.7 billion, just slightly above the $ 144 billion target in the Gramm-Rudman budget balancing law. Next year's target is $ 136 billion. In June, the largest spending category was interest on the national debt, followed by the military, Social Security, and other programs in the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Human </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION>. Military spending totaled $ 24.6 billion last month and $ 213.3 billion for the fiscal year so far, up 3.9 percent from the same period a year ago. Spending for Social Security totaled $ 21.3 billion last month and $ 160.8 billion for the past nine months, up 5.6 percent from the same period in the 1987 fiscal year. The other programs in the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Human </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION>, including <ORGANIZATION> Medicare </ORGANIZATION> and Medicaid, spent $ 13.7 billion in June and $ 118.7 billion so far this budget year, a 6 percent increase over the first three quarters of fiscal 1987. Interest on the $ 2.5 trillion national debt totaled $ 31.6 billion last month and $ 169.1 billion so far this fiscal year, an increase of 10.2 percent over the same period last year.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880723-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-23-88 0229EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     07-23 0915</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0950</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names In The News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ROME (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON> says she could do without fame, but since she's got it she will put it to good use. `` My life is outside films ... my life is now working for AIDS,'' Miss <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON> said at a news conference Friday to promote <PERSON> Franco </PERSON> <PERSON> Zeffirelli </PERSON>'s new film, `` The Young <PERSON> Toscanini </PERSON>.'' `` I do n't really like being famous,'' she said. But in raising money to combat aquired immune deficiency syndrome, she said, `` I thought that using my fame could do some good.'' The film, set in 1880s <LOCATION> Rio </LOCATION> <LOCATION> de </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Janeiro </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION>, stars American <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Howell </PERSON> as the conductor as a young man and <PERSON> Sophie </PERSON> <PERSON> Ward </PERSON>, an Englishwoman, as his lover. Miss <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON>, 56, has a supporting role as an aging soprano, <PERSON> Nadina </PERSON> <PERSON> Bulicioff </PERSON>, inspired to return to singing by an 18-year-old <PERSON> Arturo </PERSON> <PERSON> Toscanini </PERSON>. <PERSON> Zeffirelli </PERSON> directed Miss <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON> and her then-husband <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Burton </PERSON> in `` The Taming of the Shrew.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>HYANNIS PORT, Mass. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> family members gathered at the clan's seaside homes here to celebrate the 98th birthday of matriarch <PERSON> Rose </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>. The family celebration began Friday with Mass and then moved to the compound for dinner. The party concluded with white cake with chocolate frosting, which Mrs. <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>'s daughter <PERSON> Jean </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> said is her mother's favorite. Mrs. <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>'s only living son, Sen. <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, D-Mass., flew to <LOCATION> Cape </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Cod </LOCATION> for the occasion as soon as the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Convention </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> concluded For her grandmother, <PERSON> Kara </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, the senator's daughter, picked 98 long-stemmed red roses from the Rose Kennedy Garden in <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> End </LOCATION>, where Mrs. <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> was born. Others at the dinner were Mrs. <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>'s daughter <PERSON> Eunice </PERSON> and son-in-law <PERSON> Sargent </PERSON> <PERSON> Shriver </PERSON>, daughters <PERSON> Patricia </PERSON> <PERSON> Lawford </PERSON> and Mrs. <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, daughter-in-law <PERSON> Ethel </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> and an assortment of grandchildren. Mrs. <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> suffered a stroke in 1984 and reportedly has been in poor health recently.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>FREEHOLD, N.J. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A trial involving a child custody battle between actor <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Toole </PERSON> and a <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> woman has ended, and the <ORGANIZATION> Superior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> judge who heard the case says he might issue a decision next week. The trial before Judge <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON> <PERSON> Lehrer </PERSON> was closed to reporters shortly after it began July 13. It ended Thursday. Five-year-old <PERSON> Lorcan </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Toole </PERSON> has been caught in a trans-Atlantic tussle between his father and <PERSON> Karen </PERSON> <PERSON> Somerville </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Toole </PERSON> since the couple separated in 1983. A <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> court gave the couple joint custody in an agreement lasting until September 1989. But both sides argued for a change in that agreement. In May, a judge in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> ordered <PERSON> O'Toole </PERSON> to return his son to Ms. <PERSON> Somerville </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Toole </PERSON> until the courts decide which parent should get permanent custody. Attorneys say <PERSON> O'Toole </PERSON> and Ms. <PERSON> Somerville </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Toole </PERSON> _ who was not married to the actor but took his name _ claim each violated the original custody agreement. Under it, each parent was to alternate custody every month until 1989, when they hoped to reach a long-term agreement. The Irish-born <PERSON> O'Toole </PERSON>, 55, met Ms. <PERSON> Somerville </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Toole </PERSON>, a 37-year-old former model, six years ago.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>Eds: A version of the following also moved on sports wires.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>MIAMI BEACH, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Five months after his infamous comments about black athletes, <PERSON> Jimmy </PERSON> `` The Greek'' <ORGANIZATION> Snyder </ORGANIZATION> is planning a comeback. In the Jan. 15 interview that got him fired, <PERSON> Snyder </PERSON> said blacks were bred to be better athletes, blacks dominate sports and if blacks become coaches there's not going to be anything left in athletics for whites. `` I did n't say anything derogatory about blacks,'' <PERSON> Snyder </PERSON> told The <ORGANIZATION> Miami </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Herald </ORGANIZATION> in an article published Friday. Since <ORGANIZATION> CBS-TV </ORGANIZATION> fired <PERSON> Snyder </PERSON> from his $ 750,000-a-year job as a pro football commentator, he has been living in a <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION> hotel, dieting and lounging on the beach. He's also been hospitalized twice for heart tests. `` I've been laying low, but you've got to come out sooner or later or retire,'' he said. <PERSON> Snyder </PERSON> has scheduled appearances on the <PERSON> Oprah </PERSON> <PERSON> Winfrey </PERSON> and <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> King </PERSON> television talk shows, plans to speak at black universities and wants to get back on television.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NASHVILLE, Tenn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A radio show that features the trio Riders in the Sky will be offered to more than 100 <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Radio </ORGANIZATION> affiliates beginning in October, the band's manager said. The trio, a Grand Ole Opry act, performs western music and comedy routines. The weekly show, `` Riders Radio Theater,'' will be taped at the <ORGANIZATION> Tennessee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Performing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Arts </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Nashville </LOCATION>, group manager <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Skepner </PERSON> said Thursday. The show has been carried on <LOCATION> Nashville </LOCATION> public radio station WPLN.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>MANTEO, N.C. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Andy </PERSON> <PERSON> Griffith </PERSON> graduated from playing first soldier in `` The Lost Colony'' to the part of Sir <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> Raleigh </PERSON> during his early theater days, but he remains dubious about how well he performed as <LOCATION> Raleigh </LOCATION>. `` I do n't think I was very good as Raleigh,'' <PERSON> Griffith </PERSON> told the choir of the outdoor drama during a recent visit, `` but I enjoyed it.'' <PERSON> Griffith </PERSON> and his wife, <PERSON> Cindi </PERSON>, were invited to speak to the choir by <PERSON> Rosalind </PERSON> <PERSON> MacEnulty </PERSON>, the music director and a longtime friend. Mrs. <PERSON> Griffith </PERSON> has also appeared in the `` The Lost Colony.'' <PERSON> Griffith </PERSON>, the star of the `` Matlock'' television series, also starred in `` The <PERSON> Andy </PERSON> <PERSON> Griffith </PERSON> Show,'' which was set in the fictional town of <LOCATION> Mayberry </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.C </LOCATION>. He has a home on <LOCATION> Roanoke </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION>, where <LOCATION> Manteo </LOCATION> is located, and has spent some time there since the Hollywood script writers strike began. He added that he's eager to get back to work.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880723-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-23-88 0311EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Burns-Meese     07-23 0298</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Burns-Meese,280</SECOND>
<HEAD>Justice Finds No Basis to Investigate Former Deputy Attorney
General Burns</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PETE YOST</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> has found no basis to investigate former Deputy Attorney General <PERSON> Arnold </PERSON> <PERSON> Burns </PERSON> for promoting a former law partner for a judgeship, sources say. The criminal division's public integrity section reached the conclusion after reviewing information about the relationship between <PERSON> Burns </PERSON> and <PERSON> Stuart </PERSON> <PERSON> Summit </PERSON>, who has been nominated to the 2nd U.S. <ORGANIZATION> Circuit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appeals </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, according to the sources, who spoke on the condition of anonymity. <PERSON> Burns </PERSON> and former criminal division chief <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Weld </PERSON> plan to testify before <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> Tuesday about their March 29 protest resignations. They quit out of concern that the continued tenure of Attorney General <PERSON> Edwin </PERSON> <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON> was hurting <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> operations and morale. The <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> Times disclosed <PERSON> Burns </PERSON>' support for Summit last month, suggesting the former deputy attorney general might have violated federal conflict-of-interest law. The <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> Times this month disclosed that <PERSON> Weld </PERSON> had been the focus of an internal <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> investigation into whether he smoked marijuana at a wedding in 1982. <PERSON> Weld </PERSON> has emphatically denied the allegation, made in an anonymous letter, and the department's Office of Professional Responsibility closed the matter. Congressional sources and sources close to the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> have said the leaking of unfavorable information about <PERSON> Burns </PERSON> and <PERSON> Weld </PERSON> has been an attempt to discourage them from testifying before the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Judiciary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Burns </PERSON> was still receiving payments from the law firm and had investments in limited partnerships with Summit at the time he was urging Summit's nomination last year. When asked Friday about the public integrity section's decision, <PERSON> Summit </PERSON> said he was `` not surprised, there never was anything to it'' and said he was pleased about the outcome.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880723-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-23-88 0311EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-US-SovietJews     07-23 0550</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-US-Soviet Jews,550</SECOND>
<HEAD>Shultz Helps Israel Settle Soviet Jews</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BARRY SCHWEID</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Diplomatic Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Secretary of State <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> has decided to help <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> hold on to Soviet Jews who might prefer settling in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, according to <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials. He will not oppose a prospective change in Israeli procedures designed to stem the exodus to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> of Jews who left the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> with exit permits for <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>, the officials said Friday. But <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> is likely to heed the advice of the bureaus that handle Soviet and refugee affairs and keep pushing <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> to permit wider emigration across the board. Most Jews who leave the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> are permitted to depart if they can get visas from <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>. Once they reach <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION>, the transit point for Soviet emigres, nearly 90 percent of them go elsewhere, mostly to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and are taken in by the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> as refugees. Concerned about the situation, the Israeli Cabinet has ordered a change in procedures. Soviet Jews granted exit permits would receive their Israeli visas in <LOCATION> Romania </LOCATION> and fly to <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>. The change in procedure, which has not been put into effect, would make it harder for Soviet Jews to come to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> because they would have to qualify for entry as immigrants. This could require long waiting periods and most would be fenced out for various reasons as ineligible. The <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>'s European bureau, which is involved in Soviet policy, and the <ORGANIZATION> Human </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rights </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> had both recommended to <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> that he urge <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> to change its policy and appeal to <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> to permit wider emigration. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Schifter </PERSON>, the assistant secretary of <ORGANIZATION> state </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Human </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rights </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Humanitarian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Affairs </ORGANIZATION>, proposed that Soviet Jews remain eligible for admission to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> as refugees even after they reach <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>'s Near Eastern bureau, which deals in Arab and <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> affairs, recommended to <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> that he not contest the Israeli Cabinet's decision _ advice he will follow, at least temporarily, according to officials who spoke on the condition they not be identified. `` The debate is less a <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> debate than a debate about feeling the Israelis would be insulted and that it would undermine the purpose of the State of <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> if refugees left the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> and did not go to <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>,'' an official said. `` They need and want immigrants.'' <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Harris </PERSON>, the <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> representative of the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Jewish </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, described the problem as `` one of the hottest and most complex issues in <LOCATION> Israeli-Diaspora </LOCATION> debate.'' He referred to divergent views among Jews living in <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> and elsewhere around the world. `` Ideally,'' <PERSON> Harris </PERSON> said, `` the compromise would be a two-track policy. Soviet Jews who want to go to <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> would leave the <LOCATION> U.S.S.R. </LOCATION> with Israeli visas. Those seeking resettlement in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> would leave with American visas. It is our hope the administration will press the <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION> in this direction. It's fair, it's equitable, its logical.'' Most Soviet citizens are unable to obtain exit permits. But thousands of Jews, Armenians and ethnic Germans over the years have enjoyed a special privilege of emigrating. Very small numbers of Jews are permitted to go directly to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. The others can leave only if they obtain visas for <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880723-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-23-88 0111EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Italy-HighFashion Bjt   07-23 0589</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Italy-High Fashion, Bjt,0604</SECOND>
<HEAD>Forgotten Italian Fashion Designers Fight Back with Frills</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DANIELA PETROFF</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Fashion Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ROME (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Italian high fashion designers presented the most ornate collections in many a season for this fall and winter, perhaps in an effort to give a lift to their own sagging image. During the five-day Roman fashion week ending Friday night, the couture runway brimmed with gold, silver, bronze and precious stones. Sequined embroidery, no longer flatly stitched, stood out in three-dimensional flora and fauna, while precious pelts of mink, sable and fox rimmed cuffs, collars and hemlines. The great success achieved by French designer <PERSON> Christian </PERSON> <PERSON> Lacroix </PERSON>, coupled with a power struggle between <LOCATION> Milan </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION> for control of the Italian fashion scene, has weakened the image of the made-in-Italy couture label, which in the 1960s presented a real threat to the supremacy of French couture. Today, only a handful of buyers and press representatives come to <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION> for the twice-a-year showings, mainly to check in at <LOCATION> Valentino </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Gianfranco </PERSON> <PERSON> Ferre </PERSON>, the popular Milanese ready-to-wear designer that began its high fashion collections two years ago. <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION> tries to put its best foot forward by using elegant hotels and historic outdoor settings for its shows. They contrast sharply with <LOCATION> Milan </LOCATION> trade fairgrounds, where the Italian ready-to-wear shows are held, and Parisian tents, where French collections are displayed. Although individual houses such as <LOCATION> Lancetti </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Mila </PERSON> <PERSON> Schoen </PERSON>, <PERSON> Galitzine </PERSON> and <PERSON> Andre </PERSON> <PERSON> Laug </PERSON> have a long list of faithful clients, the Valentino couture label is the only one that can still give the French a run for their money. The look for the fall-winter Italian style is vaguely Russian, with sable playing heavily for day and night on hats, coats, jackets, sweaters and evening gowns. Redingote coat styles abound, as well as wide lapels on jackets and high collars on dresses and blouses alike. Shades tend toward fall greens, purples and browns. Flannel gray makes a big comeback, and the newest shade of the season is ruby red, championed by <PERSON> Gianfranco </PERSON> <PERSON> Ferre </PERSON> in his much applauded collection. In a situation emblematic of their unsettled state, the designers could not agree on one hemline, with some diving way below the knee, while others still offered short skirts. However, the tiny miniskirt is out, and the preferred length is right on the knee. Although not prominent, pants dot the collections, with <PERSON> Ferre </PERSON> offering the newest idea: gray flannel man-tailored trousers by night worn with a sumptuous sequined top. Heels are very high, makeup is pronounced with bright red lips, and hairstyles are neat, often pinned back at the neck. For evening wear, the designers let themselves go, often tailoring their gowns from shimmering gold, silver or bronze fabrics and decorating an otherwise simple sheath with heavy jeweled sequins or entire life-sized floral arrangements of fabric and sequins. And if that's not enough, fur trimming is sometimes added for extra winter warmth. With prices for a couture gown starting at $ 10, OOO and soaring over $ 100,000 for more elaborate models, it is understandable that the designers are eager to give the client her money's worth. However, the look can and often does fall into fashion kitsch. Only <PERSON> Valentino </PERSON> and <PERSON> Ferre </PERSON> were able to carry this opulence off gracefully. <PERSON> Ferre </PERSON> unburdened his floral-sequined and fur-trimmed silver gray ballgown by interspersing its layers of velvet and taffeta with yards and yards of airy tulle. <PERSON> Valentino </PERSON> streamlined the look by relegating ornate sequins to cummerbunds on a simple chiffon gown and fashioning his floral creations out of bands of satin.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880723-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-23-88 0315EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-US-Iran-Contra     07-23 0407</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-US-Iran-Contra,400</SECOND>
<HEAD>Iran-Contra Investigation To Continue Into Next Presidential Term</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID BRISCOE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> WASHINGTON </LOCATION> _ Extension of the life of the Iran-Contra grand jury will push the 18-month-old investigation into the start of the next president's term with more charges possible. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Chief Judge <PERSON> Aubrey </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> acted Friday, just six days before the jury was to be disbanded, to extend its work for six more months, through Jan. 27, 1989. By then, President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s successor will be in office. <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON>, in his order, responded to a sealed motion from independent counsel <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Walsh </PERSON> to extend the inquiry, even as <PERSON> Walsh </PERSON>'s staff prepares for the scheduled Sept. 20 opening of the trial of former White House aide <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> <PERSON> North </PERSON>. Lawyers for <PERSON> North </PERSON> have asked that the trial be postponed until March 1989. <PERSON> Walsh </PERSON> is expected to continue looking into the activities of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials and others in <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> following the indictment last month of a former <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> station chief in <LOCATION> Costa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rica </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Fernandez </PERSON>. An unspecified number of co-conspirators were cited along with <PERSON> Fernandez </PERSON> in an illegal supply network aimed at getting funds to the Contras in 1986, when <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> had banned <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> aid to the Nicaraguan rebels. <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON>'s order said the purpose of the extension was `` for the investigations identified by the government in its motion.'' <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Wieghart </PERSON>, <PERSON> Walsh </PERSON>'s spokesman, said he could not comment on specifics of the planned investigations mentioned in the judge's order <PERSON> Walsh </PERSON>'s investigation previously focused on <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> fund-raising efforts for the Contras, arms sales to <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> and the diversion of profits from the sales to the rebels. This led to charges against <PERSON> North </PERSON>, former national security adviser <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Poindexter </PERSON> and arms dealers <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> V. </PERSON> <PERSON> Secord </PERSON> and <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Hakim </PERSON> for their roles in the Iranian arms sales and the diversion of profits from the sales to private use and to the Contras. Two fund-raisers and former national security adviser <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> McFarlane </PERSON> earlier pleaded guilty to other charges resulting from <PERSON> Walsh </PERSON>'s grand jury investigation. The charges against <PERSON> Fernandez </PERSON> accused him of helping <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Secord </PERSON> coordinate air drops of weapons and supplies to <LOCATION> Contra </LOCATION> groups in 1986. Trials of <PERSON> Poindexter </PERSON>, <PERSON> Secord </PERSON> and <PERSON> Hakim </PERSON> will follow that of North. On Tuesday, <PERSON> North </PERSON>, <PERSON> Poindexter </PERSON> and <PERSON> Hakim </PERSON> petitioned the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appeals </ORGANIZATION> to have their indictments dismissed because they believe testimony given to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> under grants of immunity would be used against them in the trials.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880723-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-23-88 0316EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Jamaica-Violence     07-23 0362</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Jamaica-Violence,0375</SECOND>
<HEAD>Business Groups Call For End To Political Violence</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LLOYD WILLIAMS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>KINGSTON, Jamaica (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Eighteen business and professional organizations urged <LOCATION> Jamaica </LOCATION>'s governing and main opposition parties to end political violence between their supporters. The call to sign a peace agreement came after backers of the opposition <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> stoned a busload of <ORGANIZATION> Jamaica </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> supporters in a fishing village Sunday. Pro-government militants then burned several shacks and chased one opposition party member into the <LOCATION> Caribbean </LOCATION>, where he drowned. `` In a climate of violence and lawlessness, the entire nation suffers from a drying up of investment and a decline in tourism and other economic activity,'' read a joint statement issued Friday by the 18 private sector groups. Several others were injured in separate attacks during the week between rival bands of the two parties. More than 700 people died in political violence during the 1980 general elections. `` The signing of a joint declaration by the leaders and the public commitment of their parties to law and order can no longer be delayed for whatever reason,'' read the statement, which asked that the agreement be signed by Aug. 1, Independence Day. Elections are expected in December, but <LOCATION> Jamaica </LOCATION>'s Constitution grants the prime minister a three-month grace period before calling new elections. Prime Minister <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Seaga </PERSON> was elected for a five-year term in 1983. `` We believe we speak for the law-abiding majority of this country in saying we are sick of ... the violence and partisan point-scoring and are disappointed by our political leaders' delay in fulfilling their national duty,'' the statement read. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Manley </PERSON>, a former prime minister and the opposition leader, said Wednesday his party is ready to sign the agreement. `` <LOCATION> Jamaica </LOCATION> is demanding that both political parties work together to bring the madness of political violence to an end,'' he said. <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Golding </PERSON>, chairman of the governing party, said the parties must have the political will to end the violence before signing a peace pact. Groups signing the statement included the <ORGANIZATION> Jamaica </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hotel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tourist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Chamber </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Bankers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Employers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federation </ORGANIZATION> and the Exporters Association of <LOCATION> Jamaica </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880723-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-23-88 0316EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-BRF--WomanAblaze     07-23 0133</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Woman Ablaze,0136</SECOND>
<HEAD>Woman Sets Herself Ablaze, Sheriff's Office Says</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SANTA ROSA, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A 52-year-old woman suffered third-degree burns and lost half her right ear after she poured gasoline over her body and set herself ablaze, the <ORGANIZATION> Sonoma </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sheriff </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> said. <PERSON> Delores </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Matteri </PERSON>, of <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rosa </LOCATION>, was listed in serious condition at <ORGANIZATION> Alta </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bates </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Burn </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Berkeley </LOCATION>. Authorities said Friday they did not know why the woman set herself on fire. Deputy <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Turner </PERSON> responded to a report of a woman on fire at 1:26 p.m. When he arrived, he found <PERSON> Matteri </PERSON> no longer ablaze but suffering from extreme burns, sheriff's spokeswoman <PERSON> Monica </PERSON> <PERSON> Labbert </PERSON> said. Turner later learned that <PERSON> Matteri </PERSON> had sat down on her back porch, poured gasoline over her body, then ignited herself, <PERSON> Labbert </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880723-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-23-88 0316EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--China-Poison     07-23 0124</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--China-Poison,0128</SECOND>
<HEAD>Five Poisoned In Chemical Mix-Up</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A chemical company in eastern <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> mistakenly sold a restaurant a lethal chemical compound instead of baking soda, and five diners died of poisoning and 140 others became ill, a newspaper reported today. The Peasant Daily said the people were poisoned June 23 after a chemical company in <LOCATION> Zhejiang </LOCATION> province sold the restaurant sodium fluosilicate rather than sodium bicarbonate, or baking soda. Sodium fluosilicate is used in insecticides and ceramics. Customers who bought the restaurant's buns containing the poisonous chemical suffered from serious stomach pains, vomiting and diarrhea, the report said. It said the person in charge of the warehouse at the chemical company was arrested after being found responsible for the mistake.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880723-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-23-88 0317EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-SugarQuota     07-23 0616</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Sugar Quota,640</SECOND>
<HEAD>Sugar Quota Will Benefit 39 Countries, Brings Praise From U.S.
Sugar Users</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID BRISCOE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> WASHINGTON </LOCATION> _ A 40 percent increase in the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> sugar quota will benefit the <LOCATION> Dominican </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Republic </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION> and 36 other countries and is bringing praise from large <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> sugar users. The increase in what had been the lowest sugar quotas in 113 years authorizes the purchase of 300,000 additional short tons of sugar in 1988 and also reallocates the 20,300 tons of sugar that would have been bought from <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> before all trade with that country was cut off. The <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> and the office of the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Trade Representative announced the sugar quota expansion to 1,056,675 tons at the end of the trading day Friday. The new quota is about 56,000 tons higher than the 1987 figure but lower than the 1986 quota of 1.7 million tons. The 1988 quota previously had been the lowest since 1875, agriculture and trade officials said. Agriculture Secretary <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Lyng </PERSON>, who has advocated a scrapping of the program that keeps <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> sugar prices higher than those on the world market, said the increase was necessary because of unexpected cuts in <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> production, `` including the likely effects of the drought on sugar beet yields.'' The low sugar quotas announced last December had brought criticism from <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> sugar users who anticipated difficulty getting enough sugar and disappointment in countries whose quotas were cut _ particularly the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION>, which has long been dependent upon the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> sugar quotas to help its ailing economy. The <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> sugar program offers a kind of dual subsidy, helping the producing countries by paying well above world market prices for their sugar and helping <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> sugar growers by guaranteeing them the higher prices, too. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> buys sugar under the quota system at the same price it pays <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> producers, about 23 cents a pound, up from 18 cents earlier this year. The current world market price is approaching 15 cents a pound after dipping to around 6 cents. Under the new quotas, the <LOCATION> Dominican </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Republic </LOCATION> will be able to sell 176,710 short tons, up from 123,200; the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION> 158,640, up from 110,600; and <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION> 145,590, up from 101,500. Those three countries account for almost half of the foreign sugar sold to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. Last December when the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> set the low quotas, officials said the cuts were justified because of decreased consumption with Americans using more artificial and other natural sweeteners. The program is designed to guarantee <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> producers a high price for their sugar and is also favored by producers of artificial sweeteners because they also can charge higher prices. Critics include manufacturers who use a lot of sugar in their products, because it keeps sugar prices high. But sugar users were pleased with the new quotas. `` We applaud the secretary of agriculture,'' said <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Hammer </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Sweetener </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Users </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, which represents companies that use sugar. `` It will stop the inflationary spiral that was going on with domestic sugar prices,'' he said. <PERSON> Hammer </PERSON> said the need was `` immediate and urgent because my members ... believe that without it, adequate supplies of sugar by late summer and fall were very much in doubt.'' Except for the elimination of <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s quota, the share of sugar purchases allocated to each country will not change. <PERSON> Lyng </PERSON> said the new quota includes a base import quota of 975,000 tons and 2,000 tons of specialty sugar. The new allocations raised the minimum quota from 5,770 tons to 8,000. It was the first mid-year increase in the sugar quota since April 5, 1984, when there was a shortfall in <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> sugar cane production.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880723-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-23-88 0325EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-China-Obscenity     07-23 0206</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-China-Obscenity,0210</SECOND>
<HEAD>Chinese Publishers Fired for Printing Irving Wallace Novel</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Two publishers were fired for printing a novel by popular American novelist <PERSON> Irving </PERSON> <PERSON> Wallace </PERSON> that local censors judged obscene, an official report said today. The <ORGANIZATION> Xinhua </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> said the government of the northeastern province had dismissed the two for printing 400,000 Chinese-language copies of the 1975 <PERSON> Wallace </PERSON> novel, `` The Fan Club.'' It identified the pair as <PERSON> Sun </PERSON> <PERSON> Yuanzhong </PERSON>, deputy director and deputy editor-in-chief of the <ORGANIZATION> Yanbian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Publishing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, and <PERSON> Cui </PERSON> <PERSON> Xingshou </PERSON>, head of the literature and art editorial department. They were dismissed by authorities in the Yanbian Korean Autonomous Prefecture in <LOCATION> Jilin </LOCATION> province. In addition, they were ordered, along with another editor, to write self-criticisms. <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> has no national obscenity laws. The prevailing political climate often determines whether a work of art dealing with sex or other sensitive subjects will be acceptable. The government has said it is drafting laws and regulations defining the limits of artistic expression and outlining standards for the censorship of movies. Englishman <PERSON> D.H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON>'s novel `` Lady Chatterley's Lover,'' long banned as pornography, has been hailed this year as a masterpiece. Paintings of nudes, pulled down from shows a year ago, are appearing in national galleries.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880723-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-23-88 0120EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-MinisterSlain     07-23 0322</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Minister Slain,0331</SECOND>
<HEAD>Aurora Minister And Civil Rights Leader Found Beaten To Death</HEAD>
<DATELINE>AURORA, Ill. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A minister active in the civil rights movement was found beaten to death Friday in his church hours after he returned from the Democratic convention, and police charged a nearby resident with murder. The Rev. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Wesby </PERSON>, 61, who headed the branch of Operation PUSH in this <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> suburb, was killed with a `` large, sharp instrument,'' <LOCATION> Kane </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> Coroner <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Lou </PERSON> <PERSON> Kearns </PERSON> said. Associates described <PERSON> Wesby </PERSON> as a longtime friend or colleague of Democratic presidential contender <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, founder of Chicago-based Operation PUSH. <PERSON> Wesby </PERSON> was not listed as a <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> delegate, but had apparently gone to the convention to support <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>. <PERSON> Wesby </PERSON>'s body was found shortly before 10 a.m., about two hours after he returned from <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>, said <PERSON> Becky </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>, who was answering telephones at his <ORGANIZATION> Progressive </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Baptist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION>, about 35 miles west of <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Wesby </PERSON> founded the church 25 years ago. Late Friday night, police acting on a tip arrested <PERSON> Calvin </PERSON> <PERSON> Green </PERSON>, 28, at his home about two blocks from the church and charged him with murder, said police Capt. <PERSON> Lou </PERSON> <PERSON> Beatus </PERSON>. He said police were still trying to determine a motive for the slaying. The suspect is black, as was the victim. <PERSON> Green </PERSON> was scheduled for a bond hearing Saturday, <PERSON> Beatus </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Kearns </PERSON> said <PERSON> Wesby </PERSON> died immediately after being attacked. No weapon was found. Police found the body near the altar of the church after responding to a call that <PERSON> Wesby </PERSON> had been beaten, said police Lt. <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> McDonald </PERSON>. Later Friday, <PERSON> Wesby </PERSON>'s friends and supporters, including <LOCATION> Aurora </LOCATION> Mayor <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON>, gathered outside the church to grieve. `` You could n't find anyone better than that man. Any time, night or day, Rev. <PERSON> Wesby </PERSON> would come and give anyone any help they needed,'' said <PERSON> Odell </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, a longtime friend. A <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> native, <PERSON> Wesby </PERSON> was the recipient of <LOCATION> Aurora </LOCATION>'s first Community Leadership Award in November 1985.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880723-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-23-88 0239EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Drought-Ants     07-23 0445</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Drought-Ants,0462</SECOND>
<HEAD>Drought Sends Parched Insect Armies Marching Into Bay Area Homes</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SAN FRANCISCO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Hordes of thirsty ants driven by drought and heat are invading homes throughout the <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION> area in search of water, and residents say no one seems to know how to stop them. `` I've never seen anything like it. There are millions of them,'' said <PERSON> Anita </PERSON> <PERSON> Lowery </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Novato </LOCATION>. `` I've almost cried.'' The ants are climbing out of light switches, creeping into baby bottles and even making their way into freezers. `` They are getting into bed with people. When you turn on the water, they come out of the faucet in globs. People finding themselves taking baths with ants,'' said <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Wolbert </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> Jackson </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Control </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Novato </LOCATION>. Experts say the tiny insects are only looking for water for their bone-dry nests, but unsympathetic human hosts are calling exterminators. `` It is really, really bad this year, and it's creating hysteria,'' said <PERSON> Kevin </PERSON> <PERSON> Pendergraft </PERSON> of <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> Exterminators in <LOCATION> Walnut </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Creek </LOCATION>. More than 150 calls have come in each day since last weekend, when temperatures soared to record highs, he said. `` The county is going under with all the ants,'' <PERSON> Wolbert </PERSON> said. `` People have called in who have n't had ants for 20 years. They have them all over the house.'' Even ant fans wish the ants would march somewhere else. As a scientist, <PERSON> Benny </PERSON> <PERSON> Fouche </PERSON> admires ants as `` survivalists,'' but as a homeowner, he's being driven crazy by the insects' persistence <PERSON> Fouche </PERSON>, a research associate in urban entomology at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION> at <LOCATION> Berkeley </LOCATION>, looks for nests in the yard of his <ORGANIZATION> El </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cerrito </ORGANIZATION> home but admits he's probably wasting his time. `` Unless you get the queen, I can almost guarantee that the ants will out-persevere you. They'll just keep coming,'' he said. `` The colony needs food and water. They have thousands of workers who will sacrifice themselves.'' If they were n't so good at surviving, they would n't have defied `` all the pest control people in the bay area,'' <PERSON> Fouche </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Wolbert </PERSON> called the situation `` just another result of nature changing'' and said a similar problem occurred during the 1977 drought. `` They just have to set up a happy home. They need water and a little food,'' he said. `` If you have food in your pantry or water in your sinks, you're going to have them.'' <PERSON> Wolbert </PERSON> said he could n't understand all the uproar: `` It's really phenomenal Ants are very clean. They're always preening each other.'' <PERSON> Susan </PERSON> <PERSON> Grippi </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Novato </LOCATION> did n't share his complacency. `` It feels like it's been a disaster,'' she said, adding that ants had surrounded her home and invaded an upstairs bathroom. `` They make me crazy.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880723-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-23-88 0326EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-US-Libyans     07-23 0582</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-US-Libyans,580</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bail Denied for Libyan Accused of Illegal Intelligence Gathering</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ALEXANDRIA, Va. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A Libyan man accused of gathering information about <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> intelligence operatives and arranging for the military training of <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> dissidents in <LOCATION> Libya </LOCATION> has been ordered held without bail. A <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> magistrate on Friday granted bail to five other defendants, including <PERSON> Mousa </PERSON> <PERSON> Hawamda </PERSON>, a travel agency owner accused of involvement in an alleged <LOCATION> Libyan </LOCATION> plot to assassinate a `` high government official in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>.'' Sources have said the official was former <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> aide <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> <PERSON> North </PERSON>, who played a key role in the 1986 <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> bombing of <LOCATION> Libya </LOCATION>. The prosecution immediately appealed the bail for <PERSON> Hawamda </PERSON>, a naturalized American described by the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> as a senior Libyan intelligence operative, and he was ordered held pending an appeals hearing early next week. The <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION>, in today's editions, quoted <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> officials as saying there is little evidence to support a federal prosecutor's assertion that <PERSON> Hawamda </PERSON> may have helped in the alleged plot. The Times said <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> officials who asked not to be identified said they were baffled when <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Attorney <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Hudson </PERSON> asserted in open court earlier this week that Hawamda should be held without bail because he was a <LOCATION> Libyan </LOCATION> intelligence officer who may have assisted in a plot to kill a government official. The officials, who asked not to be identified, said that while there may have been an assassination plot aimed at North, the only information linking <PERSON> Hawamda </PERSON> to such a conspiracy came from an informer whose reliabiity is uncertain. <PERSON> Hudson </PERSON> had no comment on the assertions that there was little evidence to support allegations about the assassination plot, the Times said. <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> <PERSON> Carroll </PERSON>, the lawyer representing <PERSON> Hawamda </PERSON>, called the prosecution's contention of a plot to kill a high government official `` ludicrous.'' <PERSON> Hawamda </PERSON> and the five others were among eight men arrested Wednesday on suspicion of a scheme to illegally use Libyan government funds to solicit support for <LOCATION> Libya </LOCATION> among American dissidents, including Indians and Black Muslims. Friday's hearing before magistrate <PERSON> Leonie </PERSON> <PERSON> Brinkema </PERSON> was to determine whether the six would be freed on bond. The bail ranged from $ 250,000 for <LOCATION> Hawamda </LOCATION> to $ 10,000 for Manhal <PERSON> Ben </PERSON> <PERSON> Mohamed </PERSON>, a Moroccan who worked for Hawamda. Two other defendants are being held in <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Colo. </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mich. </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Alvin </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Binder </PERSON>, a criminal lawyer from <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> who represented four of the defendants in court, said the case was `` very political. <PERSON> Binder </PERSON>, a criminal lawyer who represented <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> child murderer <PERSON> Wayne </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> in 1982, said the prosecution had made `` allegations with no concrete evidence.'' <PERSON> Hudson </PERSON> told reporters after the detention hearing that `` the case involves issues far beyond just a diversion of funds.'' But he refused to elaborate, saying additional charges would be made when indictments are returned, possibly late next week. Speaking for the prosecution, <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> special agent <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bartnik </PERSON> said the defendant held without bail, <PERSON> Saleh </PERSON> <PERSON> Al-Rajhi </PERSON>, was a <LOCATION> Libyan </LOCATION> intelligence operative who in June 1987 was ordered to gather the names and addresses of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> intelligence officials dealing with the <LOCATION> Mediterranean </LOCATION> region. The <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> seized a document handwritten by <PERSON> Al-Rajhi </PERSON> as a cover letter for a computer list of intelligence operatives, <PERSON> Bartnik </PERSON> said. The list and letter were sent to the head of Libyan intelligence, <PERSON> Mohamed </PERSON> <PERSON> Madjoub </PERSON>, he added. <PERSON> Al-Rajhi </PERSON> also wrote <PERSON> Madjoub </PERSON> a memo which indicated the Libyans had promised to fund American dissident groups in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and pay for their military training in <LOCATION> Libya </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Bartnik </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880723-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-23-88 0236EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Eastern Bjt   07-23 0626</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Eastern, Bjt,0645</SECOND>
<HEAD>Eastern Plan To Cut 4,000 Jobs Causes Bitterness, Fear</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto MH1</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By WILL LESTER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MIAMI (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION>' announcement that it would lay off 4,000 employees and eliminate service to 14 cities to cut costs was met with bitterness and fear by workers, who should learn their fate by Monday. `` I've heard rumors this way since I've been working here,'' said <PERSON> Evelyn </PERSON> <PERSON> Perez </PERSON>, a ticket agent at <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> <LOCATION> International </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION> who has been with Eastern for 11 years. `` It's always been felt, but now it's real.'' The plan announced Friday by the loss-plagued airline would trim 12 percent of the work force and eliminate service to the 14 cities on Aug. 31. Included among the layoffs or early retirements will be 520 jobs in <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION>, 300 in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> and 350 in <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mo. </LOCATION>, which will no longer be the carrier's Western hub, <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION> President <PERSON> Phil </PERSON> <PERSON> Bakes </PERSON> said. The reductions also will include 1,100 jobs from the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> area, including 600 at a reservations center in <LOCATION> Woodbridge </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.J. </LOCATION>, and 500 flight attendants, pilots and managers based at <LOCATION> Kennedy </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> LaGuardia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Newark </LOCATION> airports. Last November, <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION> eliminated 3,500 jobs, mostly from the company's union ranks. `` We are preserving the airline. We're strengthening the airline. I do n't care to place the blame anywhere,'' Bakes said, citing high operating costs and increased competition for Eastern's huge losses But <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bavis </PERSON>, chairman of the 3,500-member <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Line </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pilots </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> contingent at <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION>, disagreed. `` They've done nothing over the past two years except squeeze the assets out of Eastern in order to help subsidize our sister airline, <ORGANIZATION> Continental </ORGANIZATION>,'' he said. Both Eastern and <ORGANIZATION> Continental </ORGANIZATION> are subsidiaries of Houston-based <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, which lost $ 466 million last year. The announcement came in the seventh month of bitter contract talks between <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Machinists </ORGANIZATION> union, which is seeking raises for 10,000 Eastern workers. The carrier is seeking $ 161 million in pay cuts and other concessions. The Miami-based airline also is seeking $ 69 million in concessions from its pilots union, which began formal contract talks with the company Friday. `` Last year, we lost $ 182 million. In essence, Eastern is returning to its basic roots in an attempt to regain strength in the marketplace,'' Bakes said. Eastern's operations in <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> will be the core of the carrier's service, he said. The 14 cities being cut are <LOCATION> Albuquerque </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.M. </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> de </LOCATION> <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Martinique </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Las </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vegas </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Reno </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Nev. </LOCATION>; Minneapolis-St. <PERSON> Paul </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Minn. </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Tulsa </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Okla </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Omaha </LOCATION>, Neb; <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Antonio </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>; Pointe-a-Pitre, <LOCATION> Guadeloupe </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Diego </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lucia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Indies </LOCATION>; and <LOCATION> Tucson </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ariz </LOCATION>. The personnel cuts will involve both union and non-union members and management personnel, <PERSON> Bakes </PERSON> said. The reductions will reduce the work force to 29,500, down from 43,300 in September 1986. The airline said the work force reduction would allow it to sell a proportional share of its fleet, cutting the number of planes it operates from 246 to 202 in the fall. Machinists local chief <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Bryan </PERSON> was en route to <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> from <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>, and could not be reached Friday. Earlier this week, after word of the impending cuts leaked, he said <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION> would have `` no credibility'' and said <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> President <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Lorenzo </PERSON> was `` evil.'' The <ORGANIZATION> Machinists </ORGANIZATION> union is seeking a two-year contract with raises of 1.5 percent and 5 percent, which <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION> says will cost $ 50 million yearly. Employees were shocked by the news of the layoffs, said a reservation operator in <LOCATION> Woodbridge </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.J. </LOCATION> `` A lot of us have 10 or 15 years seniority and now we're going to be looking for other jobs,'' said the woman, who would only identify herself as <PERSON> Josephine </PERSON>. `` There's a lot of crying going on.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880723-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-23-88 0131EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Saudi-Hajj 3rdLd-Writethru a0401 07-23 0823</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Saudi-Hajj, 3rd Ld-Writethru, a0401,0845</SECOND>
<HEAD>Tehran Radio Reports Pilgrims Protest, Police Attack Some</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: LEADS with seven grafs to UPDATE with Saudi denial. Pick up
8th pvs, `Residents in...'</NOTE>
<DATELINE>JIDDAH, Saudi Arabia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
