<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880402-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-02-88 0001EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Blind-Airlines     04-02 0683</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Blind-Airlines,650</SECOND>
<HEAD>Blind Attorney: Airlines Treat Handicapped `Like Baggage'</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By H. JOSEF HEBERT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A blind attorney who was carried forcibly from a jetliner after a dispute over where she should be seated complains that airlines look at the handicapped `` as if we're a safety risk and have to be treated like baggage.'' The attorney, <PERSON> Peggy </PERSON> <PERSON> Pinder </PERSON>, said Friday she is still angry over an incident Thursday evening aboard a <ORGANIZATION> Midway </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> jetliner waiting to take off from <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> National </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION> on a flight to <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>. After boarding, she said, she sat in a window seat in the second row from the back of the cabin in the smoking section. But she was told to move to the first row in the front of the cabin because she is blind and needed to be closer to a full-door emergency exit. When she refused, arguing that there are no federal safety regulations that require her to sit in a particular seat, police were summoned and carried her off the plane. She was charged with trespassing. `` It was embarrassing,'' <PERSON> Miss </PERSON> <PERSON> Pinder </PERSON>, 34, an attorney from <LOCATION> Grinnell </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>, and a vice president of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federation </ORGANIZATION> of the <PERSON> Blind </PERSON>, said in an interview. `` They told the police to carry me off and they did.'' She insisted that she sought no confrontation and wanted only to return to her hometown when the dispute erupted aboard Midway Flight 179 as it prepared to depart for <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>. The flight was delayed about 45 minutes because of the confrontation, according to airport officials. Ironically, <PERSON> Miss </PERSON> <PERSON> Pinder </PERSON> had flown to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> to meet with several members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and officials of the <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> platform committee to discuss problems blind people are having in air travel. She said she was told by a flight attendant that she could not sit at the rear of the aircraft even though her seat did not block access to any emergency exit doors because of the airlines' policy on dealing with handicapped passengers. `` Then the captain came. He said, ` You will do what the flight attendant tells you and sit where you're told or not fly on this airplane.','' she recounted. She refused to budge and airport police were called to carry her off the plane, according to accounts related by airline and airport officials as well as Miss <PERSON> Pinder </PERSON>. `` They -LRB- airline officials -RRB- feel that blind people are not the same as other passengers, that we're a safety risk and that we have to be treated like baggage in order to carry us safely,'' said <PERSON> Miss </PERSON> <PERSON> Pinder </PERSON>. `` That's not federal law. They violated my rights.'' She has been summoned to appear at an arraignment on the trespass charge May 19. <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> Farrar </PERSON> said the <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> has no requirements on where blind passengers should be seated, although the agency has recomended that they not be seated in a row that has an emergency exit. Miss <PERSON> Pinder </PERSON> said she sat in a row with no such exit. A <ORGANIZATION> Midway </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman, <PERSON> Sandra </PERSON> <PERSON> Allen </PERSON>, said that the airline has a firm policy of seating handicapped passengers, including those who are blind, on the front row of the aircraft cabin because those seats are closest to a floor-level emergency door. Responding to the incident involving Miss <PERSON> Pinder </PERSON>, <PERSON> Miss </PERSON> <PERSON> Allen </PERSON> said `` she refused to be briefed -LRB- on safety procedures -RRB- and maintained she could sit where she wanted ... We could not take off seated where she was and asked her to step off -LRB- the plane -RRB- because she was inconveniencing 100 passengers.'' Because of her confrontation Thursday night she remained in the capital another day and on Friday accompanied several other officials of the National Federation of the Blind to a meeting with <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Burnley </PERSON> to discuss alleged discrimination against the handicapped by the airlines, a spokewoman for the federation said. The <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aviation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>, which is part of the department, is developing new regulations aimed at giving the airlines closer guidance on how to provide for the handicapped, but those regulations are not expected to be announced for several months.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880402-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-02-88 0002EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Candidates-Schedules     04-02 0291</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Candidates-Schedules,290</SECOND>
<HEAD>Presidential Candidates' Schedules</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are tentative schedules for the presidential candidates for the week beginning April 3. The information was provided by the candidates. Sunday, April 3: Democrats: <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gore </LOCATION> _ <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jackson </LOCATION> _ <ORGANIZATION> Colorado </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Simon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> _ </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Milwaukee </ORGANIZATION> and <PERSON> Madison </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Wis. </LOCATION>. Republicans: <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION> <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION> Monday, April 4: Democrats: <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> _ <ORGANIZATION> Milwaukee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Gore </ORGANIZATION> _ <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jackson </LOCATION> _ <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Simon </LOCATION> _ <LOCATION> Stevens </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Point </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Milwaukee </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wis. </LOCATION>. Republicans: <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION> <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Norfolk </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>. Tuesday, April 5: Democrats: <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gore </LOCATION> _ <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jackson </LOCATION> _ <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Phoenix </LOCATION> -RRB- <LOCATION> Simon </LOCATION> _ <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> Republicans: <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION> <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> _ open Wednesday, April 6: Democrats: <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gore </LOCATION> _ <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jackson </LOCATION> _ <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Indianapolis </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Simon </LOCATION> _ <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION> Republicans: <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION> <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> _ open Thursday, April 7: Democrats: <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gore </LOCATION> _ <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jackson </LOCATION> _ <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Simon </LOCATION> _ open Republicans: <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION><LOCATION> , </LOCATION> <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION> <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> _ open Friday, April 8: Democrats: <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Suffolk </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gore </LOCATION> _ open <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Simon </LOCATION> _ open Republicans: <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION> <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> _ open Saturday, April 9: Democrats: <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Albany </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Syracuse </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gore </LOCATION> _ open <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Simon </LOCATION> _ open Republicans: <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION> <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> _ open Sunday, April 10: Democrats: <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> _ down day <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> _ open <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> _ open <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> _ open Republicans: <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION>
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880402-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-02-88 0006EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-BankAgency-Probe     04-02 0591</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bank Agency-Probe,580</SECOND>
<HEAD>Federal Bank Official Sought FBI Probe of Critic</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVE SKIDMORE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> congressman says `` something just does n't smell right'' about a federal banking agency's request for an <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> check of one of its critics. The request to the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> from a <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Home </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Loan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> official `` smacks of a way of life that seems to be more appropriate to life in <LOCATION> Latin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> than it does in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>,'' Rep. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Florio </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.J. </LOCATION>, said Friday. The <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> check was revealed by an internal bank board investigation requested by <PERSON> Florio </PERSON>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> consumer protection subcommittee. The report, by bank board Inspector General <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Gibbons </PERSON>, disclosed that the office of <PERSON> Rosemary </PERSON> <PERSON> Stewart </PERSON>, bank board enforcement director, asked the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> on Aug. 17 to check on <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Juliano </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Mount </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Laurel </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.J. </LOCATION>, developer. The <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> returned the request, which listed only <PERSON> Juliano </PERSON>'s name and address, stamped `` insufficient information,'' and Ms. <PERSON> Stewart </PERSON> decided not to pursue the matter. Because of <PERSON> Juliano </PERSON>'s criticism, <PERSON> Florio </PERSON> had asked for an investigation of the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Asset </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Disposition </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, the arm of the <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> that manages and sells real estate from bankrupt savings and loans. <ORGANIZATION> FADA </ORGANIZATION> was under attack from <PERSON> Juliano </PERSON>, other business people and members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> for reported mismanagement and conflicts of interest. <PERSON> Juliano </PERSON> had threatened to bring a class action lawsuit against <ORGANIZATION> FADA </ORGANIZATION> on behalf of disgruntled developers who believed they had been poorly treated by the agency. Ms. <PERSON> Stewart </PERSON> told investigators she was asked in June to obtain the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> check from FADA General Counsel <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Axley </PERSON>, who said <PERSON> Juliano </PERSON> had made verbal threats and written nasty letters to then <ORGANIZATION> FADA </ORGANIZATION> President <PERSON> Rosyln </PERSON> <PERSON> Payne </PERSON>. <PERSON> Axley </PERSON> told the investigators that Ms. <PERSON> Payne </PERSON> asked him to `` have <PERSON> Juliano </PERSON> checked out'' after she received anonymous telephone calls in the middle of the night to her unlisted home telephone. <PERSON> Axley </PERSON> said he subsequently received a tip that <PERSON> Juliano </PERSON> had ties to organized crime. However, the bank board report said the tip referred to someone with a different first name than <PERSON> Juliano </PERSON>'s. After her request to the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> was returned, Ms. <PERSON> Stewart </PERSON> said she learned more about the nature of <PERSON> Juliano </PERSON>'s dispute with <ORGANIZATION> FADA </ORGANIZATION>, consulted her superiors at the bank board and decided it was not appropriate for her to resubmit the query to the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION>. But <PERSON> Florio </PERSON> said, `` For the bank board to even contemplate investigating a citizen for complaining raises a lot of questions. ... Something just does n't smell right here.'' Ms. <PERSON> Stewart </PERSON> did not immediately return telephone messages left at her office Friday afternoon. There was no answer at <PERSON> Juliano </PERSON>'s office <PERSON> Karl </PERSON> <PERSON> Hoyle </PERSON>, a bank board spokesman, said the agency acknowledges that the request to the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> should never have been made. `` Once we were aware of it, we indicated we did n't want that pursued and after that it was not,'' he said. `` <PERSON> Rosemary </PERSON>, to her credit, said ` Maybe we're not supposed to be doing that sort of thing.''' The bank board has also acknowledged that a law firm hired by <ORGANIZATION> FADA </ORGANIZATION> engaged a private detective agency to look into <PERSON> Juliano </PERSON>'s finances <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> said the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> would not consider it proper to investigate a government critic. The bureau's practice, he said, is to ask for more information about the reason a background check is requested and if the explanation is not appropriate it can recommend administrative or disciplinary actions against the person who made the request. <PERSON> Hoyle </PERSON> said Ms. <PERSON> Stewart </PERSON> has not been reprimanded.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880402-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-02-88 0042EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-HorseradishHorrors     04-02 0472</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Horseradish Horrors,0483</SECOND>
<HEAD>Passover Horseradish Health Hazard Cited By Doctors</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LEE SIEGEL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Science Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Horseradish eaten during traditional Passover dinners can pose a health hazard, says a Jewish doctor whose father collapsed after consuming an olive-sized serving of the bitter herb. Dr. <PERSON> Haya </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Rubin </PERSON> said Friday that her father, <ORGANIZATION> Cleveland </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> sociologist <PERSON> Israel </PERSON> <PERSON> Rubin </PERSON>, quickly recovered after he fainted, keeled over and suffered a small seizure during a Seder, or traditional Passover meal, several years ago. She said the incident shows that people prone to high blood pressure, heart or artery disease or stroke might be better off if they let horseradish fumes evaporate by keeping it uncovered for a half hour before the Seder, or use a substitute such as chopped romaine lettuce stalks. <PERSON> Rubin </PERSON> suffered high blood pressure before the incident, said his daughter, an internist at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>, and consultant to the <ORGANIZATION> Rand </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp </ORGANIZATION>. The Passover holiday, which celebrates the Israelites' Exodus from slavery in ancient <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION>, extends from Friday night until sundown April 9. Seders are held on the first two nights. Horseradish is eaten during the ceremonial meal as a `` bitter herb'' symbolizing the bitterness of slavery. A letter warning that horseradish can be dangerous was published Friday in the Journal of the American Medical Association by Ms. <PERSON> Rubin </PERSON> and Dr. <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Wu </PERSON>, a clinical instructor at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Diego </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Wu </PERSON> said the horseradish-induced sudden loss of blood pressure that caused <PERSON> Rubin </PERSON> to faint and collapse could trigger a fatal stroke, heart attack or abnormal heart rhythm in people with heart disease. <PERSON> Wu </PERSON> and Ms. <PERSON> Rubin </PERSON> trained together at <ORGANIZATION> Mount </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sinai </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>. They decided to write the letter after <PERSON> Wu </PERSON> spotted a letter about a similar incident published in the same journal in January. In that letter, Dr. <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Spitzer </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> Montefiore </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> told how a healthy 63-year-old man collapsed after eating a large mound of wasabi, or green-colored Japanese horseradish, during a meal of sushi. <PERSON> Spitzer </PERSON>'s letter was headlined: `` Horseradish Horrors: Sushi Syncope.'' <PERSON> Syncope </PERSON> means fainting. The follow-up letter by Ms. <PERSON> Rubin </PERSON> and <PERSON> Wu </PERSON> carried the headline `` The Bitter Herbs of Seder: More on Horseradish Horrors.'' Ms. <PERSON> Rubin </PERSON> said horseradish usually is grated. But the night her father collapsed, the family ground it in a food processor, then placed it in an airtight container, preventing vapors from escaping and making the horseradish unusually potent. <PERSON> Wu </PERSON> said the collapse probably occurred because the horseradish vapors caused a reflexive drop in blood pressure. Coupled with the elder <PERSON> Rubin </PERSON>'s consumption of Passover wine and use of medicine to reduce his high blood pressure, that briefly deprived the brain of enough blood. `` He still eats horseradish,'' Ms. <PERSON> Rubin </PERSON> said. `` My dad is sort of macho.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880402-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-02-88 0042EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-HashBash     04-02 0250</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Hash Bash,0258</SECOND>
<HEAD>400 Get High On Pot Reform</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ANN ARBOR, Mich. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 About 400 people huffed and puffed Friday at the 17th annual Hash Bash, a spring rally for the legalization of marijuana. Police made no arrests and issued no citations during the event on the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION> campus. University officials had issued a permit for the event but emphasized they were not endorsing it. Possession of small amounts of marijuana in <LOCATION> Ann </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arbor </LOCATION> is punishable by a $ 5 fine. `` I've been coming to this since I was a little boy,'' said a 29-year-old who called himself Jizmo Noodles and was one of the first to light up. `` My first one was in 1973. It's a means of expression, civil disobedience.'' Noodles, carrying incense and wearing jeans, a T-shirt and a denim vest with a peace sign, described himself as a `` student of life.'' <PERSON> Jon </PERSON> <PERSON> Gettman </PERSON>, assistant director of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> for the Reform of Marijuana Laws, or <ORGANIZATION> NORML </ORGANIZATION>, told the gathering that pot smokers were tired of being labeled criminals. `` We're here for a lot of different reasons today,'' he said. `` A lot of people think that because this is April Fools' Day, that this is some some kind of a joke. We are serious, very serious.'' <ORGANIZATION> NORML </ORGANIZATION> wants marijuana legalized, with taxes on it used to develop treatment centers for cocaine and heroin users. <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Amicone </PERSON>, sophomore history major, said he started smoking marijuana at 16. `` I got a late start,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880402-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-02-88 0112EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-WashingtoninBrief     04-02 0788</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Washington in Brief,780</SECOND>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 American corporations that owe taxes to <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> will be allowed the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> foreign tax credit if payments are made to the government of ousted President <PERSON> Eric </PERSON> <PERSON> Arturo </PERSON> <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> Internal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Revenue </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> says. Friday's announcement was aimed at discouraging <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> businesses from sending tax payments to the Panamanian government controlled by military strongman <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>, which <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> does not recognize. Some large U.S.-based multinational firms recently made quarterly tax payments just in time to give that government a desperately needed infusion of cash. The foreign tax credit is designed to prevent two national governments from taxing the same dollar of income. In general, the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> will not tax income that an American corporation earns in and pays taxes on to a foreign country. <LOCATION> WASHINGTON </LOCATION> -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> -RRB- _ The <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Accounting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> recommends mandatory inspection of all nuclear power plants for pipe deterioration following findings that nearly one-third of the nation's commercial reactors already have such a problem. The congressional watchdog agency deemed the industry-wide inspections necessary after reviewing actions taken by the <ORGANIZATION> Nuclear </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Regulatory </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> and the utilities themselves since a pipe rupture at the <ORGANIZATION> Surry </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Unit </ORGANIZATION> 2 plant in <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> killed four workers in late 1986. Rep. <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Markey </PERSON>, D-Mass., who released the <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION> report, declared that the <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` failure to act aggressively on this matter is astounding. After the Surry accident, the <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION> did develop evidence of widespread pipe deterioration at the Trojan nuclear plant in <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION>, and as of Jan. 21 this year the commission had identified a total of 34 plants with at least some pipe damage caused by erosion or corrosion. In defense of the <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION>'s approach, <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Newlin </PERSON>, a commission spokesman, said the commission had sent out `` several notices'' to the industry asking them to inspect their own plants and report back. <LOCATION> WASHINGTON </LOCATION> -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> -RRB- _ Taking advantage of an appeals court ruling earlier this week, the <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> has ordered a resumption of random drug testing of civilian employees in certain critical jobs. `` The directive went out today,'' <PERSON> Paige </PERSON> <PERSON> Eversole </PERSON>, an <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman at the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION>, said Friday. `` It orders resumption of the program effective immediately.'' The move had been expected since Tuesday, when a federal appeals court struck down a preliminary injunction that had stopped the drug-testing program a month ago. A three-judge panel of the <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Circuit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appeals </ORGANIZATION> said it was staying the injunction granted to employee unions while it considered the legal merits of the case. <LOCATION> WASHINGTON </LOCATION> -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> -RRB- _ The <ORGANIZATION> Veterans </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> is raising its maximum interest rate for federally backed <ORGANIZATION> VA </ORGANIZATION> home mortgages by one-half percentage point to 10 percent. The <ORGANIZATION> VA </ORGANIZATION> said it was making the change, which will take effect Sunday, to reflect recent increases in interest rates in financial markets. In the past 12 months, the <ORGANIZATION> VA </ORGANIZATION> rate has been changed seven times, fluctuating between 9.5 percent and 11 percent. The last change was Feb. 1, when the rate was lowered a full percentage point from 10.5 percent to 9.5 percent. The <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Home </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Loan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mortgage </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> said Friday that the national average for 30-year conventional mortgages, those without government guarantees, rose above 10 percent for the first time since late January. The national average rate was 10.05 percent, up from 9.99 percent the previous week. <LOCATION> WASHINGTON </LOCATION> -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> -RRB- _ The <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> has rewritten its contracts covering development of the new Midgetman mobile nuclear missile, canceling almost $ 1 billion worth of work planned by six contractors. The service, in a brief statement, stressed it could not speak for the six contractors involved but estimated the cutbacks could affect the jobs of as many as 2,300 private-sector employees. The <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> action became inevitable several months ago when <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Carlucci </PERSON> decided the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> could not afford to develop and deploy the single-warhead Midgetman within the budget levels set by the White House and <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> had recommended <PERSON> Carlucci </PERSON> kill the program outright, but the <ORGANIZATION> defense </ORGANIZATION> secretary decided to request $ 200 million in fiscal 1989 to keep the program alive pending a final decision by the next president. <LOCATION> WASHINGTON </LOCATION> -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> -RRB- _ The <ORGANIZATION> Food </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Drug </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> is warning consumers not to use <PERSON> Nutrien </PERSON> and Vitalite powdered drink mixes because they may be contaminated with salmonella bacteria. Both products are nutritional supplements marketed as powdered drink mixes by Sunrider International of <LOCATION> Torrance </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, and marketed nationally through more than 37,000 independent distributors, generally individuals who sell them door-to-door or to friends. The <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> reported there have been at least seven cases of illness associated with the products. It said <PERSON> Sunrider </PERSON> has agreed to begin a nationwide recall, but has not supplied the agency with specific distribution information.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880402-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-02-88 0051EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Philippines-Escape 6thLd-Writethru a0435 04-02 0651</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Philippines-Escape, 6th Ld - Writethru, a0435,0666</SECOND>
<HEAD>Coup Leader Honasan Escapes From Navy Prison Ship</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: LEADS with two grafs to CLARIFY that those who escaped with
Honasan were his guards. Picks up 3rd graf, `Chief of ...</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT H. REID</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MANILA, Philippines (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The leader of the August coup attempt that almost toppled the government of President <PERSON> Corazon </PERSON> <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON> escaped Saturday from his prison ship in <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION>, the military announced. A statement said former Lt. Col. <PERSON> Gregorio </PERSON> `` Gringo'' <PERSON> Honasan </PERSON> fled at about 2:30 a.m. Saturday -LRB- 1:30 p.m. EST Friday -RRB- aboard two rubber boats along with 13 of his guards. Chief of Staff Gen. <PERSON> Renato </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Villa </PERSON> ordered a massive search for the 39-year-old <PERSON> Honasan </PERSON> and alerted subordinate commands nationwide to be on the lookout for him. The charismatic former lieutenant colonel had been detained on the navy ship since his arrest last December in a <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION> suburb. Col. <PERSON> Oscar </PERSON> <PERSON> Florendo </PERSON>, chief military spokesman, said a reserve lieutenant who was frustrated over his inability to obtain a regular commission had aided in the getaway. <PERSON> Florendo </PERSON> said the boats used in the escape had been sent to increase security after the military learned of a plot to free <PERSON> Honasan </PERSON>. <PERSON> De </PERSON> <PERSON> Villa </PERSON> immediately relieved the commander of the vessel, the RPS <PERSON> Andres </PERSON> <PERSON> Bonifacio </PERSON>, and ordered his arrest, <PERSON> Florendo </PERSON> said in a radio address. He appealed to the public to provide information to help recapture <PERSON> Honasan </PERSON>. <PERSON> Honasan </PERSON>, former chief of security at the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION>, played a key role in the Feb. 22, 1986, mutiny which triggered the popular uprising that toppled President <PERSON> Ferdinand </PERSON> <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON>. But <PERSON> Honasan </PERSON> became disillusioned with <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON>' successor, President <PERSON> Corazon </PERSON> <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON>, accusing her of `` weak and inept'' leadership that fortified the 18-year-old communist insurgency. On Aug. 28, <PERSON> Honasan </PERSON> led a force of 2,000 men who attacked the presidential palace and seized several media and military installations in the capital before they were driven off by pro-Aquino forces. The coup attempt left 53 people dead and wounded hundreds, and Mrs. <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON> said it was aimed at killing her and her family. <PERSON> Honasan </PERSON>'s effort was the most serious of several major plots to unseat Mrs. <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON>'s government. Military sources, speaking on condition of anonymity, said the former colonel was so popular that he had become the `` dominant figure'' aboard the ship which was supposed to be his prison. `` It is with sadness that the AFP -LRB- Armed Forces of the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION> -RRB- makes public the unfortunate escape from custody of ex-Col. <PERSON> Gregorio </PERSON> <PERSON> Honasan </PERSON> from his detention,'' <PERSON> Florendo </PERSON> said in a statement `` During a normal inspection of the ship, it was discovered that subject detainee together with his guards headed by Lt. j.g. <PERSON> Gerardo </PERSON> <PERSON> Mojica </PERSON> and 12 enlisted personnel were found missing. `` Initial investigation revealed that <PERSON> Honasan </PERSON> was apparently assisted and joined by his guards led by Lt j.g. <PERSON> Mojica </PERSON> ... It is believed that bribery was a factor that led to the betrayal of their oath and sworn duty.'' <PERSON> Florendo </PERSON> said <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Villa </PERSON> had alerted the military to take precautions to ensure that <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> rebels did not take advantage of the confusion to launch `` terroristic actions.'' The spokesman said troops were being deployed around <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION> to search for <PERSON> Honasan </PERSON>. <PERSON> Florendo </PERSON> said the military received information a week ago that <PERSON> Honasan </PERSON> would try to escape and it sent rubber boats to guard the ship. He said the military expected outsiders to try to storm the vessel but `` instead it came from the inside.'' <PERSON> Honasan </PERSON> was security chief of the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> when opposition Sen. <PERSON> Juan </PERSON> <PERSON> Ponce </PERSON> <PERSON> Enrile </PERSON> was minister of national defense. <PERSON> Enrile </PERSON> was fired in November 1986 after the government said it thwarted a coup attempt by his followers. <PERSON> Honasan </PERSON> remained in hiding for months after the August coup. Brig. Gen. <PERSON> Ramon </PERSON> <PERSON> Montano </PERSON>, commander of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Capital </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Regional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Command </ORGANIZATION>, said weeks before the arrest that <PERSON> Honasan </PERSON> was being protected by undisclosed civilian and military figures.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880402-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-02-88 0111EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i BC-Japan-Stocks     04-02 0027</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Japan-Stocks,0026</SECOND>
<HEAD>Market Up In Tokyo</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Nikkei Stock Average closed at 26,282.12 points, up 177.90 points, on the <ORGANIZATION> Tokyo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Stock </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Exchange </ORGANIZATION> Saturday.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880402-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-02-88 0139EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     04-02 0772</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0807</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in the News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON> <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON>, one of the `` founding fathers'' of broadcast journalism, signed off after more than four decades on the air by thanking his coworkers and his viewers during his last TV appearance for CBS. `` And so ends the chapter of almost 46 years as this reporter moves on along the journey,'' <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON>, 70, said on Friday's midday `` CBS <LOCATION> Newsbreak </LOCATION>.'' `` A deep bow of gratitude, love and respect to the men and women of <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> and to the company for which they stand. To you out there, thank you for honoring me with your presence in my audience, and most of all for your voices, your most sweet voices. <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON> <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>.'' <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON> was the nation's first nightly TV anchorman, preceding <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> Cronkite </PERSON> in the job at <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> in 1948. <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON> joined <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Radio </ORGANIZATION> in 1942, and was a member of <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Murrow </PERSON>'s legendary <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> staff toward the end of World War II. He also served as <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> bureau chief. <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON>' last radio broadcast was Friday night. At its close, <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> vice president <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Dembo </PERSON> wished <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON> `` goodbye and Godspeed,'' and <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Evening </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> anchorman <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Rather </PERSON> saluted him as `` one of the founding fathers'' of broadcast journalism. President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> sent a congratulatory letter calling <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON> a `` consummate professional.'' <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON> plans to move to <LOCATION> Sarasota </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>, and continue lecturing on broadcast journalism while he starts work on a book.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actress <PERSON> Britt </PERSON> <PERSON> Ekland </PERSON> has given birth to her third child, an 8-pound, 12-ounce boy named <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Jefferson </PERSON> <PERSON> Ekland </PERSON> <PERSON> McDonnell </PERSON>, her manager says. The baby, born Thursday at <ORGANIZATION> Cedars-Sinai </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>, is Miss <PERSON> Ekland </PERSON>'s first child with husband <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> McDonnell </PERSON>, manager <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Cohen </PERSON> said Friday. Miss <PERSON> Ekland </PERSON> and <PERSON> McDonnell </PERSON>, former drummer for the Stray Cats rock group have been married four years. Miss <PERSON> Ekland </PERSON>, 45, has appeared in more than 30 films, including such movies as `` The Man With the Golden Gun.'' Her other children are <ORGANIZATION> Victoria </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sellers </ORGANIZATION>, 23, and <PERSON> Nickolai </PERSON> <PERSON> Edland </PERSON> <PERSON> Adler </PERSON>, 14.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>SALEM, Ore. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Gov. <PERSON> Neil </PERSON> <PERSON> Goldschmidt </PERSON> will play host next week to an ex-boss _ former President <PERSON> Jimmy </PERSON> <PERSON> Carter </PERSON>. <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> is coming to <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION> to give a lecture at <ORGANIZATION> Linfield </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> in nearby <LOCATION> McMinnville </LOCATION>, and plans to stay Wednesday night at the governor's residence here, <PERSON> Goldschmidt </PERSON> spokesman <PERSON> Gregg </PERSON> <PERSON> Kantor </PERSON> said Friday. <PERSON> Goldschmidt </PERSON> served as secretary of transportation under <PERSON> Carter </PERSON>. <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> also plans to spend some time vacationing in <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Kantor </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>Eds: A version also moving sports wires.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>GREENBRAE, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Hall of Fame pitcher <PERSON> Vernon </PERSON> `` Lefty'' <PERSON> Gomez </PERSON> was hospitalized after complaining of chest pains, and was expected to remain in the hospital for several days, a hospital spokeswoman said. <PERSON> Gomez </PERSON>, 79, was in improved condition, <ORGANIZATION> Marin </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION> nursing supervisor <PERSON> Diana </PERSON> <PERSON> Rich </PERSON> said Friday night. `` He's doing very well, but he'll be here awhile longer,'' she said. <PERSON> Gomez </PERSON> has a longstanding heart condition. He was driven to the hospital by his wife, June, from their home in nearby <LOCATION> Novato </LOCATION>, 25 miles north of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION>. `` If he lets me drive him, he has to be sick,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Gomez </PERSON> said. `` Thirteen years ago he had a heart attack and he drove me to the hospital. He said he did n't trust me to drive. Then he had a triple bypass.'' <PERSON> Gomez </PERSON>, a strong left-hander who pitched for 14 years in the major leagues, all but one year with the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Yankees </ORGANIZATION>, had a career record of 189-102. He was 6-0 in appearances in five World Series.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>CHICAGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Performers <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Cray </PERSON>, <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Collins </PERSON> and <PERSON> Kim </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> of The Fabulous Thunderbirds are to headline a benefit concert Sunday for Grammy-winning blues singer <PERSON> Koko </PERSON> <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON>, who was injured in an auto accident. Miss <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON>, known as the `` Queen of the Blues,'' suffered broken ribs and a broken collarbone in the Feb. 4 accident, which also injured three band members. `` It was a disaster, but we are so fortunate to be alive,'' Miss <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON> said in a telephone interview Friday from her <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> home. `` I'm very thankful that so many people think so much of me to put on this benefit.'' Sunday's benefit will raise money to pay for the $ 40,000 in medical bills, said <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Iglauer </PERSON>, president of <ORGANIZATION> Alligator </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Records </ORGANIZATION>, who helped arrange the event at the <LOCATION> Riviera </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Nightclub </LOCATION>. Miss <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON> said she was unsure whether she'll be able to attend. But she was grateful for the support, and for the thousands of cards and letters she's received. `` It makes me know there are lots of people out there that care,'' she said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880402-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-02-88 0148EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-Drive-ByShootings     04-02 0212</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Drive-By Shootings,0220</SECOND>
<HEAD>One Dies, 10 Wounded in Drive-By Shooting</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Gunmen in a passing car opened fire indiscriminately on people gathered in several groups along a street Friday night, killing one and wounding at least 10, police said. Among the wounded was a 4-year-old boy shot four times, a hospital spokeswoman said. The shooting started around 7:20 p.m. when several gunmen in a car `` indiscriminately fired at people who were on a sidewalk,'' said Deputy Police Chief <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Rathburn </PERSON>. At least 11 people initially were reported wounded, although <PERSON> Rathburn </PERSON> said others may have been hit. Four people were taken to <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> County-USC Medical Center, where a 19-year-old man shot in the right side was pronounced dead, said hospital spokeswoman <PERSON> Adelaida </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> la </PERSON> <PERSON> Certa </PERSON>. The 4-year-old boy was in serious but stable condition, Ms. <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> la </PERSON> <PERSON> Certa </PERSON> said. A 29-year-old man hit in the right hand and right leg and a 20-year-old man shot in the left leg were both in fair condition. The other seven wounded were taken to other hospitals, she said. Drive-by shootings have become a problem in recent months in the <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> area. Police have attributed many of them to gang wars, but did not say if Friday's shootings were gang-related.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880402-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-02-88 0204EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-CometTheory Bjt   04-02 0603</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Comet Theory, Bjt,0618</SECOND>
<HEAD>New Evidence That Millions Of Small Comets Hit Earth Each Year</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LEE SIEGEL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Science Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PASADENA, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Two years after an <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> physicist nearly ruined his reputation by suggesting that 10 million small, speedy comets hit Earth's atmosphere annually, a <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> scientist has found evidence supporting <PERSON> Louis </PERSON> <PERSON> Frank </PERSON>'s theory. `` I'm happy, but it's been a long two years,'' <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> said Friday, adding that he was met with `` total disbelief'' and `` lost a lot of friends'' after proposing that billions of water-bearing comets could have provided enough water to fill the seas during <LOCATION> Earth </LOCATION>'s early history. Other scientists said they remained skeptical of the new evidence, which came from telescope observations by <PERSON> Clayne </PERSON> <PERSON> Yeates </PERSON>, a physicist at the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aeronautics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Space </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>'s Jet Propulsion Laboratory here `` I'm very convinced that what I'm seeing is real,'' said <PERSON> Yeates </PERSON>, who is deputy project scientist for the planned 1989 launch of the Galileo space probe to <LOCATION> Jupiter </LOCATION>. `` These objects would not have been seen inadvertently during other searches. They're small, they're dark and they're moving fast.'' The theory by <PERSON> Frank </PERSON>, a physicist at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Iowa </ORGANIZATION>, is `` one of the decade's most controversial astronomical theories,'' a <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> news release said. <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> proposed the theory after ultraviolet photographs of Earth taken by <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION>'s Dynamics Explorer 1 spacecraft between 1981 and 1986 revealed countless dark spots that appeared to be tiny holes in <LOCATION> Earth </LOCATION>'s atmosphere. He theorized that about 10 million comets, essentially 30-foot-diameter fluffy snowballs with a dark coating, plunge into the atmosphere each year, forming holes, then breaking up and vaporizing. <PERSON> Yeates </PERSON> said his observations on the 36-inch Spacewatch Telescope at <ORGANIZATION> Kitt </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Peak </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Observatory </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION> make him believe that at least a million such comets hit the atmosphere annually at a speed of 22,000 mph. The comets appeared as white streaks on enhanced telescope images, he said. In a telephone interview from <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> said a soon-to-be-published study, in which atmospheric holes were recently observed by <LOCATION> Sweden </LOCATION>'s Viking spacecraft, also supports his theory. `` I'm a little skeptical,'' said astronomer <PERSON> Anita </PERSON> <PERSON> Cochran </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION> at <LOCATION> Austin </LOCATION>. `` He -LRB- <PERSON> Yeates </PERSON> -RRB- may be seeing something, but to leap to 10-meter comets is a fairly large leap of imagination.'' <PERSON> Cochran </PERSON> voiced the most common objection to <PERSON> Frank </PERSON>'s theory: If so many icy comets hit Earth's atmosphere, they also should strike the <LOCATION> moon </LOCATION>, creating a lot of water vapor. Yet the <LOCATION> moon </LOCATION> has very little water vapor. University of <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION> physicist and planetary scientist <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Donahue </PERSON> said that until he examines <PERSON> Yeates </PERSON>' findings, `` I'm not going to say this sounds like confirmation of <PERSON> Frank </PERSON>'s comets or not. But it certainly is exciting.'' About a year ago, <PERSON> Donahue </PERSON> used 1977 data from the Voyager 2 space probe to show that Earth's atmosphere contained an excess of hydrogen atoms released from water vapor. He said the discovery could be consistent with <PERSON> Frank </PERSON>'s theory, but also could be explained if the hydrogen came from 10 million times fewer comets that were smaller, faster and much more active than those postulated by <PERSON> Frank </PERSON>. The less abundant comets would n't provide enough water to fill the oceans, <PERSON> Donahue </PERSON> said. `` I really am a bit skeptical'' of <PERSON> Yeates </PERSON>' observations, said <PERSON> Brian </PERSON> <PERSON> Marsden </PERSON>, associate director for planetary sciences at the Harvard-Smithsonian Center for Astrophysics in <LOCATION> Cambridge </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mass </LOCATION>. `` If they -LRB- comets -RRB- are as numerous as he's talking about, then some of these should show up when the telescope is in more normal operation, and they have n't,'' <PERSON> Marsden </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> said only two specialized telescopes in the country, including Spacewatch, are capable of observing the comets.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880402-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-02-88 0206EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-PoliticalBriefs     04-02 0558</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Political Briefs,550</SECOND>
<HEAD>Koch Says Jackson as President Would Bankrupt U.S. in 3 Weeks</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Mayor <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> I. </PERSON> <PERSON> Koch </PERSON> says he disagrees with <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> on virtually every issue, but will vote for <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> if he is the Democratic presidential nominee. `` I think that in three weeks, based on all the social programs we would be putting into effect -LRB- under <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> -RRB-, if you did everything he said he wanted to do, we'd be in bankruptcy,'' <PERSON> Koch </PERSON> said Friday. `` People know that's pie in the sky.'' In response, <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s campaign manager, <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Austin </PERSON>, said <PERSON> Koch </PERSON> has `` solidified his position in the national exaggeration hall of fame.'' <PERSON> Koch </PERSON> said <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> is `` on the wrong side of every issue I know of with two exceptions: drugs _ he's great in opposition to drugs _ and he's great in talking about the need for family responsibility and particularly as it relates to education. `` On the economy, he's terrible. We'd be in bankruptcy.'' Nevertheless, the mayor said, he'd vote for <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> if he were the nominee out of party loyalty and because `` he'd be better than -LRB- Vice President <PERSON> George </PERSON> -RRB- <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>.'' In <LOCATION> Green </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wis. </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> told reporters he had not heard of <PERSON> Koch </PERSON>'s remarks. But when they were described to him he said, `` That's unfortunate. I should not dignify that statement.''
</TEXT>
<HEAD>___</HEAD>
<HEAD>Iowa Democrats Vow Big Push Against LaRouche Backers</HEAD>
<DATELINE>DES MOINES, Iowa (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> Democrats say they'll expose and work to defeat supporters of political extremist <PERSON> Lyndon </PERSON> <PERSON> LaRouche </PERSON> who filed as Democrats to run in legislative and congressional primaries. `` What they seek to do is clothe themselves with the respectability and tradition of the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> in order to further their misguided beliefs,'' said House Speaker <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Avenson </PERSON>. `` I will use all the available resources to ensure the defeat of LaRouche candidates in every Democratic primary contest.'' `` They apparently feel this is fertile ground, but we are going to teach them a major lesson,'' said <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Shanahan </PERSON>, who runs legislative elections for the party. Their alarm grew out of the number of <PERSON> LaRouche </PERSON> supporters meeting Friday's deadline for filing nomination papers to run in the June 8 primary for legislative and congressional seats. <PERSON> Roeder </PERSON> and <PERSON> Shanahan </PERSON> said they've identified 16 <PERSON> LaRouche </PERSON> supporters who had filed nominating petitions to run in the Democratic primary.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>___</HEAD>
<HEAD>Dukakis Picks Nebraska Campaign Chairs</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LINCOLN, Neb. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Gov. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> has named former Lincoln Mayor <PERSON> Helen </PERSON> <PERSON> Boosalis </PERSON> and former <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committeemen </ORGANIZATION> <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Morgan </PERSON> as co-chairmen of his presidential campaign in <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION>, the campaign announced. Mrs. <PERSON> Boosalis </PERSON> was the unsuccessful <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> candidate for governor in 1986 and is a former director of the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aging </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Morgan </PERSON>, a rancher, was active in former Vice President <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> Mondale </PERSON>'s 1984 presidential campaign in <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>___</HEAD>
<HEAD>Anaya Says Nation, Jackson Matured</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PUEBLO, Colo. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Both <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> have matured to the point where <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> could become president, says former <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Toney </PERSON> <PERSON> Anaya </PERSON>. <PERSON> Anaya </PERSON> on Friday was priming <PERSON> Pueblo </PERSON> voters for <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s campaign swing through <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION> today and Sunday. The political climate is `` getting warmer every day,'' <PERSON> Anaya </PERSON> said, and <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s `` time has come.'' <PERSON> Anaya </PERSON> said <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> has come a long way from being the `` anti-establishment'' candidate he projected himself as four years ago, when he finished third to <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> Mondale </PERSON> and <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Hart </PERSON> among Democratic candidates.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880402-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-02-88 0213EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Panama Bjt   04-02 0622</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Panama, Bjt,0641</SECOND>
<HEAD>Jailed Opposition Leader Called ``Hostage''; U.S. Boosts Military
Presence</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DOUGLAS GRANT MINE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PANAMA CITY, Panama (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Soldiers were off the streets as Easter weekend began and a jailed opposition leader's wife said her husband was being held hostage in Gen. <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>'s effort to maintain power Also Friday, the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> said it was sending 1,300 more military personnel to protect <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> bases and thousands of <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> residents, bringing to nearly 12,000 the number of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> troops in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>. Opposition leaders said they planned to meet today or Sunday to decide whether to lift a 12-day-old general strike that has shut down most commercial activity in an effort to oust <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s de facto leader and heads of its 15,000-member <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forces </ORGANIZATION>. Virtually all businesses were closed for Good Friday. The general strike had eased earlier in the week, with groceries and pharmacies reopening, reportedly under government pressure. In the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, news reports said <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration officials had discussed trying to force <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> from power through military intervention, kidnapping or by arranging a coup. The general is under <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> indictment on drug trafficking charges. <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Gonzalez </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> la </PERSON> <PERSON> Lastra </PERSON>, a top leader of the opposition National Civic Crusade, spent his fifth day in jail Friday. Other Crusade leaders and several journalists arrested with him Monday had all been released by midday Tuesday. `` All legal efforts on his behalf have been useless,'' <PERSON> Vilma </PERSON> <PERSON> Gonzalez </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> la </PERSON> <PERSON> Lastra </PERSON> told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> Friday night. `` They have not charged him, but they do n't let him go. `` We consider <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> a political hostage,'' she said of her husband. The Pentagon said many of the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> personnel to be dispatched next week are military police, but army helicopter units will be included. The <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Command </ORGANIZATION>, based in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>, had about 600 security personnel among its 10,000 troopers before <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> intensified its campaign for <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>'s removal. Over a 10-day period that ended March 24, the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> dispatched 670 more security personnel to <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> for the stated purpose of protecting military facilities. Southern Command spokesman Col. <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Sconyers </PERSON> said the latest troop increase was prompted by `` a longstanding look at what has been going on down here.'' He said it was not made in anticipation of an imminent departure of <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> and any instability that might follow. No evacuation plans have been discussed with the 45,000 Americans living in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>, he added. Limitations on movement for <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military personnel were decreased Friday to the lowest of four levels for the first time since the crisis began Feb. 26, permitting them to move freely but avoid crowds and demonstrations. Panamanian police patrols replaced soldiers Friday for the first time since a failed March 16 coup attempt against <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>. It was an indication of how the city has quieted for the holiday weekend, after weeks of protest. Banks have been closed since March 3, and Panamanians who had cash appeared to be using it only for essentials. Despite rumors the decision to lift the strike had been made, two Crusade leaders, <PERSON> Roberto </PERSON> <PERSON> Aleman </PERSON> and <PERSON> Luis </PERSON> <PERSON> Casco </PERSON> <PERSON> Arias </PERSON>, said that was not the case. `` To the contrary, no decision on that will be made until we are able to meet to discuss it,'' said <PERSON> Casco </PERSON> <PERSON> Arias </PERSON>. The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Private </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Enterprise </ORGANIZATION>, an umbrella group of business organizations, has decided to continue the stoppage, <PERSON> Aleman </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> supporters in the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Legislature </ORGANIZATION> ousted civilian President <PERSON> Eric </PERSON> <PERSON> Arturo </PERSON> <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON> on Feb. 26 after <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON> tried to fire the general. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> subsequently froze Panamanian government deposits in <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> banks in an effort to drive out <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>. The shortage of money and a run on <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s banks forced them to shut down.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880402-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-02-88 0226EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Salvador     04-02 0478</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Salvador,0495</SECOND>
<HEAD>Right-Wing Party Vows to Seek Nullification of Assembly Election</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ANNIE CABRERA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SAN SALVADOR, El Salvador (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The right-wing <ORGANIZATION> Nationalist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> has vowed to seek a nullification of the <ORGANIZATION> Legislative </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION> elections, in which it fell short of a clear majority by gaining 30 of the 60 seats. Party leaders accused the <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Elections </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> of manipulating the official results of the March 20 balloting, which were announced Friday. The council said the party known by its Spanish acronym <PERSON> Arena </PERSON> won 30 seats, President <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Napoleon </PERSON> <PERSON> Duarte </PERSON>'s centrist <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democrat </ORGANIZATION> 23 and the conservative <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conciliation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> seven. Arena emerged as the strongest single party, replacing the <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democrats </ORGANIZATION>, but its failure to win a majority could produce a legislative deadlock during <PERSON> Duarte </PERSON>'s final year in office. National Conciliation lawmakers were reported considering an alignment with the <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democrats </ORGANIZATION>. That would give them the balance of power on major issues and counter <PERSON> Arena </PERSON>'s strength. In the outgoing <ORGANIZATION> Legislative </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION>, elected in March 1984, the <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democrats </ORGANIZATION> had 33 seats and <PERSON> Arena </PERSON> 13. <PERSON> Mario </PERSON> <PERSON> Samayoa </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> elections </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> council </ORGANIZATION> and a director of the <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, said the final results presented an `` interesting situation because no party will predominate.'' He also said that while the computer count of votes for mayors in the nation's 262 municipalities was not complete, it appeared <PERSON> Arena </PERSON> candidates had won in 178 races. The elections council report was denounced by angry <PERSON> Arena </PERSON> leaders, who earlier had claimed their party won 35 assembly seats and a firm majority. On Tuesday, <PERSON> Arena </PERSON> removed its representative from the panel of observers from the three major parties overseeing the vote count. <PERSON> Francisco </PERSON> <PERSON> Merino </PERSON>, the Arena representative, said the <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democrat </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conciliation </ORGANIZATION> delegates were trying to make a `` game of the vote tallies in order to change the results of the elections.'' <PERSON> Roberto </PERSON> <PERSON> d'Aubuisson </PERSON>, the former army major who founded <PERSON> Arena </PERSON>, said the alliance would petition the council to nullify the official results and if that was rejected the issue would be taken to the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>. Three days after the election, <PERSON> d'Aubuisson </PERSON> had said `` we do n't want to promote violence But we want to play clean and they wo n't let us. <PERSON> Samayoa </PERSON> said Friday that <PERSON> Arena </PERSON> would have to accept the results and `` re-evaluate its positions.'' The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Private </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Enterprise </ORGANIZATION> declared it would call a general strike if the elections council did not report an <PERSON> Arena </PERSON> majority. <PERSON> Duarte </PERSON>, a staunch <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> ally, was elected in 1984 and is barred by the constitution from seeking another five year term next year. In the 1984 campaign he pledged to improve the economy and end the 8-year-old war with leftist rebels. Arena had based its campaign this year on the continuing conflict, unemployment estimated at 40 percent and inflation running at an annual rate of 40 percent.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880402-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-02-88 0230EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Gulf-Mines     04-02 0428</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Gulf-Mines,0446</SECOND>
<HEAD>Navy Robots Successful In Locating Mines</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RICHARD PYLE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MANAMA, Bahrain (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> says it has succeeded in using underwater robots to locate mines in the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> for the first time since mine-sweeping operatons began last year. A spokesman for the Florida-based <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Command </ORGANIZATION> said the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> used the devices to locate two mines in the so-called <LOCATION> Farsi </LOCATION> channel of the northern gulf, where the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> mine-sweeping operations have been concentrated. He spoke on condition he not be identified. On Monday, the mine sweeper Fearless used its new `` Super Sea Rover,'' as the submersible is known, to locate a mine tethered to a seabed anchor in 90 feet of water, he said. On Wednesday, the Fearless' submersible robot found another mine, this time by following an anchor and cable to where the explosive lay on the bottom, the spokesman said Friday. Both mines, covered with a layer of marine growth indicating they had been in the water a long time, were detonated by <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> divers. The <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> also said Friday that it has found and destroyed 41 mines in the gulf since its sweeping operations began. The updated figure doubles the number of mines previously reported to have been destroyed by the Americans. In late November, after the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>'s Korean War-vintage ocean mine sweepers went into action and quickly found 15 mines in the northern gulf, commanders reported the mine threat was `` under control.'' On Friday, when asked about the current situation, the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> said through its spokesman that `` our mine countermeasure force is well-suited for the requirements at hand.'' <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officers have refused to say whether they have found evidence of any recent mine-laying activity by <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>, which is believed to have planted the explosives. The mines found by the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>, as well as about 20 found in other areas of the gulf by the French and the British navies, were all of the 1908-model contact-type, which explode when a ship bumps against their detonator spikes. One such mine damaged the 401,283-ton supertanker <LOCATION> Bridgeton </LOCATION> during the first northbound convoy of U.S.-flagged Kuwaiti tankers July 21. The <LOCATION> Bridgeton </LOCATION> incident prompted the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and five <LOCATION> European </LOCATION> governments to send mine sweepers to the gulf. The Soviets and <LOCATION> Saudi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arabia </LOCATION> also maintain minesweeping vessels in the waterway, where the `` tanker war,'' an offshoot of the 7 -LCB- - year-old Iraq-Iran war, has raged for four years The <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> spokesman said the 41 mines destroyed by the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> are in addition to 14 others that were recovered intact for research purposes.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880402-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-02-88 0245EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-OverseasBrats Bjt   04-02 0552</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Overseas Brats, Bjt,0568</SECOND>
<HEAD>Magazine Helps Reunite Americans Whose Schools Were Far From Home</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID SEDENO</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SAN ANTONIO, Texas (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Overseas Brats, a magazine for Americans who went to high school half a world away from their homeland, is helping them find classmates they have n't seen for years, says its Army brat publisher. `` The difference between stateside graduates and <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> brats, <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> brats, <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> juniors and others is that those in stateside have a hometown to go to for a reunion,'' said publisher and editor <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Condrill </PERSON>. `` But the brats, after they graduate, they leave the military environment and sometimes are lost,'' he said. Military dependents often are seen as pampered kids living off their globe-traveling parents, <PERSON> Condrill </PERSON> said recently. But they endure hardships abroad and often have trouble adjusting to American life, he said. Class reunions help by bringing overseas graduates together, he said. `` These people need someone who understands their predicament,'' said <PERSON> Condrill </PERSON>, 32. At least 1 million people have gone to overseas <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> schools since the institutions were created in 1946, <PERSON> Condrill </PERSON> said. More than 80,000 students attend overseas schools each year and more than 5,000 graduate. `` We're not going to find everybody through the magazine, but at least this is one way of finding some of them,'' said <PERSON> Condrill </PERSON>, whose father was an Army colonel. <PERSON> Condrill </PERSON>, a 1973 graduate of the <ORGANIZATION> Tehran </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> High </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>, said many military dependents are unable to have 10-year high school reunions like graduates of stateside schools because their classes usually are so small. Some can not return to their alma maters because it would be too expensive. Because of the difficulty in organizing reunions, many students who attended a particular overseas school get together, even if they graduated in different years. `` These reunions create incredible bonds,'' <PERSON> Condrill </PERSON> said. `` When you put these people together I'm not surprised to see strangers talking like old friends.'' <PERSON> Condrill </PERSON>, who founded his quarterly magazine in 1986, boasts 1,000 subscribers in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and 12 countries. During the day he works for a floor products company, but spends evenings and weekends answering correspondence or writing stories for Overseas Brats. His byline appears on most stories, but there are a few subscribers who offer articles reminiscing about growing up overseas. The 12-page tabloid also carries announcements about upcoming reunions and personal advertisements that resemble lost-and-found ads. <PERSON> Peggy </PERSON> <PERSON> Roth </PERSON>, a 1976 graduate of <ORGANIZATION> George </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dewey </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> High </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Subic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION>, organized a reunion in 1986 before the magazine was founded. She says the magazine has made finding friends much easier today. `` Overseas Brats has been a big help,'' said the <LOCATION> Arlington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, woman. `` It's interesting reading other people's experiences, and it has made me realize that we are a unique group, sort of a loose fraternity It has helped us unite.'' <PERSON> Condrill </PERSON> also has helped organize reunions. In 1982, only six overseas schools held reunions, but 30 three-day reunions are planned this summer throughout the country, <PERSON> Condrill </PERSON> said. `` This takes them back to a happier time, to a more innocent time in their lives,'' he said. `` At these things they are not talking about kids, about taxes. They feel much younger than they are and they're talking with people who were in the same predicament as they were.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880402-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-02-88 0308EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-PoliticalRdp 1stLd-Writethru a0439 04-02 0731</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Political Rdp, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0439,740</SECOND>
<HEAD>Dukakis Borrows From Populist Playbooks</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: SUBS 2nd graf pvs to CORRECT Dukakis delegate count to 653.55
and INSERTS new 3rd graf to include higher mention of Colorado
caucuses.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By NANCY BENAC</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> is borrowing a few pages from the populist playbooks of rival <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> and ex-rival <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> as the presidential candidates try to drum up delegates in next week's <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION> primary With <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> neck-and-neck in the delegate count thus far _ <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> with 653.55 to <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s 643.55 _ another 81 delegates are at stake in Tuesday's primary in <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION>. Both candidates also planned weekend forays into <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION>, which holds caucuses Monday that begin the selection process for 45 of the state's 51 Democratic delegates and its 36 <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> delegates to the national conventions. The <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> governor on Friday stepped up his quest for blue-collar votes in <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION> by sounding the themes of economic populism that had been articulated by <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> until the <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION> congressman exited the race last month. `` The human cost of seven years of Republican indifference is staggering,'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> said in a television ad that started airing Friday. `` Who in this administration could look right into the eyes of the laid-off factory worker or the homeless family and say they've kept the promise of <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>? I say they've broken that promise.'' The new emphasis was evident in his speeches as well. `` Wall Street pirates and corporate hit teams are n't the model for a new <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> told a crowd of about 500 people crowded into the <ORGANIZATION> Racine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON>, interviewed on the syndicated show `` One on One,'' said he did n't mind seeing his ideas circulate among those left in the race he'd once hoped to finish first. `` Everybody has stolen it,'' he said. `` I willed it to everybody when I pulled out and I hope they will use it. It is the issue of this campaign.'' <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, who sounds the populist message as well, on Friday called for higher prices for farm products and said consumers easily could pick up the tab. `` The fact is farmers deserve fair prices and workers deserve fair wages and the rich must pay fair taxes,'' <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> told a gathering at the farm of Bud and <PERSON> Faye </PERSON> <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Amery </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wis. </LOCATION> `` The reality is if urban people are working, they can pay a few more pennies for a glass of milk or for a cone of ice cream or for a loaf of bread.'' <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, speaking later Friday in <LOCATION> La </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Crosse </LOCATION>, invited disgruntled Republicans to vote for him in Tuesday's primary. For people who made the `` colossal error'' of voting for President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and now `` realize your mistake, you can correct your error,'' he said. <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION> law allows voters to select a candidate from any party regardless of their political affiliation. <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> Sen. <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, lagging behind in the Democratic race, continued to be the main voice of criticism against <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, whose popularity has surged in recent contests. `` An end to bigotry does not mean some candidates are game for criticism and some are immune,'' <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> said. Bringing up the rear was <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Simon </PERSON>, who aimed his fire at <PERSON> Gore </PERSON>. <PERSON> Simon </PERSON>, visiting about 100 supporters at an airport rally in <LOCATION> Eau </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Claire </LOCATION>, accused <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> of making bold promises to farmers and added: `` If you're looking for a candidate with all kinds of easy promises, I'm not your candidate. I voted against the 1985 farm program that caused a drop in milk prices. We have to do better and I wo n't make promises, unlike some people.'' <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> favors government price supports for dairy farms and is proposing a two-tier support formula that he said would help family farms compete against corporate farms. On the Republican side, 47 delegates were at stake in <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION>, with Vice President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> the commanding leader over token competitor <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON>. <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> was spending the weekend in <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION>, which holds caucuses Monday, trying to drum up some support Western-style. His schedule included talks to an estimated 5,000 people in Denver-area congregations on Easter Sunday. <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> has conceded he has virtually no chance of being the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> nominee, but wants to help influence the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> platform at the convention. `` He wants to represent conservatives and Christians in the formation of the platform so that we can have a voice,'' said aide <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880402-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-02-88 0446EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--StupidParade     04-02 0125</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Stupid Parade,0128</SECOND>
<HEAD>`Free the Lunch, Hold the Mayo'</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SAN FRANCISCO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Hundreds of costumed revelers paraded through the Financial District, celebrating `` St. Stupid's Day'' in a parade sponsored by the `` First Church of the Last Laugh.'' The revelers _ most wearing dunce caps, gorilla outfits, roller skates, tap shoes or capes _ chanted `` free the lunch, hold the mayo'' and other nonsensical phrases during the traditional April Fools Day procession Friday. `` This parade is dedicated to the fools, bimbos, bozos and ding-a-lings who know how to have a good time,'' said actor <PERSON> Ed </PERSON> <PERSON> Holmes </PERSON>. Not everyone who saw the affair were entertained. `` I think this is pretty stupid,'' said <PERSON> Alex </PERSON> <PERSON> Nisenbaum </PERSON>, an 8-year-old from <PERSON> Loomis </PERSON> visiting the city. `` Grown-ups are really weird.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880402-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-02-88 0403EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-GangRape     04-02 0464</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Gang Rape,0481</SECOND>
<HEAD>13-Year-Old Girl Raped, Then Robbed of $1</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LAURA MYERS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>RENO, Nev. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Four youths linked to a <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> youth gang were defiant and almost boastful as they admitted raping a 13-year-old girl and stealing a dollar from her, police said. The gang members also were accused of robbing a 17-year-old of his watch and wallet Thursday night, then looking for a girl to rape, Assistant Police Chief <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Kirkland </PERSON> said Friday. `` Last evening they said the sole purpose of them getting together was simply to commit a sexual assault,'' said Lt. <PERSON> Ron </PERSON> <PERSON> Glensor </PERSON>, who interviewed three of the four youths arrested. Police said the youths were defiant and almost boastful as they talked. The youths stole a car Tuesday, decorated it with graffiti, then plotted Thursday's night of crime, <PERSON> Kirkland </PERSON> said. The girl told investigators she was riding her bicycle with her brother and a friend when a car carrying the youths drove by. The strangers threw concrete blocks at her and her two companions, who ran in different directions, she said. The four youths threatened her with an ax handle and force her into the car. She said she was driven to a remote area, raped by all four, robbed of her dollar bill, then dropped off back in town, where she telephoned police. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>, 22, and <PERSON> Marc </PERSON> <PERSON> Banks </PERSON>, 19, were arrested Thursday night for investigation of kidnapping, sexual assault, sexual assault of a victim under the age of 14, robbery and possession of stolen property. They were held under $ 122,500 bail each. If convicted they could face life in prison without parole. <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> and Banks came from the <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> area where the `` Crips'' gang is based, <PERSON> Glensor </PERSON> said. The juveniles, who were not identified, were held in a detention center, and have been charged with the same crimes under juvenile statutes, <PERSON> Glensor </PERSON> said. One, a 16-year-old who has lived in <PERSON> Reno </PERSON> about eight months, told police he was a former member of a <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> Crips gang that was a satanic cult, <PERSON> Glensor </PERSON> said. The other is a 13-year-old apparently recruited from the Reno area. The youths wore all-blue Crips-type clothing, from their bandanas, to jeans, jackets and T-shirts, police said. Pictures of the suspects and other alleged gang members were confiscated from the arrested youths. The pictures showed gang members holding sawed-off shotguns and painting Crips graffiti on walls. Scores of black <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> area youth gangs are broadly affiliated under the Crips banner, and are sometimes opposed to another loose confederation known as the `` Bloods.'' Authorities have become particularly concerned in recent years as gang turf wars over drug dealing have intensified. There have been reports from around the West of Crips members trying to set up drug rings.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880402-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-02-88 0351EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-India-Sikhs     04-02 0430</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-India-Sikhs,0440</SECOND>
<HEAD>Gandhi Urged To Declare Emergency; 14 More Slain As Security
Stepped Up</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW DELHI, India (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Leaders in <LOCATION> Punjab </LOCATION> called on Prime Minister <PERSON> Rajiv </PERSON> <PERSON> Gandhi </PERSON> to impose a state of emergency in their northern state to quell violence by <ORGANIZATION> Sikh </ORGANIZATION> separatists that has killed more than 100 people this week. Late Friday and early today, Sikh extremists killed 14 more people in the <LOCATION> Punjab </LOCATION> state as police stepped up security on <PERSON> Gandhi </PERSON>'s orders, the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> India </ORGANIZATION> reported. The prime minister also called the federally appointed <LOCATION> Punjab </LOCATION> governor, <ORGANIZATION> S.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ray </ORGANIZATION>, to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Delhi </LOCATION> today for urgent consultations on the violence. In addition, police and paramilitary troops began stepping up security on <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>' border with the state, where police say smugglers have been moving large quantities of new weapons to the Sikh extremists, <ORGANIZATION> UNI </ORGANIZATION> said. The latest killings raised to 111 the number of people who have died in <LOCATION> Punjab </LOCATION> since Sunday in attacks blamed on militant Sikhs who have since 1982 been waging a guerrilla war for a separate homeland. So far this year, more than 635 people have died in <LOCATION> Punjab </LOCATION> state, including Hindus and moderate Sikhs. Sikh militants say they are discriminated against by <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>'s Hindu majority. Right-wing Hindu groups called for a general strike in <LOCATION> Amritsar </LOCATION> District today to protest the killings. Residents of the Sikh holy city of <LOCATION> Amritsar </LOCATION> said about half of the city's shops were shuttered today, but government offices and schools remained open and transportion was normal. <LOCATION> Punjab </LOCATION> leaders of <PERSON> Gandhi </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> called Friday for the state of emergency. They included <PERSON> Bhagwan </PERSON> <PERSON> Dass </PERSON>, vice president of the state <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>'s governing committee, two of the state party's general secretaries and a former president. The federal government last month was empowered by Parliament to impose an emergency in a single state to combat `` internal disturbances.'' Under an emergency, the government would have the authority to detain people without warrants, suspend press freedom and take other steps against the militants. Sikhs, whose religion was formed about 500 years ago as an alternative to <LOCATION> Hinduism </LOCATION> and Islam, make up less than 2 percent of <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>'s population of 800 million but are in a majority in <LOCATION> Punjab </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> UNI </ORGANIZATION> said that eight Sikhs, four Hindus and two unidentified people were killed overnight in three districts of <LOCATION> Punjab </LOCATION> by suspected Sikh gunmen. Thirty-seven people were reported killed Thursday night and Friday in the state, the worst one-day toll since March 4, when 45 people were reported slain in a single day, 34 of them at a festival marking the Indian holiday of Holi.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880402-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-02-88 0419EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Panama-Shultz     04-02 0477</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Panama-Shultz,0493</SECOND>
<HEAD>Newspaper Says George Shultz Suggested Noriega Kidnapping, Other
Measures</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Panama Troops, Bjt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Secretary of State <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> has recommended kidnapping Panamanian strongman <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> and a CIA-coordinated military coup as ways of unseating the general, a newspaper reported today. <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> and <PERSON> Elliott </PERSON> <PERSON> Abrams </PERSON>, assistant secretary of state for <LOCATION> Latin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, also suggested landing more than 3,000 <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> soldiers in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> to encourage Panamanian military officers opposed to <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>, said the <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> Times. The proposals were strongly opposed by the <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Carlucci </PERSON>, who labeled them dangerous and ill-timed, said the Times, quoting unidentified administration officials on both sides of the discussion. However, actions still being considered by the Cabinet include fomenting a coup against <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> and landing more than 3,000 soldiers at <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> installations in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> in a show of force, the Times said. A group of Panamanian officers attempted a coup last month, but failed. <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Redman </PERSON>, traveling with <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION>, would not comment on the report. <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> and <PERSON> Abrams </PERSON> suggested sending a special operations team to kidnap <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> and bring him to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> for trial on drug trafficking charges, the newspaper said. A kidnapping was ruled out after opponents argued that the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>' image would be blackened if <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> were accidentally killed during such an attempt, the Times said. They also warned <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> of the repercussions of arresting a foreign leader in his own country to face criminal charges in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> and <PERSON> Abrams </PERSON> also proposed taking unspecified military action inside <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> in response to a request from deposed civilian President <PERSON> Eric </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON>, the newspaper said. <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON> was ousted by <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> last month after he attempted to fire the general. The <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> announced Friday that it was sending about 1,300 additional military personnel to <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> to improve security for <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> bases and for <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> civilians living there. The move fell far short of the steps advocated by <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON>, who urged the use of force against <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> after aides concluded <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> economic pressure on the troubled Central American country was faltering, the Times said. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> already has about 10,000 troops in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> to protect the strategic <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Canal </LOCATION>. An additional 17,000 <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION> citizens live in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>. Pressure against <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>'s regime has been mounting since he was named in a federal indictment alleging he helped drug traffickers move cocaine into the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials have also alleged that <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> was dealing with Cuban President <PERSON> Fidel </PERSON> <PERSON> Castro </PERSON> while was ostensibly cooperating with <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> drug and intelligence agencies. The <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration precipitated an economic crisis in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> last month by cutting off the supply of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> dollars to Panamanian banks. But the maneuver appeared to weaken this week after <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> broke a general strike, seized flour mills and reopened <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s ports.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880402-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-02-88 0502EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Obit-Jordan     04-02 0552</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Obit-Jordan,0573</SECOND>
<HEAD>Jim Jordan, Radio's Fibber McGee, Dies</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RICHARD DE ATLEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Jordan </PERSON>, whose likeable but bumbling <PERSON> Fibber </PERSON> <PERSON> McGee </PERSON> character delighted millions who tuned into radio's classic comedy `` <PERSON> Fibber </PERSON> <PERSON> McGee </PERSON> and <PERSON> Molly </PERSON>'' for 22 years, is dead at age 91 <PERSON> Jordan </PERSON> died Friday at <ORGANIZATION> Beverly </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> about a week after suffering a blood clot in the brain following a fall at his home, said family friend and broadcast personality <PERSON> Fran </PERSON> <PERSON> Allison </PERSON>. `` His show was one of the greatest continuing radio shows that ever existed,'' said <PERSON> Miss </PERSON> <PERSON> Allison </PERSON>, who starred in early television's `` <PERSON> Kukla </PERSON>, Fran and <PERSON> Ollie </PERSON>'' show. `` <PERSON> Fibber </PERSON> <PERSON> McGee </PERSON> and <PERSON> Molly </PERSON>'' was on the <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> radio network from 1935 to 1957. It spawned such maxims as: `` Tai n't funny, <PERSON> McGee </PERSON>,'' `` Heavenly days,'' `` You're a hard man, <PERSON> McGee </PERSON>'' and `` Dad-rat the dad-ratted ...'' Familiar routines included <PERSON> McGee </PERSON>'s overstuffed closet, which always unloaded mercilessly on <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION>'s character whenever it was opened. Even the <PERSON> McGee </PERSON>'s address, 79 <ORGANIZATION> Wistful </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Vista </ORGANIZATION>, became a place on <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s cultural roadmap. Each Tuesday night, <PERSON> Jordan </PERSON> welcomed to his home such unforgettable characters as <ORGANIZATION> Wallace </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wimple </ORGANIZATION>, The Old Timer, Beulah the Maid and Myrt, <PERSON> McGee </PERSON>'s omnipresent telephone operator. `` Even though he had become very frail, his mind and his humor were as fresh as ever. We all adored him,'' said <PERSON> Lenore </PERSON> <PERSON> Kingston </PERSON>, a vice president of <ORGANIZATION> Pacific </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pioneer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Broadcasters </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Jordan </PERSON> had served as chairman of the radio veterans' group. Like the couple in the `` <PERSON> Fibber </PERSON> <PERSON> McGee </PERSON> and <PERSON> Molly </PERSON>'' scripts, the show's stars were married. <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> and <PERSON> Marian </PERSON> <PERSON> Jordan </PERSON> came to radio out of vaudeville to formulate with writer <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Quinn </PERSON> the quintessential situation comedy. `` We do n't like _ I mean, people do n't like _ humor that suggests anything repulsive,'' <PERSON> Jordan </PERSON> said in an interview during the show's height. Anatomy gags, jibes about marriage and mothers-in-law were kept out. `` It is typically American humor, neither the Broadway type nor <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION> influenced,'' <PERSON> Hubbard </PERSON> <PERSON> Keavy </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> wrote in 1940. `` They get their humor from simple things like fixing the brakes or playing checkers. They never just tell jokes. They never step out of character.'' The situations in the show turned on such simple items as Fibber deciding, against <PERSON> Molly </PERSON>'s advice, to tune the piano. His bumbling effort was invariably interrupted by the `` bong-bong'' of the door chimes. The <ORGANIZATION> McGees </ORGANIZATION>' neighbors were a classic set of American humor characters. <PERSON> Hal </PERSON> <PERSON> Peary </PERSON> played the rumbling, pompous <PERSON> Throckmorton </PERSON> <PERSON> Gildersleeve </PERSON>; <PERSON> Cliff </PERSON> <PERSON> Arquette </PERSON> was the cantankerous Old-Timer; <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON> was henpecked <PERSON> Wallace </PERSON> <PERSON> Wimple </PERSON> and <PERSON> Gale </PERSON> <PERSON> Gordon </PERSON>, later a regular on `` The Lucy Show,'' was Mayor La Trivia. After the show ended in 1957, a television version was attempted in <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s 1959-1960 season. Of the original cast, only <PERSON> Peary </PERSON> remained and he played Mayor La Trivia, not <PERSON> Gildersleeve </PERSON>. <PERSON> Jordan </PERSON>, a native of <LOCATION> Peoria </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ill. </LOCATION>, met <PERSON> Marian </PERSON> <PERSON> Driscoll </PERSON> at choir practice when both were in their teens. They married in 1918. The couple began appearing on radio in 1925, but still worked vaudeville because the new medium paid so little. In 10 years of trial-and-error work, they created <PERSON> Fibber </PERSON> <PERSON> McGee </PERSON> and <PERSON> Molly </PERSON>. Mrs. <PERSON> Jordan </PERSON> died of cancer in 1961. <PERSON> Jordan </PERSON> married <PERSON> Gretchen </PERSON> <PERSON> Stewart </PERSON> the following year. She survives him. Other survivors include a son, <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, and daughter, <PERSON> Kathryn </PERSON>, from his marriage to <PERSON> Marian </PERSON>, as well as several grandchildren.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880402-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-02-88 0556EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Drive-byShootings     04-02 0337</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Drive-by Shootings,0348</SECOND>
<HEAD>Police Comb Southside For Gang Members Who Shot 13 People At
Random</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
