<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880916-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-16-88 0158EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-People-Leary     09-16 0519</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-People-Leary,0533</SECOND>
<HEAD>'60s Drug Guru Timothy Leary to Have Head Frozen After Death</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GEORGE GARTIES</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Sixties drug guru <PERSON> Timothy </PERSON> <PERSON> Leary </PERSON> said he's signed up to have his head removed and frozen after he dies for possible resurrection, but he admits the technology is `` a long shot. `` I do n't want to just go belly-up when my <ORGANIZATION> Blue </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION> runs out,'' said the 67-year-old former <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> psychology professor who once advised the youth of <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> to `` tune in, turn on and drop out'' with mind-altering drugs. <PERSON> Leary </PERSON> said Thursday he's formalizing a $ 35,000 agreement to have his head preserved for posterity in so-called `` cryonic suspension'' by the <ORGANIZATION> Alcor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Life </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Extension </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Riverside </LOCATION>. `` It's the second dumbest idea in the world,'' <PERSON> Leary </PERSON> said of cryonics, the practice of freezing the recently dead. `` The first is that you go to the worms. It's a long shot but it's worth a try.'' <ORGANIZATION> Alcor </ORGANIZATION> is best known for a long-running battle with authorities about whether an elderly woman client was actually dead when her head was surgically severed and immersed in liquid nitrogen. A judge backed <ORGANIZATION> Alcor </ORGANIZATION> in its refusal to turn in the head for tests, and the matter remains at a standoff. <PERSON> Leary </PERSON>, who recently has been appearing at colleges and nightclubs after years of relative obscurity, said he has followed developments in cryonics since 1976, when he wrote a paper on 22 alternatives to `` involuntary, irreversible death.'' `` He's been interested the last 30 years in any cutting edge technology,'' explained his agent, <PERSON> Eric </PERSON> <PERSON> Gardner </PERSON>. `` And this, if you'll pardon the expression, is cutting edge technology.'' For his $ 35,000, <PERSON> Leary </PERSON>, who says he is perfecly healthy, would become a member of the non-profit <ORGANIZATION> Alcor </ORGANIZATION> foundation. That gives him the right to have his head surgically removed after death and immersed in liquid nitrogen at minus 320 degrees Fahrenheit. <ORGANIZATION> Alcor </ORGANIZATION> also freezes entire bodies, but <PERSON> Leary </PERSON> said he could n't afford the $ 100,000 price Mainstream scientists scoff at cryonics, but adherents believe the essence of a person's mental or spiritual being resides physically in the brain. That essence could someday be transferred to a mechanically produced or biologically cloned body, said <ORGANIZATION> Alcor </ORGANIZATION>'s president, <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Mondragon </PERSON>. `` There's about as good a chance that they'll be able to bring you back in 50 years than there is that we'll get a good president of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, or that they'll find a cure for the common cold,'' <PERSON> Leary </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Leary </PERSON> does n't think his much-publicized drug use ruined his brain for revival, but is prepared: `` I'd be very happy, if they do n't bring me back, to have it turned over to the neurologists.'' <ORGANIZATION> Alcor </ORGANIZATION> has six heads and two complete bodies frozen in concrete vats of liquid nitrogen, <PERSON> Mondragon </PERSON> said. He said 109 members signed up to be suspended after they die. The controversy over the head of 85-year-old <PERSON> Dora </PERSON> <PERSON> Kent </PERSON> boosted interest in membership and <PERSON> Leary </PERSON>'s endorsement may do the same, said <PERSON> Mondragon </PERSON> `` A lot of people may have negative reactions to Dr. <PERSON> Leary </PERSON>, but people without open minds do n't generally come to us anyway,'' said <PERSON> Mondragon </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880916-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-16-88 2359EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-PollutionSettlement     09-16 0237</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Pollution Settlement,230</SECOND>
<HEAD>Allis-Chalmers Agrees to Pay $4.5 Million Penalty For Pollution</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Allis-Chalmers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> has agreed to pay the federal government $ 4.5 million to clean up 13 hazardous waste sites in seven states, the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> announced Friday. The payment agreement was filed in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, where <ORGANIZATION> Allis-Chalmers </ORGANIZATION>, a Milwaukee-based farm equipment manufacturer, is reorganizing under Chapter 11 of the Bankruptcy Code in <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bankruptcy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>. The $ 4.5 million payment is subject to approval by the federal court. The agreement was the result of the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>'s program to make sure certain environmental cleanup issues are addressed when companies reorganize under federal bankruptcy law, said Assistant Attorney General <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Marzulla </PERSON> of the Land and Natural Resources Division. <PERSON> Marzulla </PERSON> said the firm pledged to pay the government regardless of other obligations under the reorganization proceedings. The $ 4.5 million will be distributed to the following sites: Maxey Flats Nuclear Disposal Site, <LOCATION> Morehead </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ky. </LOCATION>, $ 325,000; <LOCATION> Bluff </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Road </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Landfill </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> S.C. </LOCATION>, $ 15,000; <ORGANIZATION> Peak </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Oil </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Tampa </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>, $ 25,000; <ORGANIZATION> Conservation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chemical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> landfill site, <LOCATION> Gary </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ind. </LOCATION>, $ 40,000; Northside Sanitary landfill-Envirochem, <LOCATION> Zionsville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ind. </LOCATION>, $ 30,000; <ORGANIZATION> Schmalz </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dump </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Site </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Harrison </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Wis. </LOCATION>, $ 2 million; Ninth Avenue Dump Site, <PERSON> Gary </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Ind. </LOCATION>, $ 625,000; <ORGANIZATION> Muskego </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sanitary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Landfill </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Muskego </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wis. </LOCATION>, $ 375,000; <LOCATION> Brookfield </LOCATION> Sanitary landfill -LRB- Loth Disposal Site -RRB-, <LOCATION> Brookfield </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wis. </LOCATION>, $ 125,000; <ORGANIZATION> Lenz </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Oil </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Lemont </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ill. </LOCATION>, $ 295,000; <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. Scrap, <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>, $ 625,000; Interstate Transformer, <LOCATION> Ellwood </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION>, $ 10,000; and <PERSON> Lee </PERSON>'s Lane Landfill, <LOCATION> Louisville </LOCATION>, Ky, $ 10,000.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880916-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-16-88 0100EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-FetalTissue Bjt   09-16 0697</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Fetal Tissue, Bjt,680</SECOND>
<HEAD>Panel Asks Anti-Abortionists If They Can Accept Fetal Tissue
Research</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDs: Committee not expected to arrive at recommendations before
midafternoon EDT; may stand for PMs</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By JERRY ESTILL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BETHESDA, Md. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Near the end of two days of scholarly talk about the ramifications of allowing intentionally aborted fetuses to be used for medical research, a <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institutes </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> advisory committee member sharpened the issue with a simple question: Will there ever be a medical benefit `` great enough'' for anti-abortionists to drop their opposition to using tissue from induced abortions? `` No,'' <PERSON> Kay </PERSON> <PERSON> James </PERSON>, public affairs director of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Right </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> to </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Life </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, told <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Martin </PERSON>, chief of neurology at <ORGANIZATION> Massachusetts </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>. ` No,'' said <PERSON> Judi </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Stafford </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Life </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> League </ORGANIZATION>. A few minutes earlier, <PERSON> Robin </PERSON> <PERSON> Chandler </PERSON> <PERSON> Duke </PERSON>, co-chairwoman of the <ORGANIZATION> Population </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Crisis </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> based in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, had acknowledged the strong opposition of anti-abortionists and said she wished there was some way to reach accommodation over the transplant issue. `` But to hold a nation hostage to a minority group who are opposed to abortion is a tragedy,'' she said. `` They must know that even if it -LRB- abortion -RRB- became illegal, it would still be done. It's just not going to go away It has been with us since the written word.'' Another member of the panel of witnesses, <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorovitz </PERSON>, dean of the college of arts and sciences at <ORGANIZATION> Syracuse </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, told <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> he empathized with his effort to find common ground but suggested the `` intractable polarity'' of positions just outlined by his fellow panelists showed that would be impossible. In the end, <PERSON> Gorovitz </PERSON> predicted, the special advisory committee will simply have to settle on `` the position for which the arguments are best,'' with the realization that one group or the other will be unhappy. `` There is no way out of that,'' <PERSON> Gorovitz </PERSON> said. Retired federal appeals court judge <PERSON> Arlin </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Adams </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION>, the advisory committee chairman, broke the 21-member committee into smaller groups for informal discussions Thursday night and again today. He planned to bring them together late today in hopes they could reach consensus on whether to recommend federal approval of using fetal tissue from induced abortions for research and, if so, what guidelines to recommend to guard against abuses. <PERSON> Adams </PERSON> said he hoped the committee could agree enough by the end of the day to allow a rough draft of a document that would be circulated for further discussion with an eye toward having a formal recommendation ready in time for presentation Dec. 1 to a standing <ORGANIZATION> NIH </ORGANIZATION> committee. Father <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> McCarthy </PERSON>, a Roman Catholic church leader from <LOCATION> Cincinnati </LOCATION>, drew a clear distinction between induced abortions and natural abortions in expressing his opposition to using tissue from the former. `` One might say that the American public becomes accomplices after the fact for these induced abortions'' if its institutions embrace policies that could tend to give a medical value to having an abortion, he said. Several committee members used the term `` custom pregnancy'' as a short way of raising the concern that some woman might become pregnant just to produce an aborted fetus for research _ either for financial gain or in an effort to help a sick relative. `` I do n't think people are as callous about abortion as that premise suggests,'' said <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Murray </PERSON>, director of the <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Biomedical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ethics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> at </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Case </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Western </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reserve </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. `` If we get to that point, I'm deeply worried.'' <PERSON> Murray </PERSON> said he was convinced that guidelines could be drawn to ensure that a woman's decision to have an abortion would be kept totally separate from the decision to allow the remains to be used for research. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Levine </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Yale </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medicine </ORGANIZATION> told the committee his institution has drawn its own guidelines that would exclude transplanting the tissue of a fetus into a relative of the mother. He said that was done out of safety considerations _ that whatever caused the disease in the relative might somehow be present in the offspring's genes _ but coincidentally also serves to negate concern about `` custom pregnancies.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880916-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-16-88 0252EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Ozone-Cars     09-16 0505</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Ozone-Cars,500</SECOND>
<HEAD>EPA Says Emission Controls May Be Better Than Planned</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GUY DARST</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> says regulations to control the volatility of gasoline and the recovery of gasoline fumes could be twice as effective as originally expected. As a result, cities close to complying with federal clean air standards will get a greater than expected reduction in ozone when <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> adopts the new rules. Implementation of the regulations had been expected to help anti-pollution efforts, but <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> Administrator <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> said Thursday the benefit would be much greater than previously believed. Earlier EPA calculations had indicated the gasoline regulations would reduce the emission of urban hydrocarbons to the atmosphere by 10 percent to 15 percent, <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> said. `` It could be as much as twice that,'' <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> said. Some cities are so close to complying with the standard that they had been expected to come into compliance simply through the retirement of older, more-polluting vehicles. <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> said he did not know how many cities would benefit from the new findings. But those helped the most will be areas where peak readings of ozone are `` in the 0.14 -LRB- parts per million -RRB- range'' and below, he said. Some cities may find that measures such as pollution inspections of cars will be unnecessary. There are 38 cities with peak readings of 0.14 ppm or below on <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION>'s list of the 68 urban and rural areas that have failed to meet the nation's ozone standard. Gasoline fumes react in sunlight with nitrogen oxides from all fuel combustion to produce ozone, which is harmful to the lungs. Ozone is the constituent of urban smog that makes the chest feel tight. The federal standard calls for limiting peak ozone to 0.12 parts per million and limiting excursions above that to no more than one hour per year. Gasoline vapor emissions to the atmosphere will be reduced more than expected because the planned regulations will sharply reduce what analysts call `` running losses,'' or the evaporation of gasoline from the tank and other fuel system components while the car is moving. Current cars must meet strict standards for emission of unburned gasoline vapor out the tailpipe and for evaporation. Evaporation is controlled by a vapor recovery system which stores gasoline vapor in a cannister of activated charcoal until they can be recycled to the tank. It is tested by collecting vapor emitted when a car is stationary, and for this, the agency uses a test fuel whose volatility has remained unchanged since 1975. Actual volatility has increased sharply since then, and on hot days it can overwhelm the cannister. In such circumstances, the car can emit to the atmosphere 25 times more gasoline vapor than is permitted out the exhaust. The volatility standard will reduce these emissions and the vapor recovery regulation will ensure that more of them are captured, agency officials say. The <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> says this would remove a large source of urban ozone that the agency had not known was there.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880916-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-16-88 0157EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-DormRules     09-16 0318</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Dorm Rules,0328</SECOND>
<HEAD>Boston University Announces Parietal Rules Despite Student Protest</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DANA KENNEDY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BOSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Boston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> rejected student protests and issued strict new rules prohibiting students from having overnight guests of the opposite sex and reducing the amount of alcohol in dormitories. The rules were released Thursday, a day after 2,000 students converged on campus for a three-hour demonstration against the visitation policy. `` All of life after 11 p.m. has been banned at <ORGANIZATION> BU </ORGANIZATION>,'' <PERSON> Jamie </PERSON> <PERSON> Sanbonmatsu </PERSON>, a senior at the <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Arts </ORGANIZATION>, told the crowd. `` The administration is stunting our growth and development by denying us the right to make decisions.'' Under the new guidelines, some of which go into effect in late fall and others during spring, guests must display identification cards and leave the dormitory by 11 p.m. on weekdays and 1 a.m. on weekends. Overnight stays by members of the same sex will be allowed if roommates agree. But members of the opposite sex will not be allowed overnight. The amount of alcohol allowed into the dorms will be limited to a six-pack of beer and a liter of other alcoholic beverages for students over age 21. <PERSON> Kevin </PERSON> <PERSON> Carleton </PERSON>, a university spokesman, said Wednesday's protest did not faze <ORGANIZATION> BU </ORGANIZATION> officials. `` I do n't think any demonstration would have an effect,'' said <PERSON> Carleton </PERSON>. `` What can have an effect is a reasonable discussion.'' Officials said they based their decision on `` concerns stated by students, staff and parents that residences too often have failed to provide the kind of environment where an individual can quietly study and have his or her right to privacy respected.'' <ORGANIZATION> BU </ORGANIZATION> officials cited problems such as parties, late-night group study and peer pressure to put up with overnight guests. There are 8,700 students housed in university residence halls. Parietal rules were dropped by many American colleges and universities, including <ORGANIZATION> BU </ORGANIZATION>, in the 1960s and'70s.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880916-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-16-88 0059EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-DeltaCrash Bjt   09-16 0602</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Delta Crash, Bjt,570</SECOND>
<HEAD>Engines Test OK From Delta Crash; More Scrutiny of Possible Pilot
Error</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By H. JOSEF HEBERT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Federal investigators say the engines from the <ORGANIZATION> Delta </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lines </ORGANIZATION> jetliner that crashed last month in <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> show no evidence of mechanical failure _ a finding that is focusing more attention on possible pilot error. The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> said Thursday the evidence shows `` that all engines -LRB- on the plane -RRB- were running as commanded and capable of producing full power at the time of impact.'' Early speculation after the Aug. 31 crash at <LOCATION> Dallas-Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Worth </LOCATION> <LOCATION> International </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION>, in which 14 of 108 people aboard <ORGANIZATION> Delta </ORGANIZATION> Flight 1141 died, was possible engine failure because witnesses reported fire coming from an engine. The cockpit voice recorder tape also included a reference by a crew member to `` engine failure'' seconds before the crash. But the <ORGANIZATION> NTSB </ORGANIZATION> said that after the three <ORGANIZATION> Pratt </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <LOCATION> Whitney </LOCATION> JT8D engines were disassembled at the manufacturer's facilities in <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION> `` there was no evidence of pre-impact failure'' in any of the engines. The findings also seemed to rule out the possibility that an object or bird was sucked into an engine since that would have caused damage or been determined when the engines were disassembled. While the safety board is continuing to examine the possibility that there was a compressor stall because of improper air flow through an engine, investigators believe that would have to have been caused by some other irregularity. Proper air flow can be disrupted through an engine if a plane is in an unusual angle that restricts the flow of air across the wings or fuselage, according to aviation experts. Investigators have said the cockpit voice recorder tape includes at least five noises that could be engine compressor stalls, but all of them occur after the plane already was having serious problems remaining aloft. The engine findings, according to one source close to the investigation, have caused investigators to focus more closely on the possibility that an error by the pilots _ such as improperly configuring the aircraft for takeoff _ was the cause of the crash. Investigators, for example, have been puzzled by conflicting evidence as to the setting of the plane's wing flaps. According to the recording of cockpit conversation, the co-pilot acknowledged during the preflight checklist that the flaps had been set at the proper 15 degree extension. But investigators found that the flaps, which help provide more lift for takeoff, were almost completely retracted and that the flaps lever in the cockpit was in the retracted position. Further tests may show whether the crash impact might have contributed to the positioning of both the flaps and the lever or whether a mechanical failure caused the flaps not to slide into proper position. Meanwhile, the cockpit crew members, all three of whom survived the crash, have yet to provide information that might shed light on the cause of the accident. Earlier this week, Capt. <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Davis </PERSON>, who was at the controls during the takeoff, told investigators he recalls one of the other pilots stating the flaps were properly extended, but does n't recall checking the flap indicators to verify if they indeed had been set. He said he recalls two `` loud bangs or explosions'' _ possibly engine compressor stalls caused by improper air flow _ seconds after liftoff and that the plane began to roll, according to <ORGANIZATION> NTSB </ORGANIZATION> officials. The co-pilot, <PERSON> Carey </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kirkland </PERSON>, has told investigators he does n't remember anything after the aircraft left the gate, while the flight engineer, <PERSON> Steven </PERSON> <PERSON> Judd </PERSON>, gave only sketchy information.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880916-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-16-88 0059EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-WarPowers     09-16 0498</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-War Powers,510</SECOND>
<HEAD>Ford Says War Powers Provisions Alterned None Of His Decisions</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto WX7</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TIM AHERN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Former President <PERSON> Gerald </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Ford </PERSON> says the legal restrictions of the controversial War Powers Act never caused him to change any of the decisions he made during his presidency. `` I did what I felt had to be done,'' the former president told a <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> subcommittee. <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION>'s comment came Thursday in response to a question from Sen. <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Pressler </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-S.D. </LOCATION>, about whether any of <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION>'s national security decisions were affected by the executive branch restrictions contained in the 1973 law. <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> is a strong opponent of the law, as have been all presidents since the measure was enacted over President <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON>'s veto The law was a congressional attempt to check some of the power which legislators felt had greatly deepened the American role in the Vietnam War. The law directs the White House to send <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> a report within 48 hours after <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military personnel are sent to areas of imminent hostilities. Those forces must then be withdrawn within 60 days, or in some cases 90 days, unless <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> votes to allow them to remain. <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> told the <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Relations </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> subcommittee </ORGANIZATION> set up to study the War Powers Act that he and his successors sent 19 reports to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> under the law, although the documents were n't submitted under provisions of the act that could trigger the 60-day withdrawal period. He added, `` in the 15 years of the War Powers Resolution, it's never been implemented, never ... It's a dormant piece of legislation. It ought to be repealed.'' But <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> added that `` I'm practical, I do n't think it will be -LRB- repealed -RRB-. I support the kind of amendments'' proposed in a reform backed by leaders of both parties. The changes would eliminate the 60 - or 90-day automatic withdrawal period and would replace the reporting requirement with a requirement that a president consult with <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> leaders about major national security decisions The latest War Powers fights have centered on President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s policy of protecting reflagged Kuwaiti tankers in the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> has refused to invoke the law. There have been seven votes in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> on attempts to force the administration to comply with the law, but all have failed. <PERSON> Abraham </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Sofaer </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> legal adviser, also argued that the law is unconstitutional. `` It incoporates a view of the relative powers of the political branches of our government, and of their proper roles, that is at odds with the Constitution's scheme and with over 200 years of relatively consistent experience,'' <PERSON> Sofaer </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Sofaer </PERSON> also objected to the 60-day restriction because `` the imposition of arbitrary and inflexible deadlines interferes with the effective and successful completion of the initiative undertaken by the president.'' `` Such limits may signal a divided nation, giving our adversaries a basis for hoping that the president may be forced to desist, or at least feel pressured to do so,'' he explained.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880916-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-16-88 0058EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Deaver     09-16 0728</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Deaver,720</SECOND>
<HEAD>Doctor Says Deaver Was Heavy Drinker</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Lead planned after resumption of hearing, set for 10 a.m. EDT</NOTE>
<HEAD>Laserphoto WX6</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JAMES ROWLEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> K. </PERSON> <PERSON> Deaver </PERSON> had been drinking up to a fifth of Scotch whisky a day when he first sought treatment for alcoholism only several weeks after he left President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s staff, according to testimony <PERSON> Deaver </PERSON>'s wife, <PERSON> Carolyn </PERSON>, told a doctor that her husband drank `` bottles and bottles of wine'' the weekend before he was hospitalized on June 3, 1985, for alcohol detoxification, Dr. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Argy </PERSON> testified Thursday at a court hearing on the former presidential aide's medical condition. <PERSON> Deaver </PERSON> is trying to get a lenient sentence for lying under oath about his lobbying activities by presenting evidence that his memory was impaired by alcoholism when he gave sworn testimony before a grand jury and a <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> subcommittee in 1986. <PERSON> Argy </PERSON> said <PERSON> Deaver </PERSON> was drinking as much as a bottle of wine or a pint of vodka a day when he was hospitalized in October 1986 for detoxification. The former deputy White House chief of staff and longtime friend of the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> family faces a possible five-year term and a $ 6,800 fine for each of three perjury convictions when he appears Sept. 23 for sentencing by <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Penfield </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>. <PERSON> Deaver </PERSON> was found guilty of two counts of lying by telling the grand jury he could n't recall contacting former <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration colleagues on behalf of high-paying lobbying clients. The third conviction stemmed from his denial to the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> subcomittee that he helped a South Korean trade envoy get an appointment to see the president. At Thursday's hearing, defense lawyer <PERSON> Randall </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Turk </PERSON> told <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> that evidence would show that <PERSON> Deaver </PERSON> was an alcoholic `` at all times relevant to the case'' and therefore his memory was impaired both during the events in question and when he was asked about them under oath. But independent counsel <PERSON> Whitney </PERSON> <PERSON> North </PERSON> <PERSON> Seymour </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> argued that records of <PERSON> Deaver </PERSON>'s hospitalization for alcoholism in June 1985 and again in October 1986 show `` nothing to support any finding that his memory was impaired.'' `` Mr. <PERSON> Deaver </PERSON>'s ability to recall was absolutely functioning, it was just that he decided to select what he wanted to recall,'' <PERSON> Seymour </PERSON> argued. Medical experts for both the defense and prosecution were expected to testify when the hearing resumed. A Roman Catholic priest who runs an alcoholism treatment center in <LOCATION> Havre </LOCATION> <LOCATION> de </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Grace </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Md. </LOCATION>, where <PERSON> Deaver </PERSON> spent a month following his second hospitalization said the former presidential aide complained of memory blackouts when he was first admitted. Prosecutors showed the Rev. <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> a treatment notation stating that during his stay <PERSON> Deaver </PERSON> `` enjoyed a nightly game of Trivial Pursuits'' _ a game that challenges players' memory of facts about popular culture and other subjects. `` Many of us have a little storehouse of useless information, you can show it in a game like that,'' <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> said <PERSON> Deaver </PERSON> came to realize that his drinking problem occurred because he `` abused power and money.'' Argy, who had earlier treated <PERSON> Deaver </PERSON> for kidney failure, testified that the former presidential aide called him on May 30, 1985, to seek help with alcoholism. On June 3, 1985, <PERSON> Deaver </PERSON> was admitted to <ORGANIZATION> Georgetown </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION> for detoxification. The defense tried to use this testimony to show that <PERSON> Deaver </PERSON> was not lying when he said he could n't recall telephoning then-Transportation Secretary <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> or White House aide <PERSON> Rogert </PERSON> <PERSON> Porter </PERSON> from his hospital bed on behalf of <ORGANIZATION> Trans </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION>. The calls were made `` while he was going through acute alcohol withdrawal and while he was sedated'' by tranquilizers, <PERSON> Turk </PERSON> argued. <PERSON> Argy </PERSON> said <PERSON> Deaver </PERSON> received between 120 and 140 milligrams of Valium to counteract the effects of alcohol withdrawal during his three-day hospital stay. But <PERSON> Seymour </PERSON> was able to show that <PERSON> Deaver </PERSON> did not receive any Valium until 45 minutes after he had telephoned Mrs. <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> on June 3. According to <PERSON> Argy </PERSON>, <PERSON> Deaver </PERSON> was given his first tranquilizer _ a 25-milligram dose of <LOCATION> Librium </LOCATION> _ 45 minutes before the 5 p.m. call to <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>, which was documented by a telephone log produced at the trial. The call to <PERSON> Porter </PERSON> was the next day. The medical testimony about <PERSON> Deaver </PERSON>'s alcoholism was not offered during the trial because defense lawyers rested their case without calling any witnesses.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880916-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-16-88 0058EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-House-Drugs Bjt   09-16 0701</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-House-Drugs, Bjt,700</SECOND>
<HEAD>Handgun Legislation Dropped From Anti-Drug Bill</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LARRY MARGASAK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Ignoring a lawmaker's plea to `` show how tough we are'' by opposing the firearms lobby, the House has likely killed for this year an attempt to force Americans to wait a week before buying a handgun. By a 228-182 bipartisan vote Thursday, the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> eliminated from an anti-drug bill a seven-day waiting period along with an optional police background check of the purchaser. The vote substituted a plan _ to be devised by the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> _ that would allow gun dealers to quickly identify convicted felons seeking to buy pistols. Sponsor <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> McCollum </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Fla </LOCATION>., said the amendment was his own idea and the major pro-gun group, the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rifle </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assocation </ORGANIZATION>, came to him with its support The waiting period language was named symbolically after presidential press secretary <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Brady </PERSON>, who was shot along with President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> in the March 30, 1981, assassination attempt against the president by <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Hinckley </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>. <PERSON> Brady </PERSON>'s wife, <PERSON> Sarah </PERSON>, vice chair of <ORGANIZATION> Handgun </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Control </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, called the vote `` disappointing and discouraging. She added, `` We came close. Twenty-four more votes would have made a difference.'' The <ORGANIZATION> NRA </ORGANIZATION>'s chief political operative, <PERSON> Wayne </PERSON> <PERSON> LaPierre </PERSON>, predicted that any attempt to resurrect the waiting period in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> this year would fail because sentiment there was `` even stronger'' against the waiting period. To change the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> result, 24 members would have to reverse course _ a seemingly insurmountable number for such a politically sensitive issue. The three-million-member <ORGANIZATION> NRA </ORGANIZATION>, which once faced little opposition in its lobbying against gun control, was up against a formidable foe this time: a coalition of gun control groups and law enforcement organizations that was better organized than ever before. Supporters of the waiting period believed they had a better chance of winning their legislation by making it part of a popular anti-drug bill near election time. But they guessed wrong, and the coalition's predictions of a razor-close vote proved inaccurate. <ORGANIZATION> NRA </ORGANIZATION> supporters were able to muster backing from 101 Democrats and 127 Republicans. Opposing were 137 Democrats and 45 Republicans. The overall drug bill would add some $ 2 billion to the nation's $ 3.9 billion drug fighting effort A final <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> vote is expected next week. The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> still has to consider its own drug fighting bill. In the closing moments of debate, waiting period supporter Rep. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Hughes </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.J. </LOCATION>, urged members to `` show how tough we are when it comes to bucking the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rifle </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> and the gun lobby.'' <ORGANIZATION> NRA </ORGANIZATION> backer Rep. <PERSON> Harold </PERSON> <PERSON> Volkmer </PERSON>, D-Mo., said after the vote that those comments backfired `` Taking on the <ORGANIZATION> NRA </ORGANIZATION> is one thing and taking on gun owners is another,'' <PERSON> Volkmer </PERSON> said. `` There's no question the <ORGANIZATION> NRA </ORGANIZATION> had a lot to do with it,'' he said, but attributed most of the substitute's support to individual gun owners who contacted their lawmakers Both sides brought police officers to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> to lobby for their positions. The McCollum amendment would order the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> to develop _ within 180 days _ a system that would allow gun dealers to check whether the applicant is a convicted felon. <PERSON> McCollum </PERSON> has said the system, which would be submitted to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, could include a telephone check such as the one that stores use to verify that credit cards are valid. His language also requires that probation be revoked for anyone found in possession of firearms. <PERSON> Dewey </PERSON> <PERSON> Stokes </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> Fraternal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Order </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION>, said, `` I do n't mind losing a fight when it's fair, but we were outgunned on this, and by outgunned I mean dollar bills. It's a shame when our congressmen have to listen to a single-shot issue group'' like the <ORGANIZATION> NRA </ORGANIZATION>. Supporters of the waiting period had argued the device was effective in the 22 states that had it, citing figures that <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> screened out more than 1,500 ineligible gun applicants in 1986; and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> stopped an average of 500 felons each year from buying guns. But Rep. <PERSON> Harley </PERSON> <PERSON> O </PERSON>. Staggers Jr., D-W. <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, said a <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> study `` says criminals actually avoid going through legal channels'' to obtain The institute is a <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> research agency.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880916-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-16-88 0057EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-US-Panama-Military Bjt   09-16 0644</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-US-Panama-Military, Bjt,640</SECOND>
<HEAD>Administration Plans To Cut Security Force In Panama</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By NORMAN BLACK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Military Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration has decided to gradually withdraw small numbers of the servicemen sent to <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> last spring on temporary security duty, administration officials say. The decision was made because a feared threat to <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> bases in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> has not materialized, according to the sources, who spoke Thursday on condition of anonymity. The sources said the move was recommended by Gen. <PERSON> Frederick </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Woerner </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, head of the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Command </ORGANIZATION>. It was blessed by the <ORGANIZATION> Joint </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chiefs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Staff </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Carlucci </PERSON> and the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> after a review that focused on `` political sensitivities, not military requirements,'' the officials added. The sources declined to say exactly how many of the extra 2,200 security personnel sent to <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> since last spring would be included in the first withdrawal. One source indicated the number would be fewer than 500, while another official said about 200 would be involved. `` This is a sensitive thing, because our opposition to the government of -LRB- strongman -RRB- Gen. <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> has n't changed and we do n't want this to be misinterpreted,'' said one official. `` But there's no sense keeping extra soldiers in the country if you do n't need them. Separately, <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> officials said Thursday the administration has decided to reduce the size of its diplomatic presence in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> because of what one official called a `` potentially confrontational situation'' in that country. The extent of the diplomatic cutback was not immediately determined, but one official said up to 160 jobs could be affected. Officials who disclosed the planned withdrawal of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> security forces from <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> said the cutbacks will be carried out gradually. `` They will come out over a period of time,'' a source said. `` We do n't want to fly in empty aircraft and load them up all at once and have <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> claiming he won. `` The situation has not improved, but these people are n't needed for the mission they were sent in for.'' Said another official: `` Most of these security personnel were put on as guards at the military installations, and we have n't been experiencing harassment in that area. `` We've been having problems with other things besides gate security. So if you do n't have enough for them to do, there's no reason to extend their tour or to replace them with fresh units.'' The sources said the decision to begin drawing down the extra security personnel amounted to acknowledgement of a standoff with <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> that features harassment but no direct threat to <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> facilities. `` The Panamanian Defense Forces continue to hassle Americans when they travel off-base, and we still have occasional intruders at our -LRB- oil -RRB- tank farm,'' said one official. `` But the bases themselves have really not been threatened.'' The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has been pressing economic sanctions against <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> for months now in a bid to oust <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>. The Panamanian general has been indicted by two federal grand juries in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> on drug trafficking charges. Last March and April, citing growing `` instability in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> and the heavy-handed tactics of <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> in dealing with the situation,'' the Pentagon began sending <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> military police and security specialists to the Central American nation. <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> _ besides being the site of the <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Canal </LOCATION> _ is the home of the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Command </ORGANIZATION>, the organization responsible for all <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military forces in Central and <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>. About 10,000 American servicemen and a like number of dependents are stationed there permanently. Over the course of the two-month build-up this spring, the Pentagon moved an extra 2,200 servicemen into <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> on temporary duty status to augment the roughly 600 security personnel assigned there permanently. The issue of withdrawing those servicemen and replacing them arises now because under military regulations, a temporary duty assignment can not last more than 180 days.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880916-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-16-88 0056EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Palau-Shooting     09-16 0296</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Palau-Shooting,0304</SECOND>
<HEAD>President's Shooting Death Ruled Suicide</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Retransmitting a0822 to fix category code; Friday is cq</NOTE>
<DATELINE>KOROR, Palau (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The gunshot that killed Palau President <PERSON> Lazarus </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Salii </PERSON> on Aug. 20 was self-inflicted, the government said Friday. `` The inescapable conclusion is that the cause and manner of death was instantaneous by self-inflicted perforating gunshot wound of the head,'' said the report issued by the offices of <PERSON> Palau </PERSON>'s attorney general and director of the <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> The report cited ballistic tests conducted at the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> laboratory in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION>, an autopsy report from forensic pathlogist Dr. <PERSON> Hee-Yong </PERSON> <PERSON> Park </PERSON> on <LOCATION> Guam </LOCATION> and statements from witnesses. <PERSON> Salii </PERSON>, 51, was the second elected president of the tiny island republic in the <LOCATION> Western </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION>. He was elected in August 1985 to succeed <PERSON> Haruo </PERSON> <PERSON> I. </PERSON> <PERSON> Remeliik </PERSON>, who was assassinated two months earlier. Three Palau men convicted at trial in connection with <PERSON> Remeliik </PERSON>'s death were acquitted on appeal <PERSON> Salii </PERSON>'s wife found his body slumped in his chair in a small sitting room in their house, the report said. A .357 - caliber Magnum revolver that <PERSON> Salii </PERSON> had borrowed from a police officer about four months earlier was found on the floor by his feet, it The autopsy report said <PERSON> Salii </PERSON> placed the gun muzzle at his left temple and fired. The bullet passed through his head. <PERSON> Palau </PERSON>, about 4,500 miles southwest of <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION> and 600 miles east of the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION>, has been beset by economic and political problems, including a lengthy legal dispute over its future political status with the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Palau </PERSON>, with a population of 15,000, is the last political entity of the Trust Territory of the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Islands </LOCATION> and has yet to conclude an agreement on a proposed <ORGANIZATION> Compact </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Free </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> with the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880916-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-16-88 0300EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--BusCrash     09-16 0079</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Bus Crash,0080</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bus Collides With Van, 21 Dead</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LAGOS, Nigeria (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A bus collided with a van in the southern state of <LOCATION> Benue </LOCATION>, killing 21 people and injuring 22 others, a newspaper said. The independent <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Concord </ORGANIZATION> said Thursday the accident occurred a day earlier near the town of <LOCATION> Aliade </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gwer </LOCATION>, 24 miles south of <LOCATION> Makurdi </LOCATION>. A government commission recently reported that road accidents claimed 69 lives daily in this West African nation of 100 million.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880916-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-16-88 0155EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--AmericansRobbed     09-16 0144</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Americans Robbed,0146</SECOND>
<HEAD>American Tourists Robbed Of Jewelry Bought On European Holiday</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BATH, England (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Four <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> tourists lost $ 173,000 worth of jewelry purchased during a two-month European tour when their car was broken into and their luggage stolen, police said. The two retired couples from <LOCATION> Palm </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>, had left their valuables in a car Wednesday while sight-seeing in Bath, the ancient Roman spa city 100 miles west of <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>, said Inspector <PERSON> Graham </PERSON> <PERSON> Cawley </PERSON> of the <LOCATION> Avon </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Somerset </LOCATION> police. The couples were at the end of a two-month tour of <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> during which they had bought several pieces of second-hand jewelry, including bracelets, rings and brooches, most of it gold, <PERSON> Cawley </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Cawley </PERSON> would not release the tourists' names. He said he did not know whether the jewelry was purchased for personal use or for resale in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880916-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-16-88 0054EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Hurricane-1900     09-16 0556</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Hurricane-1900,0573</SECOND>
<HEAD>Great 1900 Storm In Galveston Still Considered Greatest U.S.
Disaster</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Hurricane Gilbert</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By MICHAEL L. GRACZYK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>GALVESTON, Texas (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The incessant surf rolled in a little higher than normal and even though it was late summer, the peak time for tropical storms, people were n't too concerned. After all, this was <LOCATION> Galveston </LOCATION>, the largest and most prosperous town in <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, the Wall Steet of the <ORGANIZATION> Southwest </ORGANIZATION>, and it had weathered storms before. In September 1900, in the days before radio and satellite photographs, people had no idea that out in the <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> a monster storm was brewing that would change <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> history and bring death and terror on a scale that never has been seen before or since in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. On Sept. 8, 1900, <LOCATION> Galveston </LOCATION> was home to nearly 38,000 people. When the sun rose the next day, nearly one-sixth of the city's residents were dead, victims of buildings toppled by winds and waves, drowned in the 15-foot storm surge, mangled by flying debris or washed out to sea The death toll was put at 6,000, but it's uncertain how many thousands of others were lost. `` Nobody knows the complete story of what happened at <LOCATION> Galveston </LOCATION>; nobody ever will know,'' <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Weems </PERSON> wrote in his classic account of the storm, `` A Weekend in September.'' Ironically, the book, written in 1956, was re-released this month to mark the 88th anniversary of the great <LOCATION> Galveston </LOCATION> storm. `` Most of them wanted to talk,'' <PERSON> Weems </PERSON> says now, recalling his conversations with storm survivors. `` The tragedies were still with them, but enough time had passed so they could talk about them. `` I got the idea some of them might be paying respect to their dead friends and relatives by talking about them.'' Although <PERSON> Weems </PERSON> believes all the hundreds of survivors he interviewed have died since, <PERSON> Jennie </PERSON> <PERSON> Graham </PERSON> <PERSON> Karboski </PERSON> is among the few still living who were there. And what she remembers most is the water, angrily rising _ and the bodies, floating everywhere. Mrs. <PERSON> Karboski </PERSON> is now 100 and lives with her daughter in <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION>. She was 12 and growing up in <LOCATION> Galveston </LOCATION> when the storm hit. `` They tried to have mass burials at sea, but the next morning many floated back in on the surf,'' she told the <ORGANIZATION> Houston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chronicle </ORGANIZATION> this week. `` The men had to dig trenches and burn them. My dad said they kept the work crews drunk. They had to.'' After a harrowing journey by rowboat and horse cart, Mrs. <PERSON> Karboski </PERSON>'s family found shelter in a Catholic seminary. Others who survived huddled in a lighthouse or a storm-tossed ship or crammed inside the upper stories of their homes. Others clung to wreckage until the waters receded. Perhaps the most lasting monument to the 1900 storm is the <LOCATION> Galveston </LOCATION> seawall, a concrete embankment 17 feet above mean low tide built after the great storm to ward off future huge storm surges. It has helped to moderate damage from hurricanes since. A more significant effect, however, was that many businessmen who considered <LOCATION> Galveston </LOCATION> the hub of activity for <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> decided they would not put themselves through another such storm. They moved inland about 50 miles to a mosquito-infested swamp town called <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION>, which 88 years later is the nation's fourth-largest city
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880916-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-16-88 0716EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-TelevisionSeason     09-16 0664</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Television Season,0680</SECOND>
<HEAD>New TV Season Starts With ABC, CBS Struggling Against NBC's
Olympics</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By KATHRYN BAKER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Television Writer_</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 But for the summerlong writers' strike, the fall television season would have begun Monday with typically fervent competition among the three networks and an advertising blitz for their new shows. But network competition has been sidelined for the next couple of weeks as the 1988 Summer Olympics play in prime time on <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, while <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> _ their new fall shows delayed for weeks by the strike _ basically twiddle their thumbs. CBS is even hoping the Olympics do well for <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>. `` We face, absent the Olympics, an audience that's going to be more restless than usual,'' said <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Poltrack </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> vice president for marketing. `` If they're going to find a place to be diverted to while waiting for the season to be launched late, the Olympics is where I'd like to see them go, not to independent stations or cable networks. `` So at this point in time, we'd like to get the majority of the audience that the Olympics do n't get, but I'd like to see the Olympics do well.'' CBS is also hoping good <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> numbers will help when <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> sells advertising in the 1994 Winter Olympics. CBS is also seeking rights to the 1992 summer games. <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> is counter-programming the Olympics with half-hour comedies, but it, too, has basically forfeited the lion's share of television viewers to <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>. `` We tried to do it with a little bit of fun, a sense of humor,'' said <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Wurtzel </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s vice president for marketing. `` Recognize something comes along every four years, and we know we're not going to beat it.'' CBS is running movies and first-run sitcoms against the Olympics in an effort to draw as many kids and older people, the groups least likely to be avid watchers of the Olympics. <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> has decided that if the Olympics are high drama, they'll counter-program with laughs The network has scheduled a month of repeats of top <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> sitcoms, plus comedy movies and specials. `` What we did was, we looked at basically what did best against us when we had the Olympics in the past, how our competitors fared,'' said <PERSON> Wurtzel </PERSON>. `` What we learned was people kind of dipped in and out of the Olympics. They do n't necessarily like every event. Programs that did best were half-hour comedies.'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> is predicting it will average about a third of the prime-time viewing audience with Olympics. Because of the strike delay, the networks are at odds over when the new television season should be declared open. Advertisers buy commercials based on viewership of individual shows, so they do n't care who wins the seasonlong horse race in the <ORGANIZATION> A.C. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nielsen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> ratings. But it is an image contest. Not surprisingly, <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> believes the new season should begin Monday, since it will have undoubtedly big ratings for the Olympics which would count on the season. `` We did not have the start-time problem that some other people may have, so we're taking the traditional outlook and starting on the 19th,'' said <PERSON> Jeff </PERSON> <PERSON> Boehme </PERSON>, director of audience measurement at <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>. `` Several broadcasters do n't have original programming. I'm sure they would prefer to start it at a later time. From our perspective, we have our programming in place, and we do n't think it would be fair to us to delete first-run programming from the season,'' he said. <PERSON> Wurtzel </PERSON> says <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> is marking the new season from about Oct. 24, the week in which it will have half its new programs on the air. <PERSON> Poltrack </PERSON> said <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> would also have the season start Oct. 24 for the same reason. If the late start is confounding the networks, viewers could benefit. Even though the television season is starting late, the networks have nevertheless put in orders for a full season's supply of episodes for most series. That means fewer reruns next spring.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880916-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-16-88 0140EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-YellowstoneFires-Tourism     09-16 0715</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Yellowstone Fires-Tourism,0731</SECOND>
<HEAD>Yellowstone-Area Officials Plot Ways To Lure Back Tourists</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By TAD BARTIMUS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WEST YELLOWSTONE, Mont. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 With Yellowstone National Park's wildfires still burning, the famous tourist attraction's gateway cities already are planning ways to lure visitors to the charred landmark next summer `` The geysers are still there, the waterfalls are still there, the elk and bison and bears are still there, the streams and fish are still there,'' said <PERSON> Suzanne </PERSON> <PERSON> Young </PERSON>, executive director of the <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Wyo. </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Chamber </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION>. `` Our job will be to get out the message that ` Yes, there is still the Yellowstone you love and remember, despite the forest fires.''' While the key landmarks are still there, so is a mosaic of charred trees as a dozen enormous fires have blazed across nearly half of <ORGANIZATION> Yellowstone </ORGANIZATION>'s 2.2 million acres in the past two months. The flames forced frequent evacuations of campgrounds and lodging facilities, and blanketed thousands of square miles with smoke. The park's tiny gateway communities are vitally linked to the giant wilderness, which in a normal year attracts 3 million visitors. Towns with economies strongly dependent on <ORGANIZATION> Yellowstone </ORGANIZATION> include <PERSON> Gardiner </PERSON>, Silver Gate, <ORGANIZATION> Cooke </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> and <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Yellowstone </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION>; <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> and <PERSON> Cody </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION>; and, to a lesser degree, <PERSON> Driggs </PERSON> and <PERSON> Victor </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION>. Officials say that so far this year, tourist visits to <ORGANIZATION> Yellowstone </ORGANIZATION> are down 12.5 percent from last year's figures, a loss of more than a quarter million visitors. Many merchants and innkeepers are wondering about the long-term economic impact of the worst fires in <LOCATION> Yellowstone </LOCATION> in 300 years. `` A month after the fires are out, or at least after they're off the TV nightly news, we want a market research firm to do attitude perception surveys to find out what people think about a vacation in <LOCATION> Yellowstone </LOCATION>,'' said <PERSON> Young </PERSON>. `` Will they be interested? What will they expect to see? Our guess is that memory is short. Nobody can even remember a hurricane name from last week. My hunch is, people will want to come see what happened here.'' <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Tedder </PERSON> of park concessioner <ORGANIZATION> TW </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION>, which runs <ORGANIZATION> Yellowstone </ORGANIZATION>'s lodging, restaurants and transportation services, expects sales to be down $ 4 million to $ 5 million _ a 25 percent drop from last year. `` It certainly has been an interesting summer,'' he said wryly. `` July and August traditionally are our biggest months, when we make up for the losses of our winter operation. It has been very dramatic _ devastating from a visitor standpoint and an operations standpoint. To date, we've had to give early release to about 800 employees. I think it was by the grace of God that we have not lost any major structures.'' <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Olson </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> TW </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION>' marketing director, said the fires have had a strong effect on the entire region. `` We have got a big job this fall just convincing the local people to come back,'' he said. `` Then we have to look at the national and international markets. I know we've got a heck of a problem.'' <PERSON> Olson </PERSON> is busy accumulating videotape and photographs showing that many areas of the park are unaffected by the fires `` so we can be sure we're telling the true story.'' He already has traveled to <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> to talk about <ORGANIZATION> Yellowstone </ORGANIZATION> with key tour group operators and newspaper travel editors. In addition, some <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wyoming </ORGANIZATION> students are using computer lists to contact tourists who canceled their reservations at <ORGANIZATION> Yellowstone </ORGANIZATION>, and find out why. <PERSON> Rick </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilder </PERSON>, executive director of the Cody, <LOCATION> Wyo. </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Chamber </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION>, hopes the federal government will step in to help, noting that a portion of profit from concessions within the park goes for park improvements. `` We're not looking for a handout or a giveaway, but it's going to be very difficult to add on any extra expense,'' said <PERSON> Wilder </PERSON>. `` The federal government is spending $ 100 million to fight the fires, so it does n't seem unrealistic to think an extra $ 2 million could be spent to get people to come back to <LOCATION> Yellowstone </LOCATION>.'' <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON>, head of <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION>'s tourism promotion effort, said <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Ted </PERSON> <PERSON> Schwinden </PERSON> and <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON> will be asked by their states' travel and tourism officials to seek federal disaster money for the park's gateway communities.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880916-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-16-88 0457EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-APArts:JapanTV     09-16 0515</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AP Arts: Japan TV,0524</SECOND>
<HEAD>Vintage American TV Shows Ride Nostalgia Boom In Japan</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By ERIC TALMADGE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Captain <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> T. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kirk </PERSON> of the starship Enterprise looks skyward from a lonely, wind-blown planet and says: `` Entapuraizu, riku kara tenso shite kure.'' For those listening to the English version of `` Star Trek,'' Captain <PERSON> Kirk </PERSON> would have said `` Enterprise, beam me up.'' Dubbed in Japanese, `` Star Trek'' is just one of many vintage American TV programs boldly exploring the late-night <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION> airwaves. During a typical week, insomnia-stricken viewers in the <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION> area can watch `` <PERSON> Burke </PERSON>'s Law,'' the 1960s adventure show starring <PERSON> Gene </PERSON> <PERSON> Barry </PERSON> as a debonair <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> police chief; <PERSON> Rod </PERSON> <PERSON> Serling </PERSON>'s `` The Twilight Zone,'' the acclaimed science fiction series; `` Bonanza,'' one of television's longest running Westerns, starring <PERSON> Lorne </PERSON> <PERSON> Greene </PERSON>; `` The Beverly Hillbillies,'' the antics of a backwoods family in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>' elitist neighborhood; `` Mission: Impossible,'' the acclaimed <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Geller </PERSON> adventure series; and `` The Addams Family,'' a sitcom based on <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Addams </PERSON>' bizarre magazine cartoon characters `` I do n't have any statistics on this,'' said <PERSON> Yoshihiro </PERSON> <PERSON> Mishima </PERSON> of the TV <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION> network, `` but we think the people who stay up to watch these programs are looking for a bit of the good old days, when they might have been too young to watch the original broadcasts.'' <PERSON> Mishima </PERSON> said the viewers are mainly college students or adults in their 30s. `` It's part of the ` retro boom,''' he said, referring to a recent trend among some Japanese to seek out things from the past. But American TV shows are nothing new to the Japanese audience. `` There have been American programs on Japanese TV for decades, going back to ` <PERSON> Ben </PERSON> <PERSON> Casey </PERSON>' and ` Rawhide,''' <PERSON> Mishima </PERSON> said. `` They've lost popularity to domestic programing, but people still watch them to get a look at <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Yuji </PERSON> <PERSON> Tagami </PERSON>, an editor with TV Station magazine, added, `` They can develop devoted fans, but ratings for late-night American programs in general are not very high.'' Limited viewership did not stop the <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION> Broadcasting System from putting the `` Nostalgic American TV'' series on its schedule last October. Since March, the series has included: `` <ORGANIZATION> Surfside </ORGANIZATION> 6,'' a'60s detective series set in <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION>, starring <PERSON> Troy </PERSON> <PERSON> Donahue </PERSON> and <PERSON> Van </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>; `` Combat!'' the longest of the World War II adventures, starring the late <PERSON> Vic </PERSON> <PERSON> Morrow </PERSON>; and `` Superman,'' starring <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Reeves </PERSON>. `` Ratings are n't a good way to judge late-night television shows' popularity. In that time slot, viewership is small and more personal. Viewers are more attached to what they watch,'' said <PERSON> Masato </PERSON> <PERSON> Ueda </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> TBS </ORGANIZATION> producer of the series. To young viewers, the appeal of the rejuvenated old programs is in their `` newness,'' <PERSON> Ueda </PERSON> said. `` We decided to go with the series when we went on the 24-hour broadcasting schedule, and though the ` retro boom' was a part of the decision, we wanted to give young people something completely new, which to them these programs are.'' Many of the American programs also feature bilingual broadcasts, with the original English-language dialogue simultaneously aired on a subchannel available on specially equipped TV sets.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880916-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-16-88 0717EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-ReaganSetsAgenda Bjt   09-16 0661</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Reagan Sets Agenda, Bjt,660</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHINGTON TODAY: Dukakis Lines Up With Reagan _ Sort Of</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP News Analysis</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BARRY SCHWEID</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Diplomatic Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 When President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> switched the other day and decided to release overdue payments to the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION>, it was another sign that as far as <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> foreign policy is concerned his views have undergone extensive alteration since he entered the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> nearly eight years ago. Presidential spokesman <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> explained the surprising switch on the dues as based on a determination by <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> that the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> had `` reformed its operation.'' That does n't alter the fact, however, that one of the tenets of the political philosophy that nurtured <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and gave identity to his pursuit of the presidency was severe skepticism of the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION>. Conservatives always have complained that the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> paid a disproportionate share of the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> bills while serving as a convenient target of the Soviet bloc and the so-called non-aligned countries. But <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> told the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> to ante up, and another corner was turned. In his twilight months in the White House only his commitment to guerrillas trying to overthrow the Sandinista government in <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> remains uncolored by the pragmatic fact that the Contras are not making much headway. On arms control, after campaigning in 1980 against all major accords with the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> and putting negotiations on a back burner for months, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> gradually adopted a stance that even diehard opponents grudgingly acknowledged was far friendlier to arms control than they had expected. They still are worried he may try to unravel the 1972 Anti-Ballistic Missile Treaty before heading home to <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, but the new 1987 accord to ban intermediate-range nuclear missiles is safely on the books. It stands as the only U.S.-Soviet agreement to eliminate an entire category of nuclear weapons, and it was negotiated on <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s watch. Meanwhile, four summit meetings with Soviet leader <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> have produced a conciliatory stance in the White House that is in striking contrast to early <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> rhetorical flourishes that included castigating <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> as an `` evil empire.'' Until November 1985, he was the first American president since <PERSON> Herbert </PERSON> <PERSON> Hoover </PERSON> not to have met with a Soviet leader. Now he has held more one-on-one superpower summits than any of them. Ironically, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> has moderated his arms control policy to such an extent that <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, who is a liberal Democrat, suggested this week in outlining a nuclear missile strategy agenda that his views were not that far from the president's. The biggest difference is over <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s Strategic Defense Initiative. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> said he would `` stop pouring billions and billions of dollars'' into the pursuit of a space-based defense against Soviet ballistic missiles. But he said he would continue a modest research program into possible missile defenses. The Republican candidate, Vice President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, who projected himself in 1980 as a moderate alternative to <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s deep conservatism, is working overtime, meanwhile, to align himself with <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s foreign policy initiatives His pitch essentially is that he would continue along the same course if he is elected. Having been part of the administration, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s job in lining up with <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> policies is hardly as difficult as the task confronting <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>. But the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> candidate's agenda on weapons moved him closer to <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> has voiced concerns about the costs of the B-1 bomber and the Midgetman missile, but he endorsed production of the Trident II submarine-launched missile and four other weapons. More significant, perhaps, was his vow that `` We'll use force when it's necessary to protect our territory, our citizens or our vital interests; to meet our treaty commitments; and to deter or to respond to terrorist attacks.'' The words were <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>'s but if you close your eyes and let your mind drift back to 1980 they might just as well have been <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Barry </PERSON> <PERSON> Schweid </PERSON> has covered diplomacy for <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> since 1973.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880916-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-16-88 0710EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a BC-Theater     09-16 0496</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Theater,0504</SECOND>
<HEAD>A New Edition of `Forbidden Broadway' Opens Off-Broadway</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: No PMs planned.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By MICHAEL KUCHWARA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Drama Critic</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Ladies and gentlemen, sharpen your scalpels. The show that dares to comment on <PERSON> Patti </PERSON> <PERSON> LuPone </PERSON>'s diction, <PERSON> Madonna </PERSON>'s acting ability, <PERSON> Nell </PERSON> <PERSON> Carter </PERSON>'s figure and <PERSON> Sarah </PERSON> <PERSON> Brightman </PERSON>'s overbite has returned with malice and entertainment for all `` Forbidden Broadway 1988,'' which arrived Thursday at off-Broadway's Theater East, is the latest edition of <PERSON> Gerard </PERSON> <PERSON> Alessandrini </PERSON>'s vest-pocket musical revues that mercilessly spoof the Broadway theater. And it's the best version of the show yet. In more than 25 musical sketches, a hard-working company of four, plus pianist <PERSON> Philip </PERSON> <PERSON> Fortenberry </PERSON>, takes aim at some of Broadway's biggest hits including `` <LOCATION> Les </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Miserables </LOCATION>,'' `` The Phantom of the Opera,'' `` M. Butterfly,'' `` Speed-the-Plow,'' `` Anything Goes'' and `` Into the Woods.'' They score a bull's - eye nearly <PERSON> Alessandrini </PERSON>, who devised the show and supplied the new lyrics as well as the direction, is a master at deflating bombast. Consider his blitz of `` Les Miserables'' _ a mock mini-musical that deflates the big Broadway blockbuster. It's not easy simulating <PERSON> Trevor </PERSON> <PERSON> Nunn </PERSON>'s turntable staging, but <PERSON> Alessandrini </PERSON> comes up with credible and hilaroius copy of it here. But then he also supplies a chandelier for something called `` The Phantom of the Musical,'' a duet for a masked <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Webber </PERSON> and a buck-toothed Miss <PERSON> Brightman </PERSON>. The author is equally effective at lancing big-time personalities. There's a narcissistic Miss <PERSON> LuPone </PERSON> mushmouthing a Cole Porter-style ditty called `` I Get a Kick Out of Me.'' Or an exasperated <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Mamet </PERSON>, author of `` Speed-the-Plow,'' singing, to the tune of `` The Rain in <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION>,'' `` We strain in vain to train <PERSON> Madonna </PERSON>'s brain.'' The performers, particularly the two women, are superb mimics. <PERSON> Toni </PERSON> <PERSON> DiBuono </PERSON> does a terrific <PERSON> LuPone </PERSON>, and a powerhouse <PERSON> Ethel </PERSON> <PERSON> Merman </PERSON> who battles it out on stage in a duet with a relentlessly perky <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Martin </PERSON>, played by <PERSON> Roxie </PERSON> <PERSON> Lucas </PERSON>. Miss <PERSON> Lucas </PERSON> also lacerates <PERSON> Elaine </PERSON> <PERSON> Stritch </PERSON>, parodying her `` Ladies Who Lunch'' number in `` Company'' with a song called `` Ladies Who Screech.'' The evening reaches the height of demented lunacy when <PERSON> Miss </PERSON> <PERSON> DiBuono </PERSON> and <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> McGrath </PERSON> take on <LOCATION> Kiri </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Te </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kanawa </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Carreras </PERSON> and the practice of using opera stars to record famous Broadway scores. Here <PERSON> Alessandrini </PERSON> has them singing a song from the rock musical `` Grease.'' Equally effective is <PERSON> McGrath </PERSON>'s explanation of the bizarre plot of `` M. Butterfly,'' done to the strains of `` Poor Butterfly.'' <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> McDonald </PERSON> lends his booming voice to an effective sendup of <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Papp </PERSON>, called `` Papp the Knife,'' and <PERSON> Papp </PERSON>'s practice of butchering the classics. He also leads the audience in a Sondheim sing-along called `` Into the Words.'' `` Forbidden Broadway'' seems to renew itself every season with the influx of new shows. Right now, you can imagine <PERSON> Alessandrini </PERSON> looking forward with glee to `` <PERSON> Jerome </PERSON> <PERSON> Robbins </PERSON>' Broadway'' and <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Allen </PERSON> in `` Legs Diamond,'' both big musicals scheduled to open this season. They should provide particularly good material for his special brand of merry meyhem.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880916-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-16-88 0321EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Sweden-Immigration     09-16 0905</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Sweden-Immigration,0934</SECOND>
<HEAD>Farming Town Resists Immigrants, Raising Questions Of Racism</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By ARTHUR MAX</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SJOBO, Sweden (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The nation's heartland is challenging <LOCATION> Sweden </LOCATION>'s generous refugee policy, raising fears that latent racism may be bubbling to the surface. It's happening in <LOCATION> Sjobo </LOCATION>, a small southern farming town where the tallest building is three stories high, downtown is one street, and everyone knows just about everybody else. The 15,000 citizens of the town and the surrounding district are holding a referendum Sunday on whether to accept about 30 refugees. It is a local issue, but the question is drawing national attention and is dominating the final weeks of the campaign for the parliamentary election on the same day. Government figures say that from 1983 to 1987, 62,600 people sought political asylum in <LOCATION> Sweden </LOCATION>, a country of 8.4 million people, making it the highest per capita rate in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>. Last year 245 of <LOCATION> Sweden </LOCATION>'s 284 municipal districts took in 18,000 newcomers as the government tried to spread them outside <LOCATION> Stockholm </LOCATION> and other cities where housing is scarce. When the request came to <LOCATION> Sjobo </LOCATION>, the town council balked. It voted last autumn by 25-24 to put the question to a popular vote. Residents say the issue has split families, friends and even the town's only church. Distrust and anger stop people from talking about it any more, and a sullenness has fallen on the town. `` A lot of people are very ashamed. It's terrible,'' said <PERSON> Madeleine </PERSON> <PERSON> Ramel </PERSON>, head of the local <ORGANIZATION> Social </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Welfare </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION>. `` The town has changed.'' Mrs. <PERSON> Ramel </PERSON> said the fight in Sjobo may spread to other communities that have been reluctant to take in refugees but that have been too afraid of public scorn to refuse. `` It is dangerous to ignore signals, and what is happening in <LOCATION> Sjobo </LOCATION> is one of the signals,'' said Mrs. <PERSON> Ramel </PERSON>. The immigration department has said <PERSON> Sjobo </PERSON> could have a say in which immigrants would be sent. The decision has been postponed until after the referendum. An influx of immigrants from <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> has spawned a right-wing backlash in <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Denmark </LOCATION> and other European countries, but that has not happened in <LOCATION> Sweden </LOCATION>. `` A lot of Swedes have a negative attitude toward immigrants. It is normally surpressed, but having a referendum is bringing it to the surface,'' said <PERSON> Anders </PERSON> <PERSON> Sonnerstedt </PERSON>, a political scientist at nearby <ORGANIZATION> Lund </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. `` Swedish people are afraid to speak about the refugee question today, because anyone who speaks out is called a racist,'' said <PERSON> Per-Ingvar </PERSON> <PERSON> Magnusson </PERSON>, a fertilizer dealer who favors keeping the immigrants out. <PERSON> Magnusson </PERSON>, chairman of the Sjobo branch of the <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, denied he is motivated by racism. He said the town lacks housing and jobs for its own young people who are moving away, and he professed astonishment at the attention the town has received. `` They make us out to be stupid, fools, farmers who live in isolation,'' he said in an interview. The town simply wants to take care of its own first, he said. Mrs. <PERSON> Ramel </PERSON>, whose welfare board would handle the immigrants if they came, dismissed <PERSON> Magnusson </PERSON>'s argument. `` It's a silly question. Why ca n't 15,000 people take care of 30 more people. I think they -LRB- the opponents -RRB- just do n't want foreigners here.'' The nay-sayers in <LOCATION> Sjobo </LOCATION> have been roundly condemned by national leaders, the media and the public. One waitress complained that a customer passing through asked rudely if the restaurant `` has racism on the menu.'' <PERSON> Magnusson </PERSON> said he gets hundreds of letters of support from other Swedes. Many of them `` do n't even dare to sign their names'' for fear of being branded as a racist. <LOCATION> Sweden </LOCATION>'s few openly racist groups are dismissed as an insignificant fringe. But the fight in <LOCATION> Sjobo </LOCATION> involves farmers who represent <LOCATION> Sweden </LOCATION>'s roots, and a political party with long and illustrious history. The issue was an embarrassment to the national <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> during its election campaign, and party leader <PERSON> Olof </PERSON> <PERSON> Johansson </PERSON> threatened to expel the Sjobo members. `` They have made their last mistake in the <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>,'' he said in a television interview. The center-right party governs the local council in a coalition with the <ORGANIZATION> Conservative </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>. On the national level, it is in the opposition against the governing <ORGANIZATION> Social </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> party. Set serenely among woodlands and wheatfields, <PERSON> Sjobo </PERSON> seems hardly the scene for a national confrontation. The town of 4,000 is laid out in neat rows of single-story homes with well-trimmed gardens. The <ORGANIZATION> Immigration </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> has said the state would pay for housing and educating the immigrants. But <PERSON> Magnusson </PERSON> said the problem goes deeper. He said the government must curb an unchecked flood of immigrants. <PERSON> Magnusson </PERSON> cited police reports that more than half the refugees seeking to live in <LOCATION> Sweden </LOCATION> destroy their passports on their way here to make it difficult to deport them. Police say as many as 25,000 people may be in <LOCATION> Sweden </LOCATION> under false identities and that as many as 15 wanted terrorists move here every year. Among them were a Palestinian who was killed by a car bomb in <LOCATION> Athens </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Greece </LOCATION> in July, and a wanted terrorist from the <ORGANIZATION> Irish </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> who was arrested in August by Dutch police while traveling through the <LOCATION> Netherlands </LOCATION>. `` There are terrorists, drug dealers and criminals coming in,'' said <PERSON> Magnusson </PERSON>. `` If the government had more control of handling refugees, there would be no need for a vote in <LOCATION> Sjobo </LOCATION>.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880916-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-16-88 0740EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--Harvard-Mideast     09-16 0146</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Harvard-Mideast,0149</SECOND>
<HEAD>Harvard Creates Institute Designed To Foster Mideast Cooperation</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CAMBRIDGE, Mass. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> John </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> F. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Kennedy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Government </ORGANIZATION> has announced an institute designed to foster regional cooperation in the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> on health, welfare and economic development. Kennedy School Dean <PERSON> Graham </PERSON> <PERSON> T. </PERSON> <PERSON> Allison </PERSON> said Thursday the <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Social </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Policy </ORGANIZATION> in the <LOCATION> Mideast </LOCATION> will bring six to 10 Arab and <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> public managers to the school's mid-career program for public officials The institute also will develop field projects in the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> in areas such as child health care and economic development in the <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strip </LOCATION>, he said. <ORGANIZATION> Fomer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION>, Education and Welfare Secretary <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Califano </PERSON> will head the institute's board of advisers. Cardinal <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Connor </PERSON>, the archbishop of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>; former Secretary of State <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Haig </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>; and <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION> investor <PERSON> Leo </PERSON> <PERSON> Fields </PERSON> will serve as vice chairmen.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880916-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-16-88 0151EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Hurricane-Mexico-Tourists     09-16 0559</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Hurricane-Mexico-Tourists,0579</SECOND>
<HEAD>British Tourist Rides Out Storm In Rental Car, Reading Horror
Story</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Hurricane Gilbert</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By CHRIS ANGELO</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CANCUN, Mexico (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Bowden </PERSON> of <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> came to this <LOCATION> Caribbean </LOCATION> resort to get a tan. He ended up spending a dark day in a rented car, reading a horror story as he rode out <PERSON> Hurricane </PERSON> <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON>, the worst storm on record. `` There was a lot of corrugated material flying about all over the place,'' said <PERSON> Bowden </PERSON>, 35. `` It was like being in an aircraft in turbulence. You felt the wind was going to lift you away.'' Other tourists crammed into <LOCATION> Cancun </LOCATION>'s hotels and shelters were becoming impatient by Thursday, the day after <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON> blasted the <LOCATION> Yucatan </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Peninsula </LOCATION> with 160-mph winds and driving rain. Food was in short supply, power was still out, the airport was closed and roads out of the city nearly impassable. `` Hysterical,'' one hotel receptionist said of the stranded vacationers. About 6,000 tourists were trapped in <LOCATION> Cancun </LOCATION> when this normally idyllic resort of sandy beaches and warm, clear waters turned into a fury of waves and wind in the predawn hours Wednesday. <PERSON> Bowden </PERSON> drove into <LOCATION> Cancun </LOCATION> Tuesday, only hours before the storm hit. By then, tourists at the beachfront resorts were being moved into shelters and hotels in the old part of the city, about six miles away. As the hurricane neared, <PERSON> Bowden </PERSON> also sought refuge in the city, but was turned away by hotels already jammed with guests from the luxury resorts. As <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON> roared into <LOCATION> Cancun </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Bowden </PERSON> said he curled up in his car with a book, a horror story involving a magic carpet. `` I got sick of it. If I'd had some postcards I would have written them to send to people, but I did not have any,'' he said. <PERSON> Bowden </PERSON> said he watched as airborne debris zipped past his car. But even worse was the sound of two support lines of a radio transmission tower twanging `` like a badly tuned guitar'' in the wind. Shortly after dawn, the storm still raging, he said left the car, looking for some place to get a cup of coffee. Unsuccessful, he returned to the vehicle. About 150 tourists who were given refuge at city hall had nothing but milk and cookies to eat. `` I think everyone's nerves are starting to get shot now,'' said <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Camuccio </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION>, who had arrived in <LOCATION> Cancun </LOCATION> Sunday. `` Everyone is going to the same bathroom,'' he said. `` There is no water or electricity. They -LRB- the toilets -RRB- do n't flush or anything. Everybody wants to get out.'' Some tourists said they were given virtually no warning that a dangerous storm was on the way. <PERSON> Maggie </PERSON> <PERSON> Frederick </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Petaluma </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, said she had just gotten dressed to go out for the evening Tuesday when there was a knock her hotel room door and a voice said: `` You're being evacuated.'' `` I started laughing thinking they were joking,'' she said. <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Long </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Effingham </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ill. </LOCATION>, who speaks no Spanish, said the language barrier added to the confusion. He and his wife, <PERSON> Jackie </PERSON>, were in <LOCATION> Cancun </LOCATION> to celebrate their fifth wedding anniversary. <PERSON> Nabil </PERSON> <PERSON> Nachawati </PERSON>, of <LOCATION> Arlington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, said his two children, ages 3 and 5, took the storm well. When the sky began to darken, the two children curled up and went to sleep.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880916-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-16-88 0323EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-DingoBaby     09-16 0778</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Dingo Baby,0804</SECOND>
<HEAD>Court Clears Lindy Chamberlain After Sensational Murder Case</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By RICHARD BILL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SYDNEY, Australia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
