<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880912-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-12-88 2344EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Ethiopia     09-12 0403</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Ethiopia,0413</SECOND>
<HEAD>Ethiopia Celebrates 14th Anniversary of Marxist Revolutiuon</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ABEBE ANDUALAM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ADDIS ABABA, Ethiopia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Mengistu </PERSON> <PERSON> Haile </PERSON> <PERSON> Mariam </PERSON> marked the 14th anniversary of <LOCATION> Ethiopia </LOCATION>'s Marxist revolution Monday with a brief address devoted to the nation's longstanding civil war in the north. Government troops and civilians mobilized since the conflict intensified in March are `` presently engaged in a bitter fight,'' <ORGANIZATION> Mengistu </ORGANIZATION> told the thousands of people packed into the capital's downtown Revolution Square His forces claim to have repulsed insurgencies in its northernmost province, <LOCATION> Eritrea </LOCATION>, and <LOCATION> Eritrea </LOCATION>'s southern neighbor, <LOCATION> Tigray </LOCATION>, where <LOCATION> Ethiopia </LOCATION> says it has retaken all major cities and towns since the rebels overran the region in April and May. No major engagements have been reported with the separatist <ORGANIZATION> Eritrean </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION> since the government in May said its forces had foiled rebel attempts to take the strategic city of <LOCATION> Keren </LOCATION>, 56 miles northwest of the provincial capital of <LOCATION> Asmara </LOCATION>. However, <ORGANIZATION> Mengistu </ORGANIZATION> said the rebels were sabotaging and endangering the lives of all citizens and hampering the development of public and private institutiones. The task ahead `` is clearly an arduous one,'' he said in his 20-minute address. The Eritrean guerrillas have been fighting a separatist battle for 27 years in <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>'s longest civil war. In <LOCATION> Tigray </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Tigray </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION> took up arms 14 years ago demanding greater autohomy for their region. <ORGANIZATION> Mengistu </ORGANIZATION> inherited the insurgencies when he and a clique of military men dethroned <LOCATION> Emperor </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Haile </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Selassie </LOCATION> in 1974 and replaced the emperor's 44-year feudal reign with a Marxist government. One day before last year's anniversary of the revolution, the provisional military government which had ruled since the revolution was replaced by a <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republic </ORGANIZATION> which has a popularly elected legislature. However, power still sits with <ORGANIZATION> Mengistu </ORGANIZATION> who has ruled <LOCATION> Ethiopia </LOCATION> since Feb. 12, 1977. In his speech, <ORGANIZATION> Mengistu </ORGANIZATION> also referred to <LOCATION> Ethiopia </LOCATION>'s unusually good rains this year and expressed confidence that if the wet weather continues, the nation `` will, in a short time, be free of food shortages which have made us the butt of an unhealthy comment.'' The Horn of <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> nation suffers chronic droughts which in 1984-85 led to a famine that killed an estimated 1 million people and sparked the largest international relief effort in history. Rains failed again in 1987 causing widespread crop failures that threatened an estimated 3.2 million people with starvation in <LOCATION> Eritrea </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Tigray </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880912-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-12-88 2344EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Britain-Mail     09-12 0426</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Britain-Mail,0441</SECOND>
<HEAD>Union Leaders Call Off 13-Day-Old Mail Strike</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Union leaders ended <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s 13-day mail strike Monday, but home and international service will remain disrupted for two weeks as workers wade through a backlog of 150 million letters and packages, officials said. The national executive board of the <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Communication </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Workers </ORGANIZATION>, which represents 180,000 <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> employees, announced its support Monday for a pact to end the walkout, said spokesman <PERSON> Allen </PERSON> <PERSON> Slater </PERSON>. `` The objective by both sides should be to return to work by Thursday,'' <PERSON> Slater </PERSON> said. The 100,000 striking workers will iron out return-to-work details with managers at local post offices, he said. `` This has been an extremely damaging dispute for our customers,'' said <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Cockburn </PERSON>, managing director of <ORGANIZATION> Royal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mail </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Letters </ORGANIZATION>, the letters and parcels division of the <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION>. `` There is a mountain of mail, and there will be an all-out effort to move it.'' Union Secretary-General <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Tuffin </PERSON> said local union chiefs will forge their own deals on overtime and the use of temporary workers. `` We are going to try to get this industry back on its feet with the cooperation of the workforce,'' he said in a TV news broadcast on Channel Four. <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> leaders agreed to a back-to-work plan last Thursday, but <PERSON> Tuffin </PERSON> said he wanted `` no misunderstanding'' and sent his negotiators back to the table over the weekend. Monday's agreement also establishes a framework for further discussions on the strike's central issue of regional pay supplements. <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman <PERSON> Melanie </PERSON> <PERSON> Corfield </PERSON> said local managers may press returning strikers to accept a number of temporary employees to cope with the `` Christmas-like'' volume of mail. International mail, first-class letters and parcels will receive priority as the backlog is cleared, said Ms. <PERSON> Corfield </PERSON>. Public mailboxes, which have been sealed throughout the dispute, will reopen `` only when we can guarantee people normal service again,'' she said. The <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> wishes to pay bonuses to new workers in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> southeast </LOCATION> <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>, where the cost of living is high and retaining workers proves difficult. The union demanded that the bonuses be paid across the country or not all and began a 24-hour work stoppage Aug. 31 that burgeoned into a series of crippling wildcat strikes. <PERSON> Tuffin </PERSON> said a deal could be reached over the pay issue within six weeks. About half of <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s 1,500 local post offices closed down during the strike and of the 82 major sorting centers, only one, in <LOCATION> Belfast </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION>, was open for business before the agreement was announced Monday, said Ms. <PERSON> Corfield </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880912-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-12-88 2345EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Japan-NorthKorea     09-12 0295</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Japan-North Korea,0300</SECOND>
<HEAD>Japan To Lift Sanctions Against North Korea</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> said it will lift its sanctions against communist <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> on Friday, the day before the Summer Olympics open in <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>, `` in the friendly and generous spirit appropriate to a festival of peace.'' The decision was announced Tuesday, a day after an opposition leader returning from <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> said the <LOCATION> Pyongyang </LOCATION> government was willing to free two Japanese seamen detained for more than four years on spying charges. <PERSON> Tsuruo </PERSON> <PERSON> Yamaguchi </PERSON>, secretary-general of the <ORGANIZATION> Japan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Socialist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, said <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korean </LOCATION> leaders wanted to improve North Korean-Japanese relations. The relations were ruptured when <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION> imposed the sanctions early this year after <LOCATION> Pyongyang </LOCATION>'s alleged bombing of a South Korean passenger flight near <LOCATION> Burma </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> denied involvement in the disaster, which killed all 115 people aboard the aircraft last November. Japanese sanctions included restrictions on contact between Japanese and <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korean </LOCATION> officials. `` Since that time, domestic and foreign interest in preventing the recurrence of terrorism has reached an unprecedentedly high level, indicating that the aim of showing <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s firm attitude against terrorism has been achieved,'' the chief <ORGANIZATION> Cabinet </ORGANIZATION> secretary, <PERSON> Keizo </PERSON> <PERSON> Obuchi </PERSON>, said in a statement following a Cabinet meeting Tuesday morning. <PERSON> Obuchi </PERSON> said <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> will lift the sanctions `` from the viewpoint that the Games may be conducted with the utmost possible relaxation of tension and in the friendly and generous spirit appropriate to a festival of peace.'' <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> is a major ally of pro-Western <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> and maintains no official diplomatic ties with <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> has sought help from third parties, including the <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION> and <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, in winning the freedom of <PERSON> Isamu </PERSON> <PERSON> Beniko </PERSON> and <PERSON> Yoshio </PERSON> <PERSON> Kuriura </PERSON>. <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> detained the two seamen in 1983 on unspecified espionage charges.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880912-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-12-88 2353EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-FrogLegs     09-12 0382</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Frog Legs,0395</SECOND>
<HEAD>Pascagoula Businessman Gears Up For Frog Leg Production</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JACK ELLIOTT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>JACKSON, Miss. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A businessman is leaping to fill the gap created by dropping supplies of bullfrogs, whose legs are consumed as a cripsy delicacy in the South. <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Maghan </PERSON> was almost hopping in anticipation Monday of an experimental program to raise the big, hopping amphibians. `` It's not really even off the ground yet. But we're pretty excited,'' the owner of <ORGANIZATION> Stillashak </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institutional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sea </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Products </ORGANIZATION> said in a telephone interview from <LOCATION> Pascagoula </LOCATION> on the Gulf Coast. `` If you look what has been done in this state for the shrimp, oyster, striped bass and redfish industies, there's no reason it ca n't be done for frog legs,'' <PERSON> Maghan </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Maghan </PERSON> said that three years ago he was paying $ 2.15 to $ 2.20 a pound for frog legs. The price is now about $ 4.06 per pound. `` I have been quoted as much as $ 5 to $ 5.10. That goes to show you that the market is way up. Three years ago, I was getting about six to eight pair of legs to the pound. Now, its about four to six pairs per pound. `` But we are also looking at the remnants of supplies, and those are depleting fast,'' he said. <PERSON> Maghan </PERSON> said in 1986-87, more than 8.6 million pounds of frog legs came into the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> from <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Bangladesh </LOCATION>. He said the market could be as much as 10 million pounds. But <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Bangladesh </LOCATION> have put a five-year moratorium on such exports, he said. `` They -LRB- the bullfrogs -RRB- are wild over there and they have taken so many of them that the insect problem has increased, so they are n't shipping any more. `` But I believe there is no reason why <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> ca n't raise all the frogs we need,'' he said. <PERSON> Maghan </PERSON> said the adult frogs eat insects, but he's trying to come up with a feed that will increase their size and growth. He plans to start with tadpoles and raise them all the way to adults. `` It is a long process,'' <PERSON> Maghan </PERSON> said. `` It is not something we expect to do overnight. We expect to raise the critters in a pond, but everything else is still up in the air.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880912-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-12-88 2338EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-FighterCrash     09-12 0232</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Fighter Crash,0240</SECOND>
<HEAD>F-14 Crashes in Atlantic</HEAD>
<DATELINE>HATTERAS, N.C. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An F-14 Tomcat jet fighter crashed in the <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ocean </LOCATION> Monday, and one crewman was killed and the other missing, the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> said. A fishing vessel, Jo-Boy II, managed to pick up one crewman, but he was pronounced dead when he arrived by helicopter at <LOCATION> Portsmouth </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Naval </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>, authorities said. A search continued late Monday for the second flier. The F-14 based at <LOCATION> Oceana </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Naval </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Air </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Station </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, went down 22 miles east of <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Inlet </LOCATION>, said <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> spokesman P.E. <PERSON> Wilkinson </PERSON>. The plane, part of <LOCATION> Oceana </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Fighter </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Squadron </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> 143 </ORGANIZATION>, was practicing air combat maneuvers with several other planes, said Lt. Cmdr. <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> John </PERSON>, spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Atlantic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fleet </ORGANIZATION> air force. The identities of the dead man and the missing man were withheld pending notification of relatives. Two charter boat captains carrying fishing parties watched from several miles away as the F-14 hit the water. `` I saw a streak of flame and a great big fireball about 500 feet from the surface,'' said <PERSON> Warren </PERSON> <PERSON> Gallop </PERSON>, captain of the Mighty Wind, which is based at the Oregon Inlet Fishing Center. `` I heard an explosion and I could see stuff flying through the air. It sounded like a big boom. It scattered stuff over a wide area.'' <PERSON> John </PERSON> said the $ 35 million aircraft sank soon after impact.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880912-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-12-88 2353EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Jordan-Jets     09-12 0210</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Jordan-Jets,0215</SECOND>
<HEAD>Jordan to Buy Tornado Jets from The United Kingdom</HEAD>
<DATELINE>AMMAN, Jordan (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Jordan </PERSON> has reached an agreement with <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> to buy an undisclosed number of the multi-role Tornado fighter jets, <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION>'s official news agency <ORGANIZATION> Petra </ORGANIZATION> reported. A senior air force official told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> on Monday that the agreement was formalized during a meeting between King <PERSON> Hussein </PERSON> and Prime Minister <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>. He did not say when the meeting took place, but <PERSON> Hussein </PERSON> has been in <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> for several days on a private visit. The official, who requested anonymity in line with air force regulations, refused to say what the deal was worth or how many planes were involved. <PERSON> Petra </PERSON> also did not give such details. Sources said earlier the king was seeking to buy 40 Tornado warplanes. The agency said the deal was part of the `` the king's desire to develop and strengthen the defense capabilities of the Jordanian air force.'' <PERSON> Jordan </PERSON> turned to <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> after the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> blocked a deal involving the sale of F-20 and F-16 warplanes to the <LOCATION> Jordanian </LOCATION> air force. Last year, <LOCATION> Saudi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arabia </LOCATION> bought 72 Tornado jets from <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> for similar reasons. In February, <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> agreed to sell <ORGANIZATION> Jordan </ORGANIZATION> 20 Mirage 2000 fighter jets.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880912-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-12-88 0000EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-6MilesUpandSleepyI-1stAdd     09-11 1024</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-6 Miles Up and Sleepy I - 1st Add,1050</SECOND>
<HEAD>UNDATED: people died.</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Both accidents were blamed on pilot error. Experts say hard evidence rarely exists to show pilots erred because they were tired. `` The problem with fatigue is it's not a bent piece of metal. It's not a liquid that can be analyzed in the laboratory,'' said Dr. <PERSON> Stanley </PERSON> <PERSON> Mohler </PERSON>, a former <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> official who heads aerospace medicine at <ORGANIZATION> Wright </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. Government and airline officials acknowledge they've heard tales of pilots napping in flight and of mistakes attributed to sleepiness, but they play down such reports. `` There is n't evidence that there is a fatigue problem,'' said <PERSON> Walt </PERSON> <PERSON> Coleman </PERSON>, spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transport </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, a trade group representing the major airlines. <PERSON> T. </PERSON> <PERSON> Allan </PERSON> <PERSON> McArtor </PERSON>, administrator of the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aviation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>, says more research is needed into the effects of long flights on the circadian system, or biological clock. But he denies a safety problem. `` There's no evidence that shows it makes flying any more hazardous,'' <PERSON> McArtor </PERSON> said. Some 600 accounts of missed approaches, near misses and near tragedies blamed on fatigue show up in voluntary pilot reports filed with the Air Safety Reporting System, an office run by <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> for pilots who want to confess to mistakes and report risky conditions without fear of retribution. Enough reports were filed by crews for commuter airlines and air taxis that the <ORGANIZATION> ASRS </ORGANIZATION> sent a memo to the <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> in May identifying `` recurring pilot deviations directly attributable to fatigue and cockpit workload.'' `` The big chunk that we have perceived out of this information is that fatigue is a real issue that needs to be addressed,'' said <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Reynard </PERSON>, who runs the reporting system. Even though the reports are protected by anonymity and are not investigated by the <ORGANIZATION> ASRS </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Reynard </PERSON> believes they are truthful. `` It is absolutely, positively valid that these numbers are real,'' he said. `` Our analysts have been in aviation for 20 to 30 years. They are very good at spotting a ringer.'' The reports provide a litany of horror stories: _ In February 1987, the co-pilot of a cross-country jumbo jet already descending into <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> looks up from his coffee cup to see the captain asleep at the controls. `` I think we need to look at the world of the pilot and see what more hours and labor unrest is doing,'' he writes. _ The next month a large airliner from <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Baltimore </LOCATION> sinks 4,000 feet below its assigned altitude, coming close enough to another plane to set off alarms at the air traffic control center. `` I do not believe it would have occurred to a rested crew,'' writes a crewmember, noting he flew all night to <LOCATION> Cleveland </LOCATION> then continued to <LOCATION> Baltimore </LOCATION> into the morning sun. `` Duty regulations.. do not in any way address the debilitating effects of flying all night and especially of continuing to work into the morning hours.'' _ Last November the co-pilot of another large jet begins a takeoff roll from <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lauderdale </LOCATION> without setting the flaps, an error then already suspected in the <ORGANIZATION> Northwest </ORGANIZATION> DC-9 crash in <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION> that had killed 154 people three months earlier. Cockpit warning horns sound and takeoff is aborted. In the <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION> crash, the horns failed to sound. `` It is quite sobering to consider that the combination of fatigue and distractions could so easily cause a breakdown in my own cockpit discipline,'' writes the co-pilot, who had flown for three days with little sleep. `` Complacency was not a factor,'' he writes. `` Simple fatigue was the culprit.'' That incident affords a good look at the shadowy effects of fatigue. Planes do n't crash because pilots are tired, say the experts. Fatigue becomes a killer only when something else _ equipment or the weather _ goes wrong as well. If, for example, the <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lauderdale </LOCATION> flight's warning horns had failed, as they did in <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION>, the tired pilot's oversight could have been fatal. In the <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION> crash, there was no evidence fatigue played a role. On paper, <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> flight rules seem favorable to pilots. Domestic pilots are limited to eight hours' flight time a day; overseas pilots fly no more than 12. All pilots must get at least eight hours of rest between flight sequences. However, the regulations count only scheduled flight time, not the hours spent on the ground between flights. So scheduled turnarounds and unscheduled delays can push a crew's day up to 16 hours. Scheduling agreements between airlines and pilots once kept flight hours well below federal standards, but concessions to management have become commonplace amid the fierce competition brought on by deregulation. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Mazor </PERSON>, spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> Airline </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pilots </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, said that 10 years ago, at the start of deregulation, the typical contract limited flight time to a maximum of 75 to 80 hours per month. Today, he says, it's 80-85 hours. <ORGANIZATION> Continental </ORGANIZATION> pilots, who lost their contract when the company reorganized in 1983, now fly 20 percent more hours a month. The company says its flight hours are still well under the industry average. `` Our ... work rules remove the anti-productivity aspects to allow reasonable productivity,'' said spokesman <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Hicks </PERSON>. Northwest pilots complain their company has interpreted regulations to allow international crews flying home to take on additional domestic flights, adding up to four flight hours to their day. Northwest, citing ongoing negotiations with the pilots, declined to comment. When <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> acquired <ORGANIZATION> Pan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION>'s <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> routes in 1986, its pilots faced extended flight hours and reduced crew size on the longer routes. A separate contract added a day of work each month. `` The Pan Am guys had a cushy job, but the company fell on hard times,'' said <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Ferg </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION>'s director of flight operations. `` We're trying to strike a balance between what's fair and equitable for the pilots and what's economical.'' Many pilots interviewed complain the scales are tipped too far toward economics at the expense of safety. `` I've got 400 people in that airplane and I take it very seriously,'' said a <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> 747 pilot. `` It's a responsibility, and you know this is n't good for the passengers.''
</TEXT>
<HEAD>NEXT: The Science of Sleepy Pilots.</HEAD>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880912-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-12-88 0004EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Asia-Australia     09-12 0830</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Asia-Australia,0853</SECOND>
<HEAD>Asians Keep Close Watch On Immigration Issue In Australia</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By LARRY THORSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Asians are keeping a close eye on an immigration debate in <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION> to see if it will mean a slow down in the flow of <LOCATION> Asian </LOCATION> emigrants into the country. Some Asians say they see signs of racism. Several Asian newspapers have published editorials reminding <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION> of its growing economic links with <LOCATION> Asian </LOCATION> countries. `` The outcome of the intense immigration debate now under way in <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION> will either confirm or confound the view Asians hold that a strong undercurrent of racism exists in the ` Lucky Country','' the conservative English-language <ORGANIZATION> South </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> China </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Morning </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> said. `` While <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION> was founded on British values, the facts today are that politically and economically the country can not always look West.'' In <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION>, a growing influx of Asian migrants is in the background of a debate over immigration rules and multi-culturalism _ a policy that encourages migrants to keep cultural links with their homelands. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Howard </PERSON>, leader of <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION>'s opposition <ORGANIZATION> Liberal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, says immigration from <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION> should be slowed in the interests of social harmony and that immigrants should embrace the English-speaking majority's Anglo-Saxon cultural values. `` I am not saying I would end Asian immigration,'' he said. `` But what I am saying is that it is a legitimate concern of any community and any government to say that it is imposing social tensions and that it is imposing a lack of social cohesion.'' The government has proposed legislation that would prohibit the use of race or ethnic origins as criteria for judging potential immigrants' acceptability. <PERSON> Howard </PERSON>, who heads a two-party national opposition, is against the bill but has lost support recently in Parliament. Prime Minister <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Hawke </PERSON>, of the <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, has vowed to fight any move to restrict <LOCATION> Asian </LOCATION> immigration and says he would maintain a policy of non-discrimination even if he thought it would mean losing an election. <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION>, a continent with only 16 million people near <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION>'s huge population of 3 billion, is an attractive destination for emigrants It is called `` lucky'' because of its rich resources and comfortable climate. The Australian Bureau of Statistics says the number of <LOCATION> Asian </LOCATION> immigrants climbed by one-third in the past year. Out of 116,430 immigrants between January and November 1987, 47,450 were Asians, compared with 36,360 in the same period in 1986. <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION> has taken in 100,000 Vietnamese since 1975, when the <LOCATION> Indochina </LOCATION> war ended, and has a growing Chinese community. Emigration counselors in several <LOCATION> Asian </LOCATION> countries list <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION> as attractive for its climate, proximity and educational opportunities for children. Increasing numbers of Asians with capital and business experience are snowing interest in emigrating to <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION>. In <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION> now surpassed <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> as the top choice of emigrants. `` People here barely knew anything about <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION> three years ago,'' said <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Chang </PERSON>, manager of <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Queter </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Company </ORGANIZATION>, which handles emigration applications to <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION>. `` But emigrating to <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION> has become a fad now.'' <PERSON> Chang </PERSON> said he understood why <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION> had doubled the capital requirement for business emigrants to 500,000 Australian dollars -LRB- $ 410,000 -RRB- in the past year. `` <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION> no longer needs foreign capital and personnel now as much as before. It is only natural that it closes the door a bit.'' In <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION>, where emigration is on the upswing due to nervousness over <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s taking sovereignty of the British colony in 1997, <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION> is the second most popular destination after <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Janet </PERSON> <PERSON> Sekavs </PERSON>, regional migration director in <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION>'s Consulate in <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION>, said 6,431 Filipinos emigrated to <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION> in 1986, compared with 5,140 from <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> and 5,032 from <LOCATION> Malaysia </LOCATION> <PERSON> Chan </PERSON> <PERSON> Ka-wai </PERSON>, editor of The Emigrant, <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION>'s magazine on emigration, said he thought the number of emigration applications would remain high even if <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION> imposes new curbs. `` <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION> is strange,'' <PERSON> Chan </PERSON> said. `` It is in <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION> but it does not treat itself as an Asian country. It is a multi-racial country and economically it should have the potential to accept more people.'' <PERSON> Susie </PERSON> <PERSON> Tse </PERSON>, migration service manager of Price Waterhouse emigration consultancy in <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION>, said, `` It would be racist if <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION> refuses Asians. But from my nine years' experience in <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION>, I have not felt any racism and am not sure if it is just over-exaggeration by the press.'' The fiercest reaction has come from a <LOCATION> Malaysian </LOCATION> newspaper, the Star in <LOCATION> Kuala </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lumpur </LOCATION>, where editor V.K. <PERSON> Chin </PERSON> wrote in a recent column that Australians he described as racists make <LOCATION> Asian </LOCATION> immigrants `` feel inadequate, insecure and even sub-human.'' `` Based on the statements of some of these pillars of the Australian political establishment, it would appear that inside every Liberal senator or member of <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION> is a racist struggling to get out,'' <PERSON> Chin </PERSON> wrote. `` <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION> may be a big, wide-open country but it is in danger of being led by small-minded people with petty prejudices and attitudes more suited to the Victorian age.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880912-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-12-88 0005EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-VermontPrimary     09-12 0669</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Vermont Primary,0683</SECOND>
<HEAD>Vermont's Lone Congressman Seeking Open U.S. Senate Seat</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By CHRISTOPHER GRAFF</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MONTPELIER, Vt. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 For years, Republican <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Jeffords </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Vermont </LOCATION>'s lone member of the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, has enjoyed the backing of many state Democrats. Two years ago, he even won re-election with both the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> and Democratic nominations. This year, though, as <PERSON> Jeffords </PERSON> seeks the seat of retiring <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Sen. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Stafford </PERSON>, R-Vt., his popularity among Democrats is being used against him by <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> challenger <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Griffes </PERSON>, who calls himself the real Republican in the race <PERSON> Griffes </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jeffords </PERSON> will face off next Tuesday in <LOCATION> Vermont </LOCATION>'s Republican primary The winner will face Democrat <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Gray </PERSON>, a former <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> attorney, in the November election. <PERSON> Gray </PERSON> is unopposed in Tuesday's Democratic primary. <PERSON> Jeffords </PERSON> is the clear favorite in the primary, but his support of Democratic initiatives over the years has angered many of the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> faithful, including former four-term Gov. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Snelling </PERSON>, who donated $ 1,000 to the <PERSON> Griffes </PERSON> campaign. `` <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Jeffords </PERSON>, while he clearly has provided a long service to <LOCATION> Vermont </LOCATION>, has not, in my opinion, been very often mindful of the fact that he gets his nominations from the <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>,'' said <PERSON> Snelling </PERSON>, himself considered a moderate to liberal. While <PERSON> Snelling </PERSON> was willing to give money to <PERSON> Griffes </PERSON>, he withheld his formal endorsement, saying the 35-year-old political newcomer had not `` sufficiently established his credentials.'' And that is clearly <PERSON> Griffes </PERSON>' weak point. While <PERSON> Jeffords </PERSON>, 54, has lived his life in <LOCATION> Vermont </LOCATION> and served as a state senator, attorney general and member of the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Griffes </PERSON> had lived in the state only a year or so in the 1970s before returning here this spring to challenge <PERSON> Jeffords </PERSON>. He served in the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> and then worked for <ORGANIZATION> Grumman </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, a major defense contractor, in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. He said he decided to move back to <LOCATION> Vermont </LOCATION> to challenge <PERSON> Jeffords </PERSON> when the congressman was the only Republican in the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> last fall to vote for a $ 12 billion deficit-reduction measure backed by the Democratic leadership on a crucial 206-205 vote. That vote was only one of the many times <PERSON> Jeffords </PERSON> has broken party ranks. In 1981, he was the sole House Republican to vote against President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s tax-cut package. In 1987, <PERSON> Jeffords </PERSON> had the second-highest anti-Reagan voting record among Republicans in the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, as analyzed by <ORGANIZATION> Congressional </ORGANIZATION> Quarterly magazine. He opposed the president on 71 percent of the key votes. `` When you get to the point where you start making decisions or doing things based upon political expedience, you've worn out your usefulness as someone who can really help,'' said <PERSON> Jeffords </PERSON>, who says he makes his decisions on what's best for Vermonters, not on what's best for the Republicans. <PERSON> Griffes </PERSON> campaigns by saying that <PERSON> Jeffords </PERSON> should be honest and seek the Democratic nomination. `` My record will be more like <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Stafford </PERSON>'s and not like <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Speaker <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>'s,'' says <PERSON> Griffes </PERSON>, a reference to <LOCATION> Vermont </LOCATION>'s retiring Republican senator and the Democratic speaker of the House. <PERSON> Jeffords </PERSON> is considered the strong favorite in the November election, should he win the primary, because of his strong Democratic support. The Republican primary for the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> is one of three statewide contests that will be decided Tuesday. With <PERSON> Jeffords </PERSON> giving up his <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> seat, four Democrats and two Republicans are seeking their respective party nominations. The two winners will be joined on the November ballot by <LOCATION> Burlington </LOCATION> Mayor <PERSON> Bernard </PERSON> <PERSON> Sanders </PERSON>, a socialist who is running a strong independent campaign for the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> seat, and candidates representing the <ORGANIZATION> Liberty </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Libertarian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> and the Small Is Beautiful Party. Former Lt. Gov. <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> is favored to win the Republican congressional race, while the Democratic race, featuring former Secretary of <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> James </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guest </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Majority Leader <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Poirier </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> President Pro Tem <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Welch </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Vermont </ORGANIZATION> professor <PERSON> Dolores </PERSON> <PERSON> Sandoval </PERSON>, is considered wide open. Gov. <PERSON> Madeleine </PERSON> <PERSON> Kunin </PERSON>, seeking her third term, is unopposed in Tuesday's primary, as is her Republican challenger, state Rep. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Bernhardt </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880912-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-12-88 0007EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-WisconsinPrimary     09-12 0810</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Wisconsin Primary,0835</SECOND>
<HEAD>Big Bucks Spent For Proxmire's Seat</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By ARTHUR L. SRB</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MADISON, Wis. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Big spending has become a big issue in Tuesday's heated Democratic primary battle for the seat held for 31 years by retiring Sen. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Proxmire </PERSON>, whose last re-election campaign cost him $ 145.10. <ORGANIZATION> Milwaukee </ORGANIZATION> millionaire <PERSON> Herbert </PERSON> <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON>, running in his first election, stands accused of trying to buy the nomination by spending more than $ 2 million, much of it on TV advertising and much of it his own money. `` Politics should be people, ideas and leadership, not multimillion-dollar TV hype,'' said Secretary of <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Douglas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> La </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Follette </ORGANIZATION>, one of <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON>'s Democratic foes. <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION> is one of six states holding primary elections Tuesday. <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON>, 53, owner of the <ORGANIZATION> Milwaukee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bucks </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> the </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Basketball </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, said he had to buy the ads to win the name recognition enjoyed by <PERSON> La </PERSON> <PERSON> Follette </PERSON>, former Gov. <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON> <PERSON> Earl </PERSON> and <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Garvey </PERSON>, who was the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> nominee two years ago. `` I'm not looking to get ahead of the other -LRB- candidates -RRB-,'' <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON> said. `` I just want to get to the point where we are even.'' On the Republican side, state <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Minority Leader <PERSON> Susan </PERSON> <PERSON> Engeleiter </PERSON>, 36, and <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> B </PERSON>. King, 47, former chairman of the state <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION>, are running a more ideological race. He has labeled her a liberal and she has called him an ultra-conservative. <PERSON> Proxmire </PERSON>, who devoted nearly 32 years in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> to fighting for budget cuts, said he was disappointed by the hefty spending in the race to replace him. <PERSON> Proxmire </PERSON> said he spent $ 145.10 in breezing to re-election in 1982. <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON>, whose slogan is `` nobody's senator but yours,'' said he would not be obligated to special interest groups if elected because the money he spent was mainly his own. In his last campaign spending report, <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON> said he spent nearly $ 2.1 million between his June 1 entry into the campaign and Aug. 24. He reported more than $ 1.5 million hand. `` We're spending way too much,'' <PERSON> Earl </PERSON> said. As of Aug. 24, <PERSON> Earl </PERSON> had spent $ 431,719 and <PERSON> Garvey </PERSON> $ 360,000. <ORGANIZATION> La </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Follette </ORGANIZATION> reported expenditures of $ 15,536. <PERSON> Engeleiter </PERSON> reported she spent $ 858,580 through Aug. 24, and King $ 342,907. One early Democratic candidate, Rep. <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Moody </PERSON>, dropped out shortly after <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON>'s entry. He said he could n't afford to compete with <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON>. A recent poll commissioned by several TV stations showed <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON> with 35 percent support and <PERSON> Earl </PERSON> with 33 percent among those who said they were likely to vote. <PERSON> Garvey </PERSON> had 16 percent and <ORGANIZATION> La </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Follette </ORGANIZATION> 6 percent. Nine percent were undecided. On the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> side, <PERSON> Engeleiter </PERSON> led King 48 percent to 32 percent. <PERSON> Earl </PERSON>, 52, is a Madison attorney and former legislator who lost his 1986 bid for re-election as governor to Republican <PERSON> Tommy </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON>. <PERSON> Garvey </PERSON>, 48, a lawyer and former executive director of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Football </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> League </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Players </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, lost a close battle to unseat Republican Sen. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kasten </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> in 1986. <PERSON> La </PERSON> <PERSON> Follette </PERSON>, 48, in his third term as secretary of state, was a professor at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wisconsin-Parkside </ORGANIZATION> before his election to the state <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> in 1972. He is a distant relative of the <PERSON> La </PERSON> <PERSON> Follette </PERSON> family that produced several top <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION> politicians, including two governors, and was an unsuccessful candidate for lieutenant governor in 1978. King, now a businessman, is a former <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> agent who later served <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON> when <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON> headed President <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON>'s Watergate-tainted re-election campaign His major campaign fund-raiser featured <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> <PERSON> North </PERSON>, a key figure in the Iran-Contra affair. <PERSON> Engeleiter </PERSON>, a 12-year veteran of the Legislature. Differences between her and <PERSON> King </PERSON> became personal when King brought up the subject of <PERSON> Engeleiter </PERSON>'s two children, ages 1 and 4. `` If my family were young, if they were pre-schoolers, I would not be making this race,'' <PERSON> King </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Engeleiter </PERSON> countered that nearly three out of four women work outside the home, and that under King's philosophy, neither <PERSON> Kasten </PERSON> nor Republican Rep. <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Petri </PERSON> would have a place in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. Here are highlights of the voting Tuesday: <LOCATION> ARIZONA </LOCATION> _ A large number of <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> legislators who voted to impeach or convict ex-Gov. <PERSON> Evan </PERSON> <PERSON> Mecham </PERSON> earlier this year are being challenged by his ultra-conservative supporters. <LOCATION> MINNESOTA </LOCATION> _ Both GOP Sen. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Durenberger </PERSON> and his likely Democratic opponent, state Attorney General <PERSON> Hubert </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Humphrey </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>, face minor opposition from within their parties. <LOCATION> NEW </LOCATION> <LOCATION> HAMPSHIRE </LOCATION> _ Republican Rep. <PERSON> Judd </PERSON> <PERSON> Gregg </PERSON> is favored to win the nomination for governor to succeed <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Sununu </PERSON>, who is retiring. Democrat <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> McEachern </PERSON> has no primary opposition. <LOCATION> VERMONT </LOCATION> _ Rep. <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Jeffords </PERSON> faces conservative <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Griffes </PERSON> for the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> nomination for the seat of retiring Republican Sen. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Stafford </PERSON>. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Gray </PERSON> is the unopposed Democratic nominee. <LOCATION> UTAH </LOCATION> _ Democrats <PERSON> Craig </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> and <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Stringham </PERSON> both seek the nomination to oppose three-term Republican Rep. <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Nielson </PERSON> for <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880912-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-12-88 0008EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Fires-Yellowstone     09-12 0624</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Fires-Yellowstone,0645</SECOND>
<HEAD>Yellowstone Becomes Fiery Battleground In Losing War With Nature</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By DAVID FOSTER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>YELLOWSTONE NATIONAL PARK, Wyo. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Buffalo graze nonchalantly near flaming trees, but people are not reacting so coolly, and residents once worried about losing business to forest fires now fear losing their homes. Fire has destroyed buildings around the Old Faithful geyser and has threatened tourist towns on the periphery of the country's first national park The <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION> towns of <LOCATION> Cooke </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> and Silver Gate outside the park's northeast entrance were evacuted twice last week. <PERSON> Jardine </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Mont. </LOCATION>, near the northern gate, was evacuated Saturday. Firefighters saved <ORGANIZATION> Cooke </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> and Silver Gate, but only by burning thousands of acres of forest to remove fuel from the fire's path The so-called backfires left the once-picturesque towns flanked by black, skeletal trees. `` All we can do ... is herd it around improvements and structures _ and do n't get anybody killed,'' said <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Martines </PERSON>, a structure protection officer in <LOCATION> Cooke </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. The 2.2 million-acre park, dedicated in 1872, attracts more than 2 million visitors a year who marvel at geysers and hot springs, mountain scenery and wild animals. But tourists have stayed away in droves this summer, and residents of tourism-dependent towns around the park have complained bitterly about the <ORGANIZATION> Park </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>'s initial reluctance to respond to the fires. `` A guy gets really bitter when it keeps dragging on and on and on,'' said <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Klatt </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Cooke </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, who spent spent three days in a motel room outside of town last week, waiting out an evacuation. In this summer of heat and drought, <ORGANIZATION> Yellowstone </ORGANIZATION> is suffering the worst fires in at least 200 years. Forest fires have charred more than 1 million acres in <LOCATION> Yellowstone </LOCATION> and in the surrounding national forests and parks in <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION>, and <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION>. Each day, firefighters pray for rain, but at park headquarters near <LOCATION> Mammoth </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hot </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Springs </LOCATION> this is the third-driest summer on record. Only 1.6 inches of rain fell at Mammoth in June, July and August _ one-third the normal rainfall. It was also the hottest summer on record, with temperatures steaming an average of 5 degrees above normal, the weather service said. Though other areas are hard hit, <ORGANIZATION> Yellowstone </ORGANIZATION> is the top concern of federal officials. Of $ 250 million spent so far on fighting fires, $ 78 million has gone toward efforts around the park, said the <ORGANIZATION> Boise </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Interagency </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fire </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>, which coordinates firefighting in the West. Since 1972, park officials have allowed lightning-sparked fires to burn. `` In the past 16 years, we had 140 fires that burned 33,000 acres. That averages about 240 acres apiece before they went out on their own,'' said <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Varley </PERSON>, chief of the park's research division. The fires help cleanse the pine forest. They clear deadwood, create new meadows for forage, release nutrients for new plants and free the pines' seeds from their cones. A cool, wet spring lulled park officials into believing this summer would be no different. But the heat and low humidity left the forest more parched than kiln-dried lumber. By July 15, when the <ORGANIZATION> Park </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> decided to start fighting the fires, it was too late to stop them. Fire crew boss <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Borton </PERSON> has battled forest fires in the West for 18 years, but the blaze he had been fighting and sleeping near for 25 nights was something new. `` This is the edge of a fire that goes back 50 miles,'' he said. `` It's as out of control as it was six weeks ago. This is the most extreme fire behavior that just about any of us has ever seen.''
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Foster </PERSON> is the <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Northwest </ORGANIZATION> regional reporter, based in <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880912-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-12-88 0013EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-RedBarron     09-12 0723</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Red Barron,0743</SECOND>
<HEAD>`Red Barron' of Florida Legislature Ousted After Three Decades</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By BILL KACZOR</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>TALLAHASSEE, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Among the portraits of former <ORGANIZATION> Florida </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> presidents hanging in the chamber, it's easy to pick out <PERSON> Dempsey </PERSON> <PERSON> Barron </PERSON>. He's the one riding the horse. The Panhandle lawyer-rancher, who friends and foes alike call one of the most powerful men in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> government, exercises his authority `` exactly like the Godfather,'' a former colleague says. But that era is coming to an end. The 66-year-old, auburn-haired `` Red Barron'' was narrowly defeated in the Democratic primary on Tuesday. He lost to <PERSON> Vince </PERSON> <PERSON> Bruner </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Walton </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION> lawyer born a year after <PERSON> Barron </PERSON> was first elected to the <ORGANIZATION> Legislature </ORGANIZATION> 32 years ago. A conservative Democrat, <PERSON> Barron </PERSON> served as <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> president in 1975-76, once ordering then-Gov. <PERSON> Reubin </PERSON> <PERSON> Askew </PERSON> to stay out of the upper chamber, although in much more colorful words. Since then, he has served almost continuously as chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rules </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, giving him control over the legislative calendar and make-or-break authority over bills. `` He's really one of a kind,'' said <PERSON> Allen </PERSON> <PERSON> Morris </PERSON>, historian and former clerk of the state House. `` I've been here since 1941 and really ca n't think of anybody who compares to him.'' His departure `` will reorganize the thinking in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>,'' <PERSON> Morris </PERSON> said. `` The senators no longer will have to puzzle over wat <PERSON> Dempsey </PERSON> thinks of each bill.'' In his successful primary challenge, <PERSON> Bruner </PERSON> cited <PERSON> Barron </PERSON>'s support of a tax increase and claimed <PERSON> Barron </PERSON> failed to pay attention to constituent needs and was too cozy to state business interests His challenge was aided by feminists angered that <PERSON> Barron </PERSON> helped kill the Equal Rights Amendment and by trial lawyers who opposed <PERSON> Barron </PERSON>'s efforts on behalf of insurance companies, many of them represented by his law firm, to limit the size of verdicts in negligence suits. `` He was the architect of the defeat of the Equal Rights Amendment in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>,'' said <PERSON> Molly </PERSON> <PERSON> Yard </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Women </ORGANIZATION>. `` Good riddance! I think we helped to dig his grave.'' As a result of <PERSON> Barron </PERSON>'s departure, some colleagues have been predicting a more partisan and open <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>, and reforms to reduce the virtually dictatorial power of the leadership. <PERSON> Barron </PERSON> exercised his power `` exactly like The Godfather,'' said former Democratic Sen. <PERSON> Roberta </PERSON> <PERSON> Fox </PERSON>. `` His ability to do that was seductive, not in a sexual sense, but he had a truly seductive personality.'' The power was wielded with little regard to party labels and party loyalty. When unable to get his way in Democratic caucuses, he forged coalitions between conservatives in his own party, or `` Dempseycrats,'' and Republicans. He angered Democrat leaders by throwing his support to Republican candidates for national and statewide office, including <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Martinez </PERSON> in his successful run for governor in 1986. Republicans did much of the mourning over his loss. `` I'm shocked, I'm sick,'' said <PERSON> Tommy </PERSON> <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON>, a former state <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> chairman. `` We knew he was in a tight race,'' said <PERSON> Brian </PERSON> <PERSON> Ballard </PERSON>, chief of operations for <PERSON> Martinez </PERSON>. `` But we all thought he would make it because he's <PERSON> Dempsey </PERSON>, he's the ` Red Barron,' and he's supposed to pull out.'' But the Democratic state chairman, <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Whitehead </PERSON>, had little sympathy. `` Sen. <PERSON> Barron </PERSON> lost the race when he and <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Martinez </PERSON> rode their horses together and put their arms around each other at the Bonifay Rodeo two years ago,'' <PERSON> Whitehead </PERSON> said. `` He alienated all the Democrats in the area by doing that. `` And it turns out <PERSON> Martinez </PERSON> and <PERSON> Barron </PERSON> joined together to give us the biggest tax increase we ever had.'' <PERSON> Bruner </PERSON> had hammered <PERSON> Barron </PERSON>, usually a steadfast opponent of taxes _ any taxes _ for his support of <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>'s ill-fated, $ 1 billion-a-year services tax. The tax was repealed in the wake of stiff opposition last year, but the governor and <PERSON> Barron </PERSON> wound up accepting an even bigger increase in the general sales tax. <PERSON> Barron </PERSON> said he has no regrets and plans to spend more time at his ranches in the <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Panhandle </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION>. `` I'm a pretty private person and I'm going to live my life with my friends and move down the road,'' he said. `` My cattle are in good shape. I'm going to go up and cut hay. ... I've enjoyed the ride. Shed no tears for me.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880912-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-12-88 0014EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-AmericanSavings     09-12 0752</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-American Savings,0774</SECOND>
<HEAD>Troubled Thrift Abandoned Industry's Traditional Conservatism</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By GEORGE GARTIES</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Business Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Savings </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; Loan became the industry's biggest financial basket case by abandoning conservative ways, and some worry that a $ 2 billion federal bailout does n't do enough to force a return to conservatism As details of the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Home </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Loan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION>'s blueprint for reviving the nation's second-largest thrift trickle out, analysts, legislators and competitors are sounding calls for caution. Some fret over the planned transfer of American to the aggressive Bass investment group and suggestions that the revived company could be allowed to venture beyond the <ORGANIZATION> standard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> S </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; L business of home loans and savings accounts. Others recall what they see as regulatory inaction during the company's four-year slide toward receivership, a slide most blame on aggressive management, too-rapid growth and risky real estate loans. <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Savings </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ; </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Loan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, with headquarters in <LOCATION> Stockton </LOCATION> and 186 branches throughout <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, was seized by the bank board Tuesday as a prelude to turning it over to the <ORGANIZATION> Robert </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> M. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bass </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Group </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fort </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Worth </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>. Bass will pump $ 550 million cash into the insolvent thrift, and the bank board has committed $ 2 billion in cash and promissory notes over the next decade. American continues to operate; its parent company, <ORGANIZATION> Financial </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Irvine </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, announced plans to file a federal bankruptcy petition. American's problems pre-date the 1983 joining of <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Savings </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; Loan and <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Savings </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; Loan, the merger gave the company its present form. State, under Chairman <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Knapp </PERSON>, was known for making loans on commercial real estate ventures and developments spurned by other S & amp; Ls. American was a virtual opposite, with a large branch network and a portfolio of conservative home loans and savings accounts on which it paid relatively low interest. Regulators already keeping an eye on State believed that the merger, which created what was then the nation's biggest <ORGANIZATION> S </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; L, would stabilize <PERSON> Knapp </PERSON>'s company. But American grew rapidly under <PERSON> Knapp </PERSON>, in part by making loans with fixed interest rates, a strategy that has come back to haunt <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> in periods of rising rates. In the summer of 1984, bank board analysts were warning that loans made by <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> and the old State Savings on real estate had been made without adequate analysis of the true value of the properties. Institutional investors were quietly withdrawing deposits amid a flurry of news reports about loan problems at American. A real depositor run began in 1984, after the <ORGANIZATION> Securities </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Exchange </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> forced American to restate its second-quarter results to account for losses on mortgage-backed securities, turning a $ 31 million profit into a $ 107 million loss. Losses from the run eventually were tallied at $ 6 billion. In August 1984, <PERSON> Knapp </PERSON> was forced out by the bank board and replaced by <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Popejoy </PERSON>. <PERSON> Popejoy </PERSON>, who had once been president of the old <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Savings </ORGANIZATION>, proceeded to cut costs, laying off 1,500 workers and selling 475 company cars and five jets. Management added to the company's reserve against bad loans, to the point where the reserve stood at more than $ 1.2 billion as of June 30. But after a period of shrinking American, <PERSON> Popejoy </PERSON> concluded the only way to save the company was to expand, adding branches and buying securities backed by mortgages with fixed interest rates. That's counter to an industry trend in recent years to issue mortgages with adjustable rates to protect the lender against rising interest rates. Competitors have pressed the bank board to rein in American, concerned that a big rescue would drive up their required payments to the industry's government-run insurance fund, the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Savings </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Loan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Insurance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp </ORGANIZATION>. Stockholders have accused <PERSON> Popejoy </PERSON> of failing to disclose the extent of the company's problems with bad loans and foreclosed real estate. Critics also have focused on a provision of the bailout that would allow <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> to engage in merchant banking, something beyond traditional S & amp; L business. At a <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Banking </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> hearing Thursday, bank board Chairman <PERSON> Danny </PERSON> <PERSON> Wall </PERSON>, seeking to allay fears <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> could venture onto risky ground, disclosed restrictions on the proposed merchant banking operation. The merchant bank would be limited to $ 1.5 billion in assets and would be barred from direct real estate investment or development. It would be barred from investing in gambling activities, foreign firms, precious metals, commodities, futures and options. And the bank board would have the right to step in to stop activities it deems too risky.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880912-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-12-88 0015EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-OlympicCity     09-12 0661</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Olympic City,0682</SECOND>
<HEAD>Olympic City Is Vibrant Mix Of Old And New Korea</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By BARRY RENFREW</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SEOUL, South Korea (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Frantic growth and modernization rub shoulders with ancient tradition in a constant blur of old and new in this vibrant city, site of the 1988 Olympics. <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION>, home to 10 million people, is the crown jewel in the economic miracle that turned <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> from one of the world's poorest nations into an economic powerhouse in just three decades The city also symbolizes how little some things have changed. Traditional ways of life exist alongside relentless expansion, and slums and poverty mix with prosperous suburbs and wealth. `` <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION> is a city of contrasts. One moment you are facing the forefront of the 20th century and then you turn around and see a scene out of the Middle Ages,'' said one foreign resident. Gleaming skyscrapers and hordes of business workers in suits and dresses blanket the commercial districts. But just a few blocks away are tiny, dirty workshops where laborers work at a frantic pace for subsistence wages. <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION> is ringed with row after row of apartment buildings that house the growing middle classes. The city is also dotted with slums where up to 10 people live in a single room without plumbing. Dazzling new department stores in the center of <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION> show off the latest fashions and electronic goods. Families dress up to shop and eat hamburgers or pizza at Western restaurants and American fast-food chains. Just a few blocks away is ancient <ORGANIZATION> Namdaemun </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Market </ORGANIZATION> where stall holders hawk their goods to throngs of people packed into the narrow streets. Roadside vendors offer rice, dog meat, squid and other foods that have been staples for centuries. But modern values and habits appear to be prevailing. Nearly everyone dresses in Western clothing and some mothers complain that their children prefer hamburgers to rice. Divorce rates are climbing and dating has become commonplace. Families save to buy cars and appliances for increasingly Western lifestyles. <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION>, devastated during the Korean War in the early 1950s and largely rebuilt, has few ancient or traditional Korean buildings. The pace in <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION> often is frantic. Workers routinely put in 10-hour shifts and work half days on Saturdays. Office workers stay at their desks to avoid being the first to leave at the end of the day. Children are inculcated with traditional Confucian values to revere their elders, obey orders and work hard. `` We want foreigners to see how much our country has attained. We are proud our country has done so well,'' said businessman <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Jong-ik </PERSON>. But older Koreans say the younger generation is not so mindful of the need to work and take weeklong vacations and other unheard of indulgences. `` These young Koreans are very different. They want everything and do n't listen to their elders,'' said a senior journalist who spoke on condition of anonymity. Many things have been neglected in <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION> to concentrate on expanding the economy as quickly as possible. Pollution has been allowed to go largely unchecked so business can flourish. The city has few parks or other recreational facilities. `` We need more time to become one of the developed countries. We are still developing,'' said businessman <PERSON> Lee </PERSON>. South Koreans hope the Olympics will cement its prosperity and modernization. They say there will be more time and money to fix problems that have been neglected. `` <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> can go worldwide through the Olympics,'' said <PERSON> Kim </PERSON> <PERSON> Chul-yong </PERSON>, a shopkeeper. The Olympics are portrayed as a national mission, and ordinary people talk seriously about their duty to help ensure the Games are a success. The Olympics have spread into almost every aspect of life. The symbol of the Olympic movement _ five interlocked circles _ is stamped on everything from milk cartons and television logos to each <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION> subway car. `` The No. 1 Games. The No. 1 people,'' proclaim the subway signs.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880912-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-12-88 0018EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Mexico-Salinas     09-12 0645</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Mexico-Salinas,0665</SECOND>
<HEAD>President-Elect Will Need All His Talent To Govern Mexico</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By CHRIS ANGELO</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MEXICO CITY (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President-elect <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Salinas </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Gortari </PERSON> is tough and highly disciplined despite his modest demeanor, qualities he will need to govern <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> for the next six years. <PERSON> Salinas </PERSON>, 40, faces protracted economic problems that affect <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>'s relationship with the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and a vocal opposition that still questions whether his mandate was won fairly. `` Given the circumstances, he is going to have to be a great president because otherwise the problems of the country will become enormously complicated,'' said <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Camacho </PERSON> <PERSON> Solis </PERSON>, a close colleague and general secretary of the governing <ORGANIZATION> Institutional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Revolutionary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>. An illustration of one lingering problem was the vote Saturday by the <ORGANIZATION> Chamber </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Deputies </ORGANIZATION> to certify <PERSON> Salinas </PERSON>' July 6 election as president. Virtually all votes came from the governing party, called the <ORGANIZATION> PRI </ORGANIZATION> for its Spanish initials. The opposition, which held the <ORGANIZATION> PRI </ORGANIZATION> to 50.7 percent of the official vote _ the lowest since <ORGANIZATION> PRI </ORGANIZATION> took power in 1929, maintains the presidency was won by fraud. <PERSON> Salinas </PERSON> was the chief architect of an economic austerity program that rescued this nation of 85 million people from near bankruptcy and has cut its record 159 percent inflation for 1987 by half this year. Still, his policies remain unpopular because workers have lost half their buying power. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> share a 2,000-mile border, and bilateral issues include <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>'s $ 104 billion debt, drug trafficking and immigration. If <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>'s economy gets worse, many Mexicans are likely to vote with their feet by moving north. <PERSON> Salinas </PERSON> also will have to deal with a party that is struggling to adapt to a more democratic environment. Many of his ideas for decentralizing the economy and reduce the role of the state are unpopular with politicians used to wielding unquestioned power. <PERSON> Salinas </PERSON>, like his three predecessors, rose in the bureaucracy and has no previous experience in elective office, although he grew up with politics. His father was a former commerce minister, his mother an economist active in party politics. Born in <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Salinas </PERSON> lived in the village of <LOCATION> Tetla </LOCATION> in central <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> while researching his doctoral thesis on the connection between government spending and political power. <PERSON> Salinas </PERSON> holds two master's degrees and one doctorate from <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, where his father also attended. He speaks fluent English. After graduation, <PERSON> Salinas </PERSON> advanced quickly in government, catching the eye of <ORGANIZATION> Miguel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> de </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> la </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Madrid </ORGANIZATION> and becoming budget secretary when <ORGANIZATION> de </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> la </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Madrid </ORGANIZATION> became president in 1982. `` He's very comprehensive, in the sense that he seems to have a computer in his head'' to manage many problems at once, said <PERSON> Otto </PERSON> <PERSON> Granados </PERSON>, information secretary of the <ORGANIZATION> PRI </ORGANIZATION>. Another associate said <PERSON> Salinas </PERSON> `` likes to be informed on everything'' and as president may have to learn to `` let go of things more.'' <PERSON> Salinas </PERSON> has had to fight the image that he is a technocrat without political experience. His public comments are unrevealing, he lacks charisma and is often depicted in local cartoons as a mouse because of his baldness, big ears and mustache. But associates say he is forceful and demanding, requiring work be done well and promptly. `` When he proposes something, he attains it,'' said one associate, noting that <PERSON> Salinas </PERSON> decided to learn tennis about three years ago and has since become a good amateur player. <PERSON> Salinas </PERSON>, who won a silver medal in an equestrian event at the <ORGANIZATION> Pan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Games </ORGANIZATION> in 1971, also runs three or four times a week. He married <PERSON> Cecilia </PERSON> <PERSON> Occelli </PERSON> after a seven-year engagement that began while they were students. `` He was very serious, but at the same time jovial,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Salinas </PERSON> said this year. <PERSON> Salinas </PERSON> does n't smoke, drinks only socially and spends any free time with his wife and their three children, associates said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880912-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-12-88 2359EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-ForestFiresRdp 2ndLd-Writethru a777 09-12 0833</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Forest Fires Rdp, 2nd Ld-Writethru, a777,0849</SECOND>
<HEAD>Firefighters Race Time with Warmer Weather on Way</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: SUBS 10th graf, `In Oregon,' with one graf to CORRECT that
residents were told to be ready to evacuate, UPDATE acreage. Subs
16th graf `We'd have' witho one graf to UPDATE acreage of Montana's
Red Bench fire.</NOTE>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto XYS3</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KURT J. REPANSHEK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>YELLOWSTONE NATIONAL PARK, Wyo. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Firefighters took advantage of chilly, damp weather Monday to strengthen lines around fires that have ravaged nearly 1 million acres inside the park, but hot, dry weather was predicted by midweek. `` It's a sleeping giant now,'' <PERSON> Denny </PERSON> <PERSON> Bungarz </PERSON>, a fire incident commander, said during a briefing Monday. `` We want to tie it down so when it wakes up it ca n't run on us.'' Fire activity was limited Monday after a weekend of showers and light snow _ the first significant precipitation since spring _ that gave firefighters a needed break from high wind and temperatures that let fires grow by thousands of acres per day last week. The fires inside the 2.2-million-acre park had burned 939,270 acres as of Monday. Temperatures remained in the 40s in the park Monday, keeping humidity levels at up to 50 percent, but the weather was expected to begin clearing Tuesday and temperatures were to reach 70 degrees by Wednesday, drying the area once again. The cool, wet weekend also helped firefighters in surrounding areas of <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION>, and in <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION>, where a 15,700-acre fire was declared under control Monday. `` We're more optimistic this morning than we have been for some weeks,'' said <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Baden </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> director at the <ORGANIZATION> Interagency </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fire </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Boise </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION>. `` With the moisture we have on the fires now it's cooled them down to where we can in and work them directly.'' The center, which coordinates forest fire suppression, calls this the worst forest fire season in 30 years. Forests and brush also burned in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, where a 400-acre fire that apparently began from an illegal campfire in an alpine area of Olympic National Park had crews from three states fighting it. And a fire in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>'s Gold Rush country in the <LOCATION> Sierra </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION> forced most of the 4,500 residents of <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Wildwood </LOCATION> to evacuate for a second time Monday. In <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION>, a fast-moving fire broke out in dry grass and timber in the <ORGANIZATION> Willamette </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> and sheriff's deputies warned residents about six miles southeast of <LOCATION> Oakridge </LOCATION> to be ready to evacuate. The fire quickly burned 1,000 acres in rolling hills 10 to 15 miles southeast of <LOCATION> Oakridge </LOCATION>, forest spokeswoman <PERSON> Lorette </PERSON> <PERSON> Laferriere </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Baden </PERSON> said there 28 fires still out of control in the West that had charred 1.8 million acres. The favorable weather allowed <ORGANIZATION> Yellowstone </ORGANIZATION> officials to open all roads through the park Monday except its northeastern entrance leading to <LOCATION> Cooke </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mont. </LOCATION>, the route inside the park from <LOCATION> Mammoth </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hot </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Springs </LOCATION> to Canyon and Tower, and <PERSON> Craig </PERSON> <PERSON> Pass </PERSON>. About 1,000 Marines from <LOCATION> Camp </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Pendleton </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, were to reach <ORGANIZATION> Yellowstone </ORGANIZATION> on Wednesday and Thursday to help firefighters, while some of the first soldiers sent to <ORGANIZATION> Yellowstone </ORGANIZATION> from <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lewis </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wash. </LOCATION>, were not to be released until at least Saturday. `` We'll have lots of people here, so maybe we can nail this thing,'' <PERSON> Bungarz </PERSON> said. Although moisture helped slow the advance of the flames, with little growth recorded during the weekend, it would probably dry out quickly, <PERSON> Bungarz </PERSON> said. He added, however, none of the fires would make major progress until the area is thoroughly dried. `` We'd have to have a heck of a lot of rain to put the fire out,'' said fire information officer <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Payne </PERSON> on the 31,500-acre Red Bench fire at Glacier National Park in <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION>. `` You're talking numbers of inches of rain. Despite the return of warmer weather, the arrival of autumn weather with lower temperatures and shorter days had officials optimistic the fires would no longer make major advances. `` We still expect fire activity, but it wo n't be as intense or as much or as fast as it has been in the past,'' said fire information officer <PERSON> Sonya </PERSON> <PERSON> Capek </PERSON>. `` The days are getting shorter, so the burning period is getting shorter.'' North of the park in <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION>, Gov. <PERSON> Ted </PERSON> <PERSON> Schwinden </PERSON> canceled his sweeping ban on all recreational activities in the state's fire-ravaged countryside because of the weekend weather About 1,000 firefighters got the day off Monday in <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION> because up to a foot of snow fell on the eastern half of the 247,000-acre <LOCATION> Cnyon </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Creek </LOCATION> fire north of <PERSON> Helena </PERSON>, said fire information officer <PERSON> Jane </PERSON> <PERSON> Weber </PERSON>. They were taken to a <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> facility to warm up and dry out their clothes. More than 100 residents evacuated from scattered homes, cabins and ranches along the fire's eastern front were returning to the region by Sunday and Monday, she added. Also in <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> Hellroaring </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Creek </LOCATION> fire that had charred 81,900 acres and moved into <ORGANIZATION> Yellowstone </ORGANIZATION> was contained Sunday, said information officer <PERSON> Chris </PERSON> <PERSON> Comstock </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880912-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-12-88 0019EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Obit-Smyslovsky     09-12 0409</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Obit-Smyslovsky,0423</SECOND>
<HEAD>Exiled Russian General Whose Troops Fought With Germans Is Dead</HEAD>
<DATELINE>VADUZ, Liechtenstein (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Boris </PERSON> <PERSON> Smyslovsky </PERSON>, an anti-communist former Russian general whose World War II unit fought with <PERSON> Hitler </PERSON>'s troops against the <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>, has died at age 91 Maj. Gen. <PERSON> Smyslovsky </PERSON>, who then called himself <PERSON> Arthur </PERSON> <PERSON> Holmston </PERSON>, led a 6,000-man contingent known as the <ORGANIZATION> First </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Russian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> of the German Wehrmacht. At the end of World War II, he and 500 remaining soldiers managed to reach neutral <LOCATION> Liechtenstein </LOCATION>, where staunchly anti-communist Prince <PERSON> Franz </PERSON> <PERSON> Josef </PERSON> <PERSON> II </PERSON> granted them political asylum. Death notices published in <LOCATION> Liechtenstein </LOCATION> newspapers said he died in the capital <LOCATION> Vaduz </LOCATION> last Monday and was buried Thursday. The mass-circulation Swiss newspaper <ORGANIZATION> Sonntagsblick </ORGANIZATION> reported his death Sunday. Once an officer in the Russian Imperial Guards, <PERSON> Smyslosvky </PERSON> went into Polish and German exile after fighting the <ORGANIZATION> Bolsheviks </ORGANIZATION> in the civil war. After <PERSON> Hitler </PERSON> invaded <LOCATION> Russia </LOCATION> in 1941, he became the first Russian to command a <LOCATION> Russian </LOCATION> unit fighting for the Germans on the eastern front. In a 1985 interview with The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>, he said his goal was to end communism in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> and get rid of <PERSON> Stalin </PERSON>. But he said he was not a Nazi. `` I thought that the Germans would be the only ones who could defeat the Soviets and that the Allies then would defeat the exhausted Germans,'' he said. `` What the Germans did was horrible. <PERSON> Hitler </PERSON> corrupted their souls,'' he said. `` But the Soviets destroyed a whole nation, <LOCATION> Russia </LOCATION>.'' <PERSON> Smyslovsky </PERSON> said volunteers from among Soviet prisoners of war formed the bulk of his army, with the rest made up of prewar exiles like himself. When the eastern front collapsed, the unit fled westward and was decimated by fighting. But <PERSON> Smyslovsky </PERSON> and his men, still heavily armed, marched through <LOCATION> Austria </LOCATION> and crossed into <LOCATION> Liechtenstein </LOCATION> on May 3, 1945. Among them was <PERSON> Grand </PERSON> <PERSON> Duke </PERSON> <PERSON> Vladimir </PERSON> <PERSON> Cyrillovich </PERSON>, heir to the <LOCATION> Russian </LOCATION> throne, whom the soldiers had picked up in <LOCATION> Austria </LOCATION>. The group encountered no resistance from <LOCATION> Swiss </LOCATION> border patrols guarding the tiny principality between <LOCATION> Austria </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Switzerland </LOCATION>, which dissolved its army in 1868. The Russians were disarmed and granted political asylum. A Soviet repatriation commission later interviewed <PERSON> Smyslovsky </PERSON>'s men, and almost half of them agreed to return `` We have never heard from them again,'' <PERSON> Smyslovsky </PERSON> told <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION>. Most of the rest went into exile in <LOCATION> Argentina </LOCATION>, including <PERSON> Smyslovsky </PERSON>. But in 1975, he returned to <LOCATION> Liechtenstein </LOCATION> with his wife <PERSON> Irene </PERSON>, who survives him.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880912-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-12-88 0006EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Philippines 2ndLd-Writethru a0402 09-12 0535</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Philippines, 2nd Ld-Writethru, a0402,0548</SECOND>
<HEAD>British Executive Slain, Supporters Celebrate Marcos' 71st
Birthday</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: LEADS with four grafs to CORRECT that firm is
Malaysian-Filipino, sted Swiss-American as reported initially by
police, and Tree's age; picks up 4th graf pvs: Communist rebels...</NOTE>
<DATELINE>DAVAO CITY, Philippines (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Six men firing submachine guns killed a British executive in an ambush about 12 miles southwest of this <LOCATION> Mindanao </LOCATION> island city, police said Sunday. Investigator <PERSON> Ernesto </PERSON> <PERSON> Fuertes </PERSON> said the victim, <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Tree </PERSON>, 56, was aboard a service vehicle that left a cocoa plantation when six gunmen opened fire about noon Saturday. Tree died instantly. His Filipino driver suffered only slight injuries, <PERSON> Fuertes </PERSON> said. Tree was vice president of the <ORGANIZATION> Philippine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cocoa </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Estate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, a Malaysian-Filipino firm. Police initially reported the firm was Swiss-American. Communist rebels near <LOCATION> Davao </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> have threatened attacks on American interests. But no such warning has been issued to British businessmen. Lt. Col. <PERSON> Franco </PERSON> <PERSON> Calida </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Davao </LOCATION> area police commander, said by telephone that the gunmen may have intended to kill the Filipino plantation manager for <ORGANIZATION> Philippine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cocoa </ORGANIZATION>. The Filipino manager had refused demands to pay `` revolutionary taxes'' to the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> and had been receiving death threats, <PERSON> Calida </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Calida </PERSON> added that the manager, <PERSON> Dioniso </PERSON> <PERSON> Capusan </PERSON>, was supposed to have driven down the same road at the time of the noon attack. <PERSON> Calida </PERSON> said he did not know if Tree had received similar threats. Supporters of <PERSON> Ferdinand </PERSON> <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> meanwhile celebrated the ousted president's 71st birthday Sunday with a rally in <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION> and a giant birthday cake in <LOCATION> Laoag </LOCATION>, a northern provincial capital about 250 miles to the north. About 5,000 <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> supporters cheered under a light rain as <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON>' niece, <PERSON> Cynthia </PERSON> <PERSON> Rocka </PERSON>, blew out the largest of 71 candles on the 30-feet-by-75-feet cake, baked by dozens of volunteers. `` I thank you for having made by brother's birthday as great as this,'' said <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON>' sister, <PERSON> Fortuna </PERSON> <PERSON> Barba </PERSON>, as she was presented the first piece. Organizers of the cake project hoped about 24,000 people would turn out for the celebration, but police estimated the crowd at about 5,000. In <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION>, about 3,000 <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> supporters marked their leader's birthday with fireworks and a rally in a downtown square, where speakers denounced President <PERSON> Corazon </PERSON> <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON>, who toppled <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> during a popular uprising in February 1986 <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> greeted his supporters in a telephone interview broadcast over <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION> radio station <ORGANIZATION> DZEC </ORGANIZATION> from <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION>, where he fled after the uprising. `` By the grace of the Almighty, we are still alive and it is my hope that I can go back there, I can come back to the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> told his followers. Mrs. <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON> has refused to allow <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> to return, citing national security. But the ousted president has asked the anti-corruption court to order his return to defend himself during a court hearing set for November. A decision by the court is pending. If the tribunal orders <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> home, the government is expected to appeal to the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON>' late mother, <PERSON> Josefa </PERSON> <PERSON> Edralin-Marcos </PERSON>, still lies in state. She died in <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION> last May 4 but remains unburied, and <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> supporters say the funeral will be delayed until Mrs. <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON> allows the former president to come home for the service.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880912-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-12-88 0048EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Candidates-Press 2Takes   09-12 0900</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Candidates-Press, 2 Takes,0925</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush, Dukakis Say They'd Be Accessible Presidents</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Vice President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and Gov. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> have issued matching promises of accessibility to the White House press, but neither was saying how often he would hold formal presidential news conferences. The rival presidential nominees made their statements on news and information policies in written responses to inquiries by the <ORGANIZATION> Freedom </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Information </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> Managing Editors Association. Their replies were made public as <ORGANIZATION> APME </ORGANIZATION> officers and committee chairmen met in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> on Monday. `` I hope words like ` accessible,' ` candid,' ` honest' and ` fair' will be adjectives used to describe my relationship with the media by historians,'' Republican <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said `` It certainly is what I will strive for during my tenure as president.'' The <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration has come under frequent criticism for limiting access to information. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> renewed that criticism. The Democratic nominee prefaced his comments on his plans with a charge that `` the Reagan-Bush administration has waged an assault on the Freedom of Information Act with every weapon in its arsenal.'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> said he has a proven record of accessibility to reporters, and would continue on that course as president. `` Throughout my public career I've believed in a free press and my record shows I've practiced that belief,'' he said. `` As president, I would hope to continue this pattern of accessibility to the White House press corps, giving them and me the opportunity to utilize our First Amendment freedoms. A questionnaire prepared for the FOI committee was given to both candidates. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> responded directly, answering each of the questions. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> replied by issuing a two-part position paper, with one section on the freedom of information law and a second on his press relations. Here is a partial transcript of their replies:
</TEXT>
<HEAD>GEORGE BUSH</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Q. As president, what sort of tone would you set regarding openness in government, access to government information and freedom of information? A. Within the limits of national security, government should be open to scrutiny by the media and the public. Ours is a democracy where goverment must be accountable to the people. The information-gathering process, from a news conference to the Freedom of Information Act, is vital and essential to our system of democracy. Q. What kind of relationship do you think you've had with the media during your public career? How would you seek to improve it, if at all? A. I think I have had a good relationship with the media. As president, I hope that I will be able to spend more time talking with smaller groups of reporters. I enjoy a good give and take, and that kind of format allows me to get to know reporters a little better and them to know me. Not only will this benefit reporters but, more importantly, such free exchange will ultimately benefit the general public as well. Q. Throughout history, presidents have had a variety of relationships with the media. Are there any styles you would emulate? Are there any you would avoid? When it comes time to write the history of your relations with the media, what will it say? A. With the media, the <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> or the public, it would be a mistake to attempt to be something or someone you're not. So, warts and all, what you see is what you'll get. I hope words like `` accessible,'' `` candid,'' `` honest'' and `` fair'' will be adjectives used to describe my relationship with the media by historians. It certainly is what I will strive for during my tenure as president. ... Q. How frequently would you meet with reporters? How would you conduct press conferences? How often would you hold press conferences? Would you make any changes in the way President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> has done his press conferences? A. There are a number of ways to communicate with both the media and the public. Press conferences are one important way and they would certainly be central to my effort to ensure accessibility in my administration. One-on-one and group interviews, satellite interviews with regional media, national televised addresses are other examples of methods that a president can and should use to provide the media with opportunities to discuss administration policies and programs. My goal would be to get the right `` mix'' of all of the options available to guarantee an open administration. Realistically, you ca n't put a number on any of the working parts of an open approach to accessibility, but you can make and keep a commitment to the goal itself. Q. More specifically, what message will you send to your executive agencies regarding Freedom of Information requests? A. My message will be simple: obey the law. ... Q. Here's a chance to offer some contructive criticism. What things would you most like to change about the news media? What should the nation's media do differently to better serve the public interest? A. Accuracy and fairness are the name of the game. The media goes to great lengths to be accurate. It needs to go to the same lengths to be fair. While it is often necessary to use unnamed sources in gathering information for a story, it puts the validity of a story at a disadvantage. I hope the news media would rely as little as possible on this approach to information gathering and reporting.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>MORE</NOTE>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880912-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-12-88 0048EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Candidates-Press-1stAdd     09-12 0648</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Candidates-Press - 1st Add,0659</SECOND>
<HEAD>NEW YORK: and reporting.</HEAD>
<TEXT>
