<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880918-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-18-88 2355EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Obit-Ho     09-18 0110</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Obit-Ho,0113</SECOND>
<HEAD>Former Acting President Ho Dies</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SEOUL, South Korea (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Ho </PERSON> <PERSON> Chong </PERSON>, who headed the <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korean </LOCATION> government as acting president in 1960, died at his home Sunday following a long illness, family members said. He was 92. The family said Monday that <PERSON> Ho </PERSON> will be buried on Tuesday at the National Cemetery on the southern bank of the <LOCATION> Han </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> which runs through this capital. He is survived by one son and one daughter. <PERSON> Ho </PERSON> was an independence fighter against Japanese colonial rule. He headed <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>'s caretaker government in 1960 following the ouster of the late President <PERSON> Syngman </PERSON> <PERSON> Rhee </PERSON> in a student-led uprising for democracy.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880918-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-18-88 0151EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Britain-Convoy     09-18 0376</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Britain-Convoy,0387</SECOND>
<HEAD>Claim military truck involved in road accident carried nuclear
weapons</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ILMINSTER, England (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A sports car crashed into a truck in a military convoy in western <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> Saturday and anti-nuclear activists claimed the convoy was transporting nuclear weapons. Police said the driver of the MG Midget car was killed but there were no other casualties. A spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> said there was no danger to the public but he would neither confirm nor deny claims a truck leading the convoy was carrying nuclear depth bombs. The accident occurred near <LOCATION> Ilminster </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Somerset </LOCATION> when the car struck a bus and then crashed head-on into the huge transporter truck, according to police. They said the truck was slightly damaged. Members of the Campaign for Nuclear Disarmament said they trailed the convoy, which they claimed included four warhead transporters, from the time it left the <LOCATION> Burghfield </LOCATION> nuclear assembly facility near Reading, 35 miles west of <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>, earlier Saturday. Press Association, <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s domestic news agency, said without attribution that the convoy was transporting four nuclear depth bombs to the <ORGANIZATION> Royal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>'s armament depot in <LOCATION> Plymouth </LOCATION> on the south coast. Depth bombs are designed for use aircraft to attack submarines. <PERSON> Colin </PERSON> <PERSON> Hines </PERSON>, a spokesman for the environmentalist group <ORGANIZATION> Greenpeace </ORGANIZATION>, said Saturday's accident and another convoy accident in January 1987 were `` a virtually inevitable consequence of the trundling around <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> of not only 128 Polaris missiles, but also the little-known 140 naval nuclear depth bombs and 50 naval nuclear free-fall bombs. `` It's time for this nuclear transport to stop and for <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s naval nuclear weapons to be put upon the disarmament agenda,'' he said A spokesman for the Avon and <LOCATION> Somerset </LOCATION> police said the area was not evacuated. `` We have special contingency plans for situations where an accident occurs involving a sensitive load. They were not put into operation in this case,'' he said. He was not indentified in keeping with British practice. The <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> spokesman, also speaking anonymously, called the collision `` a very minor incident.'' On Jan. 10, 1987, a 20-ton truck, part of a top-secret military convoy, skidded off an icy country road near <LOCATION> Salisbury </LOCATION> in western <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>. A large area was sealed off while the military spent 18 hours righting the vehicle.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880918-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-18-88 0000EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-StudentShot 1stLd-Writethru a0634 09-18 0468</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Student Shot, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0634,0476</SECOND>
<HEAD>Precede LITTLE ROCK</HEAD>
<HEAD>Suspect Arrested In Slaying of Art Student</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: UPDATES throughout with arrest.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By LARRY McSHANE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A paroled killer with a drug addiction was arrested Saturday night and charged with murdering a 24-year-old <LOCATION> Arkansas </LOCATION> artist a week after she arrived in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> to study, police said. The suspect, <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> DeChirico </PERSON>, 37, of <LOCATION> Brooklyn </LOCATION>, was grabbed by police on a <LOCATION> Brooklyn </LOCATION> street corner and charged in Wednesday's slaying of <PERSON> Judith </PERSON> <PERSON> Anne </PERSON> <PERSON> Wrappe </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Little </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rock </LOCATION>, said police spokesman Sgt <PERSON> Raymond </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Donnell </PERSON>. DeChirico is addicted to crack, the highly potent cocaine derivative, and was paroled in December 1986 after serving 13 -LCB- years for manslaughter, <PERSON> O'Donnell </PERSON> said. Miss <PERSON> Wrappe </PERSON> was shot in the chest when she would not give up her purse to a robber near the <LOCATION> Brooklyn </LOCATION> campus of the <ORGANIZATION> Pratt </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION>, where she had just begun studying for a graduate degree in fine arts. The arrest came hours after hundreds of friends and relatives gathered at a requiem Mass in her hometown and remembered Miss Wrappe for her spirit of independence and her vision as an artist. `` She wanted to stand on her own,'' said <PERSON> Bishop </PERSON> <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> McDonald </PERSON>. `` She wanted to prove her independence. That very spirit found her on the streets of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> on the way home after finishing her part-time job earlier this week. On that street, the artist, the hard worker, died, a victim of senseless crime.'' <PERSON> DeChirico </PERSON> was picked up by police just blocks from the slaying, at about 7:30 p.m., said <PERSON> O'Donnell </PERSON>. He was booked for murder, robbery and criminal possession of a deadly weapon, the spokesman said. The last charge involves the alleged murder weapon, which was not recovered, <PERSON> O'Donnell </PERSON> said. Police had no immediate details about the suspect's previous manslaughter conviction. <PERSON> DeChirico </PERSON> was identified by several witnesses in the area of the shooting, <PERSON> O'Donnell </PERSON> said. Miss <PERSON> Wrappe </PERSON> was fatally shot when she refused to surrender her purse to an attacker as she returned home from her first night at work. Witnesses said <PERSON> Miss </PERSON> <PERSON> Wrappe </PERSON>, who was shot in the chest, struggled with the robber and screamed as he took her purse about 1 a.m. one block from her dormitory. She was returning home after her first night at a part-time job as a waitress in <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION>. Police found Miss <PERSON> Wrappe </PERSON>'s purse a couple of blocks away, with a dollar and other objects inside. Miss Wrappe, of <LOCATION> Little </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rock </LOCATION>, was a 1987 graduate of <ORGANIZATION> Notre </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dame </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. <ORGANIZATION> McDonald </ORGANIZATION> said <PERSON> Miss </PERSON> <PERSON> Wrappe </PERSON>'s parents gave their six children space to `` grow and be themselves. <PERSON> Judith </PERSON> <PERSON> Anne </PERSON> marched to a different drummer. She set standards for herself. ... She was not afraid to be different. <PERSON> Judith </PERSON> <PERSON> Anne </PERSON> was an artist _ photography, water coloring, charcoal, painting.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880918-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-18-88 0152EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Marshall's-Racism     09-18 0241</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Marshall's-Racism,0247</SECOND>
<HEAD>Store Fined, Agrees To Anti-Racism Training</HEAD>
<DATELINE>OAKLAND, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Marshall </PERSON>'s, a department store company, has agreed to pay a $ 17,500 fine to settle a lawsuit filed by a customer over a racial incident at one of its stores, the company said. The company said it also has agreed to conduct an anti-racism training program for its employees. The company announced the settlement at a news conference in <LOCATION> Oakland </LOCATION> on Friday. <PERSON> Cynthia </PERSON> <PERSON> Sterling </PERSON>, 25, who is black, sued <PERSON> Marshall </PERSON>'s after she tried to exchange an $ 80 comforter at the <PERSON> Marshall </PERSON>'s store in <LOCATION> Newark </LOCATION>, about 15 miles south of <LOCATION> Oakland </LOCATION>. She was shown a memo written by a store supervisor instructing clerks not to allow blacks to return bed linens `` for any reason.'' The supervisor was later fired and the store issued an apology. Sterling and the store also agreed to a monetary settlement, but both sides agreed not to disclose details. The fine was a penalty assessed by the judge who approved the settlement of the civil lawsuit. In another agreement between <PERSON> Marshall </PERSON>'s and the state <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fair </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Employment </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Housing </ORGANIZATION>, the store agreed to develop anti-racism guidelines for employees and distribute them throughout the chain. <PERSON> Marshall </PERSON>'s also agreed to develop an internal system to allow customers to complain if they believe they have been discriminated against, and to notify the local branch of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Advancement </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Colored </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> progress </ORGANIZATION> with the agreement.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880918-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-18-88 0153EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Noriega     09-18 0379</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Noriega,0390</SECOND>
<HEAD>Noriega: U.S. Has Invited Me To Talk</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MIAMI (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration has sent two messages to <LOCATION> Panamanian </LOCATION> military leader <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> in recent days inviting him to resume bilateral talks that collapsed in May, the general said in an interview. <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> said he sees the alleged overtures by the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government as a `` positive step'' and added that his regime is ready to start `` serious, scientific and realistic'' negotiations immediately, The <ORGANIZATION> Miami </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Herald </ORGANIZATION> reported from <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> in its Sunday edition. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials confirmed there were meetings with `` members of the ruling coalition'' in the last few days, but added these were part of `` regular meetings with a cross-section of Panamanian political leaders.'' They denied these were proposals for new negotiations. <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> said he is ready to meet face-to-face with ousted president <PERSON> Eric </PERSON> <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON> `` without preconditions,'' if that helps solve <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s crisis. Previously, <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> said he would never sit down with <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON>, who unsuccessfully tried to fire him as commander of <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s Defense Forces early this year <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> had generally shunned the press since he was indicted Feb. 4 in <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> and in <LOCATION> Tampa </LOCATION> for drug smuggling and his country exploded into political crisis. The <ORGANIZATION> Herald </ORGANIZATION> interview Thursday was at the main office of the General <PERSON> Torrijos </PERSON> military base in <LOCATION> Rio </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hato </LOCATION>, about 68 miles northwest of <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. The <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government in May offered to lift two drug indictments against <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>, if he would step down. But subsequently, presidential candidates <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> both said they oppose any deal that would result in dismissal of the indictments. Referring to the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> dispatches, <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> said, `` We have received a message from the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> transmitted to us through -LRB- <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s -RRB- commerce minister <PERSON> Mario </PERSON> <PERSON> Rognoni </PERSON>, with suggestions or open doors to continue the talks that had been suspended.'' <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Maisto </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION>'s deputy chief of mission, delivered the message last Wednesday to <PERSON> Rognoni </PERSON>, <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> said. An embassy official said `` written talking points'' were delivered describing <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> positions on <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>, but said they were summaries of on-the-record <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> policy. The <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> has set out guidelines that no further negotiations with <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> are expected. The <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration has said it still recognizes <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON>, who is in hiding in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>, as the head of state.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880918-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-18-88 0017EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Haiti-Churches     09-18 0372</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Haiti-Churches,0384</SECOND>
<HEAD>Caribbean Religious Group Condemns Haiti's Rulers for Church
Massacre</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BRIDGETOWN, Barbados (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Caribbean </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Churches </ORGANIZATION> denounced the killing of 13 parishioners and the burning of two churches in <LOCATION> Haiti </LOCATION> and urged the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Caribbean </LOCATION> governments to condemn <LOCATION> Haiti </LOCATION>'s military rulers. But late Saturday, <LOCATION> Haiti </LOCATION> deposed its military leader, Lt. Gen. <PERSON> Henri </PERSON> <PERSON> Namphy </PERSON>, and two military commanders took power, a government spokesman said in <LOCATION> Port-au-Prince </LOCATION>, the Haitian capital. It was unclear whether the attacks on Sept. 11 and the following day, blamed on the government, were related to <PERSON> Namphy </PERSON>'s ouster. The church council, which represents <ORGANIZATION> Roman </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Protestant </ORGANIZATION> churches in 16 <LOCATION> Caribbean </LOCATION> countries, said the bloody attacks were `` cold-blooded cruelty which was shocking even by the brutal standards of Haitian repression.'' While army critic Rev. <PERSON> Jean </PERSON> <PERSON> Bertrand </PERSON> <PERSON> Aristide </PERSON> said Mass Sept. 11 at <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Jean </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bosco </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Haiti </LOCATION>, two dozen people armed with guns and knives attacked killed parishioners before burning down the building as soldiers watched from across the street. Nine were killed in the massacre and 77 were wounded, of which four died at in the hospital, <ORGANIZATION> Radio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Haiti </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inter </ORGANIZATION> said Saturday. Five men and a woman that night boasted on government television they took part in the massacre, and the next day arsonists burned down a second Roman Catholic church. `` The inaction of the government security forces can only be interpreted as collusion with the method of terrorizing the Haitian population into silence,'' said the council's statement, released Friday. Though the government of Lt. Gen. <PERSON> Henri </PERSON> <PERSON> Namphy </PERSON> said it `` regretted'' the massacre and promised to punish the culprits, similar statements issued after mass killings in the past have never resulted in investigations or convictions. <PERSON> Namphy </PERSON> returned to power after ousting the 4-month-old government of civilian President <PERSON> Leslie </PERSON> <PERSON> Manigat </PERSON> in a coup June 19. <PERSON> Namphy </PERSON> previously ruled for two years after the exile to <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> of President-for-Life <PERSON> Jean-Claude </PERSON> <PERSON> Duvalier </PERSON> on Feb. 7, 1986. But on Saturday, <PERSON> Namphy </PERSON> was ousted in a military coup and taken to the airport, said <PERSON> Frantz </PERSON> <PERSON> Lubin </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Haiti </LOCATION>'s director of information. <PERSON> Lubin </PERSON> said he believed Commander Prosper <PERSON> Avril </PERSON> had been named the new head of state and <ORGANIZATION> Dessalines </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Barracks </ORGANIZATION> Commander <PERSON> Jean-Claude </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> as new commander-in-chief of the army.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880918-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-18-88 0048EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-Gilbert-Tourists     09-18 0368</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Gilbert-Tourists,0383</SECOND>
<HEAD>Eastern Airlines Fetches U.S. Tourists Stranded In Mexico</HEAD>
<HEAD>With Hurricane Gilbert, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MICHAEL WARREN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MIAMI (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Almost 200 tourists expressed their relief and thanks over being home when they landed here Saturday night after enduring Hurricane <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Cancun </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>. Damage in the Mexican resort was extensive, said passengers upon arrival at <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> <LOCATION> International </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION> at 8:53 p.m. EDT. `` <LOCATION> Cancun </LOCATION> does n't exist anymore,'' said <PERSON> Ana </PERSON> <PERSON> Maria </PERSON> <PERSON> Cardoso </PERSON>, who weathered the hurricane in a hotel. `` We were lucky. Our hotel is a very old, well-built building. `` Unfortunately, those poverty stricken people are really suffering. They're going to have to start all over again.'' `` Everybody's glad to be home,'' said <PERSON> Angela </PERSON> <PERSON> Harvey </PERSON>, 23, of <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>. The first thing the tourists requested was fresh water, said an <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> crew member. Eastern does not normally fly to <LOCATION> Cancun </LOCATION>, but arranged for an L-1011 jet with room enough for 316 passengers to pick up the stranded tourists after the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> appealed for help, said the airlines' chief spokesman, <PERSON> Robin </PERSON> <PERSON> Matell </PERSON>. Hundreds of Americans were scattered in shelters in <LOCATION> Cancun </LOCATION>, passengers said, but only 196 made it to the airport in time to take the flight. Eastern delayed takeoff for almost two hours and sent members of the plane's ground crew into town in hopes of picking up more passengers, but many tourists never got the word, the passengers said. The airline encouraged <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> area hotels to let the tourists stay overnight free of charge, <PERSON> Matell </PERSON> said. `` We're trying to keep their costs to a minimum,'' he said. <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> accommodations would be a welcome change compared to the shelters they stayed in during the hurricane, said <PERSON> Medina </PERSON> <PERSON> Sutherland </PERSON>, 24, of <LOCATION> Chattanooga </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Tenn. </LOCATION> `` They put eight of us in a room with two beds, no power, no lights, no food and no plumbing for two days,'' she said. `` We had never met before. Now we're best friends.'' <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON> was a fierce storm when it rammed the <LOCATION> Yucatan </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Peninsula </LOCATION> Wednesday, killing 29 people and badly damaging the popular resort towns of <LOCATION> Cancun </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Cozumel </LOCATION>. But after making landfall again Friday in northern <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON> quickly lost power. It was downgraded to a tropical depression Saturday.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880918-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-18-88 0050EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-HurricaneGilbert-US 6thLd-Writethru a0689 09-18 0925</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Hurricane Gilbert-US, 6th Ld - Writethru, a0689,0949</SECOND>
<HEAD>Gilbert Down To Tropical Depression But Spawns Tornadoes And Heavy
Rains</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Inserts one graf after 4th graf `Texans inland...' to UPDATE
with tornado damaging 50 homes and destroying 15. Picks up 5th graf
pvs `Gilbert was...'</NOTE>
<HEAD>LaserPhotos SA1,2, HRY3,4, Map NY35</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOEL WILLIAMS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BROWNSVILLE, Texas (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Hurricane <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON> spun off dozens of tornadoes in <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> that killed at least two people as the nearly spent storm steamed inland Saturday, a `` huge rain-making machine'' with potential for deadly flooding. Thousands of <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Coast </LOCATION> residents from <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> began returning home to areas struck only a glancing blow by the main storm, at one time the most powerful on record in the <LOCATION> Western </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hemisphere </LOCATION>. `` What could have been one of the most deadly storms in history appears to have missed us,'' said <PERSON> Betty </PERSON> <PERSON> Turner </PERSON>, mayor of <LOCATION> Corpus </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Christi </LOCATION>. Texans inland braced for more twisters and flash flooding, with as much as 20 inches of rain expected. A tornado Saturday evening damaged 50 homes and destroyed 15 in <LOCATION> Del </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rio </LOCATION>, 150 miles west of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Antonio </LOCATION> and just northwest of the Mexican border, officials said. Two people were treated for minor injuries and released, but scores of others spent the night with relatives or stayed in shelters set up in the city, said police dispatcher <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Weaver </PERSON>. <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON> was downgraded early Saturday to a tropical storm. At midday, its top sustained winds were 35 mph and it was downgraded to a tropical depression. A woman was killed Saturday when a tornado hit her mobile home south of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Antonio </LOCATION>, some 300 miles north of <LOCATION> Brownsville </LOCATION>. A man died in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Antonio </LOCATION> when a tree toppled onto his house during a thunderstorm Friday. In <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION>, a man trying to cross a rain-swollen creek in <LOCATION> Tallapoosa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> southeast of <LOCATION> Birmingham </LOCATION> was swept to his death early Saturday, officials said. A tornado heavily damaged a <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Antonio </LOCATION> apartment complex just after sunrise. `` I just heard a loud, loud roar, like the wind blowing through the broken patio door in my living room,'' said <PERSON> Wes </PERSON> <PERSON> Spencer </PERSON>, whose apartment was hit. `` I just looked out, I freaked out. The roofs were gone on the buildings. Cars were tossed all over the parking lot.'' <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Antonio </LOCATION> Mayor <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> Cisneros </PERSON> also signed a disaster declaration for his city so <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> personnel could fly in parts needed to repair air conditioning at two hospitals hit by tornadoes earlier Saturday. At least 98 deaths and billions of dollars in damage were blamed on the storm in the <LOCATION> Caribbean </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>. An additional 200 people were feared drowned after a river swollen by rain from the hurricane jumped its banks and overturned four buses Saturday in <LOCATION> Monterrey </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>. The storm never made an expected turn to the north and spared the <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> coast, where thousands had fled to shelters after boarding up homes and businesses along the entire length of the state's 370-mile coastline. <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON> rolled ashore late Friday afternoon in northeastern <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> with 120 mph wind about 150 miles south of <LOCATION> Brownsville </LOCATION>, where gusts of 82 mph were recorded at <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Padre </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Laurie </PERSON> <PERSON> Swayze </PERSON> <PERSON> Miller </PERSON>, owner of a <LOCATION> Harlingen </LOCATION> jewelry store, picked up the pieces after a twister hit her shop. `` A policeman found a diamond ring out in the parking lot,'' she said. Wind gusted to nearly 40 mph at midday at <LOCATION> Brownsville </LOCATION>, but coastal residents were allowed to return to their boarded-up homes to begin cleaning up. Damage from the hurricane itself appeared to be minor. <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Padre </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Port </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Isabel </LOCATION>, which had expected to receive the brunt of the once-fierce storm when it roared ashore, reopened to the public at noon. Other coastal cities began closing emergency shelters. `` I was surprised because I was expecting a lot of water,'' <PERSON> Eduardo </PERSON> <PERSON> Campiran </PERSON>, <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Padre </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> city manager, said Saturday. `` We have no knowledge of significant damage. Most of the damage is like roofs, windows, awnings, this kinds of stuff.'' <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Padre </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> Mayor <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Pinkerton </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> estimated the storm would cost local businesses $ 3 million to $ 5 million in lost tourist revenue but said he expected business to be back to normal by next weekend. Only a few low-lying coastal roads remained closed because of flooding. The greatest damage appeared to be to trees, with many uprooted or missing branches. `` It just trimmed the trees a little and that's about it,'' <PERSON> Ron </PERSON> <PERSON> Reynolds </PERSON>, 31, said as he cleaned up around his home. `` My neighbor back there had a tree go through a fence. We came through it real lucky.'' At 11 a.m., the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hurricane </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> put the storm center 220 miles west-southwest of <LOCATION> Brownsville </LOCATION> and 45 miles southwest of <LOCATION> Monterrey </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, moving toward the west-northwest at 12 mph. Tornado and flash flood watches and warnings were posted for a 26-county area of southern <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>. Inland rainfall of 10-15 inches was likely with up to 20 inches possible, forecasters said. <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON>'s remnants should bring very heavy rain to the <LOCATION> Rio </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Grande </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION> before heading north up the <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION> as a `` huge rain-making machine,'' said <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Zimmer </PERSON>, meteorologist at the National Hurricane Center. In the 24 hours up to 7 a.m., <LOCATION> Brownsville </LOCATION> received 4.53 inches of rain. In <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Reserve </ORGANIZATION> reported 5.7 inches in 24 hours. By midweek, the storm should be in the lower <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION> and end up in the <LOCATION> Great </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lakes </LOCATION> as nothing more than foul weather, forecasters said. `` The people in the <LOCATION> Midwest </LOCATION> better dust off their umbrellas,'' <PERSON> Zimmer </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880918-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-18-88 0100EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Haiti-Profiles     09-18 0389</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Haiti-Profiles,0396</SECOND>
<HEAD>Profiles Of Figures In Coup</HEAD>
<HEAD>With AM-Haiti-Shooting</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are brief profiles of some of the figures in Saturday's coup that deposed Lt. Gen. <PERSON> Henri </PERSON> <PERSON> Namphy </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Haiti </LOCATION>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Namphy </PERSON> _ Took over after President <PERSON> Jean-Claude </PERSON> <PERSON> Duvalier </PERSON> fled to exile in <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> on Feb. 7, 1986. Returned to power after ousting the 4-month-old civilian government of President <PERSON> Leslie </PERSON> <PERSON> Manigat </PERSON> on June 19. <PERSON> Namphy </PERSON> previously ruled for two years following <PERSON> Duvalier </PERSON>'s flight to <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> <PERSON> Namphy </PERSON> said he removed <PERSON> Manigat </PERSON> and his government because the president illegally blocked the transfers of several officers.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 Brig. Gen. Prosper Avril _ Also adjutant general of the military, was believed named new head of state, according to <PERSON> Frantz </PERSON> <PERSON> Lubin </PERSON>, the government's director of information. Many observers believe <PERSON> Avril </PERSON>, who had been a military adviser to <PERSON> Duvalier </PERSON>, was a key figure in the coup in June. <PERSON> Avril </PERSON> was head of the presidential guard when <PERSON> Manigat </PERSON> tried in June to relegate him to an administrative post before the coup. <PERSON> Avril </PERSON> was an adviser to the military-led junta until anti-government demonstrations forced him to resign that post in early 1986.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 Col. <PERSON> Jean-Claude </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> _ Commander of <ORGANIZATION> Dessalines </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Barracks </ORGANIZATION> and considered second-most powerful figure in the military after <PERSON> Namphy </PERSON>, was believed named the new commander-in-chief of the army, according to <PERSON> Lubin </PERSON>. Behind <PERSON> Namphy </PERSON>, <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> was considered the most powerful figure in the military regime. In March, <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> was indicted by a federal grand jury in <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> for allegedly conspiring to import cocaine into the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> denied any involvement. The 700-man <ORGANIZATION> Dessalines </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Barracks </ORGANIZATION>, the 7,000-member military's largest unit, lies adjacent to the presidential palace. In June, <PERSON> Namphy </PERSON> reassigned <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> to an administrative position, but <PERSON> Paul </PERSON>, with backing from then-President <PERSON> Leslie </PERSON> <PERSON> Manigat </PERSON>, refused. <PERSON> Namphy </PERSON> then ousted <PERSON> Manigat </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Franck </PERSON> <PERSON> Romain </PERSON> _ Mayor of <LOCATION> Port-au-Prince </LOCATION>, the capital, until <PERSON> Duvalier </PERSON>'s ouster. Returned to that office in army-run elections in January and remained after <PERSON> Namphy </PERSON> ousted <PERSON> Manigat </PERSON>. In commenting on a massacre Sept. 11 in which 13 parishioners were killed at a church led by the Rev. <PERSON> Jean-Bertrand </PERSON> <PERSON> Aristide </PERSON>, an outspoken critic of the military government, <PERSON> Romain </PERSON> said <PERSON> Aristide </PERSON> was `` justly punished'' by the incident. A former colonel in ex-dictator <PERSON> Francois </PERSON> `` Papa Doc'' <PERSON> Duvalier </PERSON>'s presidential guard and former chief of police under <PERSON> Jean-Claude </PERSON> <PERSON> Duvalier </PERSON>, <PERSON> Romain </PERSON> denied city hall had been involved in the killings.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880918-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-18-88 0124EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Britain-Diplomat 1stLd-Writethru   09-18 0260</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Britain-Diplomat, 1st Ld - Writethru,a0677,0264</SECOND>
<HEAD>Tunisian Diplomat Expelled for Unpaid Parking Tickets</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: LEADS with two grafs to DELETE extraneous wording in lead,
Foreign Office confirming article; pickup 3rd graf pvs, `The
article ...</NOTE>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A Tunisian diplomat has been expelled for failing to pay hundreds of dollars in parking fines, the <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> said Saturday. The office confirmed a published report in Sunday's editions of The Mail, in which <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> Minister <PERSON> Timothy </PERSON> <PERSON> Eggar </PERSON> wrote that administrative attache <PERSON> Sadok </PERSON> <PERSON> Kassous </PERSON> was ordered to leave about three weeks ago as part of a crackdown on envoys who break the law. The article did not give an exact figure. The report of <PERSON> Kassous </PERSON>' departure follows the expulsion within the past week of three diplomats _ <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION>'s ambassador, a Cuban attache and a <LOCATION> Vietnamese </LOCATION> envoy _ in connection with firearms violations In 1984 diplomats in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> failed to pay about 100,000 parking tickets, he said. The newspaper, in a separate article on the expulsion, quoted Tunisian economic attache <PERSON> Hatem </PERSON> <PERSON> Bergaoui </PERSON> as saying <PERSON> Kassous </PERSON> refused to pay the tickets because his embassy was allocated three parking spaces for six diplomats. A Foreign Office official said he did not know when <PERSON> Kassous </PERSON> left the country. <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION>'s ambassador and commercial attache were expelled Tuesday after the attache opened fire in a <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> street and wounded a man. <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> said he fired at a <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> operative trying to get him to defect. Their expulsion came within days of a Vietnamese diplomat being ordered out for brandishing a gun at demonstrators outside his embassy.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880918-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-18-88 0211EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Anti-AbortionProtests 1stLd-Writethru a0658 09-18 0419</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Anti-Abortion Protests, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0658,0426</SECOND>
<HEAD>Anti-Abortion Protesters Arrested In New Jersey, California</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Leads with 1 graf to UPDATE with 450 arrested. Picks up 2nd
graf, `The arrests ...' Subs 4 grafs for 9th graf to UPDATE with
San Francisco arrest total at 200. Picks up 11th graf, ```We're
just ...' EDITS to trim and conform.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 About 450 anti-abortion activists were arrested during demonstrations Saturday outside clinics where abortions are performed in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, police said. The arrests were the latest resulting from Operation Rescue, a <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York-based </LOCATION> organization that has spawned anti-abortion protests around the nation in recent months. Police in <LOCATION> Shrewsbury </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.J. </LOCATION>, arrested about 250 chanting and singing protesters for blocking entrances to a Planned Parenthood clinic. `` We picked Planned Parenthood because they are the McDonald's franchise of the abortion industry,'' said <PERSON> Chris </PERSON> <PERSON> Slattery </PERSON>, a spokesman for Bi-state <ORGANIZATION> Operation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rescue </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Network </ORGANIZATION>, which organized the demonstration in <LOCATION> Shrewsbury </LOCATION>, about 45 miles southeast of <LOCATION> Newark </LOCATION> The Planned Parenthood in <LOCATION> Shrewsbury </LOCATION> is the only one of eight in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> that performs abortions as well as provide family planning counseling, said <PERSON> Phyllis </PERSON> <PERSON> Kinsler </PERSON>, executive director of Planned Parenthood of <LOCATION> Monmouth </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>. She said the 15 or so women who had appointments for abortions for Saturday were warned of the demonstration, but none rescheduled their appointments. `` Ironically, what has happened is that these people scared away walk-ins who may have wanted birth-control devices or information,'' she said. `` At the same time, the people who wanted the abortions were there. They showed up.'' The demonstrators were taken to the <LOCATION> Shrewsbury </LOCATION> Fire Department, where they were arraigned on charges of trespassing and violating a 1984 court injunction that prohibits protests at the clinic. In <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION>, about 200 people were arrested Saturday when they surrounded the Pregnancy Consultation Center, police said. Police Chief <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Jordan </PERSON> said the arrest procedure was very lengthy because demonstrators were `` lifted up and carried away, which is very time consuming.'' `` We were trying to be as diplomatic as possible,'' said Sgt. <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Senkir </PERSON>. `` But it's obvious these people want to be arrested.'' In <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION>, police estimated 250 anti-abortion protesters and 50 counterprotesters demonstrated at the center, which performs abortions twice a week. `` We're just trying to prevent abortions,'' said <PERSON> Liz </PERSON> <PERSON> Brouth </PERSON>, a spokeswoman for Operation Rescue, which claims 1,000 members in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Brouth </PERSON> said 250 members and supporters surrounded the facility starting at 7 a.m. However, police later cleared a path to the back entrance for employees.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880918-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-18-88 0147EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-YellowstoneFires 2ndLd-Writethru a0669 09-18 0648</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Yellowstone Fires, 2nd Ld-Writethru, a0669,0662</SECOND>
<HEAD>Yellowstone Firefighters Rejoice In Forecast Of Up To 6 Inches Of
Snow</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Subs 2 grafs for 15th graf pvs `Elsewhere, officials...' to
UPDATE with release of firefighters and weather in Montana. Picks
up 16th graf pvs, `High humidity ...' Subs last graf to UPDATE with
increased acreage of Oregon fires. No pickup.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By ELLEN HADDOW</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>YELLOWSTONE NATIONAL PARK, Wyo. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A forecast for up to 6 inches of snow gave firefighters prospects Saturday of reinforcing battle lines against fires that have burned for nearly three months. `` This forecast is music to our ears,'' said <PERSON> Ken </PERSON> <PERSON> Dittmer </PERSON>, one of <ORGANIZATION> Yellowstone </ORGANIZATION>'s area commanders. But high winds preceded the storm, with more than 40 mph gusts in some areas. Firefighters fought a fire that threatened <ORGANIZATION> Roosevelt </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lodge </ORGANIZATION> because of the winds. `` I hope this thing decides to take a nap soon,'' said Capt. <PERSON> Ron </PERSON> <PERSON> Goetzinger </PERSON>, who heads a team of firefighters from <LOCATION> Brainerd </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Minn. </LOCATION> `` The snow should take care of it. We sure hope so.'' The storm, forecast to swing into <ORGANIZATION> Yellowstone </ORGANIZATION> sometime Saturday night, was expected to leave much of its moisture on the northern sections of the country's first national park, <PERSON> Dittmer </PERSON> said. Fires burning in northern <LOCATION> Yellowstone </LOCATION>, including the 335,300-acre <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Fork </LOCATION> blaze, have been the most active in recent days and got the least moisture from a front that passed through the park a week ago, according to the commander. That previous rain represented about the first significant moisture in the park since spring. `` It could n't come to a better place,'' he said. The North Fork fire is the one that burned buildings in the tourist complex at Old Faithful geyser, and threatened <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Yellowstone </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mont. </LOCATION>, and park headquarters at <LOCATION> Mammoth </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hot </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Springs </LOCATION>. It and other fires have blackened almost half of the 2.2-million-acre park. Despite progress toward containment of the flames with fire lines, park officials declined even to venture when the blazes could be called controlled. Officials would say only that they predict the North Fork, half contained Saturday, may be fully contained sometime the middle of next month. The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Weather </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> said showers would change to snow during the night with accumulations of 4 to 6 inches possible by Sunday morning. Daytime temperatures were expected to remain in the 40s and 50s through Wednesday, falling below freezing at night. `` It's time to break out the sweaters,'' commented park spokeswoman <PERSON> Judy </PERSON> <PERSON> Jennings </PERSON>. She said the fires did not grow Friday despite gusty winds that whipped up flames after several days of calm. Other major fires in the park included the 411,500-acre Clover-Mist fire in northeastern <ORGANIZATION> Yellowstone </ORGANIZATION>, 75 percent contained Saturday, and the 225,500-acre Huck-Mink fire in southern <ORGANIZATION> Yellowstone </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Bridger-Teton </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION>, declared fully contained. Elsewhere, officials gave a day off to some firefighters in Glacier National Park, where a 35,000-acre fire has resisted efforts to douse it, and crews were released from another wildfire as steady rain and snow pelted much of western and central <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION> Saturday. The weather bureau issued a winter storm warning for today in western and central <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION>, predicting up to a half-foot of snow in the foothills and a foot of snow in the mountains. High humidity and temperatures in the 40s helped firefighters in <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION> to keep most fires within the boundaries of the <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Church-River </PERSON> of No Return, Gospel Hump and Selway-Bitterroot wilderness areas. Still active fires had charred nearly 200,000 acres. `` The only thing consistently in our favor is winter is coming,'' said <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Zabinski </PERSON>, spokeswoman for the <ORGANIZATION> Nez </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Perce </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> in central <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION>. In <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION>, a $ 5,000 reward has been offered for information leading to the conviction of the person responsible for starting a forest fire that had burned 8,200 acres of the <ORGANIZATION> Willamette </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> by Saturday. Investigators believe it was started by a careless hunter with a cigarette.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880918-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-18-88 0158EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-SynagogueArson 1stLd-Writethru a0674 09-18 0273</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Synagogue Arson, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0674,0275</SECOND>
<HEAD>12-Year-Old Boy Arrested for Arson at Synagogue</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Leads with 4 grafs to UPDATE with arrest of juvenile, search
for others, charges. Picks up 2nd graf pvs, `The fire ...'</NOTE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A 12-year-old boy was arrested Saturday night and charged with arson for a fire that nearly destroyed a synagogue where 15 swastikas also were spray-painted, police said. Other youths were still being sought, said a police spokesman, Sgt. <PERSON> Raymond </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Donnell </PERSON>. The youth, whose name was withheld because of his age, surrendered with a parent to detectives, <PERSON> O'Donnell </PERSON> said. He was charged as a juvenile delinquent with arson and burglary and would be released to his parents for an appearance in family court at a later date, <PERSON> O'Donnell </PERSON> said. The fire, reported early Saturday, started on the main floor of <ORGANIZATION> Orthodox </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Congregation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rabbinical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sharai </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Torah </ORGANIZATION> in the borough of <LOCATION> Brooklyn </LOCATION>, said Sgt. <PERSON> Maurice </PERSON> <PERSON> Howard </PERSON>, a police spokesman. He said the fire caused extensive interior structural damage. `` These people have violated not only the criminal law, they have violated every law of decency, and people of every religion have to be horrified that any temple of religion has been desecrated,'' said Mayor <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> I. </PERSON> <PERSON> Koch </PERSON>. <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> said a torah, a parchment scroll containing Scriptures, was set on fire, and 15 swastikas and some obscenities were spray-painted on the interior. Because the fire and desecration were declared a bias incident, a task force was formed to investigate the incident. The <ORGANIZATION> Jewish </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Community </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Relations </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> said it was offering a $ 5,000 reward for information leading to the arrest and indictment of the arsonists.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880918-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-18-88 0243EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a BC-Marcos     09-18 0249</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Marcos,0255</SECOND>
<HEAD>Marcos Says Possible Indictment Based on Hearsay</HEAD>
<DATELINE>HONOLULU (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Ferdinand </PERSON> <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> said Saturday that reported efforts by <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials to indict him for fraud `` are mere repetitions of charges pending in the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION>.'' The <ORGANIZATION> Los </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Angeles </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> reported Saturday that federal officials have overcome major legal obstacles in their case against the deposed <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION> leader and likely would ask a federal grand jury to indict him. `` I will not try to guess what the motivation is -LRB- behind the possible federal indictment -RRB-, but as I have said in the past several times and so have my lawyers _ we can prove the charges are false and we have evidence to do so,'' <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> responded through a spokesman. <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> said 35 cases are filed in a <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION> court involving billions of dollars allegedly misappropriated during and after his 20-year rule. `` And so, why is there an effort to file a similar case in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> which are mere repetitions -LRB- sic -RRB- of charges pending in the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION>?'' <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> asked. The indictment is expected to deal only with alleged of wrongdoing after <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> left the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION> during a civilian-military revolt that swept <PERSON> Corazon </PERSON> <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON> to power in February 1986, the newspaper reported. According to the report, the investigation focuses on allegations that <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> and his wife, <PERSON> Imelda </PERSON>, conspired with others to violate <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> injunctions by secretly transferring ownership of hundreds of millions of dollars in stolen art and <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION> real estate bought with <LOCATION> Philippine </LOCATION> government funds.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880918-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-18-88 0317EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p AM-HawaiiPrimary 2ndLd-Writethru a0656 09-18 0514</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Hawaii Primary, 2nd Ld - Writethru, a0656,0525</SECOND>
<HEAD>Democratic Congressional, Honolulu Mayoral Races Highlight Hawaii
Primary</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Leads with 11 grafs to UPDATE with early returns, pickup 11th
graf `The election...'</NOTE>
<DATELINE>HONOLULU (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Former <ORGANIZATION> Voice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION> director <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Bitterman </PERSON> led two other Democrats in early returns of the state's primary Saturday for the right to face Republican Rep. <PERSON> Patricia </PERSON> <PERSON> Saiki </PERSON>. Former City Councilwoman <PERSON> Marilyn </PERSON> <PERSON> Bornhorst </PERSON> led three other former Council members and a community activist in the race to oppose <LOCATION> Honolulu </LOCATION> Mayor <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Fasi </PERSON>. Voters also chose nominees for 100 federal, state and local offices. In the congressional race, <PERSON> Bitterman </PERSON> led in early returns by almost 17 percentage points over <LOCATION> Honolulu </LOCATION> City Councilman <PERSON> Leigh-Wai </PERSON> <PERSON> Doo </PERSON> and by almost 35 percentage points over former teacher union executive <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Radcliffe </PERSON>. <PERSON> Saiki </PERSON>, 58, was unopposed in the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> primary for the urban <LOCATION> Honolulu </LOCATION> district. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Sen. <PERSON> Spark </PERSON> <PERSON> Matsunaga </PERSON>, seeking his third term, was far ahead of a little known Democratic opponent, <LOCATION> Honolulu </LOCATION> writer <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Zimmerman </PERSON>, and was expected to coast to a November victory over the rancher <PERSON> Maria </PERSON> <PERSON> Hustace </PERSON>, the apparent Republican nominee. <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION>'s other <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> House member, six-term Democratic Rep. <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Akaka </PERSON>, was unopposed in the primary, and no one ran in the Republican primary. His only opponent in the general election will be a Libertarian, <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Mallan </PERSON>. <PERSON> Fasi </PERSON>, 68, was expected to easily defeat two relatively unknown Republicans in the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> primary. <PERSON> Bornhorst </PERSON> had a lead of 4 -LCB- percentage points over former Rep. <PERSON> Patsy </PERSON> <PERSON> Mink </PERSON>. <PERSON> Randall </PERSON> <PERSON> Iwase </PERSON>, <PERSON> Dennis </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Connor </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Souza </PERSON> were far behind. <PERSON> Bornhorst </PERSON>, <PERSON> Iwase </PERSON>, and <PERSON> O'Connor </PERSON> resigned their City Council seats, as required by law, to try to move into the <LOCATION> Honolulu </LOCATION> mayor's office Mink gave up her council seat two years ago to make an unsuccessful bid for governor. Activist <PERSON> Souza </PERSON> has campaigned for more affordable housing.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 The election campign was generally low key, with little controversy. In both major primary races, the Democrats stressed their professional backgrounds and government experience in their appeal to voters. The three Democrats who sought to unseat <PERSON> Saiki </PERSON> became known as `` The Three Amigos'' because of their general agreement on issues. They aimed most of their criticism at the first-term Republican, who gained some national exposure last month as the secretary of the Republican National Convention. <PERSON> Bornhorst </PERSON> is the front-runner among the five Democrats running for <LOCATION> Honolulu </LOCATION> mayor, according to a recent Advertiser-Channel 2 News poll. She is also leading <PERSON> Fasi </PERSON> in the poll for the general election, but <PERSON> Fasi </PERSON> was narrowing the gap and many voters were still undecided. <PERSON> Fasi </PERSON> served three terms as a <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> mayor but lost in the 1980 primary. He came back as a Republican and won again in 1984. <PERSON> Souza </PERSON> gained headlines during the mayoral primary campaign when he was excluded from a debate because, debate organizers said, he had less than 1 percent of the vote in a poll. <PERSON> Matsunaga </PERSON>, 71, was in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> for most of the primary campaign. <PERSON> Zimmerman </PERSON> gained some publicity for his low-budget campaign when he was arrested for handing out pamphlets at a farm fair held on city property.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880918-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-18-88 0450EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Haiti-Shooting 11thLd-Writethru a0718 09-18 0882</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Haiti-Shooting, 11th Ld - Writethru, a0718,0909</SECOND>
<HEAD>New Military Ruler Seizes Power in Haiti</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: LEADS throughout with new president saying he will respect
human rights and liberties, RESTORES first reference to Lubin;
EDITS to CONFORM and TRIM throughout</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By MICHAEL NORTON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> PORT-AU-PRINCE </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Haiti </LOCATION> -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> -RRB- _ Brig. Gen. <PERSON> Prosper </PERSON> <PERSON> Avril </PERSON> declared himself leader of <LOCATION> Haiti </LOCATION> Sunday after ousting Lt. Gen. <PERSON> Henri </PERSON> <PERSON> Namphy </PERSON> in a military coup. Residents reported hours of gunfire Saturday near the presidential palace. In an address on national television at 2:30 a.m. EDT, <PERSON> Avril </PERSON> said the presidential guard he commanded had toppled <PERSON> Namphy </PERSON> Saturday because it was `` sickened'' by the way <LOCATION> Haiti </LOCATION> had been governed. <PERSON> Avril </PERSON>, a former adviser to President <PERSON> Jean-Claude </PERSON> <PERSON> Duvalier </PERSON>, said <LOCATION> Haiti </LOCATION> will respect all international treaties, liberties and human rights and said that `` dialogue will be honored for the sake of national reconciliation.'' <PERSON> Namphy </PERSON> was arrested and escorted under guard to the international airport late Saturday, a government spokesman said. The <LOCATION> Dominican </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Republic </LOCATION> announced <PERSON> Namphy </PERSON> and <LOCATION> Port-au-Prince </LOCATION> Mayor <PERSON> Franck </PERSON> <PERSON> Romain </PERSON> had requested and been granted political asylum in its <LOCATION> Port-au-Prince </LOCATION> embassy. It said they were in the embassy and would be flown on a military plane to the capital of <ORGANIZATION> Santo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Domingo </ORGANIZATION> Sunday. The reports on <PERSON> Namphy </PERSON>'s whereabouts could not be independently confirmed early Sunday. The government reported <PERSON> Namphy </PERSON>'s ouster several hours after shooting broke out at the main plaza in front of the presidential palace. The gunshots sent dozens of people fleeing for cover in what appeared to be fighting between army factions, witnesses said. Earlier, <PERSON> Frantz </PERSON> <PERSON> Lubin </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Haiti </LOCATION>'s director of information, had told The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> soldiers were reportedly slain during the coup, but no casualties were mentioned by <PERSON> Avril </PERSON>. Rapid gunfire continued until about 11:45 p.m. Saturday. <PERSON> Avril </PERSON> has been a key figure in <LOCATION> Haiti </LOCATION>'s succession of governments since <PERSON> Duvalier </PERSON> fled to exile in <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> on Feb. 7, 1986. He served as an adviser to a military-civilian junta headed by <PERSON> Namphy </PERSON> which succeeded <PERSON> Duvalier </PERSON>. <PERSON> Avril </PERSON> was forced to resign that post in early 1986 by anti-government demonstrations. He then participated in the June 19 coup that toppled the 4-month-old civilian government of President <PERSON> Leslie </PERSON> <PERSON> Manigat </PERSON>, who had tried to transfer <PERSON> Avril </PERSON> from commander of the presidential guard to an administrative post. In his speech at the national palace, <PERSON> Avril </PERSON> promoted himself to lieutenant general and said he had been forced to act. Speaking from the national palace before the presidential guard, <PERSON> Avril </PERSON> said: `` The presidential guard, sickened by the way the country has been governed since the 7th of February, 1988 ... has been forced to act again.'' <PERSON> Manigat </PERSON> was named president Feb. 7, 1988. Earlier, <PERSON> Frantz </PERSON> <PERSON> Lubin </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Haiti </LOCATION>'s director of information, had told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> that Dessalines Barracks Commander <PERSON> Jean-Claude </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> had been named the new commander-in-chief of the army, but <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> was not mentioned during the address. Behind <PERSON> Namphy </PERSON>, <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> was considered the most powerful figure in the military regime. <PERSON> Avril </PERSON>, a bespectacled, slim man of medium height, was dressed in uniform during his address. He was introduced as `` the most honest officer in the armed forces'' by Sgt. <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Heubreux </PERSON>, who wore full battle gear. He reference to `` dialogue'' followed a similar proposal by opposition leader <PERSON> Marc </PERSON> <PERSON> Bazin </PERSON>. <PERSON> Bazin </PERSON>, a conservative leader of the <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Understanding </ORGANIZATION>, recently said the democratic opposition and military government should meet. <PERSON> Bazin </PERSON> was one of four leading candidates for president in the aborted Nov. 29 civilian-run national elections. A <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman, <PERSON> Susan </PERSON> <PERSON> Clyde </PERSON>, said early Sunday that the new government made initial contacts with <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials. `` The stated intentions of this new government ... were to correct the abuses of the <PERSON> Namphy </PERSON> era, and to try to re-launch a period of change and progress for <LOCATION> Haiti </LOCATION>,'' she said. `` And obviously we hope that the government will be able to carry out these intentions.'' A usually reliable source, speaking on condition of anonymity, said an army major told him that a group of officers detained <PERSON> Namphy </PERSON> after preventing him from entering the palace at 4:30 p.m. Sources said the fighting involved army factions and members of the <ORGANIZATION> Tonton </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Macoutes </ORGANIZATION>, dreaded agents that terrorized Haitians during the 29-year-old dictatorships of the <PERSON> Duvalier </PERSON> family. A French diplomat who spoke on condition of anonymity and <ORGANIZATION> Radio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Metropole </ORGANIZATION> said the shooting, including automatic gunfire, broke out around 5 p.m. Satuday on the Champ-de-Mars Plaza, in front of the Presidential Palace and near the army general headquarters and <ORGANIZATION> Dessalines </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Barracks </ORGANIZATION>. Several dozen panicked people were seen running away from the plaza. The coup came six days after about 20 thugs invaded the <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Jean </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bosco </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Roman </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> church during a Mass being said by the Rev. <PERSON> Jean </PERSON> <PERSON> Bertrand </PERSON> <PERSON> Aristide </PERSON>, a critic of the military government. The thugs, armed with guns, machetes and knifes, killed 13 people and wounded 77 and then set fire to the church as soldiers watched from across the street. That night, five men and a woman boasted on government television that they took part in the massacre and on Monday thugs burned down a second Catholic church. Some people in the St. <PERSON> Jean </PERSON> <PERSON> Bosco </PERSON> church during the attack said they recognized several City Hall employees among the assailants. <PERSON> Namphy </PERSON>'s government said it `` regretted'' the killings. It has made similar statements after earlier killings but no arrests were announced.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880918-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-18-88 0625EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i BC-Burma-Coup 2ndAdd a0721-a0722 09-18 0119</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Burma-Coup, 2nd Add, a0721-a0722,0117</SECOND>
<HEAD>URGENT</HEAD>
<HEAD>RANGOON: street protests.</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Saw <PERSON> Maung </PERSON> became <LOCATION> Burma </LOCATION>'s fourth leader since the July 23 resignation of Ne Win, who had ruled the country since he staged a military coup 26 years ago. <PERSON> Saw </PERSON> <PERSON> Maung </PERSON>, the 59-year-old armed forces commander, also became defense minister in July. <PERSON> Maung </PERSON> <PERSON> Maung </PERSON>, who took power Aug. 19, had offered to end <LOCATION> Burma </LOCATION>'s one-party rule hold general elections under a multiparty system as early as late October But increasingly restive demonstrators said <PERSON> Maung </PERSON> <PERSON> Maung </PERSON>'s authoritarian <ORGANIZATION> Burma </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Socialist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Program </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> party could not be trusted Protesters have demanded the formation of an interim government to conduct the polling _ something the authorities had given no indication they would concede.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>MORE</NOTE>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880918-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-18-88 0948EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i BC-Haiti     09-18 0826</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Haiti,0856</SECOND>
<HEAD>New Military Ruler Seizes Power in Haiti</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MICHAEL NORTON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> PORT-AU-PRINCE </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Haiti </LOCATION> -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> -RRB- _ Brig. Gen. <PERSON> Prosper </PERSON> <PERSON> Avril </PERSON> declared himself president of <LOCATION> Haiti </LOCATION> on Sunday after ousting the nation's leader, Lt. Gen. <PERSON> Henri </PERSON> <PERSON> Namphy </PERSON>, in a military coup In an address on national television early Sunday morning, <PERSON> Avril </PERSON> said the Presidential Guard he commands had toppled <PERSON> Namphy </PERSON> on Saturday because it was `` sickened'' by the way <LOCATION> Haiti </LOCATION> had been governed. Earlier Saturday, residents reported hearing heavy gunfire near the presidential palace in what appeared to be fighting between military factions. <PERSON> Namphy </PERSON> was head of the armed forces, while <PERSON> Avril </PERSON> commanded the <ORGANIZATION> Presidential </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION>, a 1,000-man force responsible for protecting the presidential palace. The coup came less than a week after Hurricane <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON>, one of the most powerful storms on record, lashed <LOCATION> Haiti </LOCATION> and killed about 30 people. <PERSON> Avril </PERSON>, a former adviser to President <PERSON> Jean-Claude </PERSON> <PERSON> Duvalier </PERSON>, said <LOCATION> Haiti </LOCATION> will respect all international treaties, liberties and human rights and said that `` dialogue will be honored for the sake of national reconciliation.'' <PERSON> Namphy </PERSON> was arrested and escorted under guard to the international airport late Saturday, a government spokesman said. The <LOCATION> Dominican </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Republic </LOCATION> said <PERSON> Namphy </PERSON> and <LOCATION> Port-au-Prince </LOCATION> Mayor <PERSON> Franck </PERSON> <PERSON> Romain </PERSON> were granted political asylum in its embassy in <LOCATION> Port-au-Prince </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Romain </PERSON> was a colonel in the Presidential Guard and chief of police under the <ORGANIZATION> Duvaliers </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Namphy </PERSON> arrived in <LOCATION> Santo </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Domingo </LOCATION> about 8:30 a.m. Sunday on a plane that landed at the private <LOCATION> Herrera </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION>, according to <PERSON> Fabio </PERSON> <PERSON> Herrera </PERSON>, deputy foreign minister in the <LOCATION> Dominican </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Republic </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Namphy </PERSON> was accompanied by his wife, <PERSON> Gabrielle </PERSON>, and his daughter, <PERSON> Melissa </PERSON>, <PERSON> Herrera </PERSON> said. The minister said he believed <PERSON> Romain </PERSON> was still at the embassy in <LOCATION> Port-au-Prince </LOCATION>. The Haitian government reported <PERSON> Namphy </PERSON>'s ouster several hours after shooting broke out at the main plaza in front of the presidential palace. The gunshots sent dozens of people fleeing for cover. <PERSON> Frantz </PERSON> <PERSON> Lubin </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Haiti </LOCATION>'s director of information, told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> soldiers were slain during the coup, but no casualties were mentioned by <PERSON> Avril </PERSON>. Sources who spoke on condition of anonymity said the fighting involved army factions and members of the <ORGANIZATION> Tonton </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Macoutes </ORGANIZATION>, the dreaded agents that terrorized Haitians during the 29-year-old dictatorships of the <PERSON> Duvalier </PERSON> family. A French diplomat who also spoke on condition of anonymity and <ORGANIZATION> Radio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Metropole </ORGANIZATION> said the shooting, including automatic gunfire, broke out around 5 p.m. Saturday on the Champ-de-Mars Plaza, in front of the Presidential Palace and near the army general headquarters and <ORGANIZATION> Dessalines </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Barracks </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Avril </PERSON> has been a key figure in <LOCATION> Haiti </LOCATION>'s succession of governments since <PERSON> Duvalier </PERSON> fled to exile in <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> on Feb. 7, 1986. He served as an adviser to a military-civilian junta headed by <PERSON> Namphy </PERSON> which succeeded <PERSON> Duvalier </PERSON>. <PERSON> Avril </PERSON> was forced to resign that post in early 1986 by anti-government demonstrations. He participated in the June 17 coup led by <PERSON> Namphy </PERSON> that toppled the four - month civilian government of President <PERSON> Leslie </PERSON> <PERSON> Manigat </PERSON>, who tried to transfer <PERSON> Avril </PERSON> from commander of the Presidential Guard to an administrative post In his speech to members of the Presidential Guard at the national palace, <PERSON> Avril </PERSON> declared himself president and promoted himself to lieutenant general. `` The Presidential Guard, sickened by the way the country has been governed since the seventh of February, 1988 ... has been forced to act again,'' he said. <PERSON> Lubin </PERSON> said <PERSON> Dessalines </PERSON> Barracks Commander <PERSON> Jean-Claude </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> was named the new commander-in-chief of the army, but <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> was not mentioned during <PERSON> Avril </PERSON>'s address. After <PERSON> Namphy </PERSON>, <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> was considered the most powerful figure in the military regime. It was not clear what role, if any, <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> played in the coup. <PERSON> Avril </PERSON>, a bespectacled, slim man of medium height, was dressed in uniform during his address. He was introduced as `` the most honest officer in the armed forces'' by Sgt. <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Heubreux </PERSON>, who wore full battle gear. A <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman, <PERSON> Susan </PERSON> <PERSON> Clyde </PERSON>, said early Sunday that the new government made initial contacts with <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials. `` The stated intentions of this new government ... were to correct the abuses of the <PERSON> Namphy </PERSON> era, and to try to relaunch a period of change and progress for <LOCATION> Haiti </LOCATION>,'' she said. `` And obviously we hope that the government will be able to carry out these intentions.'' The coup came six days after about 20 thugs invaded the <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Jean </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bosco </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Roman </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> church during a Mass being said by the Rev. <PERSON> Jean </PERSON> <PERSON> Bertrand </PERSON> <PERSON> Aristide </PERSON>, a critic of the military government. The thugs, armed with guns, machetes and knifes, killed 13 people and wounded 77 and then set fire to the church as soldiers watched from across the street. That night, five men and a woman boasted on government television they took part in the massacre. On Monday thugs burned down another Catholic church. Some people in the St. <PERSON> Jean </PERSON> <PERSON> Bosco </PERSON> church during the attack said they recognized several City Hall employees among the assailants. <PERSON> Namphy </PERSON>'s government said it `` regretted'' the killings. It has made similar statements after earlier killings but no arrests were announced.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880918-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-18-88 1016EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i BC-Burma-Coup 3rdLd-Writethru a0726 09-18 0733</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Burma-Coup, 3rd Ld-Writethru, a0726,0753</SECOND>
<HEAD>URGENT</HEAD>
<HEAD>Burma's Military Seizes Power, Protesters Take To Streets</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: New thruout to UPDATE with demonstrators pouring into streets
of Rangoon, new leader names others in regime, declares curfew.
TRIMS. No pickup.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By SEIN WIN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>RANGOON, Burma (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Military commander <PERSON> Saw </PERSON> <PERSON> Maung </PERSON> overthrew civilian President <PERSON> Maung </PERSON> <PERSON> Maung </PERSON> in a coup Sunday, saying it was necessary to halt deteriorating conditions in <LOCATION> Burma </LOCATION>, the state-run Radio <LOCATION> Rangoon </LOCATION> announced. Saw <PERSON> Maung </PERSON>, 59, widely regarded as a hard-line officer and a right-hand man of former President <PERSON> Sein </PERSON> <PERSON> Lwin </PERSON>, promised to hold multiparty elections once law and order is restored in <LOCATION> Burma </LOCATION>, the radio broadcast said. <PERSON> Sein </PERSON> <PERSON> Lwin </PERSON> resigned Aug. 12 after bloody clashes between troops and unarmed protesters. Shortly after the broadcast Sunday, thousands of people surged into the streets of <LOCATION> Rangoon </LOCATION> in a spontaneous rejection of the new regime and shouted for others to come out of their homes with weapons. The protesters felled trees and threw them across the roads to obstruct military traffic. But no military movements were spotted by nightfall. The coup came a day after soldiers shot at protesters marching on government buildings in <LOCATION> Rangoon </LOCATION> to demand the end of 26 years of repressive rule by the <ORGANIZATION> Burma </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Socialist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Program </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, the sole legal party. The protests have been led by students and monks and included striking civil servants. <PERSON> Saw </PERSON> <PERSON> Maung </PERSON>, the defense minister and <LOCATION> Burma </LOCATION>'s fourth leader in two months, identified himself as chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Peace </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Restoration </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>. A later broadcast named the other 18 military officers in the committee, including the vice chiefs of the army, navy and air force. It said authorities imposed an immediate 10 p.m. to 4 a.m. curfew and banned public gatherings but did not specify if that was nationwide or only in <LOCATION> Rangoon </LOCATION>. All government and state bodies were dissolved, including local administrations nationwide, it said. All striking government workers were told to return to work by Sept. 26 or face dismissal. Nationwide protests since July have forced the resignation of two leaders and more recent strikes, demonstrations, looting and lawlessness have paralyzed the economy and pushed the nation on the verge of anarchy. The statements Sunday said the military had taken over state authority `` to curb further deterioration of the general situation in the country.'' It said military authorities would `` restore law and order, peace and tranquility in the country ... and ease the daily livelihood of the people.'' `` After accomplishing the above objectives, -LRB- the regime will -RRB- hold general elections under a multiparty system. Political parties which accept and practice true democracy can prepare for the general elections from now on.'' The broadcast said the election supervision commission formed earlier by <PERSON> Maung </PERSON> <PERSON> Maung </PERSON>'s government would be retained. <PERSON> Maung </PERSON> <PERSON> Maung </PERSON>, a Western-educated lawyer, on Aug. 19 became the nation's first civilian leader since the 1962 military coup that installed the <ORGANIZATION> Burma </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Socialist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Program </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Maung </PERSON> <PERSON> Maung </PERSON> offered general elections under a multiparty system, but demonstrators demanded an interim government to conduct the polling. There had been several signs of military resistance to the government's response to its opposition. Security forces have sided with protesters in several towns, including <LOCATION> Victoria </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Point </LOCATION> in the southernmost <LOCATION> Mergui </LOCATION> province bordering <LOCATION> Thailand </LOCATION>. On Sept. 9, about 500 servicemen mutinied and joined protest marches in <LOCATION> Rangoon </LOCATION> in the first major military defections in the capital. On Saturday, <ORGANIZATION> Buddhist </ORGANIZATION> monks and armed students took over a government building after a soldier opened fire on two protesters. The 24 soldiers inside surrendered, and the monks and students disguised them as protesters and got them past a heavily armed, 100,000-strong mob threatening to behead them. Up to 500,000 demonstrators, including striking government workers and policemen, took part n marches Saturday in <LOCATION> Rangoon </LOCATION>. State-run <ORGANIZATION> Radio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rangoon </ORGANIZATION> said Saturday the government had ordered soldiers to support the state and national unity. Security forces killed scores of people in quelling student-led protests in March and June. That set the stage for the July 23 resignation of Ne Win, who had ruled since he staged the 1962 military coup. More protests flared after <PERSON> Sein </PERSON> <PERSON> Lwin </PERSON>, a former general, succeeded him. By government count, at least 112 people were killed in <LOCATION> Rangoon </LOCATION> during the riots against <PERSON> Sein </PERSON> <PERSON> Lwin </PERSON>, who resigned Aug. 12 after 17 days in power. Protesters blame the rigid socialism of the ruling party for turning resource-rich <LOCATION> Burma </LOCATION> into one of the poorest countries in <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880918-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-18-88 1116EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-Fire-Rebirth Bjt   09-18 0682</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Fire-Rebirth, Bjt,0699</SECOND>
<HEAD>One Year After Deadwood Blaze, Nature `Does Its Thing'</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARK WARBIS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CASCADE, Idaho (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 While many lament the fires that have charred much of <ORGANIZATION> Yellowstone </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Park </ORGANIZATION>, a wilderness that went up in smoke just one year ago already displays lush and diverse greenery that attracts herds of elk. `` The fire created more wildlife habitat than anything we could have ever done,'' <PERSON> Forest </PERSON> <PERSON> Ranger </PERSON> <PERSON> Morris </PERSON> <PERSON> Huffman </PERSON> said of the Deadwood Summit fire in the <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Church-River </PERSON> of No Return Wilderness in the <ORGANIZATION> Boise </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION>. The fire 250 miles west of <LOCATION> Yellowstone </LOCATION> burned more than 50,000 acres during the summer of 1987. `` It's a natural mosaic now, with open meadows and stands of timber,'' said forest spokesman <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Carroll </PERSON>. `` A forest that was just getting older and deader has now been beautifully revived.'' Federal land managers, rocked by criticism of their hands-off approach to dealing with naturally sparked wildfires in wilderness areas and parks, point to Deadwood Summit as an example of a good burn. It's a tough sell. Fires this summer have charred more than 1.5 million acres in and around <LOCATION> Yellowstone </LOCATION>. An early decision to let the flames go unchecked within prescribed boundaries ignited a firestorm of controversy, and <ORGANIZATION> Interior </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Hodel </PERSON> has said a change is likely. <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Cecil </PERSON> <PERSON> Andrus </PERSON>, a former <ORGANIZATION> Interior </ORGANIZATION> secretary, and others have called the `` let burn'' policy a prescription for disaster, especially during the region's worst drought in decades. But while the tourist-dependent communities surrounding <ORGANIZATION> Yellowstone </ORGANIZATION> look with apprehension at changes nature will take generations to erase, others say Deadwood Summit is, and <ORGANIZATION> Yellowstone </ORGANIZATION> will be, an ecologically healthier place as a result of being burned. `` When fire goes through an area and turns those trees into ash, one of the things that happens is that the minerals the tree has captured during its life are returned to the soil,'' said <PERSON> Tracey </PERSON> <PERSON> Trent </PERSON>, chief of program coordination for the <ORGANIZATION> Idaho </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fish </ORGANIZATION> and Game. `` That really increases the productivity of the soil for a number of years after the fire.'' Or as <PERSON> Huffman </PERSON> puts it: `` It does n't take long before nature starts doing its thing.'' The Deadwood Summit fire was started by lightning on Aug. 1, 1987, about 25 air miles east of <LOCATION> Cascade </LOCATION> and three miles east of the <ORGANIZATION> Frank </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> wilderness boundary. The blaze was doused by rain and snow three months later, after burning about 40,000 acres inside the wilderness and 11,500 acres elsewhere inside a 75-mile perimeter. `` The Deadwood fire in some senses is an example of how the natural fire policy can be very successful,'' <PERSON> Carroll </PERSON> said. `` Even though it burned longer than we predicted and got much bigger than we predicted, it actually was an outstanding fire from a forest-management standpoint.'' Today, the burned acreage is virtually covered with grass and other forage. Brush is starting to return and the area provided summer range this year to as many or more elk than before the blaze, officials said. <PERSON> Stacy </PERSON> <PERSON> Gebhards </PERSON>, regional supervisor for the state <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fish </ORGANIZATION> and Game, said he has received reports of 150 elk or more on some meadows. That's good news for hunters, and an archery season for elk is going on as usual this month, with general elk hunting opening in the area later this fall. Before, there were uniform stands of lodgepole pine like tree farms, some of it infested with pine bark beetles like those that left thousands of acres of <ORGANIZATION> Yellowstone </ORGANIZATION> timber dead and dry. Beneath the canopy the ground was relatively barren, the smaller, more succulent plant life crowded out by the trees. Now there is the kind of diversity sought in a wilderness by land managers who try to let nature manage itself. Plants like service berry and buck brush have adapted to fire over the centuries, and some lodgepole pine cones wo n't release their seeds until they're burned. `` There's probably some pretty good arguments that maybe this year we should have done something different,'' <PERSON> Carroll </PERSON> said. `` But the bottom line is, nature heals itself.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880918-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-18-88 1119EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Brites     09-18 0473</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Brites,0490</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bright &amp; Brief</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ONEONTA, Ala. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The `` Rambo of Moon Pie eaters'' is in serious training to try to become the first man to repeat as the world champion wolfer of the sweet, gooey, Southern treats. `` I've been practicing,'' said <PERSON> Rodney </PERSON> <PERSON> Frazer </PERSON>, a stockman at an <LOCATION> Oneonta </LOCATION> discount store. `` I've been eating a Moon Pie every time I go on break.'' His boss, <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Love </PERSON>, describes him as `` 270 pounds of rompin, stompin, genuine, 100 percent <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION> Moon Pie-eating country boy who loves Moon Pies like a hawg loves slop.'' First place in the Oct. 8 contest brings $ 100, second place $ 25 and third $ 15. Last year, there were 51 contestants when <PERSON> Frazer </PERSON> won the title by eating 15 within the 10-minute limit. `` He is the Rambo of Moon Pie eaters,'' Love said. Moon Pies, made in <LOCATION> Chattanooga </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Tenn. </LOCATION>, are made of a thick slab of marshmallow cream surrounded by thick coats of banana, vanilla or chocolate. `` I like the banana ones best,'' <PERSON> Frazer </PERSON> said. `` You could mix'em up in the contest but I do n't know how good they'd taste.'' A year ago he fasted a couple of days to get ready, and consumed a bunch of Rolaids after the Saturday eating bout. `` I was feeling all right by Tuesday,'' he said. `` They make you feel like you've got little bricks in you. Although a rescue squad was on hand last year, and will be again this time, `` nobody choked,'' Love said. `` A few got sick and a few did n't wait until they got away from the table. It got pretty messy right there at the end.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WORTHINGTON, Minn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Hot, humid weather was perfect for <LOCATION> Ruby </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Begonia </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> turkey </LOCATION> from <LOCATION> Cuero </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, outran <PERSON> Worthington </PERSON>'s Paycheck to win the first leg of the 16th annual Great Gobbler Gallop `` We brought with us the hot <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> weather, the kind of weather our bird likes,'' <LOCATION> Cuero </LOCATION>'s coach, C.L. <PERSON> Duckett </PERSON>, said after the southern bird won Saturday at <LOCATION> Worthington </LOCATION>'s King <LOCATION> Turkey </LOCATION> Days. The gallop was started in 1973 to decide which city would claim the title `` <LOCATION> Turkey </LOCATION> Capital of the World.'' The first leg is held in <LOCATION> Worthington </LOCATION>, the second leg in <LOCATION> Cuero </LOCATION>, Oct. 8. Whichever turkey has the best combined times is named overall winner. Paycheck has won the last three years and <PERSON> Worthington </PERSON> has a record of 10-5. Neither bird appeared to like the course. At the start of the block-and-a-half race, both birds headed for the crowds, and Paycheck initially wanted to go the wrong way. Paycheck also picked up two penalty points, based on how many times the turkey has to be touched to keep it moving on course. `` We might have to replace our bird,'' said Paycheck coach <PERSON> Jon </PERSON> <PERSON> Benson </PERSON>. `` This bird was just too friendly and always wanted to visit the crowd.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880918-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-18-88 1120EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-BoudoirPhotos     09-18 0470</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Boudoir Photos,0490</SECOND>
<HEAD>Boudoir Photo: An Intimate Gift For the Man Who Has Everything</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CHICAGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Some women are finding that a boudoir photo makes the perfect gift for the boyfriend or husband who has everything. At <ORGANIZATION> Design </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Studio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chicago </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> <PERSON> Binder </PERSON>, a 39-year-old insurance executive, posed for a photographer while sprawled on a black leather sofa with an emptied bottle of <PERSON> Dom </PERSON> <PERSON> Perignon </PERSON> champagne and a black mink coat on the floor. She was clad in high heels, sheer nylon stockings, garter belt and a black silk teddy with the straps hanging off her shoulders. `` I was engaged to a man who literally had everything, so for his birthday I got him this,'' she said of the photos. `` It's completely opposite of my corporate image Doing it was a fantasy for me, something very personal. `` I would recommend that any woman do it. Men, too.'' In the <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> area, more than 30 studios offer boudoir photography _ soft, sexy portraits to be given to boyfriends or husbands. A 1986 industry survey indicated that boudoir photography was the fastest growing segment of the business. `` It's stylized photography, a very intimate portrait of a woman,'' said photographer <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Byrnes </PERSON>, who took the shots of Ms. <PERSON> Binder </PERSON>. It also is definitely not a cheap gift. <PERSON> Byrnes </PERSON>, who has done this sort of work for four years, charges $ 250 or more for a session. Other <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> photographers quote prices ranging from $ 150 to $ 500. But the photographers can give customers their money's worth. Mattresses or a strategically draped sheet can be used to hide fat. After the shots are taken, retouching can eliminate stretch marks, facial puffiness and dark circles under the eyes. `` We know how to make a woman look good,'' <PERSON> Byrnes </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Schnur </PERSON>, a photographer at <ORGANIZATION> Furia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Studios </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>, said customers sometimes ask him to duplicate a pin-up picture or even a shot from the Sports Illustrated swimsuit calendar. `` Others just say, ` Make me look sexy, make me look 10 years younger,''' <PERSON> Schnur </PERSON> said. Men have also started posing for their ladies and there is a trend toward portraits of couples. <PERSON> Paula </PERSON> <PERSON> Ray </PERSON>, 32, a <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> actress and model, said she had her picture taken embracing her boyfriend in softly erotic poses. `` Posing with my boyfriend made it more personal than posing alone,'' she said. `` The pictures captured the way we are when we're together.'' But sometimes a boudoir photo is not the perfect gift. <PERSON> Sherri </PERSON> <PERSON> Northrup </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> writer-publicist, said she paid $ 800 for a series of color shots two years ago as a St. Valentine's Day present for her husband. Ms. <PERSON> Northrup </PERSON>, now divorced, said her husband hardly reacted. `` He just kind of blew the whole thing off, like it was no big deal,'' she said. `` I should have got divorced right then and there.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880918-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-18-88 1122EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-BRF--HusbandBeheaded     09-18 0085</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Husband Beheaded,0086</SECOND>
<HEAD>Wife Kills Husband For Refusing Her Food, Giving It To Dog</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NAIROBI, Kenya (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A woman decapitated her husband with an axe in a village north of <LOCATION> Nairobi </LOCATION> after he refused to eat the meal she had prepared and fed it his dog, the Sunday Nation newspaper reported. The independent newspaper said the man was killed Wednesday in <LOCATION> Kinyaga </LOCATION>, 100 miles north of <LOCATION> Kenya </LOCATION>'s capital. Police confirmed the incident but refused to identify the 35-year-old woman or her 38-year-old husband.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880918-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-18-88 1122EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-BRF--Japan-Emperor     09-18 0134</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Japan-Emperor,0139</SECOND>
<HEAD>Emperor Suffering From Fever, Cancels Visit</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Emperor <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON> suffered from a mild fever Sunday that forced him to cancel his visit to the <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION> sumo arena for the fall wrestling meet, the <ORGANIZATION> Imperial </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Household </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> reported. The 87-year-old emperor had a fever of 100 degrees Fahrenheit on Sunday morning, and doctors advised him not to attend the matches, the agency said. It said the emperor's fever dropped to 99 degrees later in the morning. The emperor `` feels well and has a good appetite. He is all right,'' said an official of the agency, who spoke on condition of anonymity. Doctors said the fever might have been caused by a slight inflammation of the intestinal tract, according to the official. A year ago, <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON> underwent an intestinal bypass operation.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880918-0025 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-18-88 1124EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Solzhenitsyn     09-18 0347</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Solzhenitsyn,0357</SECOND>
<HEAD>Soviet Critic Hopes Solzhenitsyn's Works Will Be Published</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MOSCOW (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON> <PERSON> Solzhenitsyn </PERSON> is a great writer whose works, now banned in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, should be made available in his native land, a prominent Soviet critic said in an interview published Sunday. The comments on the exiled Nobel Prize winner were made by <PERSON> Natalya </PERSON> <PERSON> Ivanova </PERSON> and printed in the <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> youth daily Moskovsky Komsomolets. They were the most positive remarks on Solzhenitsyn to appear in the official Soviet press in recent memory and a further sign of an ongoing reassessment of his works. <PERSON> Solzhenitsyn </PERSON>, who spent eight years in labor camps under dictator <PERSON> Josef </PERSON> <PERSON> Stalin </PERSON>, wrote `` The Gulag Archipelago,'' a voluminous study of the political repression and purges that marred <PERSON> Stalin </PERSON>'s 29-year reign. Under Soviet leader <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>, <PERSON> Stalin </PERSON> and his legacy have been sharply criticized. <PERSON> Solzhenitsyn </PERSON>, who won the Nobel Prize for literature in 1970, was expelled from the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> in 1974 and stripped of his Soviet nationality. He now lives in <LOCATION> Cavendish </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Vt. </LOCATION>, and is a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> citizen. `` I consider that he is a very great writer,'' Ms. <PERSON> Ivanova </PERSON> was quoted as telling Moskovsky Komsomolets in a wide-ranging interview about contemporary Soviet literature. `` It is a great misfortune for our literature that the young generation has been deprived of the possibility of reading his books. I hope that this abnormal situation will be corrected.'' Although the greater openness fostered by <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> has led to the publication of once-banned works by <PERSON> Boris </PERSON> <PERSON> Pasternak </PERSON>, <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> Bulgakov </PERSON> and other Soviet authors, <PERSON> Solzhenitsyn </PERSON> has so far remained off limits. The editor of the literary monthly `` Novy Mir'' has said he is negotiating for the rights to print <PERSON> Solzhenitsyn </PERSON>'s novel `` Cancer Ward.'' But a work such as the `` Gulag'' triology, which maintains that wide-scale political repression began in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> under Soviet founder <PERSON> Vladimir </PERSON> <PERSON> I. </PERSON> <PERSON> Lenin </PERSON>, is still at odds with official ideology, which pins the blame on <PERSON> Stalin </PERSON>. Ms. <PERSON> Ivanova </PERSON>, whose literary criticism regularly appears in the weekly magazine <ORGANIZATION> Ogonyok </ORGANIZATION>, also said she believed <PERSON> Solzhenitsyn </PERSON> should be given his Soviet citizenship back.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880918-0026 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-18-88 1129EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p AM-HawaiiPrimary     09-18 0428</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Hawaii Primary,0440</SECOND>
<HEAD>Political Newcomer Wins Hawaii's Democratic Congressional Primary</HEAD>
<DATELINE>HONOLULU (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Bitterman </PERSON>, a former <ORGANIZATION> Voice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION> director seeking her first elective office, beat two other Democrats in <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION>'s state primary and will face first-term Republican Rep. <PERSON> Patricia </PERSON> <PERSON> Saiki </PERSON> in November. Former Democratic City Councilwoman <PERSON> Marilyn </PERSON> <PERSON> Bornhorst </PERSON> won the right to face Republican <LOCATION> Honolulu </LOCATION> Mayor <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Fasi </PERSON> after defeating three other former council members and a community activist in Saturday's election. Voters also chose nominees for 100 federal, state and local offices. <PERSON> Bitterman </PERSON>, 44, received 51,942 votes, while <LOCATION> Honolulu </LOCATION> City Councilman <PERSON> Leigh-Wai </PERSON> <PERSON> Doo </PERSON> had 35,579 and former teachers union executive <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Radcliffe </PERSON> trailed with 15,258. <PERSON> Saiki </PERSON>, 58, was unopposed in the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> primary for the urban <LOCATION> Honolulu </LOCATION> district. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Sen. Spark <PERSON> Matsunaga </PERSON>, 71, had an easy time with his little-known Democratic opponent, <LOCATION> Honolulu </LOCATION> writer <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Zimmerman </PERSON>. <PERSON> Matsunaga </PERSON> gathered 180,853 votes, or 82 percent, to <PERSON> Zimmerman </PERSON>'s 27,360, or 12 percent, and faces Libertarian candidate <PERSON> Ken </PERSON> <PERSON> Schooland </PERSON> in the general election Six-term <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Rep. <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Akaka </PERSON>, whose district includes outlying areas of <LOCATION> Oahu </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Neighbor </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Islands </LOCATION>, was unopposed in the Democratic primary. His only competition in November will come from <ORGANIZATION> Libertarian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lloyd </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mallan </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Fasi </PERSON>, 68, received 36,608 votes, almost 90 percent, to easily defeat two relatively unknown candidates in the Republican primary. <PERSON> Gordon </PERSON> <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON> finished second with 1,167 votes and <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Hirayasu </PERSON> had 1,035 votes. <PERSON> Bornhorst </PERSON>, 61, received 57,097 votes to defeat former Council members <PERSON> Patsy </PERSON> <PERSON> Mink </PERSON>, <PERSON> Randall </PERSON> <PERSON> Iwase </PERSON> and <PERSON> Dennis </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Connor </PERSON>, and activist <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Souza </PERSON>. Mink got 48,771, <PERSON> Iwase </PERSON> and <PERSON> O'Connor </PERSON> trailed with 22,906 and 21,585 votes respectively and <PERSON> Souza </PERSON> had 3,469. <PERSON> Bornhorst </PERSON>, <PERSON> Iwase </PERSON> and <PERSON> O'Connor </PERSON> were required by law to give up their City Council seats to run for mayor. <PERSON> Mink </PERSON> resigned her council seat two years ago when she mounted an unsuccessful campaign for governor. There was little bad blood in the two major Democratic primary races. In fact, the three Democrats who sought to unseat <PERSON> Saiki </PERSON> became known as `` The Three Amigos'' because of their reluctance to criticize each other and their general agreement on the issues. The Democrats stressed their professional backgrounds and government experience in their appeal to voters. <PERSON> Bornhorst </PERSON>, a 13-year <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> veteran, is the front-runner in the <LOCATION> Honolulu </LOCATION> mayor's race, according to a recent <ORGANIZATION> Honolulu </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Advertiser-Channel </ORGANIZATION> 2 News poll. Although she leads <PERSON> Fasi </PERSON> in the poll for the general election, <PERSON> Fasi </PERSON> was narrowing the gap and many voters were still undecided. <PERSON> Fasi </PERSON> served three terms as a <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> mayor before losing in the 1980 primary. He came back as a Republican and won again in 1984.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
