<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880824-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-24-88 2338EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-RockMusicAuction     08-24 0534</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Rock Music Auction,0552</SECOND>
<HEAD>Elvis Costumes Fetch Top Dollar at Auction</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A stage costume worn by <PERSON> Elvis </PERSON> <PERSON> Presley </PERSON> sold Wednesday at a rock' n'roll and film memorabilia auction for $ 43,700, a record price for a piece of the late singer's clothing, auctioneers said. Bidding was also fierce for another Presley costume, for a 1964 telegram from former Beatle <PERSON> Ringo </PERSON> <PERSON> Starr </PERSON> and for a four-foot wall thermometer featuring <PERSON> Marilyn </PERSON> <PERSON> Monroe </PERSON>, officials said at <LOCATION> Phillips </LOCATION> auction house. <PERSON> Warren </PERSON> <PERSON> Stone </PERSON> of the Hard Rock Cafe in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> bought `` Shooting Star,'' a suit Presley wore at a 1972 concert at Madison Square Garden in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, the auctioneers said. Hard Rock cafes are decorated with rock music memorabilia. Commission costs raised the total purchase price of the costume to $ 48,050, a Phillips statement said. Former country music singer <PERSON> Jimmy </PERSON> <PERSON> Velvet </PERSON> bought for $ 23,500 a Presley stage suit nicknamed `` Good Luck'' by the singer and worn on a 1972 tour of <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION>. `` This makes six jump suits which were once worn by <PERSON> Elvis </PERSON> which I now own,'' said <PERSON> Velvet </PERSON>, who plans to exhibit the outfit at an Elvis Presley museum he runs in <LOCATION> Nashville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Tenn </LOCATION>. The costumes were the highlights of 550 items on sale, said <PERSON> Wendell </PERSON> <PERSON> Milton </PERSON>, rock and pop memorabilia specialist for the <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> auction house. `` They very rarely come up for auction,'' said <PERSON> Milton </PERSON>. `` Most of them are in Graceland,'' the <LOCATION> Nashville </LOCATION> mansion Presley owned before his death in 1977. It now is a museum. Former Beatle drummer <PERSON> Starr </PERSON> sent his telegram to a Dutch newspaper to apologize for pulling out of a Beatles tour of <LOCATION> Holland </LOCATION> because of tonsillitis. `` I'm very sorry I could n't come to <LOCATION> Holland </LOCATION> and hope to see all my <LOCATION> Dutch </LOCATION> fans on the next trip. <PERSON> Ringo </PERSON> <PERSON> Starr </PERSON>,'' it said. It had been expected to fetch $ 336. But Stone bid against <PERSON> Brian </PERSON> <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON> of <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Hard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rock </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cafe </ORGANIZATION> and won with an offer of $ 3,000. `` I bought it because I liked it,'' <PERSON> Stone </PERSON> said. `` I know it was a lot to pay.'' Stone estimated he spent about $ 74,000 at Wednesday's auction. He said he will exhibit all his purchases. A private collector paid $ 7,700 for the bright-orange thermometer featuring <PERSON> Marilyn </PERSON> <PERSON> Monroe </PERSON> to promote her 1959 film `` Some Like It Hot.'' The collector was not identified. <PERSON> Phillips </PERSON> said it had been expected to sell for $ 1,340. `` I think people go crazy for anything to do with <PERSON> Marilyn </PERSON> <PERSON> Monroe </PERSON>,'' <PERSON> Milton </PERSON> said. `` She's so in vogue right now.'' <PERSON> Milton </PERSON> said the auction raised $ 287,300, but had its disappointments _ including handwritten lyrics by <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Springsteen </PERSON> and stage clothing worn by <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>. Six sets of singer and guitarist <PERSON> Springsteen </PERSON>'s lyrics were offered for auction, but only two lyric sheets for the songs `` I've Got A Fever'' and `` Cancel My Tomorrows,'' found buyers, <PERSON> Milton </PERSON> said A shirt <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> wore at the <ORGANIZATION> Jackson </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Brothers </ORGANIZATION>' first concert after the group left the Motown label in 1976 sold for $ 1,680, about half the estimate, he said. Four glittery stage suits worn by the <ORGANIZATION> Osmond </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Brothers </ORGANIZATION> on their 1975 European tour sold for a total of $ 4,370. Each suit was marked with the name of the brother who owned it: <PERSON> Donny </PERSON>, <PERSON> Merrill </PERSON>, <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jay </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880824-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-24-88 2335EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Sweden-Spies     08-24 0130</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Sweden-Spies,0133</SECOND>
<HEAD>Security Police Arrests Suspected Spies</HEAD>
<DATELINE>STOCKHOLM, Sweden (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Security police arrested three Swedes suspected of spying for an East European country, national Swedish television reported Wednesday. The two men and a woman were detained Tuesday in the southwestern port city of <LOCATION> Goteborg </LOCATION> and Chief Public Prosecutor <PERSON> Sven-Olof </PERSON> <PERSON> Hakansson </PERSON> will ask a court Thursday to arraigned them, the report said. `` It concerns military secrets, but I ca n't say of which country,'' the Swedish news agency <ORGANIZATION> TT </ORGANIZATION> quoted <PERSON> Hakansson </PERSON> as saying. The three suspects, originally from East European countries, have not been conducting spying activities against <LOCATION> Sweden </LOCATION> but against `` another country'', the television report said. The suspects, whose names were not released in accordance with press regulations, were said to have worked for an unidentified East European country.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880824-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-24-88 2339EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-North-Arrests     08-24 0340</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-North-Arrests,0349</SECOND>
<HEAD>Protests At Oliver North Appearance Result In Arrests</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DANIEL BEEGAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WAUKESHA, Wis. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A face-off between demonstrators supporting and opposing <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> <PERSON> North </PERSON> resulted in a dozen arrests Wednesday night outside a Republican fund-raiser where the Iran-Contra defendant appeared. Twelve anti-North demonstrators were taken into custody for disorderly conduct, Lt. <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> <PERSON> Martorano </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Waukesha </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sheriff </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> said. He said two were also cited for resisting arrest and one for possession of a controlled substance. No injuries were reported By 10 p.m., most of those arrested were free on bail, he said, adding that they would face court dates in about two weeks. <PERSON> Martorano </PERSON> said most of the arrests involved demonstrators who were `` generally not adhering to rules set up out there for the protesters to follow.'' Police required the anti-North demonstrators to stay within a specific area preventing any intermingling of the two protest groups. Reporters at the scene said there were about 125 anti-North protesters and 60 pro-North demonstrators. <PERSON> Ardelle </PERSON> <PERSON> Hough </PERSON> of <PERSON> Madison </PERSON>, who described herself as an officer of the Women's <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> League </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Peace </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Freedom </ORGANIZATION>, contended the police rules and the arrests violated the protesters' constitutional rights of free speech and free assembly North, a former <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> aide, retired earlier this year as a lieutenant colonel after 20 years in the <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corps </ORGANIZATION>. He was among four people named in an indictment sought by a special prosecutor who investigated the sales of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> arms to <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> and diversion of funds to aid rebels in <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>. The protesters gathered outside the <ORGANIZATION> Waukesha </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Exposition </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in the Town of <LOCATION> Pewaukee </LOCATION> where <PERSON> North </PERSON> was appearing at a fund-raiser for former state <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> King </PERSON>, who is seeking the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> nomination for <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Hough </PERSON> said <PERSON> King </PERSON> is a former <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> agent with a national security background. `` The issue is n't <PERSON> Ollie </PERSON> <PERSON> North </PERSON>,'' she said. `` The issue is n't even <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> The issue is <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> foreign policy, pushing around all the rest of the people of the world.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880824-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-24-88 0012EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--DogPlunge     08-24 0166</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Dog Plunge,0173</SECOND>
<HEAD>Dog Survives 12-Floor Fall</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MYRTLE BEACH, S.C. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A 3-pound <LOCATION> Yorkshire </LOCATION> terrier survived a fall from a 12th-floor balcony and may be walking again by the end of the week, a veterinarian says. `` It's really a lucky dog,'' said veterinarian <PERSON> Earl </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>, who treated the tan and black dog named <PERSON> Missy </PERSON>. `` I did n't think she was going to make it, to tell you the truth ... it's a definite miracle.'' Doctors said Monday the dog had an 85 percent to 90 percent chance of total recovery. <PERSON> Missy </PERSON> fell Friday from the penthouse balcony of the Sea Mark Tower condominium. Her owners, <PERSON> Roy </PERSON> and <PERSON> Ann </PERSON> <PERSON> Gipson </PERSON>, said strong winds created a vacuum that sucked the small dog through a 5-inch-wide opening in a guard rail. <PERSON> Missy </PERSON> landed in a sandy area, just missing a brick walkway and an air conditioner. A tree limb apparently helped break her fall. <PERSON> Missy </PERSON> was in shock with a broken leg when taken to an animal hospital.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880824-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-24-88 0001EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Peru-American 1stLd-Writethru a0601 08-24 0457</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Peru-American, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0601,0470</SECOND>
<HEAD>U.S. Woman Leaves Peru After Being Freed of Terrorism Charges</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: New material and editing throughout, UPDATING with departure,
comments. No pickup</NOTE>
<DATELINE>LIMA, Peru (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An American tourist accused of terrorism left <LOCATION> Peru </LOCATION> for <PERSON> Shannon </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION>, on Tuesday hours after she was released from jail for the second time. <PERSON> Cynthia </PERSON> <PERSON> McNamara </PERSON>, 40, a native of <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION>, had been imprisoned for nearly five months on charges of taking part in an attack by guerrillas of the Maoist Shining Path movement in which two people were killed. A <LOCATION> Lima </LOCATION> court cleared her on April 26 but she was rearrested on the same charges Aug. 2 and was held in jail until Monday night. The <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> issued a brief statement Tuesday expressing approval that she was released. But her departure entered a tense hour at <LOCATION> Lima </LOCATION>'s international airport when the embassy sent word that <LOCATION> Peru </LOCATION> was refusing to allow her to travel anywhere but to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, her lawyers said. Attorney <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Burneo </PERSON> said the embassy and former <LOCATION> Lima </LOCATION> Mayor <PERSON> Alfonso </PERSON> <PERSON> Barrantes </PERSON> made phone calls to Peruvian officials `` at the highest levels'' to gain final approval for her departure. About 20 friends and journalists witnessed her departure at 5:15 p.m. aboard a Soviet Aeroflot flight for <PERSON> Shannon </PERSON>. `` My name is cleared. I feel relieved,'' she said. Police first arrested her Dec. 5 in <LOCATION> Ayacucho </LOCATION> state, 225 miles southeast of <LOCATION> Lima </LOCATION>, while she was on a trip through <LOCATION> Peru </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Chile </LOCATION> as a tourist. She was charged with taking part in a guerrilla attack in August 1987 in <LOCATION> Vilcashuaman </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Ayacucho </LOCATION> in which two government employees were slain. Ms. <PERSON> McNamara </PERSON> was released from jail after a <LOCATION> Lima </LOCATION> court cleared her of the charges. Her attorneys and the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> said two survivors of the <LOCATION> Vilcashuaman </LOCATION> attack testified she was not among the assailants. Other witnesses said she was in <LOCATION> Puquio </LOCATION>, 90 miles south of <LOCATION> Vilcashuaman </LOCATION>, when the attack occurred. <ORGANIZATION> Lima </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Superior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> upheld the ruling on July 13 and Ms. <PERSON> McNamara </PERSON> began making arrangements to leave <LOCATION> Peru </LOCATION>. She was rearrested on an outstanding warrant stemming from the <LOCATION> Vilcashuaman </LOCATION> attack when she appeared at a <LOCATION> Lima </LOCATION> police station on Aug. 2 to get approval to depart. She spent the next three weeks in jail as her attorneys fought to prevent her transfer to Cangallo, the province in <LOCATION> Ayacucho </LOCATION> state where <LOCATION> Vilcashuaman </LOCATION> is located. Her release came after an <LOCATION> Ayacucho </LOCATION> court ruled Monday that she could not be tried twice for the same crime, <PERSON> Burneo </PERSON> said. Ms. <PERSON> Mcnamara </PERSON> said she plans to go to <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> and meet friends before seeking a job teaching English `` somewhere in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>.'' She reiterated her innocence to reporters Tuesday. She has frequently disavowed any ties with the Shining Path.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880824-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-24-88 0014EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-NYCSchoolChief     08-24 1108</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-NYC School Chief,1133</SECOND>
<HEAD>NYC School Chief Sees No Quick Fix for Ailing District</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By LEE MITGANG</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Education Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Green </PERSON>, head of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>'s trouble-plagued schools for six months, faces the start of his first full school year and has no glib, instant answers for problems decades in the making Asked in a lengthy interview what his chief accomplishments have been so far, the former superintendent of <LOCATION> Minneapolis </LOCATION>'s schools answered without apology: `` None.'' `` I did n't rush to judgment because I thought: Who are you to come in, to be invited into somebody's home, and decide what's wrong with the home But I do believe I'm responsible starting this school year,'' he said. For Green, whose quiet, methodical speech belies a steely core, it's the little things, the symbols, that will lead to big changes. This month, for example, he conducted the first-ever count of people working for the central board, a bureaucracy almost legendary for its inscrutability. The answer: 6,447. Next, <PERSON> Green </PERSON> wanted to show teachers he really cares about their professional status. He chose a symbol, giving each of the city's 974 schools until December to rid themselves of the time clocks that teachers have had to punch As for the biggest issues _ the dropout rate, the racial polarization, the sorry state of education for the handicapped, the taming of custodians who had grown all-powerful in many schools _ Green pleads with <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Yorkers </LOCATION> not to expect real solutions for years. Here are highlights of the interview: Q: Now that six months have passed, do you ever wonder what you've gotten yourself into? Are you surprised or shocked at what you've found here? A: No. I think it's a very unusual and special opportunity to affect the lives of nearly one million students. The common theme throughout <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, despite the dropout rate, despite the fact that we have had students with weapons in school, is an underlying feeling that we've got to make the schools work by working together. And that's a very motivating thing for me. Q: What would you list as your key accomplishments so far? A: None. I have n't accomplished anything. I've come to set the stage for making education work. I'm working toward ... making this the most successful school year that <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> has had. Q: Let's talk about some of the toughest problems you'll face. The city has handled education for the handicapped so badly that it's been under federal court monitoring for a decade. When do you think things will improve enough for that to end? A: Maybe five years. Anybody looking for an instant response to that will be disappointed. There are too many complicating factors, particularly the numbers of children who are non-English speaking. The reason litigation builds up over time is that there was a loss of communication and trust. It's going to take time with those advocacy groups and parent groups to restore the trust that was, or create what never was. Q: The city's school minority population stands at over 80 percent. Only a handful of high schools have white enrollments above 50 percent. Is racial integration now an impossible dream for most of our schoolchildren? A: It seems to me we're a country very dependent on diversity, a society that stands for access, not exception. The goals of integration ought to be widely clung to ... The majority of students in this city, unless they are selected by special schools, will very unlikely have the opportunity for an integrated experience. Students can not travel the long distances required in this large and complex city. In order to have large scale racial integration, you need large-scale racial balance in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. You do n't have it. Q: Let's talk about the status of school reform here in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>. One idea you became famous for in <LOCATION> Minneapolis </LOCATION> was your program of testing kindergarten children and holding back those who flunk. You've raised the possibility of starting that in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> despite warnings by many educators that such testing is inappropriate for children that age. Are you still pushing for this? A: What I have observed in American education in my nearly 30 years is that those systems relying on social promotion missed the mark. I do n't care if students are retained or not. What I care about is that we know how well they are performing so that they do n't become victims of the system If you do n't have some process by which ... a teacher you can look a parent in the eye and say, you're child is really ready, you're almost rendering some children to academic failure the rest of their life. The gap seems to be particularly damaging for minority students, and minority males to be specific. I'm prepared to continue our discussion. It really does not matter to me that <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> adopt the <LOCATION> Minneapolis </LOCATION> model about retention. But teachers do have to be accountable for what they are willing to recommend to the next level of teacher. Otherwise it's not going to work Q: You said in your inaugural address last March that schools should stop making teachers punch time clocks. Will they still be doing so in September? A: I said in my inaugural comments that I thought it was unprofessional. Some people have replied, you ca n't trust anybody. People see others not doing what they should, the guy next door who went off to watch the <ORGANIZATION> Knicks </ORGANIZATION> or the <ORGANIZATION> Yankees </ORGANIZATION>. But I still say they're professionals. So I am putting out a memo asking principals to work with their staffs to determine how they can account for attendance in the absence of time clocks, or whether they want to sustain them. They will make the decision building-by-building, and no one will ever be able to say they did n't have a chance to participate in a work related issue that I think is symbolic. Q: Your style seems to be low-key, methodical, deliberate, in a town that's brash and brassy. Do you worry that your lower profile makes people wonder, what's this guy doing? Is that a problem in this town? A: I have no idea. My mission, it may sound altruistic, is to serve children. I hope to represent the school community in the best possible way. My eye is on that prize. For those who want a daily performance report, they're not going to find me a very willing participant. I do n't think it has anything with education. I do n't think it has anything to do with children.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880824-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-24-88 0006EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-BeachWastes     08-24 0203</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Beach Wastes,0207</SECOND>
<HEAD>Assembly Strengthens Infectious Waste Dump Rules</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ALBANY, N.Y. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The state Assembly Tuesday night gave final legislative approval to a measure that would stiffen penalties for those caught illegally dumping infectious medical wastes. The bill, which passed 142-0 without debate, also provides more money for enforcement and needs only the signature of Gov. <PERSON> Mario </PERSON> <PERSON> Cuomo </PERSON> to become law. It's designed to stem the flow of medical debris that washed ashore on several <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Long </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> beaches, closing them to bathers on some of the hottest days of the year. The bill would provide penalties of up to 10 years in jail and fines of $ 100,000 for people convicted of disposing of `` red bag'' wastes, so named because the waste is required to be thrown out in specially marked containers. <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> state will also provide $ 2 million to add new illegal dumping patrols. State Environmental Conservation Commissioner <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Jorling </PERSON> concluded last month that there was no single source for the waste washing up on <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> beaches. He said the waste may have come through the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> sanitation system, through illegal dumping, casual dumping from boats or some combination of all of these.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880824-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-24-88 0027EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-NYCSchools-Glance     08-24 0107</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-NYC Schools-Glance,0117</SECOND>
<HEAD>A Statistical Look at NYC Schools</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-NYC School Chief</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Just how big is the nation's biggest school system? Here, at a glance, is a statistical profile: _ 1988-89 budget _ $ 5.6 billion. _ Number of schools _ 974. _ Number of teachers _ 61,991. _ Central administrative staff _ 6,447. _ Number of students _ 940,000. _ Number of handicapped students _ 113,000. _ Ethnic composition of student body: 38.1 percent black, 33.9 percent Hispanic, 21.3 percent white, 6.6 percent Asian @ <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION>, 0.1 percent Native American @ Eskimo. _ Estimated high school dropout rate _ 29.2 percent.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880824-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-24-88 0040EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Salvador-Left Bjt   08-24 0903</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Salvador-Left, Bjt,0930</SECOND>
<HEAD>Salvadoran Leftists Say Time Is Ripe To Compete In Elections</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in advance as b0183.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By DOUGLAS GRANT MINE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SAN SALVADOR, El Salvador (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 After years of exile and scorn for the ballot box, <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>'s leftist political parties allied with Marxist-led guerrillas are preparing to compete in next year's presidential election `` Elections here between 1982 and now have been part of a plan designed principally to counter action of the guerrilla army, part of a counter-insurgency project,'' said <PERSON> Hector </PERSON> <PERSON> Oqueli </PERSON>, organization secretary of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Revolutionary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Movement </ORGANIZATION>. `` It could therefore be argued that we are now lending our support for that same project, and that we're contradicting ourselves,'' he said. However, <PERSON> Oqueli </PERSON> added, more `` political space has opened up'' since the presidents of <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION> and four other <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> countries signed a peace plan Aug. 7, 1987. `` We want to take maximum advantage of that political opening, even though we are certain that doing political work in those spaces is like swimming in a river full of crocodiles,'' he said in an interview in his party's <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION> headquarters. The regional plan has not ended guerrilla conflicts in <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Guatemala </LOCATION>, but it has contributed to broadening the range of political expression in <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Revolutionary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Movement </ORGANIZATION>, as part of the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Revolutionary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION>, has been allied since 1981 with the <ORGANIZATION> Farabundo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Marti </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION>, the guerrilla organization known as the <ORGANIZATION> FMLN </ORGANIZATION> that has been fighting the U.S.-backed Salvadoran government for eight years. Leaders of the political front who had left in the early 1980s because of rampant rightist death squads began returning to <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION> in November and are still coming. Among them are <PERSON> Guillermo </PERSON> <PERSON> Ungo </PERSON>, <PERSON> Oqueli </PERSON> and <PERSON> Ruben </PERSON> <PERSON> Zamora </PERSON>, general secretary of the <ORGANIZATION> Popular </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Social </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Movement </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Zamora </PERSON>'s party is a left-leaning offshoot of the centrist <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> of President <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Napoleon </PERSON> <PERSON> Duarte </PERSON>, who sat on military-civilian juntas in 1980-82 and has governed since 1984. <PERSON> Duarte </PERSON> has cancer and his doctors say it is terminal. The Oqueli's Revolutionay Movement, the Social Christians and the <ORGANIZATION> Social </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> have formed the Democratic Convergence. <PERSON> Oqueli </PERSON>'s group announced in July its participation, via the Convergence, in the presidential election set for March. Although the electoral front has yet to announce its participation officially, it is already hard at work launching a campaign. <PERSON> Zamora </PERSON>, in an interview with The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>, said the Convergence's activity `` is generating a political alternative capable of attracting ample sectors of the population that have been left without alternative.'' `` We're also contributing little by little to overcoming people's fear, because of past repression, of participating in politics,'' he said. The leftists do not harbor illusions of an electoral victory. `` We are not taking part strictly for the votes, rather we're mounting a historical project that transcends election day,'' said <PERSON> Oqueli </PERSON> The main plank in the leftist platform is a negotiated end to the war. The government has rejected two such proposals by the insurgents so far this year. `` The country's principal problem is the war,'' <PERSON> Oqueli </PERSON> said. `` If the armed conflict is not resolved, we will not be able to resolve the economic, social and political problems _ health, housing, nutrition, employment. So we're telling the <LOCATION> Salvadoran </LOCATION> people that a solution to the war is necessary, and for us that solution is a negotiated political one.'' <PERSON> Duarte </PERSON>'s position is that the guerrillas lay down their arms before talks can begin, but the rebels say that would be tantamount to surrender. The guerrillas imposed a nationwide transport ban during legislative and municipal elections in March to underscore their characterization of them as `` a farce.'' The prospect of watching their political allies take part in similar elections next year is thought to be a difficult pill for them to swallow. `` The <ORGANIZATION> FMLN </ORGANIZATION> does n't have to either approve or disapprove of our participation,'' said <PERSON> Oqueli </PERSON>. `` They simply must respect it, as we respect their principal means of struggle.'' He said political and military revolutionary leaders met in <LOCATION> Managua </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>, in mid-July to discuss electoral participation. `` Our position and our objectives were fully understood -LRB- by the guerrillas. -RRB-'' he said. The Convergence will go up against an incumbent party shattered by infighting and deteriorated by the exercise of power during years of crisis. <PERSON> Duarte </PERSON>'s promises of peace and increased well-being have gone unfulfilled. The Republican Nationalist Alliance, the main rightist opposition, is running on the full head of steam produced by its victories in March. The party, known as <PERSON> Arena </PERSON>, gained control of the legislature and two thirds of municipalities nationwide. The leftist political front could face its most difficult dilemma if no candidate in March receives more than 50 percent of the vote. That would require a second round with the top two finishers in the running. Most observers doubt either the <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democrats </ORGANIZATION> or <PERSON> Arena </PERSON> will receive a majority in the first round. If the Convergence obtains around 10 percent of the vote, which is considered feasible, it could decide the outcome by casting its lot with one of the two major parties. <PERSON> Oqueli </PERSON> said he believes abstention would be advisable in a second round. `` If we tie ourselves to the <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democrats </ORGANIZATION>, and they continue as they have been, we dirty our future,'' he said. `` And <PERSON> Arena </PERSON> represents the oligarchic past that brought the country to where it is now.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880824-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-24-88 0057EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-AbortionArrests     08-24 0713</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Abortion Arrests,0733</SECOND>
<HEAD>Atlanta Jerks Welcome Mat From Under Anti-Abortion Protesters</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By JOSEPH B. FRAZIER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ATLANTA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 More than a month of demonstrations by an anti-abortion group trying to close local clinics have worn out the city's welcome mat, and Southern hospitality is being withdrawn. During and just after the Democratic National Convention, police carried anti-abortion protesters to waiting jail buses. Now, more than 700 arrests and a dozen demonstrations later, they drag them. `` We're giving them the opportunity to walk the 10 feet to the bus,'' said police Sgt. <PERSON> Melvin </PERSON> <PERSON> Denson </PERSON>. `` We are no longer extending certain courtesies,'' says Sgt. <PERSON> Carl </PERSON> <PERSON> Pydrum </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr </PERSON>. The jails are getting crowded, although corrections officials say they can manage, even if some demonstrators have to bunk on cell floors. And the cost of protecting the clinics and of arresting and holding the protesters has shot past $ 250,000. Operation Rescue, a New York-based anti-abortion group, kicked off the protests July 19, the second day of the convention, when scores of activists who were not carrying identification tried to block access to a clinic where abortions and other procedures are performed. Those arrested refused to give their names, identifying themselves as Baby <PERSON> Jane </PERSON> <PERSON> Doe </PERSON> or Baby <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Doe </PERSON> to show solidarity with the fetuses. Some remain jailed; others have been identified or have won their release by giving their names. Comrades keep coming. Authorities wo n't release those who refuse to give their names, saying they could not be sure the protesters would return for court dates. Mayor <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> <PERSON> Young </PERSON> rejected a request last week by 44 congressmen, including the entire <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION> delegation, to release the prisoners. He said the protesters could go when they give their names, and noted that <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> pays $ 10,000 a week in police overtime because of the protests. It costs about $ 50 a day to keep a person in jail. The city's tactics in dealing with the activists have changed as the protests have dragged on. The convention expedient of releasing arrested protesters on recognizance bonds is history; authorities now require cash or a surety bond ranging from $ 300 to $ 2,000. About 300 demonstrators remain in city and <LOCATION> Fulton </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> jails, now mixed in with the general jail population instead of being kept apart. Some demonstrators are being charged with felony obstruction counts instead of misdemeanor trespassing. Vans taking protesters to the clinics have started getting traffic tickets. But leaders of Operation Rescue continue urging people to come, block entrances to clinics and get arrested. `` Our objective is to close the clinics,'' said <PERSON> Lowell </PERSON> <PERSON> Patterson </PERSON>, an Operation Rescue spokesman who added that the group is opening a permanent office in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>. `` The effect is a heavy arrest load but we're not listing -LRB- overloading jails -RRB- as a main goal.'' He said about 50 of the 134 arrested in the first demonstration remain in jail, and some have vowed to stay 100 days. The most recent demonstration was Friday, when 40 were arrested. The seven clinics in the metropolitan area remain open, guarded by police, but <PERSON> Patterson </PERSON> contends that does not mean defeat. `` Our objective is to save lives. Preventing people from going in -LRB- to the clinics -RRB- is the same thing. Whether it is open or not is a matter of words,'' he said. Lawsuits are pending against Operation Rescue in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION>. Attorney <PERSON> Margie </PERSON> <PERSON> Pitts </PERSON> <PERSON> Hames </PERSON>, who represents some Atlanta-area clinics, said such a lawsuit is being considered in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>, `` but it is not a priority. -LRB- The clinics -RRB- have not decided what to do. The focus has been on maintaining service.'' <PERSON> Patterson </PERSON> said Operation Rescue has no plans to stop the demonstrations as long as volunteers are willing to come to <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> and go to jail. He told of a businessman from <LOCATION> Austin </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, due in this week with a busload of 25 employees and bail money for them, of people calling promising to arrive weeks hence, saying they are planning vacation time and arranging for discount air fares. `` People from 39 states have been through the jail here,'' he said. `` Now I'm calling people in states we're missing. I just talked to a woman in <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION> who said they were sending down a van-load. That will be the 40th state.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880824-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-24-88 0101EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Panama-Analysist     08-24 0720</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Panama-Analysist,0740</SECOND>
<HEAD>Noriega Opposition In Limbo</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Analysis</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By REID G. MILLER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PANAMA CITY, Panama (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Neither public protest nor <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> pressure has budged Gen. <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>, and the Panamanian movement to oust the nation's de facto ruler appears mired in uncertainty and despair. <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>'s political foes did not even draw much enthusiasm from a huge anti-government demonstration that accompanied the funeral Aug. 15 of a revered former president whom the military threw out of office three times. Tens of thousands of people marched 40 and 50 abreast in the funeral procession for <ORGANIZATION> Arnulfo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Arias </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Madrid </ORGANIZATION>, but <PERSON> Roberto </PERSON> <PERSON> Aleman </PERSON>, a leader of the opposition alliance, discounted its significance. `` In the short and medium term, I doubt that it will mean much,'' he said. `` In the longer term, we may see some life put back into the movement or we may see it fractionalized. The thing is, <PERSON> Arnulfo </PERSON> is gone but <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>'s still here.'' Behind <PERSON> Aleman </PERSON>'s assessment was his concern, shared by other opposition leaders, that the death could split the Authentic Panamanian Party, which <PERSON> Arias </PERSON> founded and built into the country's largest opposition force `` There's no one of <ORGANIZATION> Arias </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Madrid </ORGANIZATION>'s stature in the wings, but if his followers can unite around someone it would certainly strengthen the entire opposition movement,'' a Western diplomat said privately. `` If they do n't, the party is likely to be split into a number of competing factions and that would just muddy things up.'' <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> has weathered a 14-month-old opposition campaign to force him out as commander of the 15,000-member <ORGANIZATION> Panama </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forces </ORGANIZATION>, which include the armed forces and police. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> economic sanctions against <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> and federal indictments on charges of drug trafficking and money laundering have had little visible impact on <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>'s standing. <PERSON> Eric </PERSON> <PERSON> Arturo </PERSON> <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON>, the president <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> put into office, rebelled and tried to fire the general a few days after the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> indictments were handed up in February. <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> arranged for the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION>, which he controls, to dismiss <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON> instead. In speeches, interviews and billboard advertisements, <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> says the government will hold a presidential election as planned in May 1989. The main questions are whether <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> will seek the presidency and whether the opposition can unite long enough to defeat either the general or the candidate he chooses. Some opposition leaders speak of boycotting the election, but most do not see that as an option. Another diplomat said: `` The <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> sanctions have n't driven <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> out, it is doubtful they -LRB- <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> -RRB- will try a military solution and there's no one in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> who can singlehandedly carry the opposition banner. The people are being driven to despair. `` There are a lot of people out there who are against <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> _ very easily the majority, I'd say _ but they feel abandoned by the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and there's not one single opposition leader with whom they feel comfortable.'' <PERSON> Morton </PERSON> <PERSON> Abramowitz </PERSON>, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> assistant secretary of state for inter-American affairs, visited <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> two weeks ago. Opposition leaders who met him said he offered nothing new. One said, on condition his name not be used: `` I got the impression that nothing will happen until after the -LRB- <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> -RRB- election, and then who knows what?'' Some observers had expected <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> to announce his presidential candidacy Aug. 12, his fifth anniversary as commander of the Defense Forces. <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> dropped no hints at the celebration, however. Instead, he delivered another diatribe against the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, accusing it of creating a crisis in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> to negate the 1977 treaties that turn the <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Canal </LOCATION> over to <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> on Dec. 31, 1999. `` Many Panamanians wrongly thought that with the new treaties of 1977, <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> were beginning a permanent honeymoon, forgetting that for the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> a treaty is no more ... than a useful but ephemeral act,'' <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> declared. On Sunday, the <ORGANIZATION> Panama </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forces </ORGANIZATION> rejected charges that its troops are harassing <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military personnel and called the accusations part of an effort to undermine the government. Its statement injected a note of sarcasm by saying <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials who make such accusations `` must have the IQ of a 3-year-old Cro-Magnon.''
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Reid </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Miller </PERSON>, a roving correspondent based in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jose </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Costa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rica </LOCATION>, has covered <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> for <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> since 1984.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880824-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-24-88 0118EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Nielsens     08-24 0375</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nielsens,0388</SECOND>
<HEAD>GOP Convention Pushes Network Ratings To Sag</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Republican National Convention would have been the top four shows in the <ORGANIZATION> A.C. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nielsen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> ratings last week if only one network had been covering it. With <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> and CBS casting about for news in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION>, however, the convention made only one appearance in the top 30 while millions of viewers deserted network television. <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, which had the lowest-rated convention coverage, nearly won the week with a big surge on Sunday night. Its `` 60 Minutes'' and `` Murder, She Wrote,'' tied for first, and CBS' Sunday night movie, `` Outrage,'' came in fifth. <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, however, held on to first place with an average 8.3 rating for the week that ended Sunday, followed by <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>' 8.2 and <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s 7.8. Each rating point represents 1 percent of the nation's 86.6 million homes with television. For the 48 weeks of the season, <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s average is 14.6, <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>' 12.3 and <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s 12.2. In combined ratings, each of the four nights of the GOP convention did better than the 15.6 rating for the top-rated `` 60 Minutes'' and `` Murder, She Wrote.'' Totals were 19.9 for Monday, 17.6 for Tuesday, 16.7 Wednesday and 20.9 on Thursday. The best any one network could do, hower, was <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s 30th place finish for its Thursday night coverage. Because of the convention coverage, the three networks had only 47 percent of the television viewing audience last week, compared with 67 percent for the season. <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> won the first night of the convention but <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> ran well ahead in the next three nights, averaging a 6.6 rating. <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> followed with 6.4 while <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, whose best showing was a second-place tie on Wednesday night, averaged 5.7. During the Democratic convention, <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> averaged 7.4, followed by <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> at 6.9 and CBS 6.5. Though it ran a poor third in convention ratings, <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> nonetheless won the evening news ratings last week with an average of 8.8. <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> was second at 8.7 and <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> averaged 8.2. After `` 60 Minutes'' and `` Murder She Wrote,'' the rest of the top 10 was <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` The Cosby Show,'' `` Golden Girls,'' CBS' `` Outrage,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Different World,'' `` Amen,'' and `` <PERSON> Hunter </PERSON>,'' and a tie between <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` 227'' and <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s Sunday movie, `` Letting Go.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880824-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-24-88 0121EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-NielsensList     08-24 0611</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nielsens List,0676</SECOND>
<HEAD>List of Week's Top-Rated TV Shows</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Nielsens</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the prime-time television ratings as compiled by the <ORGANIZATION> A.C. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nielsen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> for the week of Aug. 15-21. Top 20 listings include the week's ranking, with full season-to-date ranking in parentheses, rating for the week, and total homes. An `` X'' in parentheses denotes one-time-only presentation. A rating measures the percentage of the nation's 88.6 million TV homes. 1. -LRB- 4 -RRB- `` 60 Minutes,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 15.6 rating, 13.8 million homes. 1. -LRB- 9 -RRB- `` Murder, She Wrote,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 15.6, 13.8 million homes. 3. -LRB- 1 -RRB- `` The Cosby Show,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 15.3, 13.5 million homes. 4. -LRB- 4 -RRB- `` Golden Girls,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 15.1, 13.3 million homes. 5. -LRB- 19 -RRB- `` Outrage!'' _ `` CBS Sunday Movie,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 14.8, 13.1 million homes. 6. -LRB- 2 -RRB- `` A Different World,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 14.4, 12.7 million homes. 7. -LRB- 17 -RRB- `` Amen,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.0, 11.5 million homes. 8. -LRB- 25 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Hunter </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.7, 11.2 million homes. 9. -LRB- 28 -RRB- `` 227,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.6, 10.2 million homes. 9. -LRB- 40 -RRB- `` Letting Go'' _ `` <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> Sunday Movie,'' 11.6, 10.2 million homes. 11. -LRB- 101 -RRB- `` Child's Cry'' _ `` CBS Fiday Night Movie,'' 11.4, 10.1 million homes. 12. -LRB- 22 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Matlock </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 10.9, 9.6 million homes. 13. -LRB- 15 -RRB- `` ALF,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 10.8, 9.5 million homes. 14. -LRB- 40 -RRB- `` Full House _ Tuesday,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 10.7, 9.4 million homes. 15. -LRB- 53 -RRB- `` 20-20,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 10.5, 9.3 million homes. 16. -LRB- 72 -RRB- `` Full House,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 10.4, 9.2 million homes. 17. -LRB- 71 -RRB- `` Mr. <PERSON> Belvedere </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 10.2, 9.0 million homes. 18. -LRB- 39 -RRB- `` Perfect Strangers,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 10.1, 8.9 million homes. 18. -LRB- 8 -RRB- `` Who's the Boss?,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 10.1, 8.9 million homes. 20. -LRB- 51 -RRB- `` The <PERSON> Hogan </PERSON> Family,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 9.9, 8.6 million homes. 20. -LRB- 25 -RRB- `` Head of the Class,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 9.9, 8.7 million homes. 22. -LRB- 45 -RRB- `` Facts of Life,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 9.8. 23. -LRB- 31 -RRB- `` Family Ties,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 9.6. 23. -LRB- 23 -RRB- `` Dress Gray, Pt. 1'' _ `` NBC Sunday Night Movie,'' 9.6. 25. -LRB- 10 -RRB- `` Growing Pains,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 9.5. 26. -LRB- 82 -RRB- `` I Married Dora,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 9.2. 27. -LRB- 65 -RRB- `` Beauty and the <LOCATION> Beast </LOCATION>,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 8.6. 28. -LRB- X -RRB- `` <ORGANIZATION> NFL </ORGANIZATION> Pre-Season Football: <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION> vs. <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 7.9. 29. -LRB- 43 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Jake </PERSON> and the Fatman,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 7.8. 30. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Republican Convention _ Thursday,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 7.7. 31. -LRB- 69 -RRB- `` MacGyver,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 7.2. 32. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s Most Wanted,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 7.1. 32. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Republican Convention _ Monday,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 7.1. 34. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Republican Convention _ Thursday,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 7.0. 34. -LRB- 30 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Newhart </PERSON>,'' CBS, 7.0. 34. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Loner,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 7.0. 37. -LRB- 77 -RRB- `` Spenser: For Hire,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 6.8. 37. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Republican Convention _ Monday,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 6.8. 39. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` Married ... With Children,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 6.7. 40. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Republican Convention _ Tuesday,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 6.4. 40. -LRB- X -RRB- `` <PERSON> Remo </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 6.4. 42. -LRB- X -RRB- `` <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> vs. <ORGANIZATION> LA </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Raiders </ORGANIZATION>,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 6.3. 42. -LRB- 92 -RRB- `` Down the <LOCATION> Long </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hills </LOCATION>, Pt. 1'' _ `` Disney Sunday Movie,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 6.3. 44. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Republican Convention _ Thursday,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 6.2. 44. -LRB- X -RRB- `` <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION>'s Way,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 6.2. 46. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Republican Convention _ Wednesday,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 6.1. 47. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Lovers, Partners and Spies,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 6.0. 47. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Republican Convention _ Tuesday,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 6.0. 47. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Republican Convention _ Monday,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 6.0. 50. -LRB- 50 -RRB- `` The Cavanaughs,'' CBS, 5.8. 51. -LRB- 89 -RRB- `` Tour of Duty,'' CBS, 5.6. 52. -LRB- 104 -RRB- `` Supercarrier,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 5.3. 52. -LRB- 105 -RRB- `` Rags to Riches,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 5.3. 52. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Republican Convention _ Wednesday,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 5.3. 52. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Republican Convention _ Wednesday,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 5.3. 52. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` 21 Jump Street,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 5.3. 57. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Republican Convention _ Tuesday,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 5.2. 58. -LRB- X -RRB- `` CBS Summer Playhouse: Roughhouse-Off Duty,'' 5.0. 58. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` It's <PERSON> Garry </PERSON> <PERSON> Shandling </PERSON>'s Show,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 5.0. 60. -LRB- 117 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Frank </PERSON>'s Place,'' CBS, 4.9. 61. -LRB- X -RRB- `` <ORGANIZATION> Sportsworld </ORGANIZATION> 10th Anniversary,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 4.5. 62. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` The <PERSON> Tracey </PERSON> <PERSON> Ullman </PERSON> Show,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 4.4. 63. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` The Reporters,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 3.4. 64. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` Duet,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 3.0. 65. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` Saturday Night at the Late Show,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 2.1. 66. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` Werewolf,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 1.4.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880824-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-24-88 0017EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-CraterVents     08-24 0214</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Crater Vents,0220</SECOND>
<HEAD>Dives End With No Vents Seen</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CRATER LAKE, Ore. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Scientists finished a series of dives in the nation's deepest lake Tuesday without fulfilling their hope of finding hydrothermal vents. <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON>, the chief ranger at <ORGANIZATION> Crater </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lake </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Park </ORGANIZATION>, said the dives, which began Aug. 5, nevertheless yielded a wealth of information. `` A variety of hydrothermal information, clues as it were, were seen _ bacterial mats, temperature anomalies, manganese deposits, which are all in association with hydrothermal activity,'' <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON> said. `` A great deal of biological and geological information is going to be derived from the samples taken,'' he added. <ORGANIZATION> Oregon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> scientists <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Dymond </PERSON> and <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Collier </PERSON> took turns making dives in the one-man submersible `` Deep Rover.'' They are in the second year of a three-year study, funded by the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Park </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>, on the possible effect of hot springs on the lake. The work is part of a larger 10-year study launched when the 1,932-foot-deep lake began to lose some of its famous clarity. The work also could produce information for use in the debate over whether <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> should be allowed to develop hydrothermal energy close outside the park. <PERSON> Dymond </PERSON> and <PERSON> Collier </PERSON> are scheduled to return next summer for the last series of dives.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880824-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-24-88 0130EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-PresidentialTransition Bjt   08-24 0778</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Presidential Transition, Bjt,780</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHINGTON TODAY: Opposing Politicians Consider Transition
Problems</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LAWRENCE L. KNUTSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Political associates of <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> sat next to each other in a meeting room for a serious, non-partisan discussion of making the jump from candidate to president of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. Many of the participants in a day of quiet talk sponsored by <ORGANIZATION> Boston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Communication </ORGANIZATION> had taken part in presidential transitions in the past, many of them by their own admission seriously flawed. <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Fahrenkopf </PERSON>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, told the group of senior campaign officials, political appointees and career civil servants that the next president-elect will have just 73 days from election to inaugural, the shortest possible period. The president-elect of 1988 will, under the terms of a new law, have $ 3.5 million in federal fuding to pay for the staff, office space and office equipment needed to mount his transition in an orderly way, <PERSON> Fahrenkopf </PERSON> said, pointing out that none of the money will be available until after the election. <PERSON> Madeleine </PERSON> <PERSON> Albright </PERSON>, senior foreign policy adviser to the <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> campaign, said during Tuesday's meeting that efforts to put together a transition staff are at a `` very embryonic stage'' because `` he will be devoting all of his efforts to win.'' But she said that from a subject to which little attention was ever paid, transition planning `` has now become a whole cottage industry'' with its own set of specialists producing studies and reports and issuing critiques. Mrs. <PERSON> Albright </PERSON> was on the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> staff in the <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> administration when the transition to <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s presidency began `` I think there was a pretty good commitment to hand it over in good shape to the people coming in,'' she said. `` We had political differences with them, but there was also a sense of responsibility.'' In a sense, she said, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> already has laid the groundwork for a transition should he win, by reaching out to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and establishing a relationship with the institution and its leaders. `` People actually do learn from mistakes,'' she said, noting there is a sense among many Democrats that `` President <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> came to town in 1976 not knowing very many of the locals,'' something that worked against him when he tried to get his program through <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Ifshin </PERSON>, who served as general counsel for the <PERSON> Mondale </PERSON> for President campaign four years ago, said the transition is important because it can have three results: get the new president off to a fast start, establish the momentum that will prevent a primary challenge when he seeks re-election and help him `` get to a second term.'' <PERSON> Darrell </PERSON> <PERSON> Trent </PERSON>, a <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> deputy campaign manager in 1976 and 1980 and director of policy coordination in the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> 1980 transition, spoke at length of his experience in <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON>'s transition in 1968. `` Beginning the day after the election, we realized little had been done to prepare us to take over the government,'' he said, describing how the transition office took over the 14th floor of the <PERSON> Pierre </PERSON> <PERSON> Hotel </PERSON> and was faced with the task of `` moving out the beds.'' `` No plans had been made for logistical support,'' <PERSON> Trent </PERSON> said. `` And nothing had been done on policy planning. <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> had thought it was necessary to concentrate totally on getting elected.'' By contrast, he said, the incoming <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> team was `` a model both campaigns should look at.'' He said its personnel operation was well organized and a team was in place immediately after the election `` to go into every department and agency.'' A plus, he said, `` was that the <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> administration was absolutely first-rate to deal with. The president ordered that every kind of cooperation would be given.'' <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Fuelner </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> Heritage </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION>, described that conservative think tank's support work for the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> transition. Speaking of the transition's efforts to get a grip on <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> policy, <PERSON> Fuelner </PERSON> said: `` One of the great difficulties was coming up with specific questions. The problem was, they never volunteered the answers to a question if you did n't know enough to ask.'' `` We had to keep reminding ourselves that we were not the government,'' <PERSON> Fuelner </PERSON> said. `` Until that magic moment, someone else was in charge. `` And when that magic moment does occur, you have a sudden loss of institutional memory'' as the old office holders leave town to pursue other careers. <PERSON> Fuelner </PERSON> had advice he said would work well no matter who wins in November: `` Work hard on your transition team. But keep your transition efforts very low key, so all of your efforts really are focused on Nov. 8.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880824-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-24-88 0132EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-ThornburghInterview Bjt   08-24 0726</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Thornburgh Interview, Bjt,720</SECOND>
<HEAD>Thornburgh Questions Last-Minute Meese Action Aimed at Congress</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOAN MOWER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Attorney General <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON> says he is concerned that a special prosecutor plan aimed at <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> by his predecessor, <PERSON> Edwin </PERSON> <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>, is a `` cure where there is no disease.'' <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON> said in an interview Tuesday that he is taking a `` second look'' at an order <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> signed on his last day as attorney general that requires special investigations of members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> suspected of criminal wrongdoing. `` I want to find out what the underlying premise was in the issuance of the order,'' said <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON>. The former <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> governor, who was sworn in Aug. 12, arrived in the waning days of the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration to head a department that had been buffeted by <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>'s tenure. <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> was the subject of a lengthy investigation by Independent Counsel <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> McKay </PERSON>, who declined to seek indictments but said in his final report that <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> `` probably'' had broken ethics laws. <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>'s final-day order for special prosecutors to investigate members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> was widely viewed on <LOCATION> Capitol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION> as a parting shot by <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> at his critics there. <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON>, 56, a former head of the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>'s criminal division in the <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> administration, said Tuesday that it is `` pretty well known that I see a very limited role for special prosecutors-independent counsels in the process of investigating and prosecuting criminal cases. He said <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> attorneys and the department's office of public integrity, which investigates corruption of public officials, do a fine job pursuing allegations of criminal conduct, and prosecuting if necessary. <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON> established the public integrity office in the mid-1970s. `` I guess what I am curious about is what is being proposed ... a cure where there is no disease'' he said. `` I am taking what could be called fairly a second look at that order.'' While <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> was attorney general, a number of high-ranking officials resigned, and a number expressed unhappiness with the attention <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> was forced to give to <PERSON> McKay </PERSON>'s investigation. Asked how he planned to restore morale, <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON> said: `` You lead by example, and I want to make it clear that my view of the department is one that requires an absolute fidelity to high standards of professional conduct and integrity in our operations ... the values and principles of any organization are transmitted from the top.'' <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON> said he will talk to an advisory group of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> attorneys to see what they think of <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>'s last-minute order on investigations of members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. The order requires that attorneys general appoint an independent counsel to investigate allegations of wrongdoing made against a senator or congressman. Although the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> already could conduct such investigations on its own, <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> said his order was designed to ensure that legislators and top executive officials are treated equitably. The 1978 Ethics in Government Act allows executive-branch employees to be investigated by special prosecutors, a provision that was designed to eliminate possible conflicts of interest in which an administration would be responsible for investigating itself. No comparable conflicts exist when the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> _ part of the executive branch _ investigates members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, who are part of the legislative branch. Sen. <PERSON> Carl </PERSON> <PERSON> Levin </PERSON>, D-Mich., chairman of a governmental affairs subcommittee, already had asked <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON> to rescind <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>'s order because it contained a drafting error and the public never got a chance to comment on it During the next five months, <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON> said he will `` take stock and make sure everything is shipshape'' in the department. He said the department will aggressively pursue the war on drugs and other criminal activity. Although he is a strong supporter of <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> presidential nominee <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON> said he will not campaign for <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and has no commitment that he will keep his job if <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> wins in November. He refused to talk about partisan politics because of the sensitivity of his position. And he said he had no idea when the department's office of professional responsibility, which looks into the conduct of <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> employees, will complete its own review of <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>'s conduct to see if it met ethical standards. The ethics review began after <PERSON> McKay </PERSON> issued his report last month. <PERSON> McKay </PERSON> concluded in his final report that <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> probably broke conflict-of-interest and tax laws, but <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> said the report `` vindicated'' him.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880824-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-24-88 0130EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lites     08-24 0409</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lites,0423</SECOND>
<HEAD>On The Light Side</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: `K' in 2nd graf of 1st item is cq.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>ATLANTA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Several of the Democrats from last month's national convention still have n't left town `` Neither <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> nor <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> has been claimed. I think <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s still there and I think Grits and <PERSON> Fritz </PERSON> are still there, too,'' said <PERSON> K </PERSON> <PERSON> Thweatt </PERSON>, public relations manager for <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION>'s Stone Mountain Park. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>, <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, Grits and <PERSON> Fritz </PERSON> are among the 11 donkeys the state park acquired for publicity purposes during the Democratic National Convention. They have yet to find a new home. The park plans to keep two of the donkeys, but the others are available for $ 150 each. <PERSON> Thweatt </PERSON> said the animals got around quite a bit during the convention. `` They probably went to more prestigious parties and events than any of us, so we feel like they're very well-traveled donkeys,'' she said. `` They know all the right people. I'm not saying how many parties they could get their owners into now, but they did all right during the convention.'' <PERSON> Thweatt </PERSON> said she's happy the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> chose <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION> for its convention. `` I shudder to think what would've happened to the park if we had had the Republican Convention,'' she said. `` I ca n't imagine all those elephants.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>PLAINVIEW, Texas (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 As Police Chief <PERSON> Roy </PERSON> <PERSON> Osborne </PERSON> explains it, there just was n't enough crime in this <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> town of 25,000 to justify keeping a patrol officer who worked like a dog. `` There was no sense wasting his talent,'' the chief said of <LOCATION> Lazer </LOCATION>, a 3-year-old Belgian shepherd. `` He needed to be moved someplace where he can be used.'' <PERSON> Lazer </PERSON> recently was shipped to an <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Paso </LOCATION> security firm. `` Our burglaries have been down to the point that we had n't had much call to use an animal in building searches. We'd like to have used him more, but we're glad we did n't have to,'' said <PERSON> Osborne </PERSON>, who added that he missed <PERSON> Lazer </PERSON>. <PERSON> Osborne </PERSON>'s decision also was prompted by the request of <PERSON> Lazer </PERSON>'s regular handler that he be transferred from his 8 p.m. to 4 a.m. shift The chief could n't find anyone in the 29-person department to replace <PERSON> Lazer </PERSON>'s keeper. But <PERSON> Osborne </PERSON> said that while the canine unit has been disbanded, his force still has another employee with a nose for sniffing out crime. <PERSON> Sonny </PERSON>, a golden retriever, will continue to live with one of the department's detectives and work on drug investigations.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880824-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-24-88 0134EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-TeensonTV     08-24 0377</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Teens on TV,380</SECOND>
<HEAD>Report: Television Offers Unrealistic Image Of Teen Girls</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CRISPIN Y. CAMPBELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Television programs fail to show teen-age girls taking the steps necessary to achieve productive lives, focusing instead on obsessions with shopping, grooming and dating, says a women's advocacy group. `` These images create the impression that one can magically jump from an adolescence of dating and shopping to a well-paid professional career,'' said <PERSON> Sally </PERSON> <PERSON> Steenland </PERSON>, author of a report, `` Growing Up In Prime Time.'' The study of more than 200 episodes of 19 network television programs featuring adolescent characters was sponsored by the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> on </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Working </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Women </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wider </ORGANIZATION> Opportunities for Women. The non-profit group seeks to improve women's status in the labor market. `` Week after week, viewers see teen-age girls with no visible skills, no favorite subjects in school, no discussion about college majors or vocational plans,'' Ms. <PERSON> Steenland </PERSON> said in prepared comments as the study was released Tuesday. `` TV's teen-age girls are portrayed as poised for professional careers and productive adulthoods without clues to the steps necessary to achieve those goals,'' the report said. The report found: _ Girls' looks are shown to count more than their brains Some episodes portray intelligent teen-age girls as social misfits. _ Adolescent girls, who outnumber their male counterparts on television, are more passive than male characters _ Weekly plots are lacking in serious conversations with parents, teachers or peers about school matters, academic interests, career goals or future plans _ Ninety-four percent of teen-age girls on television are middle-class or wealthy In reality, more than one-third of adolescent girls live in families with annual incomes of under $ 20,000. The study said some episodes featured well-liked, intelligent girls and teen-agers who linked their interests to career goals, but the report singled out an installment of <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Mr. Belvedere'' for criticism. The episode involved a college fraternity's `` bowser ball'' to which pledges must invite the ugliest girls on campus. `` Throughout the ` Mr. <PERSON> Belvedere </PERSON>' episode, the smart girl is portrayed as clumsy, homely, unpopular, unsure of herself and desperate for a date,'' the report said. `` ... According to the show, the drunken advances of a boy who thinks they are ugly and dates them as a joke are preferable -LRB- to being alone -RRB-.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880824-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-24-88 0138EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Bush-BentsenSons     08-24 0830</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bush-Bentsen Sons,820</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush and Bentsen Sons Say No Strings Pulled in Their Guard
Sign-ups</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RITA BEAMISH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The sons of <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> say no strings were pulled to ensure their entrance into the National Guard during the Vietnam War. <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, son of the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> presidential candidate, and <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>, the son of the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> vice presidential candidate, discussed their military service Tuesday in response to the flap over whether family influence helped <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> vice presidential candidate <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> join the Guard and avoid being drafted for combat in <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>. The younger <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> were Guardsmen together at <ORGANIZATION> Ellington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Base </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION>. Both said they applied to enter the <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> in 1968 when it was inevitable they would be called to serve in the military. But the two, who had known one another in <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION> before joining the same Guard unit, said they enlisted on their own without use of their fathers' influence. Their fathers have affirmed that position. Both men said in interviews that they signed up after personally contacting the commander of the fighter group they wanted to join at <LOCATION> Ellington </LOCATION>. Circumstances of joining the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> have become an issue in the case of <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>, a youthful advocate of the Vietnam War who is now a hardliner on defense in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>. During the <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> era, entrance into the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> was viewed by some as a way to avoid being drafted and sent to <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> has denied any such motivation. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>'s student deferment from the draft was about to expire in 1969 and he had been called for his pre-induction physical, an indication he was about to be drafted. Most of those drafted during the period were sent to <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>. A retired <ORGANIZATION> Indiana </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> official acknowledged Tuesday that he told the Guard personnel office to hold open a space for <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> after receiving a call from a <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> family employee in 1969. Both <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s son and <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>'s son acknowledged it was inevitable they would have to serve in the military after they graduated from college, so they chose <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> service. The younger <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>, 43, railed at a claim by <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Sununu </PERSON> that <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>'s father had rushed to get his son a spot in the National Guard when he learned of an opening. `` He was absolutely, categorically wrong,'' the son said. `` Shortly after I graduated, I went to a party with some of my friends and one of the people introduced me to Brig. Gen. <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> Staudt </PERSON>, who was the commander of the 147th <ORGANIZATION> Fighter </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Group </ORGANIZATION> in the <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION>.'' <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> said <PERSON> Staudt </PERSON> told him at a later meeting that because of his masters business degree, `` he could use someone like me'' for an accounting and finance officer. <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> said he went home and discussed the matter with his father, a businessman at the time, and decided to enlist. He became a finance officer `` as luck would have it,'' serving `` past my six-year requirement,'' and achieving the rank of captain, he said. In the younger <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s case, the circumstances also involved talking to Staudt. `` It was obvious that somewhere I would have to serve and I was fully prepared to do so,'' said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, whose father was a decorated fighter pilot in World War II. The 42-year-old son said he, too, wanted to be a pilot. `` I heard the National Guard was looking for pilots,'' he said. He called Staudt, who confirmed the unit did need new pilots. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said he could not remember how he learned of the need for pilots or knew to call Staudt, but that ultimately he became the third of six new pilots who were selected in that <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> unit. He said he passed the pilot training exam, then served 18 months on active duty, six months in <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION> and another 12 months of pilot training in <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION> where he flew F102 fighters, then flew on a regular basis until 1973. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said he supported the <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> cause and he `` jumped at the opportunity'' to be a pilot, joining the Guard because he could not be assured a pilot job in the other military branches. `` I was going into the service one way or the other,'' he said. Some senior pilots from his unit did fly in <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> on a voluntary basis, he said. <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>'s son said he was motivated to join the Guard partly because he had just finished graduate school. `` I felt, as I think all of us did in 1968, that it was inevitable that we would be drafted within six to nine months. I did n't worry about going to <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>. In general I supported the war effort. ... My concern was that the military had a history of mismatching a person's experience with the job that they got and I was afraid they were going to make me a clerk typist somewhere.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880824-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-24-88 0140EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Quayle-Veterans     08-24 0774</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Quayle-Veterans,770</SECOND>
<HEAD>Quayle Statements on Vets Don't Square with Voting Record, Group
Says</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TIM AHERN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> veterans' group is criticizing <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> vice presidential candidate <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> for voting against what the group says are the interests of former <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> servicemen. `` On a number of different occasions, the <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION> senator has had a chance to show just how deep his fondness for <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> veterans goes, and in each case he's dropped the ball,'' said <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Stout </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> Vietnam </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Veterans </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>'s military record is under fire amid reports he used the influence of his powerful newspaper publishing family to join the <ORGANIZATION> Indiana </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> in 1969, shortly before he would have been eligible for the draft at the height of the Vietnam War. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>'s office released his military records Tuesday. The 47 pages of military records show that <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> scored below average on journalism tests he took after working more than four years as a <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> public affairs official. But the records do n't have any information about whether <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> used connections to join the Guard. The Vietnam Veterans of <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> on Tuesday criticized <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>'s votes in the past two years on veterans-related issues, including his opposition to a bill making the <ORGANIZATION> Veterans </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> a Cabinet-level department During an appearance Monday night before the Veterans of Foreign Wars, <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> also was criticized by some veterans for that same vote. When he introduced <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>, <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Rivers </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> VFW </ORGANIZATION>'s senior vice commander-in-chief, was applauded when he said, `` <PERSON> Dan </PERSON>, we applaud your stance on defense and foreign policy issues, but you and I still have some talking to do in the area of veterans legislation.'' <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> did a quick about-face on the issue, saying moments later, `` I'm sure that as I grow older that I will learn my youthful indiscretions of failing to vote for the <ORGANIZATION> Veterans </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>. I will recognize my mistake and it will turn out to be the greatest cabinet we have in our government _ no doubt about that.'' The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> voted 84-11 passage on July 12 of the bill making the <ORGANIZATION> VA </ORGANIZATION> a Cabinet-level agency. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> was one of the 11 opposition votes. Sen. <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Texas </LOCATION>, the Democratic vice presidential nominee, voted for the bill. A day earlier, both <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> and <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> voted against legislation which would permit veterans to go to federal courts to challenge VA decisions, a right that veterans do n't now have. Veterans organizations have pushed for that right of judicial review. On Oct. 16, 1987, <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> voted with the minority in an unsuccessful attempt to close the 188 storefront counseling centers scattered around the nation for <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> veterans. The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> rejected the closure on a 57-33 vote. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> was one of the 33 minority votes, while <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> voted to keep the centers open. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> and <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> joined a unanimous 89-0 vote on May 8, 1987, when the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> approved a bill to continue indefinitely the GI bill, a sweeping measure which provides education benefits for veterans. Last Dec. 4, <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> and <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> both again joined a unanimous 88-0 vote approving an increase in the disability rate for veterans and improved veterans benefits. Generally, the military records released Tuesday are routine papers, detailing immunizations and copies of orders mentioning <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>'s name. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> entered the guard May 19, 1969, six days before he was to graduate from <ORGANIZATION> DePauw </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> and become eligible for the draft. He had been called for his pre-induction physical April 9, 1969, an indication he was likely to be drafted. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> spent almost all his Guard career in the 120th Public Information Detachment. Most of his time was as a clerk-typist, although he also was rated as a senior information specialist. He also was trained as a welder, but he did not perform that task in the service. When <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> was evaluated as public information specialist in July 1975, two months after he left the service, he scored 56 points on a written test, 19 points below the average score of 75, the records show. The written test included questions on seven military journalism categories. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> scored `` low'' in five of the seven and `` average'' in the other two. There were five possible scores, ranging from `` very low'' and `` low'' through `` average,'' `` high,'' and `` very high.'' The written test was one of three parts of the evaluation. The records do not detail the scores on the other two sections, but they indicate <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>'s overall rating was an 82. There was no explanation for the missing scores, nor was there an indication of how the 82 figure compared with scores for other Guard members.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880824-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-24-88 0140EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-TreasuryAuction     08-24 0098</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Treasury Auction,100</SECOND>
<HEAD>Yields On Treasury Notes Up</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Yields on two-year <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> notes rose in the latest auction to the highest level in almost three years. The average yield Tuesday was 8.72 percent, up from 8.41 percent at the last auction on June 27. It was the highest rate since two-year notes averaged 8.9 percent on Oct. 23, 1985. The notes will carry a coupon interest rate of 8 | percent with each $ 10,000 in face value selling for $ 9,982.90 A total of $ 8.78 billion in notes were sold out of bids totalling $ 35.27 billion.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880824-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-24-88 0143EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w BC-TradeBill-Glance     08-24 0765</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Trade Bill-Glance,760</SECOND>
<HEAD>Highlights Of Trade Bill Signed Into Law By Reagan</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are major provisions of a trade bill signed into law by President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> on Tuesday to curb record <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> trade deficits: _ Guarantees accelerated congressional consideration of agreements reached in the current <LOCATION> Uruguay </LOCATION> Round of international trade talks and bars any congressional amendments to such measures _ Requires the president to retaliate against trade agreement violations and other `` unjustifiable'' trade practices but permits the president to waive such action under certain circumstances _ Directs the administration to pinpoint high-priority unfair trade practices and take initial steps toward possible retaliation while seeking to resolve the problem through negotiations over three years _ Enlarges the definition of unfair trade practices to include export targeting, or concerted government action to increase the competitiveness of certain industries, as well as denial of worker rights and establishment of foreign cartels _ Transfers from the president to the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> trade representative authority to decide if a foreign trade practice is unfair under <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> law and to take remedial action _ Requires companies seeking import curbs against foreign competition to prove not only that imports are inflicting economic injury on them but that such relief would help the company adjust and become more competitive _ Authorizes $ 80 million for worker retraining for employees who are laid off _ Authorizes $ 980 million a year for two years for a new program to provide comprehensive aid to displaced workers _ Bars <ORGANIZATION> Toshiba </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Kongsberg </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Vaapenfabrikk </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Norway </LOCATION> from selling to the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government for three years and two of their subsidiaries from selling commercially in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> for the same period in retaliation for the subsidiaries' sale of submarine-silencing equipment to the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> _ Requires the <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> to enter into discussions aimed at establishing a Third World debt management facility _ Extends the <ORGANIZATION> Export </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Enhancement </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Program </ORGANIZATION> _ which pays surplus farm commodities in government bins to exporters to stimulate overseas shipments _ for two years and authorizes a level of $ 2.5 billion _ Doubles the price tag on the Targeted Export Assistance program _ which subsidizes advertising and promotional activities for <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> farm goods overseas _ to $ 215 million Increases the authorization for the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agricultural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> by $ 20 million. _ Establishes a triggered marketing loan program under which the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> would provide major new export subsidies to wheat, feed grains and soybeans producers for their 1990 crops if significant progress is not made through trade talks _ Repeals the 1980 windfall profits tax on oil industry earnings _ Provides special authority to the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> trade representative to negotiate the opening of telecommunications markets _ Eases the way for businesses to halt the import of goods produced in violation of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> trademark, patent and copyright laws _ Authorizes federal funds for programs to promote literacy _ Calls for $ 175 million in grants to school districts and state educational agencies to improve instruction in math, science, foreign languages and computers _ Authorizes $ 20 million for model foreign language programs in elementary and secondary schools, $ 85 million in university research grants and $ 21.5 million to spur the interest of students in science, engineering and math _ Calls for $ 200 million to improve basic skills of high school students and $ 50 million for dropout prevention plus $ 37.5 million for programs to enhance math, science and language learning with telecommunications technology, $ 15 million for regional technology transfer centers and $ 2 million each for technology education and technology literacy _ Reduces controls on export of technology, mainly to <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> countries and <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, that could have military applications _ Bars the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reserve </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> from allowing foreign-owned securities firms to serve as primary dealers of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government securities, unless their home countries grant the same privilege to <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> firms _ Requires the government to initiate multination talks with other major industrialized countries to achieve better coordination of economic policies _ Directs the <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> to start talks with nations that it believes are manipulating their exchange rates if they are running trade surpluses with the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> _ Relaxes the Foreign Corrupt Practices Act to make it easier for American executives to defend themselves on bribery charges resulting from payments by their overseas representatives to foreign officials _ Authorizes two so-called `` tied aid'' programs that combine foreign aid grants with export financing _ Directs the president to pinpoint nations that discriminate against <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> suppliers in their government procurement, and bars federal agencies from buying goods and services produced in such nations _ Authorizes $ 3.5 million to step up small business activities in international trade _ <ORGANIZATION> Expands </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Food </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Drug </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> monitoring to determine if food imports contain residues of banned pesticides
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880824-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-24-88 0030EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p AM-ElectionRdp 3rdLd-Writethru a0755 08-24 0681</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Election Rdp, 3rd Ld - Writethru, a0755,0693</SECOND>
<HEAD>Congressional Primaries in Oklahoma, Alaska; Olympics Vote in
Anchorage</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Leads with 9 grafs to UPDATE with later returns, Glassco
winning, quotes. Picks up 7th graf pvs `In Alaska...' Material
below dash will stand. Polls close at midnight EDT in Alaska.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
